<?xml version='1.0' encoding='us-ascii'?>
<news>
    <entry author="By Duane D. Stanford" datetime="Apr 15, 2014  4:23 PM ET" progress_sentiment="u" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-15/coca-cola-profit-meets-estimates-as-global-volume-increases.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola First-Quarter Results Soothe Soda Slowdown Fear</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Co. (KO) Chief Executive
            Officer Muhtar Kent can exhale now. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The world's largest soda maker today showed signs of a
            rebound in the first three months of the year, easing the
            concerns that arose when the company unsettled investors with
            surprisingly sluggish global sales in the fourth quarter.
            Earnings met estimates, sales volume in North America halted its
            slide, and sales gains were strong in markets such as China. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;After the fourth-quarter report, Kent promised improvement
            and implemented a cost-cutting program that's already showing
            some progress. Global sales volume rose 2 percent, and an
            emphasis on new package sizes helped boost pricing by 2 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Add it all together and profit excluding some items was 44
            cents a share in the three months ended March 28, Atlanta-based
            Coca-Cola said today in a statement. That matched the average of
            18 analysts' estimates compiled by Bloomberg. Net income fell
            7.5 percent $1.62 billion, or 36 cents a share, from $1.75
            billion, or 39 cents, a year earlier. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'We don't think this is a great result, but satisfying as
            one step in the right direction to restore momentum,' Kent said
            during a conference call. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Volume in North America was little changed in the first
            quarter, compared with a 1 percent decline in the fourth
            quarter. Sales on that basis strengthened in emerging markets,
            including a 12 percent gain in China. &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: Kiyoshi Ota/Bloomberg

            &lt;p&gt;
            Coca-Cola Co. Chief Executive Officer Muhtar Kent, facing sluggish soft drink sales in the U.S., has
            implemented a cost-cutting program to boost earnings and is collaborating with Keurig Green Mountain Inc. to
            compete in at-home soda making. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Duane D. Stanford" datetime="Apr 16, 2013  4:22 PM ET" progress_sentiment="u" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-04-16/coca-cola-profit-tops-estimates-as-latin-america-sales-increase.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola Rises Most Since 2009 on Profit, Bottler Deal</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Co. (KO) jumped the most in
            more than four years after reporting first-quarter profit that
            topped analysts' estimates and announcing a deal to sell some
            bottling distribution rights in North America. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The shares rose 5.7 percent to $42.37 at the close in New
            York for the Atlanta-based company's largest gain since Feb. 12,
            2009. The volume of shares traded was higher than the three-
            month daily average by more than threefold. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Net income fell 15 percent to $1.75 billion, or 39 cents a
            share, from $2.05 billion, or 45 cents, a year earlier, Coke
            said today in a statement. Excluding some items, profit was 46
            cents a share, compared with the 44-cent average of 14 analysts'
            estimates compiled by Bloomberg. The results were helped by
            higher Latin America sales volume. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chief Executive Officer Muhtar Kent has introduced new
            package sizes in Latin America and emphasized Coca-Cola branded
            soft drinks, Del Valle juices and Powerade. In North America,
            where Kent has worked to streamline distribution, the company
            said today it will retain manufacturing under the new agreement
            while selling and swapping some distribution rights among five
            smaller franchise bottlers. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'This is a first step in their eventual divestment of much
            of the U.S. bottling operations,' Thomas Mullarkey, an analyst
            for Morningstar Inc. (MORN) in Chicago, said today in a telephone
            interview. 'They don't want all those capital-intensive
            distribution assets sitting on their balance sheet in
            perpetuity.' &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: David Paul Morris/Bloomberg

            &lt;p&gt;
            Net income fell 15 percent to $1.75 billion, or 39 cents a share, from $2.05 billion, or 45 cents, a year
            earlier, Atlanta- based Coca-Cola said today in a statement. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Noah Buhayar" datetime="Apr 16, 2013  4:51 PM ET" progress_sentiment="u" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-04-16/berkshire-gains-as-buffett-s-coca-cola-stake-rallies.html">
        <headline>Berkshire Gains as Buffett's Coca-Cola Stake Rallies</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Warren Buffett's Berkshire Hathaway
            Inc., the largest investor in Coca-Cola Co. (KO), jumped the most
            since January in New York trading on gains in the value of its
            stake in the soft-drink maker. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Berkshire Class A shares rallied $4,000, or 2.6 percent, to
            $161,000, a record closing price. Atlanta-based Coca-Cola surged
            5.7 percent after posting first-quarter profit that beat
            analysts' estimates and announcing a deal to sell some bottling
            distribution rights in North America. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Buffett's firm has 400 million Coca-Cola shares, making it
            one of the four largest holdings at Omaha, Nebraska-based
            Berkshire, along with investments in Wells Fargo Co., American
            Express Co., and International Business Machines Corp.
            Berkshire's stakes in the companies may increase in the future
            as the firms buy back shares, Buffett said in a letter to
            investors last month. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'The four companies possess marvelous businesses and are
            run by managers who are both talented and shareholder-
            oriented,' Buffett said in the letter. 'Too much of good thing
            can be wonderful.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>

    <entry author="By Noah Buhayar and Laura Marcinek" datetime="Apr 23, 2014  2:28 PM ET" progress_sentiment="u" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-23/coca-cola-wins-compensation-vote-overcoming-winters-opposition.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola Wins Compensation Vote, Overcoming Winters's Fight</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Co. (KO) won investor approval
            for its plan to award employees with stock, overcoming an
            argument from money manager David Winters that lavish pay
            packages are diminishing returns for shareholders. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Eighty-three percent of votes cast supported the equity
            plan, according to preliminary results in an e-mailed statement
            today from the company. The annual meeting was held in Atlanta,
            the city where Coca-Cola is based. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Winters had waged a campaign since March to persuade
            investors to reject the soft-drink maker's proposal. The new
            plan, in addition to ones already enacted, could transfer $29.8
            billion to the managers, he said. Investors such as the Ontario
            Teachers' Pension Plan and Calvert Investments had sided with
            Winters, who runs the firm Wintergreen Advisers LLC. Coca-Cola
            said its board was pleased with the vote. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'The company's compensation programs are performance-based
            and the equity plan is fair, competitive and consistent with
            shareowners' interests and our pay for performance philosophy,'
            according to the statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In making his case, Winters appealed directly to Berkshire
            Hathaway Inc. Chief Executive Officer Warren Buffett, who
            controls the biggest stake in Coca-Cola. Buffett, the world's
            third-richest person, used to be on Coca-Cola's board, and his
            son is a director. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;'Extraneous Factors' &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'His fiduciary duty is to all of the Berkshire
            shareholders,' Winters said in an interview yesterday. Buffett
            shouldn't vote based on 'any other extraneous factors.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola has said that stock repurchases, including $4.8
            billion of buybacks in 2013, cushion the dilution tied to
            employee awards. Dilution related to equity plans has been less
            than 1 percent annually over the past three years, 'and is
            expected to be in this range going forward,' the company said
            in a presentation. Coca-Cola also said that the link of the pay
            to performance means that all the potential awards may not be
            earned. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola said a separate advisory vote on executive
            compensation won 90 percent support. Investors also voted
            against a measure that called for an independent board chairman. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>

    <entry author="By Clementine Fletcher" datetime="Apr 29, 2013 11:19 AM ET" progress_sentiment="d" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-04-29/coca-cola-hbc-sees-margin-rebound-as-bottler-makes-london-debut.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola HBC Sees Margin Rebound as Bottler Makes London Debut</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola HBC AG, the soft-drink
            bottler that switched its primary listing to the London Stock
            Exchange today, expects profitability to rebound this year as
            sugar and oil prices rise at a slower pace than previous years. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Commodity costs will increase at a 'low single-digit'
            pace, after climbing 14 percent in 2011 and 6 percent in 2012,
            Chief Executive Officer Dimitris Lois said in an interview at
            the London bourse. Cost reduction measures such as consolidating
            some office processes will also boost margins, helping offset a
            slowdown in revenue growth, Lois said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Rising prices for commodities have presented an additional
            challenge for food and drink makers in recent years as they
            struggle to contend with weakening consumer demand. Coca-Cola
            HBC's operating margin declined to 6.4 percent of sales in its
            2012 fiscal year from 10.8 percent in 2007. Lois said today that
            he expects the margin to return to levels seen before the
            European financial crisis, without giving a timeframe. European
            markets show few signs of stabilization, he also said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'It's a bit of a challenge,' the CEO said. 'At some
            stage this year we'll be able to look back and say that probably
            the worst is behind us, but it's still a tough year.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola HBC shares traded at 1,737 pence at 4:17 p.m. on
            their first day of London trading, giving the company a market
            value of about 6.1 billion pounds ($9.5 billion). The bottler
            said in October it would move its primary listing from Athens to
            London, fleeing the epicenter of Europe's debt crisis. It also
            switched its domicile to Zug, Switzerland. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;'Quite Complex' &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The listing process was 'innovative and quite complex,'
            and 'made the company known to a wider audience who aren't
            particularly knowledgeable about the Coke bottling system,'
            Lois said. The move will make Coca-Cola HBC eligible for
            inclusion in London's benchmark FTSE 100 Index (UKX) in September. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Cost reduction measures such as consolidating finance and
            human resources into one center will reduce expenses by about 65
            million euros this year, Chief Financial Officer Michalis Imellos said in the same interview. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Revenue, excluding currency shifts, will grow at a slower
            pace than last year's 2 percent, Lois said, as austerity
            measures in the Eurozone weigh on improvements elsewhere. He
            declined to comment on whether the volume of products sold would
            increase after being unchanged last year. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola HBC operates in countries with lower per-capita
            consumption of sparkling drinks than the rest of the Eurozone,
            which will help in boosting volume growth, Lois said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Russia, Nigeria &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola HBC buys concentrate from Coca-Cola Co. and
            blends, bottles and sells the products in European countries
            including Greece and Italy. Lois said he's optimistic about the
            emerging markets of Russia and Nigeria this year. Sales of Coca-
            Cola in Russia were helped by a government ban on selling beer
            at freestanding kiosks, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'We still have a lot of consumers to recruit,' Lois said,
            noting that per-capita consumption in most of its markets for
            sparkling beverages is lower than the Eurozone average. He cited
            Italy, one of the country's biggest markets, which has a 20
            percent lower per-capita consumption of sparkling beverages than
            Serbia, and 40 percent lower consumption than Bulgaria. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The company expects to sell bonds in the next six-to-nine
            months, the CEO said, as it seeks to refinance about 1 billion
            euros of debt due by 2014. Coca-Cola HBC will sell bonds in
            euros and seek an average debt maturity of about 5 years. It's
            not looking to raise money for acquisitions and isn't interested
            in buying Coca-Cola's German bottling operations, Lois said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Enterprises Inc., another bottler of the
            bestselling soft drink, said April 25 that it let a right to buy
            Coca-Cola's German bottling operations lapse. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Stephan Nielsen" datetime="Aug 01, 2013  2:56 PM ET" progress_sentiment="d" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-01/light-to-build-cogeneration-plant-at-coca-cola-factory-in-brazil.html">
        <headline>Light to Build Cogeneration Plant at Coca-Cola Factory in Brazil</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Light SA (LIGT3), the Brazilian power
            utility, plans to build a 90 million-real ($39 million)
            cogeneration plant at a Coca-Cola factory by December. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Light will operate the plant in Rio de Janeiro state for 15
            years, Marco Donatelli, director of the company's energy-efficiency unit Light Esco, said today at a
            conference in Sao
            Paulo. The facility will turn natural gas into power, steam,
            carbon dioxide and nitrogen for soft-drink production, he said.
            It may include a boiler that will run on wood pellets. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Jaime Myslik and Duane D. Stanford" datetime="Aug 05, 2014  1:17 PM ET" progress_sentiment="d" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-05/coca-cola-to-invest-5-billion-in-africa-with-partners.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola to Invest $5 Billion in Africa With Partners</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Co. (K), the world's largest
            beverage company, plans to invest $5 billion with its bottling
            partners in Africa over the next six years, to create new
            manufacturing capacity, sustainability initiatives and jobs. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The new expenditure will raise investment in the region to
            $17 billion from 2010 to 2020, the Atlanta-based company said in
            a statement. The company also announced the initiative at the
            U.S.-Africa Business Forum, which is taking place in Washington
            today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chief Executive Officer Muhtar Kent is expanding in Africa
            to capitalize on a growing middle class with more money to spend
            on high-end soft drinks and juices. Nigeria and Kenya, among the
            major economies in the region, consume fewer than 50 servings of
            Coke's beverages per person each year, compared with the 745
            servings per individual consumed in Mexico. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Even as we see tremendous growth potential in Africa, we
            know that the strength and sustainability of our business are
            tied directly to the strength and sustainability of the African
            communities we proudly serve,' Kent said in the statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola is increasingly relying on overseas markets to
            maintain growth as it contends with sluggish demand for drinks
            such as juice and Diet Coke in North America. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The new investment will also be channeled into Coca-Cola's
            cooling and distribution equipment and production, its supply
            chain across the continent, as well as supporting programs for
            safe water access, sustainable sourcing and the economic
            empowerment of women, the company said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Kent also announced that the Coca-Cola Africa Foundation
            will expand its Replenish Africa Initiative to reach an
            additional four million African people through 2020. The
            program, which works with public and private partners, supports
            clean water access and sanitation initiatives across the region.
            The new target is in addition to an existing goal of reaching
            two million people by 2015. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Today's U.S.-Africa Business Forum is hosted by Bloomberg
            Philanthropies and the U.S. Commerce Department. Bloomberg
            Philanthropies is led by Michael Bloomberg, the founder and
            majority owner of Bloomberg LP, the parent of Bloomberg News. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>

    <entry author="By Sarah Shannon" datetime="Aug 08, 2013  2:53 AM ET" progress_sentiment="d" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-08/coca-cola-hbc-sales-decline-as-established-european-markets-slip.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola HBC Sales Decline as Established European Markets Slip</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola HBC AG (CCH), the bottler that
            switched its listing from Athens to London, said second-quarter
            sales fell 2 percent as a volume gain in emerging markets failed
            to offset declines in countries including Greece and Austria. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Revenue fell to 1.95 billion euros ($2.6 billion) in the
            three months ended June 28, the company said today in a
            statement. That missed the prediction of Mike Gibbs, an analyst
            at JPMorgan Cazenove who estimated sales of 1.989 billion euros. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Volume gained 2 percent in emerging markets, Coca-Cola HBC
            said, while levels dropped 6 percent in so-called established
            economies and 3 percent in developing markets. The company buys
            concentrate from Atlanta-based Coca-Cola Co. and sells the
            products in Europe. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola HBC said it will start a 'progressive' dividend
            policy in 2014 that targets an annual payout with a ratio to
            profit after tax of 35 percent to 45 percent. The company, which
            switched its primary stock listing in April, paid a dividend of
            34 euros cents a share in July worth 124.7 million euros, or
            about 43 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola HBC maintained volume share in sparkling drinks
            'in the majority of our markets' in the first half, the
            company said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The bottler operates in countries with lower per-capita
            consumption of sparkling drinks than the rest of the eurozone,
            which will help it boost volume growth, Chief Executive Officer
            Dimitris Lois said in April. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Brendan Coffey" datetime="Aug 15, 2014  4:15 PM ET" progress_sentiment="u" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-15/coca-cola-s-stake-buy-makes-monster-founders-billionaires.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola's Stake Buy Makes Monster Founders Billionaires</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Rodney Sacks and Hilton Schlosberg wanted to get into the packaging business. Frustrated in their
            attempt to find a company to buy, the partners took a tip from an investment banker and purchased debt-laden
            soda maker Hansen Natural Corp. in 1992. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Two decades, a name change and a whole lot of
            caffeine later, the partners have emerged as billionaires as their company, Monster Beverage Corp. (MNST),
            agreed to sell a 17 percent stake to Coca-Cola Co. (KO) yesterday for $2.15 billion. The stock jumped 30
            percent to $93.49 at 4:15 p.m. today in New York. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The deal gives Coca-Cola greater
            exposure to the energy drinks market, one of the fastest-growing segments in the beverage industry, having
            doubled in sales since 2007, according to Euromonitor International Ltd. The carbonated soft drinks
            category, which includes offerings from PepsiCo Inc. (PEP) and Coca-Cola, expanded just 0.3 percent in 2013.
            &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;'If you look across mature beverage categories, it's impossible to find someone with a
            growth rate that does not let up like Monster Beverage's,' said Jeffrey Klineman, editor of trade
            publication BevNet. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The company's main product, Monster Energy, has sold more than 10
            billion units since its introduction in 1997. It has almost four times the amount of caffeine as Coke,
            according to the website Caffeine Informer. &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: Patrick T. Fallon/Bloomberg

            &lt;p&gt;
            Monster has 34.3 percent share of the energy drink market to Red Bull's 33.9 percent, according to a Monster
            presentation to investors in January. Last year, Monster started a protein drink, Muscle Monster. In a nod
            to its natural soda roots, it introduced a kale flavored Hansen-brand soda earlier this year. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By David Fickling" datetime="Aug 20, 2014  3:36 AM ET" progress_sentiment="d" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-20/coca-cola-amatil-flags-drop-in-full-year-earnings-as-costs-rise.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola Amatil Flags Earnings Drop as Costs Rise</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Amatil Ltd. (CCL) flagged a
            second consecutive drop in full-year earnings amid weak consumer
            confidence and rising costs in Indonesia. Its shares fell the
            most in more than two months. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Earnings before interest and tax fell 12 percent from a
            year earlier to A$317 million ($295 million) in the six months
            ended June 30, Australia's largest beverage company said in a
            regulatory statement today. Net income fell 16 percent to its
            lowest first-half level in three years. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Declining profits add to pressure on new Managing Director
            Alison Watkins, who's reviewing the company's businesses and
            considering new products. She faces domestic price competition
            as Asahi Group Holdings Ltd. sells Pepsi as much as 33 percent
            cheaper than Coke. Annual net income last year hit a 21-year low
            due to a A$404 million writedown at its packaged-foods unit. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Amatil needs to make considerable price investments,' to
            cut its differential over Pepsi, Michael Simotas, an analyst at
            Deutsche Bank AG in Sydney, wrote in an Aug. 6 note to clients.
            'The increasing negativity toward sugar and the resultant
            reduction in consumption remains a key concern.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The shares declined 2.1 percent to A$9.54 at the close of
            trading in Sydney, the sharpest fall since June 5. The stock has
            slumped 21 percent this year, compared to a 5.3 percent
            improvement in the benchmark SP/ASX 200 index. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Full-year earnings will be 'materially below' those
            during the 12 months ended December, with revenue falling in its
            alcoholic drinks unit and competition and costs hitting its
            Indonesian business. The company is trying to cut A$100 million
            of costs over the next three years, it said today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Low-Calorie Drinks &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Sydney-based Coca-Cola Amatil will offer more low and no-calorie drinks in future as a result of a
            strategic review
            announced after Watkins took over its top job. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'As a business we have been slow to adapt to these changes
            in market conditions and shifting consumer trends,' she said in
            today's statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Net income in the period was A$182 million, compared with
            the A$173 million average of three analysts' estimates compiled
            by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>

    <entry author="By Duane D. Stanford" datetime="Dec 13, 2013 11:00 AM ET" progress_sentiment="d" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-13/coca-cola-ceo-shakes-up-management-to-speed-u-s-bottling-revamp.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola Shakes Up Management to Speed U.S. Bottling Revamp</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Co. (KO) Chief Executive
            Officer Muhtar Kent, trying to speed efforts to improve the
            company's North American distribution system, shook up his
            management team, resulting in the departure of a leader once
            considered a contender to succeed him. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Steve Cahillane, president of Coca-Cola Americas, will
            leave the company as his unit is dissolved, the Atlanta-based
            company said in a statement yesterday. North America operations,
            including brand marketing, food service and new product
            development, will be handed back to 25-year Coke veteran Sandy Douglas, who stepped aside as president of
            the region in 2012.
            Coke's bottling operations in the U.S. and Canada will be folded
            into the company's international bottling group. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'We organized the business to intensify focus on key
            markets, streamline reporting lines and provide flexibility to
            adjust the business within these geographies in the future,'
            Kent said in the statement. The changes, he said, will
            'accelerate the refranchising of our bottling system in our
            flagship market.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In 2010, Kent took control of 90 percent of Coca-Cola's
            North American distribution network with the purchase of its
            largest bottler, hoping to stem volume sales declines and boost
            profit. He is reversing a decades-old model in which Coca-Cola
            sold franchises in the U.S. to bottlers who handled everything
            from production to distribution, buying beverage concentrates
            from Coca-Cola. &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

            &lt;p&gt;
            Coke's bottling operations in the U.S. and Canada will be folded into the company's international bottling
            group. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>


    <entry author="By David Fickling" datetime="Feb 18, 2014  1:07 AM ET" progress_sentiment="d" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-18/coca-cola-amatil-apologizes-after-a-404-million-spc-writedown.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola Amatil Apologizes After $367 Million SPC Writedown</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Amatil Ltd. (CCL) Managing
            Director Terry Davis told investors he was sorry after a A$404
            million ($367 million) writeoff at its packaged-foods unit SPC
            Ardmona drove profit to its lowest level since 1992. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'I apologize to not be able to bring you a better
            result,' Davis, who's leaving the job March 3, told investors
            on a call today after announcing an 83 percent drop in net
            income to A$79.9 million for the year ended Dec. 31. 'Hopefully
            we've turned the tide' with SPC, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Sales volumes at Coca-Cola Amatil's main Australian soft
            drinks business fell 3.2 percent to 338 million cases last year,
            cutting group revenue by 1.1 percent to A$5.08 billion, the
            first decline since 2006, according to data compiled by
            Bloomberg. Australia's biggest beverage company fell 5.3 percent
            to A$11.22 at the close in Sydney, its lowest price since August
            2011. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Australian food companies have been hurt by currency swings
            in recent years. The Australian dollar's rise to a 29-year high
            of $1.11 in July 2011 lowered the cost of competing imports, and
            its subsequent decline to 90 cents has increased the price of
            raw materials. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Asahi Group Holdings Ltd. (2502)'s Schweppes Australia unit, which
            sells Pepsi in the country, raised prices for the first time in
            two years this month, Citigroup Inc. analyst Gino Rossi wrote in
            a Feb. 7 note to clients, driven by an estimated 3.5 percent
            increase in costs of imported ingredients. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;That will lessen pricing pressure on Coca-Cola, which sells
            at a premium of more than 50 percent to Pepsi, according to
            Rossi. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Aggressive competitor pricing' was responsible for the
            poor result from Coca-Cola Amatil's Australian beverage unit,
            the company said today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;State Support &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The results were a negative for Coca-Cola Amatil's credit,
            Moody's Investors Service senior vice president Ian Lewis wrote
            in an opinion after the announcement. It wouldn't affect the
            company's investment-grade ratings, which are stable at A3, he
            wrote. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'The high Australian dollar has enabled a flood of cheap
            imported product to be sold in Australia below the cost of
            production here while decimating SPCA's export markets,' Coca-Cola Amatil said in a regulatory statement
            today. The company
            will pursue anti-dumping measures, changes to import tariffs,
            and enforcement of standards on ingredients, according to the
            statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;'Corporate Welfare' &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Australia's federal government, which has said it doesn't
            believe in 'corporate welfare,' on Jan. 30 turned down Coca-Cola Amatil's request for a A$25 million grant
            to fund
            efficiency savings at SPC Ardmona. The government of Victoria
            state will instead provide A$22 million alongside A$78 million
            from the company, the parent company said Feb. 13. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The remaining book value of SPC Ardmona is 'just north of
            A$300 million,' Alison Watkins, who will take over from Davis
            next month, told investors on the call. The state's investment
            won't eliminate Coca-Cola Amatil's ability to exit the business
            if it continues to underperform, Davis said, without giving
            further details. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Duane D. Stanford" datetime="Feb 18, 2014  4:30 PM ET" progress_sentiment="d" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-18/coca-cola-profit-falls-8-4-as-cost-cuts-announced.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola Plans $1 Billion in Cost Cuts as Profit Falls</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Co. (KO), the world's largest
            beverage company, dropped the most in more than two years after
            North American soft-drink demand shrank and its once-effervescent growth in emerging markets showed signs of
            slowing. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Fourth-quarter net income slid 8.4 percent to $1.71
            billion, or 38 cents a share, from $1.87 billion, or 41 cents, a
            year earlier, Atlanta-based Coca-Cola said today in a statement.
            Sales fell 3.6 percent to $11 billion in the period, missing the
            average analyst estimate compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chief Executive Officer Muhtar Kent, facing sluggish demand
            worldwide, embarked on a plan to cut $1 billion in annual costs
            by 2016, aiming to reduce supply and data-management expenses
            and overhaul marketing programs. Still, the company has been
            slow to react to health concerns about its drinks, as well as
            the growing desire for beverages that aren't carbonated colas,
            said Ali Dibadj, an analyst at Sanford C. Bernstein Co. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'The changes that the company is making just aren't
            enough,' Dibadj, who is based in New York, said in an
            interview. 'Many investors aren't sharing the confidence that
            management does of the company's future.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola shares fell 3.8 percent to $37.47 in New York,
            marking the biggest one-day decline since August 2011. The
            shares have dropped 9.3 percent this year, compared with a 0.4
            percent decline for the Standard Poor's 500 Index. PepsiCo
            Inc. (PEP), the company's biggest competitor, has decreased 5.7
            percent in that period. &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: Patrick Fallon/Bloomberg

            &lt;p&gt;
            Bottles of Coca-Cola Co. soda are displayed for sale at a convenience store in Redondo Beach. Global sales
            volume rose 2 percent for the year and 1 percent for the quarter, less than the 4 percent annual and 3
            percent quarterly growth reported a year ago. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Duane D. Stanford" datetime="Feb 19, 2014  4:31 PM ET" progress_sentiment="d" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-19/buffett-s-coca-cola-complacency-warning-foretells-troubled-year.html">
        <headline>Buffett's Coca-Cola Complacency Warning Foretells Trouble</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Warren Buffett, speaking last April at Coca-Cola Co. (KO)'s annual meeting, warned that the
            beverage giant shouldn't get complacent about its success. Ten months later, those words could come back to
            haunt the company. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The world's largest soft-drink maker, facing sluggish growth overseas
            and concerns about the healthiness of its product at home, posted its fourth straight quarter of declining
            sales yesterday. The results sent the stock on its biggest one-day decline in more than two years -- bad
            news for both Coke and Buffett, the company's largest shareholder. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The slowdown has
            raised concerns about the long-term plan of Chief Executive Officer Muhtar Kent, who has promised big
            revenue gains by 2020. Investors are looking for Kent to take bolder steps, said Ali Dibadj, an analyst at
            Sanford C. Bernstein Co. While the company announced a $1 billion budget-tightening plan yesterday, it
            doesn't go far enough, he said. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Related:&lt;/p&gt;
            Berkshire Investors Lacking Data Take Buffett on Faith

            Opinion: Buffett's Pal Munger Heads a Very Weird Company

            &lt;p&gt;'There needs to be much more cost cutting,' Dibadj, who is based in New York, said in an interview.
            'There needs to be much faster innovation. There needs to be much more return of cash to shareholders.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coke's fourth-quarter sales fell 3.6 percent to $11 billion, missing the average analyst estimate
            compiled by Bloomberg. Net income slid 8.4 percent to $1.71 billion, or 38 cents a share, from $1.87
            billion, or 41 cents, a year earlier. &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: Daniel Acker/Bloomberg

            &lt;p&gt;
            Warren Buffett, chief executive officer of Berkshire Hathaway, with a Cherry Coca-Cola in Omaha, Nebraska.
            Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>

    <entry author="By Duane D. Stanford" datetime="Feb 20, 2014  2:04 PM ET" progress_sentiment="u" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-20/coca-cola-names-waller-finance-chief-as-fayard-retires.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola Names Waller Finance Chief as Fayard Retires</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Co. (KO) said Kathy Waller,
            vice president of finance and controller, will become chief
            financial officer, replacing Gary Fayard, who is retiring. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Waller, 55, joined Coca-Cola as a senior accountant in
            1987, the Atlanta-based company said today in a statement.
            Fayard, who is 62 years-old and has been CFO since 1999, will
            retire in May. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chief Executive Officer Muhtar Kent is leading the world's
            largest soft-drink maker in a plan to cut $1 billion in costs by
            2016 and plow the savings into marketing to help revive demand.
            Earlier this week, Coca-Cola shares had their biggest one-day
            decline in two months after the company posted fourth-quarter
            results that showed North American soft-drink demand is
            shrinking and growth in emerging markets was slowing. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola rose 0.6 percent to $37.30 at 1:52 p.m. in New
            York. The shares fell 10 percent this year through yesterday,
            compared with a 1.1 percent drop for the Standard Poor's 500
            Index. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tara Lachapelle" datetime="Jan 10, 2014  5:38 PM ET" progress_sentiment="u" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-01-10/monster-s-surging-sales-argue-for-coca-cola-bid-real-m-a.html">
        <headline>Monster's Surging Sales Argue for Coca-Cola Bid: Real M&amp;amp;A</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Even after getting $3 billion more
            expensive in two years, Monster Beverage Corp. (MNST) could still be a
            desirable target for beverage companies in need of a sales jolt. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The long-standing subject of takeover speculation is
            increasing revenue faster than every major U.S. soft drink
            maker, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. That includes
            Coca-Cola Co. (KO), which is poised to report its first annual sales
            drop since the financial crisis. Coca-Cola may be motivated to
            bid for the maker of Monster and Worx brand energy drinks and
            Peace Tea to protect their distribution agreement, said Stifel
            Financial Corp. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Monster's growth would be costly to buy, and any suitor
            would have to weigh the risk of betting on energy drinks at a
            time when health concerns about caffeine-rich products have
            spurred a U.S. regulatory investigation. Still, even at a 41
            percent premium, the $16 billion purchase could boost Coca-Cola's earnings, according to Bank of Montreal.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'It's going to be an expensive acquisition because of the
            growth,' Jack Russo, a St. Louis-based analyst at Edward Jones
            Co., said in a phone interview. 'Certainly any buyer that
            wants to get into this category has to look at the regulatory
            environment and see that there are a lot more alarm bells going
            off about energy drinks. Those two things need to be weighed.' &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: Patrick T. Fallon/Bloomberg

            &lt;p&gt;
            The Monster Beverage Corp. logo is displayed on the window of a refrigerator housing cans of the company's
            energy drink for sale at a convenience store in Redondo Beach, California. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Greg Stohr" datetime="Jan 10, 2014  5:50 PM ET" progress_sentiment="u" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-01-10/coca-coca-pomegranate-drink-targeted-in-high-court-case.html">
        <headline>Coca-Coca Pomegranate Drink Targeted in High Court Case</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;The U.S. Supreme Court agreed to
            decide whether a rival drink-maker can sue Coca-Cola Co. (KO) for
            allegedly deceiving consumers about the amount of pomegranate
            juice in one of its beverages. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A federal appeals court barred the suit by Pom Wonderful
            LLC, saying Food and Drug Administration regulations authorize
            the Coca-Cola product's name. The label on the drink says
            'Pomegranate Blueberry Flavored Blend of 5 Juices,' with the
            first two words appearing in larger letters. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Pom Wonderful says the label is misleading because the
            drink contains only 0.3 percent pomegranate juice and 0.2
            percent blueberry juice. Apple and grape juice constitute 99
            percent of the juice, Pom Wonderful says. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The appeals court ruling 'undermines the transparency that
            health-conscious consumers rightly expect so that they can make
            informed decisions about what they eat and drink,' Los Angeles-based Pom Wonderful said in an e-mailed
            statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola says the label accurately tells consumers that
            the product is a blend of fruits and tastes like pomegranate and
            blueberry. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'We are confident our labeling fully complies with
            applicable FDA regulations, as the lower courts have
            consistently found,' the Atlanta-based company said in an e-mailed statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The legal question is whether the Lanham Act, which
            authorizes false-advertising suits, can apply even when the FDA
            regulates a product. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A San Francisco-based federal appeals court threw out the
            suit saying, 'we must respect the FDA's apparent decision not
            to impose the requirements urged by Pom.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Justices Samuel Alito and Stephen Breyer didn't take part
            in the court's action today, raising the prospect that only
            seven members of the court will participate in the case. As is
            the court's custom, Alito and Breyer gave no reasons. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The case is Pom Wonderful v. Coca-Cola, 12-761. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>

    <entry author="By Sonali Basak" datetime="Jan 14, 2014  5:05 PM ET" progress_sentiment="u" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-01-14/coca-cola-femsa-falls-to-lowest-since-november-on-junk-food-tax.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola Femsa Declines to Seven-Week Low on Junk-Food Tax</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Femsa (KOFL) SAB, the world's
            biggest franchised bottler of the soft drink, sank to a seven-week low on concern Mexico's junk food tax is
            making sugary
            drinks more expensive. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The shares fell 1.8 percent to 151.10 pesos at the close of
            trading in Mexico City, the lowest since Nov. 26. The stock has
            declined 23 percent in the past year. The benchmark IPC index
            climbed 0.7 percent today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The 1 peso per liter levy on sugary drinks that took effect
            Jan. 1 increases the price 13 to 14 percent, said Karla Miranda,
            an analyst at Corporativo GBM SAB in Mexico City, who expects
            the stock to be volatile until the company releases earnings.
            Femsa draws about 40 percent of its revenue from Mexico. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Bottling is going to be more expensive,' Miranda said.
            'The market is really nervous about what the outcome will be
            regarding results.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Arca Continential SAB, Latin America's second biggest
            bottler of Coca-Cola, fell 1.8 percent to 76.80 in Mexico City
            trading, the lowest level on a closing basis since Nov. 19. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Femsa yesterday sold $150 million more in 10-year
            bonds and $200 million more in 30-year bonds on Monday in part
            to repay outstanding debt. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Duane D. Stanford and Chris Burritt" datetime="Jan 15, 2013  4:32 PM ET" progress_sentiment="d" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-01-15/coca-cola-starts-advertising-to-curb-u-s-obesity.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola Uses TV Spots to Show How It's Fighting Obesity</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Co. (KO) has taken to television to fight back against an obesity epidemic the world's
            largest soft-drink maker has been blamed for fueling. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The company will air ads
            throughout the year, including one tomorrow on Fox Broadcasting Co.'s 'American Idol,' to bring attention to
            the importance of exercise and calories in curbing obesity. The first two-minute spot aired yesterday on
            cable TV, highlighting Coca-Cola's low- and zero-calorie products, the Atlanta-based company said yesterday
            in a statement. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The commercials are the most overt move yet in a more than three year
            campaign by Coca-Cola to counter criticism that it contributes to America's obesity epidemic. Almost 36
            percent of adults and about 17 percent of children are obese, according to the Centers for Disease Control
            and Prevention in Atlanta. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;'This is part of Coke's effort to blunt the opposition they
            are running into in all different sectors,' said Michael Jacobson, executive director of Washington-based
            Center for Science in the Public Interest, whose 1998 report 'Liquid Candy' propelled criticism of sugary
            drinks. 'The opposition is not sitting still these days.' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;One of Coca-Cola's new ads,
            called 'Coming Together,' suggests consumers pay attention to the calories they consume in order to manage
            their weight. The commercial points out the company 'can play an important role' in fighting obesity. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Smaller Packages &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;A female narrator goes on to say the company offers more
            than 180 low- and no-calorie beverages among its more than 650 drinks. This helped reduce calories per
            serving across the U.S. beverage industry by 22 percent during the past 15 years, according to the ad.
            Coca-Cola will offer smaller packages in about 90 percent of the U.S. market by the end of the year, it
            said. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The commercial to debut tomorrow on 'American Idol' states that a can of Coca-Cola
            contains 140 calories and encourages consumers to find fun ways of burning those calories. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola
            will air 30- and 60-second versions of the ads throughout the year in national broadcast and Spanish
            language media, according to Diana Garza Ciarlante, a company spokeswoman. She would not disclose spending
            on the effort. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Health advocates agree soft drinks are an unhealthy source of sugar in
            Americans' diets. Obesity in the U.S. comes at a 'staggering' financial cost, the CDC has said. Everything
            from treatments for diabetes to lost work by obese employees cost Americans about $147 billion in 2008,
            according to one estimate cited by the agency. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Obesity Cost &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Obesity
            is measured by using weight and height to calculate a number called body mass index, according to the CDC.
            An adult who is 5 feet, 9 inches tall and weighs 203 pounds or more is considered obese. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In
            2009, President Barack Obama recommended exploring a federal tax on sugary drinks to help pay for
            health-care reform. Lawmakers in 30 states then proposed levying their own soda taxes on the $74 billion
            U.S. soft drink industry. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Obama's suggestion prompted Coca-Cola Chief Executive Officer
            Muhtar Kent to call the idea of a federal tax on soft drinks 'outrageous.' Kent has argued that programs
            encouraging exercise and health education in schools and communities are more effective at curbing obesity.
            &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;'I have never seen it work where a government tells people what to eat and what to
            drink,' Kent said in September 2009, responding to an audience question at the Rotary Club of Atlanta. 'If
            it worked, the Soviet Union would still be around.' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;New York &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;The
            comments marked a shift in Coca-Cola's approach to soft drink critics. Until that point, the company let its
            chief lobbying association, the American Beverage Association, handle most of the push back. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Between
            2009 and 2011, Coca-Cola, PepsiCo Inc. (PEP) and the American Beverage Association spent as much as $70
            million on lobbying and issue ads, according to the Center for Science in the Public Interest, a proponent
            of soda taxes. The money helped defeat efforts to enact such levies in 30 states. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Last
            year, the beverage industry squared off against New York City, whose health department plastered placards
            all over New York's subways comparing sugary drinks with globs of fat and packets of sugar. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The
            ABA countered with its own subway ads touting lower- calorie options and package sizes as progress against
            obesity. They were part of a nationwide public relations campaign started in February, and an offshoot of
            similar ABA programs in recent years. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In September, New York City's Board of Health
            voted to restrict sales of sugary soft drinks to no more than 16 ounces a cup in restaurants, movie
            theaters, stadiums and arenas after it was proposed by Mayor Michael Bloomberg. The mayor is founder and
            majority owner of Bloomberg News parent Bloomberg LP. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Coke shares rose 0.9 percent to
            $37.32 at the close in New York. The stock advanced 3.6 percent in 2012, its fourth consecutive year of
            gains. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>

    <entry author="By Sonali Basak" datetime="Jan 27, 2014  4:04 PM ET" progress_sentiment="d" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-01-27/coca-cola-femsa-reaches-21-month-low-as-pepsico-plans-investment.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola Femsa Reaches 21-Month Low as PepsiCo Plans Investment</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Femsa SAB, the world's
            biggest franchised bottler of the soft drink, tumbled to a 21-month low after PepsiCo Inc. announced last
            week that it will
            invest $5 billion in Mexico over five years. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Shares of Femsa dropped 3.7 percent to 137.82 pesos at 2:59
            p.m. in Mexico City, the lowest on closing basis since May 2012.
            The decline was the biggest among the 35 members of the
            benchmark IPC stock index, which fell 0.3 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Mexico City-based Coca-Cola Femsa has dropped 13 percent
            since the beginning of the year, when a tax on junk food took
            effect. PepsiCo, based in Purchase, New York, said last week
            that it will expand its food and beverage business in Mexico,
            citing the nation's growing middle class and opportunities for
            long-term growth. The maker of Cheetos and Pepsi Cola controls
            more than 65 percent of Mexico's sales of sweet and savory
            snacks, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'There is always going to be a strong dominance of Coca-Cola here, but with new taxes the consumer
            is going to be more
            aware of the price environment if Pepsi is able to reduce
            prices, increase competition or introduce new products,'
            Cristina Morales, an analyst at Punto Casa de Bolsa SA de CV in
            Mexico City, said in a telephone interview. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Mexico represents a 'tremendous opportunity' for growth,
            PepsiCo Mexico President Pedro Padierna said in an e-mailed
            statement last week. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Jose Castro, the head of investor relations at Coca-Cola
            Femsa, didn't immediately return a request for comment today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Jason Scott" datetime="Jan 30, 2014  1:50 AM ET" progress_sentiment="d" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-01-30/abbott-rejects-a-25-million-aid-for-coca-cola-amatil-fruit-unit.html">
        <headline>Abbott Rejects A$25 Million Aid for Coca-Cola Amatil Fruit Unit</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Australia refused to give a A$25
            million ($21.8 million) grant to local fruit processor SPC
            Ardmona Ltd. saying parent Coca-Cola Amatil Ltd. (CCL) was capable of
            restructuring the company without government support. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Amatil is a 'very, very strong business,' Prime
            Minister Tony Abbott told reporters in Canberra today after his
            Cabinet decided to turn down the request for aid. 'This is a
            business which well and truly has the resources to ensure that
            SPC Ardmona is in a strong position to restructure.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Abbott's government, elected in September vowing to cut
            taxes and ease red tape for businesses, has said it doesn't
            believe in 'corporate welfare' to prop up ailing companies.
            Coca-Cola Amatil had applied for temporary tariff protection to
            stop imported packaged fruit being dumped into Australia and
            sought a government grant to support a restructuring of the
            unit's operations. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Amatil, which had pledged to invest A$90 million
            in the unit contingent on the grant being approved, said the
            decision meant a further A$25 million in aid from Victoria state
            wouldn't go ahead. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The company will undertake a review of the unit's carrying
            value and a write down of its assets, with details to be
            announced at its full-year results on Feb. 18, it said in a
            regulatory statement today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Shares in Coca-Cola Amatil declined 11 percent last year,
            compared with a 15 percent gain for the benchmark SP/ASX 200
            Index. The announcement came after the market closed in Sydney,
            and the stock ended down 0.9 percent at A$11.79. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Sydney-based company said in a November trading update
            it expected earnings before interest and tax in the year ending
            Dec. 31 to be as much as 7 percent lower than the previous year,
            before significant items. Net income fell 12 percent to A$216
            million in the six months through June, Coca-Cola Amatil
            reported Aug. 20. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;SPC Ardmona has produced and canned tomatoes, stone fruit
            and vegetables in Australia's southeast for more than 90 years,
            according to its website. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>

    <entry author="By Duane D. Stanford" datetime="Jul 16, 2013  4:19 PM ET" progress_sentiment="d" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-16/coca-cola-profit-declines-as-european-sales-volumes-fall.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola Profit Hit as Global Economy, Weather Misbehave</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Co. (KO) said profit fell 4 percent last quarter, the second decline in a row, as sales
            were sapped by economic weakness in China and Europe, shifting tastes in the U.S. and unseasonable weather
            in places such as India. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola has long touted its broad geographic reach and
            ability to make up for sluggish sales in one market with increases elsewhere. The second-quarter results
            show there's a limit to that strategy, especially when Mother Nature and global economic forces refuse to
            cooperate. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;'This was a confluence of events,' Chief Executive Officer Muhtar Kent said
            today during a conference call. 'The portfolio effect of our global business did not work in our favor in
            this particular case.' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;To counter slower growth, Kent said he's speeding up efforts in
            China and other emerging markets to expand Coca-Cola's reach by adding smaller, more affordable package
            sizes. He said the company has not pulled back on marketing and advertising to blunt losses. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;'This
            is more of an anomaly, we should not see this as a trend or a systemic issue,' Kent said. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In
            India, for example, monsoons swamped sales, especially given unusually high growth one year ago after the
            monsoon season came late, Kent said. In Brazil, consumer spending was depressed by a credit crisis, he said.
            &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: Patrick Fallon/Bloomberg

            &lt;p&gt;
            Chief Executive Officer Muhtar Kent has tried to raise pricing to make up for weaker demand. Sales volume in
            Europe declined 4 percent, hurt by a 'slow' economy, Coca-Cola said. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Yoshiaki Nohara and Masaaki Iwamoto" datetime="Jul 16, 2013  7:05 PM ET" progress_sentiment="d" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-16/japan-stock-futures-fall-on-higher-yen-coca-cola-profit.html">
        <headline>Japan Stock Futures Fall on Higher Yen, Coca-Cola Profit</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Japanese stock futures fell,
            signaling the Nikkei 225 Stock Average may retreat from an
            eight-week high, after the yen rose, Coca-Cola Co. (KO)'s profit
            dropped and a Federal Reserve official called for cuts to U.S.
            stimulus. Australian equity futures declined. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;American depositary receipts of Toyota Motor Corp. (7203), a
            Japanese carmaker that gets 31 percent of its sales in North
            America, dropped 1.1 percent from the closing share price in
            Tokyo. Those of Mitsubishi UFJ Financial Group Inc., Japan's
            biggest lender, fell 1.1 percent. ADRs of Woodside Petroleum
            Ltd. (WPL), Australia's second-largest oil and gas producer, declined
            0.2 percent after crude fell. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Futures on Japan's Nikkei 225 expiring in September closed
            at 14,515 in Chicago yesterday, compared with 14,600 in Osaka,
            Japan. They were bid in the pre-market at 14,510 in Osaka at
            8:05 a.m. local time. Futures on Australia's SP/ASX 200 Index
            slipped 0.1 percent. New Zealand's NZX 50 Index was little
            changed. Futures on Hong Kong's Hang Seng Index and the Hang
            Seng China Enterprises Index of mainland companies trading in
            Hong Kong both climbed 0.3 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Share markets in Japan and the U.S. are overheating and
            need a quick correction,' said Hiroichi Nishi, an equities
            manager in Tokyo at SMBC Nikko Securities Inc., a unit of
            Japan's second-biggest lender by market value. 'Investors are
            paring back their optimistic outlook for U.S. earnings.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Stimulus Debate &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Futures on the Standard Poor's 500 Index rose 0.1 percent
            today. The gauge dropped 0.4 percent in New York yesterday,
            halting its longest rally since January, as Coca-Cola reported
            profit fell 4 percent, the second quarterly decline in a row, as
            sales were sapped by economic weakness in China and Europe,
            shifting tastes in the U.S. and unseasonable weather in places
            such as India. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Fed Bank of Kansas City President Esther George said
            yesterday the U.S. was on the 'right path' for economic
            recovery and that cuts in the pace of stimulus are
            'appropriate.' Fed Chairman Ben S. Bernanke will deliver his
            semi-annual monetary policy report to Congress this week,
            starting today at the House Financial Services Committee. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The yen gained 0.8 percent to 99.10 per dollar yesterday
            before trading at 99.15 at 7:50 a.m. in Tokyo. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;West Texas Intermediate crude for August delivery slid 32
            cents to settle at $106 a barrel on the New York Mercantile
            Exchange. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The MSCI Asia Pacific Index gained 5.1 percent this year
            through yesterday. The Asian benchmark traded at 13.3 times
            estimated earnings, compared with 15.2 times for the SP 500 and
            13.2 times for the Stoxx Europe 600 Index. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Bloomberg China-US Equity Index of the most-traded
            Chinese stocks in the U.S. gained 0.5 percent to 88.77
            yesterday, the strongest level since June 10. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Jenna M. Dagenhart" datetime="Jul 18, 2014  3:29 PM ET" progress_sentiment="u" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-18/coca-cola-bottler-arca-gains-in-mexico-city-on-consumer-outlook.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola Bottler Arca Reaches 11-Month High on Consumer Outlook</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Arca Continental SAB (AC*), the second-largest Coca-Cola bottler in Latin America, rose to an
            11-month
            high as company executives cited prospects for improved consumer
            spending in Mexico and Argentina. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Shares of Arca climbed 3 percent to 92.98 pesos at 2:14
            p.m. in Mexico City, the highest level on a closing basis since
            August 2013. The gain was the biggest on the benchmark IPC
            equity index, which advanced 0.8 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Arca executives said on a conference call yesterday that
            they see evidence of increased consumption and reduced sugar
            prices although a full recovery from Mexico's excise tax on
            sweet drinks will take a 'couple of years.' Second-quarter
            adjusted net income increased 3 percent from a year earlier. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Concerns about commodity costs and consumer confidence
            are improving with the more stable environment,' Lauren Torres,
            an HSBC Holdings Plc analyst, said by phone from New York.
            'Investors know that if there are going to be price increases
            in the future, then they will be selective.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Torres cited Arca's strategy of raising prices in the first
            quarter to cover the excise tax and then adding another increase
            in the second quarter to account for inflation. HSBC maintained
            its hold rating in a report today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Mexico began taxing sugary drinks in January at one peso
            per liter in an effort to curb obesity. Also this year, the
            government applied an 8 percent levy on junk food. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'The challenging economic and consumption environments
            facing the first half of the year in Mexico and Argentina
            require us to be more productive and efficient on the cost and
            expense side,' Emilio Marcos Charur, the chief financial
            officer of Monterrey, Mexico-based Arca, said on the conference
            call. 'We expect a better consumption environment in the coming
            months.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Matthew Leising" datetime="Jul 21, 2013  1:09 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-21/coca-cola-workers-end-strike-at-ontario-bottle-plant-union-says.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola Workers End 3-Week Strike in Ontario, Union Says</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Workers at a Brampton, Ontario-based
            bottling plant operated by Coca-Cola Co. (KO), the world's largest
            soda maker, ended a three-week strike after approving a three-year contract, the Canadian Auto Workers Union
            said in a
            statement today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Production at the plant will resume tomorrow after the deal
            was approved by 83 percent of workers, according to the
            statement. Workers will receive pay increases in the second and
            third years of the contract and won an agreement 'that would
            end demands to outsource existing work.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'The real fight here was over the defined benefit pension
            plan, with Coca-Cola pushing us to move to a defined
            contribution plan,' Jerry Dias, assistant to the CAW National
            President, said in the statement. 'We were ultimately
            successful in keeping the defined benefit pension plan and
            improving upon it.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The union also negotiated a weekend-worker program that
            includes two 12-hour premium shifts to allow for 24-hour, seven
            day-a-week production, according to the statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A call to Kent Landers, a spokesman for Atlanta-based Coca-Cola, wasn't immediately returned. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Canadian Auto Workers Union represents about 700
            employees at the bottling plant, according to the statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Duane D. Stanford" datetime="Jul 22, 2014  4:25 PM ET" progress_sentiment="d" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-22/coca-cola-misses-sales-estimates-amid-juice-diet-coke-slowdown.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola Misses Sales Estimates Amid Juice, Diet Coke Slide</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Co. (KO), the world's largest
            beverage company, reported second-quarter sales that missed
            analysts' estimates amid sluggish demand for drinks such as
            juice and Diet Coke in North America. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Revenue fell 1.4 percent to $12.6 billion in the period
            ended June 27, Atlanta-based Coca-Cola said today in a
            statement. Analysts had estimated $12.8 billion on average,
            according to data compiled by Bloomberg. Global juice sales
            volume declined 1 percent, hurt by price increases in North
            America to offset higher ingredient costs. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chief Executive Officer Muhtar Kent is cutting costs and
            overhauling marketing as he contends with a slowdown in the
            market for fizzy beverages. Coca-Cola also is increasingly
            relying on overseas markets to maintain growth. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Coke's Q2 result was weaker than expected,' said Dara Mohsenian, an analyst at Morgan Stanley in
            New York. 'The bar
            is low for Coke, but with weak topline results, worse than
            expected underlying profit, and slight negative EPS guidance
            revisions in H2, we would expect the stock to be down today.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola fell 2.9 percent to $41.19 at the close in New
            York. The shares have dropped less than 1 percent this year,
            compared with a 7.3 percent gain for the Standard Poor's 500
            Index. &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: Jin Lee/Bloomberg

            &lt;p&gt;
            Coca-Cola Co. Chief Executive Officer Muhtar Kent said in the statement, 'We remain focused on the work
            required to return our business to the level of sustainable growth we and our shareowners expect.' Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Duane D. Stanford and Haslinda Amin" datetime="Jun 04, 2013  9:39 PM ET" progress_sentiment="d" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-04/coca-cola-ceo-opens-myanmar-bottling-plant-to-stave-off-pepsico.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola Says Myanmar's Opening Is Like Fall of Berlin Wall</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Co (KO). Chief Executive Officer Muhtar Kent marked the return of the world's largest
            soda maker to Myanmar after 60 years by opening a bottling plant and pledging more investment in the newly
            opened economy. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The company will invest $200 million in the next five years and a second
            plant will open in a month's time, Kent said in an interview with Haslinda Amin on Bloomberg Television.
            &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;'It's a great moment in history, just like it used to be when we opened up our business
            in east and central Europe in the former Soviet Union right after the fall of the Berlin wall,' Kent said.
            'We can retain and grow our leadership that we already have in this market today.' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola's
            new plant begins in earnest a race with PepsiCo Inc. (PEP) to control beverage markets in the Southeast Asia
            nation, which reopened its borders last year to foreign investment. Myanmar President Thein Sein has allowed
            more political freedom and loosened economic controls since coming to power two years ago, attracting
            companies such as Ford Motor Co., MasterCard Inc. (MA) and Unilever NV. (UNA) &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The
            country is boosting economic, military and political ties with Western nations after years of isolation that
            left its 64 million people among Asia's poorest. Its transition to democracy last year after about five
            decades of military rule prompted the U.S. to ease sanctions last May. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Boosting Ties
            &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola will need to focus on distribution to win over the nation's consumers, Kent
            said. PepsiCo has been building drinks distribution in the country, will soon distribute snacks there and is
            pursuing plans for a factory. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;'As important as price, it is availability, it is serving
            the product in the right conditions, making it available, making it at an arms reach of desire,' Kent said.
            'We have plans to ensure that we have the best, most modern 21st century consumer distribution system in the
            country.' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;While Coca-Cola left Myanmar about 60 years ago, PepsiCo has more recent
            experience in the nation. The world's largest snack maker pulled out of Myanmar in 1997 after activists
            urged the company to sever ties with the military dictatorship because of human-rights violations. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Unilever has said it will focus on opportunities in new markets in Southeast Asia, such as Myanmar,
            which could be 'another Vietnam' in 20 years, according to Peter Ter-Kulve, the London- and Rotterdam-based
            company's chief executive officer for Southeast Asia. The company is already selling its products through
            100,000 outlets in the country, he said in an interview last month. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Katie Linsell" datetime="Jun 10, 2013  8:15 AM ET" progress_sentiment="d" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-10/coca-cola-hbc-joins-poste-italiane-selling-bonds-as-yields-rise.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola HBC Joins Poste Italiane Selling Bonds as Yields Rise</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola HBC AG (CCH) is issuing its
            first bonds since the world's second-biggest bottler of the soft
            drink switched its stock listing to London from Athens as
            European borrowing costs climb to a three-month high. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Air Liquide SA (AI), the French maker of industrial gases, and
            Poste Italiane SpA, the state-owned postal service, are also
            raising debt as the average yield investors demand to hold
            investment-grade company bonds in euros rose to 1.90 percent
            from a record low of 1.64 percent reached May 17, according to
            Bank of America Merrill Lynch index data. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola HBC moved its listing to London to access a wider
            pool of investors, Chief Financial Officer Michalis Imellos said
            in April. Borrowing costs are climbing after Federal Reserve
            Chairman Ben S. Bernanke said the central bank could taper asset
            purchases if the employment outlook shows sustainable
            improvement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'There's an element of some of these companies looking to
            get into the market before nervousness spreads further,' said
            Duncan Warwick-Champion, the London-based head of corporate
            research at ECM Asset Management Ltd. which oversees $9.5
            billion. 'There's a lot of discussion about the potential for
            yields rising further so some of the companies that haven't
            locked in their refinancing for 2013 and 2014 are looking to do
            so now.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Coca-Cola &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola HBC wants to sell 800 million euros ($1.1
            billion) of seven-year notes that will be priced to yield 105
            basis points more than the benchmark midswap rate, according to
            a person familiar with the deal. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The bottler is also offering to buy back any or all of the
            500 million euros of 7.875 percent notes due 2014 to lower its
            interest costs and improve its debt profile, the company said
            today in a statement. Philip Walters, an external spokesman for
            Coca-Cola HBC, declined to comment on the new bond sale, which
            needs to be completed before the buyback can begin. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Air Liquide is raising 700 million euros from notes in
            three tranches, according to a person familiar with the
            transaction. The Paris-based company is selling 250 million
            euros of six-year fixed-rate bonds, 250 million euros of two-year floating-rate notes and 200 million euros
            of three-year
            floating-rate notes. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Poste Italiane is raising 750 million euros of bonds from
            its first sale since 2002. The company is offering five-year
            securities to yield 225 basis points, according to a person
            familiar with the transaction. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Anna Maria Morsucci, a spokeswoman for the Rome-based
            company, didn't immediately respond to an e-mail seeking comment
            on the transaction. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Rolls-Royce &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;SSE Plc (SSE), the U.K.'s second-biggest energy supplier, is
            selling its first bonds this year. The Perth, Scotland-based
            company is raising 600 million euros from seven-year bonds that
            will be priced to yield 70 basis points more than swaps,
            according to a person familiar with the offer. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Rolls-Royce Holdings Plc (RR/), Europe's largest maker of
            aircraft engines, has mandated banks to organize a call with
            investors today before a possible sale of securities in euros
            and pounds. It would be the London-based company's first bond
            issue since 2009, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In the high-yield market, Groupe SMCP, a French distributor
            of women's apparel, is selling 290 million euros of seven-year
            securities through its subsidiary, SMCP SAS, to yield about 8.75
            percent, according to a person familiar with the deal. The
            proceeds will be used to repay existing debt and finance part of
            its acquisition by KKR Co., Moody's Investors Service reported
            on June 4 when it provisionally rated the notes B3, six levels
            below investment grade. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>

    <entry author="By Greg Stohr" datetime="Jun 12, 2014  2:37 PM ET" progress_sentiment="d" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-12/coca-cola-must-face-pomegranate-drink-suit-court-says.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola Must Face Pomegranate Drink Suit, Court Says</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Co. (KO) must defend against
            accusations that it deceived consumers about the amount of
            pomegranate juice in one of its beverages, as the U.S. Supreme
            Court revived a lawsuit by rival drink-maker POM Wonderful LLC. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The unanimous ruling gives companies a greater role in
            policing competing product labels for misleading advertisements.
            The justices said private parties can press false-advertising
            suits under a federal law known as the Lanham Act even when the
            U.S. Food and Drug Administration regulates a product. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The FDA 'does not have the same perspective or expertise
            in assessing market dynamics that day-to-day competitors
            possess,' Justice Anthony Kennedy wrote for the court. 'Lanham
            Act suits draw upon this market expertise by empowering private
            parties to sue competitors to protect their interests on a case-by-case basis.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The label on Coca-Cola's drink says 'Pomegranate Blueberry
            Flavored Blend of 5 Juices,' with the first two words appearing
            in larger letters. A lower court had said FDA juice-labeling
            regulations authorized the Coca-Cola product's name. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;POM Wonderful says the label is misleading because the
            drink contains only 0.3 percent pomegranate juice and 0.2
            percent blueberry juice. Apple and grape juice constitute 99
            percent of the juice, POM Wonderful says. &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: Tish Wells/MCT via Getty Images

            &lt;p&gt;
            POM Wonderful says the label on Coca-Cola's 'Pomegranate Blueberry Flavored Blend of 5 Juices,' is
            misleading because the drink contains only 0.3 percent pomegranate juice and 0.2 percent blueberry juice.
            POM Wonderful is separately fighting accusations over its own advertising. In a case now pending at a
            federal appeals court, the Federal Trade Commission says POM is deceiving consumers with claims about the
            health benefits of its pomegranate drinks. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Randall Hackley" datetime="Jun 20, 2014  9:25 AM ET" progress_sentiment="u" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-20/danube-river-water-restoration-works-to-get-wwf-coca-cola-aid.html">
        <headline>Danube River Water Restoration Works to Get WWF, Coca-Cola Aid</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;The Danube, the European Union's
            longest river, will receive aid from the WWF and Coca-Cola Co. (KO)
            for projects to help restore wetlands, floodplains and water
            quality for six countries along the famed waterway. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The nature conservancy and beverage maker today announced
            the partnership would work to improve the equivalent of at least
            7,400 football fields of wetland habitat and 12 million cubic
            meters of water from Romania to Austria by 2020. Fish and
            wildlife would benefit from the works as would reconstructed
            wetlands that help conserve freshwater resources, the
            organizations said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The partnership includes building a fish pass funded by a
            Coca-Cola grant, removing dykes to reconnect floodplains and
            boost flooding capacity and are part of efforts supported by
            local and EU authorities, the groups said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Brendan Case" datetime="Jun 29, 2013 12:01 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-29/coca-cola-femsa-targets-brazil-growth-with-fluminense-purchase.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola Femsa Targets Brazil Expansion With Fluminense Deal</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Femsa SAB (KOFL), the largest
            bottler of the soft drink in Latin America, agreed to buy
            Brazil's Cia. Fluminense de Refrigerantes for $448 million in
            cash to expand in the region's largest country. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The purchase will bolster Coca-Cola (KO) Femsa's Brazilian
            business by linking two other areas it serves, clearing the way
            for 'the reconfiguration of the supply chain of our combined
            operations,' Chief Executive Officer Carlos Salazar said
            yesterday in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Fluminense deal caps a $4 billion acquisition spree in
            the past two years by Mexico City-based Coca-Cola Femsa, which
            also has purchased four Mexican bottlers and control of Coca-Cola Co.'s Philippines bottling operation.
            Fluminense, which was
            founded in 1949 in the state of Rio de Janeiro, posted sales of
            about $232 million in the year ending March 31, shipping 56.6
            million unit cases of beverages, including beer. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'This acquisition highlights the long-term strategic
            importance of the Brazilian market for Coca-Cola Femsa as we
            believe in the attractive domestic consumption prospects and
            socio-economic dynamics,' Salazar said in the statement. 'This
            transaction underscores our commitment to continue focusing on
            the opportunities that the Latin American Coca-Cola bottling
            system presents.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Femsa will seek to increase sales by offering a
            broader range of products, adding coolers at retailers and
            serving more points of sale, according to investor relations
            chief Jose Castro. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Beverage Breakdown &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The deal is subject to approval by Brazil's antitrust
            regulator, said Coca-Cola Femsa, which is controlled by
            Monterrey, Mexico-based Fomento Economico Mexicano SAB. (FEMSAUBD) The
            bottler also will seek approval from Atlanta-based Coca-Cola.
            The transaction is expected to close in the fourth quarter,
            Castro said, and is being funded with the company's existing
            cash balances. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Fluminense had an estimated $40 million in consolidated
            earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation and amortization
            in the 12 months ended March 31, Coca-Cola Femsa said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;With one bottling plant and four distribution centers, it
            operates in parts of Sao Paulo, Rio de Janeiro and Minas Gerais
            states. Carbonated soft drinks make up 86 percent of its
            business, with 8 percent coming from beer, 5 percent from non-carbonated beverages and 1 percent from water,
            Castro said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Femsa sold 494.2 million unit cases last year in
            Brazil, up 1.8 percent from a year earlier, the company said
            Feb. 27. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Chris Cooper" datetime="Mar 27, 2014 12:00 PM ET" progress_sentiment="d" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-03-27/coca-cola-to-suzuki-myanmar-factory-rush-spurs-shipping.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola to Suzuki Myanmar Factory Rush Spurs Shipping</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Co. (KO) and Suzuki Motor
            Corp. (7269) are among companies pushing demand for transportation of
            machinery to Myanmar to bottle drinks and make trucks, after the
            country's five decades of isolation during military rule. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola, which opened a bottling plant in Myanmar last
            year, plans to invest $200 million over five years while Suzuki
            restarted production of trucks last year after leaving the
            market in 2010. Asahi Group Holdings Ltd. (2502), Japan's biggest
            beermaker, said this month it's forming a venture to start
            operations there this year. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Because much of the machinery is too big to fit in regular
            containers, Japan's Mitsui O.S.K. Lines Ltd. and other shippers
            are increasingly using vessels that can handle oversized cargo.
            The Southeast Asian nation, formerly known as Burma, is
            importing basic materials to improve infrastructure after the
            U.S., Europe and Japan eased sanctions following elections in
            2012 in which the country's leading dissident, Aung San Suu Kyi,
            a political prisoner for 15 years, was elected to parliament. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'It will take time for Myanmar to be a big manufacturing
            country,' said Masayuki Kubota, chief strategist at Rakuten
            Securities Economic Research Institute. 'They're buying
            machinery now as part of the process to become a big
            manufacturing country. It needs a huge amount of investment.' &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: Dario Pignatelli/Bloomberg

            &lt;p&gt;
            An employee passes a bottle of Coca-Cola soda to another employee as they inspect bottle labeling on the
            production line at the Coca-Cola Co. bottling plant in Hmawbi, Myanma. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>

    <entry author="By Duane D. Stanford" datetime="May 13, 2014  5:18 PM ET" progress_sentiment="u" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-05-13/coca-cola-increases-holding-in-keurig-green-mountain-to-16-.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola Raising Keurig Stake to 16%, Becoming Top Owner</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Co. (KO) will become Keurig
            Green Mountain Inc. (GMCR)'s largest shareholder after raising its
            stake to 16 percent, doubling down on the maker of Keurig coffee
            brewers at a time when consumers are increasingly shunning
            sugary sodas. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Keurig jumped 7.6 percent to $119.07 after Coca-Cola
            announced the plan in a filing today. The soft-drink company
            will own about 26 million shares within nine months after it
            exercises an option to add additional stock. It had bought an
            initial stake of 10 percent in February. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The investment fits into Coca-Cola's strategy of taking
            equity stakes in promising new brands and technologies as
            healthier habits hits its main revenue growth. The companies are
            working together on the Keurig Cold single-cup beverage system
            that will be sold in Keurig's fiscal 2015, starting later this
            year. The coffee maker will also produce and sell Coca-Cola-branded pods to go with the machine. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The 'purchases demonstrate our continued belief that
            Keurig Green Mountain has substantial growth potential,'
            Atlanta-based Coca-Cola said in an e-mailed statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Shares of Waterbury, Vermont-based Keurig have jumped 47
            percent since Feb. 5, the day Coca-Cola announced it was the
            buying the stake. Coca-Cola's stock advanced 0.7 percent to
            $41.11 today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;SodaStream Competition &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Under today's agreement, Coca-Cola owns about 19.5 million
            shares and has the right to buy as much as 6.5 million more. The
            company signed a pact with Credit Suisse Group AG to purchase
            the balance of the stake by Feb. 13, 2015. The bank will set the
            price, determined by timing and an agreed-upon formula,
            according to the filing. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The partnership between Coca-Cola and Keurig will ratchet
            up competition for SodaStream International Ltd., a Lod, Israel-based company that makes home carbonation
            appliances and soft-drink syrups. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In February, Coca-Cola bought 16.7 million newly issued
            shares in Keurig for about $1.25 billion and said it had the
            option to raise the stake to as much as 16 percent during the
            first 36 months. Amanda Rosseter, a spokeswoman for Coca-Cola,
            declined to elaborate on the timing of the agreement beyond the
            filing. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola previously took equity stakes in Zico coconut
            water and Honest Tea, and helped incubate them. Coca-Cola
            eventually acquired all of Zico and Honest. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola's investment in Keurig could be seen as a
            precursor to an eventual acquisition, though not right away, Ali Dibadj, a New York-based analyst at Sanford
            C. Bernstein Co.,
            said last month. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Keurig, which changed its name from Green Mountain Coffee
            Roasters Inc. in March, has been speculated as a takeover
            candidate for at least three years, in part because of its rapid
            growth. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Bloomberg News" datetime="Nov 07, 2013 11:00 AM ET" progress_sentiment="u" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-07/coca-cola-to-invest-more-than-4-billion-in-china-from-2015-2017.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola to Invest More Than $4 Billion in China From 2015-2017</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Co. (KO), the world's largest
            beverage company, plans to invest more than $4 billion in China
            from 2015 to 2017 as it builds factories and adds new products
            to meet demand and counter rising competition. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Atlanta-based company is also open to acquisitions in
            China and may consider deals with complementary businesses, such
            as makers of juices or plant-protein drinks like almond milk,
            David Brooks, president of Coca-Cola's Greater China and Korea
            business unit, said in an Nov. 6 interview in Shanghai. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'You will see an absolute increase in investment on an
            annual basis and on a three-year basis,' Brooks said,
            commenting on the company's future plan for China. Coca-Cola is
            investing $4 billion in the country for 2012-2014. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The U.S. soda maker is ramping up its China investment as
            the company and its bottlers seek to double global revenues to
            $200 billion in the 10 years to 2020. While it is the country's
            largest soft-drink maker, it faces competition from companies
            including PepsiCo Inc. (PEP) and the local Hangzhou Wahaha Group as it
            seeks to expand in the most populous nation. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;PepsiCo, the world's second-largest soft-drink maker, is
            stepping up its push into China. The company has also opened new
            factories and sought to expand distribution through a tie-up
            with Tingyi Cayman Islands Holding Corp. (322) &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Competition in China's beverage industry is intense and the
            sector is one with 'low growth and weak profitability,'
            analyst Jean Chan from Sanford C. Bernstein Co. wrote in a
            Sept. 25 report. Sales are typically driven by promotions, she
            said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;China Sales &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola said in July that its second-quarter sales volume
            in China was little changed after rising 7 percent a year ago.
            Sales in the third quarter have shown improvements, and this will
            continue over the next several quarters, Brooks
            said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Asian nation has pared economic growth projections to
            an average of 7 percent this decade, compared with 10.5 percent
            in the previous 10 years. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola plans to open as many as two facilities each year
            in China over the next decade, Brooks said. In the nearer term,
            it will invest about $40 million in a new pulp blending factory
            in Shanghai, and likely open a plant in the southwestern Guizhou
            province in the next two years, Brooks said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'The beverage market in China is still very fragmented,'
            the executive said. 'No company has predominant market share,
            and there is a huge amount of untapped opportunity left to
            grow.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Chinese Flavors &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The company also plans to expand its offerings of Chinese-style beverages, with traditional Chinese
            items such as wolf
            berries and herbal ingredients all being considered in future
            drinks, Brooks said, declining to elaborate further. It will
            also roll out more low-calorie and no-calorie drinks as it
            caters to an aging population, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'People like new flavors,' Chan, the analyst, said.
            'Going forward, product innovations will help you expand your
            categories and also drive growth.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chinese consumers are buying more juices and ready-to-drink
            teas and fewer carbonated drinks as they seek a healthier
            lifestyle, Chan said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;China regulators blocked the Coca-Cola's planned $2.3
            billion buyout of China Huiyuan Juice Group Ltd. in 2009. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Emerging markets are increasingly important to the U.S.
            company, which got about 79 percent of its operating income
            outside North America last year, data compiled by Bloomberg
            show. In the U.S., beverage makers have come under scrutiny in
            recent years as public officials in several states have looked
            to curb high obesity rates by slowing consumption of sugary soft
            drinks with proposed restrictions and excise taxes. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Local Cooking &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola, which broke ground on the first of its 43
            factories on the mainland in 1980, already sells snow-pear fruit
            drinks and sour-plum sparkling beverages there. On its website,
            there are suggested recipes including sweet and spicy hoisin
            spare ribs with Coca-Cola, encouraging consumers to incorporate
            the carbonated beverage into local cooking. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The maker of drinks ranging from green teas and milk-based
            Minute Maid Milky Pulpy had a 15.7 percent share in China's 67.5
            billion litre soft-drink market in 2012, according to industry
            researcher Euromonitor International. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Taiwan's Ting Hsin International Group, which partly owns
            Tingyi, ranked second with 12.8 percent, while PepsiCo had 4.5
            percent. Wahaha Group, controlled by the nation's second richest
            man, Zong Qinghou, had a 7.3 percent share. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Low per-capita consumption and rising incomes will boost
            beverage demand in China, helping the Asian nation become Coca-Cola's largest market by sales volume by
            2020, from third-largest today, Brooks said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;China Plenum &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;China's third plenum, a meeting of Communist Party leaders
            to discuss economic-policy reforms, begins this week in Beijing.
            The outcome of the conclave will be closely watched by foreign
            investors as it would give an indication of the country's
            roadmap for the next 10 years, said Brooks, who has lived and
            worked in Greater China since 1975. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'The overall trend of opening and continuing to become
            more transparent is very clear,' he said. 'Market forces
            playing a stronger role in the economy going forward is good for
            all players whether you are a foreign company or state-owned
            enterprise.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>


    <entry author="By Craig Giammona" datetime="Oct 01, 2014  4:35 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="u" progress_sentiment="n" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-10-01/coca-cola-reins-in-stock-compensation-plan-in-wake-of-criticism.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola Trims Stock Compensation Plan After Criticism</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Co. (KO), whose employee stock-compensation plan was called excessive by billionaire
            Warren Buffett and other investors, agreed to rein in the program. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Fewer shares will be issued to employees, and more
            transparency will be provided into how the program works, the
            Atlanta-based company said today in a statement. The number of
            shares granted will be no more than 0.8 percent of total
            outstanding stock in 2015 and an average of 0.4 percent for the
            remainder of the plan. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola investor Wintergreen Advisers LLC, run by David
            Winters, railed against the compensation plan this year, calling
            it a 'raw deal' for shareholders that was too generous and
            diluted the stock. Buffett, Coca-Cola's largest shareholder,
            also spoke out against the program, though only after the plan
            passed. He abstained from voting on it at Coca-Cola's annual
            meeting in April. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'By approving the equity plan in April, our shareowners
            authorized the compensation committee to manage something
            precious '- shares of the Coca-Cola company,' Maria Elena Lagomasino, chairman of Coca-Cola's compensation
            committee,
            wrote in a letter to shareholders today. 'The existing equity
            plan was designed to provide significant flexibility in how and
            to whom long-term equity awards are made. These guidelines are
            designed to be clear and simple, driven by our desire to enhance
            transparency with our shareowners.' &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: Daniel Acker/Bloomberg

            &lt;p&gt;
            Warren Buffett, Coca-Cola's largest shareholder, also spoke out against the program, though only after the
            plan passed when he abstained from voting on it at Coca-Cola's annual meeting in April. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>

    <entry author="By Jonathan Levin" datetime="Oct 11, 2013 12:56 PM ET" progress_sentiment="u" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-10-11/coca-cola-bottler-arca-retreats-on-report-of-higher-proposed-tax.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola Bottler Arca Retreats on Report of Higher Proposed Tax</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Arca Continental SAB, Latin
            America's second-biggest Coca-Cola bottler, extended its third
            straight weekly decline after a newspaper reported that
            lawmakers are considering a higher proposed tax on soda. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The shares fell 1.2 percent to 82.16 pesos at 11:35 a.m. in
            Mexico City, extending the weekly slump to 2.1 percent. The
            benchmark IPC index of 35 Mexican companies rose 1.1 percent and
            was little changed for the week. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Lower-house lawmakers from the ruling Institutional
            Revolutionary Party and the opposition Democratic Revolutionary
            Party plan to increase the rate of a proposed tax on sodas,
            Reforma reported today on its website. The move would tax sodas
            2 pesos per liter instead of 1 peso under an earlier bill,
            Reforma said, citing unidentified negotiators from both parties. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'That's surely what's hitting the share price,' Karla Miranda, an analyst at Corporativo GBM SAB,
            said in a telephone
            interview from Mexico City. 'For several weeks, beverage
            company stocks have been reacting to rumors about news on the
            soda tax.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Arca Continental's Mexico drinks unit accounted for 76
            percent of its sparkling-beverage volume during the first half
            of the year. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Duane D. Stanford" datetime="Oct 15, 2013  4:22 PM ET" progress_sentiment="u" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-10-15/coca-cola-third-quarter-net-climbs-as-north-america-sales-rise.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola Quarterly Net Climbs as North America Sales Rise</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Co. (KO), the world's largest
            beverage company, said third-quarter profit rose as sales
            volumes advanced in North America and the European business
            began to rebound. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Net income rose 5.9 percent to $2.45 billion, or 54 cents a
            share, in the three months ended Sept. 27, compared with a year
            earlier, Atlanta-based Coca-Cola said today in a statement.
            Excluding some items, profit was 53 cents a share, in line with
            the average of 16 analysts' estimates compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chief Executive Officer Muhtar Kent fought back in the
            quarter against persistent consumer uncertainty in developed
            nations and what he called 'increasing volatility across
            emerging markets' by strategically raising prices and getting
            more consumers to grab a drink on the go. Kent said he still
            expects the company and its bottlers to reach $200 billion in
            global revenue by 2020, double that generated in 2010. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Muhtar and his team are continuing to succeed at their
            game plan even though the economy in some emerging markets,
            South America and some parts of Europe continue to create near-term challenges,' Thomas Mullarkey, an
            analyst for Morningstar
            Inc. (MORN) in Chicago, said today in a telephone interview. &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: Patrick Fallon/Bloomberg

            &lt;p&gt;
            Sales volume declined 1 percent in Europe, compared with a 4 percent decline in the second quarter,
            Coca-Cola said. North America volume rose 2 percent. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Callie Bost" datetime="Oct 29, 2013  5:35 PM ET" progress_sentiment="u" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-10-29/credit-swaps-in-u-s-fall-coca-cola-sells-5-billion-of-bonds.html">
        <headline>Credit Swaps in U.S. Fall; Coca-Cola Sells $5 Billion of Bonds</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;A measure of U.S. company credit
            risk declined as Federal Reserve policy makers began a two-day
            meeting. Coca-Cola Co. (KO) raised $5 billion in its biggest bond
            offering ever. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Markit CDX North American Investment Grade Index, a
            credit-default swaps benchmark that investors use to hedge
            against losses or to speculate on creditworthiness, decreased
            0.7 basis point to 71.1 basis points at 5:16 p.m. in New York,
            according to prices compiled by Bloomberg. The benchmark closed
            Oct. 22 at 70.1 basis points, the lowest level since November
            2007 in data that adjust for the effects of the market's shift
            to a new version in September. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The central bank, which concludes the meeting tomorrow,
            will delay the first reduction in its asset buying until March
            after a partial government shutdown slowed fourth-quarter
            growth, according to a Bloomberg News survey of economists. The
            Federal Open Market Committee's policy statement may help
            investors gauge when the Fed will start reducing its $85 billion
            in monthly bond purchases, which have boosted credit markets. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Investors are waiting on direction from the Fed rather
            than committing to one view or another,' Edward Marrinan, a
            macro credit strategist at Royal Bank of Scotland Group Plc's
            securities unit in Stamford, Connecticut, said in a telephone
            interview. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The swaps index typically falls as investor confidence
            improves and rises as it deteriorates. Credit swaps pay the
            buyer face value if a borrower fails to meet its obligations,
            less the value of the defaulted debt. A basis point equals
            $1,000 annually on a contract protecting $10 million of debt. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Coca-Cola &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola issued fixed- and floating-rate debt maturing in
            three to 10 years in a five-part offering, according to data
            compiled by Bloomberg. The largest portion was for $1.5 billion
            of 3.2 percent, 10-year bonds that yield 70 basis points more
            than similar-maturity Treasuries. Proceeds from the sale, which
            exceeded a $4.5 billion offering in November 2010, will be used
            to repay or redeem debt, the Atlanta-based company said in a
            regulatory filing. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Laboratory Corp. of America Holdings, a clinical testing
            company based in Burlington, North Carolina, sold $400 million
            in 2.5 percent, five-year bonds that yield 125 basis points more
            than similar-maturity Treasuries and $300 million in 4 percent,
            10-year notes with a relative yield of 165 basis points. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The risk premium on the Markit CDX North American High
            Yield Index, a credit-swaps benchmark tied to speculative-grade
            bonds, declined 1.5 basis points to 345.4 basis points,
            Bloomberg prices show. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The average extra yield investors demand to hold dollar-denominated, investment-grade corporate
            bonds rather than
            similar-maturity Treasuries increased 0.5 basis point to 125.8
            basis points, Bloomberg data show. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Investment-grade debt is rated Baa3 or higher at Moody's
            Investors Service and at least BBB- by Standard Poor's. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Charles Mead" datetime="Oct 29, 2013  6:09 PM ET" progress_sentiment="u" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-10-29/coca-cola-plans-five-part-bond-offering-to-refinance-obligations.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola Borrows $5 Billion With Its Biggest Bond Offering Ever</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Co. (KO) raised $5 billion in
            its biggest bond offering ever as the world's largest beverage
            company prepares to refinance debt with borrowing costs falling
            back toward a record low. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The soft-drinks maker issued equal $500 million portions of
            fixed- and floating-rate securities due in 2016, two $1.25
            billion pieces that mature in 2018 and 2020 and $1.5 billion of
            10-year bonds, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The transaction comes two weeks after the Atlanta-based
            company reported a 5.9 percent increase in third-quarter profit
            to $2.45 billion with Chief Executive Officer Muhtar Kent
            working to raise prices and entice customers to grab a drink on
            the go. Kent has forecast the company and its bottlers would
            reach $200 billion in global revenue by 2020, double the amount
            generated in 2010. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'The company remains on track to deliver on its 2020
            vision of doubling revenues,' Edward Mui, an analyst at New
            York-based debt researcher CreditSights Inc., wrote today in a
            report that maintained an 'outperform' ranking on Coca-Cola
            bonds. The beverage maker has a 'large and diverse
            international footprint, stable and robust free cash flows, and
            healthy credit metrics,' Mui wrote. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;2010 Sale &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Today's sale exceeds a $4.5 billion offering in November
            2010, Bloomberg data show. Proceeds will be used to repay or
            redeem its $1.25 billion of 0.75 percent bonds due Nov. 15, as
            well as $1 billion of floaters and $900 million of 3.625 percent
            notes both maturing in March, Coca-Cola said today in a
            regulatory filing. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The three-year floaters pay 10 basis points more than the
            London interbank offered rate, and the similar-maturity 0.75
            percent bonds yield 22 basis points more than Treasuries,
            Bloomberg data show. The 1.65 percent five-year debentures have
            a spread of 42, the 2.45 percent seven-year securities pay an
            extra 60, and the 3.2 percent 10-year bonds yield 70 more than
            benchmarks. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The spread on the 2023 bonds exceeds the relative yield on
            Coca-Cola's similar-maturity outstanding bonds as of yesterday
            by 7 basis points, Bloomberg Valuation estimates show. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Average yields on dollar-denominated investment-grade bonds
            fell to 3.19 percent yesterday from a more than 19-month high of
            3.67 percent on Sept. 5, according to Bank of America Merrill
            Lynch index data. They reached a record-low 2.65 percent in May
            and have averaged 5.87 percent during the past two decades. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola is ranked Aa3 at Moody's Investors Service, an
            equivalent AA- by Standard Poor's and a step lower at A+ by
            Fitch Ratings. Libor (US0003M), the rate at which banks say they can
            borrow from each other, was set at 0.24 percent today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Bank of America Corp., Deutsche Bank AG, HSBC Holdings Plc
            and Morgan Stanley helped to manage the sale, the filing shows. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Irina Savu and Andra Timu" datetime="Oct 30, 2013  9:46 AM ET" progress_sentiment="d" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-10-30/coca-cola-invests-30-million-to-boost-romania-as-export-hub.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola Invests $30 Million to Boost Romania as Export Hub</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Co. and Coca-Cola HBC AG (CCH)
            invested 22 million euros ($30 million) in a new production line
            at a Romanian bottling plant to help transform the Balkan state
            into an export hub for 100 million consumers in eastern Europe. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In addition to the new line, which was completed in July,
            the company has built a new warehouse and a power plant in 2009,
            investing 45 million-euros, Coca-Cola HBC Chief Executive
            Officer Dimitris Lois told reporters in the southern town of
            Ploiesti today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The plant, Coca-Cola HBC's largest in southeast Europe,
            will sell Coca-Cola products in six European countries, Coca-Cola Chief Executive Officer Muhtar Kent said
            at the same
            briefing. Coca-Cola and Coca-Cola HBC have invested a total of
            about 525 million euros in Romania since 1991, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'This wonderful investment is growing this business and it
            will be a center of export to a group of countries that together
            will have more than 100 million consumers,' Kent said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Duane D. Stanford" datetime="Sep 15, 2014 12:01 PM ET" progress_sentiment="d" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-15/coca-cola-brings-back-surge-soda-to-tap-1990s-nostalgia.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola Brings Back Surge Soda to Tap 1990s Nostalgia</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Co. (KO)'s newest social-media campaign reaches back to a time when even MySpace didn't
            exist. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Surge, a citrus-flavored Mountain Dew knockoff that was discontinued by Coke
            about 12 years ago, has reappeared in limited supply today. The only place to get it: Amazon.com. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Billed as the company's first ever e-commerce reintroduction, the news was announced by the
            Facebook Fan site 'Surge Movement,' whose 128,000 members lobbied for its return and paid for a billboard in
            Atlanta. Coke gave the drink a Twitter account, too, so loyalists can 'follow the brand's journey.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Surge is back,' the Facebook page's organizers said, urging readers to buy and spread the word.
            'The Movement does not end here!' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;At the website listserv.com, Surge is listed as No. 7
            on a Top 10 list of discontinued sodas, beating out Hubba Bubba Soda. Surge, a sweet and caffeinated green
            pop, will be sold in 12-packs of 16-ounce cans printed with the original graphics for $14. Coke said it may
            expand the drink to other retailers and add to the campaign, depending on how consumers react. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'This will be a great learning experience for us and a refreshing opportunity for fans,' Wendy
            Clark, Coke's president of North America Sparkling Strategic Marketing, said in a statement. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Scott
            Williamson, a Coke spokesman, declined to say how much of the drink the company has produced intially. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;'Extremely Rare' &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola has struggled for decades to counter PepsiCo Inc.
            (PEP)'s Mountain Dew juggernaut. Surge was one of those efforts. Introduced in 1996, the last bottles and
            cans were offered in 2001, two years before the social-networking site Myspace debuted. Facebook would come
            even later. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;At the Surge Movement Facebook page, founded just before Christmas 2011,
            fans shared a 1997 commercial for the drink. Another post showed a way to get 'extremely rare' Surge syrup
            on Ebay.com. One fan photo shows an artifact that was discovered at a flea market in Okoboji, Iowa: a giant
            Surge bottle once used at events to ice down drink samples. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;'I stole one of these when
            Surge first came out,' one commenter responded. 'Sadly, it was lost at the top of Happy Jack Mountains
            outside of Laramie Wyoming when someone got in it and tried to ride it down a mountain. It was a prize
            possession.' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The group sold 'The Surge Movement' t-shirts, and it crowdfunded a $4,000
            billboard near Coke headquarters in Atlanta that read: 'Dear Coke, We couldn't buy Surge so we bought this
            billboard instead.' It's the largest to 'pledge' for the revival of any discontinued product. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Mountain Dew &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;The site's managers urged fans to call Coca-Cola routinely with
            reminders like, 'Did you make your call today?' A mysterious undated video posted yesterday showed the
            Facebook page's administrators meeting at a hotel in Atlanta. Users wanted to know why but they weren't
            saying. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It's no wonder Coke keeps trying. Mountain Dew, the fourth-best-selling soft
            drink in the U.S., has been one of the few bright spots in PepsiCo's soda lineup in recent years as
            consumers drink less soda. Popular with teens, video gamers and extreme sports enthusiasts, Mountain Dew
            outperformed both the soda category and Pepsi-Cola last year, according to Beverage Digest data. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coke may have found its opening, though. Dew's volume sales declined last year. Sales volume for
            regular Dew fell 2.2 percent, compared with declines of 3.6 percent for Pepsi-Cola and 3 percent for the
            category. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>

    <entry author="By Duane D. Stanford" datetime="Sep 23, 2014  2:10 PM ET" progress_sentiment="d" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-23/coca-cola-pepsico-pledge-to-cut-drink-calories-consumed-by-20-.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola, PepsiCo Pledge to Cut Drink Calories Consumed by 20%</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Co. (KO) and PepsiCo Inc. (PEP) agreed to cut the amount of beverage calories that
            Americans consume by 20 percent over the next decade, saying they'll more heavily promote smaller portion
            sizes, water and diet drinks. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The American Beverage Association-backed effort, which
            also involves Dr Pepper Snapple Group (DPS), made the commitment at the Clinton Global Initiative Annual
            Meeting in New York today. The move builds on a 2006 agreement to limit portion sizes targeted at school
            kids, which resulted in beverage calories shipped to schools falling 90 percent between 2004 and 2010. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The latest campaign is a response to growing criticism of the industry, which is blamed for
            contributing to America's obesity epidemic. Demand for sugary drinks has already been declining, though,
            suggesting that the industry could achieve these goals without much additional effort, said Jeff Cronin, a
            spokesman for the Center for Science in the Public Interest, one of the first groups to sound the alarm
            about sodas in the 1990s. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;'Non-diet soda is already in a free fall,' Cronin said in an
            interview. 'There is no reason to think that trend wouldn't accelerate on its own.' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Cronin
            estimates sales for such drinks have declined 15 percent since 1998. Volume sales could drop another 20
            percent within a decade with no action by soft-drink makers at all, he said. &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: Daniel Acker/Bloomberg

            &lt;p&gt;
            The move by Coca-Cola Co. and PepsiCo Inc. builds on a 2006 agreement to limit portion sizes targeted at
            school kids, which resulted in beverage calories shipped to schools falling 90 percent between 2004 and
            2010. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Kristen Schweizer" datetime="Sep 30, 2013  8:53 AM ET" progress_sentiment="d" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-09-30/apple-overtakes-coca-cola-as-most-valuable-brand-study-finds.html">
        <headline>Apple Overtakes Coca-Cola as World's Most Valuable Brand</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Apple (AAPL) has unseated Coca-Cola as the
            world's No. 1 brand, as the company founded by Steve Jobs is a
            leader in design and performance, according to a study of the
            Top 100 brands by Interbrand Corp. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Apple Inc.'s brand value jumped 28 percent to $98.3 billion
            and Google Inc. (GOOG)'s rose in second place at $93.3 billion. The
            Coca-Cola Co. name slipped from the top spot after 13 years to
            third place at $79.2 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Every so often, a company changes our lives -- not just
            with its products, but with its ethos,' Jez Frampton, chief
            executive officer at New York-based brand consultancy
            Interbrand, said in a statement. Current Apple CEO 'Tim Cook
            has assembled a solid leadership team and has kept Steve Jobs'
            vision intact -- a vision that has allowed Apple to deliver on
            its promise of innovation time and time again.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The annual study, closely watched by the industry,
            determines a brand's value by examining its financial
            performance, role in influencing consumer buying and ability to
            secure earnings. The Top 10 is rounded out in descending order
            by IBM, Microsoft, GE, McDonald's, Samsung, Intel and Toyota.
            The 100 have a combined value of $1.5 trillion, an 8.4 percent
            increase from last year. &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: Craig Warga/Bloomberg

            &lt;p&gt;
            A customer views an Apple Inc. iPhone 5c displayed during the devices launch at the company's store in New
            York. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>
</news>