<?xml version='1.0' encoding='us-ascii'?>
<news><entry author="By Mary Jane Credeur" category="RETAIL" date="Jan 22, 2007  4:26 PM ET" keywords="Coca-Cola Bottling Co Consolidated, Coca-Cola Co/The, Coca-Cola Enterprises Inc, Coca-Cola Femsa SAB de CV, Beverages, Consumer Goods, Containers, Emerging Markets, Georgia (U.S.), Industries, Latin America, Mexico, North America, North Carolina, Packaging, Regions, Retail, Specialized Regions, U.S. South, U.S. Southeast, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-22/coca-cola-shifts-minnick-s-marketing-duties-to-kent-update1-.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Shifts Minnick's Marketing Duties to Kent</headline><body>
Coca-Cola Co. (KO), the world's largest
soft-drink maker, will shift some of outgoing marketing chief
Mary Minnick's responsibilities to recently promoted President
Muhtar Kent. 
Kent will oversee marketing for the Atlanta-based company
beginning March 1, Chief Executive Officer Neville Isdell, said
today in an internal memo to employees. Minnick, who was passed
over when Kent was named president and chief operating officer
in December, said last week she will leave in February to pursue
other personal and professional goals in the U.K. 
The move gives more responsibility to Kent, 54, who is
Coca-Cola's second-highest ranking executive and likely
successor to Isdell. Coca-Cola's strategy and innovation groups,
formerly overseen by Minnick, will report to Isdell. 
``As the health of our business continues to improve, the
factors that necessitated the combining of marketing, strategy
and innovation have evolved,'' Isdell, 63, said in the memo. 
The new structure allows Coca-Cola to ``increase the impact
and effectiveness of the global marketing community, while
preserving the benefits we have captured'' by previously
combining the groups, wrote Isdell, who hasn't said when he
plans to retire. 
Coca-Cola also said today Marc Mathieu, who previously
oversaw marketing for brands such as Coca-Cola, Sprite and
Fanta, will assume similar duties for noncarbonated drinks
including Dasani and Powerade. 
Shares of Coca-Cola fell 23 cents to $48.03 at 4 p.m. in
New York Stock Exchange composite trading. They increased 20
percent last year, the biggest annual gain since 1997. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Mary Jane Credeur in Atlanta at 
mcredeur@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Michael Nol at  mnol@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Mary Jane Credeur" category="RETAIL" date="Jan 24, 2007  4:42 PM ET" keywords="Coca-Cola Bottling Co Consolidated, Coca-Cola Co/The, Coca-Cola Enterprises Inc, Coca-Cola Femsa SAB de CV, PepsiCo Inc, Advertising, Beverages, Consumer Goods, Containers, Emerging Markets, Food, Georgia (U.S.), Industries, Latin America, Media, Mexico, National Football League, New York, North America, North Carolina, Packaging, Retail, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, U.S. South, U.S. Southeast, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-24/coca-cola-will-run-first-super-bowl-ads-since-1998-update3-.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Will Run First Super Bowl Ads Since 1998</headline><body>
Coca-Cola Co. (KO) will go head-to-head
with PepsiCo Inc. (PEP) in Super Bowl television advertising for the
first time in almost a decade as it tries to boost sales of its
top-selling drink. 
One new ad for Coca-Cola Classic will air during
professional football's championship game along with two spots
that debuted during the television show ``American Idol,'' the
Atlanta-based company said in a statement today. Coca-Cola hasn't
run promotions during the Super Bowl since 1998. 
Advertising during television's most-watched event pits
Coca-Cola against PepsiCo as both companies try to reverse a drop
in U.S. soda sales. PepsiCo has advertised during the Super Bowl
for 21 consecutive years and will sponsor the half-time show for
the first time. 
``Coke wants back in the game,'' said Z. John Zhang,
marketing professor at the Wharton School at the University of
Pennsylvania. ``They've waited this many years to come back, so
the pressure is on them to have the louder voice.'' 
Both soft-drink makers are trying to stop declines in the
U.S., where soda consumption dropped in 2005 for the first time
in at least 15 years because of concern that sugary beverages
contribute to obesity. Coca-Cola's soft drink volume fell 1
percent in North America during the third quarter, and PepsiCo's
dropped 2 percent. 
Cost of Ads 
Coca-Cola's Super Bowl advertisements include a 60-second
spot titled ``Video Game,'' showing a character who passes out
bottles of Coca-Cola Classic to people he meets on the street.
Coca-Cola will also run a 30-second ad called ``Happiness
Factory'' that follows a bottle of Coke through an imaginary
vending machine. 
The company won't say anything about the new commercial
being made for the Super Bowl. The ads were created by
independent agency Wieden + Kennedy, based in Portland, Oregon. 
``Coca-Cola Classic has always been about having fun, and
that's what people get together to do when they watch the Super
Bowl,'' said Katie Bayne, senior vice president for Coca-Cola
brands in North America. 
Shares of Coca-Cola fell 1 cent to $48.13 at 4 p.m. in New
York Stock Exchange composite trading. They gained 20 percent
last year, the biggest gain since 1997. 
PepsiCo shares climbed 36 cents to $65.20. They rose 5.9
percent last year. 
Coca-Cola spokeswoman Susan McDermott wouldn't say how much
the company is spending on the game. A 30-second ad during the
Super Bowl can cost $2.5 million, according to AdWeek. Coca-
Cola's advertising budget was $2.48 billion in 2005. 
Bears vs. Colts 
More than 141 million people watched last year's Super Bowl.
This year's game, scheduled for Feb. 4 at Dolphin Stadium in
Miami Gardens, Fla., is a match-up between the Chicago Bears and
the Indianapolis Colts. 
The Super Bowl will be broadcast on CBS Corp.'s CBS network.
The television show American Idol, the most popular show on
primetime television, airs on News Corp.'s Fox network. 
In addition to the half-time show sponsorship, PepsiCo plans
to run 90 seconds of ads during the first half of the Super Bowl,
spokeswoman Nicole Bradley said. She wouldn't say how much the
company is spending, or which ads it plans to run. 
PepsiCo has a promotion featuring a sterling silver can of
Pepsi studded with diamonds, rubies and sapphires. The company
will give away the can, worth $100,000, and Super Bowl tickets
for life after the half-time show, which includes a performance
by the musician Prince. 
``We thrive on the Super Bowl spotlight. It's been a part of
our game plan for more than two decades,'' Bradley said. 
Last year, Coca-Cola sponsored a Super Bowl pre-game show
with its Full Throttle energy drink. Ads showed a semi-tractor
trailer truck mounted with an oversized can of Full Throttle
overtaking a small pickup truck with a slender can of rival
energy drink Red Bull. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Mary Jane Credeur in Atlanta at 
mcredeur@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Michael Nol at  mnol@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Mary Jane Credeur" category="US, RETAIL" date="Feb 01, 2007  4:39 PM ET" keywords="Coca-Cola Bottling Co Consolidated, Coca-Cola Co/The, Coca-Cola Enterprises Inc, Coca-Cola Femsa SAB de CV, Beverages, Consumer Goods, Containers, Corporate Actions, Corporate Finance, Emerging Markets, Georgia (U.S.), Industries, Latin America, Mergers &amp;amp; Acquisitions, Mexico, New Jersey, New York Times Play, North America, North Carolina, Packaging, Regions, Retail, Specialized Regions, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, U.S. South, U.S. Southeast, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-02-01/coca-cola-agrees-to-buy-fuze-to-add-healthier-drinks-update4-.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Agrees to Buy Fuze to Add Healthier Drinks</headline><body>
Coca-Cola Co. (KO), the world's largest
soft-drink maker, agreed to buy Fuze Beverage LLC to add more
juice, tea and energy drinks in an effort to catch up with
PepsiCo Inc. 
Coca-Cola gains a half-dozen new products including Fuze
Tea, NOS energy drinks and Fuze Slenderize, which has chromium
and amino acids that Fuze says help promote weight loss. Atlanta-
based Coca-Cola didn't disclose terms of the purchase. 
Fuze beverages may help Coca-Cola win back customers who
switched from sugary sodas to drinks such as PepsiCo's SoBe tea.
It's Coca-Cola's biggest U.S. acquisition since buying Odwalla
Inc. in 2001 for $186 million to gain protein drinks and juices,
said John Sicher, editor of industry journal Beverage Digest. 
``This represents Coke aggressively getting itself into a
better place in the noncarbonated business in the U.S.,'' Sicher
said. ``Fuze is small but growing strongly.'' 
Sicher estimated that Coca-Cola paid $225 million to $250
million for closely held Fuze. He said the Englewood Cliffs, New
Jersey-based company sold about 11.5 million cases last year, up
from 8 million cases in 2005, generating $90 million to $100
million in revenue. 
Shares of Coca-Cola rose 22 cents to $48.10 at 4:22 p.m. in
New York Stock Exchange composite trading. They increased 20
percent last year, their biggest gain since 1997. 
Bottlers 
The Fuze purchase may help sate bottlers that had
complained about Coca-Cola falling behind PepsiCo in adding
drinks other than soda. Coca-Cola depends on soda for 80 percent
of its volume, compared with less than 20 percent for PepsiCo. 
Coca-Cola Enterprises Inc. (CCE), the largest distributor, agreed
to distribute Arizona bottled teas in the U.S. last year, making
good on a promise to get new drinks from someone other than Coca-
Cola if it needed to. The bottler is 36 percent owned by Coca-
Cola. 
``This should be well-received by Coke's bottlers,'' Bill Pecoriello, an analyst at Morgan Stanley, wrote today in a note. 
Fuze was already distributed by 20 Coca-Cola bottlers
including Coca-Cola Bottling Co. United of Birmingham, Alabama,
and the Philadelphia Coca-Cola Bottling Co. 
Only about 15 percent of Fuze's volume currently goes
through Coca-Cola bottlers, Pecoriello wrote. The Cadbury
Schweppes Bottling Group had distributed Fuze in much of the
U.S., Sicher said. 
Coca-Cola Bottling Co. Consolidated, the second-largest
bottler for Coca-Cola, sells Cinnabon bottled coffee and created
a separate unit called Beverages and Beyond Brands to create or
buy drinks it wasn't getting from the soda maker. 
Coca-Cola's soda volume in the U.S. dropped by a low single
digit in 2005, while noncarbonated volume jumped 10 percent. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Mary Jane Credeur in Atlanta at 
mcredeur@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Michael Nol at  mnol@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Will McSheehy and Claudia Maedler" category="MIDDLE_EAST, FINANCE" date="Feb 07, 2007 10:17 AM ET" keywords="Deutsche Bank AG, JPMorgan Chase &amp;amp; Co, Africa, Arabian Region, Asia, Asia ex. Japan, Australia, Banking, Buyout, China, Construction &amp;amp; Engineering, Corporate Actions, Corporate Finance, Egypt, Egypt Econonmy, Emerging Markets, Energy, Euro Members, Europe, Financial Services, Germany, India, Industries, Korea, Kuwait, Markets, Mergers &amp;amp; Acquisitions, Middle East, Mideast, Mutual &amp;amp; Hedge Funds, New York, North America, Oil, Pacific Rim, Pakistan, Pakistan Economy, Persian Gulf, Private Equity, Regions, Saudi Arabia, Saudi Arabia Economy, Securities Firms, South, Southeast Asia, Specialized Regions, Taiwan, Trusts, Turkey, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, United Kingdom, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-02-07/jpmorgan-bear-stearns-hired-for-mideast-buyout-fund-update2-.html"><headline>JPMorgan, Bear Stearns Hired for Mideast Buyout Fund</headline><body>
JPMorgan Cazenove Ltd. and Bear
Stearns Cos. will help raise up to $2 billion for a Kuwaiti
buyout fund offering international investors a way to tap oil-fueled economic growth in the Middle East and North Africa. 
Global Investment House KSCC (GI5B), Kuwait's biggest investment
bank, will open its Global Buyout Fund to investors tomorrow,
Shailesh Dash, head of the lender's strategic investment group,
said in a phone interview today from Kuwait. It aims to raise
about $1.5 billion for conventional private equity, and another
$500 million for Islamic investments. 
``This is the first time a Gulf fund has attracted two
international placement agents without giving them a role on
the fund's management board,'' Dash said. ``This region's
current account surpluses, construction boom and opening
economies are really attracting investors now.'' 
The economy of Saudi Arabia, the world's biggest oil
producer, will expand by 6.5 percent this year as the
government spends oil surpluses on new infrastructure, the
International Monetary Fund forecasts. Economic growth in Egypt
will accelerate to 7.5 percent this year after the government
cut taxes and tariffs to spur investment, Prime Minister Ahmed Nazif said in a Jan. 25 interview. 
The IMF expects Middle Eastern countries will earn a
combined current account surplus of $306 billion in 2007, up
from $282 billion in 2006, it says on its Web site. 
Wall Street 
JPMorgan Cazenove and Bear Stearns, Wall Street's fifth-biggest firm, join Western investors including Deutsche Bank AG (DBK)
and Carlyle Group raising money to buy Middle East and North
African companies. 
Deutsche in May started a $2 billion Islamic private
equity fund for the region with Dubai's Abraaj Capital and
Bahrain's Ithmaar Bank that aims to grow investors' money by 15
percent a year. Muslim Shariah law forbids investment in
companies with high levels of debt or that are active in
proscribed businesses like gaming and alcohol sales. 
Carlyle, manager of more than $44 billion worldwide, plans
to hire 15 people to buy companies and identify potential
partners in the Middle East, North Africa and Turkey, Walid Musallam, the U.S. buyout firm's regional managing director,
said in November. 
20 Percent Return 
Global Investment's 7-year fund will seek buyouts of
between $100 million and $150 million to achieve an internal
rate of return of 20 percent for its investors, according to
Dash. 
Private equity raised $432 billion globally last year, led
by buyout funds which raised $212 billion, London-based Private
Equity Intelligence Ltd. said in a Jan. 25 report. Investors
like pension funds, endowments and wealthy individuals have
poured increasing amounts of money into private equity as some
funds outperform public markets. 
Blackstone Group LP's 2002 $6.45 billion fund had annual
returns of 63 percent to July compared with an annual return of
6.3 percent in the Standard  Poor's 500 Index from 2002. 
Buyout firms typically aim to increase a company's profit
by changing managers or strategy before selling their holdings
within five years to a new buyer or to investors in an initial
stock sale. The firms raise cash from institutional investors
and use a combination of cash and loans to make purchases. The
acquired company's cash flow is then used to pay down debt. 
Global Investment manages about $1 billion of private
equity investments within a total $7.2 billion of assets under
management, according to Dash. The bank's shares closed down 1
percent to 960 fils ($3.3) in Kuwait today and have fallen by
13 percent this year. 
To contact the reporters on this story:
Will McSheehy in Dubai on 
wmcsheehy@bloomberg.net
Claudia Maedler in Dubai at 
cmaedler@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Gavin Serkin at  gserkin@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Mary Jane Credeur" category="RETAIL" date="Apr 18, 2007  4:24 PM ET" keywords="Coca-Cola Bottling Co Consolidated, Coca-Cola Co/The, Coca-Cola Enterprises Inc, Coca-Cola Femsa SAB de CV, Beverages, Consumer Goods, Containers, Earnings, Emerging Markets, Georgia (U.S.), Industries, Latin America, Mexico, North America, North Carolina, Packaging, Regions, Research, Retail, U.S. South, U.S. Southeast, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-04-18/coca-cola-s-isdell-keeping-promise-of-steady-growth-update2-.html"><headline>Coca-Cola's Isdell `Keeping Promise' of Steady Growth</headline><body>
Coca-Cola Co. (KO) Chief Executive
Officer Neville Isdell said the world's largest soft-drink maker
is ``keeping our promise'' to return the company to steady
growth by focusing on emerging markets such as China. 
Coca-Cola's profit has resumed growing after a two-year
slowdown, Isdell said today on a Webcast of the company's annual
meeting in Wilmington, Delaware. The company reported yesterday
that first-quarter profit rose 14 percent on the biggest sales
gain in more than a decade. 
``Last year, I told you the company completed the
transition, and that stabilization would be achieved in 2006,''
Isdell said. ``I said as a result of that, the company would
return to sustainable growth, and my message to you today is
that we are keeping our promise.'' 
Coca-Cola is headed for its biggest increase in annual
profit since 2003, buoyed by demand for its drinks in fast-
growing markets such as China and Brazil. Worldwide volume
increased 6 percent in the first quarter, compared with a 3.3
percent average annual gain since Isdell became CEO in 2004. 
Eleven analysts surveyed by Bloomberg estimate the Atlanta-
based company's annual profit will jump 18 percent this year,
compared with a 4 percent gain last year and less than 1 percent
the prior year. 
Shares of Coca-Cola rose 9 cents to $51.66 at 4 p.m. in New
York Stock Exchange composite trading, after closing yesterday
at their highest since June 2004. The shares have gained 25
percent in the past year, compared with 13 percent for PepsiCo
Inc. 
U.S. `Problems' 
Coca-Cola is still ``working through some problems'' in
North America, its largest unit, where volume dropped 3 percent
in the first quarter after higher prices hurt soda sales. 
The company is trying to bolster sales with more
advertising and healthy drinks such as juices and teas made by
Fuze Beverage LLC, which Coca-Cola bought in March. 
Coca-Cola's soft drink volume in the U.S. dropped 1.2
percent last year, according to data by industry journal
Beverage Digest. 
The company wants to ``reinvigorate'' soda sales, Isdell
said. Coca-Cola has promoted and expanded Coca-Cola Zero, a
calorie-free drink formulated to taste like regular Coke. The
company has added a cherry-flavored version, and the drink will
be available in 40 countries by the end of this year. 
``Along the way, we will make corrections wherever we make
inevitable mistakes as we hit the bumps that occur on the
road,'' Isdell said. 
Also at the meeting, shareholders voted against proposals
seeking limits on executive pay and restricted stock grants. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Mary Jane Credeur in Atlanta at 
mcredeur@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Michael Nol at  mnol@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Igor Muller" category="MANUFACTURING" date="Apr 27, 2007 12:29 PM ET" keywords="Dongfang Electric Corp Ltd, Gazprom OAO, Morgan Stanley, Asia, Asia ex. Japan, Australia, China, Commonwealth of Ind States, Currencies, Eastern Europe, Emerging Markets, Energy, Europe, Financial Services, Industries, Investment Advisers, Korea, Machinery, Manufacturing, Market Strategists, Markets, Natural Gas, Oil, Pacific Rim, Regions, Russia, Securities Firms, Specialized Regions, Taiwan" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-04-27/morgan-stanley-ups-forecast-for-emerging-markets-update1-.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Ups Forecast for Emerging Markets</headline><body>
Morgan Stanley (MS), the world's second-largest securities company, raised its forecast for emerging-market stocks this year on expectations for worldwide economic
growth and rising commodity prices. 
Jonathan Garner, head of global emerging-market strategy in
London, raised his year-end projection for the Morgan Stanley
Capital International Emerging Markets Index by 8.2 percent to
1,060. That represents a gain of 7.8 percent from yesterday's
close. 
The benchmark has risen 6.8 percent so far this year after
recovering from a slump that began in late February when equity
markets dropped worldwide on concerns about slowdown of the U.S.
economy. 
``The global growth story is about strengthening economies
in Japan, European Union, especially Germany and emerging
markets,'' Garner said in a telephone interview. ``It's
inappropriate to have such a U.S. centric view.'' 
A report showed today that last quarter's growth rate in the
U.S. was the weakest since the first three months of 2003,
trimmed by the slump in home construction and a bigger trade
deficit. Growth in the 12 months ended in March slowed to 2.1
percent, the weakest year-over-year gain since the second quarter
of 2003, while inflation rose. 
Garner said the slowdown is mostly led by non-traded housing
market in the world's largest economy and doesn't have a major
impact on global and emerging market stocks. 
Counterbalance 
Morgan Stanley expects the global economy to grow 4.5
percent this year, as it expects the slowdown of the U.S. economy
to be counterbalanced by reviving expansion in countries that
share euro currency, Garner said in the note. 
At the same time Morgan Stanley sees commodity prices and
prices for oil to rise above prices in 2006. Garner has
recommended buying South African basic resource stocks in his
report from March 20. 
Metals such as copper has gained 23 percent this year as
demand surged in China, the world's largest copper consumer.
Crude oil has advanced 6.6 percent so far this year. 
Garner added Dongfang Electrical Machinery Co. (600875), China's
third-biggest maker of power-generation equipment, to its list of
recommended shares and removed OAO Gazprom (GAZP), Russia's natural gas
export monopoly, citing concern about dividend yields and
earnings outlook in Russia. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Igor Muller in Vienna at 
imuller@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Balduin Hesse at 
bhesse2@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Nariman Gizitdinov" category="ENERGY_MARKETS, ENERGY" date="May 24, 2007  8:46 AM ET" keywords="BG Group PLC, Chevron Corp, Eni SpA, Exxon Mobil Corp, Lukoil OAO, Asia, Asia ex. Japan, Australia, California, Chemicals, Commodities, Commodities Markets, Commonwealth of Ind States, Crude Oil, Eastern Europe, Emerging Markets, Energy, Energy Trading, Euro Members, Europe, FTSE 100 Index, Financial Services, Industries, Italy, Kazakhstan, Liquefied Petroleum Gas, Markets, Natural Gas, Natural Gas Market, North America, Oil, Oil Markets, Oil Products, Pacific Rim, Pipelines, Refineries, Regions, Research, Russia, Specialized Regions, Texas, Trade, U.S. Southwest, U.S. West, United Kingdom, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-05-24/chevron-to-sell-gas-to-kazakh-petrochemical-complex-update2-.html"><headline>Chevron to Sell Gas to Kazakh Petrochemical Complex</headline><body>
A Chevron Corp. (CVX) unit that produces
about a quarter of Kazakhstan's oil will provide 7 billion cubic
meters of gas a year to the country's first ``world-scale''
petrochemical complex when it opens in 2011. 
The Chevron unit, Tengizchevroil LLP, and Kazakhstan
Petrochemical Industries signed an agreement today to supply gas
from the Tengiz field to the petrochemical complex planned in
western Kazakhstan, the state-run news agency Kazinform reported
from Atyrau. 
``The memorandum of understanding is an important milestone
in our discussions with Kazakhstan Petrochemical Industries, a
demonstration of the progress made,'' Tengizchevroil said by an
e-mail. 
``Tengizchevroil and KPI have worked to outline terms for
the sales of feedstock to KPI for their planned petrochemical
facilities,'' Chevron's venture said. It gave no financial
details of the agreement. 
Kazakhstan Petrochemical Industries is a venture between a
publicly traded subsidiary of KazMunaiGaz National Co., the
state-owned oil and gas company, and Sat  Co., a privately
owned Kazakh industrial company. 
Tengizchevroil's Supplies 
Tengizchevroil will supply 7 billion cubic meters of dry
gas and 550,000 tons of liquid propane to the plant, Shukhrat
Danbay, KazMunaiGaz National's executive director of refining
and petrochemicals, said in a phone interview today. The complex
will be built in 2010 and 2011, and it will buy gas at an
``acceptable price,'' he said. 
The petrochemical complex will include refineries to
process gas from the Tengiz field, and later from the Kashagan
and Karachaganak fields, all of which are being developed by
foreign-led ventures. Basell Holdings NV, the world's largest
producer of polypropylene, used to make car fenders, will help
build and manage the refineries. 
The partners also have an agreement with an Eni SpA-led
group to provide supplies of 3 billion cubic meters of dry gas
from the Kashagan field, according to the Energy Ministry's May
17 statement. Eni expects to start production in 2010 at
Kashagan, the largest discovery worldwide in the past 30 years. 
Chevron's venture plans to nearly double oil production to
550,000 barrels a day after building a $5.5 billion gas-processing plant and gas-injection system for oil extraction in
2008, TengizChevroil said in January. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Nariman Gizitdinov in Almaty, through the Moscow newsroom at 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Daniel Tilles at  dtilles@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Angela Greiling Keane and Jonathan D. Salant" category="POLITICS, AUSTRALIA_NEW_ZEALAND, US, FINANCE, TRANSPORTATION" date="Jun 11, 2007 11:10 AM ET" keywords="Goldman Sachs Group Inc/The, Macquarie Group Ltd, Macquarie Infrastructure Co LLC, YRC Worldwide Inc, Asia, Australia, Banking, Chile, Commercial Services, Congress, Dept of Transportation, Emerging Markets, Euro Members, Europe, Financial Services, Greet The Week, Illinois, Indiana, Industries, Kansas, Latin America, Markets, Mutual &amp;amp; Hedge Funds, Mutual Funds, New Jersey, New York, New Zealand, North America, Pacific Rim, Pennsylvania, Politics, Securities Firms, South America, Spain, Spain &amp;amp; Portugal, Tennessee, Transportation, Trucking, Trusts, U.S., U.S. Government, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, U.S. Midwest, U.S. South, U.S. Southeast, United States, Virginia" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-06-11/goldman-macquarie-face-fight-on-private-toll-roads-update1-.html"><headline>Goldman, Macquarie Face Fight on Private Toll Roads</headline><body>
The trucking industry and
congressional Democrats are trying to put the brakes on state
efforts to lease toll roads to Macquarie Bank Ltd., Goldman Sachs
Group Inc. (GS) and other private investors. 
Urged on by truckers such as U.S. Xpress Enterprises Ltd.,
House Democrats are considering withholding highway funds from
states whose leases with companies fail to meet proposed federal
standards. Critics of leasing say private investors are more
likely to raise tolls than government authorities are. Private
investors would also find it easier to fire toll collectors and
other employees. 
New federal restrictions could make investments in the $1.7
trillion of public roadways less attractive to private interests.
And the mere fact of congressional attention might have a
chilling effect on such deals, says Mike McDermott, an analyst
who works on toll-road transactions in the New York office of
Fitch Ratings Ltd., which rates debt used to finance
infrastructure. 
``Those kinds of public debates would make politicians at
the state level more cautious,'' he says. 
For states with heavily traveled roadways, lease agreements
with the likes of Macquarie and Goldman are potential windfalls
that would allow them to meet budget needs without raising taxes. 
Leasing the Turnpike 
Pennsylvania, which says it faces a $1.7 billion shortfall
in transportation funds during the next 20 years, might raise as
much as $12 billion to $18 billion by leasing the 537-mile
Pennsylvania Turnpike, according to an analysis by Morgan
Stanley. New Jersey Democratic Governor Jon Corzine, 60, is also
looking at leasing state toll roads to raise money for highway
construction and maintenance. 
Such arrangements are common in Australia, Chile, Spain and
elsewhere around the world. Sydney-based Macquarie, the world's
largest private manager of public facilities, said last month
that it raised $10 billion to buy more infrastructure assets in
Europe and North America. Those assets would be added to its
existing stakes in the Indiana Toll Road -- leased in 2006 for
$3.85 billion -- and the Chicago Skyway, leased for 99 years in
2005 for $1.83 billion. 
New York-based Goldman Sachs, the biggest U.S. securities
firm by market value, raised $6.5 billion last year for a new
fund to invest in toll roads and other infrastructure. Goldman is
one of 48 firms interested in leasing the Pennsylvania Turnpike. 
Shortchanging the Public 
Alex Doughty, a spokesman for New York-based Macquarie
Infrastructure Group, didn't respond to requests for comment.
Goldman Sachs spokesman Michael DuVally declined to comment. 
House Democrats say they are concerned the public will be
shortchanged by long-term private leases. ``Public-private
partnerships need to take the public interests in mind,'' House
Transportation Committee Chairman Jim Oberstar, 72, a Minnesota
Democrat, said in a statement provided by his office. 
Oberstar's proposed guidelines for private leasing
agreements would include guarantees that states could upgrade
highways parallel to leased toll roads and protection against
price gouging by private companies. States that didn't comply
would face the loss of federal highway funds. 
Oberstar and House highways subcommittee chairman Peter DeFazio have sent letters to state officials urging them to go
slow. ``If public-private partnerships are abused, what you will
cause is a reaction on the state and federal level that will put
an end to this,'' says DeFazio, 60, an Oregon Democrat. 
A `Patronage Bastion' 
Pennsylvania Governor Edward Rendell -- like Oberstar and
DeFazio, a Democrat -- says the congressional concerns are
overblown. In his state, Rendell, 63, said in an interview, much
of the opposition to leasing the turnpike has come from
entrenched partisan interests fearing the loss of what has been a
``huge patronage bastion for both political parties.'' 
Congressional Democrats have found unlikely allies in
Chattanooga, Tennessee-based U.S. Xpress and other trucking
companies, which in the last 10 years have given about 80 percent
of their campaign donations to Republicans, according to the
Center for Responsive Politics, a Washington-based research
group. 
The growing interest in road leasing shows that ``someone's
figured out how to make a lot of money doing these deals and also
that someone, probably the users of these roads, is going to pay
exponentially,'' says former Kansas Governor Bill Graves, 54,
chief executive of the American Trucking Associations. The trade
group, based in Alexandria, Virginia, represents among others
U.S. Xpress and Overland Park, Kansas-based YRC Worldwide Inc. (YRCW),
the largest U.S. trucking company. 
Taxes Over Tolls 
The truckers' trade group says the industry pays $3 billion
to $4 billion a year in tolls now. Graves, a Republican, says the
industry would prefer higher fuel taxes to increased tolls. 
Large trucking companies typically sign long-term contracts
with customers that factor in fuel-price fluctuations. Patrick Quinn, 61, president of U.S. Xpress and chairman of the ATA, said
in an interview that private control of U.S. highways is
``unpredictable and unknown'' and could increase tolls. 
Frequent toll hikes, Quinn says, would make cost planning
difficult. ``We feel kind of comfortable with the system'' now,
he says. 
After Indiana signed its lease agreement, truck tolls on its
157-mile toll road rose 24 percent -- the first increase since
1985. They rose another 25 percent in April and are due to go up
again in 2008 and 2009. 
Benefits and Risks 
For politicians, there may be both benefits and risks in
such arrangements. Private control may free officials from being
blamed for higher tolls, says McDermott, the Fitch Ratings
analyst. They can say ``it's not me that's raising rates,'' he
says. 
On the other hand, the higher charges in Indiana helped
Democrats capture control of the state House of Representatives
and win a congressional seat in the district that straddles the
highway. 
``People thought it was done in an unfair way, and they
wanted someone who would stand up for it,'' says Democratic U.S.
Representative Joe Donnelly, 51, who ousted Republican Chris Chocola, 45. 
Matt Pierce, a spokesman for the Indiana Toll Road, says the
lease benefits motorists. ``Our primary responsibility is to the
consumers who travel the road,'' he says. ``We're selling them
time. We're selling them that ease of moving the goods.'' 
The Bush administration is backing the states' drive to get
business investment to run highways. ``Public-private
partnerships are vital to fixing this nation's mounting mobility
crisis because private investment is based on demand and not
political influence,'' Transportation Secretary Mary Peters, 58,
told a highway group in Myrtle Beach, South Carolina, on June 1. 
With Bush's backing, and given the financial needs of the
states, Pennsylvania's Rendell predicts more such deals in the
future. The balding governor says he'll be able to ``comb my hair
in a pompadour'' before Congress clamps down on the trend. 
To contact the reporters on this story:
Angela Greiling Keane in Washington at 
agreilingkea@bloomberg.net;
Jonathan D. Salant in Washington at 
jsalant@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Michael Forsythe at  mforsythe@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Ting Ting Ng and Clare Cheung" category="MANUFACTURING" date="Jun 11, 2007  6:41 AM ET" keywords="Johnson Electric Holdings Ltd, Asia, Asia ex. Japan, Australia, Auto Parts, Automobiles, China, Consumer Goods, Electronics, Emerging Markets, Equity Movers, Hong Kong, Industries, Korea, Machinery, Manufacturing, Markets, Pacific Rim, Retail, Taiwan, Toys, Transportation" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-06-11/johnson-electric-falls-on-disappointing-forecast-update2-.html"><headline>Johnson Electric Falls on `Disappointing' Forecast</headline><body>
Shares of Johnson Electric Holdings
Ltd. (179), the maker of miniature motors used in ATMs and Ford Motor
Co. cars, had their biggest drop in more than 12 months after the
company said profit was unlikely to rise this fiscal year. 
The stock fell 6.3 percent to HK$4.73 in Hong Kong, after
slumping as much as 7.5 percent. That was the biggest fall since
April 28, 2006. The company is unlikely to increase its profit in
the year ending March 2008 because of slowing demand and rising
raw material costs, it said on June 8. 
Copper and steel prices have surged as China's economic
growth fuels demand for the metals, pushing up Johnson Electric's
costs. The company will also likely suffer from falling demand
for new vehicles in North America and Europe. 
``The guided business outlook is very disappointing,''
Credit Suisse Group analyst Kenny Lau said in a report today. The
fiscal 2008 profit forecast is 31 percent lower than the
consensus among analysts of $160 million, Lau added. 
Johnson Electric, which makes motors for adjusting
headlights and car seats, increased net income 17 percent in the
year ended March after it bought two companies to expand in
Europe and the U.S. Sales climbed 37 percent to $2.09 billion. 
The price of copper has risen 62 percent since the end of
2005 on the London Metals Exchange. Prices of hot-rolled coil
steel, an industry benchmark, have risen 4.5 percent this year in
China, according to metal research firm Beijing Antaike
Information Co. 
U.S. sales of new cars and light trucks fell 1.2 percent in
the first five months of the year, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. European vehicle sales declined 0.2 percent in the
first four month of the year to 5.52 million, according to the
European Automobile Manufacturers Association. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Ting Ting Ng in Hong Kong at 
tng9@bloomberg.net
Clare Cheung in Hong Kong at 
scheung4@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Tom Kohn at 
tkohn@bloomberg.net
Bret Okeson at 
bokeson@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Haslinda Amin and Anuchit Nguyen" category="ENERGY" date="Jun 20, 2007  8:20 AM ET" keywords="Chevron Corp, PTT Exploration &amp;amp; Production PCL, Asia, Asia ex. Japan, Australia, California, Commodities, Crude Oil, Currencies, Emerging Markets, Energy, Environment, Industries, Liquefied Petroleum Gas, Markets, Natural Gas, North America, Oil, Oil Products, Pacific Rim, Refineries, South, Southeast Asia, Thailand, U.S. West, United States, Utilities, ex-Energy" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-06-20/chevron-ptt-get-extension-on-thai-oil-exploration-update1-.html"><headline>Chevron, PTT Get Extension on Thai Oil Exploration</headline><body>
Chevron Corp. (CVX) and PTT Exploration
and Production Pcl (PTTEP), Thailand's two biggest natural gas
producers, have got an extension on their exploration and
production contracts at some fields. 
Chevron can continue exploration and production at three
blocks in the Gulf of Thailand for another 10 years, Energy
Minister Piyasvasti Amranand said in an interview in Bangkok
today. PTT Exploration will also receive permission to develop
the Bongkot field for another 10 years, he said. The contracts
for those gas and oil fields were scheduled to expire in 2012. 
Thailand has given more areas to Chevron, PTT Exploration,
Hess Corp. and other companies to explore as part of the
government's attempt to boost domestic output of natural gas
and oil. The country imports almost all of its crude oil and
about a third of natural gas. 
``Those companies should give more time to develop those
fields as they have done a very good job in exploration and
production,'' said Piyasvasti. ``There are significant amounts
of remaining natural gas reserves in those fields that need
additional investments to be developed.'' 
Chevron may invest $8 billion in the Southeast Asian
nation should the government extend its concessions for another
10 years, the Bangkok Post reported today, citing Songpop
Polachan, deputy director of the Mineral Fuels Department. 
Chevron is working with the department to extend
production period for Blocks 10 to 13 under the existing
concessions until 2022, Nicole Hodgson, Chevron's spokeswoman
in Bangkok, said in an e-mailed response to a question today.
Hodgson declined to comment on the report about Chevron's
investment plan, saying: ``Chevron does not release forward
looking investment figures by country.'' 
Chevron, the second-biggest U.S. oil company, had invested
$11.2 billion in gas and oil exploration and production in
Thailand between 1962 and 2005, according to the company's data. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Anuchit Nguyen in Bangkok at 
anguyen@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Tony Jordan at  tjordan3@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Mary Jane Credeur and Thomas Black" category="LATIN_AMERICA" date="Jul 18, 2007  5:00 PM ET" keywords="Coca-Cola Bottling Co Consolidated, Coca-Cola Co/The, Coca-Cola Enterprises Inc, Coca-Cola Femsa SAB de CV, Fomento Economico Mexicano SAB de CV, Alcoholic Beverages, Antitrust, Beverages, Consumer Goods, Containers, Emerging Markets, Georgia (U.S.), Industries, Latin America, Legal Affairs, Litigation, Mexico, North America, North Carolina, Packaging, Research, Retail, Rules and Regulations, U.S. South, U.S. Southeast, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-07-18/coca-cola-femsa-get-approval-to-buy-jugos-del-valle-update4-.html"><headline>Coca-Cola, Femsa Get Approval to Buy Jugos del Valle</headline><body>
Coca-Cola Co. (KO), the world's largest
soft-drink maker, and its Mexican bottler received antitrust
approval to buy a juice producer for $380 million with
conditions to encourage competition. 
Mexico's antitrust agency approved the purchase of Mexican
juice-maker Jugos del Valle SAB on the condition that Coca-Cola
and local bottler Coca-Cola Femsa SAB don't impose exclusivity
contracts on retailers or tie juice sales to soft-drink sales,
the regulator said in an e-mailed statement today. 
Coca-Cola and Coca-Cola Femsa agreed to buy Jugos del
Valle, Mexico's second-largest juice producer, in December to
boost non-carbonated drink sales in Latin America. The company
sells drinks under brands such as Frutsi and Bebere in Mexico
and Brazil. 
Antitrust regulators blocked the purchase in May, then
reversed themselves yesterday with the conditional approval
after the companies appealed. 
Coca-Cola owns 32 percent of Coca-Cola Femsa, which is a
unit of Fomento Economico Mexicano SA (FEMSAUBD), Latin America's largest
beverage company. 
The agency also limited exclusive sales to Fomento
Economico's OXXO stores and said refrigerators the companies
provide to small retailers must be able to display competing
drinks. The companies must also divest Jugos del Valle's soft-
drink brands, among other conditions. 
Separately today, Jugos del Valle said securities
regulators fined the company for failing to fully inform the
public during its sale to Coca-Cola and Coca-Cola Femsa. 
Mexico's National Banking and Securities Commission said
the company's statements to the stock exchange before the sale
were ``insufficient.'' The commission fined the company 1.9
million pesos ($176,540), Mexico City-based Jugos del Valle
said. 
Shares of Coca-Cola rose 26 cents to $53.43 at 4:01 p.m. in
New York Stock Exchange composite trading. They've gained 11
percent this year. Shares of Coca-Cola Femsa increased 68
centavos, or 1.3 percent, to 51.5 pesos in Mexico. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Mary Jane Credeur in Atlanta at 
mcredeur@bloomberg.net or
Thomas Black in Monterrey, Mexico at 
tblack@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Michael Nol at  mnol@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Mary Jane Credeur" category="RETAIL" date="Sep 14, 2007  4:13 PM ET" keywords="Coca-Cola Bottling Co Consolidated, Coca-Cola Co/The, Coca-Cola Enterprises Inc, Coca-Cola Femsa SAB de CV, Beverages, Consumer Goods, Containers, Emerging Markets, Food, Georgia (U.S.), Industries, Latin America, Mexico, New Products, North America, North Carolina, Packaging, Retail, Retailing, U.S. South, U.S. Southeast, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-09-14/coca-cola-will-sell-odwalla-juice-based-energy-drink-update3-.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Will Sell Odwalla Juice-Based Energy Drink</headline><body>
Coca-Cola Co. (KO), the world's largest
soda maker, will begin selling an energy drink under its Odwalla
juice line to capture more sales in the faster-growing market. 
The first variety of Odwalla Serious Energy is made with
pineapple, mango, guava and passion-fruit juices, Atlanta-based
Coca-Cola said today in an e-mailed statement. The 15.2-ounce
drinks will have a suggested retail price of $3.29. 
Coca-Cola is adding more juice and tea-based beverages to
woo consumers who have cut back on soda amid obesity concerns.
Coca-Cola's energy drink sales almost doubled last year, to 17.8
million cases, led by Full Throttle and Tab Energy, according to
data from industry journal Beverage Digest. 
The company's soft-drink sales have dropped for four
straight quarters in North America. Coca-Cola Classic, the top-
selling soda, posted a 2 percent drop in volume last year to
1.76 billion cases in the U.S., according to Beverage Digest. 
The Odwalla energy drink has extracts of guarana, yerba
mate, green tea and ginseng, which the company says help
increase alertness. Some of those ingredients have naturally
occurring caffeine, although no additional caffeine is added,
Coca-Cola spokesman Ray Crockett said. 
Most energy beverages, such as those made by Red Bull GmbH
as well as Hansen Natural Corp.'s Monster Energy, use caffeine
and guarana as stimulants. 
Coca-Cola rose 53 cents, or 1 percent, to $56.40 at 4:03
p.m. in New York Stock Exchange composite trading. The shares
have gained 17 percent this year. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Mary Jane Credeur in Atlanta at 
mcredeur@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Michael Nol at  mnol@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Nicole Ostrow" category="HEALTH_CARE" date="Oct 09, 2007  6:52 PM ET" keywords="Actavis plc, Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson, Merck KGaA, Chemicals, Consumer Goods, Consumer Products, Drugs, Euro Members, Europe, Germany, Health Care, Health Research, Household, Industries, Medical, Medical Technology, New Jersey, New York, North America, Pharmaceuticals, Retail, Science, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, U.S. Southeast, United States, Virginia" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-10-09/johnson-johnson-s-seizure-drug-may-fight-alcoholism-update1-.html"><headline>Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson's Seizure Drug May Fight Alcoholism</headline><body>
Johnson  Johnson (JNJ)'s seizure medicine
Topamax helped alcoholics cut their drinking, according to
research that may lead to a new approach to fighting the
addiction. 
The study, appearing in tomorrow's Journal of the American
Medical Association, found that Topamax, also approved in the
U.S. for the treatment of migraines, helped alcoholics reduce the
number of days they spent drinking heavily. 
Topamax isn't approved for use in alcoholics and Johnson 
Johnson said today it won't conduct further trials or seek U.S.
approval for the medicine for alcohol dependency. Still, Mark
Willenbring, a director at the National Institute on Alcohol
Abuse and Alcoholism in Bethesda, Maryland, said that won't stop
doctors from using the drug anyway, called ``off label''
prescribing. 
``We now have very high-quality evidence that shows
efficacy. The medical world doesn't wait for the indication,''
said Willenbring, who wrote an editorial that accompanies the
study, in a telephone interview today. ``Topamax is a drug that
many physicians have used and many patients have had an
experience with because of its use in migraines.'' 
About 18 million people in the U.S. have drinking problems.
Alcohol contributes to 100,000 deaths each year, making it the
third-leading cause of preventable death in the U.S. behind
smoking and obesity, according to the National Council on
Alcoholism and Drug Dependence. 
Brain Chemicals 
Topamax is thought to restore balance in the levels of
chemicals released in the brain that are affected by alcoholism,
said Bankole Johnson, a professor at the University of Virginia
in Charlottesville and the study's lead author, in an interview. 
``First, it reduces your craving for alcohol; second, it
reduces the amount of withdrawal symptoms you get when you start
reducing alcohol; and third, it reduces the potential for you to
relapse after you go down to a low level of drinking or zero
drinking,'' Johnson said. ``I wouldn't say it's a cure; I would
say it's a very big improvement over what we've had before. We
will continue working toward a cure.'' 
The company-sponsored study followed 371 men and women who
were heavy drinkers for 14 weeks. About half were given a
placebo. Results showed that 27 of 183 patients, or 15 percent,
taking Topamax quit drinking by the end of the study. That
compares with 6 participants, or 3.2 percent, of 188 given a
placebo. 
Less Heavy Drinking 
The study also found that those taking Topamax had an
average 8.4 percent fewer heavy drinking days than those given a
placebo. One drink is considered a 10-ounce beer (283.5 grams),
four ounces of wine or 1 ounce of 100-proof liquor. 
Study participants taking Topamax also had a higher rate of
achieving 20 or more days of continuous abstinence and 28 or more
days of continuous non-heavy drinking. 
Side effects of the drug included abnormal skin sensations,
distorted sense of taste, anorexia and difficulty with
concentration. 
Three drugs currently are approved in the U.S. to treat
alcoholism. They include naltrexone, which interrupts the high of
drinking, and disulfiram, which makes people sick when they
drink. Forest Laboratories Inc. (FRX) and Merck KGaA (MRK)'s Campral,
approved in the U.S. in July 2004, helps reduce the physical and
emotional discomfort felt in the weeks and months after a patient
stops drinking, making abstinence from alcohol easier. 
Willenbring with the National Institutes of Health said
research in this area should yield more medications to treat
alcoholism in the next five to 10 years. The institute is
sponsoring about 33 clinical trials of drugs that have potential
to treat alcoholism, he said. 
``There are many other medicines that are in the pipeline,''
he said. ``It's a very exciting time.'' 
Public Citizen 
Public Citizen, a Washington-based advocacy organization,
said the study showed an increased incidence of dizziness, injury
and difficulty concentrating among patients who consumed heavy
amounts of alcohol while taking Topamax, the group said in a
letter today to the Food and Drug Administration. 
Sidney Wolfe, director of the Health Research Group at
Public Citizen, urged the FDA to stop an ``illegal and dangerous
promotional campaign'' that he said was tied to the Johnson 
Johnson-sponsored study. 
``It is not the research or the publication of the study
that is illegal but the promotional material that goes beyond the
research to solicit new sales for the drug,'' Wolfe said in an e-mailed copy of the letter. 
`Off-Label' Use 
Johnson  Johnson said it won't support off-label use of its
drug, which may lose some patent protection next year. 
``We absolutely, positively don't support any reference to
off-label use of our products,'' said Kara Russell, a spokeswoman
for Johnson  Johnson's Ortho McNeil Neurologics division, in a
telephone interview today. ``We only promote the use of Topamax
for the approved indications of migraine prevention and
epilepsy.'' 
Doctors in the U.S. are free to prescribe any medicine they
feel would best treat a given condition, regardless of what the
label says. Drugmakers are prohibited from promoting medicines
for uses not approved by the Food and Drug Administration. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Nicole Ostrow in New York at 
nostrow1@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Robert Simison at  rsimison@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Pierre Paulden" category="EUROPE, US, BONDS, CORP_BONDS" date="Mar 10, 2008  4:22 PM ET" keywords="Blackstone Group LP/The, CIFC Corp, Citigroup Inc, Credit Suisse Group AG, Deutsche Bank AG, JPMorgan Chase &amp;amp; Co, Morgan Stanley, NexPoint Credit Strategies Fund, Royal Bank of Scotland Group PLC, Weibo Corp, iHeartMedia Inc, Asset-Backed Securities, Banking, Bonds, Buyout, CDOs-Collateralized Debt, Closed-End Funds, Commercial Services, Corporate Actions, Corporate Bonds, Corporate Bonds-New Issues, Corporate Finance, DAX Index, Entertainment, Euro Members, Europe, FTSE 100 Index, Financial Services, Germany, High-Yield Bonds, Industries, Loans &amp;amp; Financing, Markets, Media, Mergers &amp;amp; Acquisitions, Mutual &amp;amp; Hedge Funds, Mutual Funds, New Bonds, New York, North America, Private Equity, Radio, Real Estate, Scotland, Securities Firms, Switzerland, Syndicated Loans, Texas, Trusts, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, U.S. Southwest, United Kingdom, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-03-10/morgan-credit-suisse-break-ranks-on-clear-channel-update4-.html"><headline>Morgan, Credit Suisse Break Ranks on Clear Channel</headline><body>
Banks struggling to find buyers for
$131 billion of unsold loans that financed last year's leveraged
buyouts are starting to break ranks and hold individual
negotiations with investors. 
Instead of sticking together in a lending group, or
syndicate, Royal Bank of Scotland Group Plc, Morgan Stanley (MS) and
Credit Suisse Group have each sought buyers for their portion of
Clear Channel Communications Inc. (CCU)'s $22 billion buyout
financing, said people with knowledge of the situation. They
declined to be identified because the talks are private. 
Banks are under pressure to sell the loans after prices for
debt that paid for last year's record $438 billion of buyouts
fell 12 percent in the past seven months, according to Standard
 Poor's. Banks and securities firms have taken about $188
billion in writedowns and credit losses since the beginning of
2007, including reserves for bad loans, data compiled by
Bloomberg show. 
``It's reached a new stage of every man for himself,''
Martin Fridson, chief executive officer of high-yield research
firm FridsonVision LLC in New York, said in an interview.
``Banks worked hard until now to hold the line and keep the
gentlemen's agreement together.'' 
Jennifer Sala, a spokeswoman for New York-based Morgan
Stanley, declined comment. Peter Ward, a spokesman for RBS,
based in Edinburgh, didn't return calls seeking comment. Zurich-based Credit Suisse hasn't sold any of the Clear Channel debt
and plans to work with the syndicate, Tom Newberry, the bank's
global head of syndicated loans in New York, said in a telephone
interview. 
`Circled the Wagons' 
New York-based Citigroup Inc. (C) is leading the group. The
other banks include Deutsche Bank AG (DBK) of Frankfurt and Wachovia
Corp. (WB) in Charlotte, North Carolina. 
Credit Suisse, Switzerland's second-biggest bank, sold its
share of $7.25 billion of loans to Las Vegas-based casino
operator Harrah's Entertainment Inc. in December, before the
other banks, which then struggled to sell the debt, people with
knowledge of the situation said. 
``Up through recently, the banking community kind of
circled wagons and everybody was protecting their positions
because they were involved in the same'' loans, said Matthew Eagan, a money manager at Boston-based Loomis Sayles  Co.,
which oversees $130 billion of assets. ``What you didn't want
was somebody under-pricing you and hurting you.'' 
In syndicated loans, banks form a financing group. One or
two institutions typically take charge in finding buyers for
chunks of the loans, such as other banks, money managers and
hedge funds, at an agreed upon price. 
Buyout Frenzy 
Investor demand for riskier assets including high-yield
loans used to finance buyouts began to dry up in the second half
of last year as losses related to the collapse of the subprime
mortgage market spread. Banks were stuck with $163 billion of
the loans at the beginning of 2008, according to a Bank of
America Corp. report last week. 
Financial firms will likely see their credit-related losses
reach at least $600 billion, UBS AG analysts wrote in a report
dated Feb. 29. 
Loans trade at an average price of 89.02 cents on the
dollar, down from 100 cents in July, according to SP data.
High-yield, or leveraged, loans are rated below BBB- by SP and
Baa3 by Moody's Investors Service. 
`Steady Decline' 
``It's been a reasonably steady decline in market
conditions,'' Blackstone President Hamilton James said on a
conference call today. The publicly traded buyout firm raised a
$1.4 billion fund to invest in loans stuck on bank balance sheets
last November. The firm still has ``100 percent dry powder'' and
expects conditions to get worse before improving, James said. 
``Temptation is growing. Some time in the next 90 days
might be the time to do something significant,'' he said on a
separate call with investors today. 
San Antonio-based Clear Channel, the largest U.S. radio
broadcaster, is being bought for $19.5 billion by private-equity
firms Bain Capital LLC and Thomas H. Lee Partners LP, both
located in Boston. 
The banks financing the deal agreed in April to provide $22
billion in debt. Banks will extend about $19.5 billion in bank
loans at the London interbank offered rate plus as much as 3.25
percentage points. The premium over Libor (US0003M) has since widened to
about 6.65 percentage points, according to SP, meaning the
banks must sell the Clear Channel loans at a discount to reflect
the wider spreads and current prices. Three-month Libor was 2.94
percent last week. 
Betrayal 
Clear Channel fell 18 cents to $33.96 in New York Stock
Exchange composite trading today. The shares have climbed 18
percent over the past month as more investors bet the deal would
be completed. The buyout firms agreed to pay $39.20 a share. 
The decision by the banks to approach investors separately
probably means they will be able to buy the loans cheaper. 
``From an investor viewpoint, they are unlikely to be upset
about banks betraying one another, because investors feel they
were treated shabbily by the banks all through the bull
period,'' Fridson said. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Pierre Paulden in New York at 
ppaulden@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Emma Moody at 
emoody@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Fabio Alves" category="US, STOCKS" date="Mar 14, 2008  4:51 PM ET" keywords="ANN INC, American Express Co, Bank of America Corp, Boeing Co/The, Cenveo Inc, Citigroup Inc, Diodes Inc, FLIR Systems Inc, GameStop Corp, Gannett Co Inc, General Motors Co, JPMorgan Chase &amp;amp; Co, Microsoft Corp, MoneyGram International Inc, Mylan Inc/PA, Newcastle Investment Corp, PNC Financial Services Group Inc/The, Shire PLC, Syncora Holdings Ltd, Universal Display Corp, Waste Management Inc, Zumiez Inc, Aerospace, Apparel, Automobiles, Banking, Bonds, California, Charge Cards, Closing Market Comments, Clothing, Colorado, Commercial Services, Computer Games, Computer Software, Computers, Consumer Goods, Credit Cards, Defense, Drugs, Drugstores, Education, Electrical Equipment, Electronics, Equity Movers, Europe, FTSE 100 Index, Financial Services, Footwear, Health Care, Illinois, Industries, Insurance, Internet, Markets, Massachusetts, Media, Michigan, New Jersey, New York, North America, North Carolina, Ohio, Pennsylvania, Pharmaceuticals, Publishing, Real Estate, Real Estate Investment Trust, Retail, Retailing, Savings &amp;amp; Loans, Securities Firms, Semiconductors, Shoes, Sporting Goods, Stock Markets by Country, Subprime Lending, Technology, Texas, Transportation, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, U.S. Midwest, U.S. Northeast, U.S. Pacific Northwest, U.S. South, U.S. Southeast, U.S. Southwest, U.S. Stock Market Comment, U.S. West, United Kingdom, United States, Video, Virginia, Washington State" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-03-14/general-motors-microsoft-mylan-talbots-u-s-equity-movers.html"><headline>General Motors, Microsoft, Mylan, Talbots: U.S. Equity Movers</headline><body>
The following is a list of companies
whose shares had unusual price changes in U.S. markets. Stock
symbols are in parentheses after company names, and prices are as
of 4 p.m. in New York. 
Advance America Cash Advance Centers Inc. (AEA US) dropped 16
percent to $5.98, the lowest since December 2004. The provider of
short-term loans to individuals was reduced to ``equalweight'' from
``overweight'' by analyst Dennis Telzrow at Stephens Inc. 
Allion Healhcare Inc. (ALLI US) fell for the first time in
four days, sinking 3.8 percent to $5.31. The pharmacy operator
signed a definitive agreement to buy Biomed America Inc, which
provides specialized biopharmaceutical medications and services to
chronically ill patients. Melville, New York-based Allion said in a
statement after the market closed yesterday it will pay $117.8
million for Biomed. The price includes $48 million of cash as well
an offering of common and preferred shares. The company will also
assume as much as $18.6 million of Biomed's debt. 
 AnnTaylor Stores Corp. (ANN)  declined the most since Jan.
10, sliding 8.2 percent to $21.95. The clothing retailer geared
toward women 25 to 55 forecast profit of 35 cents to 40 cents a
share in the first quarter. That missed the average estimate of 42
cents, according to a Bloomberg survey of analysts. 
Bear Stearns Cos. (BSC US) had its biggest drop since its
initial public offering in October 1985, falling 47 percent to $30.
The securities firm, to which JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)  and the
New York Federal Reserve agreed to provide funding, said its cash
position has ``significantly deteriorated.'' 
Other financial shares also tumbled. JPMorgan dropped 4.1
percent to $36.54. American Express Co. (AXP)  retreated 4
percent to $40.01. Bank of America Corp. (BAC US) declined 3.9
percent to $35.69. Citigroup Inc. (C US) slipped 6.1 percent to
$19.78. Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. (LEH US) fell 15 percent, the
most since April 2000, to $39.20. 
Boeing Co. (BA)  had the only gain in the Dow Jones
Industrial Average, climbing 2.7 percent to $76.23. The world's
second-largest commercial-aircraft maker was raised to
``overweight'' from ``equal weight'' at Morgan Stanley, which said
the Chicago-based company may win 600 aircraft orders this year. 
 Cenveo Inc. (CVO)  dropped the most since May 2003, sliding
16 percent to $11.53. The Stamford, Connecticut-based commercial
printer reported revenue of $584.4 million in the fourth quarter.
That trailed the average estimate of $596.5 million from analysts
in a Bloomberg survey. 
Diodes Inc. (DIOD)  fell 8.3 percent to $20.22, the lowest
since December 2005. The maker of electronic components used in
computers and DVD players lowered its first-quarter revenue
forecast, predicting the slowest growth in six years. 
DynCorp International Inc. (DCP US) gained the most since
Feb.19, adding 8.8. percent to $16.85. The provider of security
guards in Iraq said it's resuming work on a $4.6 billion contract
to provide translation services for the U.S. Army after a protest
by losing bidder L-3 Communications Holdings Inc. (LLL US) was
withdrawn. 
GameStop Corp. (GME)  gained 4 percent to $49.05, the
biggest advance in the Standard  Poor's 500 Index. Credit Suisse
Group analyst Gary Balter reiterated his ``outperform'' rating for
the world's largest video-game retailer, saying that he expects a
``strong'' first quarter on accelerating software growth. Gamestop,
which is reporting fourth-quarter results on March 18, may say it
earned $1.12 a share, according to Bloomberg estimates. 
Gannett Co. (GCI)  dropped 5.1 percent to $28.43, the lowest
since November 1995. The largest U.S. newspaper company said pro
forma revenue fell 7.2 percent last month as classified advertising
sales declined. 
General Motors Corp. (GM) (GM US) tumbled 5.4 percent to $19.22,
the lowest since April 2006. The world's biggest automaker is
recalling 208,000 Buick Regal and Pontiac Grand Prix sedans because
of oil leaks that may lead to engine fires, Carolyn Markey, a
spokeswoman for Detroit-based GM, said in an interview today. 
ICx Technologies Inc. (ICXT US) dropped the most since its
Nov. 7 initial public offering, sliding 30 percent to $4.39. The
developer of technology to detect chemical and explosive materials
was cut to ``market perform'' from ``outperform'' by analyst Brian W. Ruttenbur at Morgan Keegan. 
MoneyGram International Inc. (MGI)  slipped 15 percent to
$2, the lowest ever. The money-transfer company's debt rating was
cut by the Standard  Poor's. An additional downgrade is possible,
SP said. 
Microsoft Corp. (MSFT)  lost the most since Feb. 29,
retreating 2.3 percent to $27.96. The world's biggest software
maker said it agreed to buy Rapt Inc., which helps clients such as
Expedia Inc. and CNET Networks Inc. place and sell ads and examine
their performance. Microsoft didn't disclose the terms of the deal
for closely held Rapt, based in San Francisco. 
Mylan Inc. (MYL)  gained the most since Jan. 9, adding 3.6
percent to $11.07. Citigroup Inc. (C) raised its recommendation on the
largest U.S. maker of generic drugs to ``buy'' from ``hold.'' 
National City Corp. (NCC US) fell 12 percent to $13.15, the
most since January 1984. The largest bank in Ohio had its debt
rating cut by Moody's Investors Service, which cited the company's
``sizable exposure'' to the U.S. housing market and possible
``material losses'' as a result. 
NDS Group Plc (NNDS US) gained the most since Feb. 13,
advancing 5.4 percent to $49.30. The company, whose technology
enables access to pay-television services, was raised to ``buy'' by
Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and added to the firm's ``conviction buy''
list. 
 Newcastle Investment Corp. (NCT)  slumped the most since
October 2002, falling 16 percent to $8.86. The New York-based real
estate investment trust cut its dividend by almost two-thirds to 25
cents a share. 
Security Capital Assurance Ltd. (SCA US) surged the most since
Jan. 23, rising 20 percent to 79 cents. The company, stripped of
its AAA bond insurer ratings, said it's trying to cancel insurance
it wrote on $3.1 billion of collateralized debt obligations. 
Shire Plc (SHP) American depositary receipts (SHPGY US) climbed 2.9
percent to $58.96, the biggest gain since Feb.22. The U.K.'s third-largest drugmaker climbed on speculation it's the target of a 1,300
pence-a-share bid by Pfizer Inc., the world's biggest
pharmaceutical company. 
SkillSoft Plc (SKIL US) rose the most since Nov. 26, climbing
13 percent to $9.84. The maker of employee training software
forecast full-year revenue of $328 million to $336 million. Five
analysts estimated $319.6 million, on average, in a Bloomberg
survey. 
Talbots Inc. (TLB US) advanced to the highest since Jan. 3,
rising 8.3 percent to $9.93. The women's clothing store chain named
Lori Wagner as executive vice president and chief marketing
officer, in a statement today. Wagner joined Talbot from Cole Haan,
a division of Nike Inc. 
Universal Display Corp. (OLED)  lost 12 percent to $14.83,
the lowest since Sept. 7. The developer of technologies used in
flat-panels reported fourth-quarter loss of 9 cents a share,
trailing analysts' estimates by 25 percent, according to Bloomberg
data. 
Washington Mutual Inc. (WM)  fell the most since Nov. 7,
losing 13 percent to $10.59. The largest U.S. savings and loan had
its senior unsecured credit rating cut to Baa3 from Baa2 by Moody's
Investors Service because of the weakening housing market. 
Zumiez Inc. (ZUMZ)  gained the most since Feb. 7, adding 8.1
percent to $15.24. The specialty sports apparel and accessories
retailer said it earned 42 cents a share in the fourth quarter.
That beat the 38-cent average estimate from analysts in a Bloomberg
survey. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Fabio Alves in New York at 
falves3@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Chris Nagi at  chrisnagi@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Pierre Paulden" category="BONDS, CORP_BONDS" date="Mar 19, 2008  4:20 PM ET" keywords="BCE Inc, Bank of America Corp, Blackstone Group LP/The, Citigroup Inc, Goldman Sachs Group Inc/The, JPMorgan Chase &amp;amp; Co, KKR &amp;amp; Co LP, Morgan Stanley, NexPoint Credit Strategies Fund, iHeartMedia Inc, Asset-Backed Securities, Banking, Bonds, Buyout, CDOs-Collateralized Debt, Closed-End Funds, Commercial Services, Corporate Actions, Corporate Bonds, Corporate Bonds-New Issues, Corporate Finance, Entertainment, Financial Services, High-Yield Bonds, Industries, Loans &amp;amp; Financing, Markets, Media, Mergers &amp;amp; Acquisitions, Mutual &amp;amp; Hedge Funds, Mutual Funds, New Bonds, New York, North America, North Carolina, Private Equity, Radio, Securities Firms, Syndicated Loans, Texas, Trusts, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, U.S. South, U.S. Southeast, U.S. Southwest, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-03-19/goldman-lehman-reduce-loan-backlog-with-discounts-update2-.html"><headline>Goldman, Lehman Reduce Loan Backlog With Discounts</headline><body>
U.S. banks from Goldman Sachs (GS) Group
Inc. to Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. have whittled their
holdings of leveraged buyout loans to $129 billion from $163
billion at the beginning of the year by offering the debt at
discounts, according to analysts at Bank of America Corp. (BAC) 
The decline is a ``ray of hope'' for banks amid a slump in
credit markets and a slowing economy, said analysts led by
Jeffrey Rosenberg. The firms also have $73.6 billion of high-yield bonds they need to sell, they said. 
Banks have been breaking ranks from their lending groups and
offering their own pieces of the LBO loans at as little as 80
cents on the dollar to get the debt off their books. New York-based Lehman yesterday said it has reduced its LBO backlog by
$6.1 billion to $17.8 billion since the beginning of the year.
Goldman Sachs halved its holdings to $20 billion and Morgan
Stanley (MS) reduced its pipeline by 20 percent. 
The buyout industry, including Blackstone Group (BX), Apollo
Management LP and Kohlberg, Kravis Roberts  Co. (KKR), all based in
New York, negotiated more than $370 billion in financing to back
acquisitions such as the $32 billion purchase of Texas power
producer TXU Corp. and the $46.8 billion sale of Canadian
telecommunications company BCE Inc. (BCE) to an investor group led by
the Ontario Teachers Pension Plan, the largest buyout ever. 
Plunging Demand 
Investor demand for the debt plummeted in July as losses on
U.S. subprime securities spread to other asset classes. The
average price of a leveraged loan fell from par to a record low
of 86.28 last month, according to Standard  Poor's data. Prices
have since climbed to 87.32 cents on the dollar. 
Banks began tackling the backlog in September, when lenders
for KKR sold $9.4 billion of loans at a discount of up to 4
percent for its takeover of Greenwood Village, Colorado-based
First Data Corp., the biggest processor of credit card payments. 
Goldman, the world's biggest securities firm by market
value, is selling its portion of Chrysler LLC's $7 billion in
loans for as little as 72 cents on the dollar, said investors,
who declined to be identified because the terms are private.
Goldman spokesman Michael DuVally declined to comment on
individual sales. 
Cerberus Capital Management LP bought Chrysler Group LLC
last August. Bankers for the Auburn Hills, Michigan-based
automaker twice failed to sell the Chrysler loans. JPMorgan Chase
 Co. (JPM), Citigroup, Morgan Stanley, Bear Stearns Cos. and Goldman,
all of New York, tried in November to sell $4 billion of the
loans at 97.5 cents on the dollar. 
The loan is priced at 400 basis points more than the three-month London interbank offered rate, or Libor (US0003M), a borrowing
benchmark. Three-month Libor is 2.6 percent. A basis point is
0.01 percentage point. 
Backlogs Reduced 
Goldman reduced its backlog of loans by $20 billion in the
past quarter from $43 billion, chief financial officer David Viniar said on an investor call yesterday. The New York-based
firm, which booked a loss of $1 billion on the loans, also added
$4 billion of new commitments during the period. 
Lehman, the fourth-biggest U.S. securities firm, booked
losses of $500 million on leveraged loans last quarter, CFO Erin Callan said on a conference call with investors yesterday. 
Morgan Stanley, the second-biggest U.S. securities firm,
reduced its leveraged finance pipeline to $16 billion from $20
billion during the first quarter, CFO Colm Kelleher said in an
interview today after the company reported first-quarter profit
fell 42 percent. 
Royal Bank of Scotland Group Plc, Morgan Stanley and Credit
Suisse Group have each sought buyers for their portion of Clear
Channel Communications Inc.'s $22 billion buyout financing, said
people with knowledge of the situation. 
LBO Buyers 
Some of the same LBO firms that generated the debt in the
first place are raising funds to buy it back at reduced prices.
Blackstone raised a $1.4 billion fund last November to buy bank
loans, and Leon Black's Apollo  has bought $1 billion of
distressed loans and bonds. 
``The leveraged loan forward calendar continues to
decline,'' Rosenberg wrote in the report on March 17. ``The
ongoing raising of distressed debt funds,'' including Apollo's,
``appears to support these efforts.'' 
In addition to the buyout firms, traditional loan investors
and hedge funds are also buying the debt. 
Dallas-based Highland Capital Management LP has raised $1
billion in the past four months from pension funds and sovereign
wealth funds, to invest in debt, including bank loans, according
to Mark Okada, co-founder and chief investment officer. 
``We are more willing to participate in new issues at these
distressed prices,'' said Scott D'Orsi, a partner at Boston-based
Feingold O'Keeffe Capital, which has $1.25 billion in assets.
``It's been a waiting game between the buy side and the banks
over the past several months, with pricing moving in favor of
investors.'' 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Pierre Paulden in New York at 
ppaulden@bloomberg.net; 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Emma Moody at 
emoody@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Michael Quint" category="MUNICIPAL_BONDS, FINANCE" date="Mar 24, 2008  9:40 AM ET" keywords="Citigroup Inc, Goldman Sachs Group Inc/The, Arizona, Auction Rate Securities, Banking, Best of the Web, Bonds, Electricity Generation, Energy, Financial Services, Industries, Markets, Municipal Bonds, New York, North America, Ratings, Securities Firms, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, U.S. Southwest, United States, Utilities" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-03-24/goldman-citi-get-fees-for-failed-auction-rate-bonds-update1-.html"><headline>Goldman, Citi Get Fees for Failed Auction-Rate Bonds</headline><body>
New York paid 10 securities firms
more than $600,000 since mid-February to handle bids for
auction-bonds even though the sales failed, saddling the state
with penalty interest rates. 
Citigroup Inc. (C), Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and eight more
firms receive $10 million a year to oversee periodic bidding
that sets rates on about $4 billion of auction bonds. When there
aren't enough buyers, the yields rise. A total of 188 of the
state's 201 auctions since Feb. 12 have failed, according to
data supplied by the state. 
``We are contractually obligated to pay these fees
regardless of whether the auction fails, and we will fulfill our
commitment,'' Matt Anderson, a spokesman for New York's Division
of Budget said in an e-mailed statement. 
State and local governments pay almost $8 million a week in
fees to banks for auctions-rate bonds, based on standard fees.
About two-thirds of auctions in the $330 billion market have
failed since mid-February, including periodic sales of preferred
stock for closed-end bond funds, Bloomberg data show. Securities
firms are receiving the same fee even when investors who wanted
to sell are unable to do so because bankers haven't found enough
bidders. 
`Systemic Problems' 
Banks covered shortfalls in demand at auctions in the $330
billion market buy purchasing bonds for their own account, even
though they weren't obliged to. They didn't tell investors or
issuers about the extent of the activity, which was one of the
practices cited by the Securities and Exchange Commission in
2006 when it fined 15 banks a total of $13 million for bid-rigging. 
New York isn't trying to renegotiate the contracts with the
10 broker-dealers it uses for auction bonds, Anderson said. The
firms also include Bank of America Corp., Wachovia Corp., UBS
AG, JPMorgan Chase  Co., Merrill Lynch  Co., Bear Stearns Cos.
Morgan Stanley and Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. 
``These failed auctions were not caused by these banks, but
by systemic problems within this market beyond their control,''
he said. 
A spokeswoman for New York-based Citigroup, Danielle Romero-Apsilos, declined to comment, as did Michael DuVally, a
spokesman for New York-based Goldman. Citigroup was the biggest
underwriter of auction-rate debt from 2000 to 2007, according to
Thomson Financial. Goldman is the most profitable investment
bank. 
Higher Rates 
When there aren't enough bidders in auctions that typically
take place every seven, 28 or 35 days, rates get set by formulas
spelled out when the debt is issued. In New York, the penalty
rates ranged from 3.59 percent to 5.64 percent in the week ended
March 14. That compares with yields on the variable-rate demand
bonds, an alternative to auction-rate notes, that were less than
3 percent for 27 of 43 issues, according to state data. 
Seven-day auction rates averaged 4.36 percent on March 19
for borrowers in New York, New Jersey, California and
Massachusetts, up from 3.47 percent on Feb. 6, the last week
before New York auctions began failing, according to index data
published by the Securities Industry and Financial Markets
Association. The rate peaked at 5.98 percent March 5. 
Before the failures, auction-rate bonds were a way to sell
long-term bonds at money market rates. They were the least
expensive kind of borrowing for New York until demand began to
weaken in September, according to a state report. 
Bank Contracts 
Anderson said copies of the contracts with banks handling
the auction bonds weren't available. Anderson and Ronald
Greenberg, a first deputy director of the budget, said state
officials are in daily contact with bankers about auction bonds.
He declined to respond to questions about the shortage of
bidders since Feb. 12. 
``Contracts for handling auctions are written by broker
dealers and presented to issuers as part of a negotiated
transaction,'' said Joseph Fichera, chief executive officer of
Saber Partners, a New York based adviser to companies and
governments. ``They can be terminated or renegotiated, like any
contract.'' 
Fichera, a financial adviser to the New York State
Dormitory Authority, declined to comment on the state's bonds. 
There is precedent for broker-dealer agreements that don't
pay banks a fee when auctions fail. 
After auctions failed to attract enough bidders in 1990 for
bonds of Tucson Electric Power Co., now a unit of Unisource
Energy Corp. (UNS), Fichera arranged a new contract that rewarded
bankers with a higher fee for selling bonds that resulted in a
lower auction rate, and no fee if bonds sold at the highest
permitted rate. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Michael Quint in Albany, New York, at 
mquint@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Robert Burgess at 
bburgess@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Shannon D. Harrington" category="BONDS" date="Apr 10, 2008  3:49 PM ET" keywords="AT&amp;amp;T Inc, Bank of America Corp, CIT Group Inc, Goldman Sachs Group Inc/The, JPMorgan Chase &amp;amp; Co, Asset-Backed Securities, Banking, Bonds, Buyout, CDOs-Collateralized Debt, Corporate Actions, Corporate Bonds, Corporate Finance, Country, Credit Default Swaps, Derivatives, Derivs, Europe, Financial Services, Hedge Funds, Industries, Loans &amp;amp; Financing, Markets, Mergers &amp;amp; Acquisitions, Mutual &amp;amp; Hedge Funds, New York, North America, North America Bonds, Private Equity, Regional Bond Mkts, Securities Firms, Swaps, Technology, Telecom Equipment, Telecom Services, Texas, Trusts, U.S. Bonds, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, U.S. Southwest, United Kingdom, United States, Wireless Communications" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-04-10/goldman-merrill-debt-risk-rises-on-concern-losses-may-increase.html"><headline>Goldman, Merrill Debt Risk Rises on Concern Losses May Increase</headline><body>
The cost to protect the debt of
banks and securities firms from default rose for a third day amid
renewed concern that losses will increase after declining asset
values forced Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. to bail out five
funds. 
Credit-default swaps tied to Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS),
Merrill Lynch  Co. and Lehman Brothers reached the highest
levels since the start of the month, signaling a decline in
investor confidence. Benchmark credit indexes in the U.S. and
Europe rose earlier today, before falling back to little changed
as stocks in the U.S. rallied. 
Lehman took $1.8 billion in assets from five of its short-term debt funds onto its balance sheet last quarter after
``market disruptions.'' Goldman, the most profitable securities
firm, late yesterday reported a 39 percent increase in hard-to-value assets, and some analysts have scrapped their earnings
estimates for Merrill Lynch and are now predicting a first-quarter loss. 
``When the banks report in the next couple of weeks, there's
going to be a reminder to a lot of investors that there's more
damage to balance sheets beyond structured finance, beyond
leveraged finance,'' said Ricardo Kleinbaum, a credit analyst at
BNP Paribas in New York. ``It's extending to a broader range of
credit classes.'' 
Credit-default swaps on Goldman climbed 8 basis points to
133 basis points, Phoenix prices show. They earlier reached
140 basis points, the highest since March 31. Lehman contracts
climbed 17 basis points to 212 and traded as high as 217, Phoenix
prices show. New York-based Merrill, which is scheduled to report
earnings April 17, rose 15 basis points to 200. 
$245 Billion 
Credit-default swaps, financial instruments based on bonds
or loans, were conceived to protect bondholders by paying the
buyer face value in exchange for the underlying securities should
the borrower default. A decrease in the price indicates improving
perceptions of credit quality, an increase shows deterioration. 
The world's largest banks and securities firms have reported
$245 billion of asset writedowns and credit losses amid record
home foreclosures and a loss of investor confidence in so-called
structured securities linked to home loans. The housing turmoil
triggered a collapse of the subprime mortgage market and spread
to debt once considered among the safest, including commercial
paper backed by assets such as mortgage securities. 
Goldman Chief Executive Officer Lloyd Blankfein told
investors today that the credit crisis is nearing an end. 
``We're closer to the end than the beginning,'' Blankfein,
53, said today at the company's annual shareholder meeting in New
York. ``We're maybe at the end of the third quarter, or the
beginning of the fourth.'' 
Money-Market Funds 
New York-based Lehman, the fourth-biggest securities firm,
recorded a $300 million loss from the bailout of five short-term
debt funds, according to a person familiar with the writedown.
Lehman's actions followed a $780 million charge by Credit Suisse
Group in February after the Zurich-based firm bought assets from
its money-market funds that had fallen in value because of a
freeze in some commercial paper markets. 
Bank of America Corp. (BAC) and Legg Mason Inc. also have propped
up money-market funds and General Electric Co.'s GE Asset
Management liquidated a short-term bond fund in November after it
lost about $225 million. 
Most of the funds held commercial paper and medium-term
notes issued by structured investment vehicles, which were shut
out of debt markets last year amid concern that some of them
bought securities linked to subprime mortgages. 
Goldman, also based in New York, disclosed in a regulatory
filing yesterday that its so-called Level 3 assets, those hardest
to value, jumped to $96.4 billion at the end of February, with
the ratio to total assets rising to 8.1 percent from 6.2 percent. 
Asian Markets 
``Investors don't like the uncertainty that it brings to
balance sheets,'' said Mark Bayley, director of credit and
structuring at ABN Amro Holding NV in Sydney. ``It indicates a
deterioration of liquidity and transparency in the markets.'' 
Credit-default swaps on the Markit CDX North America
Investment Grade Index, linked to the debt of 125 companies in
the U.S. and Canada, fell 2 basis point to 122 basis points as of
2:59 p.m. in New York, according to Phoenix Partners. The index
earlier reached 130 basis points, the widest since April 1. The
Markit iTraxx Europe index fell 0.5 basis point to 104.5 basis
points in London, according to JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) 
In Asia, the Markit iTraxx Japan index rose 16 basis points
to 120 basis points, according to Morgan Stanley. The benchmark
gauge of credit risk has erased almost half its decline this
month. 
Bear Stearns 
The iTraxx and CDX indexes reached record highs last month
after a cash squeeze at Bear Stearns Cos., the fifth-biggest U.S.
securities firm, prompted the Federal Reserve to back an
emergency sale of the firm to JPMorgan Chase  Co. 
The Fed's intervention in the Bear Stearns crisis on March
14, and its creation of a new lending facility designed to
prevent other banks from collapsing, eased investor concern and
sent credit-default swaps plunging from their record highs. The
North American investment-grade index reached a record 198.5
basis points on March 14, according to CMA Datavision in London. 
``I think we're going to settle into a range here for a
little bit; the market needs to figure out what it wants to do
next,'' said Ashish Shah, head of credit strategy at Lehman
Brothers in New York. ``The good news is that you are going
through the de-levering process as banks and brokers try to shed
assets they don't want and continue to raise capital.'' 
To contact the reporters on this story:
Shannon D. Harrington in New York at 
sharrington6@bloomberg.net; 
To contact the editors responsible for this story:
Emma Moody at 
emoody@bloomberg.net; 
</body></entry><entry author="By Kyunghee Park" category="MANUFACTURING" date="Jun 06, 2008  6:41 AM ET" keywords="Ford Motor Co, Johnson Electric Holdings Ltd, Asia, Asia Industrial Reporting, Asia ex. Japan, Australia, Automobiles, Brazil, China, Commodities, Copper, Earnings, Electrical Equipment, Electronics, Emerging Markets, Europe, Health Care, Health Research, Hong Kong, India, Industries, Korea, Machinery, Manufacturing, Markets, Medical, Medical Technology, Metals, Non-Ferrous Metals, North America, Pacific Rim, Russia, Specialized Regions, Steel, Taiwan, Technology, Transportation, United States, ex-Energy" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-06-06/johnson-electric-full-year-profit-climbs-19-percent-update1-.html"><headline>Johnson Electric Full-Year Profit Climbs 19 Percent</headline><body>
Johnson Electric Holdings Ltd. (179), the
Hong Kong-based maker of electric motors for automakers including
Ford Motor Co. (F), said full-year profit rose 19 percent on demand
for its products in North America and China. 
Net income climbed to $130.8 million, or 3.57 cents per
share, in the year ended March 31, from $109.7 million, or 2.99
cents, a year earlier, the company said in a Hong Kong stock
exchange filing today. Sales rose 6 percent to $2.22 billion. 
Johnson Electric said it has relocated plants to China to
cuts costs, ``strengthened'' technologies and closed some ``non-core'' businesses. It expects sales to grow 5 percent to 7
percent in the fiscal year ending March 2009. 
``Growth in emerging economies remains extremely robust,
partially cushioning global manufacturers from weaker domestic
demand,'' Johnson Electric said in the statement. ``In coming
years, we plan to increase our focus on and direct resources
towards rapidly developing countries such as Brazil and Russia.'' 
European sales rose 10 percent, those in North America
climbed 3.8 percent and those in Asia rose 3.4 percent. 
Johnson Electric, controlled by the family of Chairman
Patrick Wang declined 8.4 percent this year in Hong Kong trading,
compared with the 12 percent drop in the benchmark Hang Seng
Index. The stock rose 0.5 percent to HK$3.92 today, before the
earnings announcement. 
The company will pay a final dividend of 1.25 cents per
share, an increase from 1.09 cents a year earlier. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Kyunghee Park in Hong Kong at 
kpark3@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Teo Chian Wei at  cwteo@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Andy Fixmer" category="US, RETAIL" date="Jun 27, 2008  4:04 PM ET" keywords="Walt Disney Co/The, California, Cinema, Entertainment, Group of 10 Member Countries, Industries, Leisure, Media, Movies, North America, Publishing, U.S. West, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-06-27/disney-s-wall-e-garbage-robot-may-spur-u-s-sales-update2-.html"><headline>Disney's `Wall-E,' Garbage Robot, May Spur U.S. Sales</headline><body>
``Wall-E,'' the movie about a trash-compacting robot, may end a slide in U.S. box-office sales for
Walt Disney Co. (DIS) and its Pixar animation studio. 
The film, opening in about 4,000 theaters today, probably
will exceed Pixar's 2007 release ``Ratatouille,'' which garnered
$47 million in its first weekend, according to Steve Mason, an
analyst in Los Angeles at FantasyMoguls.com, a box-office Web
site. He estimated weekend sales of $55 million. 
Disney, which bought Pixar in 2006, needs a hit to climb
from last place among the largest studios in 2008 U.S. sales.
``The Chronicles of Narnia: Prince Caspian'' missed Box Office
Mojo LLC's $86.9 million estimate last month, taking in $55
million in its opening weekend. Through June 22, Disney's
domestic ticket sales dropped 36 percent to $457.4 million,
according to the Burbank, California-based film tracker. 
```Wall-E' translates well around the world because of the
physical comedy and emotional aspects,'' Mark Zoradi, president
of Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures Group, said in an
interview. ``Nothing binds it to the United States. It's a
creative project that will work in 100 countries around the
world.'' 
The movie from ``Finding Nemo'' creator Andrew Stanton
follows Wall-E, short for Waste Allocation Load Lifter Earth-Class, who clears garbage left by humans who fled the planet to
live on space ships. He falls in love with another robot, Eve,
the Extra-terrestrial Vegetation Evaluator sent to Earth to look
for signs of life. 
`Love Story' 
The film may take in as much as $210 million in ticket
sales during its U.S. run, said David Joyce, an analyst at
Miller Tabak  Co. in New York, who recommends shares of
Burbank, California-based Disney and doesn't own them. That
would pass the $206 million of ``Ratatouille,'' according to
Internet Movie Database Inc., a unit of Amazon.com Inc. that
provides film data. 
```Wall-E' boasts the best love story I've seen in 2008,''
said Gitesh Pandya, editor of industry newsletter
BoxOfficeGuru.com in New York. ``Word of mouth will be terrific
with all ages and this will last a long time.'' 
Disney, the second-largest U.S. media company, rose 4 cents
to $31.57 at 4 p.m. in New York Stock Exchange composite
trading. The shares have slipped 2.2 percent this year, compared
with a 13 percent drop in the SP 500 Index. 
2003 Peak 
Since 2003's ``Finding Nemo,'' the No. 2 animated film of
all time according to Box Office Mojo, each Pixar release has
produced lower U.S. box-office sales, a benchmark for subsequent
sales of DVDs and television revenue. 
``U.S. box office is the most important factor in
anticipating all the other ancillary revenue streams,'' said
David Davis, founder of Arpeggio Partners LLC, a Santa Monica,
California-based consultant to Hollywood studios. ``It's not the
only factor, but it's the best indicator.'' 
U.S. box-office sales for Pixar, which Disney bought for
$8.06 billion, peaked in 2003 with ``Finding Nemo,'' which was
produced for $94 million and took in $340 million, according to
Internet Movie Database. ``Ratatouille'' cost $150 million,
while ``Wall-E'' cost $120 million, IMDB said. 
``The jury is still out'' on the Pixar purchase, said Tuna Amobi, an analyst at Standard  Poor's in New York who
recommends Disney shares and doesn't own them. ``It was a hefty
price, no doubt about it. Disney is looking at it as a marathon,
not a sprint.'' 
Fewer Films 
Since buying Pixar, Disney has cut film production overall,
betting it could boost profit by making fewer, more popular
movies. Last year, filmed entertainment generated profit of $1.2
billion, a sixfold increase over two years, on slightly lower
sales of $7.49 billion. 
The company produced 13 films last year, down from 17 in
2005, and will release 11 in 2008. 
This year is proving tougher. Through the first half of
fiscal 2008, studio profit rose 6.5 percent to $891 million,
while sales gained 6.7 percent to $4.46 billion. For the year
ending in September, the unit's profit is likely to fall 1
percent to $1.19 billion, as sales dip 1.8 percent to $7.36
billion, according to Michael Nathanson, an analyst with Sanford
C. Bernstein  Co. in New York. 
Robert Iger, Disney's chief executive officer, said last
month at an investor conference that Hollywood makes too many
movies. 
``It shouldn't surprise anybody in the business why there
is so much failure and why the returns on investment are so
modest,'' Iger said. 
The following table ranks Pixar movies by their worldwide
box-office sales. Figures are in millions of dollars. 

Movie          Year      Budget      U.S.        Worldwide
                                    Total         Total
Finding Nemo   2003       $94       $340          $865
Incredibles    2004        92        261           631
Ratatouille    2007       150        206           621
Monsters Inc.  2001       115        256           525
Toy Story 2    1999        90        246           485
Cars           2006       120        244           462
Bug's Life     1998        45        163           363
Toy Story      1995        30        192           362

Sources: Internet Movie Database Inc., Box Office Mojo LLC

To contact the reporter on this story:
Andy Fixmer in Los Angeles at 
afixmer@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Jennifer Sondag at 
jsondag@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Adam Haigh and Beth Jinks" category="RETAIL" date="Jul 08, 2008 11:47 AM ET" keywords="Belmond Ltd, Morgans Hotel Group Co, Analyst Downgrades, Analyst Rating Changes, Analyst Ratings, Bermuda, Central America, Colombia, Emerging Markets, Equity Movers, Europe, Group of 10 Member Countries, Industries, Latin America, Lodging, Markets, North America, Panama, Research, South America, Stock Markets by Country, U.S. Stock Market Comment, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-07-08/morgans-hotel-orient-express-fall-on-merrill-lynch-downgrades.html"><headline>Morgans Hotel, Orient-Express Fall on Merrill Lynch Downgrades</headline><body>
Morgans Hotel Group Co. (MHGC) and Orient-Express Hotels Ltd. (OEH) fell at least 7.5 percent in U.S. trading
after having their ratings cut to ``underperform'' at Merrill
Lynch  Co. because of a slowdown in demand for U.S. lodging. 
``We remain cautious on the group as we expect occupancy to
decline further before reaching trough levels,'' New York-based
analyst Amanda Bryant wrote in a note today. Previously, Bryant
advised investors to hold both stocks. 
Morgans Hotel Group, based in New York, lost 82 cents to
$10.19 at 11:44 a.m. in Nasdaq Stock Market composite trading.
Bermuda-based Orient-Express Hotels, the owner of more than 40
properties, dropped $3.12 to $38.63 on the New York Stock
Exchange. 
Separately, Orient-Express will own 50 percent of three
hotels being built by U.S. real-estate developer Related Group
under a new partnership, Orient-Express spokeswoman Pippa Isbell
said today in a telephone interview from London. 
The companies will build and run hotels and residences in
Florida's South Beach region of Miami; Cartagena, Colombia; and
Panama City, Panama, which are set to open in three years,
according to Orient-Express. Orient-Express and Related Group
intend to collaborate on more joint projects, Isbell added. 
To contact the reporters on this story:
Adam Haigh in London at 
ahaigh1@bloomberg.net;
Beth Jinks in New York at 
bjinks1@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editors responsible for this story:
Daniel Hauck at 
dhauck1@bloomberg.net;
Michael Nol at  mnol@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Tim Culpan" category="LAW, ASIA" date="Aug 18, 2008  3:37 AM ET" keywords="Acer Inc, Microsoft Corp, Antitrust, Asia, Asia ex. Japan, Australia, China, Computer Software, Computers, Crime, Electronics, Emerging Markets, Group of 10 Member Countries, Korea, Legal Affairs, Litigation, North America, Pacific Rim, Rules and Regulations, Taiwan, Technology, U.S. Pacific Northwest, United States, Washington State" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-08-18/microsoft-under-antitrust-probe-in-taiwan-over-vista-update1-.html"><headline>Microsoft Under Antitrust Probe in Taiwan Over Vista</headline><body>
Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), the world's largest
software maker, is being probed by Taiwan's Fair Trade Commission
after an activist group filed a complaint saying consumers are
being forced to buy its Windows Vista operating system. 
``We have received the complaint and are now conducting our
own investigation, which may last around six months,'' Chou Ya-shu, the antitrust regulator's spokeswoman, said in a telephone
interview today. Microsoft can face fines of as much as NT$25
million ($796,000) and be ordered to halt illicit practices if
found guilty of fair-trade breaches, she said. 
Sophia Chang, a spokeswoman for Microsoft in Taipei, denied
the company forces people to buy Vista and declined to comment
further on the case. 
Microsoft should be fined for using its monopoly to force
consumers to adopt Vista after the company ended sales of Windows
XP in June, Taiwan's Consumer Foundation, a non-profit group,
said in its complaint posted on its Web site on Aug. 15. 
Microsoft, based in Redmond, Washington, stopped selling XP
individually and pre-installing the operating system in most
computers in June to spur Vista sales. Vista, which was released
for consumers in January last year, requires more memory capacity
and greater processing power than XP. 
``It would be a very unusual and creative interpretation of
antitrust law to say that a company is obliged to keep selling a
product,'' said Brendon Carr, an attorney who advises
multinational companies on antitrust issues at the law firm Hwang
Mok Park in Seoul. 
Demand For XP 
The Consumer Foundation said its research showed 56 percent
of consumers buying a computer with Vista would reinstall XP,
while 67 percent oppose Microsoft ending the sale of the earlier
operating system. Windows XP remains available preinstalled in
some low-cost computers such as Acer Inc. (2353)'s Aspire One laptop. 
Under Taiwan's Fair Trade Act, a company may not ``use
incentives or other devious means to induce a business to alter a
consumer's shopping choices,'' the foundation said in the
statement. 
``The Fair Trade Commission should fine Microsoft a large
enough amount that would strip away its profits from selling
Vista,'' the foundation said. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Tim Culpan in Taipei at 
tculpan1@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Young-Sam Cho at  ycho2@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry></news>