<?xml version='1.0' encoding='us-ascii'?>
<news><entry author="By Caroline Byrne" category="LAW" date="Jan 03, 2007  8:22 AM ET" keywords="Buyout, Canada, Corporate Finance, Europe, Financial Services, Hedge Funds, Industries, Law Firms, Legal Affairs, Litigation, London, Market Regulators, Markets, Mutual &amp;amp; Hedge Funds, New York, North America, Private Equity, Regions, Rules and Regulations, Trusts, U.K. Finl Services Authority, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, United Kingdom, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-03/kaye-scholer-hires-u-k-regulatory-lawyer-watkins-update1-.html"><headline>Kaye Scholer Hires U.K. Regulatory Lawyer Watkins</headline><body>
Kaye Scholer LLP, the 500-lawyer New
York law firm whose clients include buyout firm Compass Capital
Partners, has hired regulatory solicitor Owen Watkins as part of
its U.K. expansion plans. 
Watkins, who spent 15 years with the Financial Services
Authority and its predecessor, joins Kaye Scholer's eight-lawyer
London office Jan. 5 as a senior consultant working with the
investment funds group, the firm said. 
``Owen brings detailed knowledge, not only about what the
FSA's position is, but why,'' Timothy Spangler, a corporate and
finance partner who heads the investment funds group, said in a
telephone interview today. ``He has been intimately involved in
the formation of the regime in the last 15 years.'' 
Kaye Scholer is moving into larger London offices this month
and plans to expand from eight to 35 lawyers focused on private
equity deals, hedge funds, corporate mergers and acquisitions and
investment funds, Spangler said. U.K. clients include buyout firm
Nova Capital Group Ltd. 
Kaye Scholer has eight offices across the U.S., Europe and
in Shanghai. In North America, the firm represents Boston-based
buyout firm J.W. Childs Associates LP, Chicago's Linden Capital
Partners and Onex Corp., Canada's largest private equity firm.
Corporate clients include Halliburton Co., the world's second
largest oilfields-services company, and casino-operator Harrah's
Entertainment Inc. 
Watkins is no longer at the FSA and couldn't be reached to
comment. 
To contact the reporter for this story:
Caroline Byrne in London at 
cbyrne12@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Eamonn Sullivan at 
esullivan@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Mike Ramsey" category="TRANSPORTATION" date="Jan 04, 2007  5:32 PM ET" keywords="Goodyear Tire &amp;amp; Rubber Co/The, IHS Inc, Office Depot Inc, Accounting, Auto Parts, Automobiles, Bonds, Commercial Services, Consumer Goods, Florida, Industries, Markets, Michigan, Municipal Bonds, North America, Office Equipment, Ohio, Ratings, Regions, Retail, Retailing, Rubber, Specialized Regions, Transportation, U.S. Midwest, U.S. South, U.S. Southeast, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-04/goodyear-among-founders-of-michigan-auto-trade-group-update1-.html"><headline>Goodyear Among Founders of Michigan Auto Trade Group</headline><body>
Goodyear Tire  Rubber Co. (GT) and three
other companies that do business with Michigan-based carmakers
and auto-parts suppliers have formed a trade group to promote the
state's ailing automotive industry. 
The founders of MICHauto want to revive a sector battered by
job cuts and factory shutdowns, especially at General Motors
Corp. and Ford Motor Co. The industry's woes have contributed to
Michigan's 6.9 percent unemployment rate, the second worst among
states and more than 50 percent higher than the national rate. 
Michigan lost 101,000 automotive manufacturing jobs between
2001 and 2006, a 32 percent drop. Meanwhile, Southern states have
increased auto-industry employment over the past 15 years by
luring new factories from Toyota Motor Corp., Bayerische Motoren
Werke AG and Nissan Motor Co. (NSANY), among others. 
``We need somebody -- an organization -- to make a fight,
get a little life into Michigan's auto industry,'' said Johann Finkelmeier, a vice president at Goodyear's North American tire
division. 
Other founding members of the group are R.L. Polk  Co., an
auto-industry researcher; accounting firm Deloitte  Touche LLP;
and Warner Norcross  Judd LLP, a law firm. 
In its first year, the group intends to meet with deans of
engineering and business schools in the state about how to
develop and retain workers. It also is planning meetings with
economic-development organizations throughout the state. 
The group is building a Web page -- http://www.michauto.org
-- and developing a directory of Michigan automotive companies
and related businesses. 
Michigan Ties 
Goodyear doesn't have plants in Michigan, according to its
Web site. It has factories in southern states including Texas,
North Carolina, Georgia, Virginia, Alabama, Florida, South
Carolina and Tennessee. Finkelmeier said that large customers are
based in Michigan, including GM, Ford and DaimlerChrysler AG's
Chrysler unit. 
Office Depot Inc. (ODP), which operates a chain of office-product
stores, has begun working with MICHauto. While the Delray Beach,
Florida-based company isn't involved in the auto industry, many
of its customers are, said Jack Tann, Office Depot's manager of
business development in Michigan. 
``We are intimately involved with companies'' in the auto
industry, Tann said. ``We have a large operation in southeastern
Michigan,'' where many auto companies and suppliers are based. 
The trade group is looking to emulate the Alabama Automotive
Manufacturers Association, which has 350 members, and the German
Association of the Automotive Industry, or VDA. 
Model Organizations 
``If you look at the organizations in the South and in
Europe, they are effective,'' said Tom Manganello, a founder of
the organization and the chairman of Warner Norcross  Judd LLP's
Automotive Industry Group. ``We do not have anything like it.'' 
Alabama's share of North American automotive production
increased from 2.9 percent in 2005 to 4.3 percent in 2006 and is
projected to be 4.6 percent in 2007, according to data collected
by Ward's Automotive Reports. Alabama, home to a Hyundai Motor
Co. plant, is the sixth-largest auto producer in the U.S.
Michigan is first. 
Michigan produced 14.4 percent of U.S.-manufactured
automobiles last year, compared with 15.4 in 2005. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Mike Ramsey in Southfield, Michigan, at 
mramsey6bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Dave Versical at  dversical@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Cecile Daurat" category="EXECUTIVE" date="Jan 04, 2007  4:21 PM ET" keywords="News Corp, Twenty-First Century Fox Inc, Asia, Australia, Cable Television, California, Entertainment, Industries, Internet, Media, New York, New Zealand, North America, Pacific Rim, Publishing, Regions, Specialized Regions, Technology, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, U.S. West, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-04/geraldo-rivera-will-host-weekend-shows-on-fox-news-update2-.html"><headline>Geraldo Rivera Will Host Weekend Shows on Fox News</headline><body>
News Corp. (NWSA)'s Fox News Channel said
``At Large with Geraldo Rivera'' will return to the cable
network on Saturday and Sunday nights after his broadcast show
failed to attract enough advertisers. 
The syndicated version of ``Geraldo at Large'' that aired
on Fox Television stations will end in mid-January, New York-based Fox News said today in a statement. Rivera will continue
to make guest appearances on ``The O'Reilly Factor'' and serve
as a correspondent during major breaking news events, Fox said. 
Fox News is moving Rivera back to cable a year after the
syndicated show started because the program suffered from a
tepid ad market and the lack of an early news lead-in in several
cities, Roger Ailes, chief executive officer of Fox News, said
in the statement. ``Geraldo at Large'' is the second syndicated
show to be canceled this year after NBC Universal pulled the
plug yesterday on ``The Megan Mullally Show.'' 
``Ratings expectations are higher in syndication than on
cable,'' said Brad Adgate, director of research at New York-based advertising firm Horizon Media Inc. ``Fox News probably
felt it's better for him to be working for a vertical news
network rather than a broad-based entertainment channel.'' 
Class A shares of News Corp., controlled by Rupert Murdoch,
fell 21 cents to $21.26 as of 4 p.m. in New York Stock Exchange
composite trading. They jumped 38 percent in 2006. 
`Competitive' 
The hour-long syndicated show, ``Geraldo at Large,''
started in November 2005, replacing ``A Current Affair'' on
stations owned and operated by Fox. Rivera has a new multiyear
deal with Fox as part of the switch. 
The program marked a return to syndication for Rivera, who
hosted ``The Geraldo Rivera Show'' for 11 seasons until 1998.
Rivera, who later hosted ``Rivera Live'' on CNBC, joined Fox
News as a war correspondent in 2001. 
The highest-rated syndicated shows include ``Jeopardy,''
``Wheel of Fortune'' and the ``Oprah Winfrey Show,'' according
to Nielsen Media Research. 
``Syndication is a very competitive market dominated by
long-running shows,'' Adgate said. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Cecile Daurat in New York at 
cdaurat@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Emma Moody at 
emoody@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Dan Hart" category="US" date="Jan 07, 2007  3:46 PM ET" keywords="Tribune Media Co, California, Illinois, Industries, Labor &amp;amp; Unions, Media, New York, North America, Publishing, Regions, Specialized Regions, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, U.S. Midwest, U.S. West, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-07/tribune-s-l-a-times-press-operators-join-teamsters-update1-.html"><headline>Tribune's L.A. Times Press Operators Join Teamsters</headline><body>
Fifty-two percent of the press
operators at Tribune Co.'s Los Angeles Times voted for
representation by the International Brotherhood of Teamsters
after a six-month organizing campaign, the union said. 
The press operators, who work in newspaper's printing
plants in downtown Los Angeles and Costa Mesa, California, voted
Jan. 4 and Jan. 5, the Teamsters said in a statement yesterday.
The vote was 140 for representation and 131 against, said union
spokesman David White. 
The move comes as Chicago-based Tribune, publisher of the
Times and Chicago Tribune, seeks takeover bids for the company
after being pressured by its largest shareholder, the Chandler
family, for a breakup. The family acquired its stake when Times
Mirror Co. was sold to Tribune for $7.5 billion in 2000. 
``With all of the uncertainty over the L.A. Times's
ownership over the past several months, our ability to bargain
strong contracts gives these new members strength in the
workplace,'' said James P. Hoffa, the union's president, in the
statement. 
No Other Unions 
The Graphic Communications Conference of the Teamsters
union also represents press operators at Newsday, another
Tribune property, the union said. 
``We are, of course, disappointed in the outcome of the
vote,'' said David Hiller, publisher of the Times, in a
statement yesterday. 
There are about 300 press operators and no other unions at
the paper, said Nancy Sullivan, a spokeswoman for the newspaper. 
The Times' weekday circulation declined 8 percent to
775,766 for the six months ended Sept. 24, according to the
Audit Bureau of Circulations. 
The Washington-based Teamsters union was founded in 1903
and has 1.4 million members. United Parcel Service Inc. is the
single biggest employer with more than 200,000 Teamster members,
according to the Teamsters Web site. 
Tribune shares fell 8 cents to $30.81 on Jan. 5. The stock
has declined 9 percent since Sept. 22, when the company agreed
to consider putting itself up for sale or selling pieces of the
company. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Dan Hart in Washington at 
dahart@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Sylvia Wier at  swier@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Mathew Carr and Lars Paulsson" category="ENERGY_MARKETS, MANUFACTURING" date="Jan 08, 2007  1:01 PM ET" keywords="E.ON SE, Macquarie Group Ltd, RWE AG, Airlines, Banking, Building, Cement, Coal, Coal Market, Commodities, Commodities Markets, DAX Index, Electricity Generation, Energy, Energy Trading, Environment, Euro Members, Europe, European Union, Financial Services, Forest Products, Germany, Indus. Materials, Industries, Machinery, Manufacturing, Markets, Metals, Natural Gas, Natural Gas Market, Nordic Region, Norway, Nuclear Power, Oil, Power Markets, Refineries, Regions, Specialized Regions, Steel, Transportation, United Kingdom, Utilities, ex-Energy" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-08/carbon-permits-fall-to-record-low-german-power-prices-decline.html"><headline>Carbon Permits Fall to Record Low; German Power Prices Decline</headline><body>
Carbon dioxide permits for 2008, the
start of a second phase of European emissions trading, fell to
record lows and power prices in Germany slid. 
European Union carbon dioxide permits for December 2008 fell
as much as 1.40 euros, or 8.9 percent, to a record 14.40 euros
($19) a metric ton, according to prices from the European Climate
Exchange in Amsterdam. Permits were at 14.50 euros a ton at 6:50
p.m. local time. 
Imported credits are ``likely to cover most of the deficit''
in the five years through 2012, said UBS AG analysts including Per Lekander. Imported credits cost less than 15 euros a ton, while EU
emission permits need to rise to more than 30 euros to encourage
utilities to switch to cleaner natural gas from coal, Lekander
said today in an e-mailed research note. 
The decline extends last week's losses, the biggest weekly
drop since May. About 11,000 factories and power stations in the
world's largest emissions trading regime can either use permits
granted by their governments to comply, or use credits created
under the 1997 Kyoto Protocol. 
The world is likely to experience its warmest recorded year
in 2007 because of the effects of the El Nino weather pattern and
global warming, the U.K. government's weather forecasting division
said Jan. 4. That will reduce demand for energy, curbing
emissions. 
Crude oil fell 0.8 percent on skepticism that OPEC, producer
of about 40 percent of the world's oil, will cut production as
much as pledged. Oil prices help set natural gas prices, and gas
produces half the emissions as coal for each unit of power
produced. Oil has fallen about 8 percent this month. 
Germany Imports 
Germany has asked the European Commission, the regulatory arm
of the EU, to allow it to boost the number of credits emitters can
import to 20 percent of their permit grant, from 12 percent. 
Any limit the commission is likely to make on Kyoto Protocol
credit imports ``is set more or less in line with demand and does
not really create a constraint,'' Lekander said. In 2008, there
may be a shortfall of permits for 167 million tons of emissions,
with 134 million of that shortfall covered by imports, he said. 
Some fuel switching may occur during summer when gas is
cheaper, resulting in an average carbon-dioxide permit price that
year of 20 euros a ton, UBS said. 
Permits for 2007 will average 3 euros this year, Lekander
forecast, because of an expected oversupply. Spot permits fell
today to a record 3.89 euros a ton, according to prices from the
Powernext exchange in Paris. There may be ``value'' in selling
spot permits and buying them back later for an even lower price,
Lekander said. 
Phase One 
The commission said in May it may have allowed EU member
states to hand out too many permits through 2007, blaming
inaccurate emissions data. 
German power for next year, which last week had its biggest
weekly drop since April, slid as falling prices for emission
allowances and oil dragged down prices in Europe's biggest
electricity market. 
Baseload next-year power contracts in Germany fell for a
fifth day, declining as much as 1.4 percent to 52.60 euros a
megawatt-hour, according to prices from broker GFI Group Inc. on
Bloomberg. That's the lowest since Sept. 25. 
To contact the reporters on this story:
Mathew Carr in London at 
m.carr@bloomberg.net 
Lars Paulsson in London at 
lpaulsson@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Daniel Tilles at  dtilles@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Chan Sue Ling" category="ASIA, FRANCE, TRANSPORTATION" date="Jan 08, 2007  3:25 AM ET" keywords="Bank of China Ltd, Boeing Co/The, General Electric Co, Aerospace, Airlines, Asia, Asia ex. Japan, Australia, Banking, CAC 40 Index, China, Contracts, Corporate Finance, Defense, Defense Dept., Earnings, Emerging Markets, Euro Members, Europe, Financial Services, France, Germany, Hong Kong, Industries, Korea, Leisure, Leisure Travel, Markets, Militaries, North America, Orders, Pacific Rim, Regions, Singapore, South, Southeast Asia, Spain, Spain &amp;amp; Portugal, Taiwan, Transportation, U.S. Government, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-08/singapore-aircraft-orders-40-airbus-boeing-planes-update5-.html"><headline>Singapore Aircraft Orders 40 Airbus, Boeing Planes</headline><body>
Singapore Aircraft Leasing Enterprise,
owned by Bank of China Ltd., will buy 40 planes from Airbus SAS
and Boeing Co., as it expands its fleet to meet demand from low-cost carriers and other airlines. 
Asia's biggest plane lessor ordered 20 planes from the A320
family, Airbus said in a statement today. The company also
exercised options for 20 Boeing 737-800s, Boeing said in a
separate release. The combined orders are worth as much as $3
billion at list prices. 
Singapore Aircraft is expanding its fleet as customers such
as AirAsia Bhd., Southeast Asia's largest budget airline, start
flying new routes. The Asia-Pacific region will need 7,900
planes over the next 20 years, 29 percent of the global demand
for aircraft during the period, according to Boeing. 
``The pie is definitely growing for the low-cost segment,''
said Peter Drolet, an analyst at UOB Kay Hian Pte in Hong Kong.
``You've now got a very tight small aircraft segment with
AirAsia and all the low-cost carriers that want to get their
hands on single-aisle aircraft.'' 
The orders are the first announced from Asia this year for
both Airbus and Boeing. Last year, Boeing booked a total of
1,044 orders for commercial airplanes. Airbus had 635 orders at
the end of November. 
Singapore Aircraft plans to expand the number of planes it
owns and manages to as many as 300, Chief Executive Officer
Robert Martin said in a Bloomberg interview in September. At
present, it manages 12 aircraft for third parties out of the 75
in its fleet, according to its Web site. 
Sustained Demand 
Singapore Aircraft ``has already placed almost all the
aircraft from its existing orders for delivery through to the
end of 2009, which is a measure of the sustained demand in the
leasing market'' Martin said in a statement today. 
All 40 planes are scheduled for delivery between 2009 and
2012, Singapore Aircraft said. The company also has options for
10 more Airbus A320s. The purchases will be financed through
cash, bank loans and other facilities offered by the U.S. and
European export credit agencies, spokesman Sean Lee said in an
e-mail reply to Bloomberg queries. 
Widebody Models 
Singapore Aircraft is also evaluating further purchases in
the near future, including widebody models, it said today. The
company may seek offers for midsize planes such as the 787 or
A350 XWB, by the end of the first quarter, Flight International
said last week, citing Martin. 
The agreement with Singapore Aircraft provides for the
option to convert to other variants within the 737 family,
Boeing said today. 
The 737, which can carry as many as 215 passengers
depending on the model and has a maximum range 3,365 nautical
miles (6,232 kilometers), is powered by engines from CFM
International, a venture of General Electric Co. (GE) and France's
Safran SA. 
The plane lessor said it hasn't selected the engines for
the Airbus planes, which seat as many as 185 people and fly as
far as 3,700 nautical miles depending on the model. 
Airbus won a total of 580 orders for its A320 family
aircraft as of the end of November, while Boeing had 729 orders
for the 737 aircraft for the whole of last year, according to
their Web sites. 
Boeing said last week it booked a record 1,044 commercial
airplane purchases in 2006, benefiting from demand for cargo
planes and the 737 airliner. The 737 model accounted for about
three-quarters of 2006 deliveries. 
Singapore Aircraft was acquired by Bank of China, the
nation's second-biggest bank, last month for $965 million. The
plane lessor posted a record profit of $34.7 million for the 12
months ended March 31, 2006, compared with $5.2 million a year
earlier, as growing travel demand spurred airlines to lease more
planes. 
In April last year, Singapore Aircraft placed an order for
10 Boeing 737s with the option and purchase rights for 20 more. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Chan Sue Ling in Singapore 
slchan@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Tony Jordan at 
tjordan3@bloomberg.net;
Bret Okeson at 
bokeson@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Brendan Murray" category="LAW, LATIN_AMERICA, US, EMERGING_MARKETS" date="Jan 09, 2007  3:15 PM ET" keywords="ConocoPhillips, Exxon Mobil Corp, Verizon Communications Inc, Caribbean, Central Banks, Commodities, Commodities Markets, Congress, Crude Oil, Emerging Markets, Energy, Energy Trading, Industries, Latin America, Markets, Media, New York, North America, Oil, Oil Markets, Oklahoma, Politics, Regions, South America, Technology, Telecom Equipment, Telecom Services, Texas, U.S., U.S. Government, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, U.S. Midwest, U.S. Southwest, United States, Venezuela, White House" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-09/chavez-urged-by-u-s-to-compensate-american-companies-update2-.html"><headline>Chavez Urged by U.S. to Compensate American Companies</headline><body>
The Bush administration urged
Venezuela to compensate U.S. companies that would be affected by
President Hugo Chavez's plan to transfer the country's utilities
to state ownership, a White House spokesman said. 
Chavez said yesterday he plans to nationalize the country's
largest phone company and utilities, gain greater control over
the oil industry and seek authority to make laws by executive
order. His comments sent Venezuelan stocks and bonds tumbling. 
The U.S. has ``seen the results of nationalization in other
places, and in general these types of actions do not produce
economic benefits as expected,'' White House spokesman Gordon Johndroe said. ``If any U.S. companies are affected, we expect
them to be promptly and fairly compensated.'' 
Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM), ConocoPhillips (COP), Chevron Corp. and Total
SA may lose their shares in the four heavy oil ventures if
Chavez's plan is approved by Venezuela's congress. New York-based Verizon Communications Inc. (VZ) has a stake in the country's
telephone network. 
Senator Joseph Biden of Delaware, a Democrat who chairs the
Foreign Relations Committee, suggested that the expansion of
government economic control would end up undermining Chavez.
``The prospect is that Chavez will continue to escalate his new
socialist revolution to the point he loses support,'' Biden
said. 
The U.S. is seeking details on how Venezuela plans to carry
out the nationalization, according to Eric Watnik, a spokesman
for the State Department's Bureau of Western Hemisphere affairs.
He expressed U.S. concern over Chavez's pledge to strip the
central bank of its autonomy. 
``Independent central banks have a global track record in
achieving low inflation and economic stability,'' Watnik said.
``Separation of powers, and checks and balances, are fundamental
to democracy.'' 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Brendan Murray in Washington at 
brmurray@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editors responsible for this story:
Michael Forsythe at  mforsythe@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Jody Shenn" category="FINANCE, REAL_ESTATE" date="Jan 09, 2007  1:48 PM ET" keywords="Signature Group Holdings Inc, Asset-Backed Securities, Banking, Bonds, CDOs-Collateralized Debt, California, Collateralized Mtge Oblig, Corporate Bonds, Corporate Finance, Financial Services, Home Builders, Industries, Loans &amp;amp; Financing, Markets, North America, Real Estate, Regions, U.S. West, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-09/fremont-toughens-sub-prime-mortgage-loan-guidelines-update1-.html"><headline>Fremont Toughens Sub-Prime Mortgage Loan Guidelines</headline><body>
Fremont Investment  Loan, the third-largest provider of sub-prime U.S. mortgages through brokers, is
making broad changes to its lending guidelines for at least the
second time within a year to reflect concerns about rising late
payments by the riskiest borrowers. 
The lender will stop giving mortgages to individuals who
can't prove their income when buying a home with no money down,
or to those that make down payments of less than 10 percent for
properties sold without real estate agents, according to an
internal memo. Fremont Investment, the main operating unit of
Santa Monica, California-based Fremont General Corp., will also
refuse to refinance loans that are more than 90 days late. 
``Change can be difficult for everyone, but in the current
market, change is necessary,'' Robert Clafford, a senior vice
president at Fremont, wrote in the memo, which outlined 11 areas
where the company would tighten standards. Clafford declined to
comment about the memo when reached by telephone yesterday. 
A slowing housing market and looser underwriting has pushed
delinquencies on sub-prime mortgages made in 2005 and 2006 to
the worst levels for their ages since loans originated in 2001,
according UBS AG and Friedman Billings Ramsey Group Inc. Sub-prime mortgages are considered the riskiest types because they
are made to people with poor or limited credit histories. 
Other lenders have also clamped down on lending practices
within the past month, including New Century Financial Corp.,
General Electric Co.'s WMC Mortgage, and First Franklin
Financial, which Merrill Lynch  Co. bought this month. 
Case for Quality 
Fremont has been seeking out chances to talk with bond
investors to encourage them to buy new securities backed by its
loans, according to Jeremy A. Shor, a portfolio manager at Brown
Brothers Harriman  Co. in New York. 
``They are really trying to step up and make the case that
they have quality underwriting standards,'' said Shor, whose
firm manages about $3 billion in asset-backed securities. 
Questions about Fremont's relative loan quality have been
raised by Moody's Investors Service and Standard  Poor's. Since
October, the rating firms have said they may downgrade low-rated
bonds created last year in securitizations of mortgages made in
late 2005 and early 2006. Rating companies typically don't
reassess such bonds' creditworthiness within their first year. 
Shares in Fremont plunged 30 percent last year, compared to
a 14 percent gain for the Standard  Poor's 500 index. They've
fallen almost 9 percent this year, trading down 33 cents to
$14.78 as of 1:45 p.m. today on the New York Stock Exchange. 
Rethinking Policies 
Lenders have started rethinking their policies as prices
fall for the riskiest sub-prime mortgages and for some
securitizations, and because of demands by investors for the
companies to repurchase loans with early repayment problems.
Fremont bought back $345.7 million of loans in the third
quarter, according to a Nov. 9 company earnings statement. 
``We periodically do changes to our underwriting
guidelines,'' said Trude Tsujimoto, general counsel for Fremont
Investment. ``That's part of our normal processes.'' She refused
to discuss the memo's details. 
In his memo, Fremont's Clafford referenced the closure of
Agoura Hills, California-based Ownit Mortgage Solutions Inc.
last month and last week's decision by Middletown, Connecticut-based Mortgage Lenders Network USA Inc. to halt its broker
business amid lower sales and higher defaults. 
Fremont Performance 
After adjusting for traits such as credit scores, loan-to-value ratios and the mortgages' ages, as well as estimates of
appreciation, securitized sub-prime mortgages made last year by
Fremont had the fourth-worst performance among those of the 20
bond issuers studied by analysts at UBS for a Dec. 19 report. 
About 19 percent of loans made by Fremont between July 2005
and December 2005 and backing a bond sold in February 30 days
late or worse, according to a Dec. 12 regulatory filing. About
5.9 percent were being foreclosed and 2.4 percent had become
seized properties, according to the filing. Standard  Poor's
said last week that it may downgrade that bond. 
Fremont had $12.6 billion in assets and was collecting
payments on $24 billion of residential real estate loans as of
Sept. 30, according to the company's recent earnings statement. 
`80-20' Program 
In mid-2006, Fremont tightened loan standards by ending
``80-20'' programs for consumers with credit scores below 600
ready to document their income or those with scores below 640
and looking to ``state'' it, according to slides on its Web site
from a December presentation to bond investors. 
The 80-20 programs allow borrowers to use home-equity loans
in lieu of down payments. Fremont also introduced new fraud
training and appraisal procedures, according to the slides. 
Tighter standards could depress sub-prime industry volumes
by more than 15 percent this year, Bose George, an analyst at
Keefe, Bruyette  Woods Inc., wrote in a report last month. 
After the earlier round of adjustments by Fremont, the
company's new residential lending, fell 23 percent between the
second and third quarters to $9.5 billion. 
Fremont did make some changes this week that favor
borrowers, including lowering the number of existing credit
accounts that first-time home buyers must have. 
Last month, the company told bond buyers that past changes
cut the amount of first-time buyers in its new loan mix from
24 percent in June, to 5.6 percent in September. 
``We are also working to provide you with competitive
advantages,'' Clafford told employees in the memo. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Jody Shenn in New York at 
jshenn@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Robert Burgess at  bburgess@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Darren Boey and Ting Ting Ng" category="STOCKS" date="Jan 09, 2007  4:35 AM ET" keywords="China Construction Bank Corp, China Life Insurance Co Ltd, China Mobile Ltd, HSBC Holdings PLC, Hang Lung Properties Ltd, Asia, Asia ex. Japan, Australia, Banking, China, China Stock Market, Closing Market Comments, Currencies, Emerging Markets, Europe, FTSE 100 Index, Financial Services, Hong Kong, Hong Kong Stocks, Industries, Insurance, Korea, Markets, Pacific Rim, Real Estate, Regions, Specialized Regions, Stock Markets by Country, Taiwan, Technology, Telecom Services, United Kingdom" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-09/hong-kong-stocks-fall-for-second-day-china-mobile-hsbc-drop.html"><headline>Hong Kong Stocks Fall for Second Day; China Mobile, HSBC Drop</headline><body>
Hong Kong stocks fell on concern a
three-month rally in China-related shares, which lifted the Hang
Seng Index to a record, more than reflected earnings prospects.
China Mobile Ltd. declined. 
``A correction is expected in the near term, given that in
the last couple of months we've seen a very sharp up-tick in the
market,'' said Teresa Chow, who helps manage $500 million at RBC
Investment Management Asia in Hong Kong. ``Some investors would
be inclined to take profits now and buy on the dips.'' 
HSBC Holdings Plc (HSBA) fell after JPMorgan Chase  Co. cut its
rating on the shares amid concern U.S. lending is in decline and
margins at the company's Hong Kong unit are peaking. 
The Hang Seng Index (HSI) lost 131.58, or 0.7 percent, to
19,898.08 in Hong Kong, extending yesterday's 0.9 percent drop.
The measure posted its first two-day decline since Dec. 12-13.
The Hang Seng China Enterprises Index, which tracks the so-called
H shares of 37 mainland companies, lost 1.3 percent to 9967.48. 
Stocks tied to China have benefited from the nation's 10
percent economic growth rate, the appreciating yuan and
speculation more companies will sell shares on the mainland. 
Earnings at seven of the Hang Seng's 10 best-performing
stocks in the past three months were related to China. The index
in that time has gained 13 percent, while the H-share measure
climbed 42 percent. 
Too Far, Too Fast 
Half of the Hang Seng Index's 36 members declined, while the
rest advanced. January futures dropped 0.5 percent to 19,929. 
China Mobile (941), the world's largest cell-phone operator by
users, fell HK$1.40, or 2.1 percent, to HK$66.45, cutting its
three-month gain to 18 percent. China Construction Bank Corp. (939),
the nation's fourth-largest lender, slid 17 cents, or 3.5 percent,
to HK$4.72. It's risen 37 percent in the same period. 
China Life Insurance Co., China's biggest insurer, slumped
HK$1.25, or 4.7 percent, to HK$25.60. The stock, which climbed as
much as 82 percent in the past three months, was the biggest drag
on the H-share index. 
The shares had benefited from speculation that the company's
mainland listing would trade at a premium to the Hong Kong stock.
China Life's yuan-denominated shares more than doubled in its
first day of trading in Shanghai today. 
``The positive impact of the listing of China Life's A
shares has already been reflected in the market,'' said Conita Hung, head of research for Delta Asia Securities Ltd. ``H shares
have run up too quickly since December, and they are undergoing
some consolidation.'' 
Buying Laggards 
Hang Lung Properties Ltd. (101), Hong Kong's fourth-largest
developer, climbed 72 cents, or 3.9 percent, to HK$19.08 as some
investors sought shares that had underperformed the broader
market. The stock had lost 7.9 percent in the week through
yesterday, more than the Hang Seng's 1.4 percent drop. 
``Hang Lung Properties is lagging behind the market,'' said
Delta Asia's Hung. ``Apart from that, investors are optimistic
about its property projects in mainland China.'' Hang Lung plans
to invest as much as HK$30 billion ($3.85 billion) to build 12
commercial properties in China. 
HSBC (5), the Hang Seng's largest constituent, fell 70 cents, or
0.5 percent, to HK$141.50. Analysts at JPMorgan cut the London-
based bank's shares to ``neutral'' from ``overweight'' and
lowered their earnings estimates by 3 percent for 2006, 7.5
percent for 2007 and by 5 percent for 2008. 
``There will be more selling in the short term because of
the downgrading of HSBC,'' said Andrew Sullivan, head of Asian
sales trading at Daiwa Securities SMBC Co. in Hong Kong. Loan
growth at HSBC ``depends on the U.S. performance.'' 
CLSA Ltd. also trimmed its target price and earnings
estimates, according to a Jan. 5 report. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Darren Boey in Hong Kong at 
dboey@bloomberg.net;
Ting Ting Ng at  tng9@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
James Regan in Hong Kong at 
jregan8@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Chris Young" category="AUSTRALIA_NEW_ZEALAND" date="Jan 09, 2007  1:22 AM ET" keywords="Asia, Asia Bonds, Asia ex. Japan, Australia, Australian Bonds, Bonds, Country, Currencies, Government Bonds, Markets, New Zealand, Pacific Rim, Regional Bond Mkts, Regions, Specialized Regions" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-09/australian-dollar-rises-as-retail-sales-gain-for-a-sixth-month.html"><headline>Australian Dollar Rises as Retail Sales Gain for a Sixth Month</headline><body>
The Australian dollar strengthened as
a government report showed retail sales rose in November,
supporting speculation the Reserve Bank of Australia may raise
interest rates to control inflationary pressures. 
The Australian dollar climbed against all 16 of the most
active currencies tracked by Bloomberg today as a gain in retail
sales signals the central bank's third rate increase in a year on
Nov. 8 didn't deter consumers from spending. 
``The number is painting a pretty solid picture of consumer
spending,'' said Warren Hogan, head of research at Australia 
New Zealand Banking Group Ltd. in Sydney. ``People will put
interest-rate bets back on the table, which will support the
Australian dollar.'' 
Australia's currency bought 78.33 U.S. cents as of 5:20 p.m.
in Sydney compared with 77.97 cents late in Asia yesterday. It
will gain to 80.20 cents in coming weeks, Hogan said. It reached
a 22-month high of 79.80 cents on Jan. 3. 
Retail sales rose 0.2 percent from October, when they gained
a revised 0.9 percent, the Bureau of Statistics said in Sydney
today. The median estimate of 19 economists surveyed by Bloomberg
News was for a 0.3 percent gain. The figures have risen every
month since May, when they were flat. 
``The consumer is in good shape,'' said Annette Beacher,
economist at Citigroup Australia in Sydney. ``This will allow the
RBA to reiterate its tightening bias, which is good for the
Australian dollar.'' 
The bureau yesterday said the number of approvals to build
or renovate houses and apartments rose 4.1 percent from October
to 12,739. The median estimate of 19 economists surveyed by
Bloomberg News was for a 2 percent gain. 
Yield-Related Support 
Australian government bonds fell for a second day, pushing
yields higher and widening their margin over U.S. Treasuries.
This makes the currency more attractive to overseas investors. 
The yield on the 10-year bond rose 1 basis point, or 0.01
percentage point, to 5.86 percent, 1.2 percentage points more
than like-dated U.S. Treasuries. That gap has averaged 82 basis
points in the past year. 
The price of the 6 percent bond maturing in February 2017
fell 0.47, or 47 cents per A$1,000 face amount, to 101.071. 
Commodity Slide 
Gains in the Australian dollar may be limited by a slide in
the price of some of the metals the nation exports, said Joanne Masters, a currency strategist at Macquarie Bank Ltd. in Sydney. 
A gauge of six metals traded on the London Metals Exchange,
including Australian exports nickel and zinc, yesterday dropped
1.6 percent, a seventh daily decline. Sales of raw materials
contribute 13.5 percent to Australia's economy. 
Copper futures in Shanghai traded near a nine-month low,
after plunging 9 percent last week, on signs the decline in
prices may spur buying from China, the world's biggest consumer
of the metal. 
The Reserve Bank of Australia raised its overnight cash rate
target to 6.25 percent in November to slow inflation that held
above its target for two straight quarters. 
Traders see a 60 percent chance the bank will increase
borrowing costs by mid-year, compared with 48 percent late last
week, according to 30-day inter-bank interest rate futures
contracts. 
Employment numbers 
Jobs advertised in major newspapers and on the Internet
jumped 12.1 percent, according to an Australia  New Zealand
Banking Group Ltd. report released yesterday. The increase was
the largest since ANZ Bank began compiling figures for Internet
advertising in July 1999. 
A government report in two days will probably show employers
added 15,000 workers in November after 36,200 new jobs were
created the previous month, according to a Bloomberg survey of
economists. This may add to pressures on wages to rise and fuel
inflation. 
``Employment numbers are arguably the single most important
economic release for the Australian dollar,'' said Richard Grace,
senior currency strategist at Commonwealth Bank of Australia in
Sydney. ``The risk with this number lies with further strength in
employment growth and a return to strength for the Australian
dollar.'' 
The currency will rise to 80 cents in the next few months,
said Grace, who in May correctly predicted it would end 2006 at
79 cents. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Chris Young in Sydney at 
cyoung12@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Sandy Hendry at 
shendry@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Alex Kennedy and Theresa Bradley" category="LATIN_AMERICA" date="Jan 10, 2007  5:20 PM ET" keywords="Central Banks, Emerging Markets, Energy, Industries, Latin America, Markets, Media, Politics, Regions, South America, Specialized Regions, Technology, Telecom Equipment, Telecom Services, Utilities, Venezuela" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-10/chavez-venezuela-foes-lack-power-to-resist-plans-update1-.html"><headline>Chavez Venezuela Foes Lack Power to Resist Plans</headline><body>
Venezuelan President Hugo Chavez
will encounter little resistance to his plans to nationalize
utilities, rein in the central bank and impose state control of
the media, the country's business and political leaders said. 
After eight years in office, Chavez, 52, controls every
element of the government, said Jose Luis Betancourt, head of
the country's biggest business group -- all seats in congress,
the entire Supreme Court, governorships in all but two of 26
states, and the military. Protests by groups such as his
Fedecamaras don't influence events, he said. 
``Chavez has come up with a strategy that, once begun, is
very difficult to stop,'' Manuel Malaver, a political analyst
and columnist at the Caracas newspaper, El Mundo, said in a
telephone interview. ``Neither institutions nor resources allow
the opposition to put forward any kind of barrier to stop Chavez
from what he is doing.'' 
Venezuelan stocks had their biggest drop on record
yesterday and bonds tumbled after Chavez, who was sworn in for a
second six-year term today, said he plans to nationalize the
country's biggest telephone company and shut a private
television station. Chavez reiterated today that he will seek
approval from the National Assembly to make law by decree and
later to change the constitution to abolish term limits. 
After giving his inaugural address this morning, in which
he said Venezuela is moving toward a ``communal state,'' Chavez
flew to Nicaragua for President-elect Daniel Ortega's swearing-in. 
Coup 
``Chavez is acting like a despot,'' Zulia state Governor
Manuel Rosales, who lost to Chavez in a Dec. 3 election with 37
percent of the vote, said yesterday in a televised news
conference. ``He's taking the country toward Marxist communism.
We have to mobilize.'' 
Apart from Rosales' remarks in Zulia, the country's
demoralized opposition shows little sign of resisting Chavez's
stepped-up campaign for a ``21st Century socialism.'' Failed
efforts over the past four years to oust or restrain the
president have weakened his opponents. 
The first was a two-day coup on April 11, 2002. Other
generals put Chavez, a former paratroop lieutenant colonel, back
in power, and he purged the ranks of his enemies. 
Then in December 2002, a coalition of business and labor
groups began a general strike to demand a recall vote. The
shutdown cost the country $13 billion in oil sales and lost
support after two months. It ended with Chavez firing 18,000
strikers at the state oil company Petroleos de Venezuela SA,
about half the workforce. 
A recall election in August 2004 ended with Chavez
capturing 59 percent of the vote. 
Stocks 
In December 2005, five opposition parties boycotted
congressional elections, saying voter confidentiality wasn't
secure. As a result, Chavez allies swept every one of the 167
seats in Venezuela's one-chamber National Assembly. 
All legislative options are now closed, said Malaver.
Although some of the president's comments might be just
rhetoric, ``people don't know what to do, in what to invest,''
he said. ``It freezes economic and cultural development.'' 
Chavez's threat to take control of ``everything that was
privatized'' sent the stock exchange index down 19 percent
yesterday. Shares of telephone company CA Nacional Telefonos de
Venezuela, which account for almost a fifth of the Caracas Stock
Exchange Index, fell 30 percent, their steepest decline ever
before trading was halted. 
The company's U.S.-traded shares jumped 15.7 percent, or
$1.92, at 3:57 p.m. New York time today after the chairman of
the congressional finance committee, Ricardo Sanguino, said
shareholders would be compensated in any nationalization. The
stock tumbled 27.5 percent yesterday. 
'Cancer' 
Trading of Electricidad de Caracas, the nation's largest
private power company, was also stopped after its shares slid 20
percent. Foreign companies with operations in Venezuela,
including power company AES Corp. and steelmaker Ternium SA,
also fell. 
Still, Venezuelan pollster Luis Vicente Leon of Datanalisis
in Caracas said he's cautioning clients not to overreact. Chavez
is going after only public service companies, populist symbols
that previously belonged to the state, he said. Ex-President
Carlos Andres Perez sold the phone company to a group of private
investors led by GTE Corp. in 1991, a year before Chavez became
a national figure by trying to overthrow Perez. 
``Yesterday, we discovered prostate cancer,'' Leon said.
``It could metastasize, but there's not sufficient information.
In no way does it mean communism is around the corner.'' 
`Fear and Intimidation' 
Ricardo Hausman, a former Venezuelan planning minister who
teaches economics at Harvard University in Cambridge,
Massachusetts, said the danger of nationalizations is that it
will scare off foreign investment and make Venezuela, the
world's fifth-biggest oil exporter, more dependent on revenue
from oil, which already accounts for 90 percent of sales abroad. 
Since Chavez took office in 1999, companies have trimmed
spending on new plant and equipment so that non-government
investment equals no more than 4 percent of gross domestic
product, one of the lowest levels in the region. 
``There are people against this but there's very little
capacity to go against the state'' Hausman said. ``It's an
environment of fear and intimidation. There's no discussion of
what's good or bad for the public interest. It's just whether
you're an enemy of Chavez or not.'' 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Alex Kennedy in Caracas at 
akennedy1@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Andrew J. Barden at 
barden@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Anil Varma and Edgar Ortega" category="ASIA, INDIA, EMERGING_MARKETS, FINANCE" date="Jan 10, 2007  5:08 PM ET" keywords="Goldman Sachs Group Inc/The, ICICI Bank Ltd, IFCI Ltd, Punjab National Bank, SoftBank Corp, Asia, Asia ex. Japan, Australia, Banking, Corporate Actions, Corporate Finance, Emerging Markets, Financial Services, India, Industries, Japan, Markets, Mergers &amp;amp; Acquisitions, New York, New York Stock Exchange, New York Times Play, North America, Pacific Rim, Regions, Rules and Regulations, Securities Firms, South, Southeast Asia, Specialized Regions, Technology, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-10/nyse-goldman-invest-in-india-s-national-market-update10-.html"><headline>NYSE, Goldman Invest in India's National Market</headline><body>
NYSE Group Inc. and Goldman Sachs
Group Inc. led a group of investors that agreed to buy 20 percent
of the National Stock Exchange of India Ltd., tapping the world's
second-fastest-growing major economy. 
The National exchange will receive $115 million from NYSE
Group for a 5 percent stake in a transaction that values India's
largest equity market at $2.3 billion. Goldman, General Atlantic
LLC and Softbank Asian Infrastructure Fund will buy 5 percent
each, the closely held NSE said without disclosing a price. 
NYSE Group, operator of the world's biggest stock exchange,
is making its first investment in Asia through a market where the
combined worth of equities rose 50 percent in the past two years
to $820 billion. The Indian government lifted a ban on foreign
ownership three weeks ago as markets race to make acquisitions
and expand internationally into trading multiple securities. 
``Goldman and NYSE are clearly investing in India's long-term growth story,'' said Navneet Munot, who helps manage the
equivalent of $4 billion of Indian stocks and bonds at Birla
Sunlife Asset Management Co. in Mumbai. ``For NSE, a tie-up with
the NYSE would mean technology, visibility and access to new
financial products.'' 
India's government on Dec. 22 allowed international
investors to buy as much as a combined 49 percent in any of the
nation's 22 stock exchanges. The limit for a single investor was
set at 5 percent by the Securities and Exchange Board of India. 
Closest Competitor 
The Mumbai-based National Stock Exchange, home to companies
such as Reliance Industries Ltd. and Infosys Technologies Ltd.,
handled a daily average of 72.3 billion rupees ($1.6 billion) in
the past six months. That's more than twice the value of its
closest competitor, the Bombay Stock Exchange. 
The 14-year-old National exchange also dominates trading in
equity-based futures contracts and owns stakes in India's
National Commodity Derivatives Exchange and the Multi-Commodity
Exchange. 
India's gross domestic product grew 9.2 percent in the three
months through September, second only to China among the world's
major economies. India may overtake China in growth this year,
Credit Suisse Group economists estimated in December. 
The investment may help the NYSE draw the listing of Indian
companies, said NYSE Group Chief Financial Officer Nelson Chai.
It currently lists 10 Indian companies. 
Investing in Asia 
``We are going to be on the ground with them, meeting people
both at the corporate level and also within the regulatory and
government level,'' Chai told reports in a conference call from
Delhi. ``We are neither in a control position nor in a position
to capture cost synergies. But we do believe there are long-term
growth prospects here, and we're closer to participating in that
growth.'' 
Chief Executive Officer John Thain said on Dec. 20 NYSE
Group was looking to invest in Japan, China or India after
shareholders approved its $14.6 billion purchase of Euronext NV.
Thain, who joined the NYSE in 2004 from Goldman, has extend the
exchange's reach overseas and beyond equities trading since
transforming the 214-year-old market into a publicly traded
company through the acquisition of Archipelago Holdings Inc. in
March. 
NYSE Group shares rose $3.63, or 3.5 percent, to $108.21 at
4:01 p.m. in composite trading in New York. The stock has gained
68 percent since its debut March 8. 
Exchange Ownership 
Rival exchanges have also pursued international
acquisitions. Nasdaq Stock Market Inc. this week urged
shareholders of the London Stock Exchange Plc to accept its
takeover bid that values the company at 2.7 billion pounds ($5.2
billion). The Bombay exchange is considering selling stakes to
five overseas investors, India's Business Standard reported last
week, citing people it didn't identify. 
India's government said today it will set rules within six
weeks opening up the nation's $600 billion commodities markets to
international investors, clearing the way for the world's third-largest gold exchange to sell shares. 
``We hope to announce norms related to exchange ownership
soon,'' Yashwant Bhave, secretary at the department of Consumer
Affairs, said today in Mumbai. ``Norms on foreign investors'
participation in the market will also be announced.'' 
The deal unveiled today will be completed this quarter,
subject to regulatory approvals from various Indian government
agencies, the NYSE said in a statement. The 20 percent stake will
be sold by companies including ICICI Bank Ltd. (ICICIBC), IFCI Ltd. (IFCI), ILFS
Trust Company Ltd., Punjab National Bank (PNB) Ltd. and General
Insurance Corp. of India Ltd., the National exchange said in its
statement. 
Goldman and NYSE 
Goldman, the most profitable brokerage in Wall Street
history, already owns a 7 percent stake in India's National
Commodity  Derivatives Exchange Ltd. Goldman and the buyout firm
General Atlantic were early investors in Archipelago and are
currently among the top five shareholders of NYSE Group. 
General Atlantic, which overseas $12 billion in Greenwich,
Connecticut, last year acquired a stake in the New York
Mercantile Exchange in anticipation of an initial public
offering. Since their debut in November, shares of the world's
largest energy exchange have more than doubled. 
To contact the reporters on this story:
Anil Varma in Mumbai at 
avarma3@bloomberg.net;
Edgar Ortega in New York at 
ebarrales@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Erik Schatzker at 
eschatzker@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Patricia Hurtado and Edgar Ortega" category="LAW" date="Jan 10, 2007  4:12 PM ET" keywords="Intercontinental Exchange Inc, Corporate Governance, Executive Compensation, Financial Services, Industries, Justice Department, Lawsuits, Legal Affairs, Litigation, Markets, New York, New York City, New York Stock Exchange, North America, Regions, Specialized Regions, U.S. Government, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-10/grasso-lawyers-urge-canceling-of-order-on-nyse-pay-update6-.html"><headline>Grasso Lawyers Urge Canceling of Order on NYSE Pay</headline><body>
Richard Grasso, former New York Stock
Exchange chairman, asked an appeals court to toss out an order to
return as much as $112.2 million in pay to the Big Board. 
Justice Charles Ramos of New York State Supreme Court issued
the order in October, deciding in favor of then-Attorney General
Eliot Spitzer in the state's lawsuit over Grasso's pay. The judge
said the former chairman breached his duty to the exchange by
accepting the money and not fully informing the board of his
compensation. The higher court today heard arguments in Grasso's
appeal of Ramos's ruling, made without a jury before trial. 
``These are jury issues, whether he acted reasonably and
what did the board know,'' Grasso's attorney Gerson Zweifach told
a four-judge panel in Manhattan. 
The pretrial appeal is one of four by Grasso, 60, and the
last to be argued before the court. The former chairman also
challenged Ramos's refusal to leave the case, his decision to
hold a nonjury trial on whether the pay package was unreasonable
and his refusal to throw out four of six claims in the suit. 
The case is on hold during the appeals. 
Spitzer sued in 2004, the year after Grasso was ousted from
the NYSE over the pay package. The state said the $190 million
package was unreasonable for a not-for-profit corporation. 
Spitzer is now governor of New York, and the attorney
general is Andrew Cuomo. 
Office Turnover 
``It's a very important hearing, because if a bad decision
comes back for the attorney general, now that you have turnover
in the office, the odds are less and less that they will pursue
it,'' said Thomas Ajamie, a securities lawyer not part of the
case. ``Delay is advantageous for Grasso. The longer that he can
delay the day of reckoning, the more likely it will be that
events and people change.'' 
Grasso says his pay was reasonable, the judge is biased and
the attorney general lacked the authority to sue on the four of
six claims. 
Ramos shouldn't have made the October decision, called a
summary judgment, because material facts are disputed and should
be decided by a jury, Grasso's lawyers said. 
``It was error for the trial court to even attempt to
decide'' the pay issue without a jury trial, Zweifach told the
judges. A jury should hear evidence that the NYSE board knew and
approved of the money Grasso was ordered to return, the lawyer
said. 
`Weak Jury Argument' 
Grasso's lawyers said NYSE directors approving his pay were
an ``all-star team'' including Henry Paulson, then chairman of
Goldman Sachs  Co., now U.S. Treasury secretary; David Komansky,
former Merrill Lynch  Co. chairman; and Richard Fuld, chairman
of Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. 
``If they felt misled, hoodwinked or in the dark at any
time, they could have spoken out,'' Zweifach told the court.
``This was a highly vocal, highly sophisticated group of
executives.'' 
Avi Schick, who led the state's case as Spitzer's deputy,
told the judges Grasso created a pattern for compensation for
other NYSE executives, so he should have been familiar with all
aspects of his own. 
``Mr. Grasso, the chairman, the CEO, the one who made
millions, whose money it was to be, said, `I don't know how much
it was,''' Schick said. 
Schick's appearance was his last in the case, he said. He
became Spitzer's appointee as president of the Empire State
Development Corp., which encourages companies to locate in New
York and assists in redevelopment financing. 
Grasso's Career 
Grasso was the first NYSE staff member to rise through the
ranks to lead the exchange. He joined as a clerk in 1968 and was
named chief executive officer in 1995. He resigned in September
2003 amid controversy over his compensation. Since then, Chief
Executive Officer John Thain converted the stock exchange into a
for-profit company. 
As part of his October ruling, Ramos rejected Grasso's bid
for damages from the exchange over the loss of his job. The judge
ruled Grasso voluntarily resigned and wasn't fired. 
Robert Michels, a lawyer for the NYSE, told the appeals
court panel today that Ramos's decision should be upheld. 
The judges didn't say when they might rule, or whether they
will decide all the appeals at once or one at a time. They heard
arguments in the first appeal in May. 
The case is New York v. Grasso, 04-401620, New York Supreme
Court, New York County (Manhattan). 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Patricia Hurtado in New York
at  pathurtado@bloomberg.net;
Edgar Ortega in New York
at  ebarrales@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Patrick Oster at  poster@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Mathew Carr" category="ENERGY_MARKETS" date="Jan 10, 2007  1:26 PM ET" keywords="Macquarie Group Ltd, RWE AG, Alternative Energy, Biofuels, Coal, Coal Market, Commodities, Commodities Markets, DAX Index, Electricity Generation, Energy, Energy Trading, Environment, Euro Members, Europe, European Union, Germany, Industries, Markets, Natural Gas, Natural Gas Market, North America, Nuclear Power, Politics, Power Markets, Regions, Specialized Regions, United Kingdom, United States, Utilities" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-10/europe-loosens-emissions-target-to-protect-economy-update4-.html"><headline>Europe Loosens Emissions Target to Protect Economy</headline><body>
The European Union, the world's biggest
trade bloc, called for an easier target for greenhouse gas
emissions to safeguard its own economy and encourage global
negotiations on mandatory caps. 
The EU proposed cutting emissions by ``at least'' 20 percent
by 2020 compared with 1990, the European Commission, the regulatory
unit of the 27-nation bloc, said today. It rejected calls for a 30
percent cut, saying it would agree to such a reduction if all
developed nations did the same. 
Emissions targets that are too ambitious may put European
manufacturers at a disadvantage with competitors from nations
including the U.S. The EU in 2005 started a compulsory emissions
trading system, the world's largest, to meet goals under the 1997
Kyoto Protocol to curb global warming. The U.S. didn't adopt the
targets, citing the cost to its economy. 
``There are large energy interests in Europe that don't want
the region to go out on its own,'' said Kate Hampton, the head of
policy at Climate Change Capital, a London bank specializing in
environmental finance. ``That's a mistake,'' because it will reduce
future sales of so-called clean technology and services from Europe
to the rest of the world, she said. 
Europe wants to keep temperatures from rising 2 degrees
Celsius. Investment to curb emissions would be 0.5 percent of total
global gross domestic product over the 18 years through 2030,
according to a commission impact assessment. That's a much lower
price than the 5 percent minimum of GDP caused by delaying action,
according to a U.K.-government report published last year. 
Costly 
The EU's recommendation for shallower cuts in emissions is
part of a policy package published today that also aims to bolster
electricity and natural-gas competition. The bloc wants to make it
more costly for the energy industry to emit greenhouse gases while
limiting price increases for consumers. 
In November, the EU failed to set a deadline from
industrialized nations gathered in Nairobi, Kenya, to fix emissions
targets after the end of the protocol compliance period running for
the five years through 2012. 
China, which may overtake the U.S. as the world's biggest
emitter in 2009, according to the International Energy Agency, said
it supports UN talks to curb global emissions after 2012 and that
discussions on new caps after that should be completed by 2009. 
The 20 percent is a compromise ``on the low side of what was
discussed in the negotiations'' in the commission and is designed
to prompt all developed nations to enter negotiations on emission
curbs, Christian Kjaer, the chief executive officer of the European
Wind Energy Association, said today in a telephone interview from
Brussels. 
Capturing Emissions 
RWE AG (RWE), Germany's second-largest utility, and other power
utilities may need to capture emissions from every coal-fired
generator built after 2020  to help curb warming, the commission
said. 
``The commission believes that by 2020 all new coal-fired
plants should be fitted with CO2 capture and storage and existing
plants should then progressively follow the same approach,'' it
said in its ``Energy Policy for Europe'' report. 
Coal produces twice the emissions for each unit of electricity
generated, compared with natural gas. 
Europe wants to boost its use of renewable energy to 20
percent by 2020, the commission said. It probably won't be more
than 10 percent by 2010, it said. 
Biofuels Target 
The commission proposed a binding minimum target for so-called
biofuels of 10 percent of transport petrol and diesel by 2020.
Grown fuels absorb carbon dioxide as they grow, making them
contribute less to emissions blamed for global warming. 
Under mandatory rules that will need the backing of the EU's
27 member states, at least 10 percent of all fuel produced for
vehicles will be made from plants and fats by that year. The
existing target is a voluntary 5.75 percent biofuels use by 2010. 
``Mandatory targets will help the European biofuels industry
as it continues to establish itself and give confidence to
investors,'' Lutz Guderjahn, chief operating officer of
Cropenergies AG, a fuel-producing unit of Suedzucker AG, the
world's largest sugar producer, said in a telephone interview from
Manheim, Germany. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Mathew Carr in London at 
m.carr@bloomberg.net; 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Daniel Tilles at 
dtilles@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Mark Herlihy" category="UK_IRELAND" date="Jan 10, 2007 11:59 AM ET" keywords="Cooper-Standard Holding Inc, Reed Elsevier PLC, Analyst Ratings, Benelux, Education, Entertainment, Euro Members, Europe, FTSE 100 Index, Industries, Internet, Markets, Media, Netherlands, Publishing, Regions, Specialized Regions, Technology, United Kingdom" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-10/reed-elsevier-may-be-buyout-target-say-analysts-update1-.html"><headline>Reed Elsevier May Be Buyout Target, Say Analysts</headline><body>
Shares of Reed Elsevier Plc (REL), the
owner of the LexisNexis database and Harcourt educational
publisher, rose after Credit Suisse analysts said the company
may become the target of a buyout firm. 
``We have screened the European media sector and Reed
scores highly for a leveraged buyout risk,'' analysts including
Robert Lambert wrote in a research note today. 
London-based Reed has low debt, an ``attractive valuation
and strong free cash flow,'' which could provide a ``very
healthy return for a private equity investor,'' the analysts
said. 
Shares of Reed Elsevier rose 7 pence, or 1.2 percent, to
582 pence in London, valuing the company at 7.4 billion pounds
($14.3 billion). The shares gained 2.7 percent last year. 
Reed's education unit competes with McGraw-Hill Cos.,
Houghton Mifflin Co. and Pearson Plc in the markets for text
books, test marking and online materials. Reed Chief Executive
Officer Crispin Davis said in November the company is focusing
on the Internet for acquisitions. 
Analysts said Jan. 5 that Reed could be a potential
takeover target of Amsterdam-based business publisher Wolters
Kluwer NV. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Mark Herlihy in London at 
Mherlihy1@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Zimri Smith at  zsmith@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Elena Distaso and Andrew Frye" category="ITALY" date="Jan 10, 2007  6:58 AM ET" keywords="GTECH SpA, Intralot SA-Integrated Lottery Systems &amp;amp; Services, Casinos, Consumer Goods, Euro Members, Europe, Gaming, Greece, Industries, Italy, Leisure, Regions, Retail, Technology, United Kingdom" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-10/lottomatica-camelot-to-bid-for-u-k-lottery-license-update1-.html"><headline>Lottomatica, Camelot to bid for U.K. Lottery License</headline><body>
Lottomatica SpA, Italy's biggest
lottery company, will bid for the license to operate the U.K.'s
lottery when it comes up for renewal in 2009, Chairman Lorenzo Pellicioli said. 
The Rome-based company will make a joint bid with Camelot
Group Plc, the current operator, Pellicioli said today in an
interview in Milan. Camelot, which won its current license in
2001, said ticket sales rose 5.2 percent to 5.01 billion pounds
($9.71 billion) in the year ended March 31, 2006. 
Lottomatica spent $4.65 billion last year buying West
Greenwich, Rhode Island-based Gtech Holdings Corp., the world's
biggest seller of computerized lottery systems, to expand abroad
and reduce its dependence on its domestic concession. 
The company may be vying for the U.K. tender along with
Intralot SA, the world's third-biggest gaming company, which has
said it intends to bid. 
Offers for the 10-year U.K. license are due by Feb. 9, and
the winner will be named in August, according to the U.K.'s
National Lottery Commission Web site. 
Camelot is a private company with five main shareholders De
La Rue Holdings, Cadbury Schweppes, Thales, Fujitsu Services,
and the U.K.'s Royal Mail. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Andrew Frye in Milan at  afrye@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editors responsible for this story:
Frank Connelly at  fconnelly@bloomberg.net
Katherine Snyder at  ksnyder@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Thom Weidlich and Christopher Scinta" category="LAW, TRANSPORTATION" date="Jan 11, 2007  6:46 PM ET" keywords="Bank of America Corp, General Motors Co, UBS AG, Auto Parts, Automobiles, Bankruptcies, Corporate Actions, Corporate Finance, Financial Services, Industries, Labor &amp;amp; Unions, Lawsuits, Legal Affairs, Litigation, Markets, Mergers &amp;amp; Acquisitions, Michigan, Mutual &amp;amp; Hedge Funds, Mutual Funds, New York, North America, Regions, Securities Firms, Specialized Regions, Transportation, Trusts, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, U.S. Midwest, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-11/delphi-creditors-drop-objections-to-cerberus-bid-update6-.html"><headline>Delphi Creditors Drop Objections to Cerberus Bid</headline><body>
Delphi Corp.'s creditors, vendors
and unions withdrew objections to a $3.4 billion investment by
five financial firms led by Cerberus Capital Management LP,
Delphi's lawyer Jack Butler said. 
``Four of our six unions filed preliminary objections which
are now resolved,'' Butler said today at a hearing in U.S.
Bankruptcy Court in New York before Judge Robert Drain. 
Shareholders of Troy, Michigan-based Delphi, the bankrupt
auto-parts maker, pushed for defeat of the investment plan, as
did the U.S. Trustee and Highland Capital Management LP, which
submitted a $4.7 billion competing bid, Butler said. 
Delphi said Dec. 18 it supported the bid by New York-based
Cerberus. Today's hearing, first set for last week, was delayed
after Dallas-based Highland's offer. Delphi met with Highland's
officials earlier this month, raising the prospect of a showdown
over the future of the onetime General Motors Corp. subsidiary.
GM supports the Cerberus proposal. 
Drain finished hearing testimony today. He will hear oral
arguments from the lawyers and rule on the Cerberus offer
tomorrow, he said. 
Witness Testimony 
In questioning witnesses, Bonnie Steingart, a Delphi
shareholders' lawyer, tried to show the millions of dollars in
fees allowed Cerberus-Appaloosa investors if the plan falls
through are too high. 
``The board had a very extensive discussion on the terms of
the fees, not only the amount and how they compared to market
but also under the terms and conditions the fees would be
received,'' said David L. Resnick, head of restructuring at
investment bank Rothschild Inc., a Delphi adviser. ``Looking at
the agreement as a whole, it felt the agreement was a reasonable
one.'' 
Steingart also tried to show the investment plan is too
advantageous to preferred-stock holders. The plan prices the
common stock at $45 a share, and preferred stock would be
convertible to common stock at $35 a share, John D. Sheehan, the
company's chief restructuring officer, testified. 
No Formal Evaluation 
Steingart asked Delphi chairman Robert S. Miller if the
board was ever told the Cerberus investors could realize a total
of $500 million in fees, expenses and implied value from the
discount on the rights offering. 
Miller said he didn't recall that figure being mentioned. 
``That number does not surprise or shock me,'' he said. ``I
sincerely hope that if we proceed on this deal, they do make a
lot of money, because that will mean Delphi was a great
success.'' 
Miller said the company is still open to other investors'
suggesting plans. Delphi said in a court filing yesterday it may
reconsider Highland's offer if certain issues are addressed. 
``If a better offer comes along, it will now have the
hurdle of overcoming the fees of these plan investors,'' he
said, referring to the Cerberus group. 
The bid by Cerberus and the others, including Chatham, New
Jersey-based Appaloosa Management LP, gives them too much
control for too little money, Highland said in a filing.
Appaloosa is Delphi's largest shareholder; Highland, the second-largest. 
The other firms in the group are Harbinger Capital Partners
Master Fund I Ltd. and Merrill Lynch  Co., both based in New
York, and UBS Securities LLC, based in Stamford, Connecticut.
Merrill is a passive minority investor in Bloomberg LP, the
parent of Bloomberg News. 
Investors' Aims 
Delphi is the biggest supplier for GM, which wants the
company to exit bankruptcy as quickly as possible. 
Before Highland announced its offer, the Committee of
Equity Security Holders, the unsecured creditors' committee, the
Delphi Trade Committee and the International Union of Electric
Workers, Delphi's second-largest union, all filed objections to
the plan by Cerberus. 
The five investors said Dec. 18 they would invest as much
as $3.4 billion in Delphi in exchange for a 30 percent to
70 percent stake in the company once it emerges from court
protection. 
Both the Cerberus and Highland investment proposals seek to
protect Delphi employee pensions. The biggest differences center
on stock. 
Highland wants all existing shareholders to participate in
a $4.7 billion rights offering, with no convertible preferred
shares. Highland proposes to keep an 8.8 percent stake in Delphi
once the parts-maker exits bankruptcy. 
Stock Purchase 
The Cerberus-Appaloosa group said it would purchase
$1.2 billion of convertible preferred Delphi stock and about
$200.5 million of common stock in the reorganized company. 
The group said it is committed to paying $1.98 billion for
any unsubscribed shares of common stock offered to existing
shareholders. 
Highland partner Patrick Daugherty testified today that his
investment firm didn't talk with the unions before submitting
its plan. He said Highland's plan calls for leaving in place
much of the strategy Delphi has developed, including the GM
framework and the treatment of the unions. 
``The only thing we changed was the $1.2 billion going to
the preferred,'' he said. ``We simply took that value and moved
it down to the shareholders.'' 
Delphi hasn't said what it will do with its current stock.
Shares of the company fell 39 cents to $3.08 in over-the-counter
trading. 
The case is In re: Delphi Corp., 05-44481, U.S. Bankruptcy
Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). 
To contact the reporters on this story:
Thom Weidlich in New York
at  tweidlich@bloomberg.net;
Christopher Scinta in New York
at  cscinta@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Patrick Oster at  poster@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Andy Fixmer" category="US" date="Jan 11, 2007  6:27 PM ET" keywords="AMC Entertainment Holdings Inc, JPMorgan Chase &amp;amp; Co, National CineMedia Inc, Regal Entertainment Group, Advertising, Banking, Buyout, Cinema, Colorado, Corporate Actions, Corporate Finance, Entertainment, Financial Services, Industries, Initial Public Offerings, Markets, Media, Missouri, Movies, Mutual &amp;amp; Hedge Funds, New Stocks, New York, North America, Private Equity, Regions, Specialized Regions, Trusts, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, U.S. Midwest, U.S. West, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-11/national-cinemedia-seeks-up-to-840-million-from-ipo-update2-.html"><headline>National CineMedia Seeks Up to $840 Million From IPO</headline><body>
National CineMedia Inc. (NCMI), a seller of
on-screen advertising shown in movie theaters, set an expected
price range of $18 to $20 for an initial public offering that
may raise as much as $840 million. 
The company, jointly owned by the three biggest U.S. cinema
chains, will sell at least 38 million common shares, or about 41
percent of its equity, it said in a U.S. Securities and Exchange
Commission filing today. At $20 each, that would make the
Centennial, Colorado-based company worth $1.88 billion. 
As advertisers look for new ways to reach audiences,
analysts including Research Associates' Marla Backer have said
rates for ads on movie screens will rise. National CineMedia
sells digital programming for almost 14,000 screens before
feature shows and for 1,722 television displays in 670 theater
lobbies, the company said in the filing. 
National CineMedia began an effort in June to help movie
producers distribute their films in digital format, a project
that will be retained by the company's owners, AMC Entertainment
Inc., Cinemark Inc. and Regal Entertainment Group. (RGC) Those
companies also will keep as much as a 59.5 percent stake in
National CineMedia after the IPO, the company said. 
Adding Loews Screens 
The three chains and affiliates own 1,100 U.S. theaters,
National CineMedia said. Another 107 Loews theaters, with 1,275
screens, will become part of the company's network in June 2008. 
While it gets more than 90 percent of sales from ads,
National CineMedia also facilitates corporate meetings in
theaters using its digital distribution network, and provides
concerts and sports events to cinema operators. The company said
the development of digital film distribution systems may help it
integrate its content-delivery business with the equipment
developed and used in theaters owned by its founders. 
After paying fees, the offering will produce proceeds of
$674.3 million, assuming the shares fetch $19 each, National
CineMedia estimates. Another 4 million shares may be sold if
demand warrants, the company said. 
Subsequent to the offering, National CineMedia will set up
an eight-year lending agreement for loans of up to $725 million,
according to the filing. 
National CineMedia, which will trade on the Nasdaq Stock
Market under the symbol NCMI, said it lost $11.2 million on
revenue of $145.2 million for the nine months ended Sept. 28,
according to the filing. 
The IPO is being managed by Credit Suisse Group, JPMorgan
Chase, Lehman Bros. and Morgan Stanley. 
National CineMedia spokeswoman Lauren Leff didn't return a
call seeking comment. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Andy Fixmer in Los Angeles at 
afixmer@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Emma Moody in New York at 
emoody@Bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By William Freebairn" category="RETAIL" date="Jan 11, 2007  5:26 PM ET" keywords="Anheuser-Busch InBev NV, Grupo Modelo SAB de CV, SABMiller PLC, Africa, Alcoholic Beverages, Antitrust, Beverages, Consumer Goods, Emerging Markets, Europe, FTSE 100 Index, Industries, Latin America, Legal Affairs, Leisure, Litigation, Markets, Mexico, Mideast, Missouri, North America, Regions, Retail, Retailing, Rules and Regulations, South Africa, Specialized Regions, Trade, U.S. Midwest, United Kingdom, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-11/modelo-says-agency-permits-exclusive-store-contracts-update3-.html"><headline>Modelo Says Agency Permits Exclusive Store Contracts</headline><body>
Grupo Modelo SA (GMODELOC), Mexico's largest
beermaker, can continue exclusive contracts with the country's
retailers after antitrust regulators rejected a complaint by
SABMiller Plc. 
The Federal Competition Commission ordered an end to the
exclusive contracts in August, and then reversed itself in a
ruling yesterday, Modelo, the maker of Corona beer, said in an
e-mailed statement. The investigation has ended, the company
said. 
The decision bolsters Modelo and limits the access of
rival SABMiller, the world's second-largest beermaker, to the
Mexican market. The contracts in question were deals with
independent stores to carry only Modelo beverage brands, often
in refrigerators provided by the beermaker. 
``Obviously, if you have to open up your coolers to other
brands, it would hurt,'' Lauren Torres, an HSBC analyst, said
today. ``With rulings like this, it makes it seem much like a
protected market.'' 
SABMiller (SAB) had accused Modelo and the country's second-
largest beermaker Fomento Economico Mexicano SAB, also known as
Femsa, of monopolistic practices in beer distribution.
Together, the two companies control 99 percent of domestic beer
sales, Torres said. 
``Modelo and Femsa dominate cooler space, particularly at
mom-and-pop retailers where people buy products cold,'' Torres
said. She initiated coverage of Modelo Dec. 13 with a
``neutral'' rating. 
Grupo Modelo shares rose 80 centavos, or 1.4 percent, to
57.76 pesos on the Mexican stock exchange. 
Uncertainty Ended? 
Modelo, which also owns a chain of convenience stores that
distribute its products, said the ruling ends uncertainty about
its distribution deals with independent retailers. 
``The exclusive contracts are competitive,'' said Jorge Siegrist Prado, vice president of corporate relations for
Modelo, in a telephone interview from Mexico City. He said the
company showed regulators that the deals did not affect prices. 
Carlos Laboy, an analyst at Bear Stearns  Co., said the
company also provided beer licenses to retailers in exchange
for exclusivity. There are several additional barriers for non-
Mexican companies to enter the market, including the widespread
use of returnable glass bottles and strength of regional
brands, he said. 
Eduardo Perez Motta, president of the FCC, wasn't
immediately available for comment, according to his office in
Mexico City. 
`Disappointed' on Ruling 
Peter Marino, a spokesman for SABMiller's Miller Brewing
Co., said the company had not seen the ruling. ``We're
disappointed if the FCC is reversing its prior decision,'' he
said in a telephone interview from Milwaukee. 
Femsa released a statement saying it has yet to hear from
the antitrust regulators on the complaint against it. 
Modelo has 55 percent of the beer market in Mexico, which
is the world's eighth-largest beer consumer, Torres wrote in a
research report last month. 
The company is 50 percent owned by Anheuser-Busch Cos. (BUD),
the world's largest brewer. In January, Modelo began a new
import agreement to allow Constellation Brands Inc. to handle
distribution of its beers including Corona for the U.S. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
William Freebairn in Mexico City at 
wfreebairn@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Michael Nol at 
mnol@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Frederic Tomesco" category="CANADA" date="Jan 11, 2007  4:23 PM ET" keywords="BCE Inc, Corus Entertainment Inc, Advertising, Cable Television, Canada, Cinema, Computer Software, Computers, Corporate Actions, Corporate Finance, Earnings, Entertainment, Industries, Internet, Manitoba, Media, Mergers &amp;amp; Acquisitions, Movies, North America, Ontario, Publishing, Quebec, Radio, Regions, Technology" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-11/astral-media-says-first-quarter-net-doubles-on-tv-update4-.html"><headline>Astral Media Says First-Quarter Net Doubles on TV</headline><body>
Astral Media Inc. (ACM/A), Canada's biggest
pay- and specialty-television broadcaster, said first-quarter
profit more than doubled as tax costs fell and TV advertising
sales increased. 
Net income in the quarter ended Nov. 30 climbed to C$32.6
million ($27.7 million), or 60 cents a share, from C$15.2
million, or 27 cents, Montreal-based Astral said today in a
statement. Astral had C$14.8 million in costs last year from
taxes after the Quebec government raised the corporate rate. 
Astral, which owns stakes in 16 specialty TV stations, won
more subscribers with channels such as Super Ecran and the Movie
Network, helping to boost TV ad sales 14 percent. Viewers have
migrated from conventional stations to pay channels that target
their interests, helping Astral increase total sales 6.9
percent. 
``Astral has excellent exposure to all of the highest
growth media segments, each of which is demonstrating solid
momentum heading into 2007,'' RBC Capital Markets analyst Drew McReynolds said in a report Jan. 8. He has a ``Top Pick'' rating
on the stock. 
Excluding some items, Astral was expected to earn 59 cents
a share, the average estimate of five analysts surveyed by
Bloomberg. The estimate of Scotia Capital analyst Andrew Mitchell was 58 cents. 
Canadian viewers of conventional television fell to 41
percent of the population in 2005 from 47 percent in 1999, while
viewers of specialty channels rose to 36 percent from 23
percent, according to Nielsen data. 
Radio, TV 
Earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation and
amortization in Astral's television unit, which accounts for 73
percent of revenue, rose 12 percent to C$43.1 million in the
quarter. On that basis, profit in the radio unit rose 4.3
percent to C$10.5 million, while earnings in the outdoor
advertising unit declined less than 1 percent to C$5 million. 
Subscription fees paid by cable and satellite-TV companies
account for about 60 percent of Astral's revenue, while the rest
comes from the time and space that the company sells to
advertisers. The company also owns more than 3,700 outdoor
advertising billboards in Quebec and Ontario and 29 radio
stations in Eastern Canada. 
Astral is seeking purchases in TV, radio and outdoor ads,
Chief Executive Officer Ian Greenberg said on a conference call
today. Rival CanWest Global Communications Corp. yesterday
agreed to buy Alliance Atlantis Communications Inc., which owns
13 specialty channels, for C$2.3 billion with Goldman Sachs
Group Inc. 
Possible Partners 
Astral could link up with broadcaster Corus Entertainment
Inc. (CJR/B) to compete with CanWest and CTVglobemedia Inc., which owns
the Globe and Mail newspaper and the CTV network, Desjardins
Securities analyst Carl Bayard said today in a report. 
Astral's widely traded Class A shares rose 16 cents to
C$44.46 by 4 p.m. in trading on the Toronto Stock Exchange. The
stock has gained 44 percent in the past year. 
(Astral held a conference call earlier today to discuss the
results. A replay will be available at
http://www.astralmedia.com.) 
To contact the reporter for this story:
Frederic Tomesco in Montreal at 
tomesco@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
David Scanlan at 
dscanlan@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By William Roberts" category="" date="Jan 11, 2007  2:00 PM ET" keywords="Aastrom Biosciences Inc, Geron Corp, StemCells Inc, Biotechnology, California, Colorado, Congress, Delaware, Drugs, Health Care, Industries, Iowa, Legal Affairs, Litigation, Massachusetts, North America, North Carolina, Pennsylvania, Pharmaceuticals, Politics, Regions, Science, Specialized Regions, Stem Cell Research, U.S., U.S. Government, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, U.S. Midwest, U.S. Northeast, U.S. South, U.S. Southeast, U.S. West, United States, White House" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-11/house-debates-stem-cell-research-under-veto-threat-update2-.html"><headline>House Debates Stem-Cell Research Under Veto Threat</headline><body>
The House of Representatives is
preparing to challenge President George W. Bush on stem-cell
research by voting again on legislation Bush vetoed last year. 
Lawmakers plan to vote today on whether to expand federal
funding for stem-cell research using discarded human embryos. 
Advocates of the measure expect to win broad bipartisan
support for the measure, though perhaps not more than the 290
votes needed to override a presidential veto. House approval of
the measure would send the legislation to the Senate, where
backers say they hope to amend it to make it more palatable to
Republicans. 
``My message to the White House is this; the president and
his advisers need to support all ethical research,'' Colorado
Democrat Representative Diana DeGette said at a press conference
yesterday with a dozen House freshmen Democrats who support the
measure. 
If enacted, the stem-cell legislation would overturn Bush's
2001 ban on federal funding of research using newly created
embryonic stem cells. The measure is part of House Speaker Nancy Pelosi and the House Democratic majority's first 100 hours
agenda. The White House today issued a veto threat. 
``The administration strongly opposes House passage of H.R.
3, which would use federal taxpayer dollars to support and
encourage the destruction of human life for research,'' the
White House's Office of Budget and Management said in a
statement of policy. ``If H.R. 3 were presented to the
president, he would veto the bill.'' 
Boehner Predicts Veto 
``It's likely to pass the Senate in the next couple of
months and be vetoed by the president,'' said Representative
John Boehner, the House Republican minority leader. ``I do not
believe that the votes are in the House or in the Senate to
override the president's veto.'' 
Advocates of stem-cell research say using cells taken from
human embryos may lead to cures for diseases such as Alzheimer's
disease, Parkinson's, juvenile diabetes and Lou Gehrig's disease
as well as spinal cord injuries and other ailments. 
``The most respected scientists across the nation are
poised to make significant advances toward a cure and better
treatments for diabetes, but are being severely restricted by
current standards,'' said Darlene Cain, head of the American
Diabetes Association, in an e-mailed statement. 
In August 2001, Bush issued an executive order limiting
federal research to 71 stem-cell lines previously derived from
fertilized human eggs, saying that creating new ones would
involve the destruction of human embryos. 
`Strikes a Balance' 
``The president's policy strikes a balance of supporting
funding -- federal funding for research into stem cells while
avoiding federal funding that would encourage the destruction of
embryos,'' White House spokesman Tony Snow said Jan. 9. 
The number of stem-cell lines that can still be replicated
for research has dwindled to 22, and most of those are
contaminated, the administration said in a report last year. 
The House legislation is sponsored by DeGette and
Representative Mike Castle, a Delaware Republican. It passed the
Republican-controlled House in 2005 by a 238-194 margin with 50
Republicans joining Democrats. 
Democrats now control the House by a 233 to 202 margin, and
most of the 30 newly elected Democrats who replaced Republicans
in the November election are likely to vote for the measure. 
``It will be difficult to get the 290 votes, but we are
gaining on it,'' DeGette said. 
Cells Mutate 
Republican opponents said research using embryonic stem
cells has yet to produce a viable therapy for humans, in part
because the cells tend to mutate as they grow. Alternatives
using adult stem-cells are proving more practical, they said. 
``We're being forced to vote this week on the promotion of
outdated stem-cell science that destroys human embryos,'' said
Representative Joe Pitts, a Pennsylvania Republican. 
``Proponents of this legislation don't just want to be able
to do embryonic stem-cell research,'' said Representative Mike Pence, an Indiana Republican. ``They want me to pay for it and,
like 43 percent of Americans who believe that life begins at
conception, I've got a problem with that.'' 
Not all Democrats support the measure. 
``I made some promises during the campaign and I am going
to keep them,'' said Representative Joe Donnelly, a Democrat
from Indiana who is Catholic and anti-abortion. ``I'm
optimistic, very hopeful that other kinds of research -- adult
stem-cell, cord-blood and amniotic stem-cell -- research will
lead to some breakthroughs.'' 
Earliest Source 
``All of these attempts to find a substitute are
specious,'' said Tom Okarma, chief executive officer of Geron
Corp. (GERN), a biotech company based in Menlo Park, California.
Embryonic stem cells are the ``earliest possible source of self-renewing cells that can form all cells in the body.'' 
Under Bush's policy, researchers and companies in other
countries are overtaking their U.S. counterparts and ``we're
wasting money on adult stem-cell research,'' Okarma said. 
DeGette said she hopes Bush will negotiate on the issue. If
not, she'll try to attach the measure to a must-pass spending
bill. 
Senate Majority Leader Harry Reid, who calls the House
measure a ``high priority,'' has made no commitment about when
he'll bring it to the Senate floor, said his spokesman Jim Manley. 
Senate Measure 
Senate legislation was introduced by Senator Tom Harkin, an
Iowa Democrat, and Senator Arlen Specter, a Pennsylvania
Republican. It is likely to be taken up by the Senate Health
Education and Labor Committee, where it may be rewritten to try
to draw support from Republican and Democratic opponents and
make it tougher for Bush to veto. 
``There will probably be amendments offered to that in the
Senate,'' said Senator Jon Kyl, an Arizona Republican who
opposes federal funding for embryonic stem-cell research. 
Kyl said he had received no signal from the White House
that the president would compromise with the Democrats. 
``If it is the same thing we voted on before, the result
will be virtually the same,'' Kyl said. 
Federal funding for stem-cell research is provided through
research grants by the National Institutes of Health in
Bethesda, Maryland. NIH will distribute $608 million in grants
for stem-cell research this year, of which $39 million will go
to human embryonic research under the 2001 restrictions put in
place by Bush. 
New Laboratories 
Arnold Kriegstein, director of the stem-cell institute at
the University of California-San Francisco, said the ban has
stymied U.S. research by preventing senior scientists from
working with embryonic cells and discouraging young researchers
from entering the field. 
Lifting the ban would ``encourage researchers to start
using human lines and bring much closer the day when stem cells
will be used as therapies for disease,'' Kriegstein said. 
Bush's ban ``forced people in the academic field to
scramble for funds, which is hard to do,'' said Okarma. ``Even
when they're successful in finding non-NIH money it's not enough
to do the science right.'' 
Sean Tipton, president of the Coalition for the Advancement
of Medical Research, a group of research and patient
organizations, said that new funding wouldn't result in
immediate breakthroughs. 
``If the president signs this bill, is stem-cell research
going to cure diabetes the next day? The answer is no,'' he
said. ``But we know that every day the current federal policy
remains is another day's delay in finding the answers.'' 
To contact the reporter on this story:
William Roberts in Washington at 
wroberts@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Michael Forsythe at 
mforsythe@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Tim Mullaney" category="EXECUTIVE, US, FUNDS, STOCKS" date="Jan 11, 2007 11:49 AM ET" keywords="Apple Inc, Baidu Inc, Best Buy Co Inc, Google Inc, Jacob Internet Fund Inc - Investor, Munder Growth Opportunities Fund - A, Tencent Holdings Ltd, Asia, Asia ex. Japan, Australia, California, China, Computer Software, E-commerce, Emerging Markets, Entertainment, Hong Kong, Industries, Internet, Korea, Leisure, Markets, Media, Mutual &amp;amp; Hedge Funds, Mutual Funds, North America, Pacific Rim, Personal Funds Column, Regions, Specialized Regions, Taiwan, Technology, Trusts, U.S. West, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-11/jacob-fund-recovers-from-bust-fails-to-win-investors-update1-.html"><headline>Jacob Fund Recovers From Bust, Fails to Win Investors</headline><body>
Ryan Jacob, whose U.S. mutual fund
plunged 95 percent when the Internet bubble burst, now ranks as
the top-performing money manager among his peers. 
His Jacob Internet Fund (JAMFX) rose at an annual rate of 23 percent
during the past five years, twice as much as the Goldman Sachs
Internet Index and the biggest gain of more than 300 technology
stock funds tracked by Chicago-based Morningstar Inc. It climbed
16 percent in 2006, marking the fifth straight year that returns
beat the Standard  Poor's 500 Index. 
Still, Jacob struggles to attract investors. The $93.4
million fund, managed from a rented beach house in Redondo Beach,
California, is less than one-fifth the size of the Munder
Internet Fund, which gained 0.4 percent last year and also lost
more than 90 percent of its value during the Internet bust. 
``I understand there are lingering feelings,'' said Jacob,
37. ``That's legitimate. We should be larger, but it's up to me
to make the effort.'' 
Jacob said he has tried to change people's perceptions about
the fund by focusing on profitable companies with cash-rich
balance sheets. That's a change from 1999 and 2000 when he clung
to shares of money-losing stocks as the fund's assets cratered to
$16 million from a peak of $300 million. He plugged the shares he
liked so often on television that he ended up marrying a producer
from CNN. 
``The mistakes we made back then were things we didn't do,''
Jacob said. ``We didn't take profits. We didn't manage position
sizes.'' 
Board's Directive 
His fund sagged in 2001 as Intertrust Technologies Corp. of
Santa Clara, California, his biggest holding, plummeted 99
percent from its peak. The second-largest investment, Internet
marketing company Be Free Inc., plunged to less than $2 from $56
before he sold his shares. Exodus Communications Inc., another
large holding, went bankrupt. 
The board of Jacob's fund ordered the money manager to
change his strategy on Aug. 16, 2001. Two days later, Jacob got
married. 
``We looked at the indexes and said, `You have to outperform
these people and you have to do it now,''' said director Jeff Schwarzchild, who was the best man at Jacob's wedding. 
Now Jacob puts almost half his fund's assets in companies
with lots of cash. One example: Napster Inc., the music
subscription service, has $90 million in cash and marketable
securities to back its $174 million market value. 
Apple and Murdoch 
Reg Liang, an analyst at Morningstar, said Jacob's fund is
risky. Its beta, a measure of volatility, is 10 percent higher
than the general market, and expenses are above average at about
$24 a year for every $1,000 invested. The T. Rowe Price Blue Chip
Growth Fund, which invests in tech companies, has fees of $8.50.
Morningstar gives Jacob's fund its highest rating of five stars. 
Jacob said he hopes to reduce the expenses to $20 by the end
of the year. 
With the rest of his fund, Jacob bets the Internet will keep
growing faster than the economy. He's invested in digital
entertainment through Apple Computer Inc. (AAPL), the Cupertino,
California-based maker of the iPod, and in Rupert Murdoch's News
Corp., owner of MySpace.com. Google Inc. (GOOG), owner of the most-used
search engine, is his largest holding, accounting for 5.7
percent. 
Jacob's biggest gains in 2006 came from China. Hong Kong-based CDC Corp., which runs the China.com portal, almost tripled.
Advertising-services company Tencent Holdings Ltd. (700), based in
Shenzhen, China, jumped more than threefold. 
Losing Share 
``He may have been a jerk years ago, but if you were in his
fund at $1 a share, it's not bad,'' said Gil Alvarado, a nurse
practitioner from Albuquerque, New Mexico, who owns Jacob
Internet in his Roth IRA. The shares of Jacob's fund closed Jan.
9 at $2.77. 
Jacob has reduced his holdings of CDC and Tencent, and cut
his stake in Baidu.com Inc. (BIDU), a Beijing-based Internet search
engine, in December after the stock gained 60 percent. 
He still makes mistakes. Jacob bought Gibraltar-based
Partygaming Plc before a U.S. Web-gambling crackdown. He lost
money on Sunnyvale, California-based Yahoo Inc., which fell 35
percent last year after surrendering market share to Google. He
said he got rid of Partygaming, and Yahoo is ``on probation.'' 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Tim Mullaney in New York at 
Tmullaney1@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Emma Moody at 
emoody@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Jeff Green" category="LAW, TRANSPORTATION" date="Jan 11, 2007  9:50 AM ET" keywords="Ford Motor Co, General Motors Co, Auto Parts, Automobiles, Bankruptcies, Bonds, Corporate Actions, Corporate Bonds, Corporate Finance, Distressed Corporate Bonds, Financial Services, Hedge Funds, Industries, Legal Affairs, Litigation, Markets, Mergers &amp;amp; Acquisitions, Michigan, Mutual &amp;amp; Hedge Funds, Mutual Funds, New York, North America, Regions, Specialized Regions, Transportation, Trusts, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, U.S. Midwest, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-11/highland-says-cerberus-bid-for-delphi-is-unfair-update2-.html"><headline>Highland Says Cerberus Bid for Delphi Is Unfair</headline><body>
Highland Capital Management LP, the
investment adviser offering to put $4.7 billion into bankrupt
Delphi Corp., said a rival offer by Cerberus Capital Management
LP and others gives them too much control for too little money. 
The $3.4 billion proposal by Cerberus, Appaloosa Management
LP and other investors would give the group the exclusive right
to control as much as 30 percent of Delphi, a maker of auto
parts, when it emerges from bankruptcy, at a price well below
the estimated equity value of $57.90 per share, Highland said in
papers filed yesterday in U.S. Bankruptcy Court in New York. 
``Highland Capital believes the Appaloosa/Cerberus
proposal, as currently presented, disenfranchises stockholders,
freezes them out of an equal opportunity to purchase common
stock and represents a failure of Delphi's board to uphold its
fiduciary duties to current stockholders,'' Highland partner
Patrick Daugherty said in a declaration filed with the court. 
Delphi said it will support the Cerberus-Appaloosa bid
because the Highland offer doesn't deliver ``superior value.''
Highland said the Cerberus proposal pays creditors $361 million
more than necessary, to the detriment of equity holders.
Appaloosa is Troy, Michigan-based Delphi's biggest shareholder;
Highland is the second-biggest. 
Hearing 
A hearing on the Appaloosa bid is scheduled for today in
bankruptcy court in New York. 
Delphi said last month that the group of five financial
firms, including Cerberus, Harbinger Capital Partners, Merrill
Lynch  Co. and UBS Securities LLC, could own from 30 percent of
70 percent of the reorganized company. 
Highland also said it has hired retired Visteon Corp. Chief
Executive Officer Peter Pestillo, a former Ford Motor Co. (F) vice
chairman, to help it with its bid. David Thursfield, who ran
Ford's international operations until 2004, runs a Cerberus
automotive unit. 
Delphi announced today that it has hired W.Y. Campbell 
Co. to explore the sale of its powertrain and suspension-mounts
business, a unit with an estimated $160 million in 2006 revenue
and 700 employees in five countries. 
Delphi, which was spun off by General Motors Corp. in 1999,
sought bankruptcy protection in October 2005. The company
reported a $2.35 billion loss in 2005 on $26.9 billion in sales. 
Delphi shares fell 10 cents to $3.47 a share in over-the-counter trading yesterday. The shares have risen 5 percent since
Dec. 15, the last trading day before the Cerberus bid was
announced. 
The case is In re: Delphi Corp., 05-44481, U.S. Bankruptcy
Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Jeff Green in Southfield, Michigan, at 
jgreen16@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editors responsible for this story:
Patrick Oster at  poster@bloomberg.net;
Dave Versical at  dversical@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Angus Whitley" category="MANUFACTURING" date="Jan 11, 2007  3:32 AM ET" keywords="Apple Inc, Cirrus Logic Inc, Unisem M Bhd, Asia, Asia ex. Japan, Australia, California, Computers, Emerging Markets, Industries, Machinery, Malaysia, Manufacturing, Markets, North America, Pacific Rim, Regions, Semiconductors, Small Cap Stocks, South, Southeast Asia, Technology, U.S. West, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-11/unisem-says-clients-working-with-apple-stock-surges-update1-.html"><headline>Unisem Says Clients Working With Apple; Stock Surges</headline><body>
Unisem (UNI) (M) Bhd., Malaysia's second-biggest semiconductor packager, said some clients have been
working with Apple Inc. (AAPL) on the production of the company's new
mobile phone. Unisem shares jumped to almost a two-year high. 
``One or two of our customers'' have been working with
Cupertino, California-based Apple, Unisem Managing Director John Chia said by phone today. ``We have not heard'' if they have won
contracts, he said, declining to name the customers. 
Apple on Jan. 9 introduced a phone based on its best-selling iPod music player, aiming to sell more than 10 million
units in 2008. U.K.-based Wolfson Microelectronics Plc, a Unisem
customer and a maker of semiconductors for Apple, may help drive
profit at Unisem if it gets an order, at least one analyst said. 
``There's definitely going to be some flow-though'' to
Unisem, said Khoo Chen Hsung, an analyst at CIMB-GK Securities
Pte in Singapore. ``The degree of impact is harder to check.'' 
Shares of Unisem climbed as much as 19 sen, or 9.6 percent,
to 2.18 ringgit and traded at 2.15 ringgit at 4:17 p.m. in Kuala
Lumpur, the highest level since March 9, 2005. The shares have
jumped 30 percent since the start of the year. 
Wolfson is one of Unisem's top five customers, which
together contribute 57 percent of the Malaysian company's sales,
said Khoo. 
Chia also said Unisem's sales and earnings before interest,
tax, depreciation and amortization may rise to a record in 2007.
Unisem has posted six consecutive quarterly profits. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Angus Whitley in Kuala Lumpur at 
awhitley1@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Tony Jordan at  tjordan3@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Josh Fineman" category="RETAIL" date="Jan 12, 2007  4:07 PM ET" keywords="Six Flags Entertainment Corp, Consumer Goods, Corporate Actions, Corporate Finance, Entertainment, Industries, Leisure, Leisure Travel, Mergers &amp;amp; Acquisitions, New York, North America, Oklahoma, Regions, Retail, Retailing, Specialized Regions, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, U.S. Midwest, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-12/six-flags-pass-sales-50-higher-than-ever-before-update5-.html"><headline>Six Flags Pass Sales 50% Higher Than Ever Before</headline><body>
Six Flags Inc. (SIX), the second-biggest
U.S. theme-park operator, sold 50 percent more season passes
than it ever has before by this point in the year. 
Passes to Magic Mountain in Valencia, California, grew 33
percent and total group sales rose 34 percent compared with a
year earlier, Chief Executive Officer Mark Shapiro said on a
conference call today with analysts and investors. Season-pass
and group sales account for 50 percent of attendance. 
The shares added 5.3 percent to an 8.7 percent gain
yesterday after Six Flags agreed to sell seven theme parks for
$312 million and use the proceeds to reduce debt. The company is
not selling Magic Mountain, one of its largest parks and one of
the nine parks it put up for sale in June. 
``All signs point to a bullish year,'' Shapiro said from
Irving, Texas, where the company is conducting a weeklong
retreat. ``We are excited about the early season indicators.'' 
Shares of New York-based Six Flags rose 31 cents to $6.21
at 4:03 p.m. in New York Stock Exchange composite trading. They
dropped 32 percent last year. 
``Management confirmed our suspicion that it was healthy
2007 season pass sales data out of Los Angeles which forced
management to re-think their stance on selling off the
property,'' wrote David Miller, an analyst at Sanders Morris
Harris Group Inc. in Los Angeles. He has a ``strong buy'' rating
on the shares. 
Six Flags sees the sale of the parks adding to cash flow,
Chief Financial Officer Jeff Speed said on the call. He said
cash flow won't be positive in 2007, though it will make
``meaningful progress in that direction.'' 
To contact the reporters on this story:
Josh Fineman in New York at 
jfineman@bloomberg.net; 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Michael Nol at  mnol@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Lucian Kim" category="EASTERN_EUROPE, EMERGING_MARKETS, ENERGY_MARKETS, ENERGY" date="Jan 12, 2007 11:58 AM ET" keywords="ConocoPhillips, Lukoil OAO, Commodities, Commodities Markets, Commonwealth of Ind States, Corporate Actions, Corporate Finance, Crude Oil, Earnings, Eastern Europe, Emerging Markets, Energy, Energy Trading, Europe, Industries, Markets, Mergers &amp;amp; Acquisitions, Natural Gas, North America, Oil, Oil Markets, Oklahoma, Pipelines, Refineries, Regions, Russia, Texas, U.S. Midwest, U.S. Southwest, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-12/lukoil-profit-advances-10-on-output-increase-update5-.html"><headline>Lukoil Profit Advances 10% on Output Increase</headline><body>
OAO Lukoil (LKOH), Russia's biggest oil
producer, reported a 10 percent increase in third-quarter profit as
the company raised output through acquisitions in Kazakhstan and
exploration ventures in Egypt. 
Net income rose to $2.43 billion, or $2.90 per share, from
$2.21 billion, or $2.67, in the year-earlier period, Moscow-based
Lukoil said today in a statement. That beat the $2.35 billion
median estimate from a Bloomberg survey of nine analysts. Revenue
rose 13 percent to $18.4 billion in earnings based on International
Financial Reporting Standards. 
``The results confirm Lukoil's leading position,'' said Artem Konchin, an analyst at Aton in Moscow. ``Lukoil's foreign expansion
suggests it is a prime candidate to become a global major along the
lines of Exxon and Shell.'' 
Chief Executive Officer Vagit Alekperov plans to double output
and raise Lukoil's value to as much as $200 billion by 2016.
Investor-owned Lukoil is struggling to keep its position as
Russia's biggest crude producer as President Vladimir Putin's
campaign to dominate the nation's energy industries helps state-run
rivals such as OAO Rosneft expand. 
``We view Lukoil as one of the best investments opportunities
in the Russian oil sector,'' said Eugene Satskov, an analyst with
Stockholm-based Gustavus Capital Asset Management, which holds
$300,000 in Lukoil shares. ``However, momentum does not favor oil
shares, as the oil-price outlook looks relatively bleak at the
moment.'' 
Shares Slip 
Shares of Lukoil closed down 0.5 percent at 2,091.14 rubles on
the Micex Stock Exchange in Moscow, after earlier declining by as
much as 2.2 percent. That values the company at about 1.78 trillion
rubles ($66.9 billion). 
Operating expenses increased by $238 million, or 27 percent,
Lukoil said. 
Lukoil's results may have been enhanced by the company's
disclosing its hedging operations for the first time in the
quarterly report, said Andrei Gromadin, an oil analyst at MDM Bank
in Moscow. Discounting their third-quarter $279 million gain,
Lukoil's earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation and
amortization would actually be 5 percent below MDM's estimate and 2
percent below consensus, Gromadin said in a phone interview. 
Earlier today, the company said it had raised oil and gas
production by 12 percent last year as output at overseas projects
soared. Oil output in 2006 reached 95.2 million tons, or 1.95
million barrels a day, Lukoil said, though foreign production still
only accounted for 6 percent of that total. 
Refining, Retail 
Russia's largest refiner is seeking new retail and processing
assets in eastern Europe and Asia while securing its reserves in
Central Asia, Latin America and the Middle East. 
The company will use a joint venture with ConocoPhillips to
extract oil at the Yuzhny-Khylchuyu field in northwestern Russia,
where full-scale production is due to start in 2008, Lukoil Deputy
Chief Executive Officer Leonid Fedun said today at a presentation
in Moscow. In the first nine months of 2006, Lukoil made a third of
its capital expenditures, or more than $1 billion, in the Timan-Pechora oil province, where Yuzhny-Khylchuyu is located, he said. 
Lukoil also plans to tap its Caspian Sea projects from 2009,
Fedun said. 
Looking Abroad 
Lukoil is being forced to look abroad as Rosneft and the
natural-gas monopoly OAO Gazprom, both state-run companies, vie for
the remains of bankrupt OAO Yukos Oil Co., once Russia's biggest
oil producer. Rosneft tripled output in late 2004 by acquiring what
was once Yukos's largest unit, which the government seized and sold
to settle claims for back taxes. 
Rosneft has said it may bid this year for other Yukos assets
as the bankrupt company is split up. It said last month it expects
to increase crude output 12 percent in 2007 to 90 million tons, or
1.8 million barrels a day. 
Gazprom is also expanding into the oil business with its
acquisition of OAO Sibneft in October 2005 and entry into Royal
Dutch Shell Plc's Sakhalin-2 oil and gas project in December.
Gazprom has since renamed Sibneft as Gazprom Neft. 
Lukoil plans to spend $27 billion over the next decade to
increase overseas output sevenfold. It's looking to add production
at sites from Kazakhstan and Uzbekistan to Venezuela and Iraq. 
Fedun reiterated the company's goal to stop trading crude in
the next few years and sell only products it refines, both at home
and overseas. 
Refining Assets 
The company also wants to add refining assets abroad. Last
month, Alekperov said Lukoil is considering building refineries in
Vietnam and may seek to revive a bid for Kuwait Petroleum Corp.'s
refinery in Rotterdam. 
The company isn't in talks to acquire refineries from  Shell,
Fedun said today. Shell, Europe's largest oil company by market
value, yesterday said it may sell three refineries in France. 
Alekperov is also using his partnership with ConocoPhillips (COP),
which owns a 20 percent stake in Lukoil, to expand the company's
profile in the retail business. In December, Lukoil announced it
was buying 376 filling stations from Conoco in Eastern Europe. 
Lukoil produced 2.2 million barrels of oil and gas per day in
2006, the company said in today's filing. Full-year oil production
from overseas operations grew 46 percent and natural-gas output
more than doubled. 
The company has been seeking to increase its refining and gas
production businesses after Russia raised extraction taxes and
export duties, squeezing profit margins for crude sales and
exports. 
Lukoil's export and excise taxes rose 52 percent in the third
quarter as Russia increased levies and the company boosted
shipments abroad. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Lucian Kim in Moscow at 
lkim3@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Daniel Tilles at 
dtilles@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Tunde Kaposi and Yon Pulkrabek" category="EASTERN_EUROPE, MANUFACTURING" date="Jan 15, 2007 11:52 AM ET" keywords="Andritz AG, Deutsche Lufthansa AG, Airlines, Austria, Austrian Stock Market, Banking, Commodities, Czech Republic, Czech Stock Market, Eastern Europe, Emerging Markets, Equity Movers, Euro Members, Europe, Financial Services, Hungarian Stock Market, Hungary, Industries, Internet, Machinery, Manufacturing, Markets, Metals, Poland, Poland Stocks, Regions, Specialized Regions, Steel, Stock Markets by Country, Technology, Telecom Services, Transportation, Utilities, Wireless Communications, ex-Energy" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-15/central-europe-stocks-rise-for-third-day-led-by-tpsa-andritz.html"><headline>Central Europe Stocks Rise for Third Day, Led by TPSA, Andritz</headline><body>
Central European stocks rose for a
third day. Telekomunikacja Polska SA, Poland's No. 1 phone
company, paced the advance after the European Commission ruled
that the country's telecommunication market regulator has no
right to control prices for Internet services. 
Andritz AG (ANDR) gained after UBS AG raised its price estimate for
shares of the Austrian maker of machines for producing pulp and
steel. 
The NTX Index of 30 companies in the region added 1.4
percent to 1782.77 in Vienna as 27 stocks rose, two fell and one
was unchanged. 
Poland's WIG20 Index jumped 2.3 percent, while Hungary's BUX
Index (BUX) climbed 1.2 percent. The Czech PX Index increased 1
percent, and Austria's ATX Index added 0.6 percent. 
TPSA shares jumped 5 percent to 25.4 zloty. Poland's
telecommunication watchdog will appeal the ruling that it has no
right to control internet prices, Gazeta Wyborcza reported on Jan
13., citing Anna Strezynska, chief of the regulator. 
``The market is reacting positively to the news that the
commission vetoed the Polish market regulator's decision,'' said
Krzysztof Kaczmarczyk of Deutsche Bank AG. 
Shares of Andritz climbed 5.6 percent to 160.99 euros. UBS
raised its price estimate to 186 euros from 170 euros citing
stronger-than-expected demand and pricing in the pulp industry. 
PKN Orlen Climbs 
PKN Orlen SA climbed 3 percent to 49.1 zloty. Poland's
largest oil company raised its stake in Lithuanian refiner AB
Mazeikiu Nafta to at least 89 percent, the Baltic News Service
reported, without citing anyone. 
Orlen, which bought 84.4 percent of Mazeikiu, the only
refiner in the Baltic states, for $2.34 billion in December,
acquired 5 percent in a mandatory buyout from minority
shareholders for 367.8 million litai ($138 million), the news
service said. 
OTP Bank Nyrt. increased 1.5 percent to 8,622 forint. UBS
raised its price estimate for the shares of Hungary's biggest
lender by 6.7 percent to 9,550 forint, saying the departure of
Deputy Chief Executive Officer Zoltan Speder won't affect the
lender negatively. 
``As Speder was one of the main driving forces behind OTP
Bank's transformation from a local savings bank to an important
regional player, we consider his departure to be an unfavorable
development,'' UBS said in note to clients today. ``At the same
time, we see Laszlo Urban as a good choice as successor, so there
is a realistic chance that this change in the top management may
not have a major adverse impact on the company.'' Urban joins OTP
from Hungary's central bank, where he has been a director. 
Austrian Airlines 
Austrian Airlines Group shares rose 1 percent to 9.37 euros
after Exane BNP Paribas raised its price estimate for the shares
of the owner of the country's largest carrier by 40 percent to
12.2 euros. 
Globe Trade Center SA jumped 5.7 percent to 46.49 zloty
after CA-IB analysts raised their recommendation for shares of
Poland's largest property developer by market value to ``hold''
from ``sell.'' 
TVN SA added 4.1 percent to 25.7 zloty. Analysts at CA-IB
raised their recommendation for shares of Poland's second-biggest
television broadcaster to ``buy'' from ``hold.'' 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Tunde Kaposi in Budapest at 
tkaposi1@bloomberg.net or Yon Pulkrabek at 
ypulkrabek@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Balduin Hesse at 
bhesse2@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Andreas Cremer" category="TRANSPORTATION" date="Jan 15, 2007 11:19 AM ET" keywords="Commerzbank AG, Credit Suisse Group AG, Daimler AG, Deutsche Bank AG, Goldman Sachs Group Inc/The, Morgan Stanley, Aerospace, Airlines, Auto Parts, Automobiles, Banking, CAC 40 Index, Corporate Actions, Corporate Finance, DAX Index, Defense, Defense Dept., Euro Members, Europe, Financial Services, France, Germany, Industries, Markets, Mergers &amp;amp; Acquisitions, Michigan, Militaries, New York, North America, Politics, Regions, Securities Firms, Shareholdings, Spain, Spain &amp;amp; Portugal, Specialized Regions, Transportation, U.S. Government, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, U.S. Midwest, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-15/german-state-lenders-may-join-group-of-eads-investors-update1-.html"><headline>German State Lenders May Join Group of EADS Investors</headline><body>
Landesbank Baden-Wuerttemberg and L-Bank may join a group of investors buying a 7.5 percent stake in
European Aeronautic Defence  Space Co. (EAD) from DaimlerChrysler AG,
officials said today. 
L-Bank, the development bank owned by the state of Baden-Wuerttemberg where DaimlerChrysler is based, may buy 2.5 percent
of the stake, spokeswoman Cordula Braeuninger said by telephone.
Landesbank Baden-Wuerttemberg, which is also partly state-owned,
is bidding for the same amount, said an official at the Stuttgart-based bank who declined to be identified. 
L-Bank has been in talks ``for a relatively long period of
time to examine the purchase,'' Braeuninger said. L-Bank has total
assets of 50 billion euros ($65 billion) and helps promote small
and medium-sized companies in Germany's southwestern region. 
As many as 12 banks may be involved in the EADS stake
purchase, a sign lenders aim to spread risks after Chancellor
Angela Merkel appealed to states to help keep DaimlerChrysler's
stake in the aerospace company in German hands. 
Germany's states of Hamburg, Bremen and Lower Saxony also aim
to take part in the acquisition to safeguard the balance between
German and French owners, Peter Kleinort, a spokesman for
Hamburg's Senator for the Economy, said on Jan. 12. 
Buying 2.5 percent shares of the Daimler stake may cost each
lender about 35 million euros each, said the Landesbank Baden-Wuerttemberg official. The Daimler stake earmarked for sale to the
investors may be worth as much as 1.5 billion euros, Reuters
reported on Jan. 10, citing unnamed bankers. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Andreas Cremer in Berlin at 
acremer@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Eddie Buckle at 
ebuckle@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Robert Simison" category="HEALTH_CARE" date="Jan 16, 2007  9:16 AM ET" keywords="Actavis plc, California, Drugs, Food &amp;amp; Drug Admin, Health &amp;amp; Human Services, Health Care, Health Research, Industries, Medical, North America, Pharmaceuticals, Regions, U.S., U.S. Government, U.S. West, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-16/watson-reports-positive-findings-for-prostate-drug-update1-.html"><headline>Watson Reports Positive Findings for Prostate Drug</headline><body>
Watson Pharmaceuticals Inc. (WPI), the
largest U.S. maker of generic drugs, reported positive results
for its experimental prostate treatment in two late-state trials. 
The drug, silodosin, was more effective than a placebo in
treating enlarged prostates, or benign prostatic hyperplasia, the
Corona, California-based company said today in a statement on PR
Newswire. The tests were in the final of three phases of trials
normally needed for regulatory approval. 
Non-cancerous enlarged prostate affects more than half of
American men in their 60s and as many as 90 percent of them by
age 85, Watson said. Prescription drug sales to treat the
disorder total $1.7 billion a year, the company said. 
Watson plans to apply for U.S. approval to market the drug
in the first half of 2008, after completion later this year of a
one-year safety trial, the company said. The two studies reported
today showed that cardiovascular and blood-pressure side effects
were low, Watson said. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Robert Simison in Washington at 
rsimison@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Robert Simison at  rsimison@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Margot Habiby and Alex Morales" category="MANUFACTURING" date="Jan 17, 2007  3:42 PM ET" keywords="Ameren Corp, American Airlines Group Inc, National Grid PLC, Northeast Utilities, OGE Energy Corp, Agriculture, Airlines, Arizona, California, Commodities, Commodities Markets, Connecticut, Currencies, Electric Utility Outages, Electricity Generation, Energy, Energy Trading, Europe, FTSE 100 Index, Illinois, Industries, Kansas, Leisure, Machinery, Maine, Manufacturing, Markets, Missouri, Natural Disasters, Natural Gas, New Hampshire, New York, North America, Oil, Oil Markets, Oklahoma, Regions, Specialized Regions, Storms, Texas, Transportation, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, U.S. Midwest, U.S. Northeast, U.S. Southwest, U.S. West, United Kingdom, United States, Utilities, Weather" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-17/texas-travel-crippled-schools-closed-as-ice-spreads-update1-.html"><headline>Texas Travel Crippled, Schools Closed as Ice Spreads</headline><body>
Houston, San Antonio and Dallas,
three of the 10 largest U.S. cities, were crippled today by a
winter storm that iced central and southern portions of Texas
overnight. 
Schools were closed in Houston, San Antonio, Austin, Fort
Worth and the Dallas suburbs after the storm coated roads with
ice and snow. Hundreds of flights were delayed or canceled at
airports in Dallas, Houston and Austin, and a 310-mile portion of
Interstate-10 was closed last night from Fort Stockton to San
Antonio. 
``A threat for a mix of frozen precipitation including ice
and snow accumulations continues across northern portions of
southeast Texas today through Thursday morning,'' the National
Weather Service's Houston-Galveston forecast office said today. 
The system is forecast to bring freezing weather into the
U.S. Southeast. Meanwhile, citrus growers in California are
calculating the damage from a severe cold snap and thousands of
people in the Northeast remain without power while temperatures
hover below freezing. 
The Associated Press put the nationwide death toll from the
past week's storms at 55. 
By 3 p.m. local time, snow and rain were easing up across
Texas and Louisiana. Forecasters said more was on the way for
Texas and New Mexico. 
About 90 percent of flights were canceled this morning at
Austin-Bergstrom International Airport after airlines ran out of
de-icer because a shipment failed to arrive yesterday, spokesman
Jim Holbrook said. AMR Corp. (AAMRQ)'s American Airlines received a
shipment at noon today, he said. 
``We will get some planes off the ground, but we won't get
them all,'' Holbrook said in an interview. 
Texas Transit Snarled 
Flights at Houston's two main airports were largely back to
normal after early morning delays, Houston Airport System
spokesman Juan Alanis said in an interview. 
Laidlaw International Inc.'s Greyhound Lines Inc. suspended
passenger bus service until further notice between Houston and
Dallas and San Antonio. 
Most of western Texas and central Oklahoma remained under a
winter-storm watch today, with an ice storm warning stretching
from Houston to Bryan, Texas. 
As much as 6 inches (15 centimeters) of snow had fallen by 8
a.m. local time today around the Big Bend region of Texas. Austin
had as much as 0.4 inch of freezing rain and ice, while Dallas
and surrounding regions had about a quarter-inch of sleet. 
``As this moisture continues eastward, areas of Georgia and
South Carolina could experience some freezing rain during
Wednesday night and early Thursday,'' according to the National
Weather Service's Hydrometeorological Prediction Center in Camp
Springs, Maryland. ``Winter weather and freezing rain advisories
have been posted for those areas.'' 
Much of Nation Iced 
The chill affected a swath of the U.S. from Texas to Maine,
killing dozens of people, mainly on the roads, and coating
telephone and electricity wires with ice. 
In the Midwest, at least 300,000 U.S. homes and businesses
remained without power after winter storms that began five days
ago downed electricity poles and lines, utilities and state
emergency bodies said. 
In California and Arizona, record-low temperatures were
reported yesterday, when California's State Food and Agriculture
Department said 75 percent of its orange crop may be destroyed by
the cold snap. 
A freeze warning remained in place for parts of California,
Arizona and Texas, according to the U.S. National Weather Service
Web site. The service said parts of Maine, New Hampshire, Vermont
and New York should expect sub-zero wind-chill today. 
U.S. President George W. Bush has declared an emergency in
parts of Missouri and Oklahoma, freeing up federal resources. The
cold spell has killed nine people so far in Missouri, and at
least 14 in Oklahoma, mainly on the roads, the two states'
emergency agencies said. 
National Grid Plc (NG/) said that about 13,000 New York state
customers were without electricity, and that outages were also
affecting some of its clients in Massachusetts. As of 5 a.m.
local time today, about 4,300 of Ameren's customers in Illinois
were without power, according to the company Web site. 
To contact the reporters on this story:
Margot Habiby in Dallas at  mhabiby@bloomberg.net; or
Alex Morales in London at 
amorales2@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editors responsible for this story:
Peter Young at 
pyoung13@bloomberg.net; or
Peter Torday at 
ptorday@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Joi Preciphs" category="HEALTH_CARE" date="Jan 17, 2007 10:51 AM ET" keywords="Community Health Systems Inc, Clinics, Corporate Actions, Corporate Finance, Dividends, Earnings, Florida, Health Care, Hospitals, Industries, Loans &amp;amp; Financing, Markets, North America, Regions, U.S. South, U.S. Southeast, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-17/health-management-will-pay-2-4-billion-dividend-update1-.html"><headline>Health Management Will Pay $2.4 Billion Dividend</headline><body>
Health Management Associates Inc. (HMA), a
U.S. hospital operator, said it would pay a $2.4 billion special
dividend, financed by $3.25 billion in new borrowing. 
The one-time dividend will amount to $10 a share, the
company said today in a statement. Health Management also
reported fourth-quarter earnings that fell short of estimates
and said it would record about $200 million in additional bad-debt expenses. 
The Naples, Florida, company said the new borrowing would
let the company lower costs by refinancing existing credit and
provide money to spend on hospitals. Fitch Ratings today
downgraded Health Management's $4.23 billion of debt and credit
facilities to junk status and gave a junk rating to the new
borrowing. 
The company, like others in the industry, ``has been
struggling with an escalation in bad debt from the increased
uninsured population and increased patient burden of higher co-pays and coinsurance,'' Fitch said in its statement. Patient
volumes are expected to be ``flat to slightly up.'' 
Health Management reported earnings per share of 28 cents
or 29 cents in the quarter, missing the 31 cent estimate of 17
analysts surveyed by Bloomberg. 
The one-time dividend will be payable March. The new
borrowing consists of a seven-year, $2.75 billion loan and a
six-year, $500 million revolving credit facility secured with
its assets. 
Shares of HMA rose by 16 cents, or less than 1 percent, to
$20.79 at 10:48 a.m. in New York Stock Exchange composite
trading. The stock has lost 7.2 percent of its value in the 12
months through yesterday. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Joi Preciphs in Washington at 
jpreciphs1@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Robert Greene in Washington at 
rgreene2@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Tan Hwee Ann" category="ASIA, AUSTRALIA_NEW_ZEALAND, COMMODITIES" date="Jan 18, 2007  6:54 PM ET" keywords="Asia, Australia, Commodities, Commodities Markets, Gold, Industries, Markets, Metals, Mining, New Zealand, Nickel, Non-Ferrous Metals, Pacific Rim, Precious Metals, Regions, ex-Energy" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-18/tectonic-restarts-nickel-project-as-prices-rise-update1-.html"><headline>Tectonic Restarts Nickel Project as Prices Rise</headline><body>
Tectonic Resources NL, an Australian
mineral exploration company, said it was restarting mining at
its RAV 8 nickel project in Western Australia, as prices of the
metal soared. 
The project has an initial mine life of three months,
without specifying how much nickel could be produced, the
company said in a statement to the Australian Stock Exchange. 
``The current proposal will look to exploit the better
grade areas around the margins of previously mined areas,'' the
company said. Mining was suspended in September 2005 at RAV 8
because nickel prices then didn't support work, it said. 
Prices of nickel, used in the making of stainless steel,
reached a record in London yesterday on concern a labor dispute
in Canada will cut supply. Prices have jumped sixfold since 2002
as stainless steel production expanded. 
Shares of the company rose 1.2 cents, or 12 percent, to 11
Australian cents, at 10:52 a.m. Sydney time. 
The mine produced 15,314 metric tons of contained nickel in
five-and-a-half years of life, the company said on its Web-Site.
It produced 1,654 tons for the year ended June 30, 2005, about
half of the previous year's output, according to the Register of
Australian Mining. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Tan Hwee Ann in Melbourne at 
hatan@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editors responsible for this story:
James Poole at  jpoole4@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Todd Zeranski" category="JAPAN" date="Jan 18, 2007  5:46 PM ET" keywords="Hoku Corp, Panasonic Corp, Asia, Construction &amp;amp; Engineering, Contracts, Electric Machine (Japanese), Electrical Equipment, Electronics, Energy, Environment, Hawaii, Industries, Japan, Markets, North America, Orders, Pacific Rim, Regions, U.S. West, United States, Utilities" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-18/hoku-wins-370-million-sanyo-contract-shares-soar-update2-.html"><headline>Hoku Wins $370 Million Sanyo Contract; Shares Soar</headline><body>
Hoku Scientific Inc., a maker of fuel
cell components, will supply polysilicon to Sanyo Electric Co.
under a seven-year agreement valued at as much as $370 million.
Hoku's shares more than doubled in value. 
Hoku Materials, a division of Hoku Scientific, will produce
the polysilicon for use in solar-fuel cells beginning in 2009,
the company said in a statement. The agreement calls for Kapolei,
Hawaii-based Hoku to supply Sanyo, the world's biggest maker of
rechargeable batteries, through December 2015. 
Osaka, Japan-based Sanyo will pay $2 million when the
contract is signed and place about $111 million, or 30 percent of
the total, in escrow, Hoku said in the statement. 
Hoku will begin building a $260 million plant to produce the
solar cells and will seek as much as half that amount in loans.
Each company has the right to terminate the agreement if Hoku
can't secure the financing, according to the statement. 
Hoku's shares rose $3.80 to $6.90 as of 4:30 p.m. New York
time in Nasdaq Stock Market composite trading. Before today, they
had fallen 66 percent in the past year. Sanyo's American
depositary receipts fell 35 cents to $7.85. Each ADR represents
five ordinary shares. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Todd Zeranski in New York at 
tzeranski@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Jeff Ward at 
jward@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By [bn:PRSN=15017728] Oliver Staley []" category="RETAIL" date="Jan 18, 2007  4:50 PM ET" keywords="Advanced Drainage Systems Inc, Bally Technologies Inc, International Game Technology, Casinos, Commercial Services, Consumer Goods, Earnings, Electronics, Gaming, Illinois, Industries, Leisure, Lodging, Nevada, North America, Regions, Retail, Retailing, Specialized Regions, U.S. Midwest, U.S. West, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-18/international-game-technology-sales-miss-estimates-update2-.html"><headline>International Game Technology Sales Miss Estimates</headline><body>
International Game Technology (IGT), the
world's largest slot machine maker, reported first-quarter sales
that rose less than analysts' estimated as casinos delayed
making new purchases. 
Sales increased 4.2 percent to $642.3 million, the Reno,
Nevada-based company said today in a statement. That missed the
$663 million average estimate of analysts surveyed by Bloomberg. 
Slot machines sales declined as IGT entered into revenue-sharing agreements instead of selling devices outright, Chief
Executive Officer T.J. Matthews said on a conference call. The
company has about 65 percent of the U.S. slot machine market and
is expanding overseas, particularly in Japan, where new
regulations mean 1.5 million machines will be replaced. 
``This lighter revenue number is a bit of an anomaly,''
said William Lerner, an analyst with Deutsche Bank in Las Vegas.
``It's a function of them placing more participation games in
lieu of product sales.'' 
Net income increased to $121 million, or 35 cents a share,
from $120.6 million, or 34 cents a share, matching analysts'
estimates. 
IGT's shares fell $1.08, or 2.3 percent, to $46.10 at 4:22
p.m. in New York Stock Exchange composite trading. Last year,
the stock rose 50 percent, compared with a 39 percent gain by
WMS Industries Inc. and a 43 percent increase by Bally
Technologies Inc. (BYI) 
Server Technology 
Matthews, 42, reiterated the company's November forecast
that profit would average 33 to 37 cents a share each quarter
for the year ending September 2007. 
The company is investing in technology for slots machines
that are centrally programmed and give casinos and players more
control over the games. The company doesn't anticipate selling
devices with the new technology for two more years, Matthews
said. 
``We are still waiting for new technology to be a primary
driver,'' he said. ``In 2009 we should start seeing some sort of
replacement demand.'' 
Harry Curtis, a J.P. Morgan Securities Inc. analyst top-ranked for accuracy by StarMine Inc, estimated first-quarter
profit of 36 cents a share. That's better than the 35 cents
predicted by 14 analysts surveyed by Bloomberg. Curtis rates IGT
shares ``overweight.'' 
Japanese Market 
IGT has about 8 percent of the Japanese market for
pachisuro machines, which resemble pachinko games. Matthews said
the company's goal is to sell 60,000 new devices in the second
half of 2007. 
``Japan can have a very substantial impact on business,''
he said. 
The company is also expanding in the U.S. as more states
approve slot machines and older slots are replaced.
Pennsylvania's legislature authorized 14 slots-only casinos with
as many as 61,000 machines statewide, the first of which opened
in November. Casinos have also opened at Florida horse tracks. 
Matthews said state legislatures in Texas, Massachusetts,
Kansas, Maryland and Florida will consider adding or expanding
gambling this year. 
Product sales fell 2.2 percent to $317.4 million as
international sales declined 6.5 percent to $110.1 million. The
company sold fewer slot machines in Australia, the U.K. and
other European countries. 
Revenue from gaming operations, which includes leased
machines where IGT shares in profits, increased 11 percent to
$324.9 million. 
Overseas, IGT is selling slot-like machines in Mexico,
where bingo halls were allowed to install video lottery
terminals in 2004, and in Macau, the only region in China where
casinos are legal, where it was 20 percent of the market. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Oliver Staley in New York at 
ostaley@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Michael Nol at  mnol@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Sophie Kernon" category="MANUFACTURING" date="Jan 18, 2007  1:35 PM ET" keywords="Bombardier Inc, Aerospace, Alberta, Canada, Defense, Electrical Equipment, Equity Movers, Europe, Illinois, Industries, Machinery, Manufacturing, Markets, North America, Quebec, Railroads, Regions, Transportation, U.S. Midwest, United Kingdom, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-18/turbo-shares-advance-on-14-million-bombardier-order-update1-.html"><headline>Turbo Shares Advance on $14 Million Bombardier Order</headline><body>
Shares of Turbo Power Systems Inc.,
a U.K. developer of emergency power systems, had their sharpest
intraday gain in six months after the company received a $14
million order from the world's biggest train maker Bombardier Inc. (BBD/B) 
The stock rose as much as three quarters of a penny, or 8.1
percent, to 10 pence, the sharpest rise since July 19, before
closing up 6.8 percent at 9.88 pence. Turbo will supply 406
power units to support Bombardier's contract with the Chicago
Transit Authority for a new fleet of subway carriages, West
Drayton, southern England-based Turbo said in a statement today. 
Turbo will meet the order between 2008 and 2011. If the
CTA, which operates the second biggest subway system in the
U.S., takes up an option for a total of 706 cars, the value of
Turbo's order may exceed 20 million pounds ($40 million). 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Sophie Kernon in London at 
skernon@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Chris Jasper cjasper@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Yuriy Humber" category="EASTERN_EUROPE" date="Jan 18, 2007 11:18 AM ET" keywords="Evraz PLC, Asia, Coal, Commodities, Commonwealth of Ind States, Eastern Europe, Emerging Markets, Europe, Industries, Japan, Markets, Metals, Mining, Pacific Rim, Regions, Russia, Specialized Regions, Steel, ex-Energy" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-18/raspadskaya-has-317-million-set-aside-to-buy-rivals-update1-.html"><headline>Raspadskaya Has $317 Million Set Aside to Buy Rivals</headline><body>
OAO Raspadskaya, Russia's second-
largest miner of coal used in steelmaking, has $317 million set
aside to buy domestic rivals, and plans to spend a further $327
million on expanding production. 
The funding for acquisitions comes from a share sale in
November, while the remaining money will be generated from income
and loans, Chief Executive Officer Gennady Kozovoy told reporters
at a briefing in Moscow today. The $327 million will be spent
through 2010, the head of the Siberian-based company said. 
``We have set up a solid base on which to consolidate''
domestic competitors,'' Kozovoy said. ``As soon as offers come
in, we will look at them.'' 
Demand for so-called coking coal has surged as steelmakers
increased production by more than half in the decade to the end
of 2005. Still, mining companies have also expanded output and
analysts expect benchmark prices to decline for a second
consecutive year from April. 
Raspadskaya is 50 percent-owned by steelmaker Evraz Group
SA, which is in turn part-owned by billionaire Roman Abramovich. 
Raspadskaya plans to increase coal production by a fifth
this year to 12.8 million metric tons, and has a target of 17
million tons by 2010. The company also processes the coal into a
product that can be used as a raw material for making coke, an
ingredient in steelmaking. Sales of processed coal will expand by
50 percent to 9.5 million tons, Kozovoy said. 
Production Capacity 
Processed coal sold for an average of $58.60 a ton last
year. On that basis, an increase of 50 percent in Raspadskaya's
sales would add $77 million of revenue. The coal miner is
spending $126 million on a processing plant with a capacity of
10.5 million tons by 2008, 3 million tons more than the company's
current capacity. 
Raspadskaya expects to sell coal for the first time to
India, South Korea, Japan, and increase sales to Ukraine and
Romania. A three-year contract with an unidentified state-owned
Indian steelmaker may be signed within the next several months,
Kozovoy said. 
Raspadskaya sells processed coal to almost all of Russia's
steelmakers. Evraz signed a contract to increase deliveries from
1.3 million tons last year to as much as 3.5 million tons within
five years, said Alexander Andreyev, deputy director for strategy
at Raspadskaya. 
OAO Magnitogorsk Iron  Steel, which runs Russia's biggest
steel mill, today signed a five-year contract with Raspadksaya.
This year, the steelmaker will buy 2.2 millions tons of processed
coal at $70 a ton, Kozovoy said. The price is 17 percent higher
than last year. 
The coal miner's other major customer, OAO Novolipetsk
Steel, will buy 1.6 million tons from the coal miner this year. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Bradley Cook in Moscow at 
bcook7@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Malcolm Fried in Amsterdam at 
mfried@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Greg Bensinger" category="TRANSPORTATION" date="Jan 19, 2007  4:39 PM ET" keywords="General Motors Co, Auto Parts, Automobiles, Industries, Michigan, North America, Regions, Specialized Regions, Texas, Transportation, U.S. Midwest, U.S. Southwest, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-19/gm-offers-750-bonus-to-clear-out-2006-2005-models-update3-.html"><headline>GM Offers $750 Bonus to Clear Out 2006, 2005 Models</headline><body>
General Motors Corp., the world's
largest automaker, is offering a $750 bonus to buyers to clear
new 2006- or 2005-model cars and trucks from dealer lots. 
The program runs through Feb. 14, John McDonald, a spokesman
for the Detroit-based company, said in an interview today. The
bonus is in addition to any other offers on those cars and
trucks. They account for less than 10 percent of GM (GM)'s inventory,
which was 1.05 million vehicles at the end of December, he said. 
``We're not too overstocked on those, but anything you can
do to help move them is great,'' said Guy Sensiba, a sales
manager for Gunn Pontiac-GMC Truck in San Antonio. 
GM is using such incentives after an 8.7 percent drop in its
U.S. sales of cars and light trucks last year. The automaker and
Ford Motor Co., second biggest in the U.S., have lost sales and
market share to Asia-based competitors led by Toyota Motor Corp. 
Sensiba said GM is also offering $200 to salespeople and $50
to sales managers for each of the 2006 and 2005 models sold.
McDonald declined to confirm that. 
Some vehicles, such as the Hummer H1, aren't included in the
offer, McDonald said. The incentive program was reported earlier
today by Automotive News. 
GM shares rose 75 cents to $31.55 at 4:01 p.m. in New York
Stock Exchange composite trading. They have gained 56 percent in
the past 12 months. 
GM's 8.375 percent note due July 2033 rose 0.5 cent to 94.75
cents on the dollar, yielding 8.9 percent, according to Trace,
the NASD's bond-price reporting service. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Greg Bensinger in New York at 
gbensinger1@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Dave Versical at 
dversical@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Susanna Ray" category="MANUFACTURING" date="Jan 19, 2007 11:06 AM ET" keywords="American International Group Inc, Boeing Co/The, FedEx Corp, United Parcel Service Inc, Aerospace, Airlines, Asia, Asia ex. Japan, Australia, CAC 40 Index, Commercial Services, Contracts, Defense, Defense Dept., Euro Members, Europe, Financial Services, France, Georgia (U.S.), Germany, Illinois, Industries, Insurance, Leisure, Machinery, Manufacturing, Markets, Militaries, New York, North America, Orders, Pacific Rim, Regions, Singapore, South, Southeast Asia, Spain, Spain &amp;amp; Portugal, Specialized Regions, Tennessee, Transportation, U.S. Government, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, U.S. Midwest, U.S. South, U.S. Southeast, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-19/airbus-to-stick-to-a380-freighter-even-if-no-orders-update1-.html"><headline>Airbus to Stick to A380 Freighter Even If No Orders</headline><body>
Airbus SAS, the world's largest
commercial planemaker, said it won't drop its superjumbo freighter
program even if it loses the last customer for the cargo version of
the A380. 
``Airbus sees that there's a market for this type of aircraft,
and we want to be in that market,'' Justin Dubon, a spokesman for
Toulouse, France-based Airbus, said in a telephone interview today.
The planemaker is sticking to its November forecast that there's
worldwide demand for 400 very large freighters over the next 20
years, he said. 
UPS may cancel its order as early as next week, French
newspaper Les Echos reported today, without citing anyone. ``We
have no information about any cancellations,'' Dubon said. 
The A380 program has been delayed at least two years due to
wiring complexity. FedEx Corp. (FDX) canceled an order for 10 A380
freighters Nov. 7, and International Lease Finance Corp. dropped
plans Dec. 4 to take five of the planes. That left United Parcel
Service Inc. (UPS), which signed a contract for 10 A380 freighters in
December 2005, as the last customer for the model, which Airbus
planned to begin producing in 2010. 
UPS is ``still studying the matter,'' Atlanta-based spokesman
Norman Black said. ``There has been no decision.'' 
Scrapping the program could allow Airbus to reduce development
costs by about 2 billion euros ($2.59 billion), said Doug McVitie,
managing director of Dinan, France-based consulting firm Arran
Aerospace. ``They have so many problems that it may well be if they
could put the freighter on the backburner just a little while, they
could concentrate more on the passenger version.'' 
Helping Airbus 
A UPS cancellation now could be good for Airbus, helping it
get all the bad news out of the way at once, he said. 
``If UPS were to decide to delay or whatever, then we will not
cancel the freighter, we will stay with the program,'' John Leahy,
Airbus's chief operating officer and head of sales, said in a Dec.
7 interview. ``If required, there may be a delay in the program,
but nothing more.'' 
Airbus fell behind Boeing Co. (BA) in orders last year, for the
first time since 2000, as engineers were unable to install the 300
miles (480 kilometers) of wiring that goes into each A380. The
project's delays increased costs and will lead the planemaker to a
loss for the year, Airbus parent company European Aeronautic,
Defence  Space Co. (EAD) said Jan. 17. 
Boeing, based in Chicago, has ``run away with the market'' for
cargo planes, Boeing Vice President Randy Baseler said that day. 
``Freight is growing like crazy, and we sold 81 freighters,''
Baseler said. ``I don't believe Airbus sold any.'' 
Airbus received net orders for 790 planes in 2006, and no new
freighters were ordered. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Susanna Ray in Frankfurt at 
sray7@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Dan Stets at  dstets@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Rachel Layne and James Gunsalus" category="MANUFACTURING" date="Jan 22, 2007  5:40 PM ET" keywords="Boeing Co/The, General Electric Co, Aerospace, Airlines, CAC 40 Index, Conglomerates, Connecticut, Contracts, Defense, Defense Dept., Euro Members, Europe, Financial Services, France, Germany, Illinois, Industries, Machinery, Manufacturing, Markets, Militaries, North America, Ohio, Orders, Regions, Spain, Spain &amp;amp; Portugal, Specialized Regions, Transportation, U.S. Government, U.S. Midwest, U.S. Northeast, U.S. Pacific Northwest, United States, Washington State" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-22/boeing-says-ge-placed-5-34-billion-order-for-39-jets-update3-.html"><headline>Boeing Says GE Placed $5.34 Billion Order for 39 Jets</headline><body>
Boeing Co. (BA), the world's second-largest commercial-airline maker, said General Electric Co. (GE)
ordered 39 of its passenger planes in a transaction with a list-price value of $5.34 billion. 
GE, the world's biggest aircraft lessor, booked the order
last year. It had been listed as unidentified in Chicago-based
Boeing's orders and deliveries tally on its Web site, the
companies said in a statement today. 
General Electric, which has a fleet of 1,450 planes leased
to 225 carriers, ordered 69 planes last year, including those
announced today. The Fairfield, Connecticut-based company is
benefiting as airlines seek to expand and replace aging planes
quickly using less of their own money. Limited production
capacity at Boeing and Airbus SAS also has spurred interest in
leases. 
GE plans to buy 15 Boeing 777s and two dozen 737s, the
world's best-selling passenger plane. Boeing on Jan. 4 said it
booked a record 1,044 orders last year, beating Airbus for the
first time in six years and topping the 1,002 orders in 2005. 
Henry Hubschman, chief executive officer of GE's plane-leasing unit, said in the statement that the company already has
customers for many of the planes. 
Shares of Boeing dropped $3.03, or 3.4 percent, to $85.66
at 4:16 p.m. in New York Stock Exchange composite trading after
Wachovia Capital Markets LLC downgraded the company to
``neutral.'' The stock gained 26 percent last year. GE fell 20
cents to $36.75. 
General Electric, also the world's biggest maker of jet-engines, is the exclusive provider of engines for the extended-range 777 model and for 737s through its CFM International
venture with France's Safran SA. Orders for the 737 last year
totaled a record 729 aircraft. 
To contact the reporters on this story:
Rachel Layne in Boston at 
rlayne@bloomberg.net;
James Gunsalus in Seattle at 
jgunsalus@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Rich Zahradnik at 
rzahradnik@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Greg Bensinger" category="TRANSPORTATION" date="Jan 22, 2007  4:26 PM ET" keywords="Swift Transportation Co, Arizona, Buyout, Corporate Actions, Corporate Finance, Industries, Markets, Mergers &amp;amp; Acquisitions, Mutual &amp;amp; Hedge Funds, North America, Private Equity, Regions, Specialized Regions, Transportation, Trucking, Trusts, U.S. Southwest, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-22/swift-shares-rise-after-moyes-agrees-to-buy-company-update5-.html"><headline>Swift Shares Rise After Moyes Agrees to Buy Company</headline><body>
Shares of Swift Transportation Co. (SWFT)
rose 9.1 percent after the company agreed to be sold for $2.4
billion in cash to a group led by founder Jerry Moyes. 
Swift announced the sale late on Jan. 19, saying the board
of the third-largest U.S. trucker accepted an offer of $31.55 in
cash and $332 million in assumed debt. The bid was a 14 percent
premium over Phoenix-based Swift's closing price that day. 
``Moyes appears to us to have gotten a good deal,'' John Larkin, a Stifel Nicolaus  Co. analyst in Baltimore, said today
in a note to investors. ``Moyes has a proven knack for buying
close to the bottom.'' Larkin rates Swift shares as ``hold.'' 
The sale agreement caps a months-long effort by Moyes to
regain control of the company he founded with one truck in 1966
and led as chairman and chief executive officer until 2005.
Swift previously rejected his Nov. 27 offer of $29 a share. 
The shares gained $2.52, or 9.1 percent, to $30.26 at 4
p.m. New York time in Nasdaq Stock Market composite trading.
Earlier, the stock touched $30.36 in trading of 15.5 million
shares, more than 11 times the daily average for the past year.
Swift shares climbed 21 percent in the 12 months ended Jan. 19. 
Moyes didn't return a call to his office in Phoenix. 
He stepped down as Swift CEO after paying $1.25 million to
the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission in September 2005 to
settle accusations of insider trading. He never admitted or
denied wrongdoing and has remained on Swift's board. 
Biggest Shareholder 
Moyes, who is buying Swift with some family members, is the
company's biggest shareholder, with a 26 percent stake, or about
19.8 million shares as of November, according to data compiled
by Bloomberg. His brother, Ronald Moyes, is the second-largest
investor, with 12 percent, or about 9 million shares, as of
November 2005. 
In addition to Swift, Jerry Moyes is majority owner of
Waco, Texas-based Central Freight Lines Inc. and part of the
group that owns most of the Phoenix Coyotes National Hockey
League team. 
The sale is expected to close in the second quarter pending
regulatory approval, Swift said in a statement announcing the
agreement. Morgan Stanley acted as a financial adviser to Moyes. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Greg Bensinger in New York at 
gbensinger1@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Dave Versical at 
dversical@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Mary Jane Credeur" category="RETAIL" date="Jan 22, 2007  4:26 PM ET" keywords="Coca-Cola Bottling Co Consolidated, Coca-Cola Co/The, Coca-Cola Enterprises Inc, Coca-Cola Femsa SAB de CV, Beverages, Consumer Goods, Containers, Emerging Markets, Georgia (U.S.), Industries, Latin America, Mexico, North America, North Carolina, Packaging, Regions, Retail, Specialized Regions, U.S. South, U.S. Southeast, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-22/coca-cola-shifts-minnick-s-marketing-duties-to-kent-update1-.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Shifts Minnick's Marketing Duties to Kent</headline><body>
Coca-Cola Co. (KO), the world's largest
soft-drink maker, will shift some of outgoing marketing chief
Mary Minnick's responsibilities to recently promoted President
Muhtar Kent. 
Kent will oversee marketing for the Atlanta-based company
beginning March 1, Chief Executive Officer Neville Isdell, said
today in an internal memo to employees. Minnick, who was passed
over when Kent was named president and chief operating officer
in December, said last week she will leave in February to pursue
other personal and professional goals in the U.K. 
The move gives more responsibility to Kent, 54, who is
Coca-Cola's second-highest ranking executive and likely
successor to Isdell. Coca-Cola's strategy and innovation groups,
formerly overseen by Minnick, will report to Isdell. 
``As the health of our business continues to improve, the
factors that necessitated the combining of marketing, strategy
and innovation have evolved,'' Isdell, 63, said in the memo. 
The new structure allows Coca-Cola to ``increase the impact
and effectiveness of the global marketing community, while
preserving the benefits we have captured'' by previously
combining the groups, wrote Isdell, who hasn't said when he
plans to retire. 
Coca-Cola also said today Marc Mathieu, who previously
oversaw marketing for brands such as Coca-Cola, Sprite and
Fanta, will assume similar duties for noncarbonated drinks
including Dasani and Powerade. 
Shares of Coca-Cola fell 23 cents to $48.03 at 4 p.m. in
New York Stock Exchange composite trading. They increased 20
percent last year, the biggest annual gain since 1997. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Mary Jane Credeur in Atlanta at 
mcredeur@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Michael Nol at  mnol@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Irene Shen" category="EMERGING_MARKETS, TRANSPORTATION" date="Jan 22, 2007  4:04 AM ET" keywords="Chongqing Changan Automobile Co Ltd, DongFeng Automobile Co Ltd, Dongfeng Motor Group Co Ltd, FAW CAR Co Ltd, Ford Motor Co, General Motors Co, SAIC Motor Corp Ltd, Tianjin Faw Xiali Automobile Co Ltd, Volkswagen AG, Asia, Asia ex. Japan, Australia, Auto Parts, Automobiles, China, DAX Index, Emerging Markets, Euro Members, Europe, Germany, Industries, Korea, Markets, Michigan, North America, Pacific Rim, Regions, Specialized Regions, Taiwan, Transportation, U.S. Midwest, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-22/china-vehicle-sales-may-climb-18-in-2007-on-economy-update3-.html"><headline>China Vehicle Sales May Climb 18% in 2007 on Economy</headline><body>
China's vehicle sales will likely
rise 18 percent this year, as economic growth boosts demand in
the world's second-biggest auto market. 
Automakers may sell 8.5 million vehicles in China this year,
compared with 7.22 million last year, the China Association of
Automobile Manufacturers said on its Web site today. 
China's economy has grown by average of about 9 percent a
year for the past decade, making vehicle ownership affordable for
more people. General Motors Corp. (GM), Volkswagen AG (VOW) and other
automakers sold 25 percent more vehicles in China last year, as
sales in the country surpassed Japan's for the first time. 
``China's booming property and stock markets have boosted
people's wealth, creating potential consumers for luxury products
like cars,'' said Li Chunbo, an analyst at Citic Securities Co.
in Beijing. ``China is on course to become the world's largest
auto market, as sales growth slows in North America.'' 
Sales of passenger cars, sport-utility vehicles and
multipurpose vehicles will likely rise to 6.3 million units this
year, while sales of commercial vehicles including buses and
trucks may climb to 2.2 million, the association said. 
GM, the largest overseas automaker in China, expects to sell
1 million vehicles in the country by next year at the latest,
Kevin Wale, chairman of its China unit, said on Jan. 7. 
Volkswagen returned to profit in China, its largest overseas
market, last year, after making its first loss in the country in
more than 20 years in 2005. The German automaker sold a record
711,298 cars on the mainland and in Hong Kong last year,
including 81,708 Audi AG sedans. 
``Passenger car consumption may grow faster than wider
vehicle sales,'' Li said. ``This will boost overseas investors'
confidence in the local market.'' 
Luxury Brands 
China's property prices have more than doubled since 2000,
while the benchmark Shanghai and Shenzhen 300 Index rose 121
percent last year, boosting the number of millionaires in the
Communist country, as well as luxury car sales. 
DaimlerChrysler AG, the world's fifth-largest automaker,
sold 32 percent more Mercedes-Benz cars in China last year,
helped by sales of locally made E-class sedans, Beijing-based
spokesman Trevor Hale said on Jan. 12. 
Bayerische Motoren Werke AG, the world's largest maker of
luxury cars, boosted its sales 51 percent in China last year to
36,357 vehicles, including Rolls-Royce and Mini cars. China
surpassed Japan as the largest market for Rolls-Royce cars in the
Asia-Pacific region last year. 
Vehicle sales in the U.S. fell 2.6 percent to 16.6 million
last year, according to Autodata Corp. 
To contact the reporters on this story:
Irene Shen in Shanghai at 
ishen4@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editors responsible for this story:
Bret Okeson at 
bokeson@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Gautam Chakravorthy" category="INDIA, FUNDS, SPORTS_WORLD" date="Jan 22, 2007  4:00 AM ET" keywords="News Corp, Twenty-First Century Fox Inc, Asia, Asia ex. Japan, Australia, China, Cinema, Emerging Markets, Entertainment, Hong Kong, India, Industries, Internet, Korea, Media, Movies, New York, New Zealand, North America, Pacific Rim, Publishing, Radio, Regions, South, Southeast Asia, Specialized Regions, Taiwan, Technology, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-22/murdoch-s-star-india-heads-resign-a-week-after-ceo-update1-.html"><headline>Murdoch's Star India Heads Resign, a Week After CEO</headline><body>
Rupert Murdoch's Star Group Ltd. said
two executives in India resigned, more than a week after the Hong
Kong-based company's chief executive officer said she will quit. 
Peter Mukerjea, chief executive officer at Star Group India,
will leave by the end of this month, while Sameer Nair, chief
executive at Star Entertainment India, quits at the end of March,
Star said in an e-mailed statement on Sunday. Michelle Guthrie
announced her resignation as Star Group CEO on Jan. 12. 
The two executives in India left the company to ``pursue
other business opportunities,'' Jannie Poon, a Hong Kong-based
spokeswoman for Star Group said in a phone interview today. 
Paul Aiello, the 42-year-old president of Star Group,
replaces Guthrie, who held the top job for six years, from March
1. The company also loses Mukerjea and Nair, who spearheaded the
Star network's shift to Hindi language and introduced the Indian
version of ``Who Wants To Be A Millionaire.'' 
Star Group, controlled by New York-based News Corp. (NWS), split
its Indian operations into two in March. Mukerjea was in charge
of legal, finance and investments of the group in the country,
while Nair was responsible for programming, marketing and new
media including the Internet. 
``The transformation of Star India into the leading
television network in the country came in no small part due to
their leadership,'' Aiello said in the statement. 
Aiello, a former investment banker at Morgan Stanley, was
also named acting chief executive officer of Star India. 
Sales of Star India fell by as much as 42 percent in the
past two years, the Economic Times newspaper said on its Web site
on the weekend, without citing a source for the information.
Advertising revenue at its flagship Star Plus channel is likely
to decline to 7 billion rupees ($158 million) in 2006 from 8.3
billion rupees a year earlier, the report said. 
Closely-held Star doesn't provide details of its financial
operations. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Gautam Chakravorthy in Mumbai at 
chakravorthy@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editors responsible for this story:
Teo Chian Wei at  cwteo@bloomberg.net;
Stephen Foxwell at  sfoxwell@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Cecile Daurat" category="US" date="Jan 23, 2007  4:14 PM ET" keywords="News Corp, Twenty-First Century Fox Inc, Asia, Australia, California, Crime, Entertainment, Industries, Internet, Media, New York, New Zealand, North America, Pacific Rim, Publishing, Regions, Specialized Regions, Technology, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, U.S. West, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-23/myspace-tightens-web-chat-rules-adds-amber-alerts-update3-.html"><headline>MySpace Tightens Web Chat Rules, Adds Amber Alerts</headline><body>
MySpace, News Corp. (NWSA)'s social-networking Web site, tightened its rules to deter predators and
started to distribute Amber alerts for missing children. 
The Web site will block users over 18 from contacting users
under that age and will limit instant messaging to users listed
on each person's friend list, MySpace said today in a statement. 
MySpace, which hosts more than 150 million personal pages,
increased restrictions to protect young users after being sued
this month over claims that five teenage girls were sexually
abused by adults they met on the site. The Amber alerts, which
are urgent bulletins about abducted kids issued by the National
Center for Missing  Exploited Children, went live today. 
``MySpace is one solution to get that information out to the
public in a quick and easy way,'' said Bob Hoever, associate
director of training at the Alexandria, Virginia-based center.
``The more eyes and ears you have out there, the better.'' 
Notices will be sent to all MySpace users who are within the
postal Zip codes that have been used to broadcast an Amber alert,
the Los Angeles-based company said. 
The Amber alert program is a voluntary partnership between
law-enforcement agencies, broadcasters and transportation
authorities to broadcast urgent bulletins regarding abductions.
It has helped recover 314 children since its creation 11 years
ago, Hoever said. 
The program was named after Amber Hagerman, 9, who was
kidnapped and murdered in 1996 in Arlington, Texas. The crime
remains unsolved. 
In addition to the new age-based restrictions, all MySpace
users must now provide a valid e-mail address to sign up and
confirm their membership, the company said. MySpace said it
removes an average 25,000 profiles each week because of age
misrepresentation. 
Class A shares of News Corp. (NWS) gained 43 cents, or 1.9
percent, to $23.21 at 4:03 p.m. in New York Stock Exchange
composite trading. They have gained 44 percent in the past year. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Cecile Daurat in New York at 
cdaurat@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editors responsible for this story:
Emma Moody at 
emoody@Bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Lyubov Pronina" category="MANUFACTURING" date="Jan 23, 2007  8:31 AM ET" keywords="BAE Systems PLC, Boeing Co/The, Lockheed Martin Corp, MTU Aero Engines AG, Rolls-Royce Holdings PLC, Safran SA, Aerospace, Airlines, Benelux, CAC 40 Index, Commonwealth of Ind States, Construction &amp;amp; Engineering, Contracts, Defense, Defense Dept., Eastern Europe, Electronics, Emerging Markets, Euro Members, Europe, FTSE 100 Index, France, Germany, Government Contract Awards, Illinois, Industries, Luxembourg, Machinery, Manufacturing, Markets, Maryland, Militaries, North America, North Atlantic Treaty Org., Orders, Regions, Russia, Spain, Spain &amp;amp; Portugal, Specialized Regions, Technology, Telecom Equipment, Transportation, U.S. Government, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, U.S. Midwest, Ukraine, United Kingdom, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-23/volga-dnepr-to-revive-production-of-world-s-biggest-cargo-plane.html"><headline>Volga-Dnepr to Revive Production of World's Biggest Cargo Plane</headline><body>
Volga-Dnepr Group, a Russian cargo
carrier whose clients range from NATO to rock stars, said it
will revive production of the world's biggest commercial
aircraft to tap surging demand for oversized shipments. 
Volga-Dnepr and Ukrainian engine maker OAO Motor Sich
agreed to form a joint venture to renew production of the
Soviet-era Antonov An-124, officials from both companies told
reporters in Moscow today. Volga-Dnepr will own 59 percent of
venture, OAO Cargo Aircraft, and Motor Sich will own the rest. 
``There's huge demand in the large-cargo market but not
enough capacity,'' said Gennady Pivovarov, head of Volga-Dnepr's
airline. Demand in dollar terms is expected jump 10-fold to $4.5
billion a year by 2020. 
Volga-Dnepr is the global leader in oversized cargo, with
more than 50 percent of the market. The United Nations uses the
big-bellied An-124 for peacekeeping missions and entertainers
including Madonna, Michael Jackson and the band U2 use the craft
for world tours. 
Designed as a strategic military freighter, the plane,
known as Ruslan, first flew in 1982 and set a world record in
1985 by carrying a payload of 171,219 kilograms (377,000 pounds)
to an altitude of 10,750 meters (35,000 feet). Once the pride of
the Soviet aircraft industry, 56 of the jets were manufactured
before production stopped after the Soviet Union collapsed in
1991. Volga-Dnepr flies 10 of the jets. 
Restarting production will require about $500 million, $100
million of which will come from the venture partners and the
rest will be raised either from the Ukrainian and Russian
governments or private investors or both, both companies said. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Lyubov Pronina in Moscow at 
lpronina@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Lars Klemming at 
lklemming@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Zhang Shidong and William Bi" category="CHINA" date="Jan 23, 2007  3:52 AM ET" keywords="Angang Steel Co Ltd, China Petroleum &amp;amp; Chemical Corp, Shanghai Pudong Development Bank, Xinjiang Ba Yi Iron &amp;amp; Steel Co Ltd, Asia, Asia ex. Japan, Australia, China, China Stock Market, Closing Market Comments, Commodities, Currencies, Emerging Markets, Energy, Equity Movers, Hong Kong, Hong Kong Stocks, Industries, Korea, Markets, Metals, Oil, Pacific Rim, Regions, Specialized Regions, Steel, Stock Markets by Country, Taiwan, ex-Energy" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-23/china-s-stocks-rise-to-record-for-third-day-pudong-bank-gains.html"><headline>China's Stocks Rise to Record for Third Day; Pudong Bank Gains</headline><body>
China's stocks rose, pushing the
benchmark to a record for a third day. Shanghai Pudong
Development Bank Co. led lenders higher after it won regulatory
approval to set up a fund-management arm. 
``The conglomeration of China's financial industry, which
will let banks, insurers and brokers expand into each other's
business, is most likely to benefit banks,'' said Liu Xiaochang,
a bank analyst at Huatai Securities Co. in Nanjing. 
The Shanghai and Shenzhen 300 Index, which tracks yuan-
denominated A shares listed on China's two exchanges, gained
16.82, or 0.7 percent, to a record 2508.13 at the close, after
earlier dropping as much as 3.1 percent. The measure has surged
8.6 percent in four sessions. 
The Shanghai Composite Index (SHCOMP), which tracks the bigger of
China's stock exchanges, rose 0.5 percent to 2949.14. The
Shenzhen Composite Index, which covers the smaller one, added
0.3 percent to 702.09. 
Pudong Bank (600000), the Chinese partner of Citigroup Inc., surged
2.26 yuan, or the 10 percent daily limit, to 24.85. The lender
said it won approval from China's banking regulator to start a
fund with French insurer Axa SA. Pudong Bank will own 51 percent
of the venture, it said. 
China has allowed domestic lenders to set up funds with
overseas investors since February 2005, to develop capital
markets and provide another income source for banks, which get
as much as 90 percent of their earnings from interest spreads. 
China Merchants Bank Co., the nation's third-biggest
publicly traded lender, rose 1.28 yuan, or 7.3 percent, to 18.81.
China Minsheng Banking Corp., the nation's first privately
controlled lender, jumped 1.04 yuan, or 10 percent, to 11.41. 
Steelmakers Gain 
Baoshan Iron  Steel Co., China's biggest steelmaker,
gained 0.58 yuan, or 6.4 percent, to 9.70. The stock trades at
13 times earnings per share, compared with 37 times for the 300
index, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. 
``The steel sector is relatively under-valued in the
market,'' said Zheng Dong, a Beijing-based steel analyst at
Guosen Securities Co. ``Investors have realized this is a good
opportunity to buy steel stocks.'' 
Wuhan Iron  Steel Co., the third biggest, advanced 0.67
yuan, or 8.7 percent, to 8.34. The shares trade at 14 times
expected earnings. Angang Steel Co. (000898), the No. 4, added 0.72 yuan,
or 5.5 percent, to 13.78. The company was rated
``neutral/neutral'' in new coverage by Song Shen, a Hong Kong-
based analyst at Goldman Sachs Group Inc. 
Xinjiang Ba Yi Iron  Steel Co. (600581), a Xinjiang-based
steelmaker, climbed 0.14 yuan, or 2.4 percent, to 6.10. The
company said the board approved its plan to borrow 1.2 billion
yuan ($154.3 million) from a bank to finance the purchase of
fixed assets. 
`Get Out' 
China Petroleum  Chemical Corp. (600028) gained after shareholders
approved a plan to buy out subsidiaries. 
China Petroleum, Asia's biggest oil refiner, also known as
Sinopec, advanced 0.33 yuan, or 3.5 percent, to 9.73. The
company said its shareholders yesterday approved a plan to issue
as much as $1.3 billion worth of convertible bonds to fund a
buyout of its units. 
Shareholders also approved a plan to sell 10 billion yuan
of bonds in mainland China to fund the construction of chemical
projects, it said. 
Some of the most valuable companies such as China Vanke Co.
and Suning Appliance Co. declined as investors judged recent
gains excessive. 
``As the market rises, investor psychology changes and some
will decide to get out,'' said Wu Jianfei, who manages about
$438 million with CCB Principal Asset management Co. in Beijing.
``The market is supported by the fundamentals, but I do
recognize that it operates on differences in perception.'' 
Relative Strength Index 
Vanke, the nation's biggest property developer, slid 0.37
yuan, or 2.1 percent, to 16.93. Suning Appliance, China's
second-biggest home appliance retailer, fell 4.01 yuan, or 5.7
percent, to 66.78. Kweichow Moutai Co., the maker of Moutai, the
fiery liquor used at official banquets, fell 7.92 yuan, or 7
percent, to 105.28. 
The 14-day relative strength measure for the 300 index, a
moving average based on whether the gauge rose or fell, was at
82.3 yesterday. A reading above 70 signals to some investors the
index is poised for a fall. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Zhang Shidong in Shanghai  at
szhang5@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
James Regan at  jregan8@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Michael Janofsky" category="US" date="Jan 24, 2007  6:00 PM ET" keywords="CBS Corp, General Electric Co, News Corp, Twenty-First Century Fox Inc, Walt Disney Co/The, Advertising, Asia, Australia, Cable Television, California, Cinema, Commercial Services, Conglomerates, Connecticut, Entertainment, Industries, Internet, Leisure, Media, Movies, New York, New Zealand, North America, Pacific Rim, Publishing, Technology, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, U.S. Northeast, U.S. West, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-24/-idol-wins-32-6-million-viewers-withstands-critics-update2-.html"><headline>`Idol' Wins 32.6 Million Viewers, Withstands Critics</headline><body>
``American Idol,'' the most popular
show in primetime television, withstood last week's criticism
over judging and returned last night with the third-largest
audience for an entertainment show this season. 
With about 32.6 million viewers, according to overnight
results from Nielsen Media Research, the latest ``Idol'' trailed
only the two ``Idol'' shows that opened its sixth season on Fox
last week with audiences of 37.4 million and 37 million and the
National Football League's American Conference championship game
on CBS last Sunday, which drew 43.5 million. 
The first two ``Idol'' shows were the second and third most-watched of the series since the show's 2002 debut. They also
spurred criticism that two of the judges, Simon Cowell and Randy Jackson, were mean-spirited in their critique of some of the
singers. 
``Controversy breeds interest,'' said Bill Carroll, vice
president and director of programming at the Katz Television
Group in New York. ``A good dustup and some inopportune words
cause even the casual viewer to check out what's going on.'' 
The dip in ``Idol'' viewers last night reflected the
``little bit of leveling off'' that some shows experience,
Carroll said. 
Bush Speech 
The schedule was also altered by President Bush's State of
the Union address, which the four networks, ABC, CBS, NBC and
Fox, all carried live. The president's speech attracted 32.7
million viewers across the networks. 
``Idol'' was the highest-rated individual show of the night,
surpassing its audience of 30.2 million in the same week last
year when Bush spoke. 
``It was in line with what most people would have
anticipated,'' said Carroll. Katz advises TV stations on
programming. ``That's really all you can ask for.'' 
The success of ``Idol'' stems, in part, from the post-performance assessments by the judges -- Cowell, Jackson and
Paula Abdul -- before singers are sent home or to Los Angeles for
the next round of competition. 
Last week, Cowell angered fans of the show when he described
a big-eyed singer with questionable talent as a ``bush baby.''
Fans on the Internet said Cowell had gone too far. 
Speaking to television reporters last Saturday in Pasadena,
California, Cowell defended himself. 
``We all say things which we're going to get criticized
for,'' Cowell said. ``But don't condemn somebody for being a bit
wacky occasionally, or whatever, because it makes it interesting.
Otherwise, it's going to be, like, just a boring show.'' 
Viewers would feel cheated if `Idol'' only showed those
singers with talent. The others, he said, are part of ``the fun
and wackiness of this show.'' 
`Grey's Anatomy' 
``Idol'' isn't the only show that has shrugged off
controversy this season. 
``Grey's Anatomy'' has also kept up ratings in the face of
controversy over one of its stars, Isaiah Washington, using an
antigay slur to describe another cast member, T.R. Knight. 
``Grey's,'' the leading show on ABC, last week drew an
audience of 21.9 million, beating a new episode of CBS's ``CSI,''
which drew 21.4 million. 
Public feuding also helped ABC's daytime talk show, ``The
View.'' 
A public spat between one of its regular hosts, Rosie O'Donnell, and real estate developer Donald Trump over Trump's
defense of a beauty pageant contestant, helped boost viewership
of ``The View'' to an average 3.3 million in the fourth quarter
of last year, a 13 percent increase and the best quarter ever for
the 10-year-old show, according to Nielsen. 
``As long as people are not overly malicious, there's
buzz,'' said Carroll of Katz Television Group. ``And any buzz is
good buzz.'' 
Trump's own show, ``The Apprentice: Los Angeles,'' may be an
exception. The sixth season of the series has steadily lost
viewers each week, falling from 9.1 million in its premier three
weeks ago to 6.9 million last Sunday. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Michael Janofsky in Los Angeles at 
mjanofsky@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Emma Moody at  emoody@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Mary Jane Credeur" category="RETAIL" date="Jan 24, 2007  4:42 PM ET" keywords="Coca-Cola Bottling Co Consolidated, Coca-Cola Co/The, Coca-Cola Enterprises Inc, Coca-Cola Femsa SAB de CV, PepsiCo Inc, Advertising, Beverages, Consumer Goods, Containers, Emerging Markets, Food, Georgia (U.S.), Industries, Latin America, Media, Mexico, National Football League, New York, North America, North Carolina, Packaging, Retail, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, U.S. South, U.S. Southeast, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-24/coca-cola-will-run-first-super-bowl-ads-since-1998-update3-.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Will Run First Super Bowl Ads Since 1998</headline><body>
Coca-Cola Co. (KO) will go head-to-head
with PepsiCo Inc. (PEP) in Super Bowl television advertising for the
first time in almost a decade as it tries to boost sales of its
top-selling drink. 
One new ad for Coca-Cola Classic will air during
professional football's championship game along with two spots
that debuted during the television show ``American Idol,'' the
Atlanta-based company said in a statement today. Coca-Cola hasn't
run promotions during the Super Bowl since 1998. 
Advertising during television's most-watched event pits
Coca-Cola against PepsiCo as both companies try to reverse a drop
in U.S. soda sales. PepsiCo has advertised during the Super Bowl
for 21 consecutive years and will sponsor the half-time show for
the first time. 
``Coke wants back in the game,'' said Z. John Zhang,
marketing professor at the Wharton School at the University of
Pennsylvania. ``They've waited this many years to come back, so
the pressure is on them to have the louder voice.'' 
Both soft-drink makers are trying to stop declines in the
U.S., where soda consumption dropped in 2005 for the first time
in at least 15 years because of concern that sugary beverages
contribute to obesity. Coca-Cola's soft drink volume fell 1
percent in North America during the third quarter, and PepsiCo's
dropped 2 percent. 
Cost of Ads 
Coca-Cola's Super Bowl advertisements include a 60-second
spot titled ``Video Game,'' showing a character who passes out
bottles of Coca-Cola Classic to people he meets on the street.
Coca-Cola will also run a 30-second ad called ``Happiness
Factory'' that follows a bottle of Coke through an imaginary
vending machine. 
The company won't say anything about the new commercial
being made for the Super Bowl. The ads were created by
independent agency Wieden + Kennedy, based in Portland, Oregon. 
``Coca-Cola Classic has always been about having fun, and
that's what people get together to do when they watch the Super
Bowl,'' said Katie Bayne, senior vice president for Coca-Cola
brands in North America. 
Shares of Coca-Cola fell 1 cent to $48.13 at 4 p.m. in New
York Stock Exchange composite trading. They gained 20 percent
last year, the biggest gain since 1997. 
PepsiCo shares climbed 36 cents to $65.20. They rose 5.9
percent last year. 
Coca-Cola spokeswoman Susan McDermott wouldn't say how much
the company is spending on the game. A 30-second ad during the
Super Bowl can cost $2.5 million, according to AdWeek. Coca-
Cola's advertising budget was $2.48 billion in 2005. 
Bears vs. Colts 
More than 141 million people watched last year's Super Bowl.
This year's game, scheduled for Feb. 4 at Dolphin Stadium in
Miami Gardens, Fla., is a match-up between the Chicago Bears and
the Indianapolis Colts. 
The Super Bowl will be broadcast on CBS Corp.'s CBS network.
The television show American Idol, the most popular show on
primetime television, airs on News Corp.'s Fox network. 
In addition to the half-time show sponsorship, PepsiCo plans
to run 90 seconds of ads during the first half of the Super Bowl,
spokeswoman Nicole Bradley said. She wouldn't say how much the
company is spending, or which ads it plans to run. 
PepsiCo has a promotion featuring a sterling silver can of
Pepsi studded with diamonds, rubies and sapphires. The company
will give away the can, worth $100,000, and Super Bowl tickets
for life after the half-time show, which includes a performance
by the musician Prince. 
``We thrive on the Super Bowl spotlight. It's been a part of
our game plan for more than two decades,'' Bradley said. 
Last year, Coca-Cola sponsored a Super Bowl pre-game show
with its Full Throttle energy drink. Ads showed a semi-tractor
trailer truck mounted with an oversized can of Full Throttle
overtaking a small pickup truck with a slender can of rival
energy drink Red Bull. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Mary Jane Credeur in Atlanta at 
mcredeur@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Michael Nol at  mnol@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Lyubov Pronina" category="EUROPE" date="Jan 24, 2007 11:07 AM ET" keywords="Aeroflot - Russian Airlines OJSC, Siberia Airlines, Aerospace, Airlines, Asia, Commonwealth of Ind States, Defense, Eastern Europe, Emerging Markets, Europe, Industries, Pacific Rim, Russia, Transportation" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-24/aeroflot-2006-passenger-numbers-rise-8-7-percent-update1-.html"><headline>Aeroflot 2006 Passenger Numbers Rise 8.7 Percent</headline><body>
OAO Aeroflot (AFLT), eastern Europe's largest
airline, carried 8.7 percent more passengers last year as the
country's growing economy boosted travel. 
State-controlled Aeroflot flew 7.3 million passengers in 2006,
the Moscow-based airline said today in a statement. The company
handled 0.2 percent less cargo, or 145,300 tons, last year. The
load factor, or proportion of seats filled, increased to 70.1
percent from 69.1 percent in 2005. 
Aeroflot is attracting more travelers as Russia's economy
expands for a ninth consecutive year, backed by rising oil prices.
The carrier joined the SkyTeam alliance of Air France-KLM Group and
Delta Air Lines Inc. in April. 
The company declined to provide information on the number of
passengers carried on domestic and international flights. 
``We have a directive not to give out those figures,''
spokeswoman Irina Dannenberg said in a telephone interview from
Moscow today. She said the company may provide it at a later date. 
Aeroflot said in the statement that revenue under Russian
accounting standards increased 18.5 percent, without providing the
full figure. 
OAO Siberia Airlines (AVSI), Russia's second-largest carrier, flew
4.9 million passengers, or 16.4 percent more, spokesman Ilya Novokhatsky said in a telephone interview today. The airline flew
60 percent of its passengers on domestic routes and 40 percent on
international. 
GTK Rossiya, the state airline which last year absorbed
Pulkovo, Russia's third-largest carrier, said it flew more than 3
million passengers last year, including 1.4 million on
international routes. The company did not provide comparative
figures for 2005. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Lyubov Pronina in Moscow at 
lpronina@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Lars Klemming at 
lklemming@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Robert Fenner" category="AUSTRALIA_NEW_ZEALAND" date="Jan 24, 2007 12:36 AM ET" keywords="Bank of America Corp, Macquarie Group Ltd, Asia, Australia, Banking, Computer Software, Computers, Corporate Actions, Corporate Finance, Entertainment, Financial Services, Industries, Internet, Markets, Media, Mergers &amp;amp; Acquisitions, Mutual &amp;amp; Hedge Funds, Mutual Funds, New Zealand, North America, North Carolina, Oklahoma, Pacific Rim, Possible sales, Publishing, Radio, Regions, Securities Firms, Shareholdings, Technology, Texas, Trusts, U.S. Midwest, U.S. South, U.S. Southeast, U.S. Southwest, United States, mergers" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-24/macquarie-media-to-buy-american-consolidated-media-update2-.html"><headline>Macquarie Media to Buy American Consolidated Media</headline><body>
Macquarie Media Group Ltd.,
Australia's largest regional radio operator, agreed to buy
American Consolidated Media Inc. and Valley Newspapers Holdings
LP for A$102 million ($80 million) to expand into U.S. newspapers. 
The purchase gives it control of 40 titles in Texas and
Oklahoma, Sydney-based Macquarie Media Group Ltd. said in a
statement today. Macquarie Media is managed by Macquarie Bank
Ltd., Australia's largest investment bank. 
Managing Director Alex Harvey targeted the assets for their
stable earnings, limited need for capital spending and low
dependence on circulation and classifieds. 
``We have identified community newspapers as an asset class
which meets our investment criteria, generating stable cash flows
from predominantly local advertisers,'' Harvey said in the
statement. ``The acquisition is part of a broader strategy to
acquire and grow a portfolio of community newspaper businesses in
the United States.'' 
Dallas-based American Consolidated Media is being bought
from a group of investors including buyout firms Halyard Capital
and Arena Capital Partners, both based in New York. BancBoston
Ventures, a unit of Charlotte, North Carolina-based Bank of
America Corp. (BAC), is also part of the investment group. 
Macquarie Media shares fell 2 cents to A$4.75 at the 4:10
p.m. close of trading in Sydney. The stock has returned 7.8
percent to shareholders in the past 12 months, including
dividends. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Robert Fenner in Sydney 
rfenner@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Peter Vercoe  pvercoe@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Jim Kennett" category="ENERGY" date="Jan 25, 2007  4:04 PM ET" keywords="Halliburton Co, Commodities, Commonwealth of Ind States, Eastern Europe, Emerging Markets, Energy, Europe, Industries, Markets, Natural Gas, North America, Oil, Oil Equipment &amp;amp; Services, Regions, Russia, Specialized Regions, Texas, U.S. Southwest, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-25/halliburton-gets-tnk-bp-contract-worth-100-million-update2-.html"><headline>Halliburton Gets TNK-BP Contract Worth $100 Million</headline><body>
Halliburton Co. (HAL), the world's second-largest oil-services provider, said it has been awarded a three-year contract valued at about $100 million from BP Plc's Russia
venture. 
Halliburton's energy services unit will service wells for
OAO TNK-BP in the Tyumen region of Russia under terms of the
contract, the Houston-based company said today in a statement.
Work is scheduled to start in the second quarter. 
Halliburton's energy-services unit is trying to add business
in the oil-dominated eastern hemisphere to balance out its
exposure in North America, where volatile natural-gas markets
dominate exploration and production. 
The contract includes an option for three additional one-year periods, the company said. Halliburton will introduce new
technologies to Russia under the contract, including its EZ-Pilot
system used for steering drill bits through the earth. 
Halliburton is tentatively scheduled to report fourth-quarter earnings tomorrow morning. The stock fell 41 cents, or
1.4 percent, to $29.74 in New York Stock Exchange composite
trading. The shares are down 4.2 percent this year. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Jim Kennett in Houston at 
jkennett@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Robert Dieterich at 
rdieterich@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Michael White" category="US" date="Jan 26, 2007  5:20 PM ET" keywords="Activision Blizzard Inc, Electronic Arts Inc, Take-Two Interactive Software Inc, California, Computer Games, Computer Software, Entertainment, Industries, Leisure, Media, New York, North America, Regions, Technology, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, U.S. Pacific Northwest, U.S. West, United States, Video, Washington State" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-26/thq-other-game-makers-shares-fall-on-xbox-outlook-update1-.html"><headline>THQ, Other Game Makers' Shares Fall on Xbox Outlook</headline><body>
Shares of video-game makers
including THQ Inc. (THQI) fell after Microsoft Corp. lowered its
forecast for Xbox 360 sales. 
THQ fell 97 cents, or 3.1 percent, to $30.76, at 4 p.m. New
York time in Nasdaq Stock Market composite trading, while
Activision Inc., Take-Two Interactive Software Inc. (TTWO) and
Electronic Arts Inc. (EA) also declined. 
Game stocks declined after Microsoft yesterday cut its Xbox
360 sales forecast to 12 million units by June from 13 million
to 15 million, as it reduces production of the money-losing
consoles. The cut probably won't have a longterm impact on the
shares or sales of video-game publishers, American Technology
Research analyst P.J. McNealy said in a report today. 
A reduction in sales of 1 million units is ``typically not
material to any given publisher's revenue forecast,'' McNealy
said. The San Francisco-based analyst rates Agoura Hills,
California-based THQ's shares ``neutral.'' 
Shares of Electronic Arts, the largest game maker, fell 64
cents, or 1.3 percent, to $48.22. Activision, the second-largest
video-game publisher, fell 30 cents, or 1.8 percent, to $16.82.
Take-Two, based in New York, dropped 30 cents, or 1.7 percent,
to $16.94. 
Activision yesterday raised its sales forecast for the
current fiscal year to $1.37 billion from $1.15 billion, citing
improved sales of games including ``Guitar Hero.'' The Santa
Monica, California-based company also reaffirmed its forecast of
fiscal 2008 sales of more than $1.6 billon. 
THQ, the maker of ``Cars'' games, had holiday sales that
beat its forecasts, reporting third-quarter revenue of $475
million for the period ended Dec. 31. 
Sales of all video-game software rose 6 percent to $7.4
billion last year, according to a report from researcher NPD
Group. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Michael White in Los Angeles at 
Mwhite8@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Emma Moody at 
emoody@Bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Debarati Roy and Stuart Wallace" category="INDIA, COMMODITIES" date="Jan 26, 2007 12:29 PM ET" keywords="Cia Siderurgica Nacional SA, Tata Steel Ltd, Asia, Asia ex. Japan, Australia, Benelux, Brazil, Commodities, Corporate Actions, Corporate Finance, Emerging Markets, Euro Members, Europe, FTSE 100 Index, India, Industries, Latin America, Markets, Mergers &amp;amp; Acquisitions, Metals, Netherlands, Pacific Rim, Regions, South, South America, Southeast Asia, Steel, United Kingdom, ex-Energy" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-26/corus-auction-begins-jan-30-with-tata-csn-bidding-update2-.html"><headline>Corus Auction Begins Jan. 30, With Tata, CSN Bidding</headline><body>
Corus Group Plc, the U.K.'s biggest
steelmaker and valued by investors at 5.2 billion pounds ($10.2
billion), will be auctioned off on Jan. 30 with bidding from Tata
Steel Ltd. (TATA) and Cia. Siderurgica Nacional SA. 
The auction will start at 4:30 p.m., with a maximum of nine
rounds of bidding, the U.K.'s Takeover Panel said today in a
Regulatory News Service statement. The cash bids may continue until
Feb. 1 and all parties have agreed to the terms set by the panel,
an independent body that supervises takeovers. 
Corus, formerly British Steel Plc, has become a prize for Tata
and CSN as they seek to enter more mature markets, increasing their
bargaining power with suppliers and clients and providing new
outlets. 
Tata bid 500 pence for London-based Corus on Dec. 10 and CSN
offered 515 pence on Dec. 11. Tata initially offered 455 pence a
share on Oct. 20, and CSN topped that on Nov. 17. Shares of Corus
closed 5 pence, or 0.9 percent, higher at 558 pence in London. 
Buying Corus will help Tata add finishing mills in Europe that
supply automakers Ford Motor Co. and Volvo AB to plants in India,
the world's second fastest growing major economy after China.
Brazilian steelmakers, bolstered by record profit, are turning to
North America and Europe for deals because of limited growth at
home. 
Tata's Offer 
Tata Steel's Dec. 10 offer was 5.03 times Corus's earnings
before interest, taxes, depreciation and amortization, or Ebitda,
based on the U.K. steelmaker's earnings in the 12 months to June
30. CSN's bid is 5.73 times Corus's Ebitda. 
Mittal Steel Co. bought Arcelor SA last year for $38.3
billion. The offer for Arcelor was 4.46 times the Luxembourg-based
company's earnings. 
Tata Steel, which was borrowing 3.3 billion pounds for the
initial bid, arranged additional $800 million funding for its 500
pence offer from Standard Chartered Bank Plc and Standard Chartered
First Bank Korea Ltd. 
Moody's Investors Service and Standard  Poor's have said they
may lower Tata's debt rating. Rio de Janeiro-based CSN has said its
debt will rise $2.5 billion after the Corus purchase. 
Arcelor Mittal accounts for about 10 percent of world steel
output and steelmakers want to get bigger, partly to cut the cost
of buying raw materials. Cia. Vale do Rio Doce, BHP Billiton Ltd.
and Rio Tinto Group control three-quarters of the iron-ore trade. 
Global iron-ore contract prices climbed for the four year by a
record 19 percent gain in 2006, spurring companies to seek
alliances that will cut costs and secure iron-ore supplies. Prices
rose again for 2007, by 9.5 percent. 
Corus was created through the combination of British Steel and
the Netherlands' Royal Hoogovens in 1999. Chief Executive Officer
Philippe Varin, who took over in 2003, has returned the company to
profit after job cuts and plant closures. 
Lazard Ltd. and Goldman Sachs Group Inc. are financial
advisers to CSN. UBS AG is also CSN's corporate broker. Credit
Suisse Group, JPMorgan Cazenove and HSBC Holdings Plc are advising
Corus. NM Rothschild  Sons Ltd., Deutsche Bank AG and ABN Amro
Holding NV are advising Tata. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Stuart Wallace in London at 
swallace6@bloomberg.net.
Debarati Roy in Mumbai at 
Droy5@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Justin Carrigan at  jcarrigan@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Scott Hamilton" category="UK_IRELAND" date="Jan 26, 2007  9:48 AM ET" keywords="Tissue Regenix Group PLC, Banking, Commercial Services, Computers, Contracts, Earnings, Earnings Estimates, Europe, Financial Services, Industries, Markets, Orders, Profit Warnings, Regions, Technology, United Kingdom" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-26/torex-says-results-miss-estimates-on-delays-to-orders-update3-.html"><headline>Torex Says Results Miss Estimates on Delays to Orders</headline><body>
Torex Retail Plc (TRX), a U.K. software
developer, said 2006 financial results ``significantly'' missed
analysts' estimates because of delays in contracts. 
The orders will now be delivered this year, Torex said in a
regulatory statement today. The company didn't provide figures or
the estimates to which it referred. ``As of late last night, the
board are unable to have clarity on the company's trading in
2006,'' spokeswoman Ginny Pulbrook said. 
Torex is in talks with its banks about its borrowings, which
were 23 million pounds ($45.2 million) higher than the company
forecast for the year ended Dec. 31, according to today's
statement. The Witney, England-based company had its stock
temporarily suspended from trading. 
``This company is either bust or there's going to be a
refinancing,'' Derek Brown, an analyst at Seymour Pierce in
London, said in an interview. ``Today's statement is
disturbing.'' Brown said his stock rating is ``under review.'' 
Torex, led by Chief Executive Officer Neil Mitchell, employs
about 2,800 people in 22 countries and sells check-out till
software to clients including Tesco Plc and J Sainsbury Plc,
according to a statement. It first sold stock to investors on
London's Alternative Investment Market in March 2004. 
Milan Radia, an analyst at Torex's joint broker Jefferies
International Ltd., estimates that Torex's operating profit for
2006 was 35 million pounds and revenue was 280 million pounds. 
On Jan. 18, Torex said it won a number of new orders. Radia
said the announcement was ``inappropriate.'' 
The shares fell 3.5 percent yesterday to 41.75p, valuing the
company at 173.2 million pounds ($340 million). They've dropped
55 percent in the past year. 
In August, Torex reported a 5 million-pound loss for the
fiscal first half, compared with a profit of 754,000 pounds, a
year earlier. 
Torex will publish an update in the next few weeks, Pulbrook
said. 
To contact the reporter responsible for this story:
Scott Hamilton in London at 
Shamilton8@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Malcolm Fried in Amsterdam at 
mfried@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Debarati Roy and Pratik Parija" category="COMMODITIES" date="Jan 29, 2007  5:08 AM ET" keywords="ArcelorMittal, JSW Steel Ltd, POSCO, Steel Authority of India Ltd, Tata Steel Ltd, Asia, Asia ex. Japan, Australia, Benelux, China, Commodities, Commodities Markets, Earnings, Earnings Estimates, Emerging Markets, Euro Members, Europe, FTSE 100 Index, India, Industries, Korea, Markets, Metals, Netherlands, Pacific Rim, Regions, South, Southeast Asia, Steel, Taiwan, Trade, United Kingdom, ex-Energy" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-29/steel-authority-s-profit-more-than-doubles-on-prices-update3-.html"><headline>Steel Authority's Profit More Than Doubles on Prices</headline><body>
Steel Authority of India Ltd., the
largest steelmaker, reported third-quarter net income more than
doubled, beating analyst estimates, because of an increase in
prices and sales. Its shares rose to a record. 
Profit rose to 14.71 billion rupees ($332 million), or 3.6
rupees a share, in the quarter ended Dec. 31, from 6.56 billion
rupees, or 1.6 rupees, a year ago, the company said today. Sales
rose by a third to 83.52 billion rupees. 
Asian steel prices are recovering because of a slowdown in
output in China, which supplies one-third of the world's steel,
and a construction boom in India. Demand for vehicles, homes and
appliances has risen amid record incomes and bank lending in
Asia's fourth-biggest economy, lifting sales at Steel Authority. 
``This has been such a good quarter with prices remaining
firm and the company raising production,'' said Sang Hyun Kim,
an analyst with ABN Amro Bank NV in Hong Kong. ``The next few
quarters also look good as steel consumption is rising and the
company is striving to cut costs.'' 
Steel prices in India were 21 percent higher in the quarter,
helped by an average 9.1 percent expansion in the economy in the
first nine months of the fiscal year. JSW Steel Ltd. (JSTL), India's
fourth-biggest producer, said Jan. 22 profit more than doubled,
while Tata Steel Ltd. (TATA), the second-biggest, may tomorrow report a
48 percent jump in net income to 11.13 billion rupees. 
Steel Authority's profit exceeded the 14.38 billion rupees
median estimate of five analysts surveyed by Bloomberg. 
`Optimism is Back' 
Shares of Steel Authority are the best-performers this year
on India's 50-share SP CNX Nifty index. The stock, which has
doubled in the past year, climbed 1.2 percent to a record 113
rupees when trading ended on the Bombay Stock Exchange. 
``We expected earnings to surprise us this quarter,'' said
Sanjay Makhija, vice president at Fortune Financial Services
Ltd., a Mumbai-based brokerage. ``Optimism is back in metals.'' 
Steel Authority sold a record 3 million tons in the three
months ended Dec. 31, up 9 percent from a year ago, as demand
rose from construction companies and carmakers. Sales reached
8.4 million tons in the April-December period, the highest-ever,
the company said today. Output in the three months ending March
will rise 5 percent from the December quarter. 
India's steel usage will expand 7.7 percent annually from
2010 to 2015, faster than 4 percent a year globally, according
to the International Iron  Steel Institute. That's encouraged
Arcelor Mittal (MT) and Posco (005490) to plan $21 billion of investments in
the South Asian nation over the next seven years. 
Raising Output 
``Domestic demand is growing, steel prices have stabilized
in China and are recovering in Europe and the U.S.,'' Chairman
S.K. Roongta told reporters in New Delhi. ``The steel market
will be stable in the near future.'' 
To meet demand, Steel Authority plans to triple capacity to
40 million tons by 2020, Minister Ram Vilas Paswan said Jan. 12.
The expansion will cost about 1 trillion rupees ($22.4 billion)
and will be done in stages, he said. 
Earnings were buoyed by a decline in prices of coal, which
accounts for two-thirds of the company's raw material costs. The
benchmark contract prices for coking coal dropped 8 percent in
2006 to $115 a ton and declined further to $98 a ton this year. 
``We're going to be draw benefits from the fall in prices
of coal,'' said Roongta. 
Input Costs 
Steel Authority, which sources it's ore requirement from
own mines, buys about 9 million tons, or two-third of its coal
requirement, from overseas. Raw material costs rose 2.5 percent
in the third-quarter to 31.65 billion rupees. 
``The company is gearing itself to meet the growing demand
and at the same time keeping a close watch on costs,'' Kshitiz Prasad, analyst at Anand Rathi Securities Pvt. in Mumbai, said.
``This is a good company to have in your portfolio.'' He has an
``outperform'' rating on the company's shares. (NIFTY) 
The company said it will pay 1.6 rupees a share in interim
dividend. The government owns 85.82 percent of the steelmaker. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Debarati Roy in Mumbai at 
droy5@bloomberg.net;
Pratik Parija in New Deli at 
pparija@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
James Poole at 
jpoole4@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Molly Peterson" category="US" date="Jan 30, 2007  6:47 PM ET" keywords="News Corp, Twenty-First Century Fox Inc, Asia, Australia, California, Computer Software, Congress, Crime, Entertainment, Industries, Internet, Legal Affairs, Litigation, Media, New York, New York City, New Zealand, North America, Pacific Rim, Publishing, Regions, Specialized Regions, Technology, U.S., U.S. Government, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, U.S. West, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-30/news-corp-s-myspace-backs-rules-to-combat-predators-update2-.html"><headline>News Corp.'s MySpace Backs Rules to Combat Predators</headline><body>
News Corp. (NWSA)'s MySpace, a social-networking Web site, endorsed U.S. House and Senate proposals
requiring convicted sex offenders to register their e-mail
addresses and other online identities with the government. 
The bipartisan proposals, introduced today, would let the
Justice Department give sites such as MySpace access to the
database if they pledged not to use the information for purposes
other than protecting minors from sexual predators. 
MySpace wouldn't let anyone on the sex-offender registry
access any part of its site, Hemanshu Nigam, chief security
officer of MySpace and Fox Interactive Media Inc., said during a
news conference today in Washington. 
The legislation comes less than two weeks after News Corp.
was sued by four families of teenage girls who said they were
sexually abused by adults they met through the networking site.
MySpace announced yesterday that it donated technology, developed
with Sentinel Technologies Inc., to help authorities collect
information on convicted sex offenders. 
``As a company, we don't want sex offenders on our site,
period,'' said Nigam, who joined lawmakers at today's briefing. 
Class A shares of New York-based News Corp. rose 25 cents to
$23.07 in New York Stock Exchange composite trading and have
climbed 47 percent in the last 12 months. 
Prison Sentences 
Convicted sex offenders who fail to register all e-mail
addresses, instant-message names and other online identifiers
could face up to 10 years in prison under the proposal. The
general public wouldn't have access to the registry. 
The legislation also would make it a crime, punishable by up
to 20 years in prison, for adults to lie about their age in an
attempt to seduce children online. 
``It's going to be hard for sexual predators to avoid
detection here,'' said Senator Charles Schumer, a Democrat from
New York who wrote the Senate bill with Republican Senator John McCain of Arizona. 
The proposal wouldn't require companies to seek access to
the government's database or block registered sex offenders from
using their sites. 
``It's voluntary, but I think there are going to be
overwhelming civil reasons why they're going to want to do
this,'' said Democratic Representative Earl Pomeroy of North
Dakota, the House bill's chief sponsor. 
Social-networking sites that ignore the registry could face
``a range of potential liabilities,'' Pomeroy said. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Molly Peterson in Washington at 
mpeterson9@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Cesca Antonelli at  fantonelli@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Editor: Schmick" category="MANUFACTURING" date="Jan 30, 2007  3:55 PM ET" keywords="Boeing Co/The, Northrop Grumman Corp, Aerospace, Airlines, Austria, Balkans, Baltics, Belgium, Benelux, CAC 40 Index, California, Congress, Construction &amp;amp; Engineering, Cyprus, Czech Republic, Defense, Defense Dept., Denmark, Eastern Europe, Electronics, Emerging Markets, Estonia, Euro Members, Europe, European Union, Finland, France, Germany, Greece, Hungary, Illinois, Industries, Ireland, Italy, Latvia, Lithuania, Luxembourg, Machinery, Malta, Manufacturing, Marine Transport, Markets, Militaries, Netherlands, Nordic Region, North America, Poland, Portugal, Regions, Rules and Regulations, Shipbuilders, Slovak Republic, Slovenia, Spain, Spain &amp;amp; Portugal, Specialized Regions, State Dept, Sweden, Trade, Transportation, U.S., U.S. Government, U.S. Midwest, U.S. Pacific Northwest, U.S. West, United Kingdom, United States, Washington State, World Trade Organization" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-30/last-request-issued-for-bids-on-u-s-tanker-program-update1-.html"><headline>Last Request Issued for Bids on U.S. Tanker Program</headline><body>
The U.S. Air Force today issued its
final request for bids to build the service at least 179 aerial
refueling tankers, a program worth up to $40 billion over the
next 15 years. 
A winner will be chosen later this year, Assistant Secretary
for Acquisition Sue Payton told reporters at the Defense
Department. That's more than five years after the Senate in
October 2001 approved a program that later collapsed over
questions of its cost-effectiveness and the illegal behavior of
senior Air Force and Boeing Co. (BA) officials. 
Boeing Co. has said it will bid on the new program. The only
other viable candidate, a team of Northrop Grumman Corp. (NOC) and
Airbus SAS parent European Aeronautic, Defence  Space Co., said
Jan. 8 it may not bid because of ``fundamental concerns'' that
some selection criteria may be biased against its KC-30 tanker. 
Payton said the Air Force modified some criteria that
Northrop challenged. The Air Force wants a plane that can be
converted to carry cargo and passengers as well as refuel Air
Force and Marine Corps planes. Northrop Grumman wanted to ensure
that the selection criteria are broad enough to take into account
the advertised capabilities of its KC-30. 
``I really don't know'' if the Northrop Grumman-EADS team
will bid, Payton said. ``I certainly hope we have a horserace.'' 
Northrop spokesman Randy Belote said the company would defer
comment until it determined how its KC-30's capabilities fit `the
requirements as specified'' in the request. 
First Plane in 2010 
The Air Force has budgeted $8.2 billion for tanker
production through 2013, with the first plane to be delivered in
2010 and the first squadron of 16 available by 2013, Payton said.
The service's intent is to buy at least 12 aircraft a year once
the plane enters its full-production phase, she said. 
The contract for the development phase will pay all costs
plus a negotiated profit, while the annual production contracts
will be ``fixed-price,'' which require the contractor to pay for
any cost overruns, Payton said. 
The Air Force has 531 KC-135 tankers with an average age of
about 44 years and 59 larger KC-10 tankers with an average age of
20.5 years. 
The original program was tainted by scandal after the
Pentagon Inspector General, U.S. Government Accountability
Office, Congressional Budget Office and other panels criticized a
proposed contract to Boeing as wasteful and inefficient. 
What was a potential $23 billion program collapsed in 2004
after disclosures that the Air Force's second-ranking acquisition
official, Darleen Druyun, was negotiating a job with Boeing Chief
Financial Officer Michael Sears during contract talks. No planes
were built. The Air Force had to start the program from scratch.
 
</body></entry><entry author="By Tony Capaccio" category="MANUFACTURING" date="Jan 30, 2007  2:06 PM ET" keywords="Boeing Co/The, Northrop Grumman Corp, Aerospace, Airlines, Austria, Balkans, Baltics, Belgium, Benelux, CAC 40 Index, California, Congress, Construction &amp;amp; Engineering, Cyprus, Czech Republic, Defense, Defense Dept., Denmark, Eastern Europe, Electronics, Emerging Markets, Estonia, Euro Members, Europe, European Union, Finland, France, Germany, Greece, Hungary, Illinois, Industries, Ireland, Italy, Latvia, Lithuania, Luxembourg, Machinery, Malta, Manufacturing, Marine Transport, Markets, Militaries, Netherlands, Nordic Region, North America, Poland, Portugal, Regions, Rules and Regulations, Shipbuilders, Slovak Republic, Slovenia, Spain, Spain &amp;amp; Portugal, State Dept, Sweden, Trade, Transportation, U.S., U.S. Government, U.S. Midwest, U.S. Pacific Northwest, U.S. West, United Kingdom, United States, Washington State, World Trade Organization" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-30/last-request-issued-for-bids-on-40-billion-u-s-tanker-program.html"><headline>Last Request Issued for Bids on $40 Billion U.S. Tanker Program</headline><body>
The U.S. Air Force today issued its
final request for bids to build the service at least 179 aerial
refueling tankers, a program worth up to $40 billion over the
next 15 years. 
A winner will be chosen later this year, Assistant Secretary
for Acquisition Sue Payton told reporters at the Defense
Department. That's more than five years after the Senate in
October 2001 approved a program that later collapsed over
questions of its cost-effectiveness and the illegal behavior of
senior Air Force and Boeing Co. (BA) officials. 
Boeing Co. has said it will bid on the new program. The only
other viable candidate, a team of Northrop Grumman Corp. (NOC) and
Airbus SAS parent European Aeronautic, Defence  Space Co., said
Jan. 8 it may not bid because of ``fundamental concerns'' that
some selection criteria may be biased against its KC-30 tanker. 
Payton said the Air Force modified some criteria that
Northrop challenged. The Air Force wants a plane that can be
converted to carry cargo and passengers as well as refuel Air
Force and Marine Corps planes. Northrop Grumman wanted to ensure
that the selection criteria are broad enough to take into account
the advertised capabilities of its KC-30. 
``I really don't know'' if the Northrop Grumman-EADS team
will bid, Payton said. ``I certainly hope we have a horserace.'' 
The Air Force has budgeted $8.2 billion for tanker
production through 2013, with the first plane to be delivered in
2010 and the first squadron of 16 available by 2013, Payton said.
The service's intent is to buy at least 12 aircraft a year once
the plane enters its full-production phase, she said. 
Contract Terms 
The contract for the development phase will pay all costs
plus a negotiated profit, while the annual production contracts
will be ``fixed-price,'' which require the contractor to pay for
any cost overruns, Payton said. 
The Air Force has 531 KC-135 tankers with an average age of
about 44 years and 59 larger KC-10 tankers with an average age of
20.5 years. 
The original program was tainted by scandal after the
Pentagon Inspector General, U.S. Government Accountability
Office, Congressional Budget Office and other panels criticized a
proposed contract to Boeing as wasteful and inefficient. 
What was a potential $23 billion program collapsed in 2004
after disclosures that the Air Force's second-ranking acquisition
official, Darleen Druyun, was negotiating a job with Boeing Chief
Financial Officer Michael Sears during contract talks. No planes
were built. The Air Force had to start the program from scratch. 
To contact the reporters on this story:
Tony Capaccio in Washington at 
acapaccio@bloomberg.net; 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Michael Forsythe at 
mforsythe@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By William Mauldin" category="EASTERN_EUROPE, EMERGING_MARKETS" date="Jan 30, 2007 11:56 AM ET" keywords="Gazprom OAO, Irkut Corp, Polyus Gold OJSC, Sberbank of Russia, Closing Market Comments, Commonwealth of Ind States, Eastern Europe, Emerging Markets, Equity Movers, Europe, Markets, Regions, Russia, Russian Stocks, Stock Markets by Country" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-30/russian-stocks-including-sberbank-fall-gazprom-shares-advance.html"><headline>Russian Stocks Including Sberbank Fall; Gazprom Shares Advance</headline><body>
Russian stocks including OAO Sberbank
fell. The country's largest lender declined after its president
set a minimum bid level for the bank's share sale that was lower
than the trading price of the stock. 
OAO Gazprom paced advancing shares, rallying late in the day
on a rise in oil prices. 
The dollar-denominated RTS Index dropped 0.7 percent to
1824.77. The ruble-based Micex Index added 0.2 percent to 1645.02
after falling as much as 2.2 percent earlier. 
Sberbank shares retreated 3.6 percent to 85,305.53 rubles
($3,213.62) on the Micex Stock Exchange, and 2.4 percent to
$3,220 on the RTS, marking a third day of declines totaling 9
percent on each index. The bank is offering to sell as many as
3.5 million additional shares starting today. 
If all of the shares were sold at the latest trading price,
the offer would be worth more than $11.2 billion, topping the
$10.6 billion OAO Rosneft, Russia's second-biggest oil producer,
raised last July in the country's largest initial public
offering. 
``Over the last two months, Sberbank (SBER) has been the driver of
the market, since oil prices are weak,'' said Alexei Belkin, who
helps manage $300 million at Aton Capital in Moscow. 
The bank's President and Chief Executive Officer Andrei Kazmin yesterday said the minimum price for bids would be 68,000
rubles, Interfax reported. That is 20 percent below today's
closing price. 
``It's my impression that Sberbank wanted to cool off the
pre-placement speculation,'' Belkin said. ``The price rise of the
last month and a half should be considered speculative.'' The
stock rose 42 percent from the start of December until its three-day losing streak began Jan. 26. 
UralSib, Rosbank 
Natalia Orlova, a banking analyst at Alfa Bank in Moscow,
wrote today that Kazmin's comments indicate that ``Sberbank's
management prefers to place all 3.5 million shares at a low price
rather than placing part of them at the market price.'' 
The issue would raise $9 billion if all shares were sold at
the minimum price mentioned by Belkin. 
Sberbank's declined was mirrored in smaller Russian banking
stocks. UralSib Bank, Russia's biggest privately owned lender,
lost 6.3 percent to 3.15 cents on the RTS. Shares of Rosbank, in
which Societe Generale SA of France owns a stake, slipped 1.5
percent to 176.19 rubles, marking a sixth straight day of
declines. 
Russia's Central Bank said it would purchase 892,601
additional shares of Sberbank. The government may press for a low
offer price for the Sberbank shares in order to minimize the
amount of rubles it will have to print to fund the purchase,
Orlova said. Increasing the ruble money supply can fuel
inflation, which was 9 percent last year in Russia. 
Energy Stocks 
Russian energy stocks retreated during morning trading after
oil dropped 2.5 percent to $54.01 a barrel yesterday in New York.
Crude for March delivery rose 1.9 percent to $55.02 today on the
New York Mercantile Exchange as markets closed in Russia. 
Shares of OAO Gazprom (GAZP), the world's largest natural gas
producer, gained 0.3 percent to 284.36 rubles. OAO Lukoil,
Russia's biggest oil producer, rose 0.2 percent to 2093.51
rubles. 
OAO Unified Energy System, Russia's national power utility,
added 2 percent to 30.39 rubles. Russian Energy Minister Viktor Khristenko today announced the construction of what will be the
country's first privately funded power station. The 124-megawatt
plant in the oil-rich Tyumen region will help Russia meet its
expanding electricity demand and fuel economic growth. 
OAO Polyus Gold (PLZL), Russia's largest gold producer, increased
2.7 percent to 1295.50 rubles. The shares have risen 9.3 percent
since the company announced on January 22 that the National
Resources Ministry had confirmed that its Natalka mine holds 48
million ounces of gold. 
OAO Irkut Corp. (IRKT) advanced 6 percent to 28.29 rubles. OAO
Unified Aircraft Corp., the state-controlled aviation holding,
offered to buy a 10 percent stake in Irkut from the European
Aeronautic Defence  Space Co. for 29.19 rubles a share. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
William Mauldin in Moscow at 
wmauldin1@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Balduin Hesse in London at 
bhesse2@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Lars Paulsson" category="ENERGY_MARKETS" date="Jan 30, 2007  9:44 AM ET" keywords="E.ON SE, Electricite de France SA, EnBW Energie Baden-Wuerttemberg AG, Macquarie Group Ltd, RWE AG, Alternative Energy, Coal, Commodities, Commodities Markets, DAX Index, Electricity Generation, Energy, Energy Trading, Environment, Euro Members, Europe, European Union, Germany, Hydroelectric Power, Industries, Markets, Natural Gas, Natural Gas Market, Nordic Region, Nuclear Power, Oil, Power Markets, Regions, Rules and Regulations, Specialized Regions, Sweden, United Kingdom, Utilities, Wind Power" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-30/europe-needs-real-time-power-gas-data-watchdog-says-update1-.html"><headline>Europe Needs Real-Time Power, Gas Data, Watchdog Says</headline><body>
European utilities should be forced to
release more information about supply and demand in the region's
electricity and natural gas markets on a real-time basis to foster
competition, a regulatory leader said. 
``There has to be real-time maximum transparency,'' and the
European Commission should propose binding guidelines, John Mogg,
chairman of European Regulators' Group for Electricity and Gas,
said today at a City  Financial conference in London. 
Energy traders want more information about supply and demand
in European markets to help them decide when to buy and sell and
at what price. Nations including the U.K. and the Nordic countries
provide details on individual power plant availability on a near
real-time basis, while others including German utilities provide
daily updates on aggregated information by fuel source. 
``The absence of transparency is putting sand in the system
in a dreadful way,'' said Mogg, who is also chairman of the U.K.'s
Office of Gas and Electricity Markets. 
The European Commission noted in a Jan. 10 policy paper that
European energy markets suffer a lack of reliable and timely
information. 
A transparent market where all participants have equal access
to market sensitive information is essential, Adam Cooper, vice
president for regulatory affairs at Merrill Lynch  Co. Inc. in
London said at the conference. 
Merrill Lynch, the third-largest securities firm, is an
active participant in Europe's power and natural gas markets. The
data is already collected, ``it just needs to be brought to the
market,'' Cooper said. 
Improved transparency would minimize risks for new market
players, ``reduce entry barriers and improve trust in the
wholesale markets and confidence in price signals,'' the
Commission said. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Lars Paulsson in London at 
lpaulsson@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Daniel Tilles at 
dtilles@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Patricia Cheng and Winnie Zhu" category="ASIA, EMERGING_MARKETS, FINANCE, INSURANCE" date="Jan 30, 2007  4:05 AM ET" keywords="AXA SA, Allianz SE, American International Group Inc, China Life Insurance Co Ltd, Asia, Asia ex. Japan, Australia, Banking, CAC 40 Index, China, Earnings, Emerging Markets, Euro Members, Europe, Financial Services, France, Germany, Hong Kong, Industries, Insurance, Korea, Markets, New York, North America, Pacific Rim, Regions, Specialized Regions, Taiwan, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-30/china-life-says-2006-profit-may-rise-more-than-50-update3-.html"><headline>China Life Says 2006 Profit May Rise More Than 50%</headline><body>
China Life Insurance Co., the
world's second-biggest insurer by market value, said profit rose
more than 50 percent last year because of investment gains,
after the nation's stock market rose to a record. 
Preliminary figures showed the state-owned company had net
income of at least 8.19 billion yuan last year. Profit was 5.46
billion yuan ($702 million), or 0.2 yuan per share, in 2005,
China Life said in a statement today. Chinese regulations
require companies to notify the stock exchange if they expect
earnings to rise or fall more than 50 percent. 
``Investment gain was the main driver last year,'' said
Paul Lee, an analyst at Tai Fook Securities in Hong Kong.
``China Life bought a lot of A shares in the second half of the
year. The mark-to-market gains would be huge.'' 
Shares traded in China more than doubled last year, helping
drive China Life's stock higher than ING Groep NV, Allianz SE (ALV)
and Axa to make it the biggest insurer by market value after
American International Group. Sales of shares by some of China's
biggest companies benefited the Beijing-based company, which
oversaw 595 billion yuan of investments as of June 30 and has
been buying more equities since. 
The Shanghai Composite Index (SHCOMP), which tracks the
performance of all stocks on the bigger of the country's two
exchanges, surged 130 percent last year. 
``Its earnings may have peaked last year,'' said Lee, who
has a ``sell'' recommendation on China Life stock and a 12-month
price target of HK$20. ``Though we remain bullish about the
mainland market, it's unlikely it'll repeat similar gain this
year.'' 
Listing Rules 
China Life made the announcement under Chinese accounting
rules to comply with Shanghai listing requirements after 1.5
billion of yuan-denominated shares started trading on the bourse
earlier this month. The insurer, whose shares trade in Hong Kong
and New York as well as Shanghai, also reports its financial
statements under international standards. 
Profit climbed 30 percent to 9.31 billion yuan in 2005 from
7.17 billion yuan a year earlier, according to international
standards, which recognize premiums, commissions and investment
gains differently from Chinese accounting rules. 
The net income calculated using international standards
should be higher because of the difference in accounting
treatments, said Lee. 
China Life's Hong Kong-traded stock slid 12 percent this
year after almost quadrupling last year. It rose 1 percent to
close at HK$23.60 today. 
The company's market capitalization more than quadrupled in
the past year, from $27.25 billion Feb. 1 to $129.5 billion
today, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. That compares
with a 22 percent rise for ING, a 38 percent increase in Axa,
and a gain of 29 percent Allianz's market value over the same
period. 
American International Group (AIG) is valued at $177.7 billion
yesterday and was worth $172 billion a year earlier, according
to Bloomberg data. 
To contact the reporters on this story:
Winnie Zhu in Shanghai at 
wzhu4@bloomberg.net;
Patricia Cheng in Hong Kong at 
pcheng9@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editors responsible for this story:
Reinie Booysen at 
rbooysen@bloomberg.net;
Ben Richardson at 
brichardson8@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Jesse Westbrook" category="US, FINANCE" date="Jan 31, 2007  6:13 PM ET" keywords="McGraw Hill Financial Inc, Moody's Corp, Banking, Bond, Bonds, Commercial Services, Congress, Corp., Corporate Actions, Corporate Bonds, Corporate Finance, Country Debt Ratings, Financial Services, Industries, Loan Ratings, Market Regulators, Markets, Media, New York, North America, Publishing, Regions, Rules and Regulations, Securities &amp;amp; Exch Comm, Specialized Regions, U.S., U.S. Government, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, U.S. Northeast, US, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-31/sec-seeks-to-foster-competition-for-credit-raters-update2-.html"><headline>SEC Seeks to Foster Competition for Credit-Raters</headline><body>
The U.S. Securities and Exchange
Commission proposed rules making it easier for credit-rating
companies to get federal approval, part of an effort to encourage
competition for Standard  Poor's and Moody's Investors Service. 
The SEC today proposed allowing debt-rating firms in
business for at least three years to register for federal
designation as long as they provide details on their ratings
performance and certifications from clients. Congress mandated
the SEC rules in a law passed last year. 
``Standard  Poor's and Moody's yield enormous influence,''
SEC Chairman Christopher Cox said at an agency meeting in
Washington. ``The goal of this new law is to improve ratings
quality by fostering competition.'' 
SEC recognition gives SP, Moody's, Fitch Ratings and two
other firms an edge in selling services to fund managers who make
investment decisions based on their ratings. The collapse of
Enron Corp., which had an investment-grade rating from SP and
Moody's four days before its 2001 bankruptcy filing, fueled
congressional demands for more competition. 
Corporations pay debt-rating companies to rank the credit-worthiness of their businesses, as well as the bonds and
preferred stock that they issue. SP, Moody's and Fitch account
for more than 90 percent of the global credit-rating market,
according to the companies' regulatory filings. 
Other Firms 
A.M. Best Co. and Dominion Bond Rating Service Ltd. are the
only other firms recognized as a ``nationally recognized
statistical rating organization'' by the SEC. Once the proposed
SEC regulations become final, the agency may have to monitor the
industry to prevent saturation, said Sean Egan, who is seeking
federal recognition for his firm, Haverford, Pennsylvania-based
Egan-Jones Ratings Co. 
``The positive is that the act opens up the industry,'' Egan
said. ``The negative is that the market will have to sort out the
timely and accurate and independent firms.'' 
The rulemaking would also boost the SEC's oversight of
credit-rating firms by giving the agency ``recordkeeping and
examination'' authority for the first time, agency commissioner
Annette Nazareth said. 
Credit-rating firms would have to report to the SEC audited
financial statements, client lists and procedures aimed at
preventing the release of non-public information to investors.
Conflicts of interest, such as a firm assigning a credit rating
to a subsidiary, would be prohibited. 
The regulation calls for the SEC to respond to completed
applications within 90 days. The agency's five commissioners have
to approve or deny an application. Currently, SEC staff decides
whether a credit-rating company should receive federal
recognition. 
Since 1975, only nine rating companies have been granted
nationally recognized status by the government, according to the
SEC. Only five now hold that designation because of mergers. 
The SEC will take public comment on the proposal for 30 days
before deciding whether to make it final. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Jesse Westbrook in Washington at 
jwestbrook1@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Erik Schatzker at 
eschatzker@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Alex Emery" category="COMMODITIES" date="Jan 31, 2007  6:12 PM ET" keywords="Freeport-McMoRan Inc, Newmont Mining Corp, Arizona, Colorado, Commodities, Commodities Markets, Copper, Emerging Markets, Gold, Industries, Latin America, Light Metals, Markets, Metals, Mining, Non-Ferrous Metals, North America, Peru, Peru Economy, Precious Metals, Regions, Silver, South America, Specialized Regions, Trade, U.S. Southwest, U.S. West, United States, Zinc, ex-Energy" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-31/peru-s-2007-gold-output-may-drop-13-on-ore-grades-update1-.html"><headline>Peru's 2007 Gold Output May Drop 13% on Ore Grades</headline><body>
Peru's gold output may drop 13 percent
this year as ore grades decline at Minera Yanacocha, the country's
biggest producer, said Isaac Cruz, president of the nation's
mining lobby. 
Output at Newmont Gold Corp. (NEM)'s Yanacocha, the world's second-
largest gold mine, dropped last year after environmental protests
kept the Denver-based company from bringing new deposits into
production, Cruz said today at a press conference in Lima. The
world's biggest gold mine, Grasberg in Indonesia, is owned by
Freeport-McMoRan Copper  Gold Inc. (FCX) 
``Mines like Yanacocha haven't been able to explore or start
up new deposits because of disputes with neighboring
communities,'' said Cruz, who is also chief executive officer of
zinc-mining company Sociedad Mineral El Brocal SA. ``We're going
to see the effects of these problems this year.'' 
Copper output will rise 13 percent in 2007 on the January
start-up of an $850 million expansion of Phelps Dodge Corp.'s
Cerro Verde mine, and zinc output will rise 4 percent, Cruz said. 
Companies plan to spend $22 billion over the next five years
on mining, oil, natural-gas and electricity projects, more than
the amount in the past 15 years, Cruz said. 
Peru is the world's fifth-largest gold producer, fourth in
copper and third in zinc. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Alex Emery in Lima at 
aemery1@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Steve Stroth at  sstroth@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Aisha Phoenix" category="UK_IRELAND, MANUFACTURING" date="Jan 31, 2007 12:09 PM ET" keywords="Apple Inc, Cirrus Logic Inc, Computer Software, Computers, Corporate Finance, Earnings, Equity Movers, Europe, Industries, Machinery, Manufacturing, Markets, North America, Regions, Scotland, Semiconductors, Small Cap Stocks, Technology, Telecom Equipment, Telecom Services, United Kingdom, United States, Wireless Communications" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-31/wolfson-s-shares-drop-as-profit-falls-on-lower-sales-update4-.html"><headline>Wolfson's Shares Drop as Profit Falls on Lower Sales</headline><body>
Shares of Wolfson Microelectronics
Plc (WLF) fell 5.8 percent after the U.K. maker of semiconductors for
mobile phones and Apple Inc. (AAPL)'s iPods said profit dropped and
forecast lower first-quarter sales. 
Fourth-quarter net income fell 43 percent to $7.99 million,
or 6.71 cents a share, and sales declined 14 percent to $52.6
million, the Edinburgh-based company said today. Wolfson forecast
first-quarter sales in the range of $37 million to $42 million,
lower than the $45.9 million reported a year earlier. 
Revenue from consumer audio applications fell ``sharply''
because of a drop in demand from makers of DVD players and
``softness'' in the personal computer market. Distribution and
selling expenses rose 35 percent to $5.8 million due to the
recruitment of sales personnel and engineers, the company said. 
``Most of what's happened today is a reaction to a first
quarter that's below even its low seasonal level and a fear that
this inventory level issue may have a hangover into the second
quarter,'' Lee Simpson, an analyst at Evolution Securities, said
today in a telephone interview. He rates Wolfson ``buy.'' 
The shares dropped 17.25 pence to 280 pence in London, giving
the company a market value of about 327.8 million pounds ($643
million). 
``For the first quarter, revenues will be impacted by
seasonality, particularly in some key applications as well as an
ongoing inventory correction in the global consumer electronics
markets,'' Wolfson said. 
Recruiting Costs 
The microchips Wolfson makes, called mixed-signal
semiconductors, convert digital signals to analogue format,
allowing users to hear sounds and see images. The company's
products are used in sound cards. 
``Most of what was reported in the fourth quarter was
signaled in the third-quarter results,'' Simpson said. ``Their
overheads are running a little bit higher than we saw it.'' 
Wolfson said in October that sales would be less than
forecast after Sony Corp. cut projections for PlayStation
Portable sales and Benq Corp.'s German handset unit filed for
insolvency. 
Administrative expenses rose 31 percent to $2.8 million as
Wolfson incurred recruitment costs related to management
appointments, the company said today. 
Chief Executive Officer David Milne, who co-founded the
company in 1984, will leave his post on Feb. 28 and remain on the
board, Wolfson said on Nov. 23. Dave Shrigley joins the board of
directors on Nov. 27 and will take over as CEO on March 1, the
company said then. 
Outlook 
Wolfson also said that research and development expenditure
rose 32 percent to $8.3 million in the fourth quarter, mainly
because of the recruitment of engineers. 
``The outlook for the company is still pretty strong in
terms of new products,'' Mark Davis, an analyst at Panmure
Gordon, said today in a telephone interview. ``In the second half
we are looking for penetration of the tier-1 handset
manufacturers, for example Nokia.'' Davis rates the stock
``hold.'' 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Aisha Phoenix in London at 
aphoenix@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Zimri Smith at  zsmith@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Katarzyna Klimasinska" category="EASTERN_EUROPE" date="Jan 31, 2007 11:26 AM ET" keywords="Orange SA, Tele2 AB, Corporate Actions, Dividends, Earnings, Eastern Europe, Emerging Markets, Euro Members, Europe, France, Industries, Internet, Nordic Region, Poland, Regions, Specialized Regions, Technology, Telecom Services, Wireless Communications" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-31/telekomunikacja-plans-to-cut-fixed-line-calls-prices-update1-.html"><headline>Telekomunikacja Plans to Cut Fixed-Line Calls Prices</headline><body>
Telekomunikacja Polska SA, Poland's
former phone monopoly, plans to cut prices for fixed-line calls
this year to compete better and keep its share of the market. 
``We assumed in this year's budget that because of the
increasing competition, our prices will fall,'' Chief Executive
Officer Maciej Witucki said in an interview from Paris today. ``We
already filed the proposed new pricelist to the regulator.'' 
Telekomunikacja, controlled by France Telecom SA (FTE), is still
adjusting to the loss of its monopoly and yesterday reported an
unexpected 21 percent decline in profit for the fourth quarter
after the company cut prices amid tougher competition. 
The regulator forced the company to rent its infrastructure
to companies such as Sweden's Tele2 AB (TEL2B) and local rival Netia SA,
which are starting a subscribed fixed-line service to gain some of
Telekomunikacja's more than 10 million customers. 
``This company is not a monopolist fighting for a survival,''
said Witucki, who took over as CEO in November. ``It's a future-oriented firm operating on a free market.'' 
The company, which still controls about 80 percent of the
fixed-line market in Poland, expects to keep customers by adding
more services, Witucki said. Last year it introduced a service
called ``triple play,'' providing telephone, TV, video on demand
and broadband services using one line for a single fee. 
Market Share 
The new products and price cuts may mean the company's loss
of fixed-line market share won't be significant this year, Witucki
said, declining to elaborate. 
Telekomunikacja expects sales to fall by 1 percent in 2007
after rising 1.5 percent to 18.6 billion zloty ($6 billion) last
year. The guidance doesn't include any ``new, sudden and
unexpected'' charges from the regulator, Witucki said. 
The company is interested in buying other mobile phone and
Internet operators in Poland or neighboring countries. 
``Telekomunikacja is based in a very interesting region and
we have certain ambitions referring to this region,'' he said. It
doesn't plan to sell online portal Wirtualna Polska SA, he added. 
The dividend policy of at least 1.40 zloty per share payout
is based on the assumption that the company may spend some capital
on acquisitions and new products, Witucki said. The dividend may
be higher if Telekomunikacja finds itself with cash, Witucki said. 
Witucki came to the company from Lukas Bank SA, a Polish unit
of France's Credit Agricole SA. Founded in 1998, Lukas was one of
the first Polish lenders to emphasize Internet and telephone
banking, and the supervisory board said Telekomunikacja needs to
follow the bank's example on customer service. 
Shares of Telekomunikacja have risen 10 percent during the
past 12 months, giving the company a market value of about $11.9
billion. Magyar Telekom Nyrt., Hungary's former phone monopoly,
has risen 2.3 percent over the same period. The company has a
market value of about $5.3 billion. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Katarzyna Klimasinska in Warsaw at 
kklimasinska@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Tony Barrett in London at 
tbarrett4@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Torrey Clark and Yuriy Humber" category="EXECUTIVE, EASTERN_EUROPE, EMERGING_MARKETS" date="Jan 31, 2007 11:05 AM ET" keywords="MMC Norilsk Nickel OJSC, Open Investments JSC, Banking, Commodities, Commonwealth of Ind States, Copper, Eastern Europe, Emerging Markets, Energy, Europe, Financial Services, Gold, Industries, Insurance, Machinery, Manufacturing, Markets, Media, Metals, Mining, Nickel, Non-Ferrous Metals, Palladium, Platinum, Precious Metals, Real Estate, Regions, Russia, Specialized Regions, Technology, ex-Energy" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-31/norilsk-billionaires-prokhorov-potanin-split-assets-update3-.html"><headline>Norilsk Billionaires Prokhorov, Potanin Split Assets</headline><body>
 Russia billionaires Vladimir Potanin and Mikhail Prokhorov agreed to split their assets,
raising investor expectations the world's largest nickel miner
will be sold to the state or a strategic investor. 
Prokhorov will resign his post as chief executive officer
of OAO GMKN Norilsk Nickel and sell his shares in the mining
company to Potanin, their holding company Interros said in an e-
mailed statement today. The business partners' 54.8 percent of
Norilsk is worth $17.2 billion, based on today's share price. 
Potanin, a government loyalist who has promised to invest
in President Vladimir Putin's bid to hold the 2014 winter
Olympics in Russia, had left the day-to-day running of Norilsk
to Prokhorov while focusing on new investments through Interros.
The two men bought Norilsk from the state in 1994. 
``One of the most politically aware oligarchs in the
country is now in charge of a strategic asset,'' said Roland Nash, chief strategist at Renaissance Capital in Moscow. This
``begs the question'' whether Potanin will sell Norilsk to a
state company. 
Shares of Norilsk rose $3, or 1.9 percent, to $165.5 as of
6:38 p.m. in Moscow today, giving the palladium and nickel
producer a market value of $31.5 billion. 
Tightening Grip 
Putin is tightening his grip on Russian industries deemed
key to national security by buying stakes from foreign companies
after threatening to revoke licenses. He forced the bankruptcy
of OAO Yukos Oil Co. and the eventual sale of most of its assets
to friendly hands. 
Nickel, used in steelmaking, rose to a record last week as
supplies monitored by global exchanges dropped to the equivalent
of two days use. 
``Potanin is much more likely to sell a stake,'' said James Fenkner, managing director of Red Star Asset Management in
Moscow, which has $100 million of assets. ``The question is
whether the state has enough desire to pay for a stake they sold
much cheaper years ago or it's a potential cross-border
transaction.'' 
The Interros statement gave no timeframe or reason for
Prokhorov's resignation, saying he would finish ``a series of
projects.'' 
Prokhorov and Potanin will also split other assets, such as
gold miner OAO Polyus, turbine maker OAO Siloviye Mashiny (SILM), media
holding Prof-Media, real estate developer Open Investments and
lender Rosbank, Interros said. Prokhorov will take full control
of the holding's energy and hydrogen assets. A new company will
be created to hold his stakes. 
Potanin, 46, and Prokhorov, 41, have discussed the split-up
for many months, Potanin said in the statement. Their Interros
holds disparate assets that could be managed more effectively
separately, he said. 
`Hunting Alone' 
``In general these guys hunt alone, they don't hunt in a
troop,'' said Eric Kraus, who manages $20 million at the Moscow-
based Nikitsky Russia Fund. ``Their business interests have been
diverging for some time.'' 
Kraus said he hasn't seen evidence of government interest
in Norilsk. 
Prokhorov will take control of Smart Hydrogen, a joint
venture between Interros and Norilsk Nickel, which also holds a
35 percent stake in Plug Power Inc. of the U.S, a developer of
electricity-producing fuel cells. In April, when the Russians
bought into Plug Power, they vowed to sink $285 million in cash
and securities to expand the developer's business. 
``Such investment demands significant intellectual and
financial commitments,'' Prokhorov said today. ``Hydrogen
technology will allow Russia to create an innovative economy.'' 
Prokhorov will acquire at least 14 percent in OAO OGK-3, a
wholesale power generation company based in west Siberia
currently held by Norilsk Nickel (GMKN) and Interros. The nickel miner
also owns Arctic power company Taimyrenergo and 24.8 percent of
electricity producer Kolenergo. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Torrey Clark in Moscow at 
tclark8@bloomberg.net;
Yuriy Humber in Moscow at 
yhumber@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Daniel Tilles at  dtilles@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Lyubov Pronina" category="EASTERN_EUROPE" date="Jan 31, 2007  4:22 AM ET" keywords="Cisco Systems Inc, Credit Suisse Group AG, Goldman Sachs Group Inc/The, HSBC Holdings PLC, Sistema JSFC, Africa, Asia, Asia ex. Japan, Australia, Banking, China, Commonwealth of Ind States, Computer Networking, Computers, Corporate Actions, Corporate Finance, Czech Republic, Earnings, Eastern Europe, Emerging Markets, Euro Members, Europe, FTSE 100 Index, Financial Services, Germany, Greece, Hong Kong, Industries, Initial Public Offerings, Internet, Korea, Markets, Middle East, Mideast, New Stocks, New York, Nordic Region, North America, Pacific Rim, Regions, Russia, Securities Firms, Shareholdings, Sweden, Switzerland, Taiwan, Technology, Telecom Equipment, Telecom Services, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, Ukraine, United Kingdom, United States, Wireless Communications" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-31/sitronics-sets-ipo-price-at-between-12-and-15-update1-.html"><headline>Sitronics Sets IPO Price at Between $12 and $15</headline><body>
OAO Sitronics, the technology unit
of Russian billionaire Vladimir Yevtushenkov's holding company
AFK Sistema (SSA), is selling stock for between $12 and $15 each in
the fifth initial public offering by a Sistema company. 
The range is for global depositary receipts and values
Sitronics at between $1.92 billion and $2.4 billion before
taking into account the proceeds received in connection with the
IPO, the Moscow-based company said in a regulatory filing,
without saying how many shares it plans to sell. Sitronics plans
to sell ordinary shares at between 24 and 30 cents. 
Sitronics is selling existing and new shares and will list
the proxy stock on the London Stock Exchange and the ordinary
shares on the RTS and Micex exchanges in Moscow. One depositary
receipt equals 50 ordinary shares, Sitronics said. 
``It is in line with the management previous estimates when
it said it plans to raise up to $550 million from the share
sale,'' said Konstantin Belov, an analyst with UralSib Financial
Corp. in Moscow. ``The key issue is whether investors will
believe the company. There are many uncertainties.'' 
Sitronics's niche micro-electronics products provide steady
orders from government agencies such as the defense ministry and
transportation companies. Even so, the company faces
international competition in consumer electronics. 
The company intends to use 50 percent of the proceeds from
the offering for acquisitions, including for the consolidation
of minority interests in its subsidiaries, Sitronics said. It
will also use 25 percent to pay off debt and the remaining 25
percent for general corporate purposes. 
Sitronics spokesman Sergei Filippov said that company will
announce the size of the stake it plans to sell in the first
half of February. 
Sistema last year said that it planned to sell about 20
percent of Sitronics in an IPO in February, and expected the
company to be valued at about $2.5 billion. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Lyubov Pronina in Moscow at 
lpronina@bloomberg.net; 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Lars Klemming at  lklemming@bloomberg.net; 
</body></entry><entry author="By Guillermo Parra-Bernal and Theresa Bradley" category="LATIN_AMERICA" date="Feb 01, 2007  5:58 PM ET" keywords="BP PLC, Chevron Corp, ConocoPhillips, Exxon Mobil Corp, Statoil ASA, Total SA, California, Chemicals, Commodities, Commodities Markets, Corporate Finance, Country Economies, Crude Oil, Emerging Markets, Energy, Energy Trading, Europe, FTSE 100 Index, Industries, Latin America, Latin American Economy, Liquefied Petroleum Gas, Markets, Natural Gas, Nordic Region, North America, Norway, Oil, Oil Markets, Oil Products, Oklahoma, Politics, Privatization, Refineries, Regions, South America, Specialized Regions, Texas, U.S. Midwest, U.S. Southwest, U.S. West, United Kingdom, United States, Venezuela, Venezuela Economy" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-02-01/chavez-expects-to-have-control-of-oil-ventures-by-may-update3-.html"><headline>Chavez Expects to Have Control of Oil Ventures By May</headline><body>
Venezuela intends to take control of
``no less than 60 percent'' of four heavy-crude-oil joint
ventures in the country's eastern Orinoco Belt by May 1,
President Hugo Chavez said. 
State-owned Petroleos de Venezuela SA, South America's
largest oil company, will add 4,000 of the employees currently
working for the ventures to its payroll, Chavez said today in a
televised press conference in Caracas. The four projects turn
tar-like oil into about 600,000 barrels of synthetic oil a day. 
``I have imparted clear instructions that as of May 1 all
those fields will wake up under our control,'' Chavez said at a
press conference at the presidential palace in Caracas. ``We want
to negotiate but the instruction is clear.'' 
Chavez also said a takeover of power companies as part of
his nationalization plans will take place ``pretty soon.'' Chavez
announced the timeframe of the seizures a day after lawmakers
granted him decree powers for 18 months to transform Venezuela
into a socialist economy. 
The projects may be seized if no agreement is reached before
the end of April, Oil and Energy Minister Rafael Ramirez said,
when asked by reporter about Chavez' earlier remarks. 
Venezuela, a founding member of the Organization of
Petroleum Exporting Countries, is the world's fifth-largest oil
exporter. The takeover of the four ventures may affect firms
including Chevron Corp. (CVX), Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM), ConocoPhillips (COP) and BP
Plc. (BP/), and has been attacked by U.S. President George W. Bush and
other heads of state. 
Exxon Comment 
Referring to the negotiations, Exxon Mobil spokesman Henry Hubble told investors that talks with the Venezuelan government
continue over the nationalization plan. The ``ball is in
Venezuela's court,'' Hubble said in a conference call. 
``To me, it sounds like provocation,'' Ramirez said,
referring to Hubble's comments. 
Chavez said that he plans to respect the stockholdings of
individual investors, and to protect mutual funds where
Venezuelan workers keep their savings. Chavez announced the
seizure of CA Electricidad de Caracas and CA Nacional Telefonos
de Venezuela, two of the five most-traded companies in the
Caracas Stock Exchange. The announcement wiped out $3 billion of
market value in Venezuela's stock market. 
Chavez, who last year raised royalties on foreign oil
companies and forced some into joint ventures with the state,
today sharpened calls to extend the state's involvement in the
economy to improve basic services, foster economic growth and cut
poverty. Bush yesterday said that Chavez's almost full control of
congress and courts means the nationalization would face little
resistance and threatens to whittle away democracy. 
``Here in Venezuela and in other countries where we are
trying to construct democracy, they dismiss us as dictators,''
Chavez said. ``Who is more of a fascist? Hitler or Bush? That's a
healthy competition.'' 
Venezuela may face millions of dollars in penalties related
to securities held by banks and bondholders as it seeks to win a
majority stake in the oil joint ventures. The rights of banks and
bondholders, which own around $6 billion in financing tied to the
projects, would be respected in the event of changes in
ownership, executives of the state oil company, known as PDVSA,
have said. 
To contact the reporters on this story:
Theresa Bradley in Caracas at 
tbradley7@bloomberg.net;
Guillermo Parra-Bernal in Caracas at 
gparra@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Robert Dieterich at 
rdieterich@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Mary Jane Credeur" category="US, RETAIL" date="Feb 01, 2007  4:39 PM ET" keywords="Coca-Cola Bottling Co Consolidated, Coca-Cola Co/The, Coca-Cola Enterprises Inc, Coca-Cola Femsa SAB de CV, Beverages, Consumer Goods, Containers, Corporate Actions, Corporate Finance, Emerging Markets, Georgia (U.S.), Industries, Latin America, Mergers &amp;amp; Acquisitions, Mexico, New Jersey, New York Times Play, North America, North Carolina, Packaging, Regions, Retail, Specialized Regions, U.S. Mid-Atlantic, U.S. South, U.S. Southeast, United States" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-02-01/coca-cola-agrees-to-buy-fuze-to-add-healthier-drinks-update4-.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Agrees to Buy Fuze to Add Healthier Drinks</headline><body>
Coca-Cola Co. (KO), the world's largest
soft-drink maker, agreed to buy Fuze Beverage LLC to add more
juice, tea and energy drinks in an effort to catch up with
PepsiCo Inc. 
Coca-Cola gains a half-dozen new products including Fuze
Tea, NOS energy drinks and Fuze Slenderize, which has chromium
and amino acids that Fuze says help promote weight loss. Atlanta-
based Coca-Cola didn't disclose terms of the purchase. 
Fuze beverages may help Coca-Cola win back customers who
switched from sugary sodas to drinks such as PepsiCo's SoBe tea.
It's Coca-Cola's biggest U.S. acquisition since buying Odwalla
Inc. in 2001 for $186 million to gain protein drinks and juices,
said John Sicher, editor of industry journal Beverage Digest. 
``This represents Coke aggressively getting itself into a
better place in the noncarbonated business in the U.S.,'' Sicher
said. ``Fuze is small but growing strongly.'' 
Sicher estimated that Coca-Cola paid $225 million to $250
million for closely held Fuze. He said the Englewood Cliffs, New
Jersey-based company sold about 11.5 million cases last year, up
from 8 million cases in 2005, generating $90 million to $100
million in revenue. 
Shares of Coca-Cola rose 22 cents to $48.10 at 4:22 p.m. in
New York Stock Exchange composite trading. They increased 20
percent last year, their biggest gain since 1997. 
Bottlers 
The Fuze purchase may help sate bottlers that had
complained about Coca-Cola falling behind PepsiCo in adding
drinks other than soda. Coca-Cola depends on soda for 80 percent
of its volume, compared with less than 20 percent for PepsiCo. 
Coca-Cola Enterprises Inc. (CCE), the largest distributor, agreed
to distribute Arizona bottled teas in the U.S. last year, making
good on a promise to get new drinks from someone other than Coca-
Cola if it needed to. The bottler is 36 percent owned by Coca-
Cola. 
``This should be well-received by Coke's bottlers,'' Bill Pecoriello, an analyst at Morgan Stanley, wrote today in a note. 
Fuze was already distributed by 20 Coca-Cola bottlers
including Coca-Cola Bottling Co. United of Birmingham, Alabama,
and the Philadelphia Coca-Cola Bottling Co. 
Only about 15 percent of Fuze's volume currently goes
through Coca-Cola bottlers, Pecoriello wrote. The Cadbury
Schweppes Bottling Group had distributed Fuze in much of the
U.S., Sicher said. 
Coca-Cola Bottling Co. Consolidated, the second-largest
bottler for Coca-Cola, sells Cinnabon bottled coffee and created
a separate unit called Beverages and Beyond Brands to create or
buy drinks it wasn't getting from the soda maker. 
Coca-Cola's soda volume in the U.S. dropped by a low single
digit in 2005, while noncarbonated volume jumped 10 percent. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Mary Jane Credeur in Atlanta at 
mcredeur@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Michael Nol at  mnol@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Lee Spears" category="CHINA" date="Feb 02, 2007  4:43 AM ET" keywords="Anhui Conch Cement Co Ltd, Holcim Ltd, Huaxin Cement Co Ltd, Lafarge SA, SOCAM Development Ltd, Asia, Asia Industrial Reporting, Asia ex. Japan, Australia, Building, Cement, China, Commodities, Construction &amp;amp; Engineering, Emerging Markets, Europe, Hong Kong, Indus. Materials, Industries, Korea, Markets, Pacific Rim, Switzerland, Taiwan" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-02-02/china-cement-output-rises-at-fastest-pace-in-11-years-update1-.html"><headline>China Cement Output Rises at Fastest Pace in 11 Years</headline><body>
China, the world's largest maker and
consumer of cement, produced 19 percent more of the building
material in 2006, spurred by spending on housing, ports and
factories. 
Kilns turned out a record 1.2 billion tons of cement,
Mainland Marketing Research Co., which releases monthly data on
behalf of the National Bureau of Statistics, said today in an e-
mailed statement from its head office in Beijing. The increase is
the biggest since 1995, according to Bloomberg data. 
Demand for cement is rising in the world's fastest-growing
major economy even after policymakers raised interest rates and
restricted lending to cool growth. China's government last month
announced plans to close small, inefficient producers and ease
approval of loans, mergers and acquisitions by 60 of the biggest
cement makers. 
Lafarge SA (LG) of France and Holcim Ltd. (HOLN) of Switzerland, the
world's two biggest makers of the material, are leading their
Chinese competitors in expanding production lines to meet rising
demand in a country that uses about half the world's cement. 
Sales of the adhesive powder in China may rise by an annual
average of 8.4 percent in the five years through 2010 to $36
billion, Cleveland, Ohio-based Freedonia Group said in an August
2006 report. 
Lafarge's joint venture in China, Lafarge Shui On Cement,
plans to more than double production in three years, Vincent Lo,
chairman of Hong Kong-based Shui On Construction and Materials
Ltd., said in a Jan. 25 interview. 
Holcim is in the midst of paying about $125 million to take
control of Huaxin Cement Co. (900933), China's second-biggest cement maker
by sales. 
Urban investment in fixed assets such as buildings and
infrastructure climbed 25 percent in 2006, slowing from 27
percent a year earlier, the government said on Jan. 25. 
Anhui Conch Cement Co. (914), the largest domestic producer, said
on Jan. 29 its 2006 profit more than doubled from 406.9 million
yuan ($52.5 million) a year earlier. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Lee Spears in Beijing at 
lspears2@bloomberg.net. 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Nicolas Johnson at  nicojohnson@bloomberg.net. 
</body></entry><entry author="By Helen Yuan" category="CHINA, COMMODITIES" date="Feb 02, 2007  1:12 AM ET" keywords="Maanshan Iron &amp;amp; Steel Co Ltd, Asia, Asia ex. Japan, Australia, China, Commodities, Emerging Markets, Ferro-alloys, Hong Kong, Industries, Iron Ore, Korea, Markets, Metals, Mining, Pacific Rim, Regions, Specialized Regions, Steel, Taiwan, ex-Energy" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-02-02/china-s-magang-to-build-mine-for-iron-ore-and-sulfur-update1-.html"><headline>China's Magang to Build Mine for Iron Ore and Sulfur</headline><body>
Magang (Group) Holdings Co., which
controls China's second-biggest Hong Kong-listed steelmaker,
received government approval to spend 1.1 billion yuan ($142
million) on an iron ore and sulfur mine. 
The Rohe mine will produce 3 million metric tons of minerals
a year, including 983,100 tons of ore with 66 percent iron
content, and 306,000 tons of minerals that contain 40 percent
sulfur, the National Development and Reform Commission said in a
statement on its Web site. Magang is based in Maanshan city of
China's eastern province of Anhui. 
Magang, the nation's seventh-biggest steelmaker by 2006
output, and other mills are speeding up iron ore exploration to
cut reliance on imports as Chinese demand has driven global
contract ore prices to records. Chinese ore typically contains 33
percent iron, about half the content found in Australia. 
Magang's existing iron ore mines will be shut down in three
to five years as reserves are depleted, the statement said. 
Shares of Magang's Hong Kong-trade unit, Maanshan Iron 
Steel Co. (323), rose 4.3 percent, the first gain in four days, to
HK$5.05 by the midday break. The stock has surged 82 percent in
the past year. 
The statement from the commission, China's top economic
planning body, did not say where the mine is located. 
To contact the reporter for this story:
Helen Yuan in Shanghai at 
hyuan@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Keith Gosman in Sydney at 
kgosman@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry><entry author="By Claudia Maedler and Zainab Fattah" category="MIDDLE_EAST" date="Feb 04, 2007  7:27 AM ET" keywords="Africa, Arabian Region, Earnings, Emerging Markets, Financial Services, Industries, Insurance, Middle East, Mideast, Oman, Persian Gulf, Qatar, Regions, Specialized Regions, Technology, Telecom Equipment, Telecom Services, Wireless Communications" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-02-04/qatar-telecom-full-year-profit-jumps-43-on-expansion-update1-.html"><headline>Qatar Telecom Full-Year Profit Jumps 43% on Expansion</headline><body>
Qatar Telecom QSC, the Persian Gulf
emirate's monopoly phone company, said full-year profit jumped
43 percent led by growth in its Omani mobile-phone unit. 
Net income rose to 1.7 billion Qatari riyals ($467
million) from 1.19 billion riyals a year earlier, the company
said in a statement to the Doha Securities Market today.
Revenue increased 48 percent to 4.42 billion riyals. The
company did not provide earnings per share or fourth-quarter
results. 
Qatar Telecom's combined mobile-phone customer base in
Qatar and Oman grew 55 percent in the past 12 month. Nawras
Telecom in Oman, which accounts for more than a third of all
its subscribers, generated revenue of 470 million riyals and
captured 31 percent of the Omani market, the operator said in
the statement. Qatar Telecom is the biggest shareholder of
Nawras, which started operations in March 2005 as the
sultanate's second mobile operator. 
Arab phone companies like Emirates Telecommunications
Corp. in the United Arab Emirates, are expanding abroad to
boost sales as domestic markets mature. Nine in 10 people
living in Qatar subscribed to mobile phone services by the end
of 2005, Bloomberg data shows. Qatar Telecom in January agreed
to buy 25 percent of a unit of Singapore Technologies Telemedia
Pte. as part of a plan to expand into Asia. 
The company's board of director proposed increasing this
year's dividend to 10 riyals, from 8.50 riyals last year. The
payout is subject to shareholder approval. 
Qatar Telecom, known as Q-Tel, is set to lose the domestic
communications monopoly it has had since 1998, under a law
signed by Qatar's ruler, Emir Sheikh Hamad al-Thani, the Doha-based Peninsula newspaper reported in November. 
Q-Tel's shares declined 5.1 percent last year, while
Doha's benchmark dropped 35 percent. Today the shares lost 1.6
percent closing at 246.9 riyals in Doha. 
To contact the reporter on this story:
Claudia Maedler in Dubai at 
cmaedler@bloomberg.net
Zainab Fattah in Dubai on 
zfattah@bloomberg.net 
To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Balduin Hesse at 
bhesse2@bloomberg.net 
</body></entry></news>