<?xml version='1.0' encoding='us-ascii'?>
<news>
    <entry author="By Joe Carroll" datetime="Apr 09, 2014  5:08 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-09/chevron-output-fall-as-it-seeks-to-reverse-declines.html">
        <headline>Chevron Output Fall as It Seeks to Reverse Declines</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX), seeking to reverse
            the longest string of production declined in a decade, said oil
            and natural gas output fell in the first two months of the year. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The second-largest U.S. energy producer by market value
            pumped the equivalent of 2.579 million barrels of oil a day
            during January and February, according to a statement on its
            website today. That compares with 2.645 million in the first
            quarter of 2013. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;When Chevron reports results for the entire three-month
            period on May 2, output is expected to come in at 2.61 million
            barrels, based on the average of three analysts' estimates
            compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron is accelerating oil exploration from Argentina to
            China to add reserves and revive output. Chairman and Chief
            Executive Officer John Watson is spending almost $40 billion
            this year to find, extract, transport and process oil and gas.
            Watson's strategy also calls for auctioning off $10 billion in
            oilfields and other assets to hone the San Ramon, California-based company's focus on the highest-profit
            projects. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron has fallen 4.7 percent this year to $119.10, after
            advancing 16 percent in 2013. In March, Watson cut the company's
            long-term production target by 6.1 percent to the equivalent of
            3.1 million barrels a day in 2017. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The company's output fell for a third consecutive year in
            2013, the longest streak of declines since the 2001-2004 period,
            according to data compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Exxon Mobil Corp. is the biggest U.S. energy company. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Lynn Doan" datetime="Apr 10, 2013  4:14 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="n" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-04-10/san-francisco-gasoline-falls-as-chevron-readies-unit-for-startup.html">
        <headline>San Francisco Gasoline Falls as Chevron Readies Unit for Startup</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Spot gasoline in San Francisco slid
            against futures as Chevron Corp. (CVX) prepared the crude unit at the
            Richmond refinery for startup after an eight-month shutdown. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The 240,000-barrel-a-day Richmond plant was cleared by
            state regulators April 5 to resume service at the No. 4 crude
            unit, shut since a fire Aug. 6. The refinery was performing a
            'pre-startup safety review' of the equipment last week, Nigel Hearne, the refinery's manager, said in an
            April 5 letter. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;California-blend gasoline, or Carbob, in San Francisco
            weakened 1 cent against futures traded on the New York
            Mercantile Exchange to a premium of 9.5 cents a gallon at 3:59
            p.m. New York time, data compiled by Bloomberg show. The fuel
            gained yesterday to the highest level against futures since Feb.
            6 after Royal Dutch Shell Plc (RDSA)'s Martinez refinery was said to
            shut units for maintenance. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Richmond refinery has been producing fuel at about half
            its capacity since the fire damaged a tower at the crude unit.
            Chevron, based in San Ramon, California, expects the unit to
            restart this quarter, Melissa Ritchie, a company spokeswoman in
            Richmond, said by e-mail today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Carbob in Los Angeles climbed 2 cents against futures to a
            premium of 7.5 cents a gallon. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The premium for Carbob in San Francisco versus the fuel in
            Los Angeles narrowed 3 cents to 2 cents a gallon, the smallest
            in a week. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Diesel Prices &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;California-blend diesel in San Francisco was unchanged
            against ultra-low-sulfur diesel futures on the Nymex at a
            premium of 7 cents a gallon. Diesel in Los Angeles held at 5
            cents a gallon above futures. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In Portland, Oregon, low-sulfur diesel dropped 3 cents to
            an 11-cent-a-gallon premium versus ULSD futures. Gasoline there
            gained 1.5 cents against gasoline futures to a premium of 5
            cents a gallon, the highest level since Feb. 27. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The 3-2-1 crack spread of Alaska North Slope crude, Carbob
            in Los Angeles and CARB diesel in Los Angeles dropped for the
            first time in three days, narrowing by $2.23 to $16.40 a barrel
            at 4:07 p.m. New York time. The spread, a rough indicator of
            refinery profit margins, hit a one-year low of $3.86 a barrel in
            December. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Pablo Gonzalez" datetime="Apr 10, 2014 12:04 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-10/chevron-to-invest-1-6-billion-with-ypf-in-argentina-shale-wells.html">
        <headline>Chevron to Invest $1.6 Billion With YPF in Argentina Shale Wells</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX), the world's third-largest oil company, signed an accord with Argentina's YPF
            SA to
            invest $1.6 billion this year in shale development and become
            the country's largest foreign producer of shale oil and natural
            gas. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron and state-run YPF plan to drill 170 wells in a
            96,000-acre area this year in Argentina's Vaca Muerta formation,
            the world's second-largest shale gas deposit and fourth-largest
            shale oil reservoir, both companies said today in separate
            statements. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Argentine President Cristina Fernandez de Kirchner's
            government expropriated a 51 percent stake in YPF from Spain's
            Repsol SA (REP) in April 2012 after saying the Spanish oil company
            hadn't invested enough in exploration. Repsol's board agreed in
            February to accept $5 billion in compensation for Argentina's
            expropriation of the unit. Ending the two-year international
            dispute may help attract investors to the country. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'This is a significant step in our subsidiaries' joint
            efforts with YPF to develop one of the most exciting shale plays
            in the world today,' Chevron Vice Chairman George Kirkland said
            in the company's statement. 'Vaca Muerta could become an
            important contributor to Chevron's long-term production
            growth.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Pilot Investment &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The latest investment follows an initial $1.24 billion
            pilot investment financed by Chevron and paves the way for a
            total plan of $15 billion. The joint venture partners are
            targeting daily output of 50,000 barrels of shale oil and 3
            million cubic meters of shale gas by drilling 1,500 wells. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Vaca Muerta, Spanish for dead cow, may hold 23 billion
            barrels of oil equivalent, according to a report by independent
            auditor Ryder Scott released in February 2012 by YPF. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;YPF's American depositary receipts were little changed at
            $30.65 at 11:52 a.m. in New York Chevron fell 1.2 percent to
            $117.64. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron late yesterday said it is on track to post its
            lowest first quarter production in eight years after bad weather
            disrupted operations in Central Asia and North America. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron is the third most valuable oil producer after Exxon
            Mobil Corp., and Royal Dutch Shell Plc. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Ben Elgin and Peter Waldman" datetime="Apr 18, 2013 12:01 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="n"
           progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-04-18/chevron-defies-california-on-carbon-emissions.html">
        <headline>Chevron Defies California On Carbon Emissions</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX) helped write the
            first-in-the-nation rule ordering reduced carbon emissions from
            cars and trucks. Its biofuels chief spoke at the ceremony where
            California Governor Arnold Schwarzenegger signed the executive
            order in 2007, the same year the oil company pledged to develop
            a gasoline replacement from wood. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Now Chevron is leading a lobbying and public relations
            campaign to undercut the California mandate aimed at curbing
            global warming, two years after the state started phasing it in.
            Research on commercially viable climate-friendly products has
            come to naught, stymied by the poor economics of coaxing
            hydrocarbons from plants' stubborn cell walls, according to
            Chevron officials. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'We've looked at 100 feedstocks, 50 conversion
            technologies, worked to shape this law the best we can, and we
            have not come up with a solution to be able to comply,' said
            Rhonda Zygocki, Chevron's executive vice president of policy and
            planning, in a Feb. 4 talk at the Commonwealth Club in San
            Francisco. Rick Zalesky, the Chevron official who celebrated the
            order's signing with Schwarzenegger, was blunt last June when he
            declared the low-carbon standard 'not achievable.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;While still promoting its commitment to renewable energy,
            the second largest U.S. oil company quietly shelved most of its
            biofuels work in 2010, according to internal documents and
            former Chevron officials. It decided products with potential
            returns of at least 5 percent weren't enough for a multinational
            used to margins triple that, said Paul Bryan, a former vice
            president of biofuels technology. &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: David Paul Morris/Bloomberg

            &lt;p&gt;
            An employee works on a Chevron Corp. sign at a gasoline station in San Francisco, California. Like other
            major investor-owned oil companies, Chevron and ExxonMobil accept climate-change science and acknowledge
            carbon emissions contribute to global warming. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Joe Carroll" datetime="Apr 26, 2013 11:16 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-04-26/chevron-net-income-falls-as-prices-decline-on-weakening-demand.html">
        <headline>Chevron Beats Profit Estimates as Gas Rally Mutes Oil Slump</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX), the world's third-
            biggest energy company by market value, reported first-quarter
            profit that exceeded analysts' estimates after boosting natural
            gas output amid rising prices for the fuel. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Net income declined 4.5 percent to $6.18 billion, or $3.18
            a share, from $6.47 billion, or $3.27, a year earlier, the San
            Ramon, California-based company said in a statement today. The
            per-share result was 8 cents higher than the average of 19
            estimates compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron's earnings from oil and gas wells outside the U.S.
            rose 3.1 percent to $4.78 billion as increased gas output more
            than offset lower crude production. In the U.S., the company
            raised gas output from new wells in Appalachia's Marcellus Shale
            formation where most of the drilling costs are being borne by
            India's Reliance Industries Ltd. (RIL) under the terms of a joint-
            venture. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron 'is almost drilling for free out there, so when
            you combine that with the prolific nature of the Marcellus, the
            returns are high,' Allen Good, an analyst at Morningstar Inc. (MORN)
            in Chicago, said in a telephone interview today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Total sales declined by 6.4 percent to $56.8 billion on
            slumping oil prices. During the January-to-March period, Brent
            crude futures fell 4.9 percent from a year earlier to average
            $112.61 a barrel, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron rose 1.3 percent to $120 at 11:13 a.m. in New York. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Increasing Production &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron is spending $36.7 billion this year on exploration,
            gas-export terminals and refinery upgrades from the Indian Ocean
            to British Columbia after oil and gas output fell to a four-year
            low in 2012. Chairman and Chief Executive Officer John S. Watson
            has expanded the company's onshore North American holdings and
            last month said it will use intensive drilling techniques
            perfected in U.S. shale formations to unlock crude reserves in
            the deep-water Gulf of Mexico. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The company's worldwide production increased 0.5 percent to
            the equivalent of 2.65 million barrels of oil a day during the
            first quarter, according to the statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;During the quarter, Chevron raised U.S. gas output by 7.3
            percent as prices that touched a 10-year low in early 2012
            surged 39 percent to an average of $3.48 per million British
            thermal units during the quarter. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron entered the Marcellus Shale in 2011 with the
            acquisition of Atlas Energy Inc. The transaction included a
            previously-signed joint venture between Atlas and Reliance that
            committed the Indian company to cover most of the drilling costs
            in exchange for a stake in each well. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Outperforming Exxon &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron expects oil and gas production to increase 1.5
            percent this year to a daily average equivalent to 2.65 million
            barrels a day, the company said in a slide presentation for
            analysts on March 13. The outlook assumes an average crude price
            of $112 a barrel for 2013. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron shares advanced 9.9 percent during the first
            quarter, outperforming bigger rival Exxon Mobil Corp (XOM), which
            increased 4.1 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron reaps 70 percent of its operating earnings from oil
            and gas sales outside the U.S., Paul Cheng, an analyst at
            Barclays Plc, said in an April 8 note to clients. Among U.S.-
            based international oil producers, only Marathon Oil Corp. (MRO) and
            Exxon gather a higher proportion of earnings overseas, according
            to Cheng. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Exxon is the world's largest energy company based on market
            value, followed by PetroChina Co. (857), according to data compiled by
            Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Lynn Doan" datetime="Apr 29, 2013  5:52 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-04-29/san-francisco-gasoline-hits-two-week-low-as-chevron-unit-starts.html">
        <headline>San Francisco Gasoline Hits Two-Week Low as Chevron Unit Starts</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Spot gasoline in San Francisco
            tumbled to the lowest level in more than two weeks as Chevron
            Corp. (CVX) started the crude unit at the Richmond refinery, the
            largest in Northern California. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The 240,000-barrel-a-day Richmond plant was feeding oil
            into its only crude unit, shut after a fire Aug. 6, last week
            and expected to increase production from other equipment in
            'the coming days,' Jeff Gustavson, Chevron's general manager
            of investor relations, said in an quarterly earnings conference
            call April 26. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;California-blend gasoline, or Carbob, in San Francisco
            dropped 13 cents to a premium of 9.5 cents a gallon against
            futures traded on the New York Mercantile Exchange at 4:16 p.m.
            New York time, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. That's
            the lowest level for the fuel in the Bay since April 10. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Royal Dutch Shell Plc (RDSA)'s 165,000-barrel-a-day Martinez
            refinery near San Francisco was also starting units after
            finishing a maintenance turnaround, an April 25 notice filed
            with Contra Costa County regulators showed. The plant shut units
            in the light-oil processing section earlier this month for
            planned repairs, a person familiar with the work said April 8. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Carbob in Los Angeles dropped 5.5 cents to a premium of 5
            cents a gallon over Nymex futures, a three-week low. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;El Segundo &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The 279,000-barrel-a-day El Segundo refinery, the largest
            in California, has resumed normal rates after a maintenance
            turnaround, Pat Yarrington, Chevron's chief financial officer,
            said in the earnings call April 26. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;San Francisco's premium to Los Angeles narrowed 7.5 cents
            to 4.5 cents a gallon, the smallest spread in three days. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;California-blend, or CARB, diesel in Los Angeles weakened
            1.5 cents to a discount of 2.75 cents a gallon against ultra-
            low-sulfur diesel futures on the Nymex, the lowest level since
            Dec. 14. CARB diesel in San Francisco dropped 1.75 cents to 5.75
            cents a gallon below futures, a three-month low. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Conventional gasoline in Portland, Oregon, jumped 4 cents
            to 15 cents a gallon over Nymex futures, a two-month high. Low-
            sulfur diesel there gained 1.75 cents against ULSD futures to a
            premium of 2.5 cents a gallon. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The 3-2-1 crack spread of Alaska North Slope crude, Carbob
            in Los Angeles and CARB diesel in Los Angeles narrowed a second
            day, shrinking $3.39 to $13.80 a barrel at 4:17 p.m. New York
            time. The spread, a rough indicator of refinery margins, is down
            53 percent from this year's high of $29.09 a barrel on Feb. 5. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Joe Carroll and Zain Shauk" datetime="Aug 01, 2014  4:19 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s"
           progress_sentiment="d"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-01/chevron-profit-rises-on-asset-sales-and-higher-brent-oil.html">
        <headline>Chevron Falls as Output Drops Despite Rising Spending</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX) fell after posting the
            lowest second-quarter oil and natural gas output in six years as
            spending on new projects surged. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron declined 1 percent to $127.90 at the close in New
            York. The production drop overshadowed the biggest quarterly
            profit increase in more than a year for the San Ramon,
            California-based company. Net income rose to $5.67 billion, or
            $2.98 a share, from $5.37 billion, or $2.77, a year earlier,
            Chevron said in a statement today. Per-share profit exceeded the
            average of 13 analysts' estimates compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Investors punished the world's third-largest energy company
            by market value after it reported output decreased 1.4 percent
            to the equivalent of 2.545 million barrels of oil a day during
            the April-to-June period, the weakest performance since 2008.
            Capital spending on new floating production platforms, wells,
            gas-export plants and other projects jumped 7.8 percent to $10.2
            billion for the quarter. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron had been expected to report output of 2.595 million
            barrels a day, based on the average of six analysts' estimates
            compiled by Bloomberg. The company cited repair work at its
            sprawling Tengizchevroil production facility in Kazakhstan as
            well as contracts that reduce its share of output from some
            wells when crude prices rise. &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: David Paul Morris/Bloomberg

            &lt;p&gt;
            A Chevron Corp. fueling station stands in Richmond, California. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Joe Carroll" datetime="Aug 01, 2014 12:07 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="n" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-01/chevron-shrugs-as-apache-quits-kitimat-lng-in-canada.html">
        <headline>Chevron Shrugs as Apache Quits Kitimat LNG in Canada</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX) said it will seek out a
            new partner for a proposed natural gas export terminal on
            Canada's Pacific Coast after Apache Corp. (APA) indicated it will
            depart from the project. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron is 'unconcerned' about Apache's announcement
            yesterday that it will divest its stake in the Kitimat liquefied
            natural gas project in British Columbia, Chevron Vice Chairman
            George Kirkland said during a conference call with analysts
            today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron has already began drilling appraisal wells in the
            gas fields that will supply the proposed Kitimat complex,
            Kirkland said. The company still is studying how much the
            project will cost and how long it will take to construct, key
            factors in a final investment decision, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Apache also said yesterday that it will sell its interest
            in the Chevron-led Wheatstone LNG venture in Australia. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron, the world's third-largest energy producer, whose
            LNG plans include a $10 billion complex in Angola and the $54
            billion Gorgon project in Australia, is betting demand for the
            fuel will begin to outpace supplies around the end of this
            decade. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Joe Carroll" datetime="Aug 02, 2013 10:25 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="d"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-02/chevron-profit-declines-as-crude-prices-fall-with-output.html">
        <headline>Chevron Profit Declines as Crude Prices Fall With Output</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX), the world's second-largest energy company by market value, posted its biggest
            second-quarter profit decline in four years and missed analysts'
            estimates as crude oil prices and production fell. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Net income dropped by 26 percent to $5.37 billion, or $2.77
            a share, from $7.21 billion, or $3.66, a year earlier, San
            Ramon, California-based Chevron said in a statement today. The
            per-share result was 19 cents below the average of 21 estimates,
            excluding one-time gains and losses, compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron's oil and natural gas output fell 1.6 percent to
            the lowest second-quarter average in half a decade as new wells
            in Angola, the Gulf of Mexico and Pennsylvania failed to make up
            for declining production from older fields, according to the
            statement. The price the company fetched for crude sold overseas
            dropped 5 percent, while profit from refining crude into fuels
            tumbled 59 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Chevron is looking at a natural decline in its resource
            base of 6 to 10 percent a year before they even do anything, so
            it's kind of like running up a down escalator,' Edmund Cowart,
            who helps manage $22 billion, including Chevron shares, at Eagle
            Asset Management Inc. in St. Petersburg, Florida, said in a
            telephone interview today. 'Refining's been tough for
            everybody.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Sales dropped by 8.4 percent to $57.4 billion. Chevron fell
            2.4 percent to $123.40 at 9:54 a.m. in New York. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Shrinking Margins &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron received an average of $94 a barrel for non-U.S.
            crude during the quarter, compared with $99 a year earlier,
            according to the statement. The company's so-called upstream
            earnings fell 12 percent during the April-to-June period as
            worldwide demand for petroleum-based fuels failed to keep pace
            with production growth. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron's refineries posted a $766 million profit compared
            with $1.88 billion a year earlier as prices for transportation
            fuels fell faster than crude, and the lingering effects of a
            California refinery fire hindered production. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Refining margins in the U.S., the world's largest motor-fuels market, narrowed as lower gasoline
            use reduced retail
            prices by 3.6 percent to a quarterly average of $3.601 a gallon,
            based on Energy Department figures. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Chairman and Chief Executive Officer John S. Watson
            pledged in March to raise oil and gas output by one-fifth to the
            equivalent of 3.3 million barrels a day by the end of 2017
            through mega-projects such as the $47 billion Gorgon gas-export
            development in Australia. Last month, Watson signed a $1.24
            billion agreement with Argentina's state-controlled YPF SA to
            explore a shale formation in the Latin American nation for oil
            and gas. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Global Production &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron estimated in March that its global output this year
            will rise 1.5 percent to an average of 2.65 million barrels a
            day, assuming crude prices around $112 a barrel. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron has been the best-performer among the largest
            international oil producers this year with a 17 percent increase
            in its share price through yesterday. Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM), the
            biggest oil company, has risen 7.1 percent, followed by Royal
            Dutch Shell Plc (RDSA)'s 0.5 percent gain, Total SA's 3.8 percent rise
            and BP Plc (BP/)'s 7.9 percent increase. PetroChina Co. Ltd. has
            fallen 17 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Brent crude averaged $103.35 a barrel during the quarter,
            compared with $108.76 a year earlier, according to data compiled
            by Bloomberg. Prices fell as worldwide oil production rose 0.6
            percent at a time when demand increased by 0.1 percent.
            Consumption increases in expanding economies such as China and
            India were more than offset by demand declines in the U.S.,
            western Europe and Japan, according to figures published by the
            International Energy Agency in Paris. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Gas Prices &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;U.S. natural gas prices climbed 71 percent to an average of
            $4.018 per million British thermal units during the April-to-June period from a year earlier, according to
            data compiled by
            Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron has been raising gas production in the Marcellus
            Shale formation in the eastern U.S. since its 2011 acquisition
            of Atlas Energy Inc. The transaction included a previously
            signed joint venture between Atlas and Reliance Industries Ltd. (RIL)
            that committed the Indian company to cover most of the drilling
            costs in exchange for a stake in each well. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Ben Elgin" datetime="Aug 13, 2014  1:30 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-13/chevron-puts-hawaiian-solar-projects-on-ice.html">
        <headline>Chevron Puts Hawaiian Solar Projects on Ice</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt; Aug. 13 (Bloomberg Businessweek) -- Chevron has taken
            another step away from its renewable-energy efforts, putting a
            pair of solar projects at its Kapolei refinery in West Oahu,
            Hawaii, on 'indefinite hold.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The tabled projects, first reported earlier this week by
            Pacific Business News, include a farm of solar panels that would
            have spanned almost five acres, supplying as much as 1 megawatt
            of electricity to the local utility. Chevron also shelved a
            demonstration solar thermal project, which would have covered
            about 15 acres and used mirrors to generate steam to help power
            the Hawaii refinery. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In recent months, Chevron, the second-biggest oil company in
            the U.S., has quietly been pulling back from renewable-energy
            endeavors, despite a long-promoted commitment to develop what its
            corporate website calls 'newer, cleaner ways to power the world.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In May, Bloomberg Businessweek reported that Chevron
            shuttered a business unit that had surpassed internal profit
            targets by helping to launch large-scale solar and geothermal
            power projects. In June, we wrote about the sale of its key
            renewable-energy subsidiary, Chevron Energy Solutions, to Oaktree
            Capital Management. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Each of the Hawaii projects would have reduced carbon
            dioxide emissions by about 5,000 tons and contributed to Hawaii's
            goal of generating 70 percent of its energy from renewable
            sources by 2030, according to Chevron's filings with the state. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Instead, they're being put on hold as the oil company
            focuses its resources on other projects, such as its $54 billion
            liquefied natural gas plant in Australia, a company spokesman
            told Pacific Business News . &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Reached by e-mail, Chevron spokesman Kent Robertson
            confirmed that the company has put its Hawaiian solar plants on
            hold. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron's pullback on renewables has come amid increasing
            concern that climate change and carbon constraints threaten
            fossil-fuel companies. Many organizations, including the
            International Energy Agency, estimate that as much as two-thirds
            of fossil-fuel reserves will need to remain unburned if the world
            is to avoid the most severe consequences of climate change.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Joe Carroll" datetime="Dec 11, 2013  5:19 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="n" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-11/chevron-2014-spending-to-fall-even-as-gorgon-lng-costs-increase.html">
        <headline>Chevron 2014 Spending to Fall Even as Gorgon LNG Costs Increase</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX) plans to spend $39.8
            billion on capital projects next year amid rising labor costs,
            increased drilling expenditures and currency fluctuations from
            Canada to Iraq. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The budget for floating platforms, oil-refinery repairs,
            pipelines and rig rentals is 5.2 percent less than Chevron's
            2013 estimated outlay of $42 billion, the San Ramon, California-based company said in a statement today. The
            cost estimate for
            the Gorgon natural gas export complex in Australia rose to $54
            billion, the second increase in 13 months. Weather and
            logistical delays will postpone startup of the project off the
            northwest coast by about three months. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chairman and Chief Executive Officer John S. Watson is
            counting on deep-water oil discoveries in the Gulf of Mexico and
            gas exports from the Indian and Pacific oceans to boost output
            20 percent by the end of 2017. Chevron aspires to become the
            world's third-largest producer of liquefied natural gas, or LNG,
            after Qatar and Royal Dutch Shell Plc, by the end of the decade. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron's full-year 2013 capital spending exceeded the
            original $36.7 billion forecast because of acquisitions that
            required additional spending, the company said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron may sell some oil and gas fields that promise
            leaner returns than the new prospects, Chief Financial Officer
            Pat Yarrington told analysts and investors during a Nov. 1
            conference call. Yarrington didn't specify what the company
            might be considering exiting, nor did she provide a time frame. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron said Nov. 22 its 240 million-barrel Rosebank field
            off the Scottish coast currently doesn't make economic sense to
            develop. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) is the largest energy company by market
            value, followed by PetroChina Co. (857), according to data compiled by
            Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Katia Dmitrieva and Liezel Hill" datetime="Dec 17, 2013  4:17 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s"
           progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-17/canadian-court-says-ecuadoreans-can-pursue-chevron-assets.html">
        <headline>Canadian Court Says Ecuadoreans Can Pursue Chevron Assets</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;A lawsuit by a group of Ecuadoreans
            to seize Chevron Corp.'s Canadian assets can proceed in the
            country, a Canadian court ruled today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Court of Appeal for Ontario ruled today that the 47
            villagers have the right to pursue Chevron's Canada assets. It
            reverses a ruling made on May 1 that stated the company did not
            have any assets in Canada. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A court in the Latin American country in 2011 found the
            company liable for about three decades of soil and water
            pollution near oil wells that ruined the health and livelihoods
            of Amazon rain forest dwellers. Since then, Ecuadorean farmers
            and fishermen have been trying to collect $19 billion in
            environmental damages from San Ramon, California-based Chevron,
            the world's third-largest oil company. The award was reduced to
            $9.5 billion from $19 billion on Nov. 12 by the Ecuadorean
            National Court of Justice, the nation's highest tribunal. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Even before the Ecuadorean judgment was released,
            Chevron, speaking through a spokesman, stated that Chevron
            intended to contest the judgment if Chevron lost,' judges James
            MacPherson, Eileen Gillese and C. William Hourigan said in the
            ruling. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The judges noted in the ruling that a Chevron spokesman had
            said: 'We're going to fight this until hell freezes over. And
            then we'll fight it out on the ice.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron's wish is granted, the judges said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'After all these years, the Ecuadorean plaintiffs deserve
            to have recognition and enforcement of the Ecuadorean judgment
            heard on the merits in an appropriate jurisdiction. At this
            juncture, Ontario is that jurisdiction,' the ruling states. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Possible Appeal &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'The decision affords the plaintiffs no substantive relief
            and merely allows the action to go forward,' Morgan Crinklaw, a
            spokesman for the company, said in an e-mailed statement.
            'Chevron Corp. is evaluating next steps, including a possible
            appeal of today's decision to the Supreme Court of Canada.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Ecuadoreans should have an opportunity to attempt to
            enforce the judgment in a court where Chevron will have to
            respond to the merits, the judges said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron's presence in Canada dates back to the 1930s and
            includes an oil-refining complex in British Columbia, an Alberta
            oil-sands venture and offshore wells in the Atlantic Ocean. The
            Ecuadoreans estimate that Chevron has $15 billion in Canadian
            assets, according to a statement today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'This decision affirms that the court in Canada has
            jurisdiction and it forces Chevron to participate in a trial
            process to enforce the Ecuadorean judgment,' Steven Donziger, a
            legal adviser to the Ecuadorean communities, said by phone
            today. 'The entirety of that judgment could be paid, every
            penny, if an enforcement action in Canada is successful.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron and Chevron Canada were each ordered to pay
            plaintiffs costs of C$50,000 ($47,000), the ruling said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The case is Yaiguaje v. Chevron Corp. (CVX), C57019, Court of
            Appeal for Ontario (Toronto) &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Joe Carroll" datetime="Feb 01, 2013  4:36 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-02-01/chevron-fourth-quarter-profit-increases-on-stronger-refining.html">
        <headline>Chevron Fourth-Quarter Profit Hits Record as Refining Surges</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX), the second-largest
            U.S. energy company, said fourth-quarter profit increased 41
            percent to a record $7.25 billion as it reported stronger
            refining results and a gain from an Australian natural gas field
            swap. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Net income rose to $3.70 a share from $2.58, or $5.12
            billion, a year earlier, the San Ramon, California-based company
            said in a statement today. Chevron was expected to report per-
            share profit of $3.06, based on the average of 19 analysts'
            estimate compiled by Bloomberg. Sales fell 3 percent to $56.3
            billion. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron's refining segment returned to profit from a loss a
            year earlier as rising supplies from U.S. shale formations
            lowered crude input costs and processing margins climbed 46
            percent. Chevron also benefited as crude prices rose in
            international energy markets. About 75 percent of the company's
            crude is pumped from non-U.S. wells. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Chairman and Chief Executive Officer John S. Watson
            plans to spend $36.7 billion this year to explore for oil, build
            gas export terminals and upgrade oil refineries. The company
            expects to reach output equivalent to 3.3 million barrels a day
            in 2017. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Strong cash flows allowed us to invest aggressively in
            our major capital projects and to acquire several important, new
            resource opportunities,' Watson said. 'We also raised the
            dividend on our common shares for the 25th consecutive year and
            continued our share repurchase program.' &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: David Paul Morris/Bloomberg

            &lt;p&gt;
            The Chevron Corp. logo stands at the entrance to the company's corporate headquarters in Richmond,
            California. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Elisha Bala-Gbogbo" datetime="Feb 01, 2013  6:23 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="s"
           progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-02-01/nigeria-fines-on-shell-chevron-not-backed-by-law.html">
        <headline>Nigeria Spill Fines on Shell, Chevron, Not Backed by Law</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Fines amounting to $8 billion sought
            by Nigeria from Royal Dutch Shell Plc (RDSA) and Chevron Corp. (CVX) for oil
            spills are not backed by law, said Bukola Saraki, chairman of
            the country's Senate Committee on Environment. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Under the existing law, there is no penalty for oil
            spills apart from just to clean it up,' Saraki, a senator
            representing the ruling People's Democratic Party from central
            Kwara state, said in an interview in Abuja on Jan. 29. 'You
            only pay 1 million naira ($6,362) for late reporting.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Without the backing of law it is difficult for the National
            Oil Spill Detection and Response Agency, or Nosdra, to enforce
            fines levied on oil companies, he said. Lawmakers have moved to
            amend the law and stipulate tougher penalties, according to
            Saraki. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Shell, Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM), Chevron, Total SA (FP) and Eni SpA (ENI) run
            joint ventures with state-owned Nigerian National Petroleum
            Corp. that pump more than 90 percent of the output of Africa's
            top oil producer. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Nosdra recommended to the government in July that Shell
            should pay $5 billion for a December 2011 rupture from its
            offshore Bonga field that spilled about 40,000 barrels of oil,
            the country's worst in more than a decade. The agency is also
            seeking $3 billion from Chevron for a rig explosion that caused
            a 46-day blaze in January last year on Nigeria's Atlantic coast.
            It has been unable enforce the penalties because 'there's no
            law,' Saraki said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Additional Penalties &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The government is studying existing laws as they relate to
            oil spills and will make pronouncements in due course,
            Environment Minister Hadiza Mailafia said yesterday in Abuja
            without giving further details. Precious Okolobo, Shell
            spokesman in Nigeria, declined to comment when contacted on his
            mobile phone. Chevron obeys the laws of the countries in which
            it operates and won't 'comment on political matters,' Jim
            Craig, a San Ramon, California-based spokesman, said in an e-
            mailed response. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A new National Oil Pollution Management Agency Bill
            proposes fines of 250,000 naira for every barrel of oil spilled
            and will compel producers to pay compensation to affected
            communities, Saraki said. The bill proposes additional penalties
            of 15 billion naira for every onshore spill incident and 5
            billion naira if it happens offshore, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;While improving the law will 'definitely strengthen'
            Nosdra's capacity to monitor energy producers, tough measures
            are unlikely to be enforced against companies engaged in
            partnerships with the government, Nnimmo Bassey, executive
            director of Environmental Rights Action, an affiliate of Friends
            of the Earth campaigning against oil pollution in Nigeria, said
            by phone today from Benin City. 'I think that's the political
            issue we still have to confront, no matter how good the law will
            be.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Nigeria, Africa's most populous country with more than 160
            million people, relies on oil for 95 percent of export earnings
            and 80 percent of government revenue, according to the Petroleum
            Ministry. With pipeline networks spread over the 70,000 square-
            kilometre (43,500 square-mile) Niger River delta region and
            largely unguarded, oil companies blame sabotage for most of the
            spills. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A Dutch District Court in The Hague ruled on Jan. 30 that
            Shell must pay compensation in one of five claims by Nigerian
            villagers from the Niger delta for a spill from its facility
            that affected their livelihood. Judge Henk Wien said Shell
            wasn't liable for four other claims. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Bonny Light crude, Nigeria's leading export grade, rose
            less than 1 percent to $117.41 as of 10.06 a.m. in London. The
            naira declined 0.1 percent to 157.20 a dollar as of 11.08 a.m.
            in Lagos, the commercial capital, according to data compiled by
            Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Bryan Bradley" datetime="Feb 04, 2013  7:10 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-02-04/chevron-gets-lithuanian-president-s-backing-for-shale-gas.html">
        <headline>Chevron Gets Lithuanian President's Backing for Shale Gas</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX), the second-largest
            U.S. energy company, won support from Lithuanian President Dalia Grybauskaite for shale-gas exploration
            plans that some of the
            country's residents and lawmakers oppose. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Lithuania needs to find out to how far its shale-gas
            reserves can go as an alternative to Russian natural gas,
            spokeswoman Daiva Ulbinaite quoted the president as saying today
            after a meeting with Jay Johnson, Chevron's head of Eurasia,
            Europe and Middle East exploration and production, in the
            capital, Vilnius. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;East European countries, including Poland and Ukraine, are
            turning to shale gas in their efforts to lower energy costs and
            their dependence on Russian supplies. Chevron in October bought
            50 percent of a Lithuanian oil and gas recovery company and in
            January submitted the only bid in a tender for shale-gas
            exploration rights in the Baltic nation. Some landowners and
            lawmakers have urged the government to halt the tender on
            concern that the exploration process could contaminate ground
            water. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'We expect to be able to engage with the local
            communities' and assuage their concerns, Chevron's Johnson told
            reporters at the president's office. 'We're very pleased with
            the chance to help create Lithuania's energy future.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Reserve Potential &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Lithuania, which wants to reduce it's total dependence on
            Russia's Gazprom OAO (GAZP) for natural gas supplies, probably has
            about 180 billion cubic meters of recoverable shale gas, KPMG
            said in a report in May. That's the equivalent of 60 years of
            gas consumption in the country, at current usage. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Shale-gas reserves in Lithuania, at an estimated depth of 2
            kilometers (1.2 miles), are twice as close to the surface as in
            neighboring Poland, so should be easier and cheaper to extract,
            KPMG said, citing geological studies. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron will assist LL Investicijos UAB, the Lithuanian
            company it half owns, with well design and seismic exploration. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Our first step is the assessment of what the resource
            potential is,' Johnson said. 'At that point we report to the
            government and we work with the government to determine any
            future progress.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron recently opened an office in Lithuania, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tina Davis" datetime="Feb 11, 2014 12:34 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-11/chevron-says-one-missing-after-well-fire-in-pennsylvania.html">
        <headline>Chevron Says One Missing After Well Fire in Pennsylvania</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX) said one person was
            hospitalized and another is missing after a fire at a well in
            Greene County, Pennsylvania. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The fire was reported at about 6:45 a.m. local time at the
            Lanco Unit 7H well, the Houston-based company said in a
            statement on its website today. Emergency personnel responded
            and are containing the fire, the company said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Drilling began on the horizontal well south of Pittsburgh
            on March 15, 2012, according to state data records. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron owned the third-largest acreage in the Marcellus
            shale as of the third quarter, according to data compiled by
            Bloomberg. Production of natural gas from the Marcellus, helped
            by hydraulic fracturing and horizontal drilling, was expected to
            exceed 13 billion cubic feet a day in December, up from less
            than 2 billion cubic feet in 2010, the Energy Information
            Administration said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Five horizontal rigs targeting gas were in Greene County as
            of Feb. 7, data compiled by oil-field services company Baker
            Hughes Inc. show. All them drill development wells 5,000 feet to
            10,000 feet deep, the company's website shows. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Joe Carroll" datetime="Jan 09, 2014  6:25 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="d"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-01-09/chevron-says-fourth-quarter-profit-little-changed-from-third.html">
        <headline>Chevron Says Net Income Suffered as Energy Production Declined</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX), the world's second-largest energy company by market value, will report a drop
            in
            fourth-quarter profit after oil and natural gas production
            declined amid slumping prices for the commodities. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Net income during the period was 'comparable' to the $5
            billion earned during the third quarter, the San Ramon,
            California-based company said in a statement yesterday. That
            compares with a $7.25 billion profit posted during the final
            three months of 2012. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron joins U.S. competitors such as ConocoPhillips (COP) hurt
            by slumping oil and gas output as weakening demand growth in the
            world's largest economies pressures prices. Chevron
            underperformed its biggest U.S. rivals -- Exxon Mobil Corp. and
            ConocoPhillips -- last year in stock performance and lagged the
            industry average by almost half. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Chevron really struggled on production last year but it
            looks like they're going to turn that around in 2014,' Brian Youngberg, an analyst at Edward Jones Co. in
            St. Louis who
            rates Chevron shares a buy, said in a telephone interview. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron is expected to report per-share profit of $2.87,
            excluding some extraordinary items, when full fourth-quarter
            results are released on Jan. 31. That's the average of 17
            analysts' estimates compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chairman and Chief Executive Officer John S. Watson plans
            to spend almost $40 billion on floating platforms, gas-export
            terminals and exploratory wells this year as part of a plan to
            boost worldwide output 20 percent by the end of 2017. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Declining Output &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron pumped the equivalent of 2.564 million barrels of
            crude daily during October and November, according to the
            statement. That's almost 4 percent lower than the full-quarter
            average of 2.668 million from the year-earlier period. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Given the decline in output, the company has no chance of
            meeting its full-year output target announced in March of 2.65
            million barrels a day, Youngberg said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;ConocoPhillips warned investors this week that fourth-quarter production slipped to a nine-year low
            because of bad
            weather in the U.S. and the North Sea that interfered with
            operations. The Houston-based company said Jan. 7 that output
            dropped to a daily average equivalent to 1.475 million barrels a
            day. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;ConocoPhillips is scheduled to release full quarterly
            results on Jan. 30, as is Exxon, the world's biggest energy
            company by market value. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Lynn Doan" datetime="Jan 13, 2014  3:22 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="d"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-01-13/los-angeles-gasoline-gains-after-chevron-refinery-reports-upsets.html">
        <headline>Los Angeles Gasoline Gains After Chevron Refinery Reports Upsets</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Los Angeles gasoline advanced for
            the first time in seven days after Chevron Corp. (CVX) reported
            malfunctions at the El Segundo refinery in Southern California. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The fuel's discount to futures narrowed after Chevron's
            279,000-barrel-a-day El Segundo plant had a compressor trip Jan.
            11, according to regulatory filings. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Carbob in Los Angeles gained 3.5 cents to 9.5 cents a
            gallon below New York Mercantile Exchange futures as of 2:04
            p.m. East Coast time, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The refinery breakdown may lower fuel production at the
            same time as two tankers, the Overseas Athens and the Maersk
            Mikage, headed for Los Angeles, IHS Inc. (IHS) data show. Both vessels
            were chartered to load fuel from the U.S. West Coast in the next
            week for delivery abroad, according to ship-fixture data
            compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;California-grade, or CARB, diesel in Los Angeles
            strengthened 0.5 cent against ultra low sulfur diesel futures on
            the Nymex to a discount of 6 cents a gallon. Jet fuel in Los
            Angeles dropped 1 cent to 5.5 cents a gallon under ULSD futures. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Carbob in San Francisco was unchanged at a discount of 24
            cents a gallon versus futures. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Retail gasoline in California fell 0.5 cent to $3.639 a
            gallon, according to Heathrow, Florida-based AAA. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The 3-2-1 crack spread, assuming two barrels of Carbob
            gasoline and one barrel of CARB diesel in Los Angeles is refined
            out of three barrels of Alaska North Slope crude, widened 64
            cents to $9.78 a barrel at 2:06 p.m. New York time, data
            compiled by Bloomberg show. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Conventional, 87-octane gasoline in Portland, Oregon, a
            benchmark for the U.S. Pacific Northwest, gained 0.5 cent to a
            discount of 17.5 cents a gallon. Low-sulfur diesel there
            weakened 0.25 cent to 5.5 cents a gallon under ULSD futures. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Lynn Doan" datetime="Jan 14, 2013  6:08 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-01-14/fire-at-chevron-el-segundo-oil-refinery-said-to-damage-equipment.html">
        <headline>Equipment at Chevron El Segundo Plant Said Damaged in Fire</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;A fire yesterday at Chevron Corp. (CVX)'s
            El Segundo refinery, California's largest, damaged equipment
            associated with the plant's fluid catalytic cracker, a person
            with knowledge of the refinery's operations said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The blaze, which ignited at around 6 p.m. local time,
            damaged the selective catalytic reduction plant, a unit that
            removes particulates from gas produced by the catalytic cracker,
            said the person, who asked not to be identified because the
            information isn't public. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The El Segundo refinery, south of Los Angeles, can process
            279,000 barrels of feedstock a day, data compiled by Bloomberg
            show. It supplies 40 percent of the jet fuel to Los Angeles
            International Airport and 20 percent of the region's gasoline,
            San Ramon, California-based Chevron said on its website. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;An 'incident' in one of the refinery's process units
            caused a power failure at the plant yesterday, resulting in the
            slowdown of several units, Rod Spackman, a Chevron spokesman at
            the refinery, said by e-mail. The upset occurred while the plant
            was preparing the unit for planned maintenance, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Aside from maintenance and the unit involved, the refinery
            is running normally, Spackman said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'There was no significant fire at the refinery, and there
            was nothing that would impact the process unit,' Spackman said
            in a later telephone interview. He declined to comment on
            whether yesterday's incident damaged equipment at the plant. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Scheduled Maintenance &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The refinery's fluid catalytic cracker was scheduled to
            shut for a 54-day maintenance turnaround that included work on
            the alkylation unit, a person with direct knowledge of the plans
            said Dec. 7. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Alkylation units produce a high-octane blending component
            for gasoline. Fluid catalytic crackers process vacuum gasoil
            into gasoline or lighter crude products. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The El Segundo Fire Department responded to an incident at
            the refinery at about 5:56 p.m. local time yesterday, Richard
            Guyer, a battalion chief for the department, said by telephone
            today. The plant extinguished 'a small ground fire' and was
            flaring gases after pressure built up in a unit and a cap
            dislodged, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The incident ended at about 8:06 p.m. local time, he said.
            Guyer said it wasn't clear whether the fire was extinguished at
            that time or whether the plant stopped flaring gases. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'The flare and the fire were all the same, really,' he
            said. 'The fire was contributing to the flare activity.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The El Segundo refinery reported a 'failure' at the fluid
            catalytic cracker yesterday at 6 p.m. local time and planned to
            flare gases until Jan. 23, notices to state and air regulators
            show. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Bryan Bradley" datetime="Jan 15, 2013  5:46 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-01-15/chevron-is-only-bidder-for-lithuania-shale-gas-rights-bns-says.html">
        <headline>Chevron Is Only Bidder for Lithuania Shale-Gas Rights, BNS Says</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Exploration and Production
            Lietuva, a Lithuanian subsidiary of Chevron Corp. (CVX), submitted the
            only bid in a tender for shale-gas exploration rights in the
            Baltic nation, Baltic News Service reported. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;If the bid is accepted, the company would need to invest at
            least 80 million litai ($31 million) in exploration of the
            Silute-Taurage field in western Lithuania, the newswire said,
            citing the head of the geological service, Juozas Mockevicius. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Karen Gullo" datetime="Jan 16, 2013  8:09 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="d"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-01-16/chevron-subpoenas-in-ecuador-suit-challenged-in-california-1-.html">
        <headline>Chevron Subpoenas in Ecuador Suit Challenged in Court</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX), which faces a $19
            billion damage award in an Ecuador environmental case, shouldn't
            be allowed to obtain information about the e-mail accounts of
            lawyers, activists and scholars in contact with plaintiff
            attorneys, a privacy rights group told a judge. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Marcia Hofmann, an attorney for the Electronic Frontier
            Foundation, asked U.S. Magistrate Judge Nathanael Cousins in San
            Francisco today to block Chevron subpoenas, saying that free
            speech and privacy rights are at stake. She alleged that the
            company is trying to harass and intimidate activists associated
            with the legal effort to hold Chevron responsible for
            environmental damage in the Amazon basin. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'These people feel intimidated by this,' said Hofmann,
            who's trying to shield the identity of people she refers to as
            'John Does' from Chevron in records it seeks from Google Inc.
            and Yahoo Inc. 'They're all engaged in political activity, and
            it's public criticism against Chevron.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron is seeking information about when and where people
            logged into e-mail accounts, not the content of e-mails, to use
            as evidence in its racketeering lawsuit against Steven Donziger,
            the lead U.S. legal adviser for the Ecuador plaintiffs, said
            Theodore Boutrous, Chevron's lawyer. The San Ramon, California-
            based company alleges Donziger and others improperly influenced
            a court expert in the case and committed fraud to win the
            damages award. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;'Innocent Bystanders' &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The fight over the subpoenas isn't a free-speech battle,
            Boutrous said. Rather than 'innocent bystanders,' the 'John
            Does' were part of the 'pressure campaign' against Chevron
            and their e-mail activity might provide proof of how the
            plaintiff lawyers funneled information to the Ecuador judge and
            ghost-wrote his decision against Chevron, Boutrous told Cousins. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'We know who every one of these people are,' Boutrous
            said. 'We allege some of them at least, many of them, were part
            of the scheme, wittingly or unwittingly.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Donziger denies wrongdoing and the oil company is attacking
            him to avoid responsibility for the damages and trying to
            intimidate people who it thinks don't have the resources to
            fight back, Karen Hinton, a spokeswoman for the Ecuadorean
            plaintiffs, said in an e-mail today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Cousins said the underlying case, which is being litigated
            in several countries and is the subject of international
            arbitration, involves political issues. He questioned whether
            there should be heightened concern about free speech rights. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;'Contract Dispute' &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'This is not a run-of-the-mill contract dispute,' Cousins
            told Boutrous. 'I'm not sure I agree with your assessment'
            that the case is about something 'agnostic and commercial.
            Isn't this a political case?' He didn't say when he would rule. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The damages against Chevron were awarded in 2011 by a
            provincial judge in Ecuador in a lawsuit brought by villagers
            who said the company was responsible for toxic pollution from
            oil drilling by Texaco Inc., which Chevron acquired in 2001.
            Chevron, the world's fourth largest oil company, says it cleaned
            up its portion of the region and was released by the Ecuadorean
            government from future damage claims. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The company has no assets in Ecuador; the plaintiffs have
            gone to court in Canada, Brazil and Argentina to seize Chevron
            funds. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The case is Chevron v. Donziger, 12-80237, U.S. District
            Court, Northern District of California (San Francisco). &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Matthew Monks" datetime="Jan 17, 2014 11:45 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="n" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-01-17/chevron-is-said-to-seek-buyers-for-1-billion-in-u-s-assets.html">
        <headline>Chevron Is Said to Seek Buyers for $1 Billion in U.S. Assets</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX) is seeking to sell
            pipeline and storage operations in Texas and Louisiana that
            together may fetch more than $1 billion, people familiar with
            the matter said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron is working with Jefferies Group LLC to find buyers
            for at least four natural gas and crude oil pipeline operations,
            said two of the people, who asked not to be named because the
            process is private. The San Ramon, California-based company
            began sending out offering materials this week, the people said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Diversified energy companies have been seeking to sell or
            spin off transportation and storage operations to cut costs and
            focus on exploration. Chevron sold a pipeline business in the
            Northwestern U.S. last year to Tesoro Logistics LP, while Royal
            Dutch Shell Plc and Chesapeake Energy Corp. made similar
            divestitures. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron is looking to sell the West Texas LPG Pipeline LP,
            a natural gas pipeline 20 percent owned by Atlas Pipeline
            Partners LP, one of the people said. It's also seeking buyers
            for a gas storage facility in West Texas, a crude oil terminal
            close to the Gulf of Mexico, and at least one of its pipelines
            in Louisiana, this person said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Spokesman Kent Robertson declined to comment on the
            sale as did Jefferies spokesman Richard Khaleel. The company
            plans to sell some oil and gas assets to focus on exploration
            prospects in Iraq, Canada, and Australia, Chevron's Chief
            Financial Officer Pat Yarrington said in a conference call with
            analysts in November. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron will report a fourth-quarter decline in profit amid
            a slump in oil and natural gas production, according to a
            statement on Jan. 9. The company, run by Chairman and Chief
            Executive John S. Watson, plans to spend close to $40 billion on
            new terminals and wells under a plan to boost output by 20
            percent by the end of 2017. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The company's shares have dropped about 4 percent this
            year, giving it a market value of over $230 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Elizabeth Amon" datetime="Jan 27, 2014 12:00 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="d"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-01-27/donziger-hires-appellate-lawyer-in-chevron-case-business-of-law.html">
        <headline>Donziger Hires Appellate Lawyer in Chevron Case: Business of Law</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Steven Donziger, a New York attorney
            accused of leading a racketeering scheme in an environmental
            lawsuit against Chevron Corp. (CVX), hired appellate attorney Deepak
            Gupta of Washington's Gupta Beck PLLC to represent him in an
            anticipated appeal, the firm said on its website. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The trial before U.S. District Judge Lewis Kaplan ended in
            November. There is no opinion yet. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Gupta specializes in Supreme Court and other appellate
            litigation on behalf of plaintiffs, with an emphasis on
            consumers' and workers' rights, class actions and constitutional
            law, according to his firm biography. He'argued for the
            plaintiffs in'the U.S. Supreme Court case over arbitration, ATT
            Mobility v. Concepcion. An adjunct law professor at Georgetown
            and American universities, he worked at Public Citizen
            Litigation Group before founding his firm in 2012. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Donziger and a team of other lawyers won a $19 billion
            judgment in 2011 on behalf of Ecuadorean rainforest villagers
            who claimed Texaco, later bought by Chevron, dumped billions of
            gallons of drilling-generated toxic waste from the 1960s through
            the early 1990s. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron, based in San Ramon, California, has refused to pay
            any of the judgment and is seeking an order from Kaplan barring
            Donziger from trying to enforce it. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Doniziger will also be represented by University of Denver
            Law School professors Justin Marceau and John Campbell, whose
            students will work with Gupta's legal team. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;New Jersey Law Firm Has Role in Hoboken Mayor Threat Claim &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;When Hoboken Mayor Dawn Zimmer said Jan. 18 that New Jersey
            Republican Governor Chris Christie's administration threatened
            to withhold Hurricane Sandy aid unless she approved a new office
            tower, the disclosure involved a politically connected state law
            firm. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The developer of the tower, New York-based Rockefeller
            Group, was represented by Wolff Samson. The New Jersey law
            firm was founded by David Samson, Christie's top appointee at
            the Port Authority of New York and New Jersey. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Wolff Samson said in a statement Jan. 23 that its
            'conduct in the representation of our client was appropriate in
            all respects' and denied Zimmer's statements. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;For more, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Firm News &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Steptoe Hires King Spalding Trio to Open Office in Palo Alto &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Steptoe Johnson LLP is opening a Palo Alto, California,
            office with the hiring of patent litigator William F. Abrams,
            formerly of King Spalding LLP, who will be managing partner. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;He is joined by Sanjeet Dutta, who will also be a partner.
            Boyd Cloern, a third King Spalding lawyer, will be a partner
            in Steptoe's Washington office. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'While Steptoe has long had clients in Silicon Valley,
            putting down roots there has been an important priority of the
            firm,' Phil West, Steptoe's chairman, said in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Partner Moves &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;King Spalding, Ropes Gray: Lateral Partner Job Changes &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;King Spalding LLP added to its SEC enforcement and white-collar criminal practices with the hire of
            Dixie L. Johnson in
            Washington and William F. Johnson in New York. The two join from
            Fried, Frank, Harris, Shriver Jacobson LLP, where they co-headed the SEC enforcement and white-collar
            criminal defense
            groups. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Commercial and securities litigator Richard Gallagher
            joined Ropes Gray LLP's litigation practice group in San
            Francisco. He was previously at Orrick, Herrington Sutcliffe
            LLP. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In Toronto, Alex Pankratz, formerly of Osler, Hoskin
            Harcourt LLP, joined Baker McKenzie LLP's global tax practice. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;DLA Piper LLP announced that Christina Houston joined the
            firm's corporate and finance practice as a partner in the
            Wilmington office. She was at KL Gates LLP.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Rupert Rowling" datetime="Jan 30, 2013 12:49 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="n" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-01-30/total-chevron-bid-for-forties-pertamina-seeks-3-months-crude.html">
        <headline>Total, Chevron Bid for Forties; Pertamina Seeks 3-Months Crude</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Total SA and Chevron Corp. both
            failed to buy North Sea Forties crude at a lower price than
            yesterday. There were no bids or offers for Russian Urals grade
            in northwest Europe or the Mediterranean. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;PT Pertamina, Indonesia's state-owned oil company, issued a
            tender to buy low-sulfur crude for delivery for three months
            from April to June, said a company official. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;North Sea &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Total sought to buy Forties at 50 cents a barrel more than
            Dated Brent for loading Feb. 17 to Feb. 23, a Bloomberg survey
            of traders and brokers monitoring the Platts pricing window
            showed. That's 5 cents less than its equivalent bid yesterday
            and compares with cargoes it bought on Jan. 22 at premiums of 35
            cents and 40 cents. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron was also unsuccessful with its bid at plus 45 cents
            for a cargo loading on the same dates, according to the survey. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Reported crude trading typically occurs during the Platts
            window, which ends at 4:30 p.m. London time. Forties loading in
            10 to 25 days rose 6 cents to 69 cents a barrel more than Dated
            Brent, data compiled by Bloomberg show. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Brent for March settlement traded at $114.71 a barrel on
            the ICE Futures Europe exchange in London at the close of the
            window, compared with $114.28 in the previous session. The April
            contract was at $113.69, a discount of $1.02 to March. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Mediterranean/Urals &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;There were no bids or offers for Urals crude, the Platts
            survey showed. Gunvor Group Ltd. bid unsuccessfully yesterday
            for 100,000 metric tons at a discount of 90 cents a barrel to
            Dated Brent on a delivered basis to Rotterdam. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Urals differential to Dated Brent in the Mediterranean
            widened by 2 cents a barrel to minus 30 cents, according to data
            compiled by Bloomberg. In northwest Europe, the discount
            increased to 88 cents from 86 cents yesterday, the data showed. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;PKN Orlen SA bought 100,000 tons of Urals from Glencore
            International Plc for loading Feb. 19 to Feb. 23 from either
            Primorsk or Ust-Luga via an informal closed tender, according to
            three people with knowledge of the matter. The company yesterday
            bought a Feb. 15 to Feb. 19 cargo from Vitol Group. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;OAO Surgutneftegas sold two lots of Urals to Gunvor and
            Repsol SA for loading next month from Ust-Luga, according to
            four traders who participate in the market. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Gunvor bought the Feb. 13 to Feb. 14 consignment while
            Repsol purchased the Feb. 15 to Feb. 16 lot, the people said,
            asking not to be identified as the information is confidential. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Surgut issued a separate tender today, offering shipments
            of 100,000 tons each for loading on Feb. 19 and Feb. 20 and Feb.
            21 to Feb. 22 from Ust-Luga and for Feb. 23 to Feb. 24 from
            Primorsk, the people said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;OAO Rosneft awarded February Urals shipments from Primorsk
            and the Black Sea port of Novorossiysk to Exxon Mobil Corp.,
            Glencore and Vitol via a tender, according to two people with
            knowledge of the matter. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;West Africa &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Benchmark Nigerian Qua Iboe blend rose 16 cents to $2.32 a
            barrel more than Dated Brent, which is the most since Jan. 11,
            Bloomberg data show. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Pertamina is seeking cargoes for its refineries at
            Balikpapan and Cilacap, said the official, who asked not to be
            identified because they aren't authorized to speak to the media.
            The tender closes tomorrow with offers valid until Feb. 1. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Joe Carroll" datetime="Jan 31, 2014  4:27 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="d"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-01-31/chevron-fourth-quarter-net-income-slides-as-production-declines.html">
        <headline>Chevron Forecasts Little Output Growth After Profit Declines</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX), the third-largest oil
            company by market value, said production this year will rise
            less than 1 percent as fourth-quarter profit tumbled 32 percent
            amid slumping prices. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Crude and natural gas output will average the equivalent of
            2.61 million barrels a day this year, a 0.5 percent increase
            from 2013, the San Ramon, California-based company said in a
            slide presentation today. For the final three months of last
            year, net income dropped to $4.93 billion, or $2.57 a share,
            from $7.25 billion, or $3.70, a year earlier, Chevron said in a
            separate statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Costs have ballooned at Chevron's flagship $54 billion
            Gorgon liquefied natural gas development in Australia, which is
            almost 75 percent complete, as the company looks to deep fields
            in Kazakhstan and the Gulf of Mexico to add supplies. Chevron is
            the latest major international energy producer to disclose
            production shortfalls while facing surging costs and unplanned
            project delays. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Production growth is going to be modest this year,' said
            Pavel Molchanov, an analyst at Raymond James Associates Inc.
            in Houston. 'In the absence of large project startups,
            production growth beyond the very low single digits is just not
            realistic.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Worst Performing &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron slid 4.1 percent, the most since October 2012, to
            $111.63 at the close in New York. It was the day's worst-performing energy producer in the Standard Poor's
            500 Index. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Both Exxon Mobil Corp. and Royal Dutch Shell Plc, the top
            two oil companies by market value, reported lower quarterly
            earnings this week compared with 2012. Chevron's stock
            underperformed Exxon and ConocoPhillips last year and lagged the
            industry average. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Brent crude, the global benchmark oil price, averaged
            $109.35 a barrel in the last three months of 2013, a 78-cent
            drop from the prior fourth quarter. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Global crude oil prices and refining margins were
            generally lower in 2013 than 2012,' Chairman and Chief
            Executive Officer John Watson said in today's statement. 'These
            conditions, as well as lower gains on asset sales and higher
            expenses, resulted in lower earnings.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Per-share results at Chevron matched the average estimate
            of 18 analysts. Sales fell 7.3 percent to $56.2 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron said its fourth-quarter production fell 3.4 percent
            to an average of 2.58 million barrels of oil equivalent a day in
            the quarter, from 2.67 million barrels a year earlier. Earnings
            from oil and gas sales dropped 29 percent to $4.85 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Watson has said he plans to spend $39.8 billion this year
            on gas-export facilities, offshore crude platforms and
            exploratory drilling as part of a plan to increase global
            production 20 percent by the end of 2017. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Joe Carroll" datetime="Jul 10, 2013  5:13 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-10/chevron-says-april-may-production-fell-from-second-quarter-2012.html">
        <headline>Chevron Says April-May Production Fell From Second Quarter 2012</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX), the second-largest
            energy company by market value, said crude oil and natural gas
            output declined 2.1 percent during April and May compared with
            the second quarter of last year. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron reported selected second-quarter data in a
            statement distributed on Business Wire today. The San Ramon,
            California-based company is scheduled to announce full quarterly
            results on Aug. 2. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Exxon Mobil Corp. is the biggest energy producer by market
            value. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Joe Carroll" datetime="Jul 10, 2014  5:47 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-10/chevron-says-second-quarter-profit-exceeded-first-quarter-result.html">
        <headline>Chevron's Second-Quarter Profit Boosted by Asset Sales</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX), the world's third-largest energy producer by market value, said more than half
            a
            billion dollars in asset sales helped lift second-quarter profit
            higher than the first three months of the year. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron sold $500 million to $600 million in assets such as
            oil and natural gas wells during the April-to-May period,
            according to a statement the San Ramon, California-based company
            issued today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Production for the first two months of the quarter averaged
            the equivalent of 2.566 million barrels of crude a day,
            according to the statement. If that pace held for the final
            month of the period, output slid 0.6 percent from the second
            quarter of 2013. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron is scheduled to release full results for the
            quarter on Aug. 1. The statement was released after the close of
            regular U.S. stock trading. Chevron shares have risen 4.3
            percent this year, underperforming the 6.3 percent gain of the
            Standard and Poor's 500 Index. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Exxon Mobil Corp. is the world's biggest energy company by
            market value, followed by Royal Dutch Shell Plc, according to
            data compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>

    <entry author="By Patricia Hurtado" datetime="Jul 16, 2013  8:56 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="n" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-16/chevron-judge-denies-ecuadoreans-request-for-trial-delay.html">
        <headline>Chevron Judge Denies Ecuadoreans' Request for Trial Delay</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX)'s civil racketeering
            case against Ecuadoreans it accuses of fabricating evidence to
            win a $19 billion verdict in a pollution lawsuit will go to
            trial on Oct. 15, a judge said in rejecting a defense request
            for a delay. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron sued Ecuadoreans who had earlier claimed the San
            Ramon, California-based company was responsible for pollution in
            the Amazon rainforest. The company said the Ecuadoreans and
            their New York-based lawyer, Steven Donziger, made up evidence
            in the initial case. The trial will be held in Manhattan federal
            court. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;U.S. District Judge Lewis Kaplan today denied Donziger's
            request to delay the trial in order to find a new attorney.
            Kaplan said Donziger has had four months to hire a new lawyer
            since his prior counsel, John Keker, asked to leave the case
            because he hadn't been paid. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'It is unclear whether he has money to pay counsel but
            chooses not to spend it, or whether he in fact does not have'
            money, Kaplan said of Donziger in a written opinion. Donziger
            'has offered no competent evidence of his financial
            situation,' the judge said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron was ordered by an Ecuadorean court in 2011 to pay
            as much as $18.2 billion in damages for Texaco's alleged dumping
            of toxic drilling waste in the jungle from 1964 to about 1992.
            Chevron acquired Texaco in 2000. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;$19 Billion &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The judgment came in an 18-year lawsuit decided by a judge
            in Lago Agrio, a provincial capital near the Colombian border.
            With interest, the judgment is now worth $19 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron denied wrongdoing, saying Texaco cleaned up its
            share of pollution at oil fields that were later taken over
            PetroEcuador, Ecuador's state-owned oil company. Chevron says it
            was released from liability by an agreement between Texaco and
            Ecuador. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In denying the defense request to postpone the October
            trial, Kaplan today said the Ecuadorean plaintiffs are still
            financing litigation in courts around the world. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Donziger and the plaintiffs claim they 'are out of
            money,' Kaplan said. 'To the contrary, the record establishes
            that they have raised millions of dollars in exchange for shares
            of any recovery.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Claims Influence &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron accuses Donziger of improperly influencing a court
            expert whose findings were relied upon by the judge in Ecuador. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Donziger denies wrongdoing, and plaintiffs in the pollution
            case said the company is attacking him to avoid paying damages. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Bill Hamilton of Fenton Communications, a spokesman for the
            Ecuadorean plaintiffs, declined to comment on Kaplan's ruling. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'We look forward to detailing the extent of fraud and
            misconduct carried out by the plaintiffs and their U.S.-based
            lawyers at trial in October,' Morgan Crinklaw, a Chevron
            spokesman, said in an e-mailed statement. ' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The racketeering case is Chevron v. Donziger, 1:11-cv-00691, U.S. District Court, Southern District
            of New York
            (Manhattan). The case in Ecuador is Aquinda v. Chevron,
            002-2003, Superior Court of Nueva Loja, Lago Agrio, Ecuador. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Mario Parker" datetime="Jul 21, 2013 10:58 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="n" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-21/chevron-phillips-flares-gases-after-unit-shut-at-sweeny-complex.html">
        <headline>Chevron Phillips Flares Gases After Unit Shut at Sweeny Complex</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Phillips Chemical Co.
            reported that it released emissions after a unit was shut at its
            Sweeny chemical plant in Texas, according to a filing with state
            regulators. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The ethylene unit was shut down after it lost a gas-fired
            turbine compressor, the company said in a filing with the Texas
            Commission on Environmental Quality. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By James Paton" datetime="Jul 23, 2013  2:17 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-23/geodynamics-starts-talks-to-supply-power-to-chevron-santos.html">
        <headline>Geodynamics Starts Talks to Supply Power to Chevron, Santos</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Geodynamics Ltd. (GDY), an explorer
            seeking to produce power from hot underground rocks, said Santos
            Ltd. (STO) and Chevron Corp. (CVX), developers of shale gas projects in
            central Australia, are interested in becoming customers. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Those discussions have commenced,' Geoff Ward, chief
            executive officer of Brisbane-based Geodynamics, said today in a
            phone interview. 'I've spoken to those operators, and they are
            very positive about acting as initial customers for us. They see
            the interest in this as a long-term supply resource.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Geodynamics expects to sign a customer in six months to 12
            months, Ward said. The company is also planning to apply for
            funding from Australia's A$10 billion ($9.3 billion) Clean
            Energy Finance Corp. and looking for a new partner after Origin
            Energy Ltd. (ORG) withdrew from a joint venture this year, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Geodynamics, trying to become the first company in
            Australia to operate a commercial geothermal plant, expects to
            start with a 5-megawatt to 10-megawatt project in central
            Australia's Cooper Basin. The company plans to use data from a
            1-megawatt pilot plant, which started producing power earlier
            this year, to form a development proposal for the project. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron, the second-largest U.S. energy company, entered
            the Australian shale industry in February with an agreement to
            pay as much as $349 million to join Adelaide-based Beach Energy
            Ltd. (BPT) in a project in the Cooper Basin. Adelaide-based Santos is
            also among shale gas explorers in the region. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Technical Setbacks &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Santos and Chevron-Beach ventures are the 'key
            targets' in the search for a customer, Ward said. 'If we can
            continue to develop it into a material asset play, then it would
            be a natural fit with their operations in the Cooper.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Geodynamics shares are down 86 percent in the past four
            years in Sydney trading, even with an 18 percent increase in
            2013. Geodynamics closed unchanged today at 13 cents. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The industry has struggled to overcome technical setbacks
            and delays, with geothermal power unlikely to deliver much more
            than a 'handful' of pilot projects and possibly some plants
            with a capacity of as much as 10 megawatts before 2020,
            Bloomberg New Energy Finance said in a June 28 report. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Geothermal developers in Australia are using technology
            that circulates water through cracks as deep as 5 kilometers
            (3.1 miles) underground, turning it to steam to run a turbine. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Patricia Laya" datetime="Jul 25, 2013 12:49 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-25/repsol-seeks-to-block-chevron-deal-with-ypf-through-world-bank.html">
        <headline>Repsol Seeks to Block Chevron Deal With YPF Through World Bank</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Repsol SA (REP) is asking a World Bank
            panel to help prevent Argentina's YPF SA from developing assets
            seized from the Spanish oil producer after Chevron Corp. agreed
            to invest $1.24 billion in a shale venture in the country. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The request was filed yesterday to the Washington-based
            International Center for Settlement of Investment Disputes,
            asking the arbitrator to instruct Argentina to abstain from
            developing strategic YPF assets such as the Vaca Muerta shale
            formation, Repsol spokesman Kristian Rix said. The filing
            couldn't immediately be verified on the ICSID website and the
            center didn't respond to an e-mailed request to comment. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron's plan to tap Vaca Muerta in an accord with YPF
            this month comes as Repsol disputes the seizure of its 51
            percent stake in the Argentine company by President Cristina Fernandez de Kirchner's government last year.
            Repsol has another
            lawsuit at the ICSID demanding fair compensation for the seizure
            of its YPF stake, which came shortly after the Argentine company
            announced Vaca Muerta discoveries of at least 23 billion barrels
            of oil equivalent. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'We need fair compensation, which is something that, after
            15 months, we haven't seen,' Repsol's Chief Financial Officer
            Miguel Martinez said today in a call with analysts. Chevron is
            interfering with Repsol's compensation by investing in what it
            considers illegally confiscated assets, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The claims lack any judicial basis because Repsol never
            owned rights over Vaca Muerta, YPF said in an e-mailed response
            to questions. Chevron didn't immediately respond to requests for
            comment. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Other Suits &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Repsol has separately filed unlawful competition suits
            against Chevron Corp. (CVX) and Bridas Group that are set to be judged
            in Spain. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron's investments in Vaca Muerta may reach as much as
            $15 billion under the accord with YPF. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Argentina holds the world's second-largest shale gas
            reserves and the fourth-largest for shale oil, according to U.S.
            Energy Information Administration data. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Rebecca Penty and Bradley Olson" datetime="Jul 31, 2014  5:19 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s"
           progress_sentiment="d"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-31/apache-exit-seen-threatening-chevron-s-canada-lng-project.html">
        <headline>Apache Exit Seen Threatening Chevron's Canada LNG Project</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX)'s plan to build a
            natural gas shipping terminal on Canada's Pacific Coast faces
            mounting challenges with the exit of its partner, Apache Corp. (APA) &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The proposal to liquefy the fuel in Kitimat, British
            Columbia, the first to get export approval in Canada, was
            already delayed by prior ownership changes including the
            departures of Encana Corp. and EOG Resources Inc. It's among
            more than a dozen Pacific Coast liquefied natural gas export
            plants being considered by companies seeking higher prices for
            the fuel in Asia, including Royal Dutch Shell Plc and Petroliam
            Nasional Bhd. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron, based in San Ramon, California, probably won't
            pursue Kitimat LNG on its own, given the cost overruns at its
            Gorgon project in Australia, said Fadel Gheit, an analyst with
            Oppenheimer Co. in New York. The cost to build Gorgon, where
            Chevron has partners including Exxon Mobil Corp., surged to $54
            billion from an estimate of $37 billion in 2009. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'The odds increase that there will be no Kitimat,' Gheit
            said in a phone interview today. 'I would not think that they
            would be interested in going it alone. They had a bad experience
            in Australia with Gorgon and their co-pilots were Exxon, the
            best in the business.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Apache, facing pressure from activist hedge fund Jana
            Partners LLC to cut spending and focus drilling in the U.S.,
            heeded the investor's advice today by announcing it will exit
            the Canadian project and will sell its stake in the Wheatstone
            LNG facility under construction in Australia. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Apache gained 1.4 percent to $102.66 at the close in New
            York after earlier rising to $104.57, the highest intraday since
            March 2012. Chevron fell 2.5 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;'World Class' &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Kurt Glaubitz, a spokesman for Chevron, declined to comment
            on Apache's departure from the project. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'I don't think the complete exit by Apache has an impact
            on Kitimat going forward one way or the other,' Apache Chairman
            and Chief Executive Officer Steve Farris said today on a
            conference call with investors. 'It is a world-class project
            with world-class reserves.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron and Apache had already been seeking a buyer to
            acquire part of their interests in Kitimat LNG to defray costs.
            The project, the first to receive an LNG export license from
            Canada's National Energy Board in 2011, has yet to be
            sanctioned. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Petronas Plan &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Petroliam Nasional, known as Petronas, plans to be the
            first to decide whether to proceed with a Canadian LNG export
            project. The Malaysian state-owned company is targeting a
            decision on the C$9 billion ($8.3 billion) to C$11 billion
            proposal by the end of this year. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Kitimat LNG was initially considered by Calgary-based
            developer Galveston LNG Inc. as an import terminal last decade
            and the concept was switched to an export facility after vast
            supplies of gas from shale across North America flooded
            continental markets. Galveston attracted Apache as a partner and
            was later acquired by EOG. Encana joined the project in 2011. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron announced it would enter Kitimat LNG the following
            year, when Encana and EOG sold their stakes to focus on
            producing onshore fuels. The project was delayed after Chevron
            joined as the partners reorganized roles, undertook additional
            studies and sought more partners to spread costs. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Kitimat LNG's early export license gave it a head start on
            the other Canadian proposals, and it succeeded in lining up
            pipeline approvals and aboriginal support. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Buyers Search &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;After that, the project struggled to find buyers for its
            gas. Apache's departure now pushes Kitimat LNG lower on the list
            of the plants that may be built, Ed Kallio and Cameron Gingrich,
            directors at Solomon Associates LLC's Ziff Energy division in
            Calgary, said in a phone interview. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'They were having issues finding markets, unlike Shell and
            Petronas,' Kallio said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;By losing Apache, Chevron may attract a partner with
            experience developing LNG and contacts in the market that missed
            the first wave of investment in Canada, said Uday Turaga, chief
            executive officer of ADI Analytics in Houston. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'I don't think there will be a dearth of suitors who may
            want to take Apache's place,' Turaga said in a phone interview.
            'It's going to be a bit of rough weather for the project until
            additional partners can be lined up.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tina Davis" datetime="Jun 04, 2014  8:38 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-04/transcanada-signs-deals-for-lng-pipeline-with-chevron-apache.html">
        <headline>TransCanada Signs Deals for LNG Pipeline with Chevron, Apache</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;TransCanada Corp. (TRP) signed agreements
            with Chevron Corp. and Apache Corp. (APA) for a C$1.9 billion ($1.7
            billion) pipeline that would help natural gas reach a proposed
            export facility near Kitimat, British Columbia. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The agreement calls for delivery of about 1.9 billion cubic
            feet of gas a day on the Merrick Mainline project, Calgary-based
            TransCanada said in a statement today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'The initial work for the project is proceeding well, and
            we anticipate filing an application with the National Energy
            Board in the fourth quarter of 2014 for approvals to build and
            operate the project,' TransCanada Chief Executive Officer Russ
            Girling said in the statement. 'Subject to the necessary
            approvals, we expect the Merrick Mainline to begin service in
            the first quarter of 2020.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Pablo Gonzalez" datetime="Jun 05, 2013  4:36 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-05/chevron-argentina-asset-freeze-revoked-easing-shale-development.html">
        <headline>Chevron Argentina Asset Freeze Revoked Easing Shale Venture</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Argentina's Supreme Court revoked the seizure of Chevron Corp.'s (CVX) assets in the country six
            months after an embargo that threatened to derail plans to develop shale deposits with state-run YPF SA.
            (YPF) &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The embargo was rejected in a five-page ruling, overturning a November decision by
            Judge Adrian Elcuj Miranda ordering 40 percent of Chevron's Argentine bank accounts to be held in escrow at
            the request of Ecuadorean plaintiffs to enforce a $19 billion award against the second-biggest U.S. oil
            company, according to the ruling posted late yesterday on the Supreme Court's website. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The
            'decision from Argentina's Supreme Court confirms that the Ecuadorian embargo should not have been issued in
            the first place,' James Craig, a spokesman for San Ramon, California-based Chevron, said yesterday in an
            e-mailed response to questions. 'This is a significant development further demonstrating the illegitimacy of
            the Lago Agrio Plaintiffs' attempt to enforce their fraudulent judgment.' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ecuador has
            blamed Texaco Inc. (677004Q), which Chevron acquired in 2001, for destroying the environment in the Lago
            Agrio region through its oil exploration activities and damaging the living conditions of 30,000
            inhabitants. The Ecuadorean plaintiffs filed the attachment order in Argentina under an international treaty
            signed by Ecuador, Argentina and Colombia. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Shale Deposits &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;'We
            respectfully disagree with the ruling,' Enrique Bruchou, the Argentine lawyer for the Ecuadorean plaintiffs,
            said in an e-mailed statement. 'The trial court, a unanimous Court of Appeals, and especially senior Judge
            Carlos Fayt in his dissent, all appreciated, Chevron's Argentine subsidiaries do have the right to be heard
            in Ecuador. We will continue pursuing the defense of the rights of the Ecuadorean plaintiffs against the
            Argentine subsidiaries of Chevron.' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Ecuadorean plaintiffs rights to sue Chevron's
            Argentine units haven't been affected by this ruling, which refers exclusively to a precautionary ruling for
            the seizure of assets, Bruchou said. The Ecuadorean plaintiffs filed the attachment order under an
            international treaty signed by Ecuador, Argentina and Colombia. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The ruling unfreezing
            Chevron's accounts paves the way for a $1.5 billion venture between Chevron and YPF (YPFD) to develop shale
            oil and gas at what may be the 'the world's second-largest shale oil reservoir,' according to Ali Moshiri,
            Chevron's head of Latin America and Africa. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Vaca Muerta &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;YPF rose
            2.2 percent to 123.15 pesos at the close in Buenos Aires, the biggest gain since May 29. Chevron slid 1.1
            percent to $121.57 in New York trading. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chevron, the fourth-largest producer of oil in
            Argentina, signed an accord on May 15 establishing terms for a definitive agreement with YPF (YPF),
            Argentina's biggest energy company, to develop an area at the shale formation of Vaca Muerta. The total
            investment in the venture could reach $15 billion. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Any deal to work with YPF in
            exploring the nation's shale formations must be preceded by a lifting of the embargo on Chevron's assets,
            Chairman and CEO John Watson said on March 12. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Alejandro Di Lazzaro, a spokesman for YPF
            in Buenos Aires, declined to comment in a telephone call. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;YPF has struggled to proceed
            with plans to tap non-conventional oil and gas deposits in Argentina to boost output a year after President
            Cristina Fernandez de Kirchner seized a 51 percent stake in the company from Spain's Repsol SA. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;YPF increased energy imports this year after a fire in April at its largest refinery in La Plata
            lowered output levels. The company has been shut out of international capital markets because of
            double-digit borrowing costs for Argentine issuers. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Chris Dolmetsch and Zain Shauk" datetime="Jun 05, 2014  3:50 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s"
           progress_sentiment="d"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-05/bp-chevron-among-refiners-sued-by-vermont-over-mtbe.html">
        <headline>BP, Chevron Among Refiners Sued by Vermont Over MTBE</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;BP Plc (BP/), Chevron Corp. (CVX) and Exxon Mobil
            Corp. (XOM) are among two dozen U.S. refiners sued by Vermont Attorney
            General William Sorrell and accused of polluting the state's
            groundwater with a gasoline additive. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Sorrell filed the case today in state court in Montpelier,
            the capital. The refiners promoted, marketed and distributed
            gasoline containing the additive Methyl Tertiary Butyl Ether, or
            MTBE, knowing that it posed 'unprecedented risks' to
            groundwater, Sorrell's office said in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'These companies knew years ago that MTBE was a uniquely
            bad actor in groundwater, and they ignored the risks and sold it
            anyway,' Sorrell said. 'This lawsuit is about holding them
            accountable and ensuring that they -- and not Vermonters -- pay
            to clean up our groundwater.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The suit is one of scores of claims filed by cities, states
            and individuals around the U.S. against oil refiners, retailers
            and distributors over MTBE. The U.S. Supreme Court in April
            upheld a jury's $104.7 million damage award against Exxon Mobil
            for contaminating New York City wells with the additive. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;New York sued oil companies in 2003, alleging they knew the
            additive would pollute groundwater. Exxon Mobil argued that
            state laws are pre-empted by the federal Clean Air Act, which
            required oil companies to reformulate gasoline to reduce air
            pollution from vehicle emissions. Oil companies added MTBE to
            make it burn more efficiently. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Exxon Statement &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;An Exxon Mobil spokesman, Todd Spitler, said the company is
            reviewing the state's claims. The foundation of MTBE litigation
            is flawed because companies are being held liable for including
            oxygenates in gasoline that were required by Congress and
            approved by regulators, he said by e-mail. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Companies that complied with the law and regulations to
            blend approved oxygenates in gasoline should not be held liable
            simply for following a government mandate,' Spitler said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;There hasn't been a single recorded case of anyone's
            becoming sick from MTBE water contamination, he said. The
            company takes seriously its responsibility to operate in an
            'environmentally sound manner' and works hard to protect the
            health and safety of the communities where it operates, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A Chevron spokesman, Braden Reddall, said the company will
            'review the complaint once we are served.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Carlton Carroll, an American Petroleum Institute spokesman,
            declined to comment on the suit. Diana Cronan, a spokeswoman for
            the American Fuel Petrochemical Manufacturers, didn't
            immediately respond to requests for comment. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;State Findings &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;While MTBE is banned as a gasoline additive in Vermont, the
            state's Agency of Natural Resources continues to oversee
            remediation of past releases and keeps finding new contaminated
            wells, according to Sorrell's office. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The state claims violations of its Groundwater Protection
            Act and alleges that the refiners used MTBE as an additive
            despite knowing it was hazardous and would pollute groundwater,
            and that they failed to inform state regulators, resellers or
            consumers of the hazards and how to mitigate them. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The case is State of Vermont v. Atlantic Richfield Co.,
            Vermont Superior Court, Washington County (Montpelier). &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Jim Snyder" datetime="Jun 11, 2013  3:29 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-11/chevron-ceo-says-industry-must-deal-with-fracking-concern.html">
        <headline>Chevron CEO Says Industry Must Deal With Fracking Concern</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Energy producers must deal with the
            'legitimate concerns' that gas development associated with
            hydraulic fracturing is unsafe by adopting tougher standards,
            Chevron Corp. (CVX) Chief Executive Officer John Watson said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;BP Plc's 2010 oil spill at its deepwater well in the Gulf
            of Mexico -- the worst in U.S. waters -- fueled public
            skepticism of the industry, Watson said today in Washington.
            Fracking, a drilling technique that has increased production by
            extracting oil and gas trapped in shale rock, has drawn oil and
            gas companies to rural communities that aren't familiar with the
            development. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Recent developments add to public awareness of the risks of
            drilling, and the industry needs to do a better job in resolving
            the concerns, Watson said at a Center for Strategic and
            International Studies event. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Public expectations are very high, and there's no reason
            they shouldn't be high,' Watson said. 'There are some risks
            out there. Some risks are overstated. But we have to engage them
            either way.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Kurt Glaubitz, a Chevron spokesman, said Watson was
            referring to concerns with truck traffic and the disposal of
            hazardous wastewater from the fracking process as areas of
            concern the industry needs to confront. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Air, Water &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In hydraulic fracturing, or fracking, producers shoot a
            mixture of water, sand and chemicals underground to break apart
            shale rock formations to free trapped oil and gas. The technique
            has led to record production of natural gas and sent domestic
            oil output to its highest level in two decades. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Opponents say fracking creates air and water pollution. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron has joined environmental groups including the
            Environmental Defense Fund to establish the Center for
            Sustainable Shale Development that has crafted 15 performance
            standards to be followed by oil and gas producers. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'I don't believe any company would be certified today, but
            we're moving towards those standards,' Watson said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The U.S. Energy Information Administration said yesterday
            that oil and gas from shale formations are greater than
            previously estimated. Tight oil resources could be 345 billion
            barrels worldwide, and shale gas estimates were increased by 10
            percent from 2011, to 7,299 trillion cubic feet, according to
            the EIA, which tracks and analyzes energy data. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Watson said it may take 'a lot of time' to develop some
            of the resources because infrastructure is in short supply. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Elisha Bala-Gbogbo" datetime="Jun 11, 2013  8:13 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="n"
           progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-11/chevron-to-sell-interest-in-two-nigeria-shallow-water-oil-leases.html">
        <headline>Chevron to Sell Interest in Two Nigeria Shallow-Water Oil Leases</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX), the second-largest
            U.S. oil company, said it plans to sell its interest in two
            Nigerian shallow-water leases in the oil-rich delta of Africa's
            top producer. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The sale of interest in oil-mining leases 83 and 85 is
            'part of a continuous process of portfolio evaluation and
            business prioritization,' James Craig, a Houston-based company
            spokesman, said today in an e-mailed response to questions. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron, the third-largest producer in the West African
            country, operates a joint venture in which it holds a 40 percent
            stake and state-owned Nigerian National Petroleum Corp. owns 60
            percent. The company holds interests in 10 deepwater oil blocks
            in Nigeria, including its 250,000 barrel-a-day Agbami field
            located 70 miles (113 kilometers) off the coast. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron joins Royal Dutch Shell Plc (RDSA) and ConocoPhillips (COP) in
            selling Nigerian oil interests. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Sheenagh Matthews" datetime="Jun 12, 2013 10:20 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="h"
           progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-12/chevron-phillips-looks-at-new-middle-east-chemical-plant.html">
        <headline>Chevron Phillips Looks at New Middle East Chemical Plant</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Phillips Chemical Co., the
            petrochemical venture of U.S. oil producer Chevron Corp. (CVX) and
            refiner Phillips 66 (PSX), is exploring ways to expand in the Middle
            East, including building a new plant. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The U.S. partnership would consider setting up a site on
            its own or in a joint venture, and the 'entire' region is
            under consideration, Benny Mermans, head of Europe and Africa at
            Chevron Phillips Chemical's international operations, said in an
            interview at a petrochemical conference in Frankfurt. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The chemical company's owners are 'very supportive' of
            growth plans, Mermans said. Woodlands, Texas-based Chevron
            Phillips, also known as CPChem, is already spending about $5
            billion on a new ethylene plant, or cracker, and two factories
            making polyethylene in Baytown, Texas, to take advantage of
            cheap natural gas, which is used as a raw material as well as an
            energy source. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Look at our ownership structure,' Mermans said. 'We
            represent a fair share of their net income. By having that
            support, by creating margins, that provides us with a lot of
            legroom' for gaining resources for growth. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Phillips has three joint ventures in the Saudi
            Arabian industrial city of Jubail as well as partnerships in
            Qatar in Messaieed and Ras Laffan, Melanie Samuelson, a
            spokeswoman at the U.S. company, said in an e-mail. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Funding Sources &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Expansion would be financed by the chemical business
            itself, and Chevron Phillips would tap capital markets for
            further cash should the need arise, Mermans said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Availability of cheaper shale gas in the U.S., extracted by
            the hydraulic fracturing process known as fracking, means that
            Europe is being 'squeezed on all sides,' Mermans said. The
            company will focus on more specialty chemicals in the region and
            is expanding a plant in Tessenderlo, Belgium, to add sulfur-based organic products. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In the U.S., Chevron Phillips is the first company in more
            than a decade to build an ethylene plant, Mermans said. The
            cracker, which will produce 1.5 million metric tons of the
            gaseous chemical a year, is on schedule to start operations in
            2017, with the company's board expected to give final approval
            in the third quarter, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Dow Chemical Co. (DOW), the largest U.S. chemical maker by sales,
            and Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM), the biggest U.S. oil company, have said
            they plan similar-sized ethylene plants in Texas. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'It's a race,' Mermans said. 'CPChem is well placed to
            be first.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Lynn Doan" datetime="Jun 13, 2013  6:28 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="n" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-13/los-angeles-gasoline-gains-on-tankers-as-chevron-plans-repairs.html">
        <headline>Los Angeles Gasoline Gains on Tankers as Chevron Plans Repairs</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Spot gasoline and diesel in Los
            Angeles advanced against futures as Chevron Corp. (CVX)'s El Segundo
            plant was said to be planning repairs on two crude units and
            five tankers were scheduled to load fuel in the West for export. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron's 279,000-barrel-a-day El Segundo refinery, the
            largest in California, will shut the No. 4 crude unit next month
            for short-term repairs, a person familiar with the schedule said
            today. The No. 2 crude unit will also be brought down in August
            for a maintenance turnaround expected to last several weeks,
            said the person, who asked not to be identified because the
            information isn't public. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;BP Plc (BP/), based in London, chartered the Valle Bianca to load
            clean products off the West Coast June 16 for delivery to Chile
            and chartered the Eagle Express to load fuel on June 24 for
            delivery to the South and Central America region, ship-fixture
            data compiled by Bloomberg show. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Hague-based Royal Dutch Shell Plc (RDSA) has scheduled the
            Marlin Topaz to take fuel off the coast on June 22 to Chile. The
            Atlantic Titan and the Nave Bellatrix were also chartered to
            load products in the West this week for delivery to Chile, the
            data compiled by Bloomberg show. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;California-blend gasoline, or Carbob, in Los Angeles
            advanced 4.5 cents against futures gasoline futures traded on
            the New York Mercantile Exchange to a premium of 29.5 cents a
            gallon at 4:21 p.m. New York time, the fuel's highest level for
            this season in five years, data compiled by Bloomberg show.
            Prompt-delivery surged 9.62 cents to $3.1563 a gallon. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The premium for Los Angeles Carbob versus the same fuel in
            San Francisco widened 4.5 cents to 8.5 cents a gallon, the most
            in more than five weeks. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Diesel Spreads &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;California-blend, or CARB, diesel in Los Angeles jumped 1
            cent against ultra-low-sulfur diesel futures to a premium of 3.5
            cents a gallon, the highest in four days. CARB diesel in San
            Francisco climbed 0.5 cent to 5.5 cents a gallon above futures. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Regular gasoline at pumps in California slipped 0.2 cent to
            $3.632 a gallon, according to Heathrow, Florida-based AAA, the
            nation's largest motoring organization. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Spot, conventional gasoline in Portland, Oregon,
            strengthened 0.75 cent against futures to a premium of 8.75
            cents a gallon. Low-sulfur diesel there jumped 5.5 cents against
            ULSD futures to a premium of 0.5 cent a gallon, the highest
            level in more than two weeks. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Portland gasoline's discount to Los Angeles Carbob widened
            3.75 cents to 20.75 cents a gallon. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The 3-2-1 crack spread of Alaska North Slope crude, Carbob
            in Los Angeles and CARB diesel in Los Angeles gained 21 cents to
            $26.28 a barrel. The spread, a rough measure of refining
            profits, reached a three-month high earlier this week. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Joe Carroll" datetime="Jun 13, 2014  1:21 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-13/chevron-sells-africxan-oilfield-and-pipeline-for-1-3-bln.html">
        <headline>Chevron Sells African Oilfield and Pipeline For $1.3 Bln</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp., the world's third-largest energy producer by market value, sold its stakes in an
            African oilfield and pipeline for $1.3 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron sold a 25 percent stake in an oil concession in
            southern Chad that produced about 18,000 barrels of crude daily,
            the San Ramon, California-based company said in a statement
            today. That equated to less than 1 percent of Chevron's
            worldwide output last year, according to data compiled by
            Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The transaction also involved divestiture of Chevron's
            interest in a pipeline that connects the Chadian oilfield to a
            port on Cameroon's coast. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Colin McClelland and Joe Carroll" datetime="Jun 16, 2013 12:40 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="h"
           progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-16/chevron-led-angola-lng-ships-first-cargo-after-18-month-delay.html">
        <headline>Chevron's $10 Billion Angola LNG Ships First Gas Cargo</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX)'s $10 billion Angola
            LNG plant shipped its first cargo today after an 18-month delay
            prompted by fires, labor shortages and U.S. shale drilling that
            erased demand for African fuel in the world's largest gas
            market. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The shipment of gas that was cooled to -256 degrees
            Fahrenheit (-160 degrees Celsius) to shrink its volume was sold
            to state-owned Sonangol EP for transport to Brazil aboard the
            ship Sonangol Sambizanga, Artur Pereira, chief executive officer
            of Angola LNG Marketing, said in an e-mailed statement today. A
            'large number' of LNG sales from the plant have been signed or
            are in negotiation, the London-based company said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron, the world's third-largest energy company by market
            value, has made LNG a linchpin of its goal to raise its
            worldwide output by 20 percent through the end of 2017 to the
            equivalent of 3.3 million barrels of crude a day. The company is
            spending more than $77 billion on two LNG projects in Australia,
            and in December acquired a 50 percent stake in the proposed
            Kitimat LNG terminal on Canada's Pacific Coast. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'First gas at Angola LNG is an important milestone in
            support of our strategic plan to grow our production,' George Kirkland, vice chairman of San Ramon,
            California-based Chevron,
            said in a statement distributed by Business Wire today. 'This
            project will commercialize natural gas resources in western
            Africa to meet growing demand in the region and
            internationally.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Shipments Planned &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Production at the liquefaction plant, with a capacity of
            5.2 million metric tons a year, was postponed because of fires,
            pipeline collapses and a lack of skilled workers, three people
            with knowledge of the situation said last month. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The facility in Soyo in northern Angola plans one or two
            shipments in June and July before performing checks on its
            systems and resuming output in the fourth quarter, said the
            people, who asked not to be identified because the information
            isn't public. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Global LNG demand is expected to exceed production around
            the end of this decade with the deficit growing to 100 million
            metric tons a year by 2025, Chevron Chairman and Chief Executive
            Officer John Watson said in a presentation to analysts in New
            York on March 12. Demand for the fuel will increase at an
            estimated average rate of 15 million tons a year through 2025,
            led by growth in Asian nations such as Japan, South Korea and
            Taiwan, Watson said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Reduced Flaring &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Angola LNG is entering the market at an exciting time,'
            Pereira said. 'The world LNG market is expected to remain tight
            over the coming years, with very limited new LNG capacity.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron is Angola LNG's largest shareholder with a 36.4
            percent stake. BP Plc (BP/), Eni SpA (ENI) and Total SA (FP) each hold 13.6
            percent, while Sonangol has 22.8 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Angola LNG's vision is to be a reliable and competitive
            supplier, a strong community partner, and a role model for the
            economic development of Angola,' Sonangol Chairman Antonio
            'rfao said in the same e-mail. 'The project provides a solution
            to minimize flaring and environmental pollution by gathering
            associated gas from Angola's offshore oil fields.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Angola produced 1.87 million barrels of oil a day in May,
            equal to Nigeria, according to data compiled by Bloomberg.
            Chevron and its partners built Angola LNG in part to market gas
            that otherwise would have been burned off because of the lack of
            a local demand for the fuel. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) is the world's largest energy company by
            market value, followed by PetroChina Co. (857), according to data
            compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Sarika Gangar" datetime="Jun 17, 2013  6:07 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="n" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-17/chevron-said-to-plan-four-part-bonds-in-first-sale-this-year-1-.html">
        <headline>Chevron Issues $6 Billion of Bonds in First Offering This Year</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX), the second-largest
            U.S. oil company, issued $6 billion of bonds in four parts for
            its first sale of 2013. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The company's $750 million of 0.889 percent, three-year
            notes yield 40 basis points more than similar-maturity
            Treasuries; $2 billion of 1.718 percent, five-year securities
            pay a relative yield of 65 basis points; $1 billion of 2.427
            percent, seven-year debt pay an 85 basis-point spread; and $2.25
            billion of 3.191 percent, 10-year bonds yield 100 more,
            according to data compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The company canceled plans to offer floating-rate notes due
            in 2016 and 2018, according to a person familiar with the
            transaction, who asked not to be identified citing lack of
            authorization to speak publicly. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Proceeds from the bonds, expected to be rated Aa1 by
            Moody's Investors Service, will be used to refinance commercial
            paper, the person said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron 'is finding it increasingly difficult to expand
            production and add reserves as many of the remaining pools of
            cheap, easily accessible resources' are owned by governments
            and national oil companies, David Schivell, an analyst at
            Chicago-based research firm Morningstar Inc., wrote in a note
            today. 'Still, the company maintains a rock solid balance
            sheet,' he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;November Deal &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Morningstar estimated a fair-value spread of 45 basis
            points on the new three-year bonds, 55 basis points on the five-year, 70 for the seven-year and 90 on the
            10-year, according to
            the report. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron last sold debt in November, issuing $2 billion each
            of 1.104 percent, five-year debentures at a spread of 47 basis
            points and 2.355 percent, 10-year securities at 72 basis points,
            Bloomberg data show. The bonds due December 2022 traded at 95
            cents on the dollar to yield 2.96 percent on June 11, or a
            relative yield of 75 basis points, according to Trace, the bond-price reporting system of the Financial
            Industry Regulatory
            Authority. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The average new issue concession on investment-grade bonds
            in the U.S. reached 11 basis points last week, the highest since
            the five days ended June 28, 2012, according to data from
            Barclays Plc. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Barclays, JPMorgan Chase Co., Morgan Stanley and Wells
            Fargo Co. managed the offering for San Ramon, California-based
            Chevron, Bloomberg data show. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Exxon Mobil Corp. is the largest U.S. oil company. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Marek Strzelecki" datetime="Jun 21, 2013  7:12 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-21/occupy-chevron-protesters-shale-permit-claims-denied-by-company.html">
        <headline>Occupy Chevron Protesters' Shale-Permit Claims Denied by Company</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX) said it has necessary
            approvals to begin work on a shale-gas license in Poland after
            protesters opposed to land being fenced off occupied the site. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Chevron respects the right of individuals to express
            their opinions within the law,' Grazyna Bukowska, a spokeswoman
            for the U.S. oil business's Polish subsidiary, said by e-mail.
            'Our exploration program is progressing.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Occupy Chevron (Poland) called for the second-largest U.S.
            oil company to abandon its plans and leave the land, saying on
            the group's website that the producer hadn't received approval
            to build fences on the site in the village of Zurawlow. Calls by
            Bloomberg to a phone number on the website went unanswered. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron says Poland is key for regional operations, even as
            Talisman Energy Inc. (TLM) exited last month and Marathon Oil Corp. (MRO)
            said it was seeking ways to dispose of its 11 Polish licenses. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Bradley Olson and Rodrigo Orihuela" datetime="Mar 03, 2013 12:50 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="h"
           progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-03/brazil-government-expects-chevron-to-bid-for-new-oil-blocks.html">
        <headline>Brazil Government Expects Chevron to Bid for New Oil Blocks</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Brazil's oil regulator expects
            Chevron Corp. (CVX), which suspended operations in the country last
            year after an offshore spill, to participate in an auction for
            new oil blocks this year, Magda Chambriard, head of the agency
            known as ANP, said in an interview in Houston. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The regulator also sees OGX Petroleo e Gas Participacoes as
            a model producer of gas for electricity plants ahead of a gas
            block auction in October, she said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Christie Smythe and Patricia Hurtado" datetime="Mar 04, 2014  4:13 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="h"
           progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-03-04/ecuador-judgment-against-chevron-ruled-a-fraud-by-u-s-.html">
        <headline>Chevron Wins U.S. Ruling Calling Ecuador Judgment Fraud</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX) won a U.S. judge's ruling that a multibillion-dollar pollution judgment issued
            in Ecuador was procured by fraud, making it less likely that plaintiffs will collect the $9.5 billion award.
            &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;U.S. District Judge Lewis Kaplan in Manhattan said today that the second-largest U.S.
            oil company provided enough evidence that a 2011 judgment on behalf of rain forest dwellers in the country's
            Lago Agrio area was secured by bribing a judge and ghostwriting court documents. Kaplan oversaw a seven-week
            nonjury trial over Chevron's allegations. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;'The decision in the Lago Agrio case was
            obtained by corrupt means,' Kaplan said in an opinion that gave Chevron a sweeping victory. 'The defendants
            here may not be allowed to benefit from that in any way.' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chevron, based in San Ramon,
            California, was ordered to pay $19 billion to a group of farmers and fishermen by the Ecuadorean court. The
            award was reduced to $9.5 billion on Nov. 12 by the Ecuadorean National Court of Justice, the nation's
            highest tribunal. That's almost half of its 2013 profit. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Ecuadorean villagers, and
            activists working on their behalf, argued the oil producer should be held financially responsible for
            pollution of the Amazon rainforest by Texaco Inc. from the 1960s through the early 1990s. Chevron, which
            bought Texaco in 2001, claims the company already paid $40 million to clean up its share of the drilling
            contamination. &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: David Paul Morris/Bloomberg

            &lt;p&gt;
            Chevron Corp., based in San Ramon, California, was ordered to pay $19 billion to a group of farmers and
            fishermen by the Ecuadorean court. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Christie Smythe" datetime="Mar 05, 2014  2:11 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-03-05/chevron-wins-ruling-ecuador-judgment-was-devil-s-deal.html">
        <headline>Chevron Wins Ruling Ecuador Judgment Was Devil's Deal</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;A U.S. judge handed Chevron Corp. a key victory in the energy company's long-fought battle against
            a multibillion-dollar pollution lawsuit in Ecuador, ruling the American lawyer leading the case resorted to
            bribery and fraud. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;U.S. District Judge Lewis Kaplan agreed with Chevron yesterday that
            attorney Steven Donziger had paid off a judge and engaged in money laundering to secure a $9.5 billion
            judgment from an Ecuadorean court against the global oil giant. The ruling leaves Donziger, who spent the
            past two decades fighting Chevron, with a slimmer chance of securing compensation for rain forest dwellers
            in the country's Lago Agrio area who claimed their land was turned into a toxic dumping ground for foreign
            oil interests. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The New York plaintiffs' attorney went over 'to the dark side' and made a
            'bargain with the devil,' to obtain the 2011 judgment from the court in Ecuador, Kaplan said in a 500-page
            opinion yesterday. He ruled U.S. courts can't be used to collect the award, cut in half from an original $19
            billion by Ecuador's highest court on Nov. 12. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;'The defendants here may not be allowed
            to benefit from that in any way,' the judge wrote. The ruling may also make it more difficult for Donziger
            and his clients to collect the Ecuador court's award by seizing Chevron assets outside the U.S. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Donziger would need to win a reversal of the decision on appeal in order to salvage a payday for
            himself and his clients after decades of litigation. Kaplan's detailed findings will make winning an appeal
            more difficult, said Cassandra Burke Robertson, a law professor at Case Western Reserve University in
            Cleveland who has followed the case. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;'The appellate court would have to conclude that
            the district court's finding is clearly erroneous, which is a very hard standard to meet,' Robertson said.
            'Donziger definitely has an uphill battle to seek reversal.' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Other Countries &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron, the second-largest U.S. oil company by market value, has waged a battle across multiple
            countries to prevent Donziger from collecting the award, which was almost half of its 2013 profit of $21.4
            billion. Kaplan's bar on profiting from the judgment 'applies anywhere in the world,' even though it doesn't
            stop Donziger from trying to make his case in foreign courts, Randy Mastro, a lead lawyer for Chevron, said
            yesterday in a conference call. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chevron claims Kaplan's opinion should be respected by
            courts in other countries, including Brazil, Argentina and Canada, where Chevron has assets and where
            Donziger and his team have already sued to try to collect on the judgment. The Court of Appeal for Ontario
            ruled in December that the 47 villagers have the right to pursue Chevron's Canada assets. The other cases
            are pending. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Brazil, Canada &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chevron General Counsel R. Hewitt Pate
            said yesterday that the company plans to share Kaplan's ruling with judges overseeing proceedings in Brazil,
            Argentina and Canada. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;'In view of the findings here about what really went on in this
            case, we don't think any serious court will entertain enforcement of the fraudulent judgment,' Pate said.
            &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ecuadorean villagers and activists working on their behalf had argued that Chevron,
            based in San Ramon, California, should be held financially responsible for pollution of the Amazon
            rainforest in the Lago Agrio area by Texaco Inc. from the 1960s through the early 1990s. Chevron, which
            bought Texaco in 2001, claimed the company already paid $40 million to clean up its share of the drilling
            contamination. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Secret Account &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;The case in Ecuador included 'things
            that normally come only out of Hollywood -- coded e-mails among Donziger and his colleagues describing their
            private interactions with and machinations directed at judges and a court-appointed expert,' Kaplan wrote.
            &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Donziger and his team paid off a supposedly neutral court expert from a secret account,
            promised $500,000 to a judge handling the case who was so inexperienced he used an 18-year-old typist to do
            legal research, and wrote the judgment themselves, Kaplan said. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;'Donziger began his
            involvement in this controversy with a desire to improve conditions in the area in which his Ecuadorean
            clients live,' said Kaplan, who oversaw a seven-week non-jury trial on the judgment. 'In the end, however,
            he and the Ecuadorean lawyers he led corrupted the Lago Agrio case.' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;'The length of the
            opinion gives the parties more ammunition to continue their fight,' said Robertson, the Case Western
            professor. 'I would be surprised if the ruling were upheld in full, but I think the ruling prohibiting
            Donziger from benefiting financially from the case will likely stand.' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;'Helpful' Ruling
            &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;John Watson, Chevron's chairman and chief executive officer, told reporters yesterday
            at the IHS CERAWeek energy conference in Houston that 'having a judgment like this from a reputable court in
            the United States will certainly be helpful in preventing enforcement actions elsewhere.' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chevron
            has also brought an arbitration case against Ecuador over its alleged failure to uphold agreements releasing
            predecessor Texaco from legal cases over the pollution. The arbitration in The Hague is pending. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Embassy of Ecuador said yesterday that Kaplan's ruling 'explicitly does not exonerate Chevron
            from its own legal and moral responsibilities resulting from its decades of contamination of the rainforest
            that has endangered the lives, culture, and environment of countless poor, indigenous people.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The embassy said Ecuador isn't a party in Chevron's case against Donziger. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In a
            statement, Donziger called Kaplan's ruling 'an appalling decision.' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Wrong, Wrong &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'We believe Judge Kaplan is wrong on the law and wrong on the facts and that he repeatedly let his
            implacable hostility toward me, my Ecuadorean clients, and their country infect his view of the case,' he
            said. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Donziger said he will pursue an 'immediate and expedited appeal.' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The
            lawyer has argued that he did nothing wrong in Ecuador and that any aggressive tactics he may have used were
            no worse than Chevron's actions. He said that Kaplan 'made it clear he would rule against us' well before
            the trial began by refusing a request to hold the proceeding before a jury. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Appellate
            lawyer Deepak Gupta, who joined Donziger's team after the trial concluded, said in a statement that Kaplan
            'has taken the extraordinary and unprecedented step of appointing itself a worldwide fact-finding
            commission,' issuing 'what is in effect a global anti-collection injunction.' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Appalling
            Verdict &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;'This decision also effectively outlaws core activity protected by the First
            Amendment such as bringing lawsuits, holding protests, issuing press releases, and engaging public
            officials,' he said, referencing tactics mentioned in Kaplan's decision. 'This is particularly appalling
            given that this case is about holding a corporation accountable for refusing to clean up decades of toxic
            pollution in the Amazon.' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Donziger, a Harvard Law School graduate, joined the case in a
            junior role in the late 1990s and gradually rose to a position as a strategist and fundraiser. He contends
            that Ecuador-based lawyers are now in charge of the case. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;He is 'intelligent,
            resourceful, and a master of public and media relations,' Kaplan said in the decision. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Some
            celebrities supported the campaign against Chevron, including Trudie Styler, who founded the Rainforest
            Foundation with her husband, musician Sting, and helped to start a project to make clean water available to
            forest inhabitants in Ecuador. Styler attended some of the New York court proceedings, bringing her husband
            to watch Donziger testify. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Actress Mia Farrow and actor Danny Glover also voiced support
            for the campaign, and the case was featured in a documentary, 'Crude,' by filmmaker Joe Berlinger. Chevron
            won access to hundreds of hours of outtakes from the film, which it contended showed Donziger acting
            inappropriately. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The racketeering case is Chevron Corp. v. Donziger, 11-cv-00691, U.S.
            District Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Joe Carroll" datetime="Mar 11, 2014 10:56 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="d"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-03-11/chevron-cuts-long-term-output-target-as-gas-drilling-slows-1-.html">
        <headline>Chevron Cuts Long-Term Output Target as Gas Drilling Slows</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX), the world's fourth-largest energy producer by market value, reduced its 2017
            production estimate and said it will sell $10 billion in assets
            during the next three years. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron lowered its production forecast by 6.1 percent as
            it slows U.S. natural gas drilling and higher crude prices
            reduce its share of production in some nations, the company said
            during a presentation to analysts in New York today. The company
            now sees output equivalent to 3.1 million barrels of crude a day
            from a previous estimate of 3.3 million. Last year Chevron
            produced the equivalent of 2.6 million barrels. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Lower-than-expected U.S. gas prices prompted the company to
            curtail some drilling in Pennsylvania's Marcellus Shale gas
            formation, said Chairman and Chief Executive Officer John Watson. New discoveries and acquisitions only
            added enough oil
            and gas to reserves to replace 85 percent of the company's
            production last year, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Our growth strategy remains intact, though some things
            have changed,' Watson said. Higher crude prices will also have
            a negative impact on output under production agreements in some
            nations that curb a company's share as prices escalate, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Rising Production &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron is spending $39.8 billion this year on gas-export
            terminals, offshore crude platforms and other capital projects
            to reverse a three-year drop in production. Chevron is alone
            among the world's three-largest energy companies in forecasting
            a production increase this year. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron's 2017 output target assumes crude prices will
            average about $110 a barrel, the San Ramon, California-based
            company said in a slide presentation prepared for today's
            meeting with analysts. That compares with the $79 price
            assumption that underlaid the prior forecast from March 2013. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The company plans to increase drilling in the U.S. Permian
            Basin by 8.6 percent this year to 505 wells, according to the
            slides. The company's production from the formation that
            straddles the Texas-New Mexico border will double by the end of
            2020. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Exxon Mobil Corp. is the world's largest energy producer,
            followed by Royal Dutch Shell Plc and PetroChina. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Joe Carroll and Katia Dmitrieva" datetime="May 01, 2013  7:07 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="n"
           progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-01/canadian-judge-stays-ecuadorean-claim-against-chevron-assets.html">
        <headline>Canadian Judge Stays Ecuadorean Claim Against Chevron Assets</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;A claim by a group of Ecuadorean
            villagers seeking to seize Chevron Corp. (CVX)'s Canadian assets was
            stayed by a judge in Ontario at Chevron's request. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Chevron does not possess any assets in this jurisdiction
            at this time,' Ontario Superior Court Justice David Brown said
            in a ruling today on the asset-seizure request filed in Toronto
            last year by lawyers for 47 Ecuadorean villagers. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A court in the Latin American country in 2011 found Chevron
            liable for 28 years of soil and water pollution near oil wells
            that ruined the health and livelihoods of Amazon rainforest
            dwellers. Since then, Ecuadorean farmers and fishermen have been
            trying to collect $19 billion in environmental damages from San
            Ramon, California-based Chevron, the world's third-largest oil
            company. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'The parties should take their fight elsewhere to some
            jurisdiction where any ultimate recognition of the Ecuadorian
            Judgment will have a practical effect,' Brown said in his
            ruling. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The plaintiffs are seeking enforcement outside their home
            country because Chevron has no refineries, oil wells, storage
            terminals or other properties in Ecuador. Lawyers for the Amazon
            River basin residents asked the Ontario court for a judgment
            equivalent to $18.26 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron said it was pleased with the judge's decision,
            according to a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Chevron Fight &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The plaintiffs plan to appeal, Alan Lenczner, principal
            lawyer in Toronto for the Ecuadorians, said in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'It cannot be right that a multinational company that
            operates entirely through subsidiaries is immune from the
            enforcement of a judgment in Canada, particularly where the
            subsidiary is 100 percent-owned and provides some of the
            billions of dollars that Chevron pays out in dividends each year
            and even more billions in share buybacks,' he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron has refused to pay the judgment or entertain the
            notion of settlement talks because it maintains the ruling
            resulted from bribery and fraud, charges that lawyers and a
            spokeswoman for the plaintiffs have rejected. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Brown said the plaintiffs 'have no hope of success' in
            their claim that Chevron's Canadian subsidiary should be used to
            fulfill the judgment of the Ecuadorean court. In his decision,
            the Ontario judge noted Chevron's determination to fight. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Chevron is on record saying: 'We will fight until hell
            freezes over and then fight it out on the ice.' While Ontario
            enjoys a bountiful supply of ice for part of each year, Ontario
            is not the place for that fight,' Brown wrote in his ruling.
            'There is nothing in Ontario to fight over.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Toxic Soil &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The plaintiffs have filed similar asset-seizure motions
            against Chevron in courts in Brazil and Argentina. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The 2011 judgment by a provincial Ecuadorean court blamed
            decades of toxic soil and water contamination on Texaco Inc.,
            which Chevron acquired in 2001. Texaco was found to have
            discharged into the environment saltwater and other byproducts
            of oil drilling. Texaco quit the country and its equipment was
            taken over by the Ecuadorean state oil company in 1992. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Brown stayed the plaintiffs' claim in Canada, while
            allowing them the right to try again if they obtain new evidence
            that Chevron possesses assets in the court's jurisdiction. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) is the world's biggest oil company by
            market value, followed by PetroChina Company Ltd., according to
            data compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Joe Carroll" datetime="May 02, 2014  4:16 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="d"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-05-02/chevron-first-quarter-profit-declines-on-bad-weather.html">
        <headline>Chevron's Goal of Record Output Slips as Production Drops</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX) Chairman and Chief
            Executive Officer John Watson's goal of breaking a production
            record three years from now just got harder to reach. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;After spending more than $100 million a day on average
            during the first three months of the year on new oil wells and
            other projects, Chevron posted its lowest first-quarter crude
            and natural gas output since 2006 today. The company pumped the
            equivalent of 2.59 million barrels a day during the period, 1
            percent below the average estimate of three analysts in a
            Bloomberg survey. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The output disappointment comes less than two months after
            Watson scaled back his 2017 output target to 3.1 million barrels
            a day from 3.3 million amid low gas prices that stalled some
            drilling and scant new discoveries. For Chevron, the world's
            third-largest energy company by market value, production in the
            era after its 2001 takeover of Texaco Inc. peaked at 2.78
            million a day in 2010. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'They are having to battle quite hard to get bottom-line
            production growing,' Stephen Clark, who helps manage $305
            billion, including Chevron shares, at Standard Life Investments
            in Boston, said in a telephone interview today. 'The sheer size
            of some of the projects is an issue.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Watson cited winter weather in Kazakhstan, the source of
            one in every eight barrels Chevron pumps worldwide, and a storm
            in Thailand for the production decline. 'We continue to advance
            our key development projects' that will begin boosting output
            next year, he said in a statement today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Still Viable &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Chevron-operated $10 billion Angola LNG complex in
            Africa that chills gas for shipment to overseas markets has been
            shut since a pipe failure in mid-April, Chief Financial Officer
            Pat Yarrington said during a conference call today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;An internal investigation into the incident should be
            concluded in a matter of days, she said. Yarrington didn't
            provide an expected restart date, though she said the outage
            will have a negative impact on Chevron's overall production. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Watson's 2017 goal 'still seems viable because they have a
            lot of big projects coming on,' said Stewart Glickman, an
            equity analyst at SP Capital IQ in New York who rates Chevron a
            buy and doesn't own any shares. New contributions to output will
            include fields beneath the Gulf of Mexico and off the Australian
            coast, he said in an interview today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;First-quarter net income was $4.51 billion, or $2.36 a
            share, compared with $6.18 billion, or $3.18, a year earlier,
            San Ramon, California-based Chevron said in the statement. Sales
            fell 6.1 percent to $50.98 billion. The company increased
            capital spending 5.6 percent to $9.4 billion during the quarter. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Russia Pipeline &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron is among international energy explorers caught in
            the middle of an intensifying row between the U.S. and its
            European allies on one side, and Russian President Vladimir Putin on the other. Putin put foreign oil
            companies on the spot
            on April 29 when he said they may be shut out of his country if
            their governments continue to ratchet up sanctions against
            Russian nationals and institutions. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron and its partners are in the midst of a $5.4 billion
            expansion of a pipeline that carries oil across Russia's
            Caucasus region from fields in neighboring Kazakhstan that
            account for 12 percent of the company's global supplies. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Spending, Selling &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Watson is spending almost $40 billion this year to drill
            for new discoveries and transport oil, gas and fuels such as
            diesel to markets. In tandem with exploration forays that span
            the globe from Argentina to China, Watson is overseeing $10
            billion in asset sales to narrow the company's focus on its
            highest-profit projects. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Brent crude futures, the benchmark for more than half the
            world's oil, declined by 4.2 percent to an average of $107.92 a
            barrel during the quarter, according to data compiled by
            Bloomberg. U.S. gas prices climbed 35 percent to average $4.712
            per million British thermal units during that period. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron dropped 0.2 percent to $124.72 at the close in New
            York. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Exxon Mobil Corp. is the world's largest energy company by
            market value, followed by Royal Dutch Shell (RDSA) Plc. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Patricia Hurtado" datetime="May 07, 2013  5:11 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="n" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-07/chevron-ceo-can-t-avoid-questioning-in-ecuador-fraud-case.html">
        <headline>Chevron CEO Can't Avoid Questioning in Ecuador Fraud Case</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX) lost a bid to stop Chief
            Executive Officer John Watson from being questioned by the
            attorney the company is suing over claims he committed fraud to
            win a $19 billion verdict in a pollution case in Ecuador. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;U.S. Magistrate Judge James Francis in Manhattan today
            ruled that Watson's experience in leading the 2001 Chevron-
            Texaco merger is 'likely to have given him personal knowledge
            of the environmental issues underlying the Ecuador litigation.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Francis also overruled San Ramon, California-based
            Chevron's objection to a deposition of vice president and
            general counsel Edward Scott by defendant Steven Donziger, who
            is accused in the racketeering lawsuit of improperly influencing
            a court expert whose findings were used by the Ecuador judge in
            the environmental damage case in the Amazon. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Kent Robertson, a spokesman for the company, didn't
            immediately respond to a phone call seeking comment on the
            ruling. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Donziger has denied wrongdoing and plaintiffs in the
            Ecuadorian case have said the oil company is attacking him to
            avoid responsibility for the damages. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The racketeering case is Chevron v. Donziger, 11-00691,
            U.S. District Court, District of New York (Manhattan). The case
            in Ecuador is Aquinda v. Chevron, 002-2003, Superior Court of
            Nueva Loja, Lago Agrio, Ecuador. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Ellen Rosen" datetime="May 08, 2014 12:01 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-05-08/patton-boggs-withdraws-from-chevron-case-business-of-law.html">
        <headline>Patton Boggs Withdraws From Chevron Case: Business of Law</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Patton Boggs LLP agreed to pay $15
            million to settle Chevron Corp.'s (CVX) lawsuit over the law firm's
            involvement in obtaining a $9.5 billion judgment against the oil
            company in Ecuador. Patton Boggs also agreed to withdraw from
            the Ecuador litigation. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;U.S. District Judge Lewis Kaplan in New York on March 4
            ruled that an attorney from another firm, Steven Donziger, had
            resorted to bribery and fraud in procuring the Chevron judgment
            in Ecuador that held the oil company liable for polluting the
            Amazon rain forest. Donziger is appealing the decision. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Kaplan's ruling 'includes a number of factual findings
            about matters which would have materially affected our firm's
            decision to become involved and stay involved as counsel,'
            Patton Boggs said in a statement yesterday. 'Patton Boggs
            regrets its involvement in this matter.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;On April 29, Kaplan threw out Patton Boggs's claim that San
            Ramon, California-based Chevron maliciously sued the firm for
            pursuing collection of the judgment. The law firm, which
            provided as much as $15 million to finance the Ecuador
            litigation, had sought access to $21.8 million Chevron had been
            ordered to post as a bond. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'We are pleased that Patton Boggs is ending its
            association with the fraudulent and extortionate Ecuador
            litigation scheme,' Chevron General Counsel Hewitt Pate said in
            yesterday's statement. 'Chevron encourages others to
            disassociate themselves from this fraud.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The law firm's case is Patton Boggs LLP v. Chevron Corp.,
            12-cv-09176, U.S. District Court, Southern District of New York
            (Manhattan). The racketeering case is Chevron Corp. v. Donziger,
            11-cv-00691, in the same court. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Lawsuit News &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Brookfield Loses Trial Bid Over $519,000 Arbitration Award &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Brookfield Residential Properties Inc. (BRP), a land investor in
            the U.S., lost a bid for a trial after having been ordered to
            pay $519,000 to Zephyr Equities Development LLC in an
            arbitration for breach of contract, according to statements from
            the companies and their lawyers. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Zephyr accused Brookfield of violating a contract to
            develop the 2,000-acre Natomas Project in Sacramento County,
            California, according to a statement from Zephyr yesterday. An
            arbitrator ruled in favor of Zephyr in April 2013, and a
            California superior court judge signed the judgment in February,
            according to the statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Bauer denied Brookfield's request for a new court
            proceeding and also awarded Zephyr the right to 3.1 percent of
            gross sales from the Natomas development, Zephyr said.
            Brookfield has appealed the ruling, the companies said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Fortunately, justice has prevailed,' Adina T. Stern, a
            Zephyr attorney, said in the statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Brookfield spokesman Andrew Willis said in a statement that
            the company will appeal the ruling. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The case is Zephyr v. Brookfield Natomas, 30-2013-00648089-CU-JR-CJC, Superior Court of California
            (Orange County). &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;West Hollywood Fur-Sale Ban Survives Luxury Retailer's Lawsuit &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;West Hollywood, California's ban on fur sales, hailed by
            the Humane Society of the United States as the first in the
            nation, survived a federal court challenge by a luxury retailer. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The city's ban doesn't illegally discriminate against
            retailers of new clothing by allowing sales of used fur by
            private parties and second-hand stores, U.S. District Judge
            George H. King in Los Angeles said in a ruling. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The ordinance went into effect last year and Mayfair House
            Inc., a retailer of high-end clothing, sued. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Michael O'Connor, a lawyer for Mayfair House, didn't
            immediately respond to an e-mail seeking comment on the ruling. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The case is Mayfair House Inc. v. City of West Hollywood,
            13-cv-07112, U.S. District Court, Central District of California
            (Los Angeles). &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Moves &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;UBS Names Crowl as General Counsel for Americas &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Michael Crowl will join UBS AG (UBSN) as general counsel for the
            Americas region and wealth management Americas on July 1. Crowl
            previously worked at Barclays Plc (BARC), where he held roles including
            general counsel, Americas. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Andrew Zajac and Tom Schoenberg" datetime="May 09, 2013  2:07 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="h"
           progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-09/chevron-wins-suit-against-u-s-over-california-oil-field.html">
        <headline>Chevron Wins Suit Against U.S. Over California Oil Field</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX) is entitled to
            unspecified damages against the federal government in a contract
            dispute over oil deposits in California worth $37 billion, the
            U.S. Court of Claims ruled. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Department of Energy 'repeatedly and materially
            violated' two agreements governing determination of equity
            interests in oil and gas deposits located in the Elk Hills
            Reserve of California, Judge Susan Braden in Washington wrote in
            a 90-page ruling. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron 'is entitled to be compensated for damages, in an
            amount to be determined, including sanctions for DOE and the
            government's 'bad faith' conduct and abusive discovery
            tactics,' Braden wrote in the ruling made public yesterday. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron filed the suit in 2004 after failing to agree on
            the exact split of its joint holdings in the Elk Hills facility
            with the Energy Department. The company and the government
            operated the field together for more than 50 years, and had
            agreed to proceed with the sale of the government's stake to
            Occidental Petroleum Corp. (OXY) while they worked out the holdings. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Steven Thai, an Energy Department spokesman, referred calls
            for comment to the Justice Department. Allison Price, a Justice
            Department spokeswoman, didn't immediately respond to an e-mail
            message seeking comment. Donald Campbell, a spokesman for San
            Ramon, California-based Chevron, didn't immediately respond to
            an e-mail message seeking comment on the ruling. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Elk Hills &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Elk Hills Field, located near Bakersfield, California,
            encompasses more than 47,000 acres and includes more than 1,000
            wells, a 47-megawatt power plant and two units that process gas.
            The government's share in the field of about 78 percent, which
            is still being disputed by Chevron, is estimated to hold
            reserves equal to about 1 billion barrels of oil. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Occidental Petroleum bought the government's stake in Elk
            Hills, one of the largest remaining oil fields outside Alaska,
            for $3.65 billion in 1997. That's about $3.65 for each barrel of
            oil-equivalent it contains. Chevron and Occidental are not
            operating the oil and gas field together. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The sale of the interest in Elk Hills reserve, set aside in
            the early 1900s for emergency military use by the U.S. Navy, was
            the largest government asset sale ever at the time. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In her ruling, Braden ordered the government to reimburse
            Chevron for 42 percent of its legal fees for two years,
            beginning in February 2007, as a sanction for 'bad faith'
            litigation tactics involving the production of documents. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The case is Chevron USA Inc. v. U.S., 04-1365, U.S. Court
            of Federal Claims (Washington). &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Adam Williams" datetime="May 12, 2014  4:05 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-05-12/chevron-seeks-pemex-partnerships-to-explore-for-oil-in-mexico.html">
        <headline>Chevron First Major Oil Producer Seeking Pemex Partnerships</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp., the world's third-largest energy company by market value, became the first major
            international oil producer to reveal partnership plans with
            state-run Petroleos Mexicanos since Mexico signed landmark
            legislation to reopen its doors to foreign producers. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron, (CVX) which operates several rigs on the U.S. side of
            the Gulf of Mexico, is in talks with Mexico City-based Pemex for
            exploration opportunities in deepwater, shallow water or shale,
            Ali Moshiri, Chevron's president of Latin America and Africa,
            said today during a conference in Mexico City. Chevron produces
            more crude in the U.S. section of the Gulf of Mexico than anyone
            except Royal Dutch Shell Plc and BP Plc, according to the U.S.
            Interior Department. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'We are not here to replace Pemex,' said Moshiri, who
            oversees exploration and production projects from Argentina to
            Angola. 'We are not here to change their strategy. We are here
            to complement what they are doing.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron, based in San Ramon, California, is waiting for the
            passage of Mexico's secondary energy legislation before deciding
            the sites of the first partnerships in Mexico. The legislation,
            which will determine Pemex's participation in new projects and
            the tax structure for private companies joining the newly opened
            energy market, could be approved as soon as June, according to
            Mexico's two largest political parties. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Investment Options &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Mexico passed an energy law last year that ended Pemex's
            75-year production monopoly to allow for private firms to tap
            the country's 13.44 billion barrels of proven oil reserves.
            Private investment is anticipated to generate an additional $30
            billion annually and create as many as 2 million jobs, Mexico's
            energy ministry has said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'We look for the opportunity that brings the most value to
            the Mexican government, the Mexican people, and our
            shareholders,' Moshiri said. 'We are a huge company. We can
            invest money in conventional, deepwater, or shallow water. What
            drives our decision is really to see what is the best for
            everybody.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Exxon Mobil Corp. and Royal Dutch Shell Plc are the world's
            first- and second-biggest energy companies by market value.
            Pemex and Exxon signed a technical collaboration agreement last
            year before the energy law was approved by President Enrique
            Pena Nieto in December. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'We are going to align our strategic direction in Mexico
            with Pemex,' Moshiri said. 'Our future in Mexico is based on
            building this exisiting partnership.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron added 0.2 percent to close $125.24 in New York. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Pablo Gonzalez" datetime="May 14, 2013  6:17 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-14/chevron-ypf-to-sign-1-5-billion-deal-to-develop-shale-in-july.html">
        <headline>Chevron, YPF to Sign $1.5 Billion Deal to Develop Shale in July</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX) will become the first
            major oil company to partner with YPF SA to develop shale oil
            and a final deal is expected in July, YPF said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Miguel Galuccio, chief executive officer of YPF, and Ali Moshiri, Chevron's head of Latin America,
            Middle East and
            Africa, visited the Patagonia shale formation today and met with
            Neuquen's governor Jorge Sapag, according to an e-mailed
            statement today from the Buenos Aires-based company. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Jim Craig, a spokesman for San Ramon, California-based
            Chevron, didn't immediately replied to a call and an e-mail
            seeking comment. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Moshiri, who in December signed with Galuccio an exclusive
            right to negotiate final terms for YPF to transfer a 50 percent
            interest in Loma de la Lata Norte and Loma Campana, was
            'surprised' with the advanced state of YPF exploration
            projects, according to the statement. The fields for the $1.5
            billion joint venture comprise an area of 290 square kilometers
            (180 miles) in southwestern Argentina. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Along with Chevron, we will constitute the first joint
            venture to develop shale,' Galuccio said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;YPF is pumping 7,000 barrels a day, according to the e-mailed press release. Vaca Muerta, which
            means 'dead cow' in
            Spanish, holds at least 23 billion barrels of oil equivalent,
            according to a report by independent auditor Ryder Scott
            released in February 2012 by YPF. Argentina holds the world's
            third-largest shale gas reserves, according to US Energy
            Administration data. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>

    <entry author="By Pablo Gonzalez" datetime="May 16, 2013  1:50 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-16/chevron-says-shale-to-help-make-argentina-energy-independent-2-.html">
        <headline>Chevron Says Shale to Help Make Argentina Energy Independent</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX), the second-biggest
            U.S. oil company, said it's preparing an investment that will
            help make the country energy independent by developing what
            could be the world's second-largest shale oil reservoir. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Some people think China is the second-largest shale
            oil,' Ali Moshiri, Chevron's head of Latin America, Middle East
            and Africa, told reporters yesterday in Buenos Aires. 'I
            believe after the U.S., Vaca Muerta holds the largest shale oil
            in terms of reserves,' he said, referring to a formation in
            southwestern Argentina that translates to Dead Cow. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Moshiri spoke along with Miguel Galuccio, chief executive
            of state-owned YPF SA, after signing a contract establishing
            terms for a definitive agreement that will start with a $1.5
            billion investment and may reach as much as $15 billion. The San
            Ramon, California-based company first agreed to the partnership
            in December. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Now it is the time for finalizing details as there are no
            significant commercial issues between the two companies,'
            Moshiri said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Both executives declined to provide details of production
            targets and capital expenditures. The final accord may be
            completed as early as July as two teams of six members each are
            writing the fiscal terms and other covenants, they said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;YPF gained 1.7 percent to 121 pesos at 2:45 p.m. in Buenos
            Aires. The stock earlier rose as much as 8.3 percent to 128.90.
            Chevron added 0.07 percent to $123.09 in New York. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Frozen Assets &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Once we sign the deal, we will immediately allocate a
            large sum of money to take the investment to the next level,'
            Moshiri said. 'We are going to provide whatever YPF asks to
            reach the target.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Moshiri said Chevron is spending $150 million a year even
            while an embargo linked to an Ecuadorean lawsuit froze 40
            percent of its accounts in Argentina. The lawsuit against
            Chevron stems from a $19 billion award for pollution in Ecuador. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Chevron will continue reinvesting all the money it makes
            in Argentina,' Moshiri said, declining to elaborate how the
            company will avoid having its funds seized. 'At the end of the
            day the right decision will be made by the people in Argentina,
            the government and the judiciary system.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Argentine President Cristina Fernandez de Kirchner's
            government seized a 51 percent YPF stake from Spain's Repsol SA (REP)
            in April 2012 to stem fuel imports that doubled to $9.4 billion
            in 2011 and are expected to rise to as much as $15 billion this
            year. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Repsol Lawsuit &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Another legal dispute threatening the agreement is a suit
            filed in November in Madrid by Repsol against the U.S. company.
            The Repsol lawsuit is an issue between shareholders, Galuccio
            said. 'There is a lot of goodwill from both sides to reach an
            agreement, nevertheless, as YPF CEO I couldn't comment
            further,' he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Repsol is open to a negotiation that includes liquid
            assets as compensation,' Kristian Rix, a spokesman for the
            Madrid-based company, said today by telephone from Madrid. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Galuccio and Moshiri said they would only discuss the
            future of Vaca Muerta now that YPF has cut well costs in half to
            $7.5 million apiece. On May 14, the two executives visited YPF's
            shale operations, which has 35 operating rigs and is expecting
            to receive four more this week. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;YPF said it's pumping 7,000 barrels of oil a day, up from
            4,000 in January. Vaca Muerta may hold at least 23 billion
            barrels of oil equivalent, according to a report by independent
            auditor Ryder Scott released in February 2012 by YPF. Argentina
            holds the world's third-largest shale gas reserves, according to
            U.S. Energy Information Administration data. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'If you look at Vaca Muerta in the future, in 30, 40
            years, you will be looking at a factory drilling operation,'
            Galuccio said. 'We are working on industrializing the process
            as that will be the key for Argentina to develop those resources
            we have on the ground.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Adam Williams and Pablo Gonzalez" datetime="May 23, 2014  3:24 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="h"
           progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-05-23/argentina-turns-to-next-shale-partners-as-chevron-triples-output.html">
        <headline>Argentina Turns to Next Shale Partners as Chevron Triples Output</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Petroliam Nasional Bhd. is among a
            group of producers looking to enter Argentina's nascent shale
            boom, according to state-owned oil company YPF SA. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Petronas, as Malaysia's state oil and gas company is known,
            is negotiating a binding deal with YPF to develop an area in
            southwestern Argentina's Vaca Muerta shale formation after
            signing a preliminary accord Feb. 18, Doris Capurro, YPF's
            director of communications, said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'We are continuing conversations' with Petronas, Doris
            Capurro, YPF's communications director, said in an interview in
            La Jolla, California yesterday. 'They are very interested in
            what we are doing in Vaca Muerta, like many other companies we
            are holding talks with.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Argentina is seeking partners to develop Vaca Muerta, an
            area the size of Belgium that holds at least 23 billion barrels
            of oil, according to a survey by Ryder Scott, in a bid to become
            energy independent. YPF's output from the Loma Campana area in
            Vaca Muerta rose to 12,800 barrels a day from 4,200 after
            investing $1.2 billion in a pilot year with Chevron Corp. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The company, which President Cristina Fernandez de Kirchner
            expropriated from Spain's Repsol SA in 2012, is also in
            conversations with Petroleos Mexicanos, Capurro said, without
            disclosing the subject of the talks. Mexico is pushing through
            legislation to open up its oil and gas fields, including shale,
            to foreign investment. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;New Find &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Petronas's preliminary deal is to develop a 187-square
            kilometer (72 square-mile) area called La Amarga Chica in
            Neuquen province, northwest of Loma Campana, where the Chevron
            pilot may become a $16 billion project. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;YPF announced this week its first unconventional discovery
            outside of Vaca Muerta at El Trebol in the D-129 formation. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Capurro called for changes to Argentina's 1967 hydrocarbons
            law to cater to offshore and unconventional operations and
            greater environmental protection demands. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'The company thinks some rules of the game should be
            revised to include shale,' she said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>

    <entry author="By Jose Orozco" datetime="May 27, 2013  5:35 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-27/chevron-lends-venezuelan-oil-venture-2-billion-for-output-boost.html">
        <headline>Chevron Lends Venezuelan Oil Venture $2 Billion for Output Boost</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Petroleos de Venezuela SA, the
            country's state-owned oil producer, signed a $2 billion
            financing agreement with San Ramon, California-based Chevron
            Corp. (CVX) to increase output at their Petroboscan oil joint venture. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The loan's interest rate is the London Interbank Offered
            Rate plus 4.5 percentage points, Oil Minister Rafael Ramirez
            told reporters in Caracas today. The money will be handled
            directly by Petroboscan and will help boost daily output to
            127,000 barrels from 107,000 barrels, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'The loan has a very low rate because it's a corporate
            loan from Chevron to its joint venture and is tied to increased
            production,' said Ramirez, who signed the credit along with Ali Moshiri, Chevron's head of Latin America,
            Middle East and
            Africa. 'That way we obligate ourselves and our partner to
            focus on increasing production.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Venezuela, which channels oil earnings into social programs
            and regional fuel subsidies, is seeking financing from foreign
            partners to tap more of the world's largest oil reserves. The
            state-owned producer reached an agreement with China on terms of
            a $4 billion loan on May 15 for the Sinovensa joint venture with
            China National Petroleum Corp. Ramirez said today he'll sign the
            financing agreement in Beijing this week. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The minister said May 3 that PDVSA would invest $15.4
            billion in exploration and production this year and that its
            partners must meet production targets or risk having projects
            disbanded. Ramirez said last month that PDVSA would ask its
            partners to finance at least $8 billion of a $25 billion
            investment program. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Venezuela is producing 830,000 barrels a day in western oil
            fields, Ramirez said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Benjamin Elgin" datetime="May 29, 2014  5:00 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-05-29/chevron-retreats-on-clean-energy-after-renewables-hit-20-margin.html">
        <headline>Chevron Retreats on Clean Energy After Renewables Hit 20% Margin</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;In January, employees of Chevron (CVX)'s
            renewable power group, whose mission was to create large,
            profitable clean-energy projects, dined at San Francisco's
            trendy Sens restaurant. Managers applauded them for almost
            doubling their projected profit in 2013, the group's first full
            year of operations. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The mood quickly turned somber. Despite the financial
            results and the team's role in helping start more than a half-dozen solar and geothermal projects capable of
            powering at least
            65,000 homes, managers told the group that funding for the
            effort would dry up, and encouraged staffers to find jobs
            elsewhere, say four people who attended the dinner, Bloomberg
            Businessweek reports in its June 2 issue. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;For the past eight years, Chevron Corp. has promoted
            'profitable renewable energy' as a core component of its
            business plan. The company's slogan, 'Finding newer, cleaner
            ways to power the world,' is splashed across its website. And
            ads begun in 2010 as part of Chevron's 'We Agree' campaign
            declare, 'It's time oil companies get behind the development of
            renewable energy.' Yet Chevron recently has retreated from key
            efforts to produce clean energy. This includes the renewable
            power group, which invested in or built utility-scale solar and
            geothermal projects with margins of 15 percent to 20 percent or
            more, according to a dozen people who worked on them. &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

            &lt;p&gt;
            Chevron Corp. Chief Executive Officer John Watson. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Joe Carroll" datetime="Nov 01, 2013  8:42 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="d"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-01/chevron-third-quarter-profit-misses-estimates-on-refining.html">
        <headline>Chevron Third-Quarter Profit Misses Estimates on Refining</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX), the second-largest
            U.S. energy producer by market value, reported third-quarter
            profit below estimates as weaker refining margins eroded gains
            from higher commodity prices and output from wells. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Net income was $4.95 billion, or $2.57 a share, compared
            with $5.25 billion, or $2.69, a year earlier, the San Ramon,
            California-based company said in a statement today. The per-share result was 13 cents lower than the $2.70
            average of 21
            analysts' estimates compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron warned in an Oct. 9 statement that quarterly profit
            had been eroded by 'significantly lower' earnings in its so-called downstream business, which includes
            refining and filling
            stations. Maintenance work at the company's El Segundo,
            California, refinery mostly offset an increase in fuel
            production at a separate Chevron plant near San Francisco,
            according to the statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chairman and Chief Executive Officer John S. Watson is
            spending $36.7 billion this year in a push to raise oil and
            natural gas production by 1.5 percent to the equivalent of 2.65
            million barrels of oil a day. The capital spending budget
            represents a 7.3 percent increase from 2012. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron's stock has increased 11 percent this year,
            outperforming the company's bigger U.S. rival, Exxon Mobil
            Corp. (XOM), which has gained less than 3 percent. Today's statement
            was released before the opening of regular U.S. stock trading.
            Chevron fell 0.3 percent to $119.96 in New York yesterday. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Joe Carroll" datetime="Nov 01, 2013 11:53 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-01/chevron-to-sell-oilfields-as-new-exploration-prospects-acquired.html">
        <headline>Chevron To Sell Oilfields as New Exploration Prospects Acquired</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. plans to sell some oil
            and natural-gas assets as newly-acquired exploration prospects
            in places such as Iraq, Canada and Australia take precedence.
            Some of the new projects may move to the top of the San Ramon,
            California-based company's development queue because they
            promise richer returns, Chief Financial Officer Pat Yarrington
            said during a conference call with analysts today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Christie Smythe" datetime="Nov 05, 2013  3:32 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-05/ecuador-judge-says-19-billion-chevron-ruling-was-his-own.html">
        <headline>Ecuador Judge Says $19 Billion Chevron Ruling Was His Own</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;A former Ecuadorean judge who issued
            a $19 billion pollution ruling against Chevron Corp. told a U.S.
            court that he worked alone on the case and denied the company's
            allegation that his decision was ghostwritten. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Nicolas Zambrano, the former judge, testified in a trial in
            federal court in Manhattan today that the only help he received
            in preparing his 188-page ruling issued in 2011 came from an
            18-year-old secretary who typed his dictation and conducted
            Internet research for him. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron claims in a racketeering case before U.S. District
            Judge Lewis Kaplan that the plaintiffs in the environmental case
            won the ruling through bribery and fraud. The San Ramon,
            California-based energy company alleges that Zambrano and
            another former Ecuadorean judge, Alberto Guerra, were bribed to
            steer the case in favor of the plaintiffs and the $19 billion
            judgment was actually written by the plaintiffs and Guerra. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'No one has helped me to write the judgment,' Zambrano
            said through a translator today when questioned by a lawyer for
            Chevron, Randy Mastro. 'I was the one who explicitly drafted
            it.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The former judge, who also served as a prosecutor in
            Ecuador, said he spent 'many hours, many days' on the ruling.
            He was unable to answer questions Mastro asked about specifics
            in the judgment, such as the identity of a substance that had
            been described in the document as 'the most powerful
            carcinogenic agent' and information described as 'statistical
            data of the highest importance to delivering this ruling.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Internet Research &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;After Zambrano said he couldn't read or speak English or
            French, Mastro asked how he had managed to cite U.S., Australian
            and French legal authorities in the judgment. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'As I stated in my deposition, the young woman who would
            help me type the judgment, she was the one going on the
            Internet' and she 'chose the Spanish option,' Zambrano said.
            'That is how I would become aware or informed of the subject I
            was interested in. She would print them so I could read them
            later.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Guerra testified Oct. 23 that Zambrano routinely paid him
            to ghostwrite rulings in his cases, including the Chevron
            ruling. Guerra also said that Zambrano had been promised
            $500,000 by the plaintiffs from the proceeds of the judgment and
            had told Guerra he could also get a share. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Draft Orders &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Zambrano testified that Guerra aided him in preparing
            drafts of court orders, although not in the Chevron case.
            Zambrano denied paying Guerra for his help. He previously has
            denied accepting bribes to issue a ruling in favor of the
            plaintiffs. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron, the second-largest U.S.-based energy firm, claims
            that lawyers for the plaintiffs, led by Manhattan attorney
            Steven Donziger, engaged in a scheme to extort money from the
            company during a 20-year legal battle over pollution in an
            Ecuador oil concession. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The company is seeking an order barring lawyers for the
            Ecuadoreans from trying to enforce the 2011 pollution judgment
            in countries where Chevron has assets. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Guerra now lives in the U.S. and receives $12,000 per month
            from Chevron along with other benefits through at least 2015
            under an agreement with the company. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Drilling Wastes &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In the environmental case, Donziger and other lawyers for
            indigenous people in Ecuador's Lago Agrio region sought damages
            for Texaco Inc.'s alleged dumping of toxic drilling wastes from
            1964 until about 1992. The lawsuit continued against Chevron
            when it acquired Texaco in 2001. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron contends that state-owned Petroecuador, a former
            Texaco joint-venture partner, is responsible for most of the
            pollution and that Texaco already paid to clean up its share. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Donziger claims he did nothing illegal in Ecuador and that
            his tactics were no different from Chevron's. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The racketeering case is Chevron Corp. (CVX) v. Donziger, 11-cv-00691, U.S. District Court,
            Southern District of New York
            (Manhattan). The appeals court case is In Re Naranjo, 13-00772,
            U.S. Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit (Manhattan). &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Dan Murtaugh, Lananh Nguyen and Eliot Caroom" datetime="Nov 15, 2013  9:46 AM ET"
           feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-15/chevron-refinery-fire-in-mississippi-leaves-one-person-dead.html">
        <headline>Chevron Refinery Fire in Mississippi Leaves One Person Dead</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX) had a furnace fire in
            the 'cracking 2 area' at its Pascagoula refinery in
            Mississippi that caused the death of one worker. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The fire occurred at 2 a.m. local time at the 330,000-barrel-a-day plant on Mississippi's Gulf
            Coast, Kurt Glaubitz, a
            San Ramon, California-based spokesman for the company, said in
            an e-mailed statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The cracking 2 unit has been shut, Terry Jackson, Jackson
            County deputy director of emergency services, said by phone. The
            rest of the refinery isn't shut, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Refinery personnel responded to the fire and secured the
            site, Glaubitz said. He wouldn't say if the fire has been
            extinguished, nor whether any portion of the refinery has been
            shut down in response. Allison Cook, a Pascagoula-based
            spokeswoman for the company, identified the location of the fire
            in a message on a community hot line. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The refinery produces 130,000 barrels of gasoline, 68,000
            barrels of diesel and 50,000 barrels of jet fuel a day,
            according to a company website. It also produces bunker fuel,
            liquefied petroleum gases and other products. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The plant processes heavy, high-sulfur crude. In August, it
            imported 278,000 barrels of oil a day from Brazil, Canada,
            Colombia, Mexico and Venezuela. Two of its shipments from
            Colombia were the highest-density crudes imported to the U.S.
            that month, according to Energy Information Administration data. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>

    <entry author="By Chris Dolmetsch and Christie Smythe" datetime="Nov 26, 2013  3:35 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s"
           progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-26/chevron-claims-trial-showed-proof-of-fraud-in-ecuador.html">
        <headline>Chevron Claims Trial Showed Proof of Fraud in Ecuador</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX) asked a federal judge
            in New York to find that a racketeering plot was behind a
            multibillion-dollar pollution verdict against the company handed
            down by an Ecuadorean court. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Closing arguments began today in Manhattan after six weeks
            of trial in which the company claimed lawyers for the plaintiffs
            in the Ecuador environmental case bribed judges and drafted much
            of the actual ruling. Steven Donziger, a New York attorney
            accused of leading the scheme, has denied allegations of
            wrongdoing and maintained the judgment is valid. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Randy Mastro, a lawyer for Chevron, the second-largest U.S.
            energy company, argued to U.S. District Judge Lewis Kaplan that
            the evidence showed the pollution ruling was a fraud. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'One thing has always been certain: this judgment was
            ghostwritten by these plaintiffs,' Mastro told Kaplan today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Mastro said 'strings of words' from Donziger's e-mails
            and sequences of numbers from an internal database that appear
            verbatim in the judgment show the plaintiffs' influence. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'This is like not even fingerprints,' Mastro said. 'This
            is like 10 fingers, both palms. Their internal work product
            shows up word for word in the document because they wrote it
            themselves.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Toxic Waste &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Donziger and a team of other lawyers won the $19 billion
            judgment in 2011 on behalf of Ecuadorean rainforest villagers
            who claimed Texaco, later bought by Chevron, dumped billions of
            gallons of drilling-generated toxic waste from the 1960s through
            the early 1990s. The award was cut in half on Nov. 12 by the
            Ecuadorean National Court of Justice, the nation's highest
            tribunal. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Richard Friedman, an attorney representing Donziger, said
            many of Donziger's statements from e-mails and documents have
            been taken out of context. The case is bigger than Donziger and
            the thousands of Ecuadoreans who will be affected by the ruling,
            Friedman said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'They'll be looking to see if American courts will follow
            their own rules of law,' Friedman said. 'They'll be looking to
            see if there are special exceptions, special rules for large
            American corporations. What he's accomplished by legitimate, yet
            noisy, boisterous, unconventional ways, has caused people around
            the world to look with fresh eyes at how our corporations treat
            the Third World.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Lead Adviser &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron, based in San Ramon, California, has refused to pay
            any of the judgment and is seeking an order from Kaplan barring
            Donziger from trying to enforce it. The company claims Texaco
            already cleaned up its share of the damage. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Donziger, a Harvard Law School graduate originally from
            Jacksonville, Florida, got involved in the Ecuadorean case in
            the 1990s and became its lead adviser. He contends that his role
            has since diminished and Ecuadorean lawyers are now in charge. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;He said in written testimony that the pollution judgment is
            'a profound historical accomplishment of indigenous and farmer
            communities in securing justice for wrongs inflicted upon them
            by one of the most powerful corporations on the planet.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;If the ruling can be upheld in a country where Chevron has
            assets to seize, Donziger stands to collect as much as $600
            million, he acknowledged in court on Nov. 18 under questioning
            by Mastro. Donziger has also been paid during the litigation,
            receiving $150,000 in one year while the lead Ecuadorean lawyer
            on the team, Pablo Fajardo, received just $24,000, Mastro said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Making Money &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Mastro, the Chevron lawyer, said today that Donziger's
            testimony about his smaller role in the case is contradicted by
            the fact that he makes 'six or seven times' more than Fajardo. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'In every business I've ever been in the boss makes more
            money,' Mastro told the judge. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'To him the ends came to justify the means, the methods
            didn't matter,' Mastro said. 'He set about to make the big
            score and set his sights on Chevron.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;So far, the team working on behalf of the plaintiffs have
            filed enforcement actions in Canada, Brazil and Argentina.
            Canada, in particular has 'a history of giving respect to
            foreign judgments' and is a country where oil companies have
            'very substantial assets,' Donziger said in an interview with
            journalists Nov. 15. Chevron has no physical assets in Ecuador. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Two Judges &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Two former Ecuadorean judges who handled the pollution case
            also testified during the trial: Nicolas Zambrano, who issued
            the ruling, and his former colleague Alberto Guerra. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Guerra told the court that he regularly drafted rulings for
            Zambrano, who wasn't as experienced at handling civil cases. He
            testified that he and his colleague were promised proceeds from
            the judgment to throw the case in the plaintiffs' favor. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Guerra, now living in the U.S. and receiving $12,000 a
            month from Chevron, said he helped write the 188-page judgment
            against the company based on materials from the plaintiffs. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Zambrano denied he was bribed. He told the court that while
            Guerra regularly helped him draft some rulings, he worked on the
            Chevron ruling with help only from an 18-year-old assistant. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Mastro said today in his closing argument that Zambrano
            lied on the stand when he denied paying Guerra to help with the
            judgment and denied being bribed to write the ruling in favor of
            the plaintiffs. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Weak Judiciary &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'He couldn't admit that he was paid to ghostwrite the
            judgment,' Mastro said. 'He admitted too much and he lied way
            too much.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron filed its racketeering case against Donziger after
            pre-trial information exchanges produced materials that included
            hundreds of hours of outtakes from a 2009 documentary on the
            Ecuador case called 'Crude,' by filmmaker Joe Berlinger. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron alleged the material showed Donziger discussing
            ways to take advantage of Ecuador's weak judiciary. Donziger
            said the outtakes were edited by Chevron and that some of his
            statements were taken out of context. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Supporters of Donziger's efforts include Trudie Styler,
            wife of musician Sting, who helped start a project to provide
            clean water for the rainforest dwellers. The couple watched
            Donziger testify in Manhattan federal court Nov. 18. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The racketeering case is Chevron Corp. v. Donziger, 11-cv-00691, U.S. District Court, Southern
            District of New York
            (Manhattan). &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Harry R. Weber" datetime="Oct 05, 2013  3:19 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-10-05/chevron-resuming-gulf-of-mexico-operations-as-karen-weakens.html">
        <headline>Chevron Resuming Gulf of Mexico Operations as Karen Weakens</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX) began returning workers
            to shuttered Gulf of Mexico operations and Anadarko Petroleum
            Corp. said it expected to follow suit as Tropical Storm Karen
            weakened off Louisiana. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;San Ramon, Calif.-based Chevron, which produces oil and gas
            from the Tahiti and Blind Faith fields and has a stake in the
            Perdido development, said on its website at 1 p.m. Eastern time
            today that it would be resuming normal operations. It didn't say
            how long that would would take. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The storm 'doesn't seem to be as significant as was once
            thought, but we're still monitoring the situation,' Vincent
            Piazza, a Princeton, New Jersey-based oil production analyst for
            Bloomberg Industries, said today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;He said it was unclear how long the disruptions would last. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Anadarko (APC), based in The Woodlands, Texas, halted production
            and cleared employees from the Independence Hub and the Neptune,
            Constitution and Marco Polo platforms. Workers on the latter two
            may return later today, John Christiansen, a spokesman at
            Anadarko's headquarters, said by e-mail. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Other companies with Gulf operations, including London-based BP Plc (BP/), the largest leaseholder
            in the deepwater there,
            kept energy production offline. Those producers and refiners
            planned to remobilize as conditions allowed. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Almost 62 percent of Gulf oil production, some 866,000
            barrels of oil per day, and 48 percent of natural gas output, or
            1.8 billion cubic feet daily, was offline today, according to
            the U.S. Bureau of Safety and Environmental Enforcement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;BP Operations &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;BP secured wells being drilled by rigs it operates in the
            Gulf. The company also halted production at all four of its
            platforms there -- Thunder Horse, Atlantis, Na Kika and Mad Dog
            -- and evacuated non-essential workers. Royal Dutch Shell Plc (RDSA)
            cut rates at Louisiana and Alabama plants. BHP Billiton Ltd. (BHP),
            Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM), Marathon Oil Corp. (MRO) and the Williams Cos. (WMB) were
            also among the companies curbing energy output. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The storm, with top winds holding at 40 mph (60kph), was
            130 miles south-southwest of Morgan City, Louisiana, as of 2
            p.m. New York time and had stalled, the National Hurricane
            Center said in an advisory. Karen would be downgraded to a
            tropical depression if sustained winds drop below 39 mph, which
            the National Hurricane Center said will probably occur tomorrow. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Energy markets expect the storm to be 'kind of a blip,'
            resulting in short-lived supply disruptions, Dave Hackett,
            president of consulting firm Stillwater Associates, in Irvine,
            California, said yesterday. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;'Lessons Learned' &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'There were a lot of lessons learned from Hurricane
            Katrina and subsequent storms,' he said. 'A big tropical storm
            is wet, but don't think it'll do any serious damage.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Gasoline futures for November delivery slid 3.2 cents, or
            1.2 percent, to $2.6076 a gallon yesterday on the New York
            Mercantile Exchange, the lowest settlement since December. Oil
            gained 0.5 percent, and natural gas rose 0.2 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Shell cut rates at its 85,000-barrel-a-day plant in Mobile,
            Alabama, and Motiva Enterprises LLC reduced output at the
            250,000-barrel-a-day Norco, Louisiana, refinery because of
            shipment delays caused by Karen, Shell said on its website
            yesterday. Motiva is a joint venture of Shell and Saudi Aramco. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Shell, based in The Hague, also was removing some
            nonessential personnel from drilling operations in the eastern
            Gulf, the company said on its website. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Valero Energy Corp. (VLO), Marathon Petroleum Corp. (MPC), Chevron and
            other refinery operators said they were monitoring the storm and
            hadn't cut production. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Four Platforms &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;London-based BP's four deepwater platforms have a combined
            capacity to produce 660,000 barrels of oil and 990 million cubic
            feet of natural gas a day, according to BP's website. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Marathon halted output and evacuated all workers from its
            Ewing Bank platform 130 miles south of New Orleans, the Houston-based company said on its website. The
            company said it shut in a
            total of 18,000 barrels of oil equivalent a day. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Melbourne, Australia-based BHP ceased production and
            evacuated its Gulf of Mexico facilities, Jaryl Strong, a
            spokesman for the company, said by e-mail yesterday. Williams
            shut and evacuated the Canyon Station, Devils Tower and Blind
            Faith platforms in the eastern Gulf of Mexico, the company said
            on its website yesterday. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Destin Pipeline LLC, which can transport 1.2 billion cubic
            feet of gas a day from the Gulf, declared force majeure Oct. 3,
            saying in a notice to shippers that it's incapable of providing
            services from its offshore receipt points because of the storm. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Enbridge Inc. (ENB)'s Manta Ray and Mississippi Canyon gas
            pipeline systems in the Gulf also declared force majeure. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;LOOP LLC, the only U.S. port capable of offloading ultra-large crude carriers, suspended tanker
            operations, the
            Covington, Louisiana-based company said in a statement on its
            website. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Christie Smythe" datetime="Oct 07, 2013  2:57 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-10-07/chevron-s-ecuador-defendants-denied-jury-trial-by-court.html">
        <headline>Chevron's Ecuador Defendants Denied Jury Trial by Court</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX) won a request to have a
            judge rather than a jury decide its case over alleged fraud in
            an Ecuadorian pollution verdict. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;U.S. District Judge Lewis Kaplan in Manhattan ruled today
            that the Ecuadorians and their legal adviser, Steven Donziger,
            don't have a constitutional right to a jury trial because the
            San Ramon, California-based company isn't seeking damages. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Defendants argue that they are entitled to a jury as a
            matter of fairness,' Kaplan said. 'But that argument -- even
            if it had merit, which it does not -- is beside the point.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron, the second-largest U.S. oil firm, alleges that
            Donziger and others, in a case over pollution in the Ecuadorian
            jungle, won a $19 billion verdict against the company by fraud.
            A trial in the lawsuit is scheduled for Oct. 15. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The trial was initially set to be held in two parts, with
            damages being sought only against Donziger and his firm and not
            the Ecuadorian plaintiffs in the environmental suit. Chevron
            dropped its damages claim against the legal adviser and said it
            no longer wanted a jury trial. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A jury in a civil case is guaranteed only if the plaintiff
            is seeking damages, Kaplan wrote. Otherwise, parties must agree
            to it, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Residents of Ecuador's Lago Agrio area near the Colombian
            border have sought damages for about 20 years for pollution in
            the Amazon rainforest that they allege was caused by Texaco
            before it was acquired by Chevron. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Wrongdoing Denied &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron denies there was any wrongdoing by it in Ecuador and
            claims that Texaco cleaned up its share of the pollution at its
            former oil fields, which were taken over by state-owned
            PetroEcuador. The U.S. company also said that it was released
            from future liability by an agreement between Texaco and
            Ecuador. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The company is seeking to bar the Ecuadorians from enforcing
            the verdict and disgorgement of any gains they won as a result
            of the alleged fraud. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The racketeering case is Chevron v. Donziger, 11-cv-00691,
            U.S. District Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan).
            The appeals court case is In Re Naranjo, 13-00772, U.S. Court of
            Appeals for the Second Circuit (Manhattan). &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>

    <entry author="By Joe Carroll" datetime="Oct 09, 2013  5:28 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="d"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-10-09/chevron-says-third-quarter-profit-hit-by-refinery-maintenance.html">
        <headline>Chevron Says Third-Quarter Profit Hit by Refinery Maintenance</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX), the world's third-largest energy producer by market value, said quarterly
            profit
            was lower than the prior three-month period amid refinery
            repairs and foreign-exchange losses. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Downstream earnings, which includes refining and retail
            operations, are expected to be 'significantly lower' than the
            second quarter, the San Ramon, California-based company said in
            a statement today. The third quarter also includes almost $300
            million in foreign-exchange losses, compared with the prior
            quarter that included a similar sized gain, the company said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron's wells produced the equivalent of 2.589 million
            barrels of oil a day in July and August, compared with 2.516
            million a day during the full third quarter of 2012. Increased
            fuel production at its Richmond, California, refinery was mostly
            offset by maintenance work at its El Segundo, California, plant,
            Chevron said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The company is scheduled to release complete third-quarter
            results on Nov. 1. The shares fell 1.3 percent to $114.63 at
            5:08 p.m. in after-hours trading in New York. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Exxon Mobil Corp. is the largest energy company by market
            value, followed by PetroChina Co., according to data compiled by
            Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Christie Smythe and Patricia Hurtado" datetime="Oct 15, 2013  7:58 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s"
           progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-10-15/chevron-claims-ecuadorians-lawyer-won-case-through-fraud.html">
        <headline>Chevron Lawyer Takes Stand in Trial Over Ecuador Verdict</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;A Chevron Corp. (CVS) attorney testified that he was charged with bogus crimes in a scheme to shake
            down the oil producer and obtain a $19 billion judgment in Ecuador. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Ricardo Reis Veiga,
            a senior managing counsel for the second-largest U.S. oil company, was the first witness called by Chevron
            in a trial that the company says will show that the Ecuadorean verdict was fraudulently obtained by lawyers
            who operated a racketeering enterprise. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In Veiga's testimony, portions of which were
            made public today, he said he and a colleague faced charges in the 1990s over their handling of a cleanup
            settlement for a drilling site in the Ecuadorean rain forest. The charges were dropped in 2011. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'I experienced an unimaginable nightmare, ranging from stress, anger, pain and frustration from
            having to face such accusations,' Veiga said in written testimony filed with U.S. District Judge Lewis
            Kaplan. Veiga also took the stand today in federal court in Manhattan to answer further questions. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Randy Mastro, a lawyer for Chevron, told Kaplan today that the verdict was obtained by fraud,
            coercion, extortion, money laundering and the bribery of the Ecuadorean judge who wrote it. In the U.S.
            case, the San Ramon, California-based company is seeking an order from Kaplan barring enforcement of the
            2011 pollution judgment. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;'Racketeering Enterprise' &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mastro pointed
            to the Ecuadoreans' lead lawyer, Manhattan attorney Steven Donziger, and said he headed a 'racketeering
            enterprise' that included two other attorneys, consultants, activists and others to 'shake down' the oil
            producer. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;'That's what Steven Donziger was trying to do against Chevron -- coerce a big
            payday against a big company until the pain went away,' Mastro said. 'But Chevron refused. It refused to be
            extorted and defrauded and that's why we're here today.' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The company wants to stop
            Donziger and his associates from trying to enforce the verdict in courts around the world where Chevron has
            assets, Mastro said. Plaintiffs have sued Chevron for payment in Canada, Argentina and Brazil without
            success. Donziger could collect as much as $1.2 billion if the judgment is collected in full, Mastro said.
            &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In the underlying 20-year-old environmental case, Donziger and other lawyers for
            indigenous people in Ecuador's Lago Agrio region sought damages for Texaco Inc.'s alleged dumping of toxic
            drilling wastes from 1964 until about 1992 that polluted about 1,500 square miles (3,885 square kilometers).
            The lawsuit continued against Chevron when it acquired Texaco in 2001. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;New Paradigm
            &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chevron contends that state-owned Petroecuador, a former Texaco partner, is responsible
            for most of the pollution. Texaco paid $40 million to clean up its share and was released from liability
            under agreements with Ecuador in 1995 and 1998, Chevron said. An international arbitration tribunal affirmed
            the accords' validity in September. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;'This is a new paradigm,' Mastro said. 'It's fraud
            and extortion and they're trying to force a payoff. If they do, it will be open season on U.S. companies.'
            &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Richard Friedman, a lawyer for Donziger, today denied his client had committed any
            bribery and wrongdoing and said he had worked to hold Chevron accountable for polluting the rain forest,
            comparing his client to U.S. civil rights leaders. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;'Like Thurgood Marshall, like Ralph
            Nader, like a host of human rights lawyers before him, Mr. Donziger understood you need legal and social
            change,' Friedman told the judge. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;'Wasn't Pretty' &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Friedman argued
            that Donziger had taken up the cause of indigenous Ecuadoreans who were mistreated and discriminated
            against, and had successfully persuaded the Ecuadorean courts to hold Chevron responsible for its actions.
            &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;'It wasn't pretty but it wasn't bribery,' Friedman said. 'He's changed the way people
            think. He's here today because of that judgment.' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Nicolas Zambrano, the judge who signed
            the Ecuadorean judgment in favor of the Lago Agrio plaintiffs, will testify on Donziger's behalf, Friedman
            said. Zambrano, who is no longer a judge, submitted a declaration denying he had been bribed. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Mastro said today the trial also will feature another Ecuadorean judge, Alberto Guerra, who
            presided over the Chevron pollution case before Zambrano. Guerra has submitted a declaration stating that
            Donziger and another lawyer bribed Zambrano to decide the case in favor of the Ecuadoreans and permitted
            them to ghostwrite the opinion which Zambrano signed. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;'One Half' &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Friedman
            said that Chevron also tried to bribe one of the Ecuadorean judges to disrupt the environmental case. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'What Chevron is asking is you hear one half of what happened in Ecuador and not hear the other
            half,' he said. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chevron contends that advocates for the Ecuadoreans, guided by Donziger,
            'sought to inflict maximum damage to Chevron's reputation.' The effort got more than $10 million in
            financing from Philadelphia lawyer Joseph Kohn and U.K.-based investment firm Burford Capital Ltd. (BUR),
            according to the company. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Burford sold its interest in the litigation in 2010, it said
            in July. Kohn was dropped from the litigation and criticized Donziger in an August 2010 letter uncovered by
            Chevron. He didn't respond to a phone call seeking comment on the trial. Mastro said today that Kohn and a
            second man who helped finance the Ecuadorean litigation would testify as witnesses for Chevron. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;'Green Issue' &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Donziger's team ran a media campaign that helped to secure an
            article in Vanity Fair's May 2007 'Green Issue' and the filming of the 2009 documentary 'Crude' by Joe
            Berlinger, featuring villagers stricken with cancer, birth defects and other diseases alleged to be related
            to exposure to toxins from Texaco's drilling, according to Chevron. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;While the film
            highlighted the pollution battle, it also gave Chevron evidence for its fraud case. In May 2010, Kaplan
            ruled that the company could have hundreds of hours of outtakes from 'Crude.' Using the footage, excerpts
            from Donziger's diary and other materials obtained through U.S. court orders, the company asserts that
            Donziger's team pressured environmental consultants and helped draft a report that inflated damages to $27
            billion. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Donziger's team used an 'army of protesters' to intimidate the judge and met
            with him frequently outside of court, Chevron alleged. The plaintiffs' lawyers also hatched 'trumped up'
            criminal charges to bring against Chevron lawyers in Ecuador, the company said. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Supervised
            Litigation &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Veiga said today in court that he supervised Chevron's litigation in the
            Ecuadorean case and updated the company about it. He told the judge in filed testimony that he also oversaw
            Texaco's settlements with Ecuador releasing the company from further liability. He was charged with
            falsifying settlement documents and environmental crimes, he said. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;'I suspected that the
            representatives of the Lago Agrio plaintiffs, including Donziger, were colluding with the Republic of
            Ecuador' to bring the charges, he said in the filing. 'I did not realize at the time, however, the
            unimaginable extent of the collusion.' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In a Nov. 17, 2005, diary entry, Donziger wrote
            that two of his associates 'were scouring the penal code to find any provision that could be used against'
            Veiga, according to a court filing. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Donziger Diary &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Chevron
            contends Donziger's diary shows that he was trying to wage a crusade to shake billions of dollars out of the
            company. In an April 4, 2007, entry, Donziger called his co-litigants 'fellow soldiers' and mused about the
            possibility of obtaining a settlement from Chevron. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;'I sit back and dream,' he wrote. 'I
            cannot believe what we have accomplished. Important people interested in us. A new paradigm of not only a
            case, but how to do a case. Chevron wanting to settle. Billions of dollars on the table. A movie, a possible
            book. I cannot keep up with it all.' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A Harvard Law School graduate, Donziger has argued
            that Chevron took comments from the 'Crude' footage out of context and that his team was following customary
            procedures in Ecuador. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In materials distributed to reporters at the trial,
            representatives for Donziger called the racketeering proceeding a 'rigged show trial designed to allow the
            overwhelming power of one of America's largest corporations to crush a single individual who played an
            instrumental role in holding the company accountable for its abuses abroad.' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Christopher
            Gowen, a spokesman for Donziger, said the lawyer didn't 'trump up' charges against Chevron attorneys and
            that they 'earned these inquiries by the way they treated the people of Ecuador.' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Donziger
            Countersuit &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Donziger alleged in counterclaims that Chevron manipulated testing at the
            pollution site, tried to influence Ecuador's government and unfairly attacked his reputation. Kaplan
            dismissed Donziger's countersuit in July, saying he didn't present strong enough evidence. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Last
            month, Donziger and his associates failed in a bid to replace Kaplan as the judge overseeing the trial
            claiming he's biased in favor of the company. A three-judge panel of the U.S. Court of Appeals in Manhattan
            rejected the request on Sept. 26. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Kaplan refused to delay the trial while the appeals
            court considered the request, saying it lacked merit. The judge also sanctioned Donziger and his
            co-defendants for withholding documents from Chevron during pretrial information sharing. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The
            case is Chevron Corp. (CVX) v. Donziger, 11-cv-00691, U.S. District Court, Southern District of New York
            (Manhattan). The appeals court case is In Re Naranjo, 13-00772, U.S. Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit
            (Manhattan). &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Christie Smythe" datetime="Oct 17, 2013 12:01 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-10-17/chevron-ecuador-lawsuit-financier-tells-judge-of-regrets.html">
        <headline>Chevron Ecuador Lawsuit Financier Tells Judge of Regrets</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;One of the financiers of an
            environmental lawsuit that led to a $19 billion verdict against
            Chevron Corp. in Ecuador told a judge that he came to regret
            funding the case once after learning that it may be a fraud. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Burford Capital LLC Chief Executive Officer Christopher Bogart told a Manhattan federal judge
            yesterday that his firm,
            which he described as the world's largest dedicated litigation
            financing provider, supplied $4 million to the Ecuadorean
            plaintiffs and later sold the share when it became 'deeply
            concerned about the mounting evidence of fraud and misconduct.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron alleges in the non-jury trial before U.S. District
            Judge Lewis Kaplan that a Manhattan lawyer, Steven Donziger, and
            others involved in the pollution case engaged in a
            'racketeering enterprise' and won the 2011 verdict through
            coercion, manufactured evidence and bribery of the Ecuadorean
            judge who wrote it. The company is seeking a ruling preventing
            the plaintiffs from trying to enforce the verdict in courts
            around the world. Burford reached an agreement with Chevron to
            provide testimony after being described in the lawsuit as a
            party involved in the scheme, Bogart said yesterday. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Donziger contends he did nothing unlawful in Ecuador and
            that Chevron engaged in similar tactics. Kaplan said in a ruling
            last week there's 'considerable evidence' the pollution case
            was 'tainted by fraud.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In a portion of testimony filed with the judge, Bogart said
            'we simply do not countenance in any way the kind of behavior
            this court has already found has occurred' and 'we never would
            have invested' in the case if they were aware of the allegedly
            fraudulent activities. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;$15 Million &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Burford is a U.S. unit of Croydon, U.K.-based Burford
            Capital Ltd. (BUR), which has more than $300 million in capital,
            according to Bogart's testimony. The firm negotiated with U.S.
            law firm Patton Boggs LLP, which also represented plaintiffs in
            the Ecuador case, to provide as much as $15 million in
            financing, Bogart said. Following an initial investment of $4
            million in November 2010, Burford sold its share in 2011 to
            another investor and provided no further funding, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;By the end of January 2011, 'I think we had probably
            reached the point in the investment by which we would have been
            happier not to have made it,' he said in court yesterday. 'But
            we had made it.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In the underlying 20-year-old environmental case, Donziger
            and other lawyers for indigenous people in Ecuador's Lago Agrio
            region sought damages for Texaco Inc.'s alleged dumping of toxic
            drilling wastes from 1964 until about 1992 that polluted about
            1,500 square miles (3,885 square kilometers). The lawsuit
            continued against Chevron when it acquired Texaco in 2001. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron contends that state-owned Petroecuador, a former
            Texaco partner, is responsible for most of the pollution and
            that the U.S. company already cleaned up its share of the site
            under agreements with Ecuador in the 1990s. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;'Maximum Damage' &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In its February 2011 complaint, San Ramon, California-based
            Chevron contended that advocates for the Ecuadoreans, guided by
            Donziger,'sought to inflict maximum damage to Chevron's
            reputation.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'That's what Steven Donziger was trying to do against
            Chevron -- coerce a big payday against a big company until the
            pain went away,' Randy Mastro, a lawyer for the oil company,
            said in court Oct. 15. Donziger stands to collect as much as
            $1.2 billion if the judgment is paid in full, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The company alleged that the team pressured environmental
            consultants and helped draft a report that inflated damages to
            $27 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A former expert for the plaintiffs, David Russell,
            testified yesterday that he provided a $6.114 billion damages
            estimate based 'largely on assumptions Donziger told me to
            use.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;'Wildly Inaccurate' &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Within a year of working for Donziger, I came to learn
            that my cost estimate was wildly inaccurate and had no
            scientific data to back it up,' he said in written testimony
            submitted to the judge. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Russell said he asked Donziger not to use the figure after
            learning it was cited in the plaintiffs' publicity campaign and
            in a letter to the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission.
            Donziger ignored the request and continued to use the number,
            Russell said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Donziger alleged in counterclaims that Chevron manipulated
            testing at the pollution site, tried to influence Ecuador's
            government and unfairly attacked his reputation. Kaplan
            dismissed Donziger's countersuit in July, saying he didn't
            present strong enough evidence. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The case is Chevron Corp. (CVX) v. Donziger, 11-cv-00691, U.S.
            District Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). The
            appeals court case is In Re Naranjo, 13-00772, U.S. Court of
            Appeals for the Second Circuit (Manhattan). &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>

    <entry author="By Lynn Doan" datetime="Oct 29, 2013 12:26 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="n" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-10-29/chevron-el-segundo-said-to-delay-unit-shutdowns-until-late-april.html">
        <headline>Chevron El Segundo Said to Delay Unit Shutdowns Until Late April</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX)'s El Segundo complex,
            the largest single refinery on the U.S. West Coast, delayed
            maintenance on crude and coker units to late April, a person
            familiar with the schedule said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Work on the coker originally set for January will begin in
            the last week of April and is expected to last about two months,
            said the person, who asked not to be identified because the
            information isn't public. Repairs on the No. 4 crude unit will
            start at the same time and take about three weeks, according to
            the person. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Rod Spackman, a spokesman for Chevron in El Segundo, didn't
            immediately respond to e-mailed and phoned requests for comment. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The El Segundo refinery can process 279,000 barrels of
            crude a day, data compiled by Bloomberg show. The plant supplies
            40 percent of the jet fuel to the Los Angeles International
            Airport and has a 20 percent share of the Southern California
            gasoline market, the company's website said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Other equipment including a naphtha hydrotreater and a
            sulfur recovery unit are also scheduled to shut for repairs
            during the turnaround, according to the person. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron is planning to replace six coke drums at the El
            Segundo refinery that arrived from Spain in late January, the
            company's website said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The plant receives about 50,000 barrels a day of its oil by
            pipeline from fields in California and 225,000 barrels a day by
            tanker, the company's website shows. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Rebecca Penty" datetime="Sep 01, 2013  3:55 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-09-01/chevron-natural-gas-pipeline-leaks-in-gulf-of-mexico-nrc-report.html">
        <headline>Chevron Natural Gas Pipeline Leaks in Gulf of Mexico: NRC Report</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX) leaked an unknown
            quantity of natural gas from a pipeline in the Gulf of Mexico
            near Pascagoula, Mississippi, according to a report filed Aug.
            30 with the U.S. National Response Center. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;An investigation was under way by a dive team according to
            the report, filed at 5:24 p.m. local time on Aug. 30. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Bloomberg News couldn't immediately verify the information
            in the filing was accurate. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Kurt Glaubitz, a Chevron spokesman, didn't immediately
            respond to an e-mail inquiry today, outside of normal business
            hours. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Ben Elgin" datetime="Sep 02, 2014  4:27 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="n" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-02/chevron-makes-it-official-with-sale-of-renewable-energy-unit.html">
        <headline>Chevron Makes It Official With Sale of Renewable-Energy Unit</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt; Sept. 2 (Bloomberg Businessweek) -- Chevron has finalized
            the sale of its renewable-energy subsidiary, Chevron Energy
            Solutions, to OpTerra Energy Services, a Chevron spokesman
            confirmed today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The sale, on Aug. 29, marks the latest in a series of moves
            away from renewables by the oil company. Earlier this year,
            Chevron sold a 48-person division that builds renewable projects
            and energy-savings retrofits for federal agencies such as the
            U.S. Department of Defense. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;OpTerra is backed by Oaktree Capital Management, a private
            equity firm in Los Angeles, according to OpTerra's website. It
            develops energy-savings projects, as well as clean-energy systems
            from technologies like solar and fuel cells. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Bloomberg Businessweek first reported the expected sale of
            Chevron's clean-energy subsidiary in June. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron declined to comment on the price of the transaction
            or the number of its employees moving to OpTerra. The company
            said in a statement that the sale 'is part of an internal
            strategic focus on supporting Chevron's Upstream and Downstream
            businesses. Chevron continues to believe that energy efficiency
            and renewable energy are an important part of the overall energy
            mix, and operates a portfolio of renewables, including wind,
            geothermal and solar.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A spokeswoman for Oaktree Capital declined to comment. An
            OpTerra representative previously declined to comment about the
            transaction and didn't respond to a new request for comment
            today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Energy Solutions was first acquired by the oil
            company in 2000 and has long been a centerpiece of Chevron's
            efforts to pursue renewable energy. A decade after acquiring the
            division, Chevron boasted that the group had developed hundreds
            of renewable and energy-efficiency projects that were 'reducing
            greenhouse gas emissions by more than 3 million metric tons.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In addition, Chevron executives frequently touted the
            division's clean-energy work in speeches and in testimony (PDF)
            before Congress. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Last month, though, Chevron confirmed that it had suspended
            two solar projects at a refinery in Hawaii, which would have
            spanned about 20 acres and reduced carbon dioxide emissions by
            about 5,000 tons apiece. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;And earlier this year, the company dismantled a renewable
            power group whose mission was to launch large, profitable
            clean-energy projects, Bloomberg Businessweek reported in May.
            The group had almost doubled its internal profit targets in 2013,
            while helping to launch solar and geothermal projects capable of
            powering tens of thousands of homes.&lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Andrew Noel" datetime="Sep 04, 2014  4:10 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="n" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-04/solvay-buys-chevron-phillips-car-plastics-unit-for-220-million.html">
        <headline>Solvay Buys Chevron Phillips Car-Plastics Unit for $220 Million</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Solvay SA (SOLB) agreed to buy a
            performance polymers business from Chevron Phillips Chemical Co.
            for $220 million to expand its offering of lightweight plastics
            for replacing heavier metal parts in cars. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The purchase of Ryton polyphenylene sulphide plants will
            also increase Solvay's exposure to the electronic-materials
            industry, where polymers are used to enhance the fire-resistance
            of components, Brussels-based Solvay said today in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Belgian chemical maker said it's looking to exploit the
            full potential of Chevron Phillips technology as car
            manufacturers increasingly use lightweight components to boost
            fuel efficiency. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Ryton PPS fits neatly with our unique specialty polymers
            portfolio and reinforces our unrivalled capabilities to provide
            solutions to our customers in dynamic innovative end-markets,'
            Augusto Di Donfrancesco, president of Solvay Specialty Polymers,
            said in the statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Solvay will gain Ryton PPS sites in Texas and Oklahoma, and
            a plant in Belgium. Solvay plans to invest in a PPS production
            technology developed by Chevron Phillips that hasn't 'achieved
            its full potential,' the company said. Completion of the deal
            is expected in the fourth quarter. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Phillips, equally owned by subsidiaries of Chevron
            Corp. and Phillips 66 (PSX), is headquartered in The Woodlands, Texas. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Patricia Hurtado" datetime="Sep 09, 2013  8:13 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-09-09/chevron-waives-some-claims-in-ecuador-pollution-case.html">
        <headline>Chevron Won't Seek Money From Ecuadorians in U.S. Lawsuit</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX) said it won't seek
            money damages against two Ecuadorians it sued in a New York
            racketeering case claiming the pair committed fraud to win a $19
            billion verdict in a pollution case in their country. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The oil company also asked that the trial, set to begin
            next month in federal court in Manhattan, be held in two parts,
            one before a jury and a second before a judge. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron, the second-largest U.S. oil company, was ordered
            to pay as much as $19 billion in compensatory and punitive
            damages for Texaco Inc.'s alleged dumping of toxic drilling
            wastes in the Ecuadorean jungle from 1964 to about 1992. The
            ruling came in an 18-year-old case decided by a judge in Lago
            Agrio, a provincial capital near the Colombian border. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The company sued in federal court in New York in 2011
            accusing Ecuadorians who were named plaintiffs in the case and
            their lead legal adviser, Steven Donziger, of improperly
            influencing a court expert in the case in Lago Agrio and
            committing fraud to win the judgment. U.S. District Judge Lewis Kaplan in New York, who is presiding over
            the case, scheduled an
            Oct. 15 trial. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The San Ramon, California-based oil company said it won't
            seek money damages against the two Ecuadorians, and that a jury
            should determine liability claims against Donziger and his law
            firm. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;'Extensive Evidence' &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Chevron has uncovered extensive evidence that the 2011
            Ecuadorian judgment was fraudulently obtained by the Lago Agrio
            plaintiffs,' Morgan Crinklaw, a company representative, said in
            an e-mail. 'However, their international campaign to
            enforcement that judgment has not gained much traction to date.
            The equitable relief Chevron continues to seek against the
            Lago Agrio plaintiffs will enable us to protect our assets, and
            those of our subsidiaries, from being seized by the Lago Agrio
            plaintiffs or in their name.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Kaplan today rejected a request by Donziger and two of the
            individual plaintiffs in the Ecuadorean suit to delay the trial
            pending a decision by the Manhattan-based U.S. Court of Appeals. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Oral arguments are to be heard Sept. 26 on Donziger and the
            Ecuadorians' request that the court remove Kaplan from the case
            and cancel several orders he issued. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Kaplan said that Donziger had failed to request a delay
            pending the appeals court's decision soon enough. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'The motion to delay the trial is without merit,
            represents a radical change in defendants' nominal position
            (though it is entirely consistent with a years-old strategy of
            delay wherever possible), and comes far too late,' he said.
            'Notwithstanding their attempts to portray themselves as
            Davids, each alone facing Goliath, the reality is quite
            different.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron asked that a jury determine what, if any,
            compensatory and punitive monetary damages should be paid by
            Donziger and asked Kaplan to determine what other remedies
            should be imposed. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Phase Two &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The company asked the judge to decide in a second phase of
            the trial whether the Ecuadorians and Donziger should be barred
            from further harming Chevron and to issue an order that protects
            its assets. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The company also requested that the Lago Agrio plaintiffs
            be prohibited from making what it called prejudicial statements
            about 'alleged environmental issues in Ecuador.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron denies there was company wrongdoing in the Lago
            Agrio lawsuit, saying Texaco cleaned up its share of the
            pollution at its former oil fields, which were taken over by
            PetroEcuador, Ecuador's state-owned oil company. Chevron said it
            was released from any future liability by an agreement between
            Texaco and Ecuador. Chevron acquired Texaco in 2001. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The racketeering case is Chevron v. Donziger, 11-00691,
            U.S. District Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan).
            The case in Ecuador is Aquinda v. Chevron, 002-2003, Superior
            Court of Nueva Loja, Lago Agrio, Ecuador. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Jeremy van Loon" datetime="Sep 12, 2014 11:16 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="n" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-12/chevron-needs-partner-agreements-before-moving-on-kitimat-lng.html">
        <headline>Chevron Needs Partner, Agreements Before Moving on Kitimat LNG</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX) needs to find a
            partner, secure natural gas contracts and assess engineering
            costs before making a decision on its Canadian liquefied natural
            gas project in Kitimat. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron is continuing to work with aboriginal groups in the
            area on the northwestern coast of British Columbia and doing
            initial work on the site, said Chief Executive Officer John Watson, in a briefing in Calgary with reporters
            today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'We've seen pressure on LNG projects around the world,'
            he said. 'We have an advantaged resource in the Horn River
            basin, but the costs are very high. You have to have good
            alignment with partners.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron is one of a handful of companies considering
            exporting natural gas from British Columbia. The Canadian
            province is closer to Asian markets than some competing parts of
            the world including the U.S. Gulf Coast, and demand for energy,
            including LNG, continues to grow, Watson said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;At the moment, LNG projects 'moving ahead' are those in
            the Gulf Coast where existing infrastructure makes them easier
            to develop, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Bryan Bradley" datetime="Sep 16, 2013  8:49 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-09-16/lithuania-regulates-shale-gas-works-as-chevron-tender-advances.html">
        <headline>Lithuania Regulates Shale-Gas Work, Chevron Tender Advances</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Lithuania strengthened
            environmental restrictions for using shale-gas and shale-oil
            technologies as a state body recommended the Baltic country
            issue a first license for such work to Chevron Corp. (CVX) &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;New regulations, among other things, require an
            environmental impact study and public consultations before
            exploration can start, the Environment Ministry in Vilnius said
            on its website. It said a tender commission today suggested the
            government grant rights to the U.S. energy company's local unit
            because 'legally no other decision is possible.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron submitted the only bid in a January tender for
            shale-hydrocarbon exploration and production rights in the
            western Lithuanian region of Silute-Taurage. The country wants
            to develop shale resources as an alternative to energy imports
            from Russia. Some local communities oppose the technology as
            environmentally unsafe. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Chevron hopes that its work helping Lithuania find and
            utilize hydrocarbon resources will facilitate the country's goal
            of energy security,' Chevron Exploration Production Lietuva
            UAB said of the tender commission's decision in a statement on
            ELTA news service. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Once the government names Chevron the winner of the tender,
            the company will have 30 days to pay the price it offered for
            the license and confirm it's still interested, Environment
            Minister Valentinas Mazuronis said in an interview on Sept. 5. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Lithuania plans to revise a law that currently taxes
            proceeds from shale-gas production at a rate of 25 percent, news
            portal Vz.lt cited Mazuronis as saying today. The minister said
            a 40 percent tariff proposed to parliament was too high and the
            government would seek a compromise somewhere between that and
            the current rate, Vz.lt reported. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron last year bought half of the Lithuanian oil and gas
            recovery company LL Investicijos, which holds a license to
            explore in Rietavas, an area contiguous to the Silute-Taurage
            block, according to the company's Lithuanian website. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Joe Carroll" datetime="Sep 16, 2014  6:08 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-16/chevron-s-search-for-alternative-fuels-stumps-best-minds.html">
        <headline>Chevron's Search for Alternative Fuels Stumps Best Minds</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX)'s attempts to turn plants into alternative fuels for profitable, large-scale
            production have failed. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The second-largest U.S. oil company by market value spent
            'significant sums' and assigned some of its best scientists to evaluate more than 100 kinds of feedstock and
            50 techniques for converting them into fuels without success, Chevron Chairman and Chief Executive Officer
            John Watson said during an address to the Economic Club of Minnesota in Minneapolis today. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;'The
            smartest minds in my company and others haven't yet cracked the code on pairing the right feedstock
            conversion technology and logistics in an economic and scalable package,' Watson said. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Major
            crude producers from Chevron to BP Plc have been scaling back investment in renewables to focus on
            higher-profit ventures such as deep-water oil wells. Chevron's setbacks echo those of Exxon Mobil Corp.
            (XOM), which last year said its $600 million foray into algae-based fuel may not succeed for another 25
            years. BP put $3.1 billion of wind assets for sale last year after withdrawing from solar in 2011. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron sold an energy-efficiency unit last month that had been losing money for half a decade,
            Watson said. The company remains dedicated to other forms of renewables such as geothermal and continues to
            pursue research into some types of biofuels, Watson told reporters after his speech. Chevron's plants
            research focused on non-food crops, he said. &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: Patrick Fallon/Bloomberg

            &lt;p&gt;
            Corn is unloaded from trucks into the grain elevator in Missouri, U.S. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Lynn Doan" datetime="Sep 19, 2014  3:10 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="n" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-19/chevron-hires-investment-bank-to-sell-kapolei-refinery-in-hawaii.html">
        <headline>Chevron Seeking Buyer for Kapolei Oil Refinery in Hawaii</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX), the world's third-largest oil producer by market value, is seeking a buyer for
            one
            of its smallest refineries, the Kapolei plant on the Hawaiian
            island of Oahu. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The sale of the the 54,000-barrel-a-day Kapolei complex is
            part of a larger plan to divest $10 billion worth of assets over
            the next three years. Closing the plant would leave Hawaii with
            a single 93,500-barrel-a-day refinery, which Par Petroleum Corp. (PARR)
            bought from Tesoro Corp. (TSO) last year. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron shares were up $1.03, or 0.8 percent, at $125.17 at
            2:42 p.m. New York time. Par Petroleum Corp., which operates the
            only other plant in Hawaii, gained 6 percent to $16.58. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron 'has decided to engage an investment banking firm
            to identify potential parties interested in the purchase of our
            assets in Hawaii,' Braden Reddall, a spokesman at Chevron's
            headquarters in San Ramon, California, said by telephone late
            yesterday. 'No decision has been made at this time other than
            to determine the level of interest of potential buyers.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Deutsche Bank has been hired by Chevron, two people with
            direct knowledge of the situation said, while asking not to be
            identified because the information isn't public. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Al Chee, a Chevron spokesman at the refinery, declined by
            telephone to comment. Ari Cohen, a spokesman for Deutsche Bank
            in New York, declined by e-mail to comment. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Fourth-Smallest &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron previously considered turning the Kapolei complex
            into a terminal. After a review three years ago, the company
            decided to continue to run it as a refinery. It's Chevron's
            fourth-smallest by capacity, data compiled by Bloomberg show. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Selling the refinery in 2011 was 'not as competitive' as
            improving its value, Michael Wirth, Chevron's executive vice
            president of downstream and chemicals, said in a conference call
            with analysts at the time of the review. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Everybody realizes that's a small refinery,' he said.
            'It's not an especially complex refinery. It's got a somewhat
            isolated and finite market. And so we're really in the space of
            optimizing every dimension of performance there.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The refinery ran 39,000 barrels a day in 2013, down from
            46,000 in 2012, the company said in its 10-K annual report. Last
            year, the plant imported 87 percent of its oil from Indonesia,
            Thailand and Vietnam, Energy Information Administration data
            show. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, Chevron extended a supply contract with
            Hawaiian Electric Co. Inc. for low-sulfur fuel. Meanwhile, Par
            Petroleum said it was losing its contracts with the utility in
            December and was 'aggressively pursuing other outlets.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Exxon Mobil Corp. and Royal Dutch Shell Plc are the two
            largest oil producers. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Christie Smythe and Bob Van Voris" datetime="Sep 26, 2013  7:16 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="n"
           progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-09-26/chevron-argues-against-judge-switch-in-case-over-ecuador.html">
        <headline>Chevron Argues Against Judge Switch in Case Over Ecuador</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;A group of Ecuadorians lost a bid
            to remove a U.S. judge set to oversee a trial over Chevron
            Corp. (CVX)'s claims that a $19 billion pollution verdict against it
            in the South American country was obtained fraudulently. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron, the second-largest U.S. oil company, today won a
            decision from the U.S. Court of Appeals in Manhattan rejecting
            the Ecuadorians' attempt to have a new judge take up the case
            and to reverse several orders by the current judge. The three-judge appeals panel issued its ruling just
            hours after hearing
            arguments over the matter. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Theodore Olson, a lawyer for the San Ramon, California-based company, argued today that U.S.
            District Judge Lewis A. Kaplan has been 'comprehensive' and 'thorough,' and that a
            switch would be a waste of resources. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'That remedy they seek is utterly unwarranted,' he said
            of the Ecuadorians' request. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Residents from the country's Lago Agrio area near the
            Colombian border have sought damages for about 20 years for
            pollution in the Amazon rainforest that they allege was caused
            by Texaco. Chevron, which bought Texaco in 2001, claims the
            Ecuadorians and their legal adviser, Steven Donziger, improperly
            influenced a court in that country to issue a $19 billion
            verdict in 2011. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A trial over the fraud allegations is scheduled for Oct. 15
            in Manhattan. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'I can't tell you how many motions or proceedings there
            have been' in the case before Kaplan, Olson told the appeals
            panel, referencing years of litigation and more than 1,400
            docket entries. 'Our opponents have won a lot of those.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Inappropriate Findings &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;James Tyrrell, a lawyer for two of the Ecuadorian
            claimants, argued that Kaplan issued inappropriate findings in
            previous orders that conflicted with an earlier decision by the
            appeals court. Tyrrell also contended that the judge is
            accommodating the oil company's effort to encourage courts
            around the world not to enforce the Ecuador verdict. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chevron denies there was company wrongdoing in Ecuador and
            claims that Texaco cleaned up its share of the pollution at its
            former oil fields, which were taken over by state-owned
            PetroEcuador. The U.S. company also said that it was released
            from future liability by an agreement between Texaco and
            Ecuador. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;This month, Chevron said it won't seek money damages
            against the two Ecuadorians in the fraud case. The oil company
            asked that a jury determine liability claims against Donziger
            and his law firm. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The racketeering case is Chevron v. Donziger, 11-cv-00691,
            U.S. District Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan).
            The appeals court case is In Re Naranjo, 13-00772, U.S. Court of
            Appeals for the Second Circuit (Manhattan). &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
</news>