<?xml version='1.0' encoding='us-ascii'?>
<news>

    <entry author="By Dakin Campbell" datetime="Apr 01, 2013  5:04 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="n" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-04-01/visa-s-partridge-stays-as-consultant-draws-562-500-bonus-1-.html">
        <headline>Visa's Partridge Stays as Consultant, Draws $562,500 Bonus</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Inc. (V)'s John Partridge, who
            retired as president of the world's largest payments network in
            March, will receive a base salary of $50,000 a month to remain
            with the company and work on special projects. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Partridge will also be paid $562,500 in November as a pro-
            rated bonus for his work as president through the end of last
            month, the Foster City, California-based firm said in a filing
            today. Partridge, 63, will continue to be eligible for other
            benefits given to U.S.-based employees, the filing said. Visa
            announced his planned retirement in a December statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Partridge was paid a salary of $750,029 in fiscal 2012,
            according to the firm's most recent proxy statement. He received
            $5.58 million in total compensation last year, including $1.47
            million in stock, $862,512 in options and a $1.82 million cash
            bonus, the firm said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;He joined the company in 1999 and named president in
            October 2009. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>

    <entry author="By Christie Smythe" datetime="Apr 11, 2013  6:36 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-04-11/visa-mastercard-judge-orders-corrections-to-swipe-fee-websites.html">
        <headline>Visa, MasterCard Judge Orders Changes on Swipe-Fee Sites</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Websites critical of a settlement
            that Visa Inc. (V) and MasterCard Inc. (MA) reached with retailers over
            so-called swipe fees are misleading and must be corrected, a
            federal judge ruled. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The sites contain 'bad information' that may have caused
            some retailers to drop out of the settlement, U.S. District
            Judge John Gleeson said today in Brooklyn, New York. He gave the
            parties a week to decide on changes. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'I'm not going to belabor this with you,' Gleeson told
            Jeffrey Shinder, a lawyer representing retail trade associations
            that established the sites and have opposed the settlement.
            'I'm just talking about basic fairness.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Sites at issue include Merchantsobject.com and home sites
            for the trade groups National Community Pharmacists Association,
            National Grocers Association and the National Association of
            Convenience Stores, among others, according to court filings
            submitted by the plaintiffs' lawyers. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The sites provide one-sided information encouraging
            retailers to object and opt out and don't fully explain
            consequences of those actions, the plaintiffs' lawyers said.
            While opting out allows merchants to pursue their own lawsuits
            against the credit card firms, it deprives them of the ability
            to receive payments for damages under the settlement, the
            lawyers said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Prominent Placement &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Merchantsobject site also fails to give prominent
            placement to a link to the official, court-approved source of
            information about the deal, paymentcardsettlement.com, the
            lawyers said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'The non-court-approved websites appear to be causing
            actual confusion among class members,' said Bonny E. Sweeney, a
            lead lawyer for the plaintiffs, in a declaration filed with the
            court. Since the sites went live, dozens of form objections have
            been filed by merchants apparently using the sites, she said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'It is currently difficult to know whether these class
            members intended to opt-out, but did not send the required
            letter or whether these class members only meant to object to
            the settlement, but picked the 'wrong' sample document provided
            on the various websites,' she said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Retail Leaders &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Today's hearing came after the Retail Industry Leaders
            Association announced it would opt out and object to the deal,
            which may be worth as much as $7.25 billion. The accord,
            estimated to be the largest-ever antitrust settlement, would end
            a case over claims that the card companies conspired with banks
            to fix the fees charged to merchants when customers pay with
            plastic. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Several retail groups have opposed the settlement since it
            was made public in July, alleging that it doesn't provide enough
            benefit for merchants and gives card companies too much leeway
            to raise rates. Retailers including Target Corp. (TGT), Wal-Mart
            Stores Inc. (WMT), and Home Depot Inc. (HD) have spoken out against the
            accord. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'We do not think the sites were misleading or that they
            misled anyone to object or opt-out,' said Shinder, in an e-
            mailed statement following the hearing. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'We do care deeply about the integrity of this process,
            and per the court's order, will endeavor to work with class
            counsel' to ensure it is 'crystal clear that those who
            submitted objections from those sites did so because they
            believe the settlement is a bad deal,' he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Lyle Beckwith, a government relations representative for
            the National Association of Convenience Stores, one of the
            groups behind the Merchantsobject site, called the request for
            changes 'not a big deal.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Nit-Picking &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'This is just unbelievable nit-picking,' he said. 'We
            are standing between attorneys and their $700 million payday and
            they don't like it.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Courts have previously ruled that the First Amendment does
            not prevent judges from supervising communications with absent
            class members about proposed settlements, the plaintiffs said in
            court filings. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The settlement covers more than 7 million retailers. If a
            sizable percentage chooses to opt out, Visa and MasterCard could
            have an option to back out of the deal. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Gleeson granted preliminary approval to the deal in
            November. A hearing on final approval is scheduled for
            September. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The case is In re Payment Card Interchange Fee and Merchant
            Discount Antitrust Litigation, 05-md-01720, U.S. District Court, &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Christie Smythe" datetime="Apr 11, 2013 10:52 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-04-11/retail-group-opts-out-of-visa-mastercard-swipe-accord.html">
        <headline>Retail Group Opts Out of Visa, MasterCard Swipe Accord</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;The Retail Industry Leaders
            Association said it will opt out of a multibillion-dollar
            antitrust settlement with Visa Inc. (V) and MasterCard Inc. (MA) over so-
            called swipe fees, calling it a 'bad deal for retailers.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The trade group said in a statement today that it would
            forgo damages payouts and object to the agreement, which may be
            worth as much as $7.25 billion. The accord, estimated to be the
            largest-ever antitrust settlement, would end a case alleging
            that the card companies conspired with major banks to fix the
            fees charged to merchants when customers pay with plastic. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The settlement 'undermines merchants' legal rights forever
            and fails to restrain the continued growth of swipe fees
            increases,' Deborah White, the Arlington, Virginia-based
            association's general counsel, said in the statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Several retail groups have opposed the settlement since it
            was made public in July, alleging that it doesn't provide enough
            benefit for merchants and gives card companies too much leeway
            in the future to raise rates. Some large retailers, including
            Target Corp. (TGT), Wal-Mart Stores Inc. (WMT), Home Depot Inc. (HD), have also
            spoken out against the accord. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Arguments Today &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;U.S. District Judge John Gleeson is scheduled to hear
            arguments today in federal court in Brooklyn, New York, over
            whether a website created by trade groups, Merchantsobject.com,
            is misinforming retailers about the settlement. The site
            encourages businesses to opt out and object to the deal. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Trish Wexler, a spokeswoman for the Electronic Payments
            Coalition, which represents credit card firms and banks, said
            RILA's announcement is a 'public relations stunt designed to
            distract attention' from the hearing. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Gleeson granted preliminary approval to the deal in
            November. A hearing on final approval is scheduled for
            September. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The case is In re Payment Card Interchange Fee and Merchant
            Discount Antitrust Litigation, 05-md-01720, U.S. District Court,
            Eastern District of New York (Brooklyn). &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>

    <entry author="By Christie Smythe" datetime="Apr 12, 2013 11:41 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="d"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-04-12/visa-mastercard-judge-asked-to-approve-settlement-fees.html">
        <headline>Visa, MasterCard Judge Asked to Approve Settlement, Fees</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Lawyers for plaintiffs in a Visa
            Inc. (V) and MasterCard Inc. (MA) antitrust case over interchange fees
            asked for final approval of a settlement along with $720 million
            in legal fees and $27 million in expenses. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The attorneys, representing a class of more than 7 million
            merchants, filed papers late yesterday in Brooklyn, New York,
            seeking a final blessing for the accord from U.S. District Judge
            John Gleeson. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The settlement, estimated to be the largest ever in an
            antitrust case, would provide for about $7.25 billion in cash
            payouts, according to a memorandum filed by Robbins Geller
            Rudman Dowd LLP, one of the lead law firms in the case. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'With the largest-ever cash relief in an antitrust class
            action settlement plus unprecedented rules changes that would
            enable merchants to recover their costs of credit card
            acceptance' the settlement 'is far more than 'fair, adequate,
            and reasonable,'' the lawyers wrote. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In a separate filing, the lawyer said their request for
            attorneys' fees is reasonable given the complexity of the issues
            and the length of time of the eight-year-long case. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'The settlement will affect as great a segment of the
            United States economy as any previous antitrust class action,'
            lawyers for the plaintiffs said in the filing, noting that about
            60 law firms worked on the case. 'Such an extraordinary
            settlement could result only from a similarly extraordinary
            effort by class counsel and their co-counsel.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Retailers Opposed &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Merchant trade groups and some large retailers including
            Target Corp. (TGT), Wal-Mart Stores Inc. (WMT), Home Depot Inc. (HD) spoke out
            against the accord, claiming it isn't large enough and gives
            card companies too much leeway to raise fees in the future. The
            lawsuit alleged the card companies and some of the country's
            largest banks conspired to fix prices of fees paid by merchants
            when customers pay with plastic. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A hearing on final approval has been scheduled for
            September. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The case is In re Payment Card Interchange Fee and
            Merchant Discount Antitrust Litigation, 05-md-01720, U.S.
            District Court, Eastern District of New York (Brooklyn). &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Jason Corcoran" datetime="Apr 24, 2014  8:18 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="d"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-24/putin-says-visa-and-mastercard-will-lose-market-share.html">
        <headline>Putin Says Visa and MasterCard Will Lose Market Share</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Russian President Vladimir Putin
            said Visa Inc. (V) and MasterCard Inc. (MA) will lose market share in
            Russia after they blocked some transactions because of U.S.
            sanctions on individuals and banks. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'We don't see any steps to punish unconscionable partners,
            but they are undermining trust, hence will lose market share for
            sure,' Putin said on Rossiya-24 state television in St.
            Petersburg today, &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Putin said Visa and MasterCard are 'very susceptible to
            political influence and pressure,' and Russia will continue to
            create its own national payments system. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa and MasterCard stopped processing cards for Bank
            Rossiya last month after the U.S. placed the lender on its
            sanctions list because of Russia's takeover of Crimea. SMP Bank,
            which also had its cards blocked by the two biggest card
            networks, said March 23 that services would resume soon. SMP
            Bank's co-owners, Arkady Rotenberg and brother Boris, were also
            hit with sanctions. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Seth Eisen, a spokesman for MasterCard, declined to
            comment. A Visa spokeswoman in the U.S. didn't immediately
            respond to a call and an e-mail seeking comment. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Elizabeth Dexheimer" datetime="Apr 25, 2014  4:18 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s"
           progress_sentiment="d"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-25/visa-tumbles-as-russia-sanctions-threaten-to-crimp-profit.html">
        <headline>Visa Tumbles as Russia Sanctions Threaten to Crimp Profit</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Inc. (V) fell 5 percent, the most
            since July, after the world's biggest bank-card network said
            economic sanctions against Russia could crimp profit this year. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The shares tumbled $10.47 to close at $198.93 in New York,
            the worst performance in the Dow Jones Industrial Average. Visa
            is the biggest component of the 30-company (INDU) index, which slid 0.8
            percent. The sanctions may trim 'several pennies' per share
            from fiscal 2014 earnings, Chief Financial Officer Byron Pollitt
            said yesterday after the firm reported quarterly results. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The U.S. imposed sanctions on more than two dozen
            individuals and St. Petersburg-based OAO Bank Rossiya, prompting
            Visa and MasterCard Inc. (MA) to stop processing payments for some
            banks. Russian President Vladimir Putin responded to the
            sanctions by recommending that his country create its own
            payments system and change its laws. He said the two companies
            will lose market share. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'The geopolitical situation will create additional risk
            for Visa and MasterCard in coming months,' Christopher Donat,
            an analyst at Sandler O'Neill Partners LP, said today in a
            note to clients. 'Pending Russian law could be negative for
            earnings.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;MasterCard, the second-biggest U.S. network, also dropped 5
            percent, the most since January. The Purchase, New York-based
            company is scheduled to report quarterly results May 1. &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: Andrey Rudakov/Bloomberg

            &lt;p&gt;
            Logos for Visa Inc., Maestro and Mastercard Inc. payment systems sit on an automated teller machine (ATM)
            inside a Credit Bank of Moscow bank branch in Moscow, Russia, on April 22, 2014. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Elizabeth Dexheimer" datetime="Apr 30, 2014  1:18 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s"
           progress_sentiment="d"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-30/mastercard-strategy-seen-beating-visa-in-target-win.html">
        <headline>MasterCard Strategy Seen Beating Visa in Target Win</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;MasterCard Inc. (MA)'s approach to making bank-card transactions more secure could give it a
            competitive edge, analysts said after Target Corp. (TGT) awarded its portfolio to the company yesterday over
            larger rival Visa Inc. (V) &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Target, which suffered a data breach during the holiday
            season, said its co-branded cards and in-house REDcards would use MasterCard's network and technology
            instead of Visa's. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Visa and MasterCard have given retailers and banks until October 2015
            to adopt so-called EMV technology or assume liability for bogus transactions. Merchants and lenders can use
            chip cards that require a signature or a personal identification number. While Visa's approach doesn't
            distinguish between the two, MasterCard's emphasizes PIN, which could improve its prospects with retailers
            who prefer that method. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;'We were not anticipating the EMV shift could be catalyst for
            portfolio movement from Visa to MasterCard and this shows that there are some opportunities,' David Darst,
            an analyst at Guggenheim Securities LLC, said of Target's decision. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Target said it would
            accelerate its move to chip-card technology after tens of millions of credit- and debit-card accounts were
            breached late last year. The Minneapolis-based retailer said yesterday that upgrade would include
            chip-and-PIN. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;'Target is very publicly broadcasting that they are an early adopter of
            EMV and it's not just EMV, it's also chip-and-PIN,' said Darrin Peller, a Barclays Plc analyst. 'That gives
            room to someone like MasterCard to gain market share.' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;'Nice Win' &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Earlier
            this month, Wal-Mart Stores Inc., the largest U.S. retailer, chose MasterCard to handle transactions for its
            store-branded credit cards, ending a nine-year relationship with Discover Financial Services. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;While Target's deal with Purchase, New York-based MasterCard is a 'nice win,' the revenue boost
            should be 'fairly negligible,' according to Sanjay Sakhrani, an analyst at Keefe, Bruyette Woods in New
            York. Target cards currently are co-branded with Foster City, California-based Visa. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The
            deal may boost MasterCard's annual revenue by about $13 million, or 1 cent a share, Sakhrani said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;MasterCard rose 0.7 percent to $72.55 at 12:03 p.m. in New York and Visa was little changed at
            $202.72. The shares have slid 13 percent and 8.9 percent, respectively, this year. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;EMV
            -- a technology named for founders EuroPay International, MasterCard and Visa -- is standard in Europe and
            much of the rest of the world and makes it more difficult for hackers to clone card data. EMV has been
            slower to catch on in the U.S. in part because it cost merchants and issuers more than cards with magnetic
            strips. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Held Accountable &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;'Target is in a position where they need
            to show how they are changing,' said Gil Luria, an analyst at Wedbush Securities Inc. 'By switching to
            MasterCard -- and going with that perception that MasterCard is more oriented toward PIN -- they can
            communicate that they are making a change to become more secure.' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Requiring a PIN adds
            security that protects against fraud involving lost or stolen cards. While MasterCard's strategy allows for
            either PIN or signature, it supports a hierarchy that holds whichever party -- issuers or merchants --
            offering the least secure method liable when cards are compromised. Visa doesn't have a similar pecking
            order. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;'Whatever verification method is adopted is the choice of our merchant and
            financial institution clients and we will support whatever verification method they prefer,' said Paul
            Cohen, a Visa spokesman. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;'More Competitive' &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Target choosing
            MasterCard also means that the company may have more opportunity to gain debit-card market share, according
            to Barclays's Peller. Visa currently has the majority of the U.S. signature debit-card market, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'It makes the landscape more competitive for debit,' as more PIN technology is introduced, Peller
            said. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Groups including the National Retail Federation have also said they prefer
            chip-and-PIN cards. As the industry continues its conversion, it's possible MasterCard may win more business
            from merchants advocating for PIN technology, according to Guggenheim's Darst. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;'There
            are different times when there could be portfolio or market share movement from Visa to MasterCard,' Darst
            said. 'This is one of them.' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>

    <entry author="By Dakin Campbell" datetime="Dec 13, 2013  6:47 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-13/visa-gives-ceo-scharf-10-5-million-compensation-for-fiscal-2013.html">
        <headline>Visa Awards CEO Scharf $10.5 Million Pay Package for Year</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Inc. (V), the world's biggest bank-card network, said it awarded Chief Executive Officer
            Charlie Scharf compensation for fiscal year 2013 valued at $10.5
            million. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The pay package included a $950,000 base salary and a bonus
            of $3.57 million, Foster City, California-based Visa said today
            in a filing. He received $2.97 million in performance shares,
            $1.48 million in options and a similar sum in restricted stock,
            the filing shows. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa has risen 37 percent this year, lagging the 60 percent
            return for MasterCard Inc. while outpacing the 24 percent
            advance for the Standard Poor's 500 Index. The shares are up
            about 49 percent since Scharf succeeded Joseph W. Saunders on
            Nov. 1, 2012. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Saunders received a pay package valued at $9.7 million in
            total compensation for fiscal year 2012, reflecting a formula
            based on U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission rules. Scharf
            was paid $24.2 million for fiscal year 2013 based on the same
            calculation, which differs from the company's number because it
            includes the compensation actually received in the year rather
            than what was awarded. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Dakin Campbell" datetime="Feb 06, 2013  5:24 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-02-06/visa-profit-beats-estimates-as-credit-card-spending-increases.html">
        <headline>Visa Profit Rises 26% as Credit-Card Spending Accelerates</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Inc., the world's biggest payments network, posted a fiscal first-quarter profit that beat
            analysts' estimates as consumer card purchases accelerated. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Net income for the three
            months ended Dec. 31 advanced 26 percent to $1.29 billion, or $1.93 a share, from $1.03 billion, or $1.49, a
            year earlier, the Foster City, California-based company said today in a statement. That beat the $1.79
            average estimate of 32 analysts surveyed by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;'Results include significant
            continued investments in our core business, accelerating international expansion and the deployment of
            next-generation payment solutions,' Chief Executive Officer Charlie Scharf, who succeeded Joseph W. Saunders
            in November, said in the statement. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Scharf, 47, inherited a goal of deriving more than
            half of Visa's revenue from outside the U.S. by 2015. A long-term global consumer shift to electronic
            payments, particularly in the Asia- Pacific region, may help. Purchases there are projected to generate 42
            percent, or $9.03 trillion, of worldwide card spending at merchants in 2016, up from 36 percent at the end
            of 2011, the Nilson Report, an industry newsletter, said in its latest issue. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;h2&gt;Cash Flow
            &lt;/h2&gt; &lt;p&gt;Visa said it would generate about $6 billion in free cash flow in fiscal 2013, fueled
            by tax benefits related to a settlement of a lawsuit over credit-card 'swipe' fees, or interchange. Guidance
            on taxes from California officials led Visa's tax rate to fall to 28 percent in the quarter and boosted
            results by 11 cents a share, the company said. &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

            &lt;p&gt;
            Card purchases in the Asia-Pacific region are projected to generate 42 percent, or $9.03 trillion, of
            worldwide spending at merchants in 2016. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Sarah Jacob" datetime="Feb 10, 2014  4:29 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="n" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-10/visa-ceo-says-china-delays-opening-card-payments-market.html">
        <headline>Visa CEO Says China Delays Opening Card-Payments Market</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Inc. (V) Chief Executive Officer
            Charlie Scharf said China isn't opening as quickly as expected
            to foreign payment processors and must be viewed as a five- to
            15-year opportunity. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'It's going to take a long time for the market to actually
            open up in a way that we actually do have that level playing
            field,' Scharf told analysts today in New York during an
            industry conference sponsored by Keefe, Bruyette Woods Inc. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Scharf plans to be in China next week and said the company
            needs to understand why the market hasn't become more open to
            foreign firms. Visa, the world's biggest bank-card network, has
            been in talks with U.S. and local officials, Chinese banks and
            China UnionPay Co., he said. UnionPay is a payment processor
            founded in Shanghai by the State Council and central bank that
            competes globally with Visa and MasterCard Inc. (MA) &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chinese law limits what Visa can do, Scharf said at his
            company's annual meeting in January. 'If you want to issue a
            card locally in China, denominated in the local currency, it has
            to be issued by a Chinese-owned company called China UnionPay,'
            said Scharf, 48. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Marie Mawad and Robert Valpuesta" datetime="Feb 20, 2014  5:36 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="s"
           progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-20/gemalto-drops-as-visa-backs-rival-mobile-payment-systems.html">
        <headline>Gemalto Drops as Visa Backs Rival Mobile Payment Systems</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Gemalto NV (GTO) fell the most in more
            than three years after Visa Inc., owner of the biggest bank-card
            network, said it's offering cheaper alternatives to the
            company's technology for payments using mobile phones. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;New capabilities include an option to host accounts 'in a
            secure, virtual cloud,' Foster City, California-based Visa said
            in a statement yesterday. This gives financial institutions more
            choice in secure payment systems with smartphones and follows
            the introduction of technology that allows Android phones to
            emulate a smartcard, so the devices can be used to 'wave to
            pay,' Visa said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'The outlook for Gemalto's Mobile Communication segment,
            which accounts for around 50 percent of its earnings, is the
            main reason for our sell recommendation,' Ali Farid Khwaja, an
            analyst at Berenberg Bank, said in a note today. The technology
            now supported by Visa 'is simpler, cheaper and the fact that
            Visa and Mastercard have approved it also suggests that it is
            secure to use for payment transactions,' he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Gemalto's offerings include chips and software that make
            bank cards and mobile phones more secure. Under Chief Executive
            Officer Olivier Piou, the Amsterdam-based company has shifted
            away from commoditized chips to sell more lucrative packages
            including security software. Its clients include mobile-phone
            carriers and banks, as well as companies including Volkswagen
            AG's Audi division and Facebook Inc. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Gemalto fell as much as 9.2 percent, the biggest intraday
            drop since August 2010. The shares were down 5.3 percent at
            78.42 euros as of 11:32 a.m. in Amsterdam, for a decline of 2
            percent this year, giving the company a market value of 6.9
            billion euros ($9.45 billion). &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>

    <entry author="By Kitty Donaldson" datetime="Feb 25, 2014  6:55 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="n" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-25/u-k-should-introduce-4-2-million-investment-visas-panel-says.html">
        <headline>U.K. Should Introduce $4.2 Million Investment Visas, Panel Says</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;U.K. Home Secretary Theresa May
            should set up a new 'premium' route for wealthy investors,
            with 100 visas a year auctioned off at a reserve price of 2.5
            million pounds ($4.2 million), an advisory panel recommended. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Migration Advisory Committee, which is made up of five
            independent economists and a representative of the Commission
            for Employment and Skills, proposed replacing the current so-called 'higher investor routes' that require
            investments of 5
            million pounds and 10 million pounds as they are 'hugely
            underused.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'We have focused our attention on how U.K. residents may
            gain from this migration route; we express some healthy
            skepticism regarding the value to U.K. residents of high net
            worth individuals coming to the U.K.,' the panel's chairman,
            David Metcalf, told reporters in London today. 'When people
            say: 'Isn't it awful to sell visas?' -- it's better than giving
            them away, which is what we are doing now.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The committee also recommended the government improves
            incentives for foreign investors to buy into financial
            instruments other than government bonds. Options include
            infrastructure bonds to improve roads or other amenities,
            Metcalf said. Venture capital projects should also be
            considered, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The new premium route would benefit from relaxed residency
            requirements, halving to 90 days a year the amount of time an
            individual has to remain resident in the U.K. It would lead to
            the settlement of individuals, not U.K. citizenship. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The auction of premium route visas would be conducted via
            sealed offers, with a bid of 2.5 million pounds comprised of an
            investment of 2 million pounds by the applicant plus a gift of
            500,000 pounds donated to the government, designed to be given
            to philanthropic causes such as charities 'or basketball
            courts,' Metcalf said. The market may settle on a higher price
            for the visas, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The panel also recommended doubling the minimum threshold
            for investors on 'standard route' visas to 2 million pounds,
            uprating a price that has not changed since 1994. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;May would need to accept the panel's advice before the
            changes could be introduced. The Home Office did not have an
            immediate response to the recommendations when contacted by
            phone. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Aoife White" datetime="Feb 26, 2014  6:40 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="n" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-26/visa-europe-settles-eu-antitrust-probe-with-credit-card-fees-cut.html">
        <headline>Visa Europe Settles EU Antitrust Probe With Credit-Card Fees Cut</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Europe Ltd.'s pledge to reduce
            credit-card fees was accepted by European Union regulators in a
            settlement that ends an antitrust probe that dates back more
            than a decade. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Europe, operator of the EU's largest payment-card
            network, will cap so-called interbank fees for processing credit
            card payments to 0.3 percent of the value of the transaction for
            cross-border and domestic payments in Europe for four years,
            from Jan. 1, 2015. The commitment will reduce card charges by 40
            percent to 60 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Card fees charged by Visa Europe and MasterCard Inc. have
            been probed by European Union regulators since at least 2002.
            MasterCard is currently challenging a similar settlement at the
            EU's highest court, saying such multilateral interchange fees
            are crucial for sharing the costs of card payments among banks,
            retailers and customers. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The agreement 'provides legal certainty' and allows the
            company focus on its payment business 'rather than pursuing
            lengthy legal cases,' Nicholas Huss, Visa Europe's chief
            executive officer, said in an e-mailed statement. Visa Europe
            will also make its pricing more transparent to help retailers
            compare rates. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A 0.3 percent cap on credit card fees for payments that
            customers make in their home nation will be applied after a two-year delay to deter banks switching to cards
            with higher
            charges, the EU said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>

    <entry author="By Tariq Panja" datetime="Jan 14, 2014  8:21 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-01-14/visa-becomes-fifth-fifa-sponsor-to-renew-through-2022-world-cup.html">
        <headline>Visa Becomes Fifth FIFA Sponsor to Renew Through 2022 World Cup</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Soccer governing body FIFA signed a
            new accord with Visa Inc. (V) through 2022, extending an agreement
            that started amid controversy in 2007. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The world's biggest bank-card network is the fifth FIFA
            partner to commit to both the 2018 and 2022 World Cups,
            following Adidas AG (ADS), Coca-Cola Co., Hyundai-Kia and Anheuser-Busch InBev NV. (ABI) This year's edition
            of the quadrennial event
            will be in Brazil. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'We're delighted to have such a strong global brand by our
            side until at least 2022,' FIFA President Sepp Blatter said in
            an e-mailed statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa joined FIFA's roster of sponsors following a dispute
            between the soccer body and its previous credit card sponsor
            MasterCard Inc. (MA) that was only settled after FIFA agreed to pay
            $90 million in compensation. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;MasterCard had been a FIFA partner for 16 years and argued
            it was contractually obliged to a first right of renewal. The
            case hurt FIFA's reputation with a judge describing its dealings
            as 'anything but fair play' and said its negotiators 'lied'
            to both MasterCard and Visa. Following the verdict FIFA fired
            its then marketing director Jerome Valcke, who's since returned
            as its general secretary, its most senior administrative
            official. &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: Dado Galdieri/Bloomberg

            &lt;p&gt;
            The Maracana Stadium, also known as the Mario Filho Stadium, stands in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. The stadium
            will host the 2014 World Cup final. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Erik Larson" datetime="Jan 24, 2013 12:36 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-01-24/visa-paypal-computer-hacker-given-18-month-sentence-in-u-k-1-.html">
        <headline>Visa, PayPal Computer Hacker Given 18-Month Sentence in U.K.</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;A computer hacker from the online
            activism group 'Anonymous' was sentenced in Britain to 18
            months in jail for conspiring to attack the websites of Visa
            Inc. (V), PayPal Inc., MasterCard Inc. (MA) and others. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The prison term was handed down today, according to a clerk
            at Southwark Crown Court in London. Christopher Weatherhead was
            found guilty in December, while three co-defendants -- Jake
            Birchall, Ashley Rhodes and Peter Gibson -- pleaded guilty
            earlier to conspiring to impair the operation of computers. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Britain's Crown Prosecution Service described Weatherhead
            in December as a 'cyber-criminal who waged a sophisticated and
            orchestrated campaign of online attacks' on computer systems. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Gibson was ordered to perform 100 hours community service
            and given a six-month suspended sentence for two years, meaning
            he faces jail if he offends again during that period. Birchall's
            sentence will be discussed at a hearing scheduled for Feb. 1,
            the clerk said. Rhodes's sentence hadn't been discussed today,
            the clerk said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The four also targeted the British Recorded Music Industry,
            Ministry of Sound and the International Federation of the
            Phonographic Industry, prosecutors said. The attacks cost the
            companies more than 3.5 million pounds ($5.5 million) in extra
            staffing, software and sales losses. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;U.K. police have been investigating 'hacktivist'
            collectives Anonymous and LulzSec for conducting denial-of-
            service attacks, which flood computer networks with requests for
            information until they shut down. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Elizabeth Dexheimer" datetime="Jan 30, 2014  9:24 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="n"
           progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-01-30/visa-s-scharf-says-traditional-payment-networks-trump-bitcoin.html">
        <headline>Visa's Scharf Says Traditional Payment Networks Trump Bitcoin</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Inc. (V) Chief Executive Officer
            Charlie Scharf said he's more confident in traditional payment
            networks than in virtual currencies like Bitcoin. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'There are certainly some interesting things about Bitcoin
            and other things like it, but there are also a great deal of
            complexities,' Scharf said today on a conference call to
            discuss quarterly results. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Payments networks such as Foster City, California-based
            Visa are safer for consumers because of 'the established
            network rules we have, the understanding of how things operate,
            understanding who the participants are, the fact that the
            business that we do has financial institutions on either side of
            the transaction.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;While Visa will continue to pay attention to developments
            surrounding Bitcoin, 'we feel very comfortable with the
            business that we have here,' Scharf said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa is the biggest bank-card network. Scharf is a former
            senior executive at JPMorgan Chase Co., the largest U.S. bank. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Elizabeth Dexheimer" datetime="Jan 30, 2014 10:44 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="h"
           progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-01-30/visa-profit-beats-estimates-on-higher-card-spending.html">
        <headline>Visa Profit Beats Estimates on Higher Card Spending</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Inc. (V), the biggest bank-card
            network, posted fiscal first-quarter profit that beat analysts'
            estimates as card spending climbed. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Net income for the three months ended Dec. 31 rose 8.8
            percent to $1.41 billion, or $2.20 a share, from $1.29 billion,
            or $1.93, a year earlier, the Foster City, California-based firm
            said today in a statement. The average estimate of 30 analysts
            surveyed by Bloomberg was for adjusted profit of $2.16. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chief Executive Officer Charlie Scharf, 48, is seeking ways
            to increase business outside the U.S., where Visa gets more than
            half its revenue, amid a global shift to electronic payments
            from cash. The firm has returned almost $17 billion to investors
            since its 2008 initial public offering and last year was the
            sixth-best performer in the Dow Jones Industrial Average,
            gaining 47 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'We feel very good about the strong financial
            performance,' Scharf said on a conference call to discuss
            results. 'Holiday spend in the U.S. was better than reported.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa rose 1.6 percent to $220.57 at 9:56 a.m. in New York.
            The shares have declined 1.7 percent this year, compared with
            the 4.7 percent slide of the 30-company Dow. Smaller rival
            MasterCard Inc. (MA), which reports results before U.S. markets open
            tomorrow, climbed 1.6 percent to $78.97. &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

            &lt;p&gt;
            Visa Inc. has returned almost $17 billion to investors since its 2008 initial public offering and last year
            was the sixth-best performer in the Dow Jones Industrial Average, gaining 47 percent. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Jim Brunsden and Stephanie Bodoni" datetime="Jul 17, 2013  7:38 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="n"
           progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-17/eu-plans-card-fee-caps-to-build-on-mastercard-visa-probe.html">
        <headline>EU Plans Card Fee Caps to Build on MasterCard, Visa Probe</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Banks and payment card providers
            would face caps on the transaction fees they can demand from
            retailers under European Union plans to rein in charges that
            have been attacked by regulators as anticompetitive. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The European Commission, the 28-nation EU's executive arm,
            will propose that interchange fees paid by retailers on card
            transactions should be capped at 0.2 percent for debit card
            payments and 0.3 percent for credit cards, according to draft
            plans obtained by Bloomberg News. The caps would initially apply
            to cross-border transactions, and then be expanded to also cover
            domestic payments after two years. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Retailers have long opposed the extra costs associated with
            accepting credit and debit cards. Unlike with checks, banks
            charge fees, known as interchange, to process card payments. The
            amounts are set by MasterCard Inc. (MA) and Visa Inc. (V), which own the
            payment networks and pass the money to the banks. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The fees 'restrict competition as they inflate the cost of
            card acceptance by merchants without leading to benefits for
            consumers,' according to the document. They result in 'higher
            final prices for goods and services.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The commission proposal, by seeking to use legislation to
            limit such fees, marks an expansion in the EU's assault against
            the practice. The agency has said that it will publish the plans
            on July 24. They would require approval by governments and the
            European Parliament before they take effect. &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: Guido Krzikowski/Bloomberg

            &lt;p&gt;
            EU antitrust regulators have targeted credit- and debit-card fees for a decade, warning that the way the
            fees are collectively agreed on is anti-competitive. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Christie Smythe" datetime="Jul 18, 2014  9:00 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="d"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-18/visa-mastercard-must-face-target-macy-s-swipe-fee-case.html">
        <headline>Visa, MasterCard Must Face Target, Macy's Swipe-Fee Case</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Inc. (V) and MasterCard Inc. (MA) lost
            their bid to dismiss more than 30 lawsuits by retailers seeking
            potentially billions of dollars in damages over fees for
            processing transactions. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Merchants including Target Corp. (TGT) and Macy's Inc. (M) pursued
            their cases after dropping out of an earlier $5.7 billion
            settlement over the charges known as swipe fees. Today, a
            federal judge in Brooklyn, New York, refused to throw out those
            lawsuits. He also rejected Visa's request to dismiss a similar
            lawsuit filed by Wal-Mart Stores Inc. (WMT) seeking at least $5
            billion in damages. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;U.S. District Judge John Gleeson said his decision was 'in
            large part driven by the requirement that I accept all well-pleaded factual allegations as true' because the
            cases were in
            the early stages of litigation. It isn't a ruling on the merits
            of the complaints. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Gleeson in December approved the card companies' settlement
            with merchants nationwide following years of antitrust
            litigation over the fees. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Dozens of large retailers appealed the approval of the
            accord. Many also dropped out of the deal and filed their own
            lawsuits, contending it wasn't enough compensation for the
            hundreds of billions of dollars in fees paid. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;'Market Power' &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In a revised complaint filed this month, Target and Macy's
            said the card companies 'have obtained and maintained market
            power in the market for merchant acceptance of credit cards'
            causing merchants 'to pay excessive interchange fees.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Wal-Mart alleged in its complaint that 'Visa's monopoly
            power has enabled it to dictate price and inhibit competition.'
            The Bentonville, Arkansas-based retailer announced in April that
            MasterCard will handle transactions for store-branded credit
            cards. MasterCard isn't named in Wal-Mart's swipe-fee complaint. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa and MasterCard argued that the merchants' claims for
            damages should be barred by legal releases in an earlier
            settlement in 2003. They also said the claims should be thrown
            out because the merchants don't directly pay fees to banks that
            issue Visa and MasterCard branded cards. The fees are deducted
            from payments merchants receive after processing. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Separately, Gleeson also denied requests by Wal-Mart and
            another group of merchants to dismiss lawsuits filed against
            them by the card firms seeking to stop their litigation over the
            fees in its tracks. The request the card firms are making in
            those cases is 'properly invoked,' Gleeson said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;'Tactical Advantage' &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'We're not seeking an unfair tactical advantage, we're
            seeking finality,' said Michael Shuster, a lawyer for Visa,
            during the hearing today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Paul Cohen, a spokesman for Foster City, California-based
            Visa, declined to comment on the judge's rulings. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Judge Gleeson's ruling was at the earliest stage of the
            case,' Seth Eisen, a spokesman for Purchase, New York-based
            MasterCard, said in an e-mail. 'We look forward to putting this
            matter behind us and continuing to work productively with the
            merchant community.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The case is In Re: Payment Card Interchange Fee and
            Merchant Discount Antitrust Litigation -- Opt Out Cases, 1:14-md-01720, U.S. District Court, Eastern
            District of New York
            (Brooklyn). &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Dakin Campbell" datetime="Jul 24, 2013  4:59 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-24/visa-profit-beats-estimates-as-credit-card-spending-increases.html">
        <headline>Visa Profit Beats Estimates as Credit-Card Spending Rises</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Inc. (V), the biggest bank-card
            network, reported a fiscal third-quarter profit that beat
            analysts' estimates as worldwide spending on credit and debit
            cards climbed. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Net income for the three months ended June 30 was $1.23
            billion, or $1.88 a share, compared with a loss of $1.84
            billion, or $2.74, a year earlier that included a litigation
            expense, the Foster City, California-based company said today in
            a statement. The average estimate of 33 analysts surveyed by
            Bloomberg was for earnings of $1.80 a share. Profit excluding
            special items from the third quarter of 2012 climbed 16 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chief Executive Officer Charlie Scharf is seeking to
            bolster Visa's business outside the U.S., where it gets more
            than half its revenue, as consumers worldwide continue to
            migrate from cash and checks to electronic payments. The company
            has returned more than $15 billion to shareholders since 2008. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'From a longer-term perspective, we continue to believe
            that Visa is the single best way' to harness returns amid the
            shift away from cash, Greg Smith, an analyst at Sterne Agee
            Leach Inc., wrote in a July 21 report. 'We expect the company
            to consistently generate at least mid-teens' earnings-per-share
            growth, he said. &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

            &lt;p&gt;
            Last year, Visa Inc. and No. 2 network MasterCard Inc. agreed to a $7.25 billion settlement over the fees
            charged to merchants when consumers pay with credit cards. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Elizabeth Dexheimer" datetime="Jul 24, 2014  4:09 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="h"
           progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-24/visa-profit-beats-estimates-as-card-spending-climbs.html">
        <headline>Visa Profit Beats Estimates as Card Spending Climbs</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Inc. (V), the world's largest
            payments network, posted a fiscal third-quarter profit that beat
            analysts' estimates as card spending increased. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Net income for the three months ended June 30 rose 11
            percent to $1.36 billion, or $2.17 a share, from $1.23 billion,
            or $1.88, a year earlier, the Foster City, California-based
            company said today in a statement. The average estimate of 30
            analysts surveyed by Bloomberg was for adjusted profit of $2.10. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa is benefiting as consumers globally replace cash with
            credit and debit cards. Chief Executive Officer Charlie Scharf,
            49, has focused on strengthening relationships with retailers,
            developing technologies to enable digital payments and working
            with governments to expand the firm's reach outside the U.S. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Visa's business is characterized by recurring revenues,
            high incremental margins, low capital expenditures and high free
            cash flow,' Tien-tsin Huang, a JPMorgan Chase Co. analyst,
            wrote in a July 23 note. The company is 'a relative safe haven
            against macro uncertainty.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The shares rose 0.7 percent to $222.74 at 4 p.m. in New
            York and have gained 0.3 percent this year. MasterCard Inc. (MA), the
            second-largest payments network, has slid 7.2 percent since Dec.
            31. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Discover Financial Services, the fourth-largest payments
            network, said July 22 that profit rose 7 percent to $644 million
            as card spending increased. American Express Co., the biggest
            card issuer by purchases, is scheduled to report earnings on
            July 29, with MasterCard following two days later. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Russia Tensions &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;After the U.S. imposed sanctions against Russia in March,
            Russian President Vladimir Putin recommended his country create
            its own payments system. Visa -- which generates about 2 percent
            of its revenue from Russia -- said the tensions may trim
            'several pennies' from this year's earnings. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The company this month introduced Visa Checkout, which it
            said will allow consumers to make purchases faster online. The
            product replaces V.me, a digital wallet that Scharf described as
            'not friendly' for clients in a May conference call. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Visa is late to the quick checkout game,' Huang said in
            a July 16 research note. 'But it is one of only a few companies
            that could establish critical mass given its payment share,
            marketing budget and brand equity.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Dakin Campbell" datetime="Jul 25, 2013 10:16 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-25/visa-advances-as-net-income-beats-estimates-san-francisco-mover.html">
        <headline>Visa Advances as Net Income Beats Estimates: San Francisco Mover</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Inc. (V) gained the most since May
            after reporting fiscal third-quarter profit that beat analysts'
            estimates as consumers stepped up use of credit and debit cards. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa rose 4.6 percent to $195.33 at 10 a.m. in New York,
            the second-best performer on the Standard Poor's 500
            Information Technology Index. The shares gained 29 percent this
            year, outpacing the 9.4 percent advance of the 70-company index. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Net income for the three months ended June 30 was $1.23
            billion, or $1.88 a share, compared with a loss of $1.84
            billion, or $2.74, a year earlier that included a litigation
            expense, the Foster City, California-based firm said yesterday
            in a statement. The average estimate of 33 analysts surveyed by
            Bloomberg was for earnings of $1.80 a share. Profit excluding
            special items from the third quarter of 2012 climbed 16 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chief Executive Officer Charlie Scharf is seeking to
            bolster Visa's business outside the U.S., where it gets more
            than half its revenue, as consumers worldwide continue to
            migrate from cash and checks to electronic payments. The company
            has returned more than $15 billion to shareholders since 2008. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'The opportunity to move transactions from cash to
            electronic means is still huge,' Scharf, 48, said yesterday in
            a conference call with analysts. 'This is true in both the
            developed and the developing parts of the world.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Share Repurchases &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The company repurchased $981 million of its stock during
            the quarter at an average of $176.75 a share and may buy back an
            additional $1.5 billion through next July, according to the
            statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Third-quarter operating revenue climbed 17 percent to $3
            billion, beating the $2.89 billion average estimate of analysts
            surveyed by Bloomberg. Revenue will increase about 13 percent
            this fiscal year, according to the statement. Earnings per share
            will rise by more than 20 percent, the company said, after an
            earlier forecast of 'around' 20 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Worldwide spending on Visa cards climbed 13 percent to
            $1.09 trillion, adjusted for currency fluctuations, according to
            the statement. Processed transactions rose 14 percent to 15
            billion. Cross-border purchases, or spending by cardholders
            outside their home countries, advanced 11 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In the U.S., debit-card purchases advanced 12 percent to
            $300 billion, and credit-card spending increased 10 percent to
            $270 billion, according to the statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Legal Settlement &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa and No. 2 network MasterCard Inc. (MA) agreed last year to
            a $7.25 billion settlement over the fees charged to merchants
            when consumers pay with credit cards. Visa sued Wal-Mart Stores
            Inc. last month to stop the biggest U.S. retailer from filing a
            lawsuit that would prolong the eight-year legal battle the
            settlement seeks to end. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;American Express Co. (AXP), the New York-based card issuer that
            also runs the third-largest U.S. bank-card network, said July 18
            that second-quarter profit rose 4.9 percent to $1.41 billion as
            customer purchases increased. Riverwoods, Illinois-based
            Discover Financial Services (DFS), the No. 4 network, said yesterday
            that quarterly net income climbed 15 percent to $602 million.
            MasterCard is set to report results July 31. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Dakin Campbell" datetime="Jul 25, 2013 12:00 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-25/visa-posts-profit-beating-estimates-as-card-spending-increases.html">
        <headline>Visa Posts Profit Beating Estimates as Card Spending Increases</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Inc. (V), the biggest bank-card
            network, reported a fiscal third-quarter profit that beat
            analysts' estimates as worldwide spending on credit and debit
            cards climbed. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Net income for the three months ended June 30 was $1.23
            billion, or $1.88 a share, compared with a loss of $1.84
            billion, or $2.74, a year earlier that included a litigation
            expense, the Foster City, California-based firm said yesterday
            in a statement. The average estimate of 33 analysts surveyed by
            Bloomberg was for earnings of $1.80 a share. Profit excluding
            special items from the third quarter of 2012 climbed 16 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chief Executive Officer Charlie Scharf is seeking to
            bolster Visa's business outside the U.S., where it gets more
            than half its revenue, as consumers worldwide continue to
            migrate from cash and checks to electronic payments. The company
            has returned more than $15 billion to shareholders since 2008. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'The opportunity to move transactions from cash to
            electronic means is still huge,' Scharf said in a conference
            call with analysts. 'This is true in both the developed and the
            developing parts of the world.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa rose 2 percent to $190.50 in extended trading in New
            York yesterday after results were announced. The shares climbed
            23 percent this year through the close of regular trading,
            outpacing the 9.3 percent advance for the 70-company Standard
            Poor's 500 Information Technology Index. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Share Repurchases &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The company repurchased $981 million of its stock during
            the quarter at an average of $176.75 a share and may buy back an
            additional $1.5 billion through next July, according to the
            statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Third-quarter operating revenue climbed 17 percent to $3
            billion, beating the $2.89 billion average estimate of analysts
            surveyed by Bloomberg. Revenue will increase about 13 percent
            this fiscal year, according to the statement. Earnings per share
            will rise by more than 20 percent, the company said, after an
            earlier forecast of 'around' 20 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Worldwide spending on Visa cards climbed 13 percent to
            $1.09 trillion, adjusted for currency fluctuations, according to
            the statement. Processed transactions rose 14 percent to 15
            billion. Cross-border purchases, or spending by cardholders
            outside their home countries, advanced 11 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;U.S. Performance &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In the U.S., debit-card purchases advanced 12 percent to
            $300 billion, and credit-card spending increased 10 percent to
            $270 billion, according to the statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa and No. 2 network MasterCard Inc. agreed last year to
            a $7.25 billion settlement over the fees charged to merchants
            when consumers pay with credit cards. Visa sued Wal-Mart Stores
            Inc. last month to stop the biggest U.S. retailer from filing a
            lawsuit that would prolong the eight-year legal battle the
            settlement seeks to end. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Scharf, 48, has pledged to be more flexible in responding
            to the demands of Visa's business partners and in February the
            company reached agreement with JPMorgan Chase Co., the biggest
            U.S. card issuer, to let the lender tailor payment solutions for
            merchants. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;American Express Co., the New York-based card issuer that
            also runs the third-largest U.S. bank-card network, said July 18
            that second-quarter profit rose 4.9 percent to $1.41 billion as
            customer purchases increased. Riverwoods, Illinois-based
            Discover Financial Services, the No. 4 network, said yesterday
            that quarterly net income climbed 15 percent to $602 million.
            MasterCard is set to report results July 31. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Jeremy Hodges" datetime="Jul 26, 2013 11:02 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="d"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-26/visa-sued-over-card-fees-by-u-k-retailers-from-asda-to-arcadia.html">
        <headline>Visa Sued Over Card Fees by U.K. Retailers Including Asda</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Inc., which operates the
            world's biggest electronic-payments network, was sued by Wal-Mart Stores Inc. (WMT)'s Asda unit, William
            Morrison Supermarkets Plc
            and Arcadia Group Plc over payment-processing fees. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The three companies sued Visa and its former European
            affiliate Visa Europe Ltd., at a London court on July 23,
            according to court records. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The European Union proposed caps this week on such levies,
            known as interchange fees, that banks can demand from retailers
            at 0.2 percent for debit card payments and 0.3 percent for
            credit cards. MasterCard Inc. (MA) is also being sued by more than a
            dozen companies over the fees in the U.K., including Asda and
            Morrison, the U.K.'s fourth-largest grocery store chain. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'We have not seen this claim,' a spokesman for Visa
            Europe, Mark Hooper, said in an e-mail. 'We are surprised that
            a case might be brought and, if it was, would strongly contest
            it.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Tania Foster-Brown, a spokeswoman for Arcadia, Russell Craig, a spokesman for Asda, and James
            French, a spokesman for
            Morrison, declined to comment beyond confirming the subject of
            the lawsuits. Comet Group Ltd., Iceland Foods Group Ltd., and
            six others also filed lawsuits on the same day. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The EU's antitrust regulators have been reviewing credit
            and debit card fees for over a decade, warning that the way the
            charges are agreed is anti-competitive. The bloc's agency said
            in 2007 that MasterCard's fees for cross-border card payments
            violated antitrust rules, unfairly inflating the fees paid by
            retailers for processing payments. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;While interchange fees can be agreed on by banks, card
            companies such as Visa and MasterCard provide default ones that
            are used unless lenders comes to their own bilateral
            arrangements. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Europe split from Visa Inc. (V) before the U.S. card
            company's initial public offering in early 2008. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The case is Asda Stores Ltd. v Visa Inc. Ors, case no.
            13-984, U.K. High Court of Justice, Queen's Bench Division. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>

    <entry author="By Donal Griffin" datetime="Jul 31, 2013  1:01 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="d"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-31/visa-falls-after-court-ruling-on-swipe-fees-san-francisco-mover.html">
        <headline>Visa Falls After Court Ruling on Swipe Fees: San Francisco Mover</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Inc. (V), the world's biggest
            payment network, fell the most in two years after a judge ruled
            that the Federal Reserve had erred by inflating the debit-card
            fees that banks can charge retailers. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa fell as much as 11 percent in New York trading before
            dropping 5.9 percent to $180.15 at 12:43 p.m., the most since
            August 2011. Swipe, or interchange fees, are set by Foster City,
            California-based Visa and MasterCard (MA) Inc., which collect the
            money and remit it to card-issuing member banks. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;U.S. District Court Judge Richard Leon in Washington ruled
            today that the Fed considered data it wasn't allowed to use in
            setting a 21-cent cap on debit-card fees under the Dodd-Frank
            Act of 2010. The decision handed a victory to retailers who
            challenged the fees as being too high. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;MasterCard, the second-biggest U.S. network, slid as much
            as 5.7 percent before falling 0.2 percent to $600.38. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Elizabeth Dexheimer" datetime="Jun 03, 2014 11:22 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="n"
           progress_sentiment="d"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-03/visa-says-cfo-pollitt-plans-to-retire-within-12-months.html">
        <headline>Visa CFO Pollitt Plans to Retire Within 12 Months</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Inc. (V) Chief Financial Officer
            Byron H. Pollitt Jr., who joined the biggest bank-card network
            the year before its 2008 IPO, will retire within the next 12
            months. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Pollitt, 62, who has been CFO for seven years, will assist
            in the search for a successor and in the transition, Foster
            City, California-based Visa said today in a regulatory filing. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Pollitt's retirement will leave four executives remaining
            on the company's management team from before its initial public
            offering: Antonio Lucio, chief brand officer; Jim McCarthy, head
            of innovation and strategic partnership; Ellen Richey, chief
            legal and risk officer; and head of corporate strategy Bill Sheedy. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Elizabeth Buse, 53, who previously ran most of the firm's
            international business, retired in March after more than 16
            years at the company. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Pollitt previously served as CFO at Gap Inc. and Walt
            Disney Co. and is a graduate of the University of California
            Riverside and Harvard Business School. He received total
            compensation of about $7.6 million in 2013, which included stock
            awarded in prior years, according to a regulatory filing. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Kelly Mahon Tullier, a senior vice president at PepsiCo
            Inc., will join as general counsel and a member of the firm's
            executive committee in October, Visa said in April. Former
            General Counsel Josh Floum left last year to return to private
            practice and was replaced on an interim basis by Richey, the
            company said in December. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa fell 0.9 percent to $211.65 at 10:10 a.m. in New York
            and has slid 4.8 percent this year. The shares have increased
            almost fivefold since the company went public. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Paul Cohen, a spokesman for Visa, declined to elaborate on
            Pollitt's retirement or the firm's succession plans. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Olga Kharif" datetime="Jun 04, 2014 12:01 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-04/yogurt-sales-go-mobile-as-stores-delay-visa-backed-chips.html">
        <headline>Yogurt Sales Go Mobile as Stores Delay Visa-Backed Chips</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Orange Leaf Frozen Yogurt, a small
            chain with exotic flavors like gingerbread and kiwi, is facing a
            tough technology choice: sink thousands of dollars into new
            credit card-reading machines by next year, or run the risk of
            fraud by waiting and adopting cheaper mobile-payment services. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;By October 2015, Orange Leaf and most of the country's 6
            million small merchants that accept credit cards are supposed to
            be ready to take cards with an embedded chip for extra security
            -- or credit-card networks may consider them liable for some
            fraud in their stores. The new cards require a technology
            called EMV that helps prevent fraud by assigning a unique code
            for every transaction. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Another option is to delay EMV and press ahead with plans
            to take payments via mobile devices, often a more convenient
            approach that's less expensive to implement and can even
            generate revenue for merchants by using smartphone applications
            to build relationships with customers. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Using a mobile wallet is a better choice right now,'
            said Michael Christy, Orange Leaf's director of information
            technology. 'We can control that, and the technical
            requirements are minimal. We want to make sure we save our
            franchisees money.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Christy's choice underscores the dilemma facing millions of
            businesses seeking to avoid the data losses that have plagued
            Target Corp. and Neiman Marcus Group Ltd. -- while aiming to cut
            costs and embrace the boom in demand for smartphones that also
            offer useful payment methods. While big companies like Wal-Mart
            Stores Inc. can afford the costs of EMV, which can run as much
            as $1,000 per checkout lane, many smaller businesses are under
            pressure to convert to the chip cards just as mobile payments
            start to gain popularity. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Skipping Generation &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'It's unfortunate,' said Doug Brown, general manager of
            mobile at payment-technology provider FIS. 'Longer-term, it'd
            be better if we could just skip a generation and just go to
            mobile payments.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In five to seven years, more than half of in-store
            transactions will be made with mobile phones instead of plastic,
            said Brown, whose Jacksonville, Florida-based company helps more
            than 14,000 financial companies use payments including EMV and
            mobile. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Today, many businesses aren't ready for EMV. According to
            Javelin Strategy Research, only about one in five businesses
            with fewer than 10 employees will be outfitted for the new
            technology by next year's deadline, which the credit-card
            companies refer to as the 'liability shift' because retailers
            will need to assume more responsibility when people make
            fraudulent transactions in their stores. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;New Equipment &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;To begin accepting EMV, stores have to get new equipment to
            read the cards' internal security chips, and a signature or PIN
            are typically used to complete a sale. The technology is
            considered more secure because EMV cards create a unique code
            for each transaction, making them more difficult to hack or
            counterfeit than striped cards. All EMV cards also have magnetic
            stripes, so they can work on older store payment terminals. EMV
            is an acronym for Europay, MasterCard and Visa, the companies
            that are pushing its adoption. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;While mobile-payment systems vary, they often work by
            storing credit-card data on a remote server and scanning a QR
            code with a phone. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Orange Leaf, which has 315 stores in the U.S., is rolling
            out a mobile-payment system for a quarter of the cost of EMV-capable technology, Christy said in an
            interview. The Oklahoma
            City-based yogurt chain is simply upgrading its current
            transaction software so customers can easily use a mobile-phone
            app from FIS and mobile-payment startup Paydiant Inc. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Phasing In &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Orange Leaf's current payment hardware can last another
            four to seven years, Christy said. Like many smaller merchants,
            it may make sense for him to wait to phase in EMV as his older
            hardware wears out. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Many small businesses don't see enough fraud to justify
            upgrading their hardware and moving to the more secure cards,
            Richard Crone, chief executive officer of payment consultancy
            Crone Consulting LLC, said in an interview. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'The fraud is tiny, in terms of transactions,' Crone
            said. 'You are talking about a minuscule amount.' Small
            businesses see fraud in 0.03 percent to 0.05 percent of all in-store transactions, he said; that means that
            a merchant with
            $500,000 in annual sales may see less than $250 in fraudulent
            sales a year. And the liability shift won't even apply in some
            situations, such as when a customer's bank hasn't yet issued an
            EMV card. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Boosting Revenue &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Companies like FIS and Paydiant also help keep mobile
            transactions secure by storing and encrypting credit-card
            information on behalf of their clients. Some mobile-payment
            systems store financial data on the device itself, which could
            be more vulnerable to hackers. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Unlike EMV, mobile payments can help merchants boost
            revenue. Mobile applications give businesses a way to track
            loyalty-card holders, distribute coupons and publish ads. Mobile
            apps can also let consumers scan items with their phones and
            self-checkout from anywhere in the store. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Mobile payments can work in a variety of ways. Orange
            Leaf's app will let consumers scan a special QR code with their
            phone at checkout. Consumers can use a credit card to upload
            money to be used through the app. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;While many retailers are enthusiastic about mobile
            payments, consumers have been slow to embrace them. Starbucks
            Corp.'s mobile app now has 10 million users after being
            introduced nationwide in 2011, and mobile payments now account
            for more than 14 percent of tender in its company-operated
            stores in the U.S. and Canada. It takes time to train customers
            and employees to use a new payment system. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Slower Transactions &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;EMV cards require their own learning curve and may also
            lead to slower transactions since they have to be inserted into
            in-store terminals throughout the entire checkout process.
            Still, large stores will probably have to upgrade to EMV
            technology because they tend to see more fraud. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'They, obviously, have far more to be concerned about, at
            least in the initial liability-shift discussion,' said Greg
            Boardman, a senior vice president at Ingenico, one of the
            world's biggest EMV-terminal makers. 'Having said that, the
            small merchant doesn't have the financial resources to absorb a
            lot of fraud loss.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>

    <entry author="By Jim Brunsden" datetime="Jun 13, 2013  5:45 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="n" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-13/visa-europe-s-offer-to-end-card-fee-probe-is-market-tested-by-eu.html">
        <headline>Visa Europe's Offer to End Card-Fee Probe Is Market Tested by EU</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;European Union antitrust regulators
            invited comments on Visa Europe Ltd.'s offer to cut
            'significantly' the fees it sets for processing cross-border
            credit-card payments in a bid to end an EU antitrust probe. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Europe's offer from last month would bring its fees
            into line with those of its main competitor MasterCard Inc. (MA), the
            European Commission said in an e-mailed statement today. The
            operator of the EU's largest payment-card network has also
            offered to overhaul its rules so that banks will be able to
            apply a reduced interbank fee when they compete for clients
            across borders. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'If the proposals address the commission's competition
            concerns, the commission may decide to make them legally binding
            on Visa Europe' in exchange for ending the probe, the regulator
            said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The commission sent a formal complaint to Visa about the
            interchange fees last year, as part of a broader campaign it has
            waged against such charges. MasterCard has started a legal
            challenge against a settlement it reached with the commission in
            2009 to avoid a daily penalty of as much as 3.5 percent of
            sales. The EU is also probing MasterCard's bank fees on foreign
            card payments such as when tourists go shopping in the 27-nation
            bloc. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The EU regulator also announced today that it has closed a
            probe into the European Payments Council, an association of
            banks that seeks to standardize payments practices, after the
            body stopped its work on e-payment rules at the center of the
            probe. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>

    <entry author="By Christie Smythe and Bob Van Voris" datetime="Jun 26, 2013  6:03 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s"
           progress_sentiment="d"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-26/amazon-com-7-eleven-sue-visa-and-mastercard-over-fees.html">
        <headline>Amazon.com, 7-Eleven Sue Visa and MasterCard Over Fees</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Amazon.com Inc. (AMZN) and 7-Eleven Inc.
            sued Visa Inc. (V) and MasterCard Inc. (MA) over card fees after
            rejecting a multibillion-dollar settlement in an antitrust case. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The retailers and about 30 others filed a lawsuit in
            federal court in Manhattan against the card companies and
            several major banks. The companies are among more than 7,000
            that have dropped out of the $7.25 billion accord over the fees,
            which are borne by merchants when customers use credit cards. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Once Visa and MasterCard acquired substantial market
            power over merchants, they maintained it by forcing merchants to
            pay even higher interchange fees to continue to fund these
            price-fixing schemes,' the retailers said in the complaint
            filed today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The settlement, under consideration by a federal judge in
            Brooklyn, New York, would put to rest about eight years of
            litigation in the nationwide suit. Dozens of retailers have said
            they're opposed to the accord because it would give Visa and
            MasterCard too much freedom to raise rates in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'These same tired arguments were already raised repeatedly
            over the course of the litigation,' Trish Wexler, a spokeswoman
            for the Electronic Payments Coalition, which represents card
            companies and banks, said in a statement. 'Had these arguments
            had any merit or strength, they would have been included in the
            final settlement.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Other Retailers &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Other retailers that dropped out of the settlement have
            also filed their own lawsuits, including CVS Pharmacy Inc. (CVS) and
            a group led by Target Corp. (TGT) and Macy's Inc. (M) &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa sued Wal-Mart Stores Inc. this month over concerns
            that the world's largest retailer would also file a separate
            swipe-fee complaint. The payment network said in a complaint
            that it wanted to prevent 'the continuation of endless,
            wasteful litigation.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The case is 7-Eleven Inc. v. Visa Inc., 13-cv-4442, U.S.
            District Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>


    <entry author="By Elizabeth Dexheimer" datetime="Mar 05, 2014  4:03 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s"
           progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-03-05/visa-says-fraud-costs-to-escalate-as-hackers-innovate.html">
        <headline>Visa Says Fraud Costs to Escalate as Hackers Innovate</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Payment networks, retailers and
            banks will continue to face significant costs to address fraud
            as hackers find new ways to steal data, according to Byron Pollitt, chief financial officer of Visa Inc. (V)
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'This is an investment cycle that never ends,' Pollitt
            said today at a technology conference in San Francisco. 'The
            resourcefulness, the intellect, the level of innovativeness in
            the fraud sector is absolutely amazing.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Lenders and merchants are under pressure to convert from
            magnetic strips to microchip technology that thwarts hackers
            after millions of consumer records were breached at retailers
            including Target Corp. One reason the conversion hasn't happened
            yet is because it's expensive for merchants to upgrade their
            systems and for lenders to issue new cards, said Pollitt, whose
            company is the world's biggest bank-card network. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'It's high investment and in the absence of a Target
            catalyst, I doubt that we would be on the track we are on
            today,' Pollitt said. The chip will address about 70 percent of
            fraud, he said. Including a requirement that consumers enter
            personal identification numbers, or PINs, would 'dramatically'
            slow its implementation because about two-thirds of retailers
            don't have the necessary equipment, Pollitt said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;American Express Co., Foster City, California-based Visa
            and MasterCard Inc. have given most U.S. merchants and issuers
            until October 2015 to adopt chips -- named EMV for founders
            EuroPay International, MasterCard and Visa. Those that refuse
            would assume liability for counterfeit card transactions. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;They are also pushing retailers to use 'tokenization,'
            where some account information is replaced with a digital ID for
            online and mobile purchases. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>

    <entry author="By Elizabeth Dexheimer" datetime="Mar 07, 2014 10:17 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="h"
           progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-03-07/mastercard-visa-form-working-group-with-merchants-on-security.html">
        <headline>MasterCard, Visa Form Working Group With Merchants on Security</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Inc. (V) and MasterCard Inc. (MA), the
            two biggest payment networks, created a working group with
            banks and merchants to accelerate the adoption of EMV chip
            technology to thwart fraud. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The group was established following recent retail data
            breaches, Purchase, New York-based MasterCard said today in an
            e-mailed statement. The group, whose other members weren't
            identified, will focus on security issues that address in-store
            and online purchases. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Lenders and merchants are under pressure to convert card
            security from magnetic strips to microchips after millions of
            consumer records were breached at retailers including Target
            Corp. American Express Co., Visa and MasterCard have given most
            U.S. merchants and issuers until October 2015 to adopt chips --
            named EMV for founders EuroPay International, MasterCard and
            Visa. Those that refuse would assume liability for counterfeit
            card transactions. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Networks are also pushing retailers to use
            'tokenization,' where some account information is replaced
            with a digital ID for online and mobile purchases. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Elizabeth Dexheimer" datetime="Mar 13, 2014  4:05 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="n"
           progress_sentiment="d"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-03-13/visa-head-of-global-solutions-group-buse-plans-to-retire.html">
        <headline>Visa Head of Global Solutions Group Buse Plans to Retire</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Elizabeth Buse, a top executive at
            Visa (V) Inc. who previously ran most of the firm's international
            business, is leaving after more than 16 years. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Buse, 53, was most recently the head of the global-solutions group, Foster City, California-based
            Visa said today
            in a filing with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission.
            Buse is retiring March 31, according to the filing. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Throughout her career, Elizabeth has worked tirelessly to
            build a stronger, more effective and engaged Visa,' Chief
            Executive Officer Charlie Scharf, 48, said in a statement. 'I
            am thankful for the foundation she has created for us to work
            from and wish her well.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa also said today that Ramon Martin, a former president
            of merchant services at American Express Co. (AXP), will be joining
            the firm. Martin will lead work related to merchant products
            that Buse previously did, according to a person familiar with
            the matter who asked not to be identified because the plans are
            private. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Buse was appointed to her role in the new global-solutions
            unit in May. She started her career at Visa in the product-organization group and was the first executive to
            oversee the
            firm's business in the Asia Pacific, Central and Eastern Europe,
            Middle East and Africa regions, the filing said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Shares of Visa fell 2.3 percent to $220.83 at 3:28 p.m. in
            New York. They have decreased less than 1 percent this year, and
            were the sixth-best performer in the 30-company Dow Jones
            Industrial Average for 2013, rising 47 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Ilya Arkhipov and Jason Corcoran" datetime="Mar 27, 2014  9:45 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="s"
           progress_sentiment="d"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-03-27/putin-touts-russian-proxy-for-visa-mastercard-after-sanctions.html">
        <headline>Putin Touts Russian Proxy for Visa, MasterCard After Sanctions</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;President Vladimir Putin said
            Russia must develop its own payments network, with companies
            that blocked some transactions following U.S. sanctions on
            Russian individuals and a bank at risk of losing market share. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'This wasn't our decision,' Putin said at a meeting with
            lawmakers outside Moscow today, adding that developing a
            domestic system will take time. 'We need to defend our
            interests. And we'll do that.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Inc. (V) and MasterCard Inc. (MA) stopped processing cards for
            Bank Rossiya after the U.S. placed the lender on its sanctions
            list. SMP Bank, which also had its cards blocked by the two
            biggest card networks, said March 23 that services would resume
            soon. SMP Bank's co-owners Arkady Rotenberg and brother Boris
            were also hit with sanctions. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The sanctions prohibit U.S. firms or individuals from doing
            business with Bank Rossiya, the U.S. Treasury said on its
            website on March 20. Russia's 17th biggest lender has about $10
            billion in assets, 'numerous relationships' with banks in the
            U.S. and Europe, and was targeted because its owners are close
            associates of President Vladimir Putin, the Treasury said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Putin last week said he would open his personal account in
            the bank targeted by the U.S. and have his salary payments
            transfered there. &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: Sasha Mordovets/Getty Images

            &lt;p&gt;
            Russian President Vladimir Putin attends a meeting with members of the Council of the Federation on March
            27, 2014. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Dakin Campbell" datetime="May 01, 2013  8:31 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-01/visa-profit-beats-estimates-as-consumer-card-spending-increases.html">
        <headline>Visa Profit Beats Estimates as Card Spending Rises</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;(Corrects worldwide spending total in eighth paragraph.) &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Inc. (V), the world's biggest
            payments network, posted a fiscal second-quarter profit that
            beat analysts' estimates as consumer spending on credit and
            debit cards climbed. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Net income for the three months ended March 31 fell 1.7
            percent to $1.27 billion, or $1.92 a share, from $1.29 billion,
            or $1.91, a year earlier, when there were more shares
            outstanding, the Foster City, California-based company said
            today in a statement. That beat the $1.81 average estimate of 32
            analysts surveyed by Bloomberg. Net income a year earlier was
            helped by a one-time tax-related gain of $208 million. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa, led by Chief Executive Officer Charlie Scharf,
            increased dividends and stepped up share repurchases as the firm
            gained financial flexibility after joining rival MasterCard Inc. (MA)
            in agreeing to a multibillion settlement with merchants over
            card swipe fees. Visa also struck a deal in February with
            JPMorgan Chase Co., the biggest U.S. card lender, to let the
            bank tailor payment solutions for merchants. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'To drive future transaction growth, we continue to invest
            in new technologies, channels and capabilities to make Visa
            transactions more valuable, accessible and secure,' Scharf, 48,
            said in the statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The payment processor raised its forecast for adjusted
            annual earnings per share growth to about 20 percent, from the
            'high teens' projected in February. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Shares Advance &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa climbed 2.1 percent to $169.50 at 4:42 p.m. in
            extended trading in New York. The shares climbed 9.5 percent
            this year through the close of regular trading, outpacing the
            4.2 percent advance for the 70-company Standard Poor's 500
            Information Technology Index. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;MasterCard, the world's second-largest payments network by
            processed transactions, said earlier today that first-quarter
            profit increased 12 percent to $766 million. Revenue at the
            Purchase, New York-based firm climbed 8.4 percent to $1.91
            billion, short of the $1.93 billion estimate of analysts in a
            Bloomberg survey. The shares, which touched an all-time high
            yesterday, fell 2.5 percent to $539.18, the most since July. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa's total operating revenue climbed 15 percent to $2.96
            billion, beating the $2.85 billion estimate of analysts surveyed
            by Bloomberg. Worldwide spending on Visa payment cards climbed
            8.8 percent to $1.03 trillion, adjusted for currency
            fluctuations, according to the statement. Processed transactions
            rose 6.2 percent to 13.9 billion. Cross-border volume, a measure
            of spending by cardholders outside their home countries,
            advanced 10 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Spending on Visa debit cards in the U.S. rose 0.3 percent
            to $285 billion, the first increase in a year, according to the
            statement. U.S. credit-card purchases climbed 9.1 percent to
            $244 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;U.S. consumer spending, which accounts for about 70 percent
            of the nation's economy, cooled in March after higher payroll
            taxes took effect in January. Scharf seeks to bolster Visa's
            growth outside the U.S. as the company has said it hopes to get
            more than half of its revenue abroad by 2015. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Stephanie Bodoni" datetime="May 14, 2013  7:33 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-14/visa-europe-offers-to-cap-credit-card-fees-to-settle-eu-probe.html">
        <headline>Visa Europe Offers to Cap Credit-Card Fees to End EU Probe</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Europe Ltd. plans to
            'significantly' reduce the fees it sets for processing cross-border credit-card payments in a bid to allay
            European Union
            competition concerns, the bloc's antitrust watchdog said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Europe's offer would bring its fees in line with those
            of its main competitor MasterCard Inc. (MA), the European Commission
            said today. The operator of the EU's largest payment-card
            network also committed to overhaul its rules so that banks will
            be able to apply a reduced cross-border interbank fee when they
            compete for clients cross-border. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'It will put at the same level the fees that are used by
            MasterCard and by Visa and this will allow cheaper use of cards
            that are a payment system used in almost half of our total
            payments in the EU,' Joaquin Almunia, the EU's antitrust
            commissioner, said in a video statement. Visa Europe's offer
            will mean 'the two big credit and debit card companies' can't
            use 'their market position to have extra profits.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Europe proposed to reduce by 40 percent to 60 percent
            its so-called interbank fees for credit-card payments to a level
            of 0.3 percent of the value of the transaction for cross-border
            and domestic transactions, the commission said. The remedies
            would last for four years. Visa Europe was sent a formal
            complaint over the levies last year. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Market Test &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Almunia said antitrust officials will carry out a so-called
            market test with industry groups before deciding to make the
            commitments legally binding. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Merchants will now be able to benefit from centralizing
            their acquiring in one place, which will bring benefits to the
            European economy as a whole,' said Ruth Milligan, senior
            adviser on payments at EuroCommerce, a group representing EU
            retailers including Carrefour SA (CA) and Ikea Group. Acquiring banks
            are those that process card payments on behalf of shops and
            traders. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'We have long argued that the card scheme's rule on cross-border acquiring were wholly contrary to
            single market
            principles and are delighted to see them go,' said Milligan. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;MasterCard in 2009 in a settlement with the Brussels-based EU regulator agreed to similar fee
            changes to avoid a
            daily penalty of as much as 3.5 percent of sales. MasterCard is
            appealing that decision at the EU courts in Luxembourg. Last
            month, the EU said it is probing MasterCard's bank fees on
            foreign card payments such as when tourists go shopping in the
            27-nation bloc. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Inflate Costs &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Europe's so-called multilateral interchange fees
            'harm competition between acquiring banks, inflate the cost of
            payment card acceptance for merchants and ultimately increase
            consumer prices,' the commission said today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;An earlier probe into Visa Europe's fees for debit-card
            payments made outside a user's home country was settled in 2011.
            The company split from Visa Inc. (V) before the U.S. card company's
            initial public offering in early 2008. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Today's outcome is the result of constructive dialogue
            between Visa Europe and the European Commission and is in line
            with the level of 0.3 percent established in the industry,'
            Peter Ayliffe, Visa Europe's chief executive officer, said in an
            e-mailed statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Christie Smythe" datetime="May 15, 2013  3:35 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s" progress_sentiment="d"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-15/visa-mastercard-swipe-deal-draws-little-rock-objection.html">
        <headline>Visa, MasterCard Swipe Deal Draws Little Rock Objection</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Little Rock, Arkansas, objected to a
            multibillion-dollar settlement of a price-fixing case against
            Visa Inc. (V) and MasterCard Inc. (MA) over the fees charged to merchants
            to process credit-card transactions. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The settlement doesn't address potential future fixing of
            the so-called interchange or swipe fees and contains
            'unacceptable obligations,' City Manager Bruce T. Moore said
            in a filing today in federal court in Brooklyn, New York, where
            the agreement is under review. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The proposed $7.25 billion settlement, estimated to be the
            largest-ever U.S. antitrust accord, has drawn criticism from
            trade associations and retailers, which contend that it grants
            the card companies too much leeway to raise rates in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Bentonville, Arkansas-based Wal-Mart Stores Inc. (WMT), the
            world's largest retailer, said in a statement in July that it
            was 'disappointed' in the settlement and would encourage
            merchants to reject the deal. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Little Rock, the state capital and home to department-store
            chain Dillard's Inc. (DDS), said it was protesting the settlement in
            its capacity as a potential member of a class that has accepted
            Visa and MasterCard credit-card payments. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Separately, the city of Oakland, California, also filed an
            objection to the settlement today. The city, which also accepts
            credit-card payments, said the accord 'explicitly permits Visa
            and MasterCard to continue to fix interchange fees for their
            banks,' forcing consumers to pay higher prices. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Higher Prices &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Interchange fees on credit card transactions result in
            higher prices for Oakland's residents, and amount to a hidden
            and regressive tax on goods and services,' the city said in its
            objection, filed by attorney Jeffrey Shinder, who is also
            representing several trade associations that oppose the deal. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Hundreds of objections have been filed since U.S. District
            Judge John Gleeson gave a preliminary sign-off to the deal in
            November, including many from smaller retailers and merchants. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Large retailers including Target Corp. (TGT) and Home Depot Inc. (HD)
            have also spoken out against the accord. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Last month, Gleeson ordered that corrections be made to
            websites established by groups opposing the settlement,
            including Merchantsobject.com, which directed business owners to
            pages where they could submit objections electronically. The
            judge said that the sites were misleading and failed to
            prominently display a link to a court-approved website,
            paymentcardsettlement.com. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Consider Remedies &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;At a follow-up hearing earlier this month, Gleeson said he
            would consider remedies for merchants that dropped out of the
            settlement, leaving them unable to receive payments for damages,
            based on what he described as misleading information on the
            sites. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The settlement was unveiled in July after about seven years
            of litigation. A hearing on final approval of the deal, which
            would cover merchants throughout the U.S., is scheduled for
            Sept. 12. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The case is In re Payment Card Interchange Fee and Merchant
            Discount Antitrust Litigation, 05-md-01720, U.S. District Court,
            Eastern District of New York (Brooklyn). &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By David McLaughlin" datetime="May 21, 2013  4:58 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="n" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-21/wal-mart-among-retailers-opting-out-of-visa-mastercard-deal.html">
        <headline>Wal-Mart Among Retailers Quitting Visa, MasterCard Deal</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Wal-Mart Stores Inc. (WMT) and Starbucks
            Corp. (SBUX) are among 19 retailers opting out of a $7.25 billion
            antitrust settlement with Visa Inc. (V) and MasterCard Inc. (MA) over
            fees charged to merchants to process credit-card transactions. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The proposed settlement would maintain and strengthens an
            anticompetitive system that allows Visa and MasterCard to fix
            so-called swipe fees for banks, the companies said today. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'It would allow credit card companies and big banks to
            perpetuate an unfair and broken system that costs all
            consumers,' Mike Cook, senior vice president of finance for
            Wal-Mart, said in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The settlement, estimated to be the largest-ever U.S.
            antitrust accord, has drawn criticism from trade associations
            and retailers contending that it grants the card companies too
            much leeway to raise rates. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa, based Foster City, California, and MasterCard, based
            in Purchase, New York, agreed to settle the case to resolve the
            legal battle over interchange fees, which are charged to
            merchants when customers pay with credit cards. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The settlement received tentative approval from a federal
            judge in Brooklyn, New York, in November. A hearing on final
            approval is set for Sept. 12. &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: Daniel Acker/Bloomberg

            &lt;p&gt;
            Wal-Mart Stores Inc., the world's largest retailer, said in a statement in July that it was 'disappointed'
            in the antitrust settlement with Visa Inc. and MasterCard Inc. and would encourage merchants to reject the
            deal. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Julie Bykowicz" datetime="May 22, 2013  1:48 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="n" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-22/tech-industry-after-2007-loss-drafts-own-rules-for-visas.html">
        <headline>Tech Industry After 2007 Loss Drafts Own Rules for Visas</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Technology companies, including Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) and Intel Corp. (INTC), have failed at
            almost every turn in their quest to persuade federal lawmakers to let them hire more foreign-born workers.
            &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In 2003, Congress took back 130,000 temporary work visas. Four years later, Silicon
            Valley was surprised when proposed legislation didn't come close to addressing companies' skilled-worker
            needs. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;After the 2007 loss, the industry took a new tack. Tech leaders helped write
            legislative drafts spelling out what they wanted; they broadened their pitch about immigration to include
            legalizing undocumented immigrants in the country; and they now are using social media to press their case.
            &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;'We knew we had to get into the game early and go strong,' said Robert Hoffman, senior
            vice president of government relations for the Information Technology Industry Council, which lobbies for
            technology companies. 'We knew we had to think several steps down the road.' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Silicon
            Valley's role in pushing for changes in immigration law adds economic urgency to a debate that for more than
            a decade has focused mostly on the treatment of 11 million undocumented residents. The tech community's
            engagement also brought to the table companies with the power to mobilize thousands of supporters to join
            ranks with the Latino community. &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: David Paul Morris/Bloomberg

            &lt;p&gt;
            A Facebook Inc. employee works on a laptop computer at the company's campus in Menlo Park, California. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Ekaterina Shatalova, Olga Tanas and Elizabeth Dexheimer" datetime="May 23, 2014  5:00 PM ET"
           feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-05-23/visa-mastercard-to-stay-in-russia-as-government-softens-stance.html">
        <headline>Visa, MasterCard Stay in Russia as Government Backs Off</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Inc. (V) and MasterCard Inc. (MA) plan to
            keep operating in Russia after President Vladimir Putin's
            government backed away from punishing the payments firms in
            response to U.S. sanctions. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa and MasterCard executives met with senior officials
            including First Deputy Prime Minister Igor Shuvalov and came
            away 'very positive' about finding a solution, Visa's country
            chief, Andrew Torre, said at the St. Petersburg International
            Economic Forum yesterday. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Russia will consider easing new measures requiring the two
            U.S. companies to pay hundreds of millions of dollars to
            continue operating, MasterCard Russia chief Ilya Riaby said. At
            stake is an estimated $403 million in combined annual revenue
            for the two payments networks as well as their foothold in a
            market that's shifting from cash to electronic payments. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;After Visa and MasterCard stopped processing payments at
            four Russian banks in response to U.S. sanctions over the crisis
            in Ukraine, Russia passed a law creating its own national
            payments system and imposing rules for foreign firms that
            include fines for denying services and a mandatory security
            deposit starting in July. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The government is committed to working with Visa and
            MasterCard, Deputy Finance Minister Alexey Moiseev said in an
            interview with Bloomberg TV. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Moiseev said the U.S. companies agreed to create a
            'nationally important' operator within 18 months. Under the
            new law, such operators are exempt from having to post
            collateral with the central bank, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;More Talks &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The companies have not yet reached a formal agreement and
            'look forward to continuing the dialog,' Paul Cohen, a
            spokesman for Visa, said in a statement. MasterCard's
            suggestions on changes to the new law were 'regarded
            favorably' and the company expects a response soon, according
            to Seth Eisen, a spokesman. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa and MasterCard have said they get about 2 percent of
            their annual revenue from Russia, or about $167 million last
            year for MasterCard and $236 million for Visa. The two control
            about 95 percent of the payments market in Russia, according to
            Morgan Stanley. Visa is based in Foster City, California, and
            runs the world's biggest payments network. MasterCard is based
            in Purchase, New York. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The bigger concern may not be the loss of revenue, 'but
            the risk of losing the opportunity for domestic processing in
            Russia,' Darrin Peller, an analyst at Barclays Plc, said in a
            research note, adding that 80 percent of transactions in Russia
            are done using cash. 'There will likely be a middle ground
            reached.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;(A previous version of this story was corrected to remove
            an erroneous combined revenue estimate in the third paragraph.) &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Halia Pavliva" datetime="May 25, 2014 11:28 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-05-25/qiwi-rally-seen-extending-as-visa-stays-in-russia.html">
        <headline>Qiwi Rally Seen Extending as Visa Stays in Russia</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;A 63 percent rally in Qiwi Plc (QIWI) in
            less than four weeks may be just the beginning for the
            electronic-payment processor as Russia eases restrictions that
            could have crimped its revenue, according to OAO Gazprombank and
            InvestCafe LLC. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Qiwi's American depositary receipts have surged to $43.85
            on May 23 from a nine-month low of $26.89 on April 28. The ADRs
            plunged earlier this year as Russia moved to tighten control of
            payment systems and imposed rules that could increase the cost
            of doing business for U.S.-based credit card companies including
            Visa Inc. and MasterCard Inc. The Bloomberg Russia-US Equity
            Index increased 4.5 percent in its fourth consecutive weekly
            gain. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Lawmakers dropped some provisions that could have limited
            online payments as they approved anti-money laundering
            legislation last month. Visa and MasterCard said on May 23 that
            they'll keep working in Russia after the government agreed to
            consider easing demands made on them after the U.S. imposed
            sanctions linked to the country's standoff with Ukraine. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Traders are shifting their focus to Qiwi's fundamentals
            as the credit card companies' decision to remain in Russia
            signals an improving business environment,' Sergey Vasin, an
            analyst at Gazprombank, said by phone from Moscow on May 23.
            'The trend is positive for Qiwi through the end of the year.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Vasin said he has begun covering Qiwi and expects to issue
            a recommendation and target price next month. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The company works in partnership with Visa, providing co-branded accounts marketed under the name
            Visa Qiwi Wallet. Those
            accounts increased increased 20 percent in the first quarter to
            15.6 million, Qiwi Chief Executive Officer Sergey Solonin said
            on a May 21 conference call with analysts. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Growth Forecast &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;After Visa and MasterCard stopped processing payments at
            four Russian banks in March as the U.S. imposed sanctions,
            Russia passed a law creating its own national payment system and
            imposing rules for foreign companies that include fining them
            for denying services. Solonin said Qiwi doesn't expect any of
            the new legislation to have much of an impact on its business in
            Russia. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Qiwi, which had more than tripled after it was listed in
            New York a year ago, expects net profit to increase between 27
            percent and 29 percent in 2014, according to its May 21 earnings
            statement. Adjusted net revenue increased 46 percent in the
            first quarter to 1.9 billion rubles ($55.6 million). &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Investors are focusing on Qiwi's improved growth forecast
            for this year and away from the fading geopolitical risks,'
            Timur Nigmatullin, an analyst at Moscow-based research firm
            InvestCafe, said by phone on May 22. He raised Qiwi to buy from
            hold on May 23, setting a price target at $52.37 per share. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Analyst Ratings &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Qiwi's 14-day relative strength index reached a nine-month
            high of 80.5 on May 22. When a security's RSI rises above 70,
            it's a signal to some analysts that it is poised to fall. The
            stock has seven buy ratings and three holds, according to data
            compiled by Bloomberg. The 28 percent advance in the five days
            ended May 23 was the biggest weekly gain since its initial
            public offering a year ago. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Bloomberg index of the most-traded Russian stocks in
            the U.S. increased to 88.75 on May 23 to complete the longest
            streak of weekly gains in 10 months. OAO RusHydro, the renewable
            energy producer, led the advance, jumping 19 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;United Co. Rusal (486), a Moscow-based aluminum producer,
            was little changed at HK$3.24 in Hong Kong trading as of
            11:25 a.m. local time. The MSCI Asia Pacific Index rose 0.2
            percent. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Poroshenko Wins &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Russian stocks had gained as concern eased that Ukraine's
            presidential election would be disrupted. President Vladimir
            Putin said on May 23 in St. Petersburg that Russia will work
            with the next Ukrainian president, even though the vote won't
            meet international standards, after saying he's withdrawing
            troops from the border. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Ukrainians elected billionaire Petro Poroshenko as
            president, two exit polls showed yesterday, handing him the task
            of stemming deadly separatist violence that's threatening to rip
            the former Soviet republic apart. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Poroshenko garnered more than half of the vote, avoiding a
            runoff with as much as 57.3 percent support, according to the
            surveys. Ex-Prime Minister Yulia Tymoshenko came second out of
            21 candidates with 12-13 percent backing, the polls showed.
            While most in Ukraine's easternmost regions didn't vote,
            Poroshenko's success was welcomed in the U.S. and Europe. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The drama in Ukraine will weigh on investors' risk appetite
            and shareholders in Qiwi are exposed to regulatory changes,
            according to David Riedel, founder of the Riedel Research Group
            Inc. in New York. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Russian equities will continue to be shunned by most
            investors other than the bravest and most adventurous,' he said
            by e-mail on May 23. 'I would be cautious on the enthusiasm for
            Qiwi payment system as the regulations and control there can be
            implemented very quickly if that avenue is being used to
            transfer money to avoid scrutiny.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Market Vectors Russia ETF (RSX), the biggest U.S. exchange-traded fund that holds Russian
            shares, jumped 5.4 percent last
            week to $25.72, the highest level since February. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Elizabeth Dexheimer" datetime="Nov 01, 2013 10:39 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="n"
           progress_sentiment="d"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-01/mastercard-momentum-over-visa-seen-building-as-europe-rebounds.html">
        <headline>MasterCard Momentum Over Visa Seen Rising as Europe Recovers</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;MasterCard Inc. (MA), the second-biggest U.S. payments network, is poised to further outperform
            bigger rival Visa Inc. amid a 3 percent gain by the euro this year and signs that European consumer spending
            is picking up. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;MasterCard, whose stock has outpaced Visa's in 2013, could gain another
            15 percent in two years as the sovereign-debt crisis eases, said Jason Kupferberg, an analyst at Jefferies
            Group LLC. Europe can boost MasterCard's purchase volume, transactions and revenue for at least the next two
            quarters, Sterne Agee Leach Inc.'s Greg Smith said. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;MasterCard does more business in
            Europe than Visa, which generates about 2 percent of its revenue in the region. Should Europe's economy and
            currency continue to strengthen at their current pace, Purchase, New York-based MasterCard is more likely to
            see a boost in profits and stock performance, both analysts said. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;'Europe is a
            significant catalyst for MasterCard relative to Visa,' Smith, who has a neutral rating on the company, said
            yesterday in a telephone interview. 'Assuming these general short trends continue, the underlying metrics
            are going to look a little better for MasterCard.' &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;MasterCard said yesterday in a
            statement that third-quarter net income rose 14 percent to $879 million, or $7.27 a share, as Europe credit-
            and debit-card spending climbed 14 percent. Visa, led by Chief Executive Officer Charlie Scharf, said on
            Oct. 30 that net income fell 28 percent as revenue missed analysts' forecasts. &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: Adam Berry/Bloomberg

            &lt;p&gt;
            A Mastercard ferris wheel in Berlin. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>

    <entry author="By Fanni Koszeg" datetime="Oct 01, 2013  5:19 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="h" progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-10-01/visa-joins-mastercard-amex-to-make-internet-purchases-safer-1-.html">
        <headline>Visa Joins MasterCard, AmEx to Make Internet Purchases Safer</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Inc. (V), MasterCard Inc. (MA) and
            American Express Co. (AXP), the biggest U.S. payment networks,
            proposed using 'digital tokens' instead of account numbers for
            processing purchases made online and with mobile devices. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Tokens provide an additional layer of security and
            eliminate the need for merchants, digital wallet operators or
            others to store account numbers,' the companies said today in a
            joint statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The standard, to be applied worldwide, will be presented to
            other payment firms and industry trade groups in coming weeks,
            according to the statement. Tokens would be the digital
            equivalent of magnetic stripes on the back of plastic bank cards
            that contain customer information. They also may help to reduce
            fraud by providing uniformity as companies such as Google Inc.
            and Starbucks Corp. (SBUX) embrace mobile commerce and offer consumers
            new ways to pay. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Mobile is the future,' Jim McCarthy, global head of
            innovation and strategic partnerships at Foster City,
            California-based Visa, said during the conference call. 'We
            haven't evolved to create a standard. For the first time, we are
            laying down the foundation.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Global card fraud losses for banks, merchants and
            processors climbed 15 percent last year to $11.3 billion from
            2011, according to the Nilson Report, a payments industry
            newsletter based in Carpinteria, California. Gross fraud losses
            in 2012 increased to 5.22 cents for every $100 in volume from
            5.07 cents a year earlier. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;EMV-Chip &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Tokens also would complement so-called EMV-chip technology,
            which has become a standard in Europe and much of the rest of
            the world. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The U.S. is among the last developed nations whose payment
            system relies primarily on cards with magnetic stripes and
            hasn't yet adopted EMV. Standards for the technology are managed
            by EMVCo, which was formed in 1999 by Europay International,
            Visa and Purchase, New York-based MasterCard. New York-based
            AmEx is also an EMVCo member. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;As merchants worldwide deploy more EMV terminals, fraud is
            moving toward transactions conducted online or over the
            telephone where physical payment cards aren't present, according
            to an August issue of the Nilson Report. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The U.S. has high fraud losses 'because it leads the world
            in online sales,' according to the trade publication. 'Smaller
            merchants who do not invest in fraud-fighting tools are
            particularly vulnerable.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Elizabeth Dexheimer" datetime="Oct 02, 2014  9:16 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="h"
           progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-10-02/visa-fends-off-usurpers-by-joining-apple-in-pay-system.html">
        <headline>How Visa Chief Is Fighting Back as Transactions Go Digital</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;A 4-foot-tall robot with a video screen for a head swerves past an orange couch and bumps into the
            wall of a conference room. A few feet away, an engineer tests a virtual reality headset that can allow a
            coffee-shop owner to forecast hot-chocolate sales during a blizzard. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This is Visa Inc.'s
            new outpost in San Francisco -- part executive office, part design laboratory and entirely the brainchild of
            Charlie Scharf, Visa's chief executive officer. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Scharf, who this July day had unveiled
            the latest version of the company's digital wallet, is sitting in an office overlooking San Francisco Bay
            one floor above the lab. He's wearing jeans, loafers and a gray shirt with no tie. One leg is propped up on
            his desk. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Moving into the heart of the city, 23 miles (37 kilometers) from Visa's
            suburban headquarters in Foster City, California, and three blocks from a Google Inc. office, is a statement
            about how Scharf is seeking to embrace the new technologies transforming the way consumers make payments,
            Bloomberg Markets will report in its November issue. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;More from the November issue of
            Bloomberg Markets:&lt;/p&gt;
            Coinbase Leads Move to Bring Bitcoin to Masses

            How Funding Circle Is Challenging Mainstream Lenders

            The Story Behind This Popular Bitcoin Photograph
            &lt;p&gt;'We have to think and act much more like a technology company than we have before,' Scharf says a
            few weeks later at a restaurant in Sag Harbor, New York, where he's on vacation with his family. 'The
            payments world is changing. There are new entrants, new opportunities for people to get into our business
            and other opportunities for us to grow our business in ways that didn't exist before.' &lt;/p&gt;


            Photographer: Ian Allen/Bloomberg Markets

            &lt;p&gt;
            Visa CEO Charlie Scharf at the company's new design lab in San Francisco. Close
            &lt;/p&gt;
        </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Edvard Pettersson" datetime="Oct 03, 2013  4:40 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="s"
           progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-10-03/smartmetric-loses-patent-ruling-in-visa-mastercard-case.html">
        <headline>SmartMetric Loses Patent Ruling in Visa, MasterCard Case</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Inc. (V) and MasterCard Inc. (MA) don't
            infringe a patent owned by SmartMetric Inc., a company that had
            sought as much as $13.4 billion for alleged use of its
            technology in 'smart' debit and credit cards. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;U.S. District Judge Michael W. Fitzgerald in Los Angeles,
            in a written ruling yesterday, affirmed his earlier tentative
            decision from a Sept. 25 hearing. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'The parties here are comparing apples and oranges,' the
            judge said in the written ruling. 'The piecemeal similarities
            that SmartMetric has identified in support of its claims do not
            change the fact that claims 1 and 14 of the '464 patent are
            simply not practiced by defendants, and no reasonable jury could
            conclude otherwise.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;SmartMetric sued Visa and MasterCard two years ago,
            claiming they infringed its patent for a system for automatic
            connection to a network. The company claimed it was entitled to
            a royalty of 25 percent of the anticipated savings Visa and
            MasterCard would receive from a drop in credit and debit-card
            fraud by the introduction of so-called EMV cards in the U.S. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The EMV cards, which are already used in Europe, include a
            microchip instead of a magnetic strip to access a payment
            system. The SmartMetric patent pertains to the process by which
            the payment system selects a network for a card transaction,
            Patrick Bright, the company's lawyer, said at the Sept. 25
            hearing. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;SmartMetric said in a statement today it will appeal the
            non-infringement ruling. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;SmartMetric fell 4 cents, or 20 percent, to 16 cents, today
            in over-the-counter trading. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The case is SmartMetric Inc. (SMME) v. MasterCard International
            Inc., 11-cv-07126, U.S. District Court, Central District of
            California (Los Angeles). &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>s
    <entry author="By Elizabeth Dexheimer" datetime="Oct 30, 2013  4:14 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="h"
           progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-10-30/visa-profit-matches-estimates-as-u-s-retail-sales-strengthen.html">
        <headline>Visa Profit Matches Estimates as U.S. Retail Sales Strengthen</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Inc. (V), the world's biggest bank-card network, posted a fiscal fourth-quarter profit that
            matched
            analysts' estimates as U.S. retail spending strengthened. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Net income for the three months ended Sept. 30 fell 28
            percent to $1.19 billion, or $1.85 a share, from $1.66 billion,
            or $2.47, a year earlier, the Foster City, California-based
            company said today in a statement. That equaled the average
            estimate of 31 analysts surveyed by Bloomberg. Results for the
            fourth quarter of 2012 were helped by a $627 million tax
            adjustment. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Retail sales in the U.S., where Visa gets more than half
            its revenue, rose toward the end of the quarter as September's
            0.4 percent gain in purchases excluding vehicles followed a 0.1
            percent increase in August. Chief Executive Officer Charlie Scharf also has pushed to expand abroad,
            particularly in
            emerging economies, where most spending is still done with cash. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'We continued investing in high-growth regions of the
            world, in products and technology to drive our performance,
            while maintaining disciplined expense control,' Scharf, 48,
            said in the statement. 'We also have been consistent and
            decisive in returning excess cash to shareholders and maintain
            this commitment.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa fell 0.2 percent to $203.82 at 4 p.m. in New York. The
            shares have increased 34 percent this year, outpacing the 19
            percent advance for the 30-company Dow Jones Industrial Average. (INDU) &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa, which has returned more than $15 billion to investors
            since its 2008 initial public offering, increased the quarterly
            dividend 21 percent to 40 cents last week. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'There's still a lot more to do considering how much
            excess cash this company has on its balance sheet,' Jason Kupferberg, an analyst at Jefferies Group LLC,
            said in an
            interview before results were announced. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;MasterCard Results &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;American Express Co. (AXP), the biggest credit-card issuer by
            purchases and operator of the third-largest U.S. payments
            network, said Oct. 16 that quarterly profit rose 9.3 percent to
            $1.37 billion on higher spending worldwide. Discover Financial
            Services (DFS), the No. 4 network, said last week that net income
            declined 6.9 percent as the company increased the amount of
            money set aside to cover future loan losses. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;MasterCard Inc. (MA), the second-biggest payments network by
            processed transactions, is scheduled to announce results before
            U.S. markets open tomorrow. The Purchase, New York-based company
            may report that third-quarter net income rose 9 percent to
            $841.4 million from a year earlier, according to the average
            estimate of 21 analysts in a Bloomberg survey. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa, MasterCard and the biggest U.S. banks are awaiting
            approval of a multibillion-dollar settlement over fees charged
            to merchants when consumers pay with credit cards. The decision
            by U.S. District Judge John Gleeson in Brooklyn, New York, could
            end an eight-year legal battle pitting the financial firms
            against retailers including Wal-Mart Stores Inc. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>

    <entry author="By Christie Smythe" datetime="Sep 12, 2013 12:00 AM ET" feeling_sentiment="n" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-09-12/visa-mastercard-judge-to-weigh-final-approval-of-fee-deal.html">
        <headline>Visa-MasterCard Judge to Weigh Final Approval of Fee Deal</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Inc. (V) and MasterCard Inc. (MA) will
            ask a judge to put to rest antitrust allegations that have
            plagued the companies for years over fees that are paid by U.S.
            merchants to support the credit card networks. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;U.S. District Judge John Gleeson in Brooklyn, New York,
            will hear arguments today over whether to grant final approval
            to a multibillion-dollar class-action settlement on behalf of
            merchants nationwide. Opposed by scores of big-box retailers and
            other consumer businesses, the accord is aimed at ending future
            court battles with U.S. merchants over the practice of setting
            credit card interchange payments, known as swipe fees. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'They're seeing this settlement as finally buying them
            some peace,' said Steven Semeraro, a former U.S. Justice
            Department lawyer who isn't involved in the case. 'And that's
            worth it to them, however many billions of dollars it's going to
            cost.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Developed by banks half a century ago, Visa and MasterCard
            have been subject to government scrutiny over their business
            practices for decades, Georgetown University law professor Adam Levitin wrote in a 2008 report on credit
            card merchant
            restraints. The card firms faced an antitrust suit filed by Wal-Mart Stores Inc. (WMT) and other retailers
            in 1996 and actions by the
            Justice Department, leading to changes in some of their rules. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Bank-owned groups spun off the card companies through
            initial public offerings in 2006 and 2008 in a move that
            merchants alleged was intended to dodge antitrust liability. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Previous Settlement &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Not long after Foster City, California-based Visa and
            Purchase, New York-based MasterCard received final approval for
            their previous settlement of more than $4 billion in January
            2004, the current case was brought against them in October 2005. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The firms thought they would be protected from future
            antitrust lawsuits over interchange fees by releases written
            into the settlement of the earlier Wal-Mart-led case, said
            Semeraro, a professor at the Thomas Jefferson School of Law in
            San Diego. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;This time, the card companies 'think they really have the
            language in there' and included an 'unbelievably broad'
            release, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'It prohibits virtually anyone except an antitrust
            enforcement authority from ever suing them again for anything
            that relates to antitrust claims,' he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Estimated to be the largest ever in a U.S. antitrust case,
            the settlement is currently valued at about $5.7 billion. In an
            August report, a court-appointed expert said that plaintiffs
            might have difficulty establishing that the companies violated
            antitrust laws at trial and are probably better off with the
            accord. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Interchange Payments &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Merchants are expected to receive about one-third of a
            year's worth of interchange payments if final approval is
            granted and the order isn't delayed by an appeal. That estimate
            is based on assumptions about the number of merchants that will
            file claims and other factors. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa and MasterCard forged ahead with the settlement
            despite objections from hundreds of retailers, including Wal-Mart and Target Corp. (TGT), which contended
            that the releases would
            cover too many of the firms' policies and allow them to raise
            rates in the future. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In a conference call with investors this July, MasterCard
            President and Chief Executive Officer Ajay Banga disclosed that
            the companies decided not to back out of the accord even though
            a termination provision had been triggered by the volume of
            merchants that dropped out. Some of those merchants have chosen
            to file their own lawsuits. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;'Gigantic Nightmare' &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The settlement will help the card companies rid themselves
            of a 'gigantic nightmare' in terms of legal fees and other
            costs, said Sarah Jane Hughes, a professor at Indiana University
            Bloomington's Maurer School of Law, who isn't involved in the
            litigation. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;MasterCard said it's confident the court will grant final
            approval. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'The scope of the release is reasonable and logical,'
            Noah Hanft, the company's general counsel, said in a phone
            interview. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Paul Cohen, a Visa spokesman, declined to comment about
            today's hearing. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In a joint court filing in April, lawyers for the card
            companies and major U.S. banks said the release 'covers only
            claims based on continued rules and practices that are the same
            as, or substantially similar to, those currently in place or
            modified by the settlement, which courts have held a class may
            properly release.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Interchange fees are collected by Visa and MasterCard and
            turned over to banks, which use the funds to help cover the
            costs of issuing cards. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The U.S. began regulating debit-card interchange fees under
            the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act of
            2010. In July, a federal judge found those fees had been set too
            high and ordered the Federal Reserve to revisit the rates. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The case is In re Payment Card Interchange Fee and Merchant
            Discount Antitrust Litigation, 05-md-01720, U.S. District Court,
            Eastern District of New York (Brooklyn). &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Doug Alexander" datetime="Sep 16, 2013  4:18 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="n" progress_sentiment="n"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-09-16/td-cibc-reach-agreement-with-aimia-on-aerogold-visa-portfolio.html">
        <headline>TD-CIBC Reach Agreement With Aimia on Aerogold Visa</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Canadian Imperial Bank of Commerce
            agreed to sell about half its Aerogold Visa credit-card
            portfolio to Toronto-Dominion Bank (TD), which is planning to start
            its own Aeroplan rewards card program in January. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Canadian Imperial will receive about C$3 billion ($2.9
            billion) cash for the outstanding card balances, as well as an
            upfront payment of C$200 million from Toronto-Dominion and
            Aeroplan owner Aimia (AIM) Inc., Toronto-based CIBC said today in a
            statement. Toronto-Dominion also agreed to pay CIBC C$37.5
            million annually for three years, the bank said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The companies had been in talks since last month, when
            Toronto-Dominion was chosen as the primary card partner of
            Montreal-based loyalty-program operator Aimia. Toronto-Dominion
            will offer co-branded Aeroplan Visa cards that offer miles for
            flights and other rewards starting in January under a 10-year
            contract with Aimia, while CIBC keeps the right to offer
            Aeroplan cards. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Toronto-Dominion said in a separate statement that it will
            acquire 550,000 cardholder accounts, primarily those who don't
            have a banking relationship with Canadian Imperial. The
            agreement, expected to be completed in December, will add about
            10 cents a share to its adjusted earnings next year, and 15
            cents in 2015, Toronto-Dominion said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Aimia Contract &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'We believe the negative in the agreement is that TD will
            no longer be the sole Canadian bank issuing Aeroplan cards,'
            John Aiken, an analyst with Barclays Plc in Toronto, said in a
            note to clients. 'We do not believe this was the original
            vision when TD initially pursued the contract with Aimia.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Toronto-Dominion plans to introduce five Aeroplan Visa
            cards in Canada and the U.S., the lender said in a conference
            call. The three-way deal gives Toronto-Dominion Aeroplan
            cardholders from the outset of its new offering, allowing the
            lender to avoid starting from scratch and having to win over
            each cardholder individually, Chief Executive Officer Ed Clark
            said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'It's just dramatically lower risk, and so I'll always say
            a bird in the hand is worth two in the bush,' Clark said in a
            telephone interview from Toronto. 'So we get an earnings base
            and we can spend vigorously on marketing to grow this file.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Renewal Option &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Canadian Imperial will retain its Aerogold Visa cardholders
            that have 'deeper' banking relationships with the lender,
            David Williamson, group head of retail and business banking,
            said today in a conference call. The bank can continue to offer
            Aeroplan cards for 10 years, and may have the option to renew
            after that, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Canadian Imperial rose 0.8 percent to close at C$81.74 in
            Toronto and Toronto-Dominion advanced 1.2 percent to C$91.02.
            Aimia surged 7.3 percent to C$17.85, the most since June 27. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'While CIBC does not receive much of a premium on the
            cardholder balances, the accounts sold were the ones that were
            the highest risk of flight and receiving any value should be
            viewed as an incremental positive,' Aiken said. 'With the
            ability to continue to issue Aeroplan cards, CIBC should be able
            to more adequately defend the customers that it retained.' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Canadian Imperial will release about C$65 million of loan-loss provisions tied to the sold
            portfolio and have about C$55
            million in costs, the bank said. Net income of upfront payments,
            the loan-loss release and closing costs is expected to be about
            C$180 million. Annual earnings will be reduced by about 45 cents
            a share, Canadian Imperial said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Air Canada &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Canadian Imperial's two-decade partnership with Aimia made
            the CIBC Aerogold Visa its most popular card. The bank buys
            Aeroplan miles from Aimia to give to cardholders on purchases,
            including flights with Air Canada (AC/B), the country's biggest
            carrier. Aimia, which owns and manages rewards programs
            including Nectar in the U.K. and Italy, counts CIBC as its
            biggest partner. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Aimia said in a separate statement that Toronto-Dominion
            becomes Aeroplan's primary financial-services partner and
            credit-card issuer, though CIBC will also continue to be an
            issuer of Aeroplan cards through 10-year agreements. CIBC will
            keep 630,000 Aeroplan accounts held by existing banking
            customers under the agreement, Aimia said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'CIBC has been an issuer of Aeroplan loyalty credit cards
            for more than 20 years, and this deal ensures that our clients
            will continue to have access to the program for the next 10
            years,' Canadian Imperial CEO Gerald McCaughey said on the
            conference call. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Aeroplan began in 1984 as a promotional tool for business
            travelers on Air Canada. CIBC Aerogold Visa was started in 1991,
            according to Aimia. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Elizabeth Dexheimer" datetime="Sep 24, 2014 12:10 PM ET" feeling_sentiment="h"
           progress_sentiment="u"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-24/visa-to-create-2-000-full-time-jobs-amid-global-tech-expansion.html">
        <headline>Visa to Create 2,000 Full-Time Jobs Amid Global Tech Push</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Visa Inc. (V), the world's largest
            payments network, is creating 2,000 full-time jobs as the
            company expands teams in Singapore and the U.S. and opens a
            technology center in India. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The total includes new roles and existing contractor jobs
            that are being converted into full-time positions, the Foster
            City, California-based company said today in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;'Recruitment efforts, which are currently under way and
            will continue through 2017, will focus on a range of technology
            needs spanning data scientists, engineers, platform architects
            and mobile developers,' the company said in the statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Visa plans to open a new technology-development center in
            India and is adding staff in Austin, Texas; Ashburn, Virginia;
            the San Francisco area and Denver. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The investment 'allows us to strengthen our talent pool
            globally, and bring more of it in-house,' Rajat Taneja,
            executive vice president of technology, said in the statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The company opened a new outpost in San Francisco in July.
            Visa has been expanding its digital and mobile products and
            services, and in July introduced Visa Checkout, which it said
            will allow consumers to make purchases faster online. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Earlier this month, Apple Inc. said its new iPhones include
            a payment system that relies on card networks including Visa as
            well as banks. As part of the partnership, Visa offers bank
            clients a new service that replaces account information with a
            digital token. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;As Visa increases its investments in in-house capabilities,
            the firm is reducing its stake in other startups. Visa said
            Sept. 18 it was considering its options regarding an investment
            in Monitise Plc, a London-based mobile-payments firm. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
</news>