
<news><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="June 30, 2014 11:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/1bfa7e90-ff6e-11e3-9a4a-00144feab7de.html"><headline>EU slams US over Microsoft privacy case</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tim Bradshaw in San Francisco" date="April 30, 2014 4:45 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f6534348-d001-11e3-a2b7-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft''s Xbox One to go on sale in China</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Daniel Thomas, Telecoms Correspondent" date="April 28, 2014 11:59 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f8531d60-cef0-11e3-ac8d-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft developing brand for smartphone products</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft is developing a brand for forthcoming smartphone products following the acquisition of Nokia, says the former chief executive of the Finnish group, who is moving to the US with the handset businesses.</p>
Stephen Elop, who will head Microsoft''s devices business, said the US group will not use Nokia or Microsoft Mobile as had been speculated for the next stage in its attempt to crack the lucrative but highly competitive smartphone market. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Daniel Thomas" date="April 25, 2014 2:28 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/33c1b882-aeb9-11e3-aaa6-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Nokia completes 5.4bn sale of handset division to Microsoft</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="April 25, 2014 2:01 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f8da7cd8-cc3e-11e3-bd33-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft''s Nadella faces handset dilemma</headline><body><![CDATA[Tricky asset: Microsoft''s 5.44bn purchase of Nokia''s handset business was approved Friday. It raises questions of how the US group navigates the all-important mobile computing marketBloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Mishkin in San Francisco" date="April 25, 2014 12:23 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c65588b2-cbed-11e3-9f27-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Nadella sets out vision for Microsoft</headline><body><![CDATA[Satya Nadella, Microsoft''s new chief executive, set out on Thursday to make it clear that anyone who still thought of Microsoft as just a struggling PC company was mistaken.</p>
In his first call with investors since becoming the third chief executive in the company''s nearly four-decade history, Mr Nadella sounded upbeat and enthusiastic as he hammered home his vision for how he will help the world''s largest software maker move away from its roots making software for a now-declining PC market.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Daniel Thomas, Telecoms Correspondent" date="April 21, 2014 5:33 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a9715754-c967-11e3-89f8-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft fine-tunes 5.4bn Nokia deal</headline><body><![CDATA[AP]]> </body></entry><entry author="By James Fontanella-Khan in Brussels" date="April 10, 2014 1:47 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/aeeb7350-c0a1-11e3-a74d-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft cloud system wins EU privacy regulators'' approval</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="April 2, 2014 9:47 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/7eda77e4-ba7d-11e3-a905-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft to give away software for smartphones</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft is to give away its software for smartphones free of charge and reverse course a second time on its controversial Windows 8 PC operating system, in the latest attempt to shore up its eroding software platform against Apple and Google.</p>
The moves came as new chief executive Satya Nadella appeared at an event in San Francisco in front of 5,000 developers  a key group that he needs to win over. A shortage of apps for handsets running Windows software has been one of the main things holding the company back in the smartphone wars.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hannah Kuchler in San Francisco" date="March 28, 2014 8:22 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a7eae32c-b6b2-11e3-8695-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft to stop invading customers'' privacy</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft has promised to stop reading suspected pirates'' emails but instead report them to the police, changing its policy in response to consumer outrage after it was revealed that the company accessed a personal Hotmail account. </p>
Brad Smith, Microsoft''s general counsel, said that, effective immediately, the company would not inspect a customer''s private content, even though it had been legal to do so when someone was suspected of trafficking in stolen Microsoft intellectual property. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters" date=" March 27, 2014 7:12 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/9e09d082-b5d3-11e3-a1bd-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft opens door to a world beyond Windows</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tim Bradshaw in San Francisco" date="March 28, 2014 12:04 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/9da38e5a-b5d1-11e3-b40e-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft boss launches Office for iPad</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="March 21, 2014 2:29 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/8ff9df6a-b096-11e3-8efc-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft caught up in fresh privacy storm</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Blackden" date="March 18, 2014 5:16 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e269f722-aebf-11e3-aaa6-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft gains on mobile market hopes</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft found itself at the top of Wall Street''s leaderboard on Tuesday on hopes new chief executive Satya Nadella will make progress in driving its software deeper into the mobile market. </p>
Mr Nadella, who took over as Microsoft chief executive last month, will release a new version of its office software for Apple''s iPad at an event in San Francisco next week, according to reports.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tim Bradshaw in San Francisco" date="March 7, 2014 2:30 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/8ae1e070-a5c1-11e3-b9ed-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft brings out giant robots in battle for console dominance</headline><body><![CDATA[Electronic Arts<p>Microsoft hopes Titanfall will help its XBox One catch up to Sony''s PlayStation 4</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="March 3, 2014 6:52 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/28feb5f4-a300-11e3-ba21-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Penn gives up ad role in Microsoft shake-up</headline><body><![CDATA[Mark Penn, a former adviser to Bill Clinton, former US president, who had led Microsoft''s aggressive marketing campaign against arch-rival Google, is to give up his responsibilities for advertising in the first overhaul of the software maker''s senior ranks by new chief executive Satya Nadella.</p>
The shake-up will also see the departure of two of the company''s top executives, Tony Bates and Tami Reller, as well as the latest in a series of reshuffles intended to bring a sharper edge to Microsoft''s marketing and advertising.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Daniel Thomas in Barcelona" date="February 25, 2014 5:33 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/840be59a-9e26-11e3-95fe-00144feab7de.html"><headline>France''s Orange in talks to sell Dailymotion stake to Microsoft</headline><body><![CDATA[<p>Stphane Richard, Orange chairman and chief executive</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Paul Taylor in Barcelona" date="February 23, 2014 11:26 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/5d41c362-9caa-11e3-9360-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft signs up new handset makers for Windows Phone</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft, which is acquiring Nokia''s smartphone business, underscored its determination to continue to support other handset makers with new Windows Phone licensing agreements.</p>
The US company signed new Windows Phone 8 licensees including China''s Foxconn, Lenovo and ZTE and Korea''s LG.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters" date=" February 7, 2014 7:10 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/37005c46-8e9e-11e3-98c6-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Satya Nadella, Microsoft''s engineer chief</headline><body /></entry><entry author="By Stephen Foley in New York and Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="February 6, 2014 8:09 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/699f9f74-8f46-11e3-9cb0-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Shareholder unease over Microsoft reshuffle</headline><body><![CDATA[Amanda Friedman<p>Bill Gates has championed funding for ''neglected tropical diseases''</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters" date=" February 5, 2014 12:07 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/081e18f6-8e07-11e3-bbe7-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Satya Nadella must force Microsoft into the post-PC world</headline><body><![CDATA[EPA]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="February 4, 2014 7:10 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/8ac6b7ac-8db9-11e3-bbe7-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft chief goes back to the future</headline><body><![CDATA[During its long years at the top of the top of the technology world, Microsoft''s veteran product developers and engineers shared a common ambition: to present their plans at formal product meetings presided over by Bill Gates.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By John Aglionby" date="February 4, 2014 3:42 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/ce464cf6-8dad-11e3-ba55-00144feab7de.html"><headline>New Microsoft chairman John Thompson is all about the cloud</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Emily Cadman" date="February 4, 2014 3:00 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/1b990f1a-8daa-11e3-bbe7-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Satya Nadella''s wisdom  letter to staff from new Microsoft chief</headline><body><![CDATA[New Microsoft chief executive Satya Nadella, previously in charge of the company''s cloud computing division, introduced himself to the company at large in a 1,046-word email to all staff.</p>
Here are the key quotes from the world according to Mr Nadella:</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By FastFT" date="February 4, 2014 2:35 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/fa2b416e-8da8-11e3-bbe7-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Where Microsoft makes its money</headline><body><![CDATA[As Microsoft appoints the third chief executive in its history, here''s a brief look at where the world''s largest software maker generates its money.</p>
Despite Steve Ballmer''s noisy push into consumer technology, selling to businesses remains the lucrative bread and butter for Microsoft.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="February 4, 2014 7:58 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/96140582-8da6-11e3-bbe7-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft banks on the cloud under Nadella</headline><body><![CDATA[Jan 2000: Steve Ballmer becomes chief executive after co-founder Bill Gates steps down to become chief software architect. Mr Ballmer said: We will...focus on the next generation opportunity''AFP]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andy Sharman" date="January 31, 2014 9:22 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/1323bcc8-8a48-11e3-ba54-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Softly-spoken techie from Hyderabad rises to top tier at Microsoft</headline><body><![CDATA[After a high-profile search for the successor to a man who screamed I love this company, a softly-spoken insider has emerged as frontrunner to take the top job at Microsoft.</p>
Satya Nadella is seen as the likely successor to Steve Ballmer, though the board is not thought to have made a formal selection. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="January 31, 2014 12:05 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/1045ec40-8a04-11e3-8829-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft cloud chief Satya Nadella tipped for top role</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>Satya Nadella: likely successor to Steve Ballmer</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hannah Kuchler and Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="January 24, 2014 12:30 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/470f5bda-8473-11e3-9710-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Xbox and cloud demand boost Microsoft</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>Microsoft Surface Pro 2 tablet computer</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By James Fontanella-Khan in Brussels and Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="January 22, 2014 10:26 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e14ddf70-8390-11e3-aa65-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft to shield foreign users'' data</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Robert Wright in New York" date="January 8, 2014 1:56 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e0eafc6e-77f8-11e3-afc5-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Alan Mulally scotches Microsoft talk to stay at Ford</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters" date=" December 18, 2013 5:46 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c1e6693a-6802-11e3-8ada-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Investors should be careful what they wish for in Microsoft chief</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters<p>Steve Ballmer, chief executive of Microsoft</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By James Crabtree in Mumbai" date="December 4, 2013 8:52 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f63ce44e-5cb7-11e3-a558-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Nokia $321m India tax row looms over sale to Microsoft</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Robert Cookson and John Aglionby" date="November 18, 2013 11:50 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/2c37bd70-5020-11e3-9f0d-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft and Google tighten block on child abuse images</headline><body><![CDATA[PA]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lisa Pollack" date="November 4, 2013 4:09 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0131b426-42df-11e3-8350-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>The siren call of Microsoft Excel</headline><body><![CDATA[Reality is a crutch for people who can''t handle drugs, proclaimed a sticker I once purchased in a suburban shopping centre. It fitted in perfectly with my collection of risqu buttons and key chains. As a teenager I had discovered accessorising was the easiest way to at least give the appearance of defying authority.</p>
Fast forward through university, and my entry into the financial industry  where I worked before becoming a journalist  presented a wholly different set of norms to which to conform. Money, rather predictably, was at the centre of many. But a less obvious one had to do with Microsoft''s Excel spreadsheet software. It seemed to be the right tool for every job, every time, according to almost everyone. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Stephen Foley in New York and Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="October 31, 2013 6:40 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/32a96336-4254-11e3-8350-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft urged to spin consumer business</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft''s next chief executive should consider spinning off consumer businesses including search advertising and the Xbox games console, according to the private investment vehicle of Microsoft co-founder Paul Allen.</p>
Mr Allen, who started the company with Bill Gates in 1975 and still holds a $2bn stake, is intrigued and interested by forthcoming changes, said Paul Ghaffari, who manages the tech investor''s $15bn fortune.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Paul Taylor" date="Last updated: October 31, 2013 3:56 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/ae7ef03e-40bf-11e3-8775-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft resurfaces with tablet updates</headline><body /></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="October 24, 2013 10:09 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a832cf5c-3ce6-11e3-86ef-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Business software helps Microsoft weather PC downturn</headline><body /></entry><entry author="By Tim Bradshaw in San Francisco" date="October 23, 2013 5:59 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e8860766-3b8a-11e3-87fa-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Apple shuts Microsoft''s window of opportunity for Office on iPad</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters" date=" October 16, 2013 7:42 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e3e0da3a-367e-11e3-aaf1-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft and Apple face different challenges to adapt</headline><body><![CDATA[You can always count on Apple to spoil a Microsoft party.</p>
So it is with next Tuesday''s expected unveiling of the latest iPad models  the same day that Microsoft had already earmarked for the launch of its new Surface tablets. It also comes hot on the heels of this Thursday''s release of the upgraded Windows 8.1, as Microsoft makes up for the missteps of last year''s launch of its first touchscreen operating system.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco and Stephen Foley in New York" date="October 3, 2013 12:07 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/74b60e22-2ba8-11e3-a1b7-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft investors wary of Gates'' role in chief executive search</headline><body><![CDATA[Some of Microsoft''s biggest shareholders have expressed concern about the effect that Bill Gates'' outsized influence at the company will have on the search for a replacement to chief executive Steve Ballmer.
</p>
The company needs to take particular care that Mr Gates'' unique role does not deter candidates nor leave questions about who will have the final say over Mr Ballmer''s replacement, said people familiar with the thinking of a number of investors.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Daniel Thomas, Telecoms Correspondent" date="October 2, 2013 7:00 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/4b49dba2-2b73-11e3-bfe2-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Google and Microsoft back UK trial to use white space'' bandwidth</headline><body><![CDATA[Google and Microsoft are backing national trials of mobile services across fallow parts of the broadcast spectrum that could help avert a looming shortage of mobile frequencies.</p>
So-called white space technology allows mobile broadband to be carried over unused, and unlicensed, broadcast frequencies, which could be used by smartphones and tablets as well as a range of business applications.</p>
<h3>Spectrum of opportunity</h3>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Milne in Salo" date="September 25, 2013 8:01 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/feb7ef76-2510-11e3-bcf7-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Hope emerges for Nokia''s future following purchase by Microsoft</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="September 23, 2013 9:18 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/8a0e072c-2462-11e3-a8f7-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft resurfaces with revamped models in tablet wars</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>Microsoft Surface Pro 2 tablet computer</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="September 20, 2013 2:21 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0492a068-2164-11e3-a92a-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft bets on rapid online growth</headline><body><![CDATA[AFP/Getty Images<p>Steve Ballmer</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Milne in Oslo and Daniel Thomas in London" date="September 19, 2013 4:27 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a50a96e6-2131-11e3-8aff-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Nokia''s Stephen Elop given 18.8m to return to Microsoft</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="September 17, 2013 6:58 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/48897be0-1fb9-11e3-aa36-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft''s Office refusal risks opening door to rivals</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft''s refusal to release its Office software for rival tablet computers risks eroding its most profitable product and has inspired a new generation of start-ups that are racing to fill the gap, according to tech executives and analysts.</p>
Microsoft has restricted users of the iPad and tablets running Google''s Android software to an online version of Office that only works when the machines are connected to the internet. The strategy of holding back the full software for Windows tablets has failed to ignite sales, however, forcing the company to take a $900m writedown on its Surface tablet in July.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="September 5, 2013 2:27 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/46d36fce-15c6-11e3-950a-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft wins landmark patent ruling</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft has won the second stage of a landmark patent case against Google''s Motorola unit, as a jury in Seattle concluded that the mobile handset maker had breached some its commitments to technology standards bodies.</p>
The verdict follows a decision that also went in the software company''s favour in the first part of the case, concluded in April. The earlier ruling, which dealt with how royalties payments should be calculated for patents that are included in technology standards, was seen as of far broader significance for the patent disputes that have rocked the smartphone industry.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="September 4, 2013 7:21 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0edebb0c-157e-11e3-b519-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Nokia patents bump up cost for Microsoft</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty<p>The Nokia Lumia 1020, unveiled in July, features a 41-megapixel camera</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters and Richard Milne" date="September 3, 2013 9:53 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/3b79f7f2-14c1-11e3-a2df-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Investors cast doubt on Microsoft deal</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="September 3, 2013 6:40 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/42648092-14b6-11e3-a2df-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Steep hill to climb for Microsoft-Nokia</headline><body><![CDATA[For Steve Ballmer, outgoing chief executive of Microsoft, there was probably no alternative but to risk one final roll of the dice. But the odds are long on his successor wielding the rump of Nokia''s handset business to turn Microsoft into a real contender in what has become the dominant market for personal computing.</p>
That was the knee-jerk verdict of investors and industry analysts on Tuesday, as Microsoft''s stock fell more than 6 per cent  in one fell swoop wiping out the lift the shares had received on the news of Mr Ballmer''s departure only days before.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Milne in Oslo and John Aglionby and Chris Nuttall in London" date="September 3, 2013 6:49 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c8204b3c-1446-11e3-9289-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft in 5.4bn deal with Nokia</headline><body><![CDATA[AFP<p>Nokia chairman Risto Siilasmaa (L) walks past Microsoft CEO Steve Ballmer during the press conference</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="August 30, 2013 11:44 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/d4b2cafa-11c1-11e3-a14c-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft cedes board seat to ValueAct</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft has bowed to pressure from an activist investor, ceding a board seat to ValueAct Capital as it tries to quell unrest on Wall Street.</p>
The pact with ValueAct, disclosed on Friday, comes a week after Steve Ballmer announced his intention to quit as chief executive as soon as a replacement was found. Mr Ballmer denied at the time of his resignation that his departure was linked to pressure from the activist investor, which has become one of Microsoft''s biggest outside shareholders.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters" date="August 29, 2013 7:48 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/4a260082-108b-11e3-b291-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Technology: Microsoft''s outlook</headline><body /></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters" date="August 25, 2013 5:44 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/638de3ac-0d96-11e3-8d9d-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Ballmer resignation unlikely to quell unease over Microsoft</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Robin Kwong and Henry Mance" date="February 4, 2014 4:09 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/527c0cdc-0c1b-11e3-8840-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Timeline: Microsoft through the years</headline><body><![CDATA[Bill Gates has stepped down from his chairmanship at Microsoft after more than 30 years in the role. </p>
The software company also appointed Satya Nadella, president of its cloud computing and enterprise business, as its new chief executive. Mr Nadella takes over from Steve Ballmer, who had been chief executive since 2000.</p>
Mr Gates will remain an important figure at Microsoft  he aims to spend a third of his time at the company helping Mr Nadella as a technology adviser. </p>
Microsoft lost roughly 40 per cent of its market value during Mr Ballmer''s tenure. </p>
The company''s new management will hope to re-establish Microsoft as a technology leader. As Mr Nadella wrote in his first email to employees: We must zero in on what Microsoft can uniquely contribute to the world. The opportunity ahead will require us to reimagine a lot of what we have done in the past for a mobile and cloud-first world, and do new things.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tim Bradshaw in San Francisco" date="August 23, 2013 7:36 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/cc5d4d62-0bf4-11e3-8840-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Ballmer to leave Microsoft within a year</headline><body><![CDATA[Steve Ballmer is stepping down as chief executive of Microsoft after 13 years at the helm in an admission by the PC pioneer that it lacks the leadership needed to steer it into the mobile era.</p>
Shareholders, who have objected to Mr Ballmer''s performance for years, sent shares in the world''s largest software company by market capitalisation up as much as 8.7 per cent on Friday. </p>
<h3>The Ballmer years</h3>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="August 14, 2013 7:40 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/034b04e2-04fa-11e3-9e71-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft to fund remake of BBC''s sci-fi cult classic Blake''s 7''</headline><body><![CDATA[<p>Picture shows L-R: Steven Pacey and Paul Darrow, from Blake''s Seven..</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Paul Taylor" date="August 12, 2013 5:40 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/95297aec-0365-11e3-980a-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Nokia and Microsoft also face tough fight for survival</headline><body><![CDATA[<p>Nokia Lumia 1020</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hannah Kuchler" date="July 22, 2013 12:03 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/792cb988-f219-11e2-8e04-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Google and Microsoft commit to UK''s child pornography crackdown</headline><body><![CDATA[Alamy]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="July 21, 2013 1:37 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/333a0cb8-f0da-11e2-929c-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>More bad news for Microsoft cranks up pressure on Steve Ballmer</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters<p>Steve Ballmer, chief executive of Microsoft</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="July 19, 2013 3:10 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/d0bc3734-efdd-11e2-8229-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft shares down 10% on Windows and Surface tablet woes</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="July 15, 2013 6:54 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/49bf0748-ed71-11e2-8d7c-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>HP bolsters board with former Microsoft strategist Ray Ozzie</headline><body><![CDATA[Ray Ozzie, the former top software strategist at Microsoft, has signed on as a director at Hewlett-Packard as the US technology company seeks to rebuild its board in the wake of the Autonomy debacle.</p>
HP also named former executives from Liberty Media and McDonald''s as new directors on Monday  to add to the financial and corporate turnround experience in its boardroom and bolster chief executive Meg Whitman''s attempt to revive the struggling conglomerate.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="July 11, 2013 7:19 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/3d2a8594-ea4b-11e2-b2f4-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Ballmer in rallying cry at Microsoft</headline><body><![CDATA[It is eight years since Ray Ozzie, the former top software strategist at Microsoft, tried to propel the company deeper into the realm of internet services, with a warning that the rise of companies like Google threatened to overturn its software kingdom.</p>
And it is seven years since chief executive Steve Ballmer indicated that a new focus on hardware devices had become paramount, releasing the ill-fated Zune digital music player to compete with Apple''s iPod.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="July 11, 2013 8:00 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0f60103a-ea3b-11e2-b2f4-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Steve Ballmer shakes up Microsoft structure in battle to compete</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters<p>Steve Ballmer, chief executive of Microsoft</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Henry Mance" date="July 5, 2013 2:48 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/50c385ec-e49c-11e2-a74d-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft reaches agreement with Sinofsky</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="July 3, 2013 11:17 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/76054914-e42c-11e2-91a3-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Zynga chief lured from Microsoft with $50m pay package</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tim Bradshaw in San Francisco" date="June 28, 2013 5:36 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f087c6f0-e001-11e2-9de6-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Console battle powers up as Microsoft adds Time Warner TV to Xbox</headline><body><![CDATA[AFP]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="June 26, 2013 9:38 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/95480f84-de94-11e2-b990-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft touts rapid Windows 8 updates</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft on Wednesday promised further rapid improvements to Windows 8 as it showed off a series of upgrades designed to overcome some of the initial poor reception to the operating system.
</p>
The world''s biggest software company also plugged a gaping hole in its arsenal of applications for the new touch-based system with the announcement of an app from Facebook.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chris Nuttall in San Francisco" date="June 19, 2013 11:42 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/955550fe-d92b-11e2-a6cf-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft to scrap Xbox One restrictions</headline><body><![CDATA[AFP]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Barker in Brussels" date="September 23, 2014 11:52 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e4e9f1f8-42ff-11e4-9a58-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>EU antitrust chief says Google case may be bigger than Microsoft</headline><body><![CDATA[EPA<p>Joaqun Almunia</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sally Davies" date="September 16, 2014 2:57 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/2196c9da-3d85-11e4-b782-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Blur Group names former Microsoft UK executive finance director</headline><body><![CDATA[Blur Group, the UK company that lets people buy and sell services online from app-making to advertising, has appointed former Microsoft executive Stephen Harvey as its chief financial officer.</p>
The company  which has been described by its chief executive as an eBay for business services  has been through three other finance directors in the past two years as it has overhauled its accounting and financial reporting practices. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Milne in Stockholm, Arash Massoudi in London and Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="September 15, 2014 7:20 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/34ad6748-3cf1-11e4-a2ab-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft buys Minecraft maker for $2.5bn</headline><body /></entry><entry author="By Sally Davies, Richard Milne and Tim Bradshaw" date="September 10, 2014 5:44 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/04e86370-38e9-11e4-9526-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft in talks to buy Minecraft maker for more than $2bn</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft is in talks to buy Mojang, the Swedish company behind retro gaming sensation Minecraft, for more than $2bn, according to two people with knowledge of the discussions.</p>
One of those people said that co-founder Markus Persson  a maverick gamer known as Notch  would probably leave the company if a deal is agreed. </p>
Mr Persson owns about 70 per cent of the business, valuing his stake at about $1.4bn. The other owners are Jakob Porser, Mr Persson''s co-founder and best friend, and chief executive Carl Manneh.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="September 7, 2014 6:24 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/15f5f5fc-369f-11e4-85be-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft drops controversial image tool</headline><body /></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="September 4, 2014 6:08 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/5fbc84e0-3450-11e4-b81c-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Getty sues Microsoft over digital images</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Daniel Thomas, Telecoms Correspondent" date="September 4, 2014 12:26 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/9eaf977c-341a-11e4-b81c-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft brings mobile personal assistant Cortana to UK and China</headline><body><![CDATA[AP<p>Slim: The Lumia 830</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Charles Clover in Beijing" date="September 1, 2014 1:32 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/31d5fdd8-31bf-11e4-a19b-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft ordered to comply over China antitrust allegations</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Avantika Chilkoti" date="August 20, 2014 10:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/4cc4515e-2822-11e4-ae44-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Steve Ballmer quits Microsoft board to focus on NBA''s Clippers</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="August 1, 2014 10:51 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c096ba4a-19c2-11e4-b06c-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft files legal complaint against Samsung</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="July 31, 2014 8:59 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0649c042-18e6-11e4-933e-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft setback in cloud era test case</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft on Thursday suffered a setback in a case testing the cross-border reach of law enforcement in the cloud computing era, after it was ordered to hand US authorities a user''s email held in a datacentre in Ireland.</p>
The decision, if it stands, represents a further reversal for the US internet industry in the wake of the Snowden revelations about widespread surveillance by the National Security Agency, according to legal experts.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Charles Clover in Beijing" date="July 30, 2014 3:44 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/27f9eb7a-17df-11e4-b842-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft raid highlights US trade troubles in China</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="July 28, 2014 4:59 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/355714d0-1665-11e4-93ec-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft targeted in China antitrust probe</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="July 23, 2014 12:01 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/dfab4988-11d8-11e4-8279-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft narrows efforts in mobile phones, Xbox games and Bing</headline><body><![CDATA[Satya Nadella, Microsoft''s new chief executive, promised to narrow the US software company''s efforts in mobile phones, the Xbox games console and Bing search engine, as he sought to persuade Wall Street that he was bringing more discipline to its strategy.</p>
However, he argued that Microsoft still needed to maintain its broad reach across both business and consumer technology markets, despite grumblings from investors that he is not doing enough to focus on its operations.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="July 21, 2014 12:44 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/61192662-10c5-11e4-812b-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft''s Satya Nadella to face tough questions from Wall Street</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David Crouch in Gothenburg" date="July 17, 2014 6:07 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0db372f6-0dce-11e4-85ab-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Anger and bewilderment in Finland over Microsoft job cuts</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>Alexander Stubb, Finland''s prime minister, said he found the job cuts "very very difficult from a human point of view."</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco, Murad Ahmed in London and David Crouch in Gothenburg" date="July 17, 2014 3:00 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/6a81e2be-0db1-11e4-b149-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft to shed 18,000 jobs</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="June 30, 2014 11:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/1bfa7e90-ff6e-11e3-9a4a-00144feab7de.html"><headline>EU slams US over Microsoft privacy case</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tim Bradshaw in San Francisco" date="April 30, 2014 4:45 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f6534348-d001-11e3-a2b7-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft''s Xbox One to go on sale in China</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Daniel Thomas, Telecoms Correspondent" date="April 28, 2014 11:59 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f8531d60-cef0-11e3-ac8d-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft developing brand for smartphone products</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft is developing a brand for forthcoming smartphone products following the acquisition of Nokia, says the former chief executive of the Finnish group, who is moving to the US with the handset businesses.</p>
Stephen Elop, who will head Microsoft''s devices business, said the US group will not use Nokia or Microsoft Mobile as had been speculated for the next stage in its attempt to crack the lucrative but highly competitive smartphone market. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Daniel Thomas" date="April 25, 2014 2:28 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/33c1b882-aeb9-11e3-aaa6-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Nokia completes 5.4bn sale of handset division to Microsoft</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="April 25, 2014 2:01 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f8da7cd8-cc3e-11e3-bd33-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft''s Nadella faces handset dilemma</headline><body><![CDATA[Tricky asset: Microsoft''s 5.44bn purchase of Nokia''s handset business was approved Friday. It raises questions of how the US group navigates the all-important mobile computing marketBloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Mishkin in San Francisco" date="April 25, 2014 12:23 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c65588b2-cbed-11e3-9f27-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Nadella sets out vision for Microsoft</headline><body><![CDATA[Satya Nadella, Microsoft''s new chief executive, set out on Thursday to make it clear that anyone who still thought of Microsoft as just a struggling PC company was mistaken.</p>
In his first call with investors since becoming the third chief executive in the company''s nearly four-decade history, Mr Nadella sounded upbeat and enthusiastic as he hammered home his vision for how he will help the world''s largest software maker move away from its roots making software for a now-declining PC market.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Daniel Thomas, Telecoms Correspondent" date="April 21, 2014 5:33 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a9715754-c967-11e3-89f8-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft fine-tunes 5.4bn Nokia deal</headline><body><![CDATA[AP]]> </body></entry><entry author="By James Fontanella-Khan in Brussels" date="April 10, 2014 1:47 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/aeeb7350-c0a1-11e3-a74d-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft cloud system wins EU privacy regulators'' approval</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="April 2, 2014 9:47 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/7eda77e4-ba7d-11e3-a905-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft to give away software for smartphones</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft is to give away its software for smartphones free of charge and reverse course a second time on its controversial Windows 8 PC operating system, in the latest attempt to shore up its eroding software platform against Apple and Google.</p>
The moves came as new chief executive Satya Nadella appeared at an event in San Francisco in front of 5,000 developers  a key group that he needs to win over. A shortage of apps for handsets running Windows software has been one of the main things holding the company back in the smartphone wars.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hannah Kuchler in San Francisco" date="March 28, 2014 8:22 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a7eae32c-b6b2-11e3-8695-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft to stop invading customers'' privacy</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft has promised to stop reading suspected pirates'' emails but instead report them to the police, changing its policy in response to consumer outrage after it was revealed that the company accessed a personal Hotmail account. </p>
Brad Smith, Microsoft''s general counsel, said that, effective immediately, the company would not inspect a customer''s private content, even though it had been legal to do so when someone was suspected of trafficking in stolen Microsoft intellectual property. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters" date=" March 27, 2014 7:12 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/9e09d082-b5d3-11e3-a1bd-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft opens door to a world beyond Windows</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tim Bradshaw in San Francisco" date="March 28, 2014 12:04 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/9da38e5a-b5d1-11e3-b40e-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft boss launches Office for iPad</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="March 21, 2014 2:29 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/8ff9df6a-b096-11e3-8efc-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft caught up in fresh privacy storm</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry></news>