
<news><entry author="fer in London" date="July 6, 2014 6:14 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a0f8ec30-0388-11e4-817f-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman muscles in on Europe''s private banks</headline><body><![CDATA[AP]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Camilla Hall in New York" date="July 2, 2014 12:07 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b20d16e2-016a-11e4-9750-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs accused of boys club'' atmosphere</headline><body><![CDATA[AP]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Nicole Bullock in New York and Philip Stafford in London" date="July 1, 2014 5:48 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c56c6aa8-012e-11e4-b94d-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs fined in dark pool debacle</headline><body><![CDATA[US regulators have fined Goldman Sachs $800,000 for failing to ensure that trades executed in the bank''s own trading venue met US laws protecting investors'' right to best market prices.</p>
The fine levelled by the Financial Industry Regulatory Authority comes amid heightened scrutiny around the US share trading industry. </p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hannah Kuchler, Arash Massoudi and Camilla Hall" date="July 1, 2014 2:51 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/91ff6f9e-0124-11e4-b94d-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Twitter hires ex-Goldman Sachs banker Anthony Noto as CFO</headline><body><![CDATA[<p>Twitter-bound: Anthony Noto, former Goldman banker</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alistair Gray in London" date="June 17, 2014 5:04 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/815610cc-f624-11e3-a038-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>RSA appoints Goldman Sachs to handle sale of its Asia business</headline><body><![CDATA[RSA, the FTSE 100 insurer trying to recover from an accounting scandal in Ireland, has appointed Goldman Sachs to handle the sale of its Asia business, estimated to be worth at least 150m.</p>
The insurer, led by former Royal Bank of Scotland chief executive Stephen Hester, is set to begin a process to sell its operations in Hong Kong, Singapore and China within weeks, people with knowledge of the process said.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="June 12, 2014 6:26 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/63ef855e-f246-11e3-ac7a-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman and Bain pay $121m to settle buyout conspiracy case</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Miles Johnson" date="June 9, 2014 12:12 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/08374420-ed8e-11e3-8a1e-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman stars fall back down to earth</headline><body><![CDATA[Cold on the outside: Goldman Sachs (headquarters pictured) lost star proprietary desk traders in the wake of the financial crisis. Many set up hedge funds but struggled to replicate their successBloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jennifer Hughes in Hong Kong" date="June 5, 2014 5:25 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0d1b99f8-ec5f-11e3-a9e3-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs beefs up Asia M&amp;A team</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs is beefing up its mergers team in Asia as deal volume in the region reaches record levels.</p>
The US investment bank is creating a new position of vice-chairman of the investment banking division for Asia Pacific excluding Japan. The role is being taken on by Richard Campbell-Breeden, who also becomes chairman of its mergers and acquisitions group.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="June 2, 2014 8:31 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/135d1262-ea78-11e3-80fb-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman creates new role in growth push</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs is planning to increase the size of its commercial bank and wealth management division as part of a quest for growth, according to people familiar with the matter.</p>
The moves are part of the mandate of Stephen Scherr, a 21-year Goldman veteran, who was promoted to a new position of chief strategy officer on Monday in a management reshuffle.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By John McDermott" date="May 30, 2014 6:39 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/419b3bf8-e696-11e3-b8c7-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs plays World Cup Moneyball</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="May 28, 2014 4:36 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/9d79bf28-e671-11e3-bbf5-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs'' Gary Cohn blames economy for trading declines</headline><body><![CDATA[Gary Cohn, president of Goldman Sachs, blamed the world economy rather than regulation for sharp declines in trading volumes at his bank and across Wall Street, but said we''re not just waiting for things to get better.</p>
In remarks to a Sanford Bernstein conference on Wednesday, Mr Cohn said regulation and fiscal and monetary policy played a role in the slide in overall fixed income volumes this year.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Gregory Meyer in New York and Xan Rice in London" date="May 20, 2014 11:15 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/4b4cc3fe-e04e-11e3-9534-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman moves to offload metals warehouses</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tracy Alloway in Dallas and Kara Scannell and Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="May 16, 2014 6:50 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f447b546-dd14-11e3-ba13-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman fears fallout if rivals plead guilty</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters<p>Goldman Sachs chief executive Lloyd Blankfein</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Morris" date="May 11, 2014 7:21 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/3483e952-cc05-11e3-9f27-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman builds up low-risk business</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs has quietly built its US defined contribution business out of the ashes of the financial crisis, scooping up fund franchises at a time when its peers were losing their nerve.</p>
The Goldman Sachs Asset Management unit now oversees $77bn in defined contribution retirement assets, of which roughly $53bn resides in stable value funds, low-risk portfolios wrapped with bank and insurance contracts to protect principal.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="May 9, 2014 4:21 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/2560c12e-d782-11e3-a47c-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman probed over Asia hiring practices</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs disclosed it was under investigation for its hiring practices in Asia and for high-frequency trading, two recent investigations that are affecting the majority of Wall Street banks.</p>
The Securities and Exchange Commission and the Department of Justice are looking at whether banks hired princelings, sons and daughters of government officials in Hong Kong and elsewhere in Asia, in return for lucrative deal advisory and underwriting work. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite and Stephen Foley in New York" date="May 6, 2014 6:52 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c9d16344-d534-11e3-adec-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman provides art-backed loan to Cohen</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>SAC co-founder Steven Cohen</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite" date=" April 21, 2014 5:49 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/ffef6d4a-c954-11e3-99cc-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>As Goldman glister fades restoring brilliance is tough</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs remained a partnership long after its rivals went public. When it finally took the plunge, in 1999, it revealed almost absurd levels of profitability: returns on equity of more than 40 per cent in some years, twice as high as its rivals.</p>
A decade later, under chief executive Lloyd Blankfein, Goldman avoided the fate of Lehman Brothers, Merrill Lynch and Bear Stearns. Call it superior risk management. Credit the big short that Goldman placed on the mortgage market. Or lay it on Goldman''s unofficial motto to be long-term greedy. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="April 17, 2014 1:05 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/6192dcd4-c622-11e3-9839-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman looks to fight rivals with capital advantage</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs was starting to benefit from the capitulation of its rivals in riskier businesses, its chief financial officer said, after earnings marked by record investment banking fees but marred by another poor performance in trading.</p>
The first-quarter results showed Morgan Stanley overtaking Goldman in equities trading and Goldman suffering an 11 per cent year-on-year decline in fixed income trading to $2.9bn, its worst start to the year since 2008.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Barker in Brussels" date="April 2, 2014 6:57 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/7e4513f0-ba20-11e3-a3ef-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman fined 37m by EU over subsea cable investment</headline><body><![CDATA[EPA]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Arash Massoudi and Tracy Alloway in New York" date="April 1, 2014 5:42 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/22431a3c-b9af-11e3-a3ef-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>End of Goldman era on the NYSE floor</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kara Scannell in New York" date="March 12, 2014 5:45 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/7e1681a2-a9f4-11e3-adab-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Ex-Goldman banker to repay $175,000 bonus and fined $650,000</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite and Gillian Tett in New York" date="March 5, 2014 3:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/5f9ffcd0-a3be-11e3-88b0-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman seeds $600m fund for women entrepreneurs</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs and the World Bank are launching a fund aimed at raising $600m in capital for 100,000 women entrepreneurs in developing countries.</p>
Lloyd Blankfein, Goldman''s chief executive, and Jim Kim, president of the World Bank, are due to unveil the initiative in Washington on Wednesday, with initial investments of $50m from the Wall Street bank and $100m from the World Bank''s International Finance Corporation.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Javier Blas, Africa Editor" date="March 2, 2014 2:11 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/1e1a17e4-9fbf-11e3-b6c7-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs joins scramble for African mobile telecoms</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs has made a bet on Africa''s booming mobile phone industry, joining a nearly $500m capital raising by Lagos-based IHS Towers, the continent''s largest mobile infrastructure company.</p>
The US investment bank joined the group''s existing shareholders, which include Wendel of France and private equity group Emerging Capital Partners, in the fundraising, according to two people familiar with the deal.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite, Tracy Alloway, Kara Scannell and Camilla Hall in New York" date="February 28, 2014 10:35 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/977f4dc2-a0b7-11e3-8557-00144feab7de.html"><headline>SEC probes Goldman and Citi bond allocations</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tracy Alloway in New York" date="February 28, 2014 6:22 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/98b90e60-a082-11e3-a72c-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Doors slide open on Goldman elevator man</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>Out of the shadows: assumed to be a Goldman insider, Twitter user GSElevator became an internet sensation</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By John Aglionby in London" date="February 25, 2014 9:51 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/840d926e-9df9-11e3-95fe-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman relief as Twitter poster of Wall St chatter is revealed</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tracy Alloway and Michael Mackenzie in New York" date="February 17, 2014 6:07 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/15c2e47c-9588-11e3-8371-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman retreats from bond platform</headline><body><![CDATA[
Goldman Sachs has quietly retreated from its electronic bond trading platform, in a move that highlights the challenges investment banks face in revamping their struggling fixed-income trading businesses.</p>
Banks including Goldman, Morgan Stanley and UBS had developed their own electronic corporate bond trading platforms in an effort to more efficiently match buyers with sellers of debt, and make money from facilitating the transactions.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Milne, Nordic Correspondent" date="February 5, 2014 6:07 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/d3a5eaee-8e75-11e3-98c6-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Dong says Goldman stake completes turnround</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Milne, Nordic Correspondent" date="January 31, 2014 2:42 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/92816e68-8a6e-11e3-9c29-00144feab7de.html"><headline>A closer look at a Goldman Sachs deal many in Denmark find rotten</headline><body><![CDATA[Alamy<p>Copenhagen, Denmark</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sharlene Goff" date="January 30, 2014 1:17 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/6321c91a-89a6-11e3-8829-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Libya''s sovereign wealth fund to sue Goldman over $1bn trades</headline><body><![CDATA[Libya''s sovereign wealth fund has taken formal legal action in London against Goldman Sachs over allegations that the investment bank exploited the fund''s limited financial experience, forcing it into risky and ultimately lossmaking investments.</p>
The claim, made in legal papers submitted by the Libyan Investment Authority on Thursday, rests on disputed equity derivatives trades amounting to in excess of $1bn.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Milne, Nordic correspondent" date="January 30, 2014 7:53 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/5ae48e0e-8992-11e3-abc4-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Danish coalition clings on amid furore over Goldman deal</headline><body><![CDATA[EPA<p>SF party''s departure leaves Helle Thorning-Schmidt''s Social Democrat-led coalition in a fragile position</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Camilla Hall in New York" date="January 24, 2014 3:34 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/2cbca1c2-8494-11e3-9710-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman weighs ban on message services</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs is considering imposing a ban on traders using some third-party computer-messaging services, in a move to reduce the risk of proprietary information leaking to others outside of the bank. </p>
The proposed measures include banning bilateral communications via messaging services from companies such as Bloomberg, Yahoo and AOL, said a person familiar with the plans, which have not yet been implemented and could change.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tracy Alloway in Las Vegas" date="January 22, 2014 8:03 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b7e490c0-832c-11e3-aa65-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman insider to cash in on Twitter fame with expos book deal</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite and Camilla Hall in New York and Gina Chon in Washington" date="January 16, 2014 10:02 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/487e2dd6-7ed6-11e3-8642-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman and Citi wreck Wall St hopes of escaping crisis doldrums</headline><body><![CDATA[Wall Street''s earnings season has dashed hopes the sector would bounce back from its post-crisis doldrums, with Goldman Sachs posting weak results in fixed income trading and Citigroup missing analysts'' forecasts for the second consecutive quarter.</p>
Financial stocks suffered a significant sell-off. Citi fell more than 4 per cent and Goldman more than 2 per cent, after the two banks reported lacklustre fourth-quarter and full-year results. JPMorgan Chase and Bank of America reported mediocre results earlier in the week. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="fer in London" date="January 16, 2014 8:56 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/aa19d38e-7ea8-11e3-8642-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman earnings fall on fixed income slide</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs enjoyed a strong performance in equity underwriting but endured its worst year for fixed income trading since 2005 as overall profits fell 19 per cent to $2.3bn.</p>
Initial public offerings, including Twitter, helped Goldman boast its revenues for equity underwriting in the fourth quarter were more than double last year''s at $622m.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By James Mackintosh" date=" January 13, 2014 7:49 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/97db977a-7c73-11e3-9179-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman turns bearish on US equities</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs has taken a bearish turn. David Kostin, the investment bank''s chief US equity strategist, spent much of a presentation to international clients on Monday showing how many measures demonstrated the SP 500 was overvalued, and by just how much. He put a 67 per cent probability on a correction of at least 10 per cent this year. And he pointed out how stretched sentiment was.</p>
Fear not, Goldman is nowhere near saying dump shares. Mr Kostin thinks the US can gain 5 per cent this year thanks to rising earnings, even as valuations flatline.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York and Gina Chon in Washington" date="January 7, 2014 11:17 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/eee0a484-77e6-11e3-807e-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs shakes up prized tech banking team</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs has shaken up its prized technology investment banking team, which landed the lucrative and high-profile Twitter initial public offering but has seen some fractious relations between its bankers.</p>
George Lee is moving from co-head of the technology, media and telecoms practice to chairman and adding the title of chief information officer for the investment banking division. He is being replaced by Dan Dees, co-head of investment banking in Asia.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="Washington and Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="December 2, 2013 11:54 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f187f47a-5b9f-11e3-848e-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Fed clears Goldman and JPM capital plans</headline><body><![CDATA[The Federal Reserve on Monday approved revised capital plans from JPMorgan Chase and Goldman Sachs, allowing the banks to press ahead with share buybacks and dividends.</p>
In a surprise move in March, Goldman and JPMorgan were singled out by the Fed for weaknesses in their procedures for planning payouts to shareholders. Their ability to continue buybacks and dividends was made conditional on better processes.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="November 21, 2013 8:30 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/18639f4e-52e1-11e3-a73e-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman defends currency trading performance</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs did not suffer a loss in our currencies business in the third quarter, the bank said on Thursday, seeking to reassure investors after reports that it had racked up more than $1bn in trading losses.</p>
The Wall Street bank took the unusual step of providing more detail on its performance, more than a month after first announcing third-quarter results. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Neil Hume and Jack Farchy in London and Gregory Meyer in New York" date="November 18, 2013 4:14 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b03bfbda-505d-11e3-befe-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman set to step up warehouse sale talks</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs is likely to step up discussions over a sale of its metals warehousing business having received numerous expressions of interest, according to people familiar with the situation.</p>
The move comes as the US Federal Reserve is reviewing the extent to which banks are permitted to trade physical commodities and own commodity infrastructure. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sam Jones, Hedge Fund Correspondent" date="November 12, 2013 8:38 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/3b7e1c7c-4bbe-11e3-a02f-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman bet looks beyond hedge fund gloom</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs is betting that the hedge fund industry can attract more investors despite its recent performance record  by raising money for a second incarnation of one of its highest-profile investment vehicles, Petershill. </p>
Like its predecessor, Petershill II will buy minority stakes in established hedge fund management companies, in order to take a slice of the profits they make from charging fees to their clients.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite and Tracy Alloway in New York" date="November 12, 2013 6:56 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/1c0ca14e-4bb2-11e3-a02f-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman''s Blankfein rejects wholesale'' change</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>Lloyd Blankfein has insisted that Goldman Sachs does not need a ''wholesale'' overhaul</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Victor Mallet in New Delhi" date="November 8, 2013 4:39 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/5508f612-482b-11e3-88be-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>India accuses Goldman Sachs of political interference</headline><body><![CDATA[India''s Congress-led government on Friday accused Goldman Sachs of interfering in the country''s politics after the investment bank upgraded its assessment of the economy on expectations that opposition leader Narendra Modi would win next year''s general election.</p>
Goldman is parading its ignorance about the basic facts of the Indian economy, and it also exposes its eagerness to mess around with India''s domestic politics, Anand Sharma, commerce and industry minister, said in an interview in The Economic Times. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite and Tracy Alloway in New York" date="November 7, 2013 10:59 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e877f840-47da-11e3-88be-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman repositions Sherwood in reshuffle</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>J Michael Evans (right), vice chairman of Goldman Sachs Group, speaks to Lloyd Blankfein, Goldman Sachs chairman and CEO, at the World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite" date="November 7, 2013 1:31 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/952d4d9a-47a6-11e3-9398-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman drawn into currencies probe</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs disclosed its involvement in the international investigation of foreign exchange markets in a quarterly regulatory filing on Thursday and gave more detail on its deteriorating trading performance.</p>
The bank simply added the word currencies to the myriad of probes to which it is subject to cover the investigation into whether some of the biggest banks in the world rigged the foreign exchange market, which has daily volumes of $5.3tn and is used by millions of companies, institutional funds and retail investors.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jack Farchy in London" date="November 4, 2013 6:23 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/ab06c17a-4579-11e3-997c-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman research rebuts warehouse critics</headline><body><![CDATA[Analysts at Goldman Sachs have argued that warehouse queues do not influence aluminium prices, rebutting complaints by users of the metal who have suggested the opposite.</p>
Long queues to take delivery of aluminium from London Metal Exchange warehouses have become the focus of a furious debate in recent months, triggering a series of complaints by metal users, criticism by senators and investigations by US regulators.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="November 3, 2013 3:25 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/d7086aee-4493-11e3-a751-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman plans $250m social impact'' fund</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs is launching a $250m social impact fund whose returns are linked to the success of projects such as affordable housing, pre-school education and how many young criminals commit new offences after leaving New York''s notorious Rikers Island prison.</p>
Wall Street banks are increasingly vying for the kudos and cash that can come with investing in projects intended to improve conditions in cities US-wide. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="fer in London" date="October 29, 2013 8:20 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0a994e7a-408c-11e3-ae19-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs eases work conditions of junior investment bankers</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chris Flood" date="October 27, 2013 4:29 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/8d4d9ae0-3d50-11e3-9928-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman backs money market funds</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs'' eye-catching acquisition last week of Royal Bank of Scotland''s money fund business is expected to be followed by more deals as regulatory change and pressure on profits drives consolidation in Europe''s 1tn money market industry.</p>
GSAM, which already managed $195bn in money funds globally, snapped up assets worth $12.4bn from RBS for an undisclosed sum, a deal that underlines the importance of acquiring scale to mitigate the growing burden of regulation.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="October 17, 2013 6:21 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c72b16dc-371c-11e3-9603-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman fixed income trading worst in class</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs reported a worse plunge in fixed-income trading than any other large Wall Street bank but protected its profits by slashing the amount of money set aside for year-end bonuses.</p>
Third-quarter net income was flat at $1.5bn, exceeding analysts'' estimates, but revenue fell short, down from $8.4bn a year earlier to $6.7bn. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York and Gina Chon in Washington" date="October 10, 2013 11:08 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a0a64a56-31e8-11e3-a16d-00144feab7de.html"><headline>New York Fed sued over Goldman oversight</headline><body><![CDATA[A former bank examiner filed a suit against the Federal Reserve Bank of New York on Thursday, claiming she was fired after criticising Goldman Sachs for its policies on managing conflicts of interest.</p>
Carmen Segarra is suing the New York Fed and three of its officials in federal court in New York, claiming that her superiors interfered with her work examining Goldman and expressed concern that the bank would be harmed by her criticism.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alistair Gray and Anne-Sylvaine Chassany" date="October 8, 2013 11:22 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/2c4a5118-3033-11e3-80a4-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs'' arm buys 50% of Hastings</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs'' merchant banking division is to complete its first UK private equity deal since 2008 by acquiring a 50 per cent stake in Hastings, giving the motor insurer an enterprise value of about 700m.</p>
The bank''s private equity arm is buying a stake worth about 150m in the business, which is run by Gary Hoffman, who led Northern Rock after its collapse, and chaired by entrepreneur Neil Utley.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Simon Rabinovitch in Shanghai, Paul J Davies in Hong Kong and Lucy Hornby in Beijing" date="October 8, 2013 1:48 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/baa9c1c8-3006-11e3-80a4-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman link to China corruption probe</headline><body><![CDATA[An education company co-founded by Goldman Sachs is at the centre of a corruption probe that has ensnared the head of a leading Chinese state-owned corporation.</p>
Lei Yi, chairman of Yunnan Tin, the world''s largest producer of the industrial metal by volumes, has been charged with accepting bribes worth Rmb20m ($3.3m), according to a state media report on the Yunnan provincial government''s website.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="October 7, 2013 7:59 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/1d4c05d6-2f65-11e3-ae87-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Zoellick joins Goldman Sachs as adviser</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Milne, Nordic Correspondent" date="October 2, 2013 7:42 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/22c02cb6-2b7f-11e3-a1b7-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs buys into Dong Energy</headline><body><![CDATA[AP]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tracy Alloway and Michael Mackenzie in New York" date="September 22, 2013 1:14 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/1749b164-2219-11e3-bb64-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs revamps bond-trading platform</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs has radically restructured its electronic bond trading platform in a last-ditch effort to lure customers to the struggling system.</p>
The move underscores one of the biggest challenges facing Wall Street. Banks and investors both say that their ability to trade corporate bonds has dropped sharply in recent years, but the two sides cannot agree on how best to improve liquidity in the $9.2tn market for US companies'' debt.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Gina Chon, Tom Braithwaite and Michael Mackenzie in New York" date="September 19, 2013 11:59 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/5cb9d9e4-217a-11e3-8aff-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman hit by New York Fed error</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs suffered a loss when a clerical error by the New York Federal Reserve left the bank without any of the three-month Treasury bills it had ordered at a government debt auction, people familiar with the matter said.</p>
The incident came only weeks after Goldman made a large number of erroneous options trades in August that disrupted trading at multiple US exchanges.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Camilla Hall, Tracy Alloway and Arash Massoudi in New York" date="September 16, 2013 6:05 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/661b3608-1eec-11e3-b80b-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs replaces chief information officer</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs has promoted Marty Chavez to chief information officer, overseeing a department that has been in the spotlight after an embarrassing trading glitch.</p>
Steven Scopellite, global head of the technology division and current chief information officer, will retire at the end of the year, according to internal memos confirmed by Goldman.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tracy Alloway and Arash Massoudi in New York" date="September 13, 2013 1:37 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/095fd274-1c59-11e3-8894-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs wins prime role in Twitter IPO</headline><body><![CDATA[When Twitter publishes the prospectus for its long-awaited initial public offering, the name of Goldman Sachs will appear on the first page, in prime position.</p>
Goldman''s selection as lead underwriter, known in the industry as the lead left, is a setback for rival Morgan Stanley, which has dominated tech deals in recent years but was criticised after last year''s botched $16.1bn initial public offering of Facebook.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By James Shotter in Zurich" date="September 12, 2013 1:07 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/7015fe86-1b81-11e3-b678-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman''s Zurich offices visited over working-hours complaint</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael Mackenzie and Arash Massoudi in New York" date="September 10, 2013 7:52 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0a3d74d2-1a18-11e3-93e8-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman joins Dow in big stocks shake-up</headline><body><![CDATA[Credit cards, investment banking and running shoes are coming to the world''s most recognisable stock market benchmark, reflecting the shift in the US economy from industry to services and consumer goods.</p>
Visa, Goldman Sachs and Nike, three major companies with high equity prices, are joining the Dow Jones Industrial Average, the select group of 30 companies that form one of America''s most well-known stock benchmarks.</p>
<h3>The Dow falls behind</h3>]]> </body></entry><entry author="in New York" date="August 25, 2013 5:19 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b65ba46c-0c37-11e3-8f77-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman puts four on leave after glitch</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Madison Marriage and Chris Newlands" date="August 25, 2013 5:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/85c1b63e-0511-11e3-9e71-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman targets 10% fiduciary market share</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters<p>Asset push: Goldman Sachs plans to exploit its tight-knit'' network of investment teams round the world</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Arash Massoudi and Tracy Alloway in New York" date="August 22, 2013 5:00 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/37fff9c6-0b36-11e3-bffc-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>17-minute trading glitch put Goldman''s reputation on the line</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Neil Munshi in Chicago" date="August 22, 2013 7:40 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/11273d72-0ab0-11e3-aeab-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman should take the hit on tech-glitch losses, says Scholes</headline><body><![CDATA[Myron Scholes, one of the founding fathers of modern options trading, has said Goldman Sachs and others should be forced to incur huge losses if they make mistaken trades, instead of being able to cancel them. </p>
Mr Scholes, co-author of the Black-Scholes formula of options pricing, made the remarks in an interview with the Financial Times the day after Goldman inadvertently flooded the US options market with a large number of unintended computer-driven trades in companies such as JPMorgan Chase and Kellogg. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Arash Massoudi, Kara Scannell and Tracy Alloway in New York" date="August 21, 2013 6:58 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c6b4aa74-0a76-11e3-aeab-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>SEC scrutinises Goldman''s trading failure</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters<p>Money markets are a very necessary'' part of business</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Arash Massoudi and Tracy Alloway in New York and Neil Munshi in Chicago" date="August 21, 2013 1:02 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f95200d6-09ad-11e3-ad07-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman faces losses on erroneous trades</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters<p>Money markets are a very necessary'' part of business</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ajay Makan in London" date="August 19, 2013 6:38 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/68305f1e-08ed-11e3-ad07-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman forecasts oil at $115 in short term</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs has raised its short-term forecasts for the oil price, citing continuing supply disruptions and better than expected demand for crude and petroleum products. </p>
Brent crude oil, the global benchmark, has climbed more than 10 per cent since April. Libyan production has plunged to the lowest levels seen since the country''s civil war in 2011, capping a series of disruptions elsewhere. On Monday ICE October Brent traded as high as $111 a barrel.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tracy Alloway in New York" date="August 18, 2013 9:32 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c21adeac-06ac-11e3-9bd9-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman seeks to lure other banks to bond trading platform</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs has been trying to recruit other banks to its electronic bond trading platform, in a move which highlights some of the tentative industry efforts under way to boost liquidity in the $9.1tn market for corporate debt.</p>
Big banks, including Goldman, have been experimenting with new ways of trading corporate bonds by setting up their own single dealer electronic trading platforms, which in theory allow investors easily to buy and sell companies'' debt.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Miles Johnson in Madrid" date="August 12, 2013 2:47 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/16709db6-034c-11e3-9a46-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs and Azora buy 3,000 Spanish apartments for 201m</headline><body><![CDATA[The regional government of Madrid has sold a portfolio of residential flats to Goldman Sachs private equity and Azora, the investment group, for 201m.</p>
The sale is the latest in a spate of foreign private equity investors buying into Spanish real estate, the highest level of activity since the collapse of the country''s decade-long property bubble forced large swaths of its banking sector into being nationalised.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alistair Gray in London" date="August 8, 2013 7:48 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/ebc31ce8-0043-11e3-ba6b-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs plans pension business stake sale</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs is planning to sell a majority stake in its London-based specialist pensions business Rothesay Life, in the latest sign banks are pulling back from the market in the face of tougher capital requirements.</p>
Bankers estimated that the operation, which insures UK companies against the expense and volatility of their defined benefit pension schemes, to be worth between 750m and 1bn.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chris Newlands" date="August 4, 2013 5:21 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/63f1f5be-fb70-11e2-a641-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman commits to money market funds</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters<p>Money markets are a very necessary'' part of business</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jack Farchy in London, and Tom Braithwaite and Gregory Meyer in New York" date="July 31, 2013 6:19 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a41080ac-fa03-11e2-b8ef-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman relents in metals warehousing row</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs has bowed to a barrage of criticism of its activities in the metals markets, proposing a series of measures to ease long queues that have helped to boost profits at its warehousing unit.</p>
The bank came under heavy fire last week at a Senate hearing on banks and commodity markets where MillerCoors, the brewer, suggested that its supply chain had been hampered by long queues to take delivery of the metal from warehouses owned by Goldman and other banks and traders.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Madison Marriage" date="July 31, 2013 11:01 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/ebb1cb78-f93b-11e2-a6ef-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman bets on eurozone recovery</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chris Newlands" date="July 19, 2013 10:17 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/711bc616-efa9-11e2-8229-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Aberdeen rejects Goldman Sachs criticisms</headline><body><![CDATA[The chief executive of Aberdeen Asset Management has rejected claims by Goldman Sachs that the UK fund house is too reliant on its emerging market funds, saying the assertions are over-simplistic.</p>
In a research note published last month, Goldman cut Aberdeen from its buy list. It cited fears that the fund house had not worked hard enough to reduce its dependence on its Global Emerging Markets and Asia-Pacific equities funds.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York and Gina Chon in Washington" date="September 26, 2014 11:46 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a327e6be-45c8-11e4-ab10-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman in stock trading curb on bankers</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Gina Chon in Washington and Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="September 26, 2014 8:07 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/af839e36-458b-11e4-ab86-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>New York Fed rejects claims of being too soft on Goldman Sachs</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jane Croft and Caroline Binham" date="September 21, 2014 3:09 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/73ffa60e-4025-11e4-936b-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman defence lifts veil on LIA relationship</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Caroline Binham and Jane Croft in London" date="September 19, 2014 8:17 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b2d79034-4021-11e4-936b-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman admits cultivating ties with Gaddafi-era Libya fund</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs has admitted in court documents that it used an internship, training, small gifts, occasional travel and entertainment to cement a strategic partnership with the Libyan Investment Authority under the former Gaddafi regime.</p>
The bank''s defence to a $1bn lawsuit filed by the LIA in London in January lifts a veil on techniques deployed by the company and other western financial institutions to win and deepen client relationships with the $66bn sovereign wealth fund  techniques that law enforcement agencies in the US are probing as to whether they tipped over into potential bribery.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Simeon Kerr in Dubai and Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="September 4, 2014 5:24 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/1af110fe-3448-11e4-b81c-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs to issue its first Islamic bond</headline><body><![CDATA[AP]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Miles Johnson in London and Peter Wise in Lisbon" date="September 1, 2014 5:08 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/d8b17e92-31e3-11e4-a19b-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman lent $835m to Banco Esprito Santo before bailout</headline><body><![CDATA[EPA]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite and Kara Scannell in New York" date="August 22, 2014 11:28 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b604de64-2a1a-11e4-a068-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman and Morgan Stanley in DoJ mortgage talks</headline><body><![CDATA[AP]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="August 20, 2014 7:52 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/3cab36ee-288a-11e4-8bda-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman gives junior bankers 20% pay rise</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Anna Nicolaou and Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="August 20, 2014 6:59 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/d3a8bede-26e8-11e4-bc19-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Calm force during Goldman''s darkest hours</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Caroline Binham, Legal Correspondent" date="August 19, 2014 4:53 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/bab6868e-27ad-11e4-ae44-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman withdraws attempt to stop $1bn Libya fund dispute</headline><body><![CDATA[<p>A pre-trial hearing in the case is scheduled for early October at the High Court in London</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tracy Alloway in New York" date="August 14, 2014 6:29 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/8b939d5c-2315-11e4-a424-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman invites Wall St to chat for $5m</headline><body><![CDATA[AP]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Hammond in New York" date="August 4, 2014 12:02 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e3db083e-1b5d-11e4-b649-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Ex-Barclays rainmaker joins Goldman Sachs</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>Paul Parker</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tracy Alloway in New York" date="July 24, 2014 4:59 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/5c5734aa-11ad-11e4-b356-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman bankers to Babble on their own chatroom</headline><body><![CDATA[AP]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Caroline Binham, Legal Correspondent" date="July 23, 2014 6:18 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/d816bfd2-127c-11e4-a581-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman rebuked over 1m legal fees claim</headline><body><![CDATA[AP]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tracy Alloway and Michael Mackenzie in New York" date="July 22, 2014 2:47 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/256884fa-0de6-11e4-85ab-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman to sell up to 10bn bonds with new swap</headline><body><![CDATA[AP]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Patrick Jenkins" date=" July 21, 2014 7:17 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/af32c054-10c2-11e4-b116-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Investors would be wise to compare Barclays with Goldman</headline><body><![CDATA[Among the famous head-to-head rivalries in banking, Goldman Sachs and Barclays never really figured.</p>
Goldman was always measured against its closest Wall Street peers. Barclays was the arch rival of fellow European, Deutsche Bank. Their styles differed, too  the US group symbolised an aggressive, ultra-smart approach; Barclays was more the cheeky challenger.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tracy Alloway and Camilla Hall in New York" date="July 15, 2014 1:16 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/34d3e306-0b68-11e4-8693-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman and JPMorgan beat trading fears</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="fer in London" date="July 6, 2014 6:14 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a0f8ec30-0388-11e4-817f-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman muscles in on Europe''s private banks</headline><body><![CDATA[AP]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Camilla Hall in New York" date="July 2, 2014 12:07 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b20d16e2-016a-11e4-9750-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs accused of boys club'' atmosphere</headline><body><![CDATA[AP]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Nicole Bullock in New York and Philip Stafford in London" date="July 1, 2014 5:48 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c56c6aa8-012e-11e4-b94d-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs fined in dark pool debacle</headline><body><![CDATA[US regulators have fined Goldman Sachs $800,000 for failing to ensure that trades executed in the bank''s own trading venue met US laws protecting investors'' right to best market prices.</p>
The fine levelled by the Financial Industry Regulatory Authority comes amid heightened scrutiny around the US share trading industry. </p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hannah Kuchler, Arash Massoudi and Camilla Hall" date="July 1, 2014 2:51 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/91ff6f9e-0124-11e4-b94d-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Twitter hires ex-Goldman Sachs banker Anthony Noto as CFO</headline><body><![CDATA[<p>Twitter-bound: Anthony Noto, former Goldman banker</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alistair Gray in London" date="June 17, 2014 5:04 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/815610cc-f624-11e3-a038-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>RSA appoints Goldman Sachs to handle sale of its Asia business</headline><body><![CDATA[RSA, the FTSE 100 insurer trying to recover from an accounting scandal in Ireland, has appointed Goldman Sachs to handle the sale of its Asia business, estimated to be worth at least 150m.</p>
The insurer, led by former Royal Bank of Scotland chief executive Stephen Hester, is set to begin a process to sell its operations in Hong Kong, Singapore and China within weeks, people with knowledge of the process said.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="June 12, 2014 6:26 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/63ef855e-f246-11e3-ac7a-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman and Bain pay $121m to settle buyout conspiracy case</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Miles Johnson" date="June 9, 2014 12:12 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/08374420-ed8e-11e3-8a1e-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman stars fall back down to earth</headline><body><![CDATA[Cold on the outside: Goldman Sachs (headquarters pictured) lost star proprietary desk traders in the wake of the financial crisis. Many set up hedge funds but struggled to replicate their successBloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jennifer Hughes in Hong Kong" date="June 5, 2014 5:25 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0d1b99f8-ec5f-11e3-a9e3-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs beefs up Asia M&amp;A team</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs is beefing up its mergers team in Asia as deal volume in the region reaches record levels.</p>
The US investment bank is creating a new position of vice-chairman of the investment banking division for Asia Pacific excluding Japan. The role is being taken on by Richard Campbell-Breeden, who also becomes chairman of its mergers and acquisitions group.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry></news>