
<news><entry author="By Sam Jones, Hedge Fund Correspondent" date="November 12, 2013 8:38 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/3b7e1c7c-4bbe-11e3-a02f-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman bet looks beyond hedge fund gloom</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs is betting that the hedge fund industry can attract more investors despite its recent performance record  by raising money for a second incarnation of one of its highest-profile investment vehicles, Petershill. </p>
Like its predecessor, Petershill II will buy minority stakes in established hedge fund management companies, in order to take a slice of the profits they make from charging fees to their clients.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite and Tracy Alloway in New York" date="November 12, 2013 6:56 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/1c0ca14e-4bb2-11e3-a02f-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman''s Blankfein rejects wholesale'' change</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>Lloyd Blankfein has insisted that Goldman Sachs does not need a ''wholesale'' overhaul</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Victor Mallet in New Delhi" date="November 8, 2013 4:39 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/5508f612-482b-11e3-88be-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>India accuses Goldman Sachs of political interference</headline><body><![CDATA[India''s Congress-led government on Friday accused Goldman Sachs of interfering in the country''s politics after the investment bank upgraded its assessment of the economy on expectations that opposition leader Narendra Modi would win next year''s general election.</p>
Goldman is parading its ignorance about the basic facts of the Indian economy, and it also exposes its eagerness to mess around with India''s domestic politics, Anand Sharma, commerce and industry minister, said in an interview in The Economic Times. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite and Tracy Alloway in New York" date="November 7, 2013 10:59 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e877f840-47da-11e3-88be-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman repositions Sherwood in reshuffle</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>J Michael Evans (right), vice chairman of Goldman Sachs Group, speaks to Lloyd Blankfein, Goldman Sachs chairman and CEO, at the World Economic Forum in Davos, Switzerland</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite" date="November 7, 2013 1:31 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/952d4d9a-47a6-11e3-9398-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman drawn into currencies probe</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs disclosed its involvement in the international investigation of foreign exchange markets in a quarterly regulatory filing on Thursday and gave more detail on its deteriorating trading performance.</p>
The bank simply added the word currencies to the myriad of probes to which it is subject to cover the investigation into whether some of the biggest banks in the world rigged the foreign exchange market, which has daily volumes of $5.3tn and is used by millions of companies, institutional funds and retail investors.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jack Farchy in London" date="November 4, 2013 6:23 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/ab06c17a-4579-11e3-997c-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman research rebuts warehouse critics</headline><body><![CDATA[Analysts at Goldman Sachs have argued that warehouse queues do not influence aluminium prices, rebutting complaints by users of the metal who have suggested the opposite.</p>
Long queues to take delivery of aluminium from London Metal Exchange warehouses have become the focus of a furious debate in recent months, triggering a series of complaints by metal users, criticism by senators and investigations by US regulators.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="November 3, 2013 3:25 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/d7086aee-4493-11e3-a751-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman plans $250m social impact'' fund</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs is launching a $250m social impact fund whose returns are linked to the success of projects such as affordable housing, pre-school education and how many young criminals commit new offences after leaving New York''s notorious Rikers Island prison.</p>
Wall Street banks are increasingly vying for the kudos and cash that can come with investing in projects intended to improve conditions in cities US-wide. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="fer in London" date="October 29, 2013 8:20 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0a994e7a-408c-11e3-ae19-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs eases work conditions of junior investment bankers</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chris Flood" date="October 27, 2013 4:29 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/8d4d9ae0-3d50-11e3-9928-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman backs money market funds</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs'' eye-catching acquisition last week of Royal Bank of Scotland''s money fund business is expected to be followed by more deals as regulatory change and pressure on profits drives consolidation in Europe''s 1tn money market industry.</p>
GSAM, which already managed $195bn in money funds globally, snapped up assets worth $12.4bn from RBS for an undisclosed sum, a deal that underlines the importance of acquiring scale to mitigate the growing burden of regulation.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="October 17, 2013 6:21 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c72b16dc-371c-11e3-9603-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman fixed income trading worst in class</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs reported a worse plunge in fixed-income trading than any other large Wall Street bank but protected its profits by slashing the amount of money set aside for year-end bonuses.</p>
Third-quarter net income was flat at $1.5bn, exceeding analysts'' estimates, but revenue fell short, down from $8.4bn a year earlier to $6.7bn. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York and Gina Chon in Washington" date="October 10, 2013 11:08 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a0a64a56-31e8-11e3-a16d-00144feab7de.html"><headline>New York Fed sued over Goldman oversight</headline><body><![CDATA[A former bank examiner filed a suit against the Federal Reserve Bank of New York on Thursday, claiming she was fired after criticising Goldman Sachs for its policies on managing conflicts of interest.</p>
Carmen Segarra is suing the New York Fed and three of its officials in federal court in New York, claiming that her superiors interfered with her work examining Goldman and expressed concern that the bank would be harmed by her criticism.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alistair Gray and Anne-Sylvaine Chassany" date="October 8, 2013 11:22 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/2c4a5118-3033-11e3-80a4-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs'' arm buys 50% of Hastings</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs'' merchant banking division is to complete its first UK private equity deal since 2008 by acquiring a 50 per cent stake in Hastings, giving the motor insurer an enterprise value of about 700m.</p>
The bank''s private equity arm is buying a stake worth about 150m in the business, which is run by Gary Hoffman, who led Northern Rock after its collapse, and chaired by entrepreneur Neil Utley.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Simon Rabinovitch in Shanghai, Paul J Davies in Hong Kong and Lucy Hornby in Beijing" date="October 8, 2013 1:48 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/baa9c1c8-3006-11e3-80a4-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman link to China corruption probe</headline><body><![CDATA[An education company co-founded by Goldman Sachs is at the centre of a corruption probe that has ensnared the head of a leading Chinese state-owned corporation.</p>
Lei Yi, chairman of Yunnan Tin, the world''s largest producer of the industrial metal by volumes, has been charged with accepting bribes worth Rmb20m ($3.3m), according to a state media report on the Yunnan provincial government''s website.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="October 7, 2013 7:59 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/1d4c05d6-2f65-11e3-ae87-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Zoellick joins Goldman Sachs as adviser</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Milne, Nordic Correspondent" date="October 2, 2013 7:42 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/22c02cb6-2b7f-11e3-a1b7-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs buys into Dong Energy</headline><body><![CDATA[AP]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tracy Alloway and Michael Mackenzie in New York" date="September 22, 2013 1:14 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/1749b164-2219-11e3-bb64-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs revamps bond-trading platform</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs has radically restructured its electronic bond trading platform in a last-ditch effort to lure customers to the struggling system.</p>
The move underscores one of the biggest challenges facing Wall Street. Banks and investors both say that their ability to trade corporate bonds has dropped sharply in recent years, but the two sides cannot agree on how best to improve liquidity in the $9.2tn market for US companies'' debt.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Gina Chon, Tom Braithwaite and Michael Mackenzie in New York" date="September 19, 2013 11:59 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/5cb9d9e4-217a-11e3-8aff-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman hit by New York Fed error</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs suffered a loss when a clerical error by the New York Federal Reserve left the bank without any of the three-month Treasury bills it had ordered at a government debt auction, people familiar with the matter said.</p>
The incident came only weeks after Goldman made a large number of erroneous options trades in August that disrupted trading at multiple US exchanges.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Camilla Hall, Tracy Alloway and Arash Massoudi in New York" date="September 16, 2013 6:05 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/661b3608-1eec-11e3-b80b-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs replaces chief information officer</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs has promoted Marty Chavez to chief information officer, overseeing a department that has been in the spotlight after an embarrassing trading glitch.</p>
Steven Scopellite, global head of the technology division and current chief information officer, will retire at the end of the year, according to internal memos confirmed by Goldman.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tracy Alloway and Arash Massoudi in New York" date="September 13, 2013 1:37 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/095fd274-1c59-11e3-8894-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs wins prime role in Twitter IPO</headline><body><![CDATA[When Twitter publishes the prospectus for its long-awaited initial public offering, the name of Goldman Sachs will appear on the first page, in prime position.</p>
Goldman''s selection as lead underwriter, known in the industry as the lead left, is a setback for rival Morgan Stanley, which has dominated tech deals in recent years but was criticised after last year''s botched $16.1bn initial public offering of Facebook.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By James Shotter in Zurich" date="September 12, 2013 1:07 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/7015fe86-1b81-11e3-b678-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman''s Zurich offices visited over working-hours complaint</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael Mackenzie and Arash Massoudi in New York" date="September 10, 2013 7:52 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0a3d74d2-1a18-11e3-93e8-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman joins Dow in big stocks shake-up</headline><body><![CDATA[Credit cards, investment banking and running shoes are coming to the world''s most recognisable stock market benchmark, reflecting the shift in the US economy from industry to services and consumer goods.</p>
Visa, Goldman Sachs and Nike, three major companies with high equity prices, are joining the Dow Jones Industrial Average, the select group of 30 companies that form one of America''s most well-known stock benchmarks.</p>
<h3>The Dow falls behind</h3>]]> </body></entry><entry author="in New York" date="August 25, 2013 5:19 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b65ba46c-0c37-11e3-8f77-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman puts four on leave after glitch</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Madison Marriage and Chris Newlands" date="August 25, 2013 5:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/85c1b63e-0511-11e3-9e71-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman targets 10% fiduciary market share</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters<p>Asset push: Goldman Sachs plans to exploit its tight-knit'' network of investment teams round the world</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Arash Massoudi and Tracy Alloway in New York" date="August 22, 2013 5:00 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/37fff9c6-0b36-11e3-bffc-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>17-minute trading glitch put Goldman''s reputation on the line</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Neil Munshi in Chicago" date="August 22, 2013 7:40 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/11273d72-0ab0-11e3-aeab-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman should take the hit on tech-glitch losses, says Scholes</headline><body><![CDATA[Myron Scholes, one of the founding fathers of modern options trading, has said Goldman Sachs and others should be forced to incur huge losses if they make mistaken trades, instead of being able to cancel them. </p>
Mr Scholes, co-author of the Black-Scholes formula of options pricing, made the remarks in an interview with the Financial Times the day after Goldman inadvertently flooded the US options market with a large number of unintended computer-driven trades in companies such as JPMorgan Chase and Kellogg. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Arash Massoudi, Kara Scannell and Tracy Alloway in New York" date="August 21, 2013 6:58 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c6b4aa74-0a76-11e3-aeab-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>SEC scrutinises Goldman''s trading failure</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters<p>Money markets are a very necessary'' part of business</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Arash Massoudi and Tracy Alloway in New York and Neil Munshi in Chicago" date="August 21, 2013 1:02 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f95200d6-09ad-11e3-ad07-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman faces losses on erroneous trades</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters<p>Money markets are a very necessary'' part of business</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ajay Makan in London" date="August 19, 2013 6:38 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/68305f1e-08ed-11e3-ad07-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman forecasts oil at $115 in short term</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs has raised its short-term forecasts for the oil price, citing continuing supply disruptions and better than expected demand for crude and petroleum products. </p>
Brent crude oil, the global benchmark, has climbed more than 10 per cent since April. Libyan production has plunged to the lowest levels seen since the country''s civil war in 2011, capping a series of disruptions elsewhere. On Monday ICE October Brent traded as high as $111 a barrel.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tracy Alloway in New York" date="August 18, 2013 9:32 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c21adeac-06ac-11e3-9bd9-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman seeks to lure other banks to bond trading platform</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs has been trying to recruit other banks to its electronic bond trading platform, in a move which highlights some of the tentative industry efforts under way to boost liquidity in the $9.1tn market for corporate debt.</p>
Big banks, including Goldman, have been experimenting with new ways of trading corporate bonds by setting up their own single dealer electronic trading platforms, which in theory allow investors easily to buy and sell companies'' debt.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Miles Johnson in Madrid" date="August 12, 2013 2:47 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/16709db6-034c-11e3-9a46-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs and Azora buy 3,000 Spanish apartments for 201m</headline><body><![CDATA[The regional government of Madrid has sold a portfolio of residential flats to Goldman Sachs private equity and Azora, the investment group, for 201m.</p>
The sale is the latest in a spate of foreign private equity investors buying into Spanish real estate, the highest level of activity since the collapse of the country''s decade-long property bubble forced large swaths of its banking sector into being nationalised.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alistair Gray in London" date="August 8, 2013 7:48 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/ebc31ce8-0043-11e3-ba6b-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs plans pension business stake sale</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs is planning to sell a majority stake in its London-based specialist pensions business Rothesay Life, in the latest sign banks are pulling back from the market in the face of tougher capital requirements.</p>
Bankers estimated that the operation, which insures UK companies against the expense and volatility of their defined benefit pension schemes, to be worth between 750m and 1bn.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chris Newlands" date="August 4, 2013 5:21 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/63f1f5be-fb70-11e2-a641-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman commits to money market funds</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters<p>Money markets are a very necessary'' part of business</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jack Farchy in London, and Tom Braithwaite and Gregory Meyer in New York" date="July 31, 2013 6:19 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a41080ac-fa03-11e2-b8ef-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman relents in metals warehousing row</headline><body><![CDATA[Goldman Sachs has bowed to a barrage of criticism of its activities in the metals markets, proposing a series of measures to ease long queues that have helped to boost profits at its warehousing unit.</p>
The bank came under heavy fire last week at a Senate hearing on banks and commodity markets where MillerCoors, the brewer, suggested that its supply chain had been hampered by long queues to take delivery of the metal from warehouses owned by Goldman and other banks and traders.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Madison Marriage" date="July 31, 2013 11:01 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/ebb1cb78-f93b-11e2-a6ef-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Goldman bets on eurozone recovery</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chris Newlands" date="July 19, 2013 10:17 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/711bc616-efa9-11e2-8229-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Aberdeen rejects Goldman Sachs criticisms</headline><body><![CDATA[The chief executive of Aberdeen Asset Management has rejected claims by Goldman Sachs that the UK fund house is too reliant on its emerging market funds, saying the assertions are over-simplistic.</p>
In a research note published last month, Goldman cut Aberdeen from its buy list. It cited fears that the fund house had not worked hard enough to reduce its dependence on its Global Emerging Markets and Asia-Pacific equities funds.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Barker in Brussels" date="September 23, 2014 11:52 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e4e9f1f8-42ff-11e4-9a58-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>EU antitrust chief says Google case may be bigger than Microsoft</headline><body><![CDATA[EPA<p>Joaqun Almunia</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sally Davies" date="September 16, 2014 2:57 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/2196c9da-3d85-11e4-b782-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Blur Group names former Microsoft UK executive finance director</headline><body><![CDATA[Blur Group, the UK company that lets people buy and sell services online from app-making to advertising, has appointed former Microsoft executive Stephen Harvey as its chief financial officer.</p>
The company  which has been described by its chief executive as an eBay for business services  has been through three other finance directors in the past two years as it has overhauled its accounting and financial reporting practices. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Milne in Stockholm, Arash Massoudi in London and Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="September 15, 2014 7:20 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/34ad6748-3cf1-11e4-a2ab-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft buys Minecraft maker for $2.5bn</headline><body /></entry><entry author="By Sally Davies, Richard Milne and Tim Bradshaw" date="September 10, 2014 5:44 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/04e86370-38e9-11e4-9526-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft in talks to buy Minecraft maker for more than $2bn</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft is in talks to buy Mojang, the Swedish company behind retro gaming sensation Minecraft, for more than $2bn, according to two people with knowledge of the discussions.</p>
One of those people said that co-founder Markus Persson  a maverick gamer known as Notch  would probably leave the company if a deal is agreed. </p>
Mr Persson owns about 70 per cent of the business, valuing his stake at about $1.4bn. The other owners are Jakob Porser, Mr Persson''s co-founder and best friend, and chief executive Carl Manneh.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="September 7, 2014 6:24 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/15f5f5fc-369f-11e4-85be-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft drops controversial image tool</headline><body /></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="September 4, 2014 6:08 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/5fbc84e0-3450-11e4-b81c-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Getty sues Microsoft over digital images</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Daniel Thomas, Telecoms Correspondent" date="September 4, 2014 12:26 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/9eaf977c-341a-11e4-b81c-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft brings mobile personal assistant Cortana to UK and China</headline><body><![CDATA[AP<p>Slim: The Lumia 830</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Charles Clover in Beijing" date="September 1, 2014 1:32 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/31d5fdd8-31bf-11e4-a19b-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft ordered to comply over China antitrust allegations</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Avantika Chilkoti" date="August 20, 2014 10:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/4cc4515e-2822-11e4-ae44-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Steve Ballmer quits Microsoft board to focus on NBA''s Clippers</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="August 1, 2014 10:51 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c096ba4a-19c2-11e4-b06c-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft files legal complaint against Samsung</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="July 31, 2014 8:59 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0649c042-18e6-11e4-933e-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft setback in cloud era test case</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft on Thursday suffered a setback in a case testing the cross-border reach of law enforcement in the cloud computing era, after it was ordered to hand US authorities a user''s email held in a datacentre in Ireland.</p>
The decision, if it stands, represents a further reversal for the US internet industry in the wake of the Snowden revelations about widespread surveillance by the National Security Agency, according to legal experts.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Charles Clover in Beijing" date="July 30, 2014 3:44 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/27f9eb7a-17df-11e4-b842-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft raid highlights US trade troubles in China</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="July 28, 2014 4:59 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/355714d0-1665-11e4-93ec-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft targeted in China antitrust probe</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="July 23, 2014 12:01 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/dfab4988-11d8-11e4-8279-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft narrows efforts in mobile phones, Xbox games and Bing</headline><body><![CDATA[Satya Nadella, Microsoft''s new chief executive, promised to narrow the US software company''s efforts in mobile phones, the Xbox games console and Bing search engine, as he sought to persuade Wall Street that he was bringing more discipline to its strategy.</p>
However, he argued that Microsoft still needed to maintain its broad reach across both business and consumer technology markets, despite grumblings from investors that he is not doing enough to focus on its operations.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="July 21, 2014 12:44 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/61192662-10c5-11e4-812b-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft''s Satya Nadella to face tough questions from Wall Street</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David Crouch in Gothenburg" date="July 17, 2014 6:07 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0db372f6-0dce-11e4-85ab-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Anger and bewilderment in Finland over Microsoft job cuts</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>Alexander Stubb, Finland''s prime minister, said he found the job cuts "very very difficult from a human point of view."</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco, Murad Ahmed in London and David Crouch in Gothenburg" date="July 17, 2014 3:00 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/6a81e2be-0db1-11e4-b149-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft to shed 18,000 jobs</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="June 30, 2014 11:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/1bfa7e90-ff6e-11e3-9a4a-00144feab7de.html"><headline>EU slams US over Microsoft privacy case</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tim Bradshaw in San Francisco" date="April 30, 2014 4:45 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f6534348-d001-11e3-a2b7-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft''s Xbox One to go on sale in China</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Daniel Thomas, Telecoms Correspondent" date="April 28, 2014 11:59 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f8531d60-cef0-11e3-ac8d-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft developing brand for smartphone products</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft is developing a brand for forthcoming smartphone products following the acquisition of Nokia, says the former chief executive of the Finnish group, who is moving to the US with the handset businesses.</p>
Stephen Elop, who will head Microsoft''s devices business, said the US group will not use Nokia or Microsoft Mobile as had been speculated for the next stage in its attempt to crack the lucrative but highly competitive smartphone market. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Daniel Thomas" date="April 25, 2014 2:28 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/33c1b882-aeb9-11e3-aaa6-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Nokia completes 5.4bn sale of handset division to Microsoft</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="April 25, 2014 2:01 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f8da7cd8-cc3e-11e3-bd33-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft''s Nadella faces handset dilemma</headline><body><![CDATA[Tricky asset: Microsoft''s 5.44bn purchase of Nokia''s handset business was approved Friday. It raises questions of how the US group navigates the all-important mobile computing marketBloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Mishkin in San Francisco" date="April 25, 2014 12:23 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c65588b2-cbed-11e3-9f27-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Nadella sets out vision for Microsoft</headline><body><![CDATA[Satya Nadella, Microsoft''s new chief executive, set out on Thursday to make it clear that anyone who still thought of Microsoft as just a struggling PC company was mistaken.</p>
In his first call with investors since becoming the third chief executive in the company''s nearly four-decade history, Mr Nadella sounded upbeat and enthusiastic as he hammered home his vision for how he will help the world''s largest software maker move away from its roots making software for a now-declining PC market.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Daniel Thomas, Telecoms Correspondent" date="April 21, 2014 5:33 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a9715754-c967-11e3-89f8-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft fine-tunes 5.4bn Nokia deal</headline><body><![CDATA[AP]]> </body></entry><entry author="By James Fontanella-Khan in Brussels" date="April 10, 2014 1:47 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/aeeb7350-c0a1-11e3-a74d-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft cloud system wins EU privacy regulators'' approval</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="April 2, 2014 9:47 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/7eda77e4-ba7d-11e3-a905-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft to give away software for smartphones</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft is to give away its software for smartphones free of charge and reverse course a second time on its controversial Windows 8 PC operating system, in the latest attempt to shore up its eroding software platform against Apple and Google.</p>
The moves came as new chief executive Satya Nadella appeared at an event in San Francisco in front of 5,000 developers  a key group that he needs to win over. A shortage of apps for handsets running Windows software has been one of the main things holding the company back in the smartphone wars.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hannah Kuchler in San Francisco" date="March 28, 2014 8:22 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a7eae32c-b6b2-11e3-8695-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft to stop invading customers'' privacy</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft has promised to stop reading suspected pirates'' emails but instead report them to the police, changing its policy in response to consumer outrage after it was revealed that the company accessed a personal Hotmail account. </p>
Brad Smith, Microsoft''s general counsel, said that, effective immediately, the company would not inspect a customer''s private content, even though it had been legal to do so when someone was suspected of trafficking in stolen Microsoft intellectual property. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters" date=" March 27, 2014 7:12 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/9e09d082-b5d3-11e3-a1bd-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft opens door to a world beyond Windows</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tim Bradshaw in San Francisco" date="March 28, 2014 12:04 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/9da38e5a-b5d1-11e3-b40e-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft boss launches Office for iPad</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="March 21, 2014 2:29 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/8ff9df6a-b096-11e3-8efc-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft caught up in fresh privacy storm</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Blackden" date="March 18, 2014 5:16 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e269f722-aebf-11e3-aaa6-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft gains on mobile market hopes</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft found itself at the top of Wall Street''s leaderboard on Tuesday on hopes new chief executive Satya Nadella will make progress in driving its software deeper into the mobile market. </p>
Mr Nadella, who took over as Microsoft chief executive last month, will release a new version of its office software for Apple''s iPad at an event in San Francisco next week, according to reports.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tim Bradshaw in San Francisco" date="March 7, 2014 2:30 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/8ae1e070-a5c1-11e3-b9ed-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft brings out giant robots in battle for console dominance</headline><body><![CDATA[Electronic Arts<p>Microsoft hopes Titanfall will help its XBox One catch up to Sony''s PlayStation 4</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="March 3, 2014 6:52 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/28feb5f4-a300-11e3-ba21-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Penn gives up ad role in Microsoft shake-up</headline><body><![CDATA[Mark Penn, a former adviser to Bill Clinton, former US president, who had led Microsoft''s aggressive marketing campaign against arch-rival Google, is to give up his responsibilities for advertising in the first overhaul of the software maker''s senior ranks by new chief executive Satya Nadella.</p>
The shake-up will also see the departure of two of the company''s top executives, Tony Bates and Tami Reller, as well as the latest in a series of reshuffles intended to bring a sharper edge to Microsoft''s marketing and advertising.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Daniel Thomas in Barcelona" date="February 25, 2014 5:33 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/840be59a-9e26-11e3-95fe-00144feab7de.html"><headline>France''s Orange in talks to sell Dailymotion stake to Microsoft</headline><body><![CDATA[<p>Stphane Richard, Orange chairman and chief executive</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Paul Taylor in Barcelona" date="February 23, 2014 11:26 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/5d41c362-9caa-11e3-9360-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft signs up new handset makers for Windows Phone</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft, which is acquiring Nokia''s smartphone business, underscored its determination to continue to support other handset makers with new Windows Phone licensing agreements.</p>
The US company signed new Windows Phone 8 licensees including China''s Foxconn, Lenovo and ZTE and Korea''s LG.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters" date=" February 7, 2014 7:10 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/37005c46-8e9e-11e3-98c6-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Satya Nadella, Microsoft''s engineer chief</headline><body /></entry><entry author="By Stephen Foley in New York and Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="February 6, 2014 8:09 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/699f9f74-8f46-11e3-9cb0-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Shareholder unease over Microsoft reshuffle</headline><body><![CDATA[Amanda Friedman<p>Bill Gates has championed funding for ''neglected tropical diseases''</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters" date=" February 5, 2014 12:07 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/081e18f6-8e07-11e3-bbe7-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Satya Nadella must force Microsoft into the post-PC world</headline><body><![CDATA[EPA]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="February 4, 2014 7:10 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/8ac6b7ac-8db9-11e3-bbe7-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft chief goes back to the future</headline><body><![CDATA[During its long years at the top of the top of the technology world, Microsoft''s veteran product developers and engineers shared a common ambition: to present their plans at formal product meetings presided over by Bill Gates.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By John Aglionby" date="February 4, 2014 3:42 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/ce464cf6-8dad-11e3-ba55-00144feab7de.html"><headline>New Microsoft chairman John Thompson is all about the cloud</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Emily Cadman" date="February 4, 2014 3:00 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/1b990f1a-8daa-11e3-bbe7-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Satya Nadella''s wisdom  letter to staff from new Microsoft chief</headline><body><![CDATA[New Microsoft chief executive Satya Nadella, previously in charge of the company''s cloud computing division, introduced himself to the company at large in a 1,046-word email to all staff.</p>
Here are the key quotes from the world according to Mr Nadella:</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By FastFT" date="February 4, 2014 2:35 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/fa2b416e-8da8-11e3-bbe7-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Where Microsoft makes its money</headline><body><![CDATA[As Microsoft appoints the third chief executive in its history, here''s a brief look at where the world''s largest software maker generates its money.</p>
Despite Steve Ballmer''s noisy push into consumer technology, selling to businesses remains the lucrative bread and butter for Microsoft.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="February 4, 2014 7:58 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/96140582-8da6-11e3-bbe7-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft banks on the cloud under Nadella</headline><body><![CDATA[Jan 2000: Steve Ballmer becomes chief executive after co-founder Bill Gates steps down to become chief software architect. Mr Ballmer said: We will...focus on the next generation opportunity''AFP]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andy Sharman" date="January 31, 2014 9:22 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/1323bcc8-8a48-11e3-ba54-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Softly-spoken techie from Hyderabad rises to top tier at Microsoft</headline><body><![CDATA[After a high-profile search for the successor to a man who screamed I love this company, a softly-spoken insider has emerged as frontrunner to take the top job at Microsoft.</p>
Satya Nadella is seen as the likely successor to Steve Ballmer, though the board is not thought to have made a formal selection. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="January 31, 2014 12:05 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/1045ec40-8a04-11e3-8829-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft cloud chief Satya Nadella tipped for top role</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>Satya Nadella: likely successor to Steve Ballmer</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hannah Kuchler and Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="January 24, 2014 12:30 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/470f5bda-8473-11e3-9710-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Xbox and cloud demand boost Microsoft</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>Microsoft Surface Pro 2 tablet computer</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By James Fontanella-Khan in Brussels and Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="January 22, 2014 10:26 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e14ddf70-8390-11e3-aa65-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft to shield foreign users'' data</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Robert Wright in New York" date="January 8, 2014 1:56 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e0eafc6e-77f8-11e3-afc5-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Alan Mulally scotches Microsoft talk to stay at Ford</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters" date=" December 18, 2013 5:46 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c1e6693a-6802-11e3-8ada-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Investors should be careful what they wish for in Microsoft chief</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters<p>Steve Ballmer, chief executive of Microsoft</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By James Crabtree in Mumbai" date="December 4, 2013 8:52 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f63ce44e-5cb7-11e3-a558-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Nokia $321m India tax row looms over sale to Microsoft</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Robert Cookson and John Aglionby" date="November 18, 2013 11:50 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/2c37bd70-5020-11e3-9f0d-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft and Google tighten block on child abuse images</headline><body><![CDATA[PA]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lisa Pollack" date="November 4, 2013 4:09 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0131b426-42df-11e3-8350-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>The siren call of Microsoft Excel</headline><body><![CDATA[Reality is a crutch for people who can''t handle drugs, proclaimed a sticker I once purchased in a suburban shopping centre. It fitted in perfectly with my collection of risqu buttons and key chains. As a teenager I had discovered accessorising was the easiest way to at least give the appearance of defying authority.</p>
Fast forward through university, and my entry into the financial industry  where I worked before becoming a journalist  presented a wholly different set of norms to which to conform. Money, rather predictably, was at the centre of many. But a less obvious one had to do with Microsoft''s Excel spreadsheet software. It seemed to be the right tool for every job, every time, according to almost everyone. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Stephen Foley in New York and Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="October 31, 2013 6:40 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/32a96336-4254-11e3-8350-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft urged to spin consumer business</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft''s next chief executive should consider spinning off consumer businesses including search advertising and the Xbox games console, according to the private investment vehicle of Microsoft co-founder Paul Allen.</p>
Mr Allen, who started the company with Bill Gates in 1975 and still holds a $2bn stake, is intrigued and interested by forthcoming changes, said Paul Ghaffari, who manages the tech investor''s $15bn fortune.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Paul Taylor" date="Last updated: October 31, 2013 3:56 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/ae7ef03e-40bf-11e3-8775-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft resurfaces with tablet updates</headline><body /></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="October 24, 2013 10:09 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a832cf5c-3ce6-11e3-86ef-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Business software helps Microsoft weather PC downturn</headline><body /></entry><entry author="By Tim Bradshaw in San Francisco" date="October 23, 2013 5:59 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e8860766-3b8a-11e3-87fa-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Apple shuts Microsoft''s window of opportunity for Office on iPad</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters" date=" October 16, 2013 7:42 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e3e0da3a-367e-11e3-aaf1-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft and Apple face different challenges to adapt</headline><body><![CDATA[You can always count on Apple to spoil a Microsoft party.</p>
So it is with next Tuesday''s expected unveiling of the latest iPad models  the same day that Microsoft had already earmarked for the launch of its new Surface tablets. It also comes hot on the heels of this Thursday''s release of the upgraded Windows 8.1, as Microsoft makes up for the missteps of last year''s launch of its first touchscreen operating system.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco and Stephen Foley in New York" date="October 3, 2013 12:07 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/74b60e22-2ba8-11e3-a1b7-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft investors wary of Gates'' role in chief executive search</headline><body><![CDATA[Some of Microsoft''s biggest shareholders have expressed concern about the effect that Bill Gates'' outsized influence at the company will have on the search for a replacement to chief executive Steve Ballmer.
</p>
The company needs to take particular care that Mr Gates'' unique role does not deter candidates nor leave questions about who will have the final say over Mr Ballmer''s replacement, said people familiar with the thinking of a number of investors.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Daniel Thomas, Telecoms Correspondent" date="October 2, 2013 7:00 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/4b49dba2-2b73-11e3-bfe2-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Google and Microsoft back UK trial to use white space'' bandwidth</headline><body><![CDATA[Google and Microsoft are backing national trials of mobile services across fallow parts of the broadcast spectrum that could help avert a looming shortage of mobile frequencies.</p>
So-called white space technology allows mobile broadband to be carried over unused, and unlicensed, broadcast frequencies, which could be used by smartphones and tablets as well as a range of business applications.</p>
<h3>Spectrum of opportunity</h3>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Milne in Salo" date="September 25, 2013 8:01 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/feb7ef76-2510-11e3-bcf7-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Hope emerges for Nokia''s future following purchase by Microsoft</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="September 23, 2013 9:18 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/8a0e072c-2462-11e3-a8f7-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft resurfaces with revamped models in tablet wars</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>Microsoft Surface Pro 2 tablet computer</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="September 20, 2013 2:21 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0492a068-2164-11e3-a92a-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft bets on rapid online growth</headline><body><![CDATA[AFP/Getty Images<p>Steve Ballmer</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Milne in Oslo and Daniel Thomas in London" date="September 19, 2013 4:27 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a50a96e6-2131-11e3-8aff-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Nokia''s Stephen Elop given 18.8m to return to Microsoft</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="September 17, 2013 6:58 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/48897be0-1fb9-11e3-aa36-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft''s Office refusal risks opening door to rivals</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft''s refusal to release its Office software for rival tablet computers risks eroding its most profitable product and has inspired a new generation of start-ups that are racing to fill the gap, according to tech executives and analysts.</p>
Microsoft has restricted users of the iPad and tablets running Google''s Android software to an online version of Office that only works when the machines are connected to the internet. The strategy of holding back the full software for Windows tablets has failed to ignite sales, however, forcing the company to take a $900m writedown on its Surface tablet in July.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="September 5, 2013 2:27 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/46d36fce-15c6-11e3-950a-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft wins landmark patent ruling</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft has won the second stage of a landmark patent case against Google''s Motorola unit, as a jury in Seattle concluded that the mobile handset maker had breached some its commitments to technology standards bodies.</p>
The verdict follows a decision that also went in the software company''s favour in the first part of the case, concluded in April. The earlier ruling, which dealt with how royalties payments should be calculated for patents that are included in technology standards, was seen as of far broader significance for the patent disputes that have rocked the smartphone industry.</p>
]]> </body></entry></news>