
<news><entry author="By Ed Crooks" date="October 29, 2010 4:17 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/df0b3eaa-e362-11df-97db-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron reports decline in profits</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron, the second-largest US oil group, has disappointed analysts'' expectations with a fall in earnings for the third quarter. </p>
Post-tax earnings were $3.77bn, down 2 per cent from $3.83bn in the equivalent period of 2009. Earnings per share were $1.87, down 3 per cent, compared to analysts'' average expectation of a 12 per cent rise to $2.15, according to forecasts compiled by Thomson Reuters.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="October 21, 2010 7:13 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/efa651a0-dd3b-11df-9236-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron to develop in Gulf of Mexico</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron, the second-largest US oil group, has given the green light to the $7.5bn development of two large fields in the Gulf of Mexico.</p>
The decision to proceed with the project, announced on Thursday, represents the largest investment in the Gulf of Mexico since the BP oil rig disaster in April and is the strongest signal yet that the region''s reserves will continue to be produced in spite of the spill.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sylvia Pfeifer" date="October 1, 2010 11:30 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0c48a5be-cd8e-11df-9c82-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Chevron cleared for oil well off UK</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron, the US oil major, is preparing to drill the first deep water exploration well in UK waters since BP''s spill in the Gulf of Mexico after receiving the government''s approval.</p>
Environmentalists have raised concerns at the risks after the BP accident on April 20, which killed 11 workers and led to the worst environmental disaster in US waters. While Washington has imposed a moratorium on deepwater drilling, Britain has refused to follow suit, arguing its safety regime is robust. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="July 30, 2010 7:11 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/7472d44e-9be2-11df-9ebd-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Moratorium on drilling to hit Chevron output</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron said on Friday that the moratorium on deep-water drilling in the Gulf of Mexico following the leak from the Deepwater Horizon well had significantly affected its exploration programme and would lead to lost production this year.</p>
The second biggest US oil company had planned to drill exploration wells and ramp up production from the Perdido project in the Gulf of Mexico before year-end, said George Kirkland, Chevron''s vice-chairman, as he delivered strong second-quarter results.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Telis Demos in New York" date="April 30, 2010 10:15 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/35fd31fc-545a-11df-b75d-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Chevron profits rise 150% in quarter</headline><body><![CDATA[An upswing in crude oil prices, combined with rising production, resulted in Chevron, the US''s second-biggest petroleum producer, reporting a nearly $3bn increase in net income for the first quarter, its most profitable since 2008.</p>
Though Chevron is a major extractor of oil and gas in the US Gulf of Mexico, with a new deepwater rig coming online in March, and also newly commissioning a Gulf exploration vessel, it said its operations would be unaffected by BP''s spill.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="April 26, 2010 3:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/39cd6f46-50cb-11df-bc86-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Chevron chief eschews rush for shale gas</headline><body><![CDATA[John Watson, chief executive of Chevron, is refusing to join rival international oil majors in the rush for US shale gas, warning that the "price tag is too high" to justify the investment required.</p>
Mr Watson, who has only been in the top job at the US''s second-biggest oil company for three months, is confident that his decision not to follow the pack into US shale gas is the right one to make.</p>
"We haven''t seen the returns," he told the Financial Times.</p>
The Chevron chief''s comments come against a backdrop of US gas producers struggling against low oil prices as a result of an</p>
oversupply.</p>
Many in the industry believe that governments worldwide, under pressure to lower their dependence on carbon fuels, will increasingly turn to natural gas until the technology is available to enable renewables to meet a substantial portion of the demand for electricity.</p>
Shale gas is about 30 per cent less carbon intensive than oil and 50 per cent less so than coal.</p>
Its supporters argue that new drilling technology has strengthened the economic case for tapping the gas, giving it a key role to play in bolstering the US''s energy security.</p>
The new techniques have led to increased projections of reserves of shale gas from 30 years'' worth of supplies, at current usage rates, to 100 years.</p>
In December, Exxon-Mobil, the US''s biggest oil company, agreed to buy XTO Energy for its strong position in shale gas, for $31bn in stock and $10bn in XTO debt.</p>
That deal has followed a string of others in the past two years, which have seen BP and BG Group of the UK, StatoilHydro, the Norwegian energy company, Eni, the Italian oil company, and other smaller companies, buying into US shale gas fields.</p>
Mr Watson has also taken a contrarian position on Iraq, where other oil majors have rushed to bid for the right to develop the country''s oilfields.</p>
He said that he was "hopeful" Chevron would have a role to play in developing fields in Iraq. But in spite of Iraq''s "vast oilfields" and the time that Chevron spent training in the country, he said that the risks and the way the fiscal system was structured meant that Iraq could not compete with other opportunities Chevron currently had.</p>
So, instead of putting in a low bid, knowing that it would inevitably fail, Chevron opted out.</p>
"We just didn''t see value," Mr Watson said. "It has to pass the hurdle."</p>
The chief executive is, however, considering the value of jumping the hurdles to oil and gas production in Russia.</p>
At a time when Conoco-Phillips is selling half of its stake in Lukoil, Russia''s largest independent oil company, Mr Watson said: "What we''re hearing out of Moscow is encouraging."</p>
See Business Life</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="April 25, 2010 6:24 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/272d6046-5088-11df-bc86-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Chevron chief shuns shale gas rush</headline><body><![CDATA[John Watson, chief executive of Chevron, is refusing to join rival international oil majors in the rush for US shale gas, warning that the price tag is too high to justify the investments required.</p>
Mr Watson, who has only been in the top job at the US''s second-biggest oil company for three months, is confident his decision not to follow the pack into US shale gas is the right one. We haven''t seen the returns, he told the Financial Times.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston and Naomi Mapstone in Lima" date="March 31, 2010 1:42 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/9b8f4528-3c4f-11df-b316-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron wins $700m oil claim against Ecuador</headline><body><![CDATA[An international arbitration tribunal in the Hague on Tuesday awarded Chevron, the US oil company, $700m in a claim against Ecuador stemming from allegations that the country failed to pay for millions of barrels of oil in the 1990s.</p>
The commercial arbitration is separate from the arbitration Chevron has sought to resolve a $27bn claim by indigenous people who charge that Texaco left an environmental disaster in its wake when it withdrew from the country. Chevron bought Texaco in 2001.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty" date="March 10, 2010 2:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/49910dda-2be5-11df-8033-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron to shed 2,000 more jobs</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron, the second- largest US oil company, said yesterday it would cut a further 2,000 positions in its refining and marketing division. It is in the process of reducing its global downstream workforce by 3,900 employees or about 20 per cent over two years.</p>
The cutbacks come as the company sells refining assets in Europe, the Caribbean and parts of Central America to reduce exposure to the poorly performing business.</p>
Chevron will also review operations in Hawaii and Africa. It expects severance pay-outs of $150m to $200m, on an after-tax basis, in this first quarter.</p>
The company will keep refining operations in North America and Asia-Pacific, its best- performing markets.</p>
The refining losses underline the pressure the sector is under from weak demand and a move towards more energy-efficient renewables.</p>
Sheila McNulty, Houston</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="March 9, 2010 7:00 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/5031b956-2b85-11df-9d96-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron to cut 2,000 jobs</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron, the US'' second biggest oil company, said on Tuesday it will cut a further 2,000 positions in its refining and marketing division as it reduces its global downstream workforce by 3,900 employees or about 20 per cent over two years. </p>
The cutbacks, which follow 1,900 announced last year, will come as the company sells refining assets in Europe, including its Pembroke refinery; the Caribbean; and parts of Central America to reduce exposure to this poorly performing segment. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty" date="January 30, 2010 2:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/2ef01680-0d3e-11df-af79-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron reports net income fall</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron yesterday reported a 37 per cent drop in net income to $3.1bn in the fourth quarter of 2009, underlining the drag of its refining division even as the US''s second-biggest oil company ramped up production.</p>
Its US refining and marketing operations lost $345m in the fourth quarter of 2009, compared with earnings of $1.03bn in the year-earlier quarter.</p>
Chevron''s international refining and marketing operations also incurred losses, of $268m in the fourth quarter, compared with earnings of $1.05bn in the same quarter a year earlier.</p>
John Watson, Chevron''s new chief executive, has pledged to restructure the division, with lay-offs planned.</p>
Overall, for 2009, Chevron''s earnings fell 56 per cent to $10.5bn. Its revenue of $167bn was down from $265bn in 2008.</p>
"Earnings decreased in 2009 as a result of lower crude oil and natural gas prices and a decline in refined product sales margins, driven by a weak global economy,'''' Mr Watson said.</p>
Sheila McNulty, Houston</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York and Jack Farchy in Moscow" date="September 30, 2014 12:54 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/586ae5c0-487c-11e4-ad19-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Exxon considers its course after sanctions hit Russian ambitions</headline><body><![CDATA[AFP<p>ExxonMobil''s Rex Tillerson and Russia''s Vladimir Putin at a partnership event in 2011</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York" date="September 19, 2014 7:08 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/8910fe7c-401f-11e4-936b-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon winds down Russian Arctic drilling campaign</headline><body><![CDATA[<p>Cold world: sanctions against Russia have raised questions on the future of expensive projects in the Kara Sea north of Siberia</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York" date="March 31, 2014 10:44 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/67f73d56-b90a-11e3-a189-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon warns global warming targets unlikely'' to be met</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil, the US oil group, said it was highly unlikely that the world would cut greenhouse gas emissions sufficiently to keep global warming within the internationally agreed limit of 2C.</p>
In two reports on the implications of climate change for its business published on Monday, Exxon rejected suggestions that policies to cut emissions would leave many of its oil and gas assets stranded  incapable of being profitably developed.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks" date="March 24, 2014 8:23 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/5ff0a564-b36c-11e3-bc21-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>BullishChevrontooutspendExxon</headline><body><![CDATA[Beacon of light: although Chevron ranks second to Exxon in the US in terms of market capitalisation, the oil major is planning to outspend its larger rival in a bet on the continuing high oil priceReuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jeremy Grant in Singapore" date="January 8, 2014 9:58 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e1f5ffda-7827-11e3-831c-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon inaugurates petrochemical processing facility in Singapore</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil, the US energy group, is moving to capitalise on growing demand in Asia by inaugurating the world''s first facility that processes crude oil directly into petrochemical products at a facility in Singapore.</p>
The facility, part of a plant that accounts for a quarter of Exxon''s global chemical output, is the largest single manufacturing investment in the Asian city-state.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York" date="December 12, 2013 4:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b68909ac-62ae-11e3-99d1-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon forecasts natural gas to be world''s second most-used fuel</headline><body><![CDATA[Natural gas will overtake coal as a global energy source in the middle of the next decade, in part because of the environmental benefits it offers, according to ExxonMobil, the world''s largest listed oil and gas company.</p>
In its annual forecasts of the energy outlook for the next three decades, published on Thursday morning, Exxon says that around 2025 gas will become the world''s second most-used fuel on an energy-equivalent basis, behind oil.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Guy Chazan" date="November 28, 2013 5:06 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/19c128a2-5818-11e3-a2ed-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>PetroChina buys Iraq oilfield stake from Exxon</headline><body><![CDATA[PetroChina, the country''s largest oil and gas producer, has agreed to buy a 25 per cent stake in Iraq''s West Qurna 1 oilfield from ExxonMobil of the US, in a deal that cements the dominant presence of Chinese energy groups in Iraq''s oil sector.</p>
Exxon will also sell a 10 per cent stake to Indonesia''s Pertamina, bringing its total interest in West Qurna 1 down from 60 per cent to 25 per cent  though it will remain operator of the field. Royal Dutch Shell''s stake remains unchanged at 15 per cent with Iraqi state entities owning the rest.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York" date="October 31, 2013 1:52 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/3371de4e-422f-11e3-bb85-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon earnings slide on refining weakness</headline><body><![CDATA[AFP]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks" date="October 31, 2013 1:10 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/93262b88-4207-11e3-bb85-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon struggles to find growth in fast-changing landscape</headline><body><![CDATA[AP]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jason Abbruzzese in New York" date="August 1, 2013 10:13 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/98c69d10-faaf-11e2-a7aa-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon ticks down but S&amp;P 500 hits record</headline><body><![CDATA[The SP 500 broke above the 1,700 level for the first time as disappointing earnings from ExxonMobil were outshined by positive economic data from the US and China.</p>
The shares of ExxonMobil, the world''s biggest oil company, fell 1.1 per cent to $92.73 after the company announced earnings that came in below expectations.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Guy Chazan" date="April 2, 2013 8:55 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/2c8b4ed6-9b9e-11e2-8485-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon floats offshore LNG plan</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil has submitted plans for a liquefied natural gas project off the north-western coast of Australia that would enter the record books as the largest offshore floating facility ever built.</p>
It is the second supermajor after Royal Dutch Shell to move ahead with plans to produce LNG at sea. Exxon lodged documents with Australia''s federal environment department on Tuesday detailing its plans to develop the Scarborough gasfield using floating LNG, or FLNG, technology. But Exxon said it and its partner BHP Billiton would not make a final investment decision on the project until 2014 at the earliest.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York" date="February 2, 2013 12:14 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e7257aa4-6c79-11e2-b774-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Exxon and Chevron toil in hunt for growth</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil and Chevron, the two largest US oil groups by market capitalisation, both reported falling oil and gas production for 2012, in a sign of the difficulties faced by large international energy groups in finding growth.</p>
US domestic oil output boomed last year but the principal beneficiaries were smaller independent companies that were the fastest into the new shale reserves.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Neil Hume in Sydney" date="November 12, 2012 8:46 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f19e52e4-2c9b-11e2-a95d-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon warns of cost blowout at PNG LNG</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil, the world''s biggest oil company by market value, has warned of a $3.3bn cost blowout at its liquefied natural gas project in Papua New Guinea but says it is still on course to start deliveries to customers in China, Taiwan and Japan in 2014.</p>
Foreign exchange fluctuations accounted for about half of the jump in costs to $19bn, Exxon said on Monday, while delays due to work stoppages and land access issues, which contributed to increased drilling and construction costs, added a further $1.2bn. The company blamed adverse weather conditions, including rainfall exceeding historic norms for the past two years, for another $700m of costs. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Guy Chazan" date="November 7, 2012 7:44 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/aba9f240-2906-11e2-86d7-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon looks to quit Iraq oilfield</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil is seeking to sell its stake in a multibillion-dollar oil project in Iraq, underscoring the growing tensions between Iraq''s central government and the autonomous region of Kurdistan.</p>
Exxon''s desire to pull out of the West Qurna-1 oilfield, confirmed by Iraqi officials, reflects the oil majors'' growing disenchantment with southern Iraq and their contrasting enthusiasm for Kurdistan, which has signed a flurry of landmark deals with western energy giants such as Exxon, Chevron and Total. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Hill in New York" date=" November 2, 2012 2:05 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e42b0090-243e-11e2-94d0-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon study wins FT book award</headline><body><![CDATA[
Steve Coll''s Private Empire: ExxonMobil and American Power has won the Financial Times and Goldman Sachs Business Book of the Year Award.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York" date="November 1, 2012 2:48 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/5af956cc-2430-11e2-9509-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Refining business bolsters Exxon profits</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil has reported a sharp fall in oil and gas production but stronger than expected earnings thanks to a strong performance from its refineries.</p>
The third-quarter results showed the impact of the turbulence in the US energy industry created by the boom in shale oil and gas, made possible by advances in production techniques that have unlocked previously uncommercial resources.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York" date="October 17, 2012 7:15 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/825abce6-186f-11e2-80af-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon seals C$3bn deal for Celtic</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil, the largest US oil group by market capitalisation, is spending C$3.1bn (US$3.2bn) to acquire oil and gas assets in western Canada, in a deal that illustrates the opportunities available to well-resourced acquirers as a result of the decline in North American natural gas prices.</p>
Exxon has agreed a takeover of Celtic Exploration, an Alberta-based oil and gas independent, for C$24.50 plus a half a share in a new company holding assets that Exxon does not want, for each Celtic share.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York and Adam Thomson in Mexico City" date="June 27, 2012 8:13 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/9a0794d4-c06f-11e1-982d-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Mexico reform crucial to Exxon investment</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil, the world''s largest oil group by market capitalisation, is interested in investing in Mexico if reforms of the industry make contract terms more attractive, the company''s chief executive has said.</p>
Rex Tillerson, Exxon''s chief executive, said at a meeting of the Council on Foreign Relations in New York: We''re hopeful that Mexico, as it continues its pathway to reforms...will open up opportunities for greater partnerships and collaborations, and bringing technology to bear on the huge resources that Mexico has.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York" date="June 27, 2012 6:13 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/1ff711c8-c066-11e1-982d-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Global warming manageable'', says Exxon chief</headline><body><![CDATA[Global warming is a manageable problem, but will require policy changes to adapt to its effects, the chief executive of ExxonMobil, the largest US oil and gas producer, has said.</p>
Rex Tillerson said at a meeting at the Council on Foreign Relations in New York that climate change was a great challenge, but it could be solved by adapting to risks such as higher sea levels and changing conditions for agriculture.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks" date="April 26, 2012 1:52 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/4e918a68-8f29-11e1-ab32-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Exxon and Chevron raise dividends</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil and Chevron, the two largest US oil companies by market capitalisation, have sharply increased their dividends in a sign of confidence in future earnings. Exxon raised its quarterly dividend by 21 per cent, and Chevron by 11 per cent.</p>
Exxon, which reports first-quarter earnings on Thursday, declared a dividend of 57 cents a share for the second quarter, up from 47 cents in the first quarter.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Catherine Belton in Moscow" date="April 18, 2012 7:40 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/8b0c869e-8977-11e1-85af-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Exxon and Rosneft seal Arctic deal</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil and Rosneft, the Russian state oil champion, unveiled a historic partnership on Wednesday that could invest more than $500bn over several decades in the development of vast offshore reserves in Russia''s Arctic and Black Seas.</p>
The deal will grant Exxon first mover access with Rosneft to develop three vast untapped fields in the Russian Arctic Kara Sea, with hydrocarbon reserves estimated at 85bn barrels of oil equivalent.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Catherine Belton in Moscow and Ed Crooks in New York" date="April 18, 2012 10:50 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/9cc00408-8583-11e1-a394-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Rosneft and Exxon ready to seal deal</headline><body><![CDATA[Rosneft is expected to finalise a groundbreaking joint venture with ExxonMobil on Monday that will grant the US oil major access to vast Russian Arctic reserves in exchange for the Russian state oil champion winning entry to resources in North America.</p>
Igor Sechin, Russia''s energy tsar, will present details of the new venture to analysts at a meeting in New York on Wednesday together with Rex Tillerson, ExxonMobil''s president, and Eduard Khudainatov, Rosneft''s chief executive, Exxon said.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York" date="March 8, 2012 6:56 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f44cafb4-693b-11e1-956a-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon holds back output for long-term gains</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil will not rush to increase production from its US oil and gas reserves because it wants to maximise the long-term value of its resources, the company''s chief executive has said.</p>
The world''s largest private sector oil company by production could afford to be deliberate about the way it developed its large holdings of onshore oil and gas, said Rex Tillerson, because it did not face the same pressure for quick cash flow as many of its smaller competitors.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Telis Demos in New York" date="January 30, 2012 3:19 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/94ce2f44-4aba-11e1-8110-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon sells Japanese marketing unit for $3.9bn</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil has restructured its Japanese operations, selling a petroleum products marketing group in response to declining demand in the country.</p>
In the deal announced yesterday, Exxon will sell 99 per cent of its stake in ExxonMobil Yugen Kaisha, its downstream product marketing subsidiary, to TonenGeneral Sekiyu, a refinery operator in which it has a controlling stake, for Y302bn ($3.9bn).</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sylvia Pfeifer" date="December 7, 2011 3:30 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/1a0e76ce-1a6d-11e1-ae14-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Big oil: Exxon move shocks the sector</headline><body><![CDATA[As a sales pitch it takes some beating. Hussain al-Sharistani, Iraq''s deputy prime minister for energy, told an audience in London last month that his nation has 143bn barrels of proven oil reserves  about 10 per cent of the world''s total. The country boasts further probable and possible reserves of about 200bn, he said.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Javier Blas" date="November 23, 2011 10:03 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/363367e0-15b5-11e1-8db8-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon''s Kurd deal contradicts conventional wisdom</headline><body><![CDATA[Conventional wisdom says that the interests of US Big Oil'' and Washington go hand-in-hand. Thus, many see ExxonMobil, the largest US oil company, as an extension of the US State Department. The recent events in Iraq appear to discredit that theory.</p>
Exxon last month signed a landmark deal with the semi-autonomous region of Kurdistan in northern Iraq to explore for oil. The deal triggered an immediate protest from the federal government in Baghdad, which runs a de facto ban on oil companies operating both in the oil-rich south of Iraq and, at the same time, investing in projects under the Kurdistan Regional Government. Baghdad had already warned Exxon it risked losing a contract to develop the large West Qurna field in the south of the country.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sylvia Pfeifer in London" date="November 22, 2011 9:14 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/83b3a3ea-151f-11e1-b9b8-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon''s Kurd contracts questioned</headline><body><![CDATA[Iraq stepped up the pressure on ExxonMobil over the US company''s surprise decision to sign exploration contracts with the country''s semi-autonomous region of Kurdistan, with the government''s highest energy official declaring they are in breach of the law. </p>
Hussain al-Sharistani, Iraq''s deputy prime minister responsible for energy, revealed that Exxon had written to the government about its recent decision. The prime minister''s office and the ministry of oil had written back, spelling out that contracts will not be recognised unless they are approved by the Iraqi government.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sylvia Pfeifer, Energy Editor" date="November 10, 2011 9:30 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/4e44f860-0bda-11e1-9861-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon signs Kurd exploration contracts</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil has become the first of the supermajor oil companies to venture into Kurdistan, in a controversial move that will be seen as a huge vote of confidence in the semi-autonomous region of Iraq but could spark a backlash in Baghdad. </p>
Exxon, the largest international oil company, signed contracts with the Kurdistan Regional Government (KRG) last month to explore for oil and gas in six blocks in the region, according to an adviser to the KRG. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="October 27, 2011 4:44 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/474408e0-0099-11e1-930b-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon boosted by commodity prices</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil, the world''s biggest international oil company by market capitalisation, suffered a drop in production in the third quarter but high commodity prices helped it report a 41 per cent rise in earnings.</p>
Exxon said field declines, divestments and Opec quotas led to a 4 per cent drop in oil-equivalent production, which followed a trend established by BP and ConocoPhillips, who reported production hits earlier in the week.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Benedict Mander in Caracas" date="September 22, 2011 5:35 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/7bcc5e16-e530-11e0-bdb8-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Venezuela ready to pay Exxon only $1bn</headline><body><![CDATA[Venezuela will pay ExxonMobil $1bn in compensation for assets nationalised in 2007, far less than the $6bn the world''s biggest oil company by market capitalisation is seeking through international arbitration, according to government officials.</p>
Rafael Ramrez, energy minister, also cast doubt on whether Venezuela would respect rulings issued by international courts, with decisions expected this year in New York''s International Chamber of Commerce and the World Bank''s International Centre for Settlement of Investment Disputes.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sylvia Pfeifer" date="September 21, 2011 5:34 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c0a2ee96-e45f-11e0-844d-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Apache buys Exxon North Sea fields for $1.75bn</headline><body><![CDATA[Apache Corporation, the US independent, has sounded a vote of confidence in the future of the North Sea in the UK, by agreeing to buy several assets from ExxonMobil for $1.75bn in a deal that will substantially increase its presence in the region. </p>
The deal, which includes the Beryl field, will significantly boost Apache''s production in the North Sea, increasing it 54 per cent and its reserves by about 44 per cent. It comes just six months after the UK government announced a surprise tax increase on North Sea production, sparking warnings from the industry that it would deter investment into the region. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York" date="September 2, 2011 6:22 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/d7cbe24a-d57c-11e0-9133-00144feab49a.html"><headline>An embodiment of Exxon''s no-nonsense culture</headline><body><![CDATA[In leadership roles at the world''s largest oil and gas companies, the traditional oilman is a dying breed. Chevron and Royal Dutch Shell are run by finance experts, and BP by a softly-spoken engineer who has sounded positive about renewable energy.</p>
At ExxonMobil, however, Rex Tillerson, the chairman and chief executive, still fits the bill. A broad-shouldered, straight-talking, sometimes abrasive Texan, a 36-year Exxon veteran who became chief executive in 2006, he is a fully committed believer in the lasting central role of oil and gas in the world economy.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Isabel Gorst in Moscow" date="August 31, 2011 7:40 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f0f3e682-d3f1-11e0-b7eb-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Rosneft looks beyond Arctic in Exxon deal</headline><body><![CDATA[Rosneft will achieve its goal of becoming a global oil major by cementing its strategic alliance with ExxonMobil to explore in Russia and other countries, officials at Russia''s state oil company said on Wednesday. </p>
Under a deal struck this week, Exxon will bear a disproportionate burden of the initial $3.2bn investment in a joint venture with Rosneft to explore in the Russian Arctic and Black Sea.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sylvia Pfeifer and Kate Burgess in London" date="August 30, 2011 7:20 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/5ca8087a-d322-11e0-9ba8-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Exxon ends BP''s Arctic dream</headline><body><![CDATA[<p>Bob Dudley, BP chief executive</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks" date="August 30, 2011 6:26 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/ce88c376-d327-11e0-9ba8-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Exxon shows surer tread in following BP''s path</headline><body /></entry><entry author="By Isabel Gorst and Charles Clover in Moscow and Ed Crooks in New York" date="August 30, 2011 8:23 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/ffa9d962-d319-11e0-9aae-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Exxon and Rosneft sign Arctic deal</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil has formed an Arctic exploration partnership with Rosneft, the Russian state oil company, in a strategic coup over rival BP.</p>
In return, Exxon, the world''s largest oil company by market capitalisation, will give the state-controlled Russian group minority stakes in projects in the US Gulf of Mexico, in onshore fields in Texas and elsewhere.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sylvia Pfeifer in London" date="July 28, 2011 2:36 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/ffff9b24-b918-11e0-bd87-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon earnings lifted by higher energy prices</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil, the world''s biggest oil company by market capitalisation, reported its best second quarter since 2008 as higher energy prices boosted earnings to more than $10bn.</p>
Exxon said second-quarter earnings were up 41 per cent from the same period last year to $10.7bn, reflecting higher energy prices, as well as improved results in refining and marketing. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="July 8, 2011 11:47 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/3a02193a-a9b2-11e0-a04a-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon faces new battle on Indonesian lawsuit</headline><body><![CDATA[A US appeals court has reinstated a lawsuit against ExxonMobil that accuses the biggest US oil company of aiding and abetting alleged cases of murder, sexual assault and torture by guards employed at its natural gas operations in Indonesia. </p>
The US Court of Appeals said on Friday in a 2-1 ruling in Washington that a judge erred in dismissing the lawsuit in 2009 because corporations can be liable under the Alien Tort Statute (ATS), which allows US jurisdiction over acts outside the US. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="July 7, 2011 8:31 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/971b9bc8-a8c2-11e0-b877-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon oil spill triggers demands</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil is battling to contain an oil leak into the Yellowstone River that has prompted calls for urgent reviews of pipeline safety.</p>
The 12-inch pipe under the Yellowstone River ruptured a week ago, 20 miles upstream from Billings, Montana, spilling up to 1,000 barrels of oil before Exxon could shut it off.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="June 9, 2011 12:56 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a1e98970-921f-11e0-9e00-00144feab49a.html"><headline>New Gulf of Mexico energy finds for Exxon</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil, the world''s biggest international oil company, announced three discoveries  one among the biggest in the Gulf of Mexico in the past decade  after drilling its first deepwater exploration well since the Macondo disaster. </p>
The announcement on Wednesday followed one by BHP Billiton Petroleum, which noted on Tuesday it had brought online the first newly drilled well in the deepwater gulf since the moratorium was imposed after the April 20, 2010 incident before being lifted in October. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David Blair and Sylvia Pfeifer" date="April 20, 2011 9:13 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/56a84578-6b82-11e0-a53e-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Exxon sees nuclear power holding its own</headline><body><![CDATA[Nuclear power''s share of the global energy mix will be unchanged in 30 years'' time in spite of the disaster in Japan, according to the chief executive of ExxonMobil.</p>
Rex Tillerson, who has led the world''s biggest publicly quoted company since 2006, said nuclear power''s importance was so great that policymakers would not allow any decline. As a supplier of fossil fuels, Exxon would stand to benefit if governments chose to reduce nuclear power''s contribution to future energy supplies.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Javier Blas" date="April 20, 2011 8:34 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/1d57d55e-6b14-11e0-9be1-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Exxon chief on supply, demand and $120 crude</headline><body><![CDATA[In the oil industry, few executives have a better vantage point on demand, supply and prices than Rex Tillerson, chief executive of ExxonMobil. </p>
So when Mr Tillerson visited the Financial Times on Tuesday for a round-table with the energy and commodities team, we asked him to weigh into some of the oil market''s current debates: are high oil prices a sign of a shortage in supplies, and is demand starting to suffer due to rising retail fuel prices?</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By FT reporters" date="April 19, 2011 9:10 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a15fa17a-6abe-11e0-80a1-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Exxon chief says BP lost time</headline><body><![CDATA[BP lost valuable time at the height of its devastating accident in the Gulf of Mexico last year pursuing solutions to contain the oil spill that were never going to succeed, the chief executive of ExxonMobil has claimed.</p>
In a sharp criticism of the handling of the disaster, Rex Tillerson said Exxon''s engineers knew that one of BP''s initial efforts to stem the oil flowing from the ruptured Macondo well  by building a containment dome  wasn''t going to work.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York" date="March 9, 2011 8:36 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a3d637b2-4a88-11e0-82ab-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Exxon''s Tillerson rejects BP take on spill</headline><body><![CDATA[Rex Tillerson, chief executive of ExxonMobil, has attacked Bob Dudley, his counterpart at BP, over his assessment of the lessons from the Deepwater Horizon disaster last year.</p>
Speaking as Exxon made its annual presentation to analysts, Mr Tillerson accused Mr Dudley of doing a great disservice to the oil industry and its employees by suggesting that the disaster had implications for all of them.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in Dallas and Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="February 27, 2011 8:37 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/624aa9be-42a3-11e0-8b34-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon urges US to resume deepwater drilling</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil, the largest US oil company, backed by industry groups, has urged regulators to allow deepwater drilling to resume in the Gulf of Mexico, as the turmoil in north Africa raises the pressure on the US to develop its own sources of supply.</p>
The US authorities have been sending mixed messages about the resumption of drilling, which was suspended after the BP oil spill last year.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="February 16, 2011 2:27 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/099a2e66-3961-11e0-97ca-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon deal highlights oil reserves issue</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil''s acquisition of XTO Energy last year accounted for 80 per cent of the reserves it added in 2010, highlighting the difficulty oil companies are having in finding new sources of crude.</p>
The world''s largest private sector oil company by market capitalisation said its reserve base increased by 3.5bn to 24.8bn oil-equivalent barrels at the end of last year. XTO, a US independent focused on shale gas production, accounted for 2.8bn of the new reserves.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York" date="January 31, 2011 7:19 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/3742e4d8-2d46-11e0-9b0f-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Exxon bolstered by higher oil prices</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil, which has bet heavily on the US gas market through the $41bn purchase of XTO, depended on higher oil prices in the latest quarter as US natural gas prices continued to fall.</p>
The world''s largest private sector oil company by market capitalisation has a long-term forecast of robust growth in demand for gas, expecting it to provide an increasing share of power generation at the expense of coal.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael Stothard in New York" date="January 31, 2011 9:36 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c48c4ec4-2d4b-11e0-9b0f-00144feab49a.html"><headline>US stocks boosted by Exxon earnings</headline><body><![CDATA[Strong earnings results from ExxonMobil 
and better-than-expected consumer spending data lifted Wall Street, helping to pare some of the sharp losses seen late last week.</p>
The US markets were one of the few around the world unruffled by the continued turmoil in Egypt, bouncing back from the 1.8 per cent losses seen on Friday. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By James Fontanella-Khan in Mumbai" date="November 1, 2010 7:46 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/2ef6f3b4-e5de-11df-af15-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>ONGC eyes Angolan assets of Exxon and Total</headline><body><![CDATA[India''s largest oil group is considering acquiring ExxonMobil''s and Total''s oil assets in Angola, in the latest effort by the state-run group to secure overseas resources to help the country achieve its double-digit growth aspirations.</p>
R.S. Sharma, chairman of Oil and Natural Gas Corp, told the Financial Times on Monday that he had met members of the Angolan government in New Delhi to discuss a number of opportunities, including buying the assets of the US and French oil majors. However, the Indian executive stressed that talks were at a very early stage and he did not specify how much ONGC would invest.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sylvia Pfeifer in London and Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="October 29, 2010 1:01 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/ca58ad0e-e2bc-11df-8a58-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon and Shell profits surge</headline><body><![CDATA[Two of the world''s biggest oil companies reported sharply higher third-quarter results on Thursday, fuelled by stronger crude prices and better refining margins. </p>
ExxonMobil, the largest oil company in the US by market capitalisation, beat analyst expectations by posting a 55 per cent jump in third-quarter earnings to $7.4bn, compared with the same quarter in 2009. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="October 28, 2010 2:55 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/763c5856-e294-11df-9ea3-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Production and price hikes boost Exxon</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil, the world''s largest publicly traded oil company, beat expectations with a 20 per cent surge in third-quarter production due to the ramping up of assets in Qatar and its acquisition of XTO Energy, the shale gas producer.</p>
The rise in production, combined with higher oil and natural gas prices and improved refining margins, pushed up third-quarter earnings by 55 per cent to $7.4bn, Exxon said on Thursday.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Carola Hoyos in London" date="August 18, 2010 11:16 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/9a4f5f8e-aaf1-11df-9e6b-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon abandons bid for Ghana stake</headline><body><![CDATA[Following months of battle with Accra, ExxonMobil, the world''s biggest western oil company, has given up trying to acquire a share of Ghana''s giant Jubilee oil field from Kosmos, the American oil company.</p>
The $4bn deal was heavily opposed by Ghana''s government and its national oil company, which felt left out of the huge profit Kosmos stood to make.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="July 29, 2010 7:59 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/87e8d6fa-9b14-11df-ae58-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Exxon shrugs off effect of moratorium</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil said on Thursday that the moratorium on new deepwater drilling in the Gulf would have no significant short-term impact on its profits. Net profits rose 91 per cent year-on-year in the second quarter to $7.6bn.</p>
The US''s biggest oil company capitalised on improving energy prices by increasing production. Its oil-equivalent production increased by 8 per cent year-on-year, driven by its natural gas-focused Qatar operations. The oil major has been increasing natural gas in its global portfolio and closed its acquisition of XTO Energy in the quarter to become the the US''s biggest natural gas producer.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bryce Elder" date="June 30, 2010 3:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/9df112d4-83de-11df-ba07-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Talk grows of Exxon bid for BP</headline><body><![CDATA[BP provided one of the few distractions for traders yesterday as global slowdown worries sent the FTSE 100 to its sharpest fall since November.</p>
BP was a talking point after JPMorgan Cazenove speculated about the chances of ExxonMobil launching a bid for its besieged rival.</p>
"We believe the economics of such a potential combination are compelling, and we question why the market is not factoring in the possibility of it ever happening," said analyst Fred Lucas.</p>
"The market has lost sight of the intrinsic value that is resident in an assetrich company like BP. We very much doubt that keen-eyed industry players have lost sight of BP''s value."</p>
Mr Lucas argued that Exxon could pay anything up to 700p per BP share before the bid became earnings dilutive. Anti-trust concerns could be sidestepped by returning BP''s $50bn downstream business to BP shareholders at a later date, he added.</p>
BP closed down 1.7 per cent to 302p - outperforming a sell-off in the wider market that pushed the FTSE 100 down 3.1 per cent or 157.46 points to 4,914.22. Every blue-chip stock ended lower.</p>
Miners dropped after a US research group cut its leading-index reading for April for growth in China due to a calculation error.</p>
"China''s overheated economy is cooling off, implying the policy tightening is working, so be ready for lower readings of Chinese data in the coming weeks," HSBC told clients.</p>
Rio Tinto  tumbled 6.4 per cent to 30.48, leading the Footsie fallers, while Xstrata  lost 6.1 per cent 908p and Antofagasta was 5.8 per cent weaker at 798p.</p>
A sharp drop in US consumer confidence hit transatlantic travel companies such as Carnival, down 5.8 per cent to 21.54, and British Airways , down 5.9 per cent to 197p.</p>
Barclays  led the banks lower, losing 6.3 per cent to 267p.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bryce Elder" date="June 30, 2010 3:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/bb3018d2-83dd-11df-ba07-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Talk gathers pace of possible Exxon bid for rival BP</headline><body><![CDATA[BP provided one of the few distractions for traders yesterday as global slowdown worries sent the FTSE 100 to its sharpest fall since November.</p>
BP was a talking point after JPMorgan Cazenove speculated about the chances of ExxonMobil launching a bid for its besieged rival.</p>
"We believe the economics of such a potential combination are compelling, and we question why the market is not factoring in the possibility of it ever happening," said analyst Fred Lucas.</p>
"The market has lost sight of the intrinsic value that is resident in an asset rich company like BP. We very much doubt that keen-eyed industry players have lost sight of BP''s value."</p>
Mr Lucas argued that Exxon could pay anything up to 700p per BP share before the bid became earnings dilutive. Antitrust concerns could be sidestepped by returning BP''s $50bn downstream business to BP shareholders at a later date, he added.</p>
"In many respects, an accurate valuation of BP today depends less on a valuation of its assets, but more on an accurate value of its potential liabilities. Who knows better how to price potential clean up costs and associated civil claims than ExxonMobil?"</p>
BP closed down 1.7 per cent to 302p - outperforming a sell-off in the wider market that pushed the FTSE 100 down 3.1 per cent or 157.46 points to 4914.22. Every blue-chip stock ended lower.</p>
Miners dropped after a US research group cut its leading-index reading for April for growth in China due to a calculation error.</p>
"China''s overheated economy is cooling off, implying the policy tightening is working, so be ready for lower readings of Chinese data in the coming weeks," HSBC told clients.</p>
Rio Tinto  tumbled 6.4 per cent to 30.48, leading the Footsie fallers, while Xstrata  lost 6.1 per cent 908p and Antofagasta was 5.8 per cent weaker at 798p.</p>
A sharp drop in US consumer confidence hit transatlantic travel companies such as Carnival, down 5.8 per cent to 21.54, and British Airways , down 5.9 per cent to 197p.</p>
Barclays  led the banks lower, losing 6.3 per cent to 267p as tomorrow''s expiry of a European Central Bank liquidity facility brought funding issues back to the fore. Lloyds Banking Group was off 2.9 per cent to 53p and Royal Bank of Scotland  slid 3.9 per cent to 41p.</p>
Vodafone  was weaker by 2.6 per cent to 142p on the back of a Credit Suisse downgrade to "neutral", on valuation grounds, while Reckitt Benckiser  lost 1.4 per cent to 30.80 in spite of an upgrade to "buy" from ING.</p>
AstraZeneca fell the least on the day, with the stock down 0.5 per cent to 29.47. Standard  Poor''s named the drugmaker among potential bid targets for cash-rich companies in the US.</p>
Among the mid-caps, Chloride  jumped 11.1 per cent to 387p after Emerson bid 375p a share for the power systems maker, trumping ABB''s 325p offer.</p>
Analysts were more cautious than traders on the chances of ABB coming back with a higher bid. The threat of ABB becoming a serious competitor in Europe "has pushed Emerson to pay ransom-strip prices for what is a relatively mundane business," Seymour Pierce analyst Ian Robertson said.</p>
McBride , the supermarket own-brand household products maker, rallied 3.4 per cent to 125p after Iain Napier, its non-executive chairman, bought 10,000 shares in the wake of last week''s warning on sales and costs.</p>
Logica  edged up 0.2 per cent to 109p after UBS added the IT services group to its "buy" list. UK public service spending, which provides about 13 per cent of Logica''s group sales, is at risk but a valuation below 10 times 2011 earnings already reflects that, Michael Briest argued. He retained a 133p price target.</p>
Carpetright  was down 9.9 per cent to 640p after its annual results showed margin pressure and the dividend was below market expectations. A cautious outlook also weighed on other big-ticket retailers, with Kingfisher  off 3.6 per cent to 212p and DSG International weaker by 2.8 per cent to 25p.</p>
Dry well sends Salamander sliding</p>
Salamander Energy dropped 5.9 per cent to 226p after the explorer plugged and abandoned a dry well offshore Vietnam. The high-risk well, 75 per cent-owned by Salamander, was the company''s first exploration well in the frontier prospect that is a key part of its 2010 drilling programme. Deutsche Bank said the failure cut potential upside from the programme by 26 per cent and cut its target price from 340p to 325p.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="ByBryce Elder" date="June 29, 2010 8:46 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/af1a5b1e-8349-11df-8451-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Talk gathers pace of possible Exxon BP bid</headline><body><![CDATA[BP provided one of the few distractions for traders on Tuesday as global slowdown worries sent the FTSE 100 to its sharpest fall since November.</p>
BP was a talking point after JPMorgan Cazenove speculated about the chances of ExxonMobil launching a bid for its besieged rival.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Burgis in Lagos" date="June 15, 2010 3:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b9b245c2-7814-11df-a6b4-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Nigerian group eyes Exxon venture</headline><body><![CDATA[A Nigerian company with close ties to China has offered $4.8bn to buy stakes in ExxonMobil''s oil venture in the country, intensifying a tussle for sub-Saharan Africa''s biggest energy reserves.</p>
Lagos-based Sunrise has made separate offers to Exxon, which holds 40 per cent and operates the joint venture, and the government, which holds 60 per cent. Sunrise is seeking to amass a 29 per cent holding, according to people familiar with the situation and leaked correspondence.</p>
The offers appear designed to capitalise on uncertainty in Nigeria''s oil industry. Chinese groups are challenging the dominance of western groups, which are resisting plans to impose tougher terms.</p>
Securing close to a third of the Exxon venture''s 720,000 barrels a day output would more than double China''s share of Nigerian production, adding to the African crude it has snapped up to fuel its fast-expanding economy.</p>
Industry analysts estimated the joint venture''s reserves at between 1.6bn and 2bn barrels, with potential for more.</p>
Sunrise, a previously little-known energy company, led last year''s audacious plan for China''s state-owned CNOOC to acquire one-sixth of Nigeria''s 36bn barrels of oil reserves for up to $50bn. Exxon blocks were among the 23 targeted.</p>
Subsequent correspondence from September between Sunrise and Emmanuel Egbogah, presidential special adviser on petroleum matters, a copy of which was obtained by the Financial Times, indicates the government was prepared to part with a 19 per cent stake in the Exxon venture.</p>
However, the government appeared to be seeking a higher price than the $3.2bn which a person close to Sunrise said the company had offered. Mr Egbogah said last month that talks on Chinese oil acquisitions in Nigeria had made little progress since October.</p>
Separately, Sunrise has in recent weeks informally approached Exxon with regards to purchasing 10 per cent of the venture from the US group for $1.6bn, people familiar with the situation said. Sunrise declined to comment. Three industry insiders said Exxon would be highly reluctant to sell part of one of its most important sources of production. Exxon said: "We do not disclose details of business discussions."</p>
However, with western energy groups, Asian powers and the government engaged in high-stakes brinkmanship, few options are off the table. The government is sorely in need of cash - from old investors or new - to fund a widening budget deficit. Proposed reforms designed to reverse years of underinvestment in the industry would also raise taxes and royalties for oil companies. Some western groups have warned of dire consequences for an industry on which Nigeria depends for 80 per cent of its revenue.</p>
African-China Trade special report, www.ft.com/ africa-china-trade-2010</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Burgis in Lagos" date="June 14, 2010 4:53 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/4a3f77d6-77ca-11df-82c3-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Nigerian group eyes stake in Exxon venture</headline><body><![CDATA[A Nigerian company with close ties to China has offered $4.8bn to buy stakes in ExxonMobil''s oil venture in the country, intensifying a tussle for sub-Saharan Africa''s biggest energy reserves. </p>
Lagos-based Sunrise has made separate offers to Exxon, which holds 40 per cent and operates the joint venture, and the government, which holds 60 per cent. Sunrise is seeking to amass a 29 per cent holding, according to people familiar with the situation and leaked correspondence.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="June 8, 2010 3:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/13513538-7294-11df-9f82-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon Valdez case points to lengthy battle for litigants</headline><body><![CDATA[It took two decades and more than $1bn (836m, 690m) in damages for ExxonMobil to resolve the last of the lawsuits from the 1989 Exxon Valdez oil spill in Alaska.</p>
BP''s continuing spill in the Gulf of Mexico is already bigger, and not only Louisiana''s fragile marshlands but also the tourist-filled beaches stretching to Florida are under threat from an estimated 12,000-19,000 barrels of oil per day gushing into the sea.</p>
"BP is saying they will pay legitimate claims, just like Exxon said after the Valdez oil spill," said Scott Summy, lead attorney at Baron  Budd, representing 18 fishermen in lawsuits against the British company. "Yet once publicity died down, Exxon litigated for over 20 years."</p>
Despite BP''s mantra that it will pay "all legitimate claims'''', Mr Summy questions how hard it will be to get the company to do that.</p>
BP said yesterday it did not comment on legal matters.</p>
Tracy Hester, director for the University of Houston''s Center for Environment, Energy and Natural Resources Law, said the federal offshore damages cap for spills of $75m would not apply to most of the claims for BP to cover clean-up costs, tort lawsuits, shareholder lawsuits, civil or criminal penalties and any state claims.</p>
"The scope of the lawsuits that could be brought to bear here will not be limited by the cap,'''' Mr Hester said. "Until the well is capped and the losses are filed, it''s very difficult to predict what any total liability might be.''''</p>
BP could follow Exxon''s example, which was to voluntarily pay $300m to more than 11,000 Alaskans and businesses immediately after the accident. In the end, the courts only ordered an additional $25m payment to some groups that had been overlooked.</p>
BP already says about 37,000 claims have been submitted and 18,000 payments have been made, totalling approximately $48m.</p>
But Robert Gordon, lawyer at Weitz  Luxenberg, representing more than 500 commercial fisherman in lawsuits against BP, said the company''s initial payments of $5,000 to boat owners and $2,500 to fishermen were inadequate considering the spill had not yet been stopped.</p>
"This case will drag on for years, as we won''t know the extent of the damages for years,'''' Mr Gordon said. How long it will take the region''s oyster, shrimp and fish populations to recover remains unknown.</p>
The Exxon Valdez litigation went on for so long because the company argued the original punitive damages ordered, $5bn, was excessive - an assessment the US supreme court agreed with, leading to a final payment of $507m and $470m in interest in 2009.</p>
The public and legal pressure on BP might be more severe than against Exxon, however, given that many Americans have visited the affected states: Louisiana, Mississippi, Alabama and Florida. For now, the lawsuits against BP have centred on those whose livelihoods have been threatened, as well as the victims and families of those on the BP-contracted rig when it exploded on April 20, killing 11 and injuring 17.</p>
Brent Coon  Associates, the key firm handling the lawsuits against BP from its Texas City refinery explosion in 2005, is representing Stephen Stone, who was injured in the rig blast.</p>
In the refinery case, the firm refused to settle until BP agreed to make $32m in worker training and healthcare donations, and that plaintiffs could release all 7m of the documents uncovered to federal agencies, and work towards making most of them public.</p>
Stopping future accidents would be a priority in this case, said Art Gonzalez, a managing partner at the firm. "The mess in the boardroom needs to be cleaned up. They can''t just turn their heads.''''</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNultyin Houston" date="June 7, 2010 7:10 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/402bb4ba-725e-11df-9f82-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Likely litigants look to Exxon Valdez precedent</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty<p>Fishing industry workers in Louisiana wait for jobs after the oil spill forced many boats to stay in dock. Lawyers have called BP''s compensation packages inadequate</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston and Carola Hoyos in London" date="April 30, 2010 3:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/34c7d392-53f0-11df-aba0-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Exxon warns on impact of BP spill</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil, the biggest US oil company, yesterday warned that the BP oil spill in the Gulf of Mexico would influence whether the US opens more areas offshore to drilling, as proposed by the Obama administration.</p>
Barack Obama, US president, recently announced a planned extension of offshore drilling access but there is growing concern in the industry that the Gulf spill will strengthen opposition to further oil development.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="April 14, 2010 3:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f9af4a7c-475d-11df-b253-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Exxon chief''s pay falls 16%</headline><body><![CDATA[The pay package of Rex Tillerson, the chief executive of ExxonMobil, the US''s biggest oil producer, fell 16 per cent in 2009, as falling commodity prices and the economic downturn resulted in a 57 per cent drop in earnings at the listed oil company.</p>
For 2009, Mr Tillerson''s total pay, including salary, bonus and stock, was $27.2m, according to Exxon''s proxy filing with the US Securities and Exchange Commission.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="March 11, 2010 3:57 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/3f062054-2d1f-11df-8025-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon to invest $28bn in 2010</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil, the world''s biggest publicly listed oil company, committed on Thursday to $28bn in capital spending in 2010 and a range of $25bn to $30bn in investment per year on average through 2014. </p>
This continues its strong investment programme of the last five years, which saw Exxon spend $110bn. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks" date="February 3, 2010 2:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/92f75054-1062-11df-a8e8-00144feab49a.html"><headline>BP sets sights on Exxon''s crown as industry leader</headline><body><![CDATA[It is a striking fact that BP''s oil and gas production is now greater than that of ExxonMobil, but its market capitalisation is more than 40 per cent smaller.</p>
That valuation gap will not disappear quickly. Exxon is a more diverse business, it is the world''s largest oil refiner and it has a substantial chemicals business, unlike BP.</p>
Yet the scale of disparity shows how BP still lags behind the acknowledged industry leader in terms of financial performance.</p>
In the past year BP''s market capitalisation has been catching up. Its shares have risen 15 per cent, while Exxon''s have fallen 13 per cent. But although Tony Hayward, chief executive, talked yesterday about 2009 as having been a "very good" year for BP, he emphasised there was "a lot more to do", to squeeze costs while making the investments needed to deliver future growth.</p>
The business environment, he pointed out, remains "challenging and volatile" with a slow recovery in the US and Europe.</p>
While the oil price has rebounded from its low point below $33 per barrel a year ago to about $75 yesterday, the price of gas, which accounts for more than a third of BP''s production, is still weak, having risen only 12 per cent in the US over the past 12 months.</p>
The gas price has been hit by a combination of cyclical factors - new export projects coming on stream as demand slumps because of the recession - and a structural shift: the fall in the cost of production that has made it possible to exploit vast reserves of previously uneconomic gas in the US.</p>
The cyclical factors will keep gas prices weak for the next three or four years, BP believes, but even after that there is likely to be a cap on any recovery because of the huge potential for increased US production.</p>
The refining business, meanwhile, is suffering a similar combination of cyclical downturn and structural decline in some markets.</p>
Those challenging conditions meant that in spite of $4bn of cost savings and 7,500 job cuts, BP did not quite manage to cover its $20bn investment programme and its $10.9bn dividend payments from its cash flows.</p>
Mr Hayward reiterated his objective to increase the dividend in line with long-term earnings growth, but the payment was unchanged for the sixth successive quarter at 14 cents a share.</p>
Meanwhile, although production growth was impressive at more than 4 per cent, BP admitted that this was helped by an unusually benign hurricane season in the Gulf of Mexico. With more normal conditions it would expect a slight fall in output this year. It expects to return to growth in 2011, but is still expecting a long-term increase of just 1-2 per cent a year.</p>
So it is easy to see why Mr Hayward is determined not too be seen to be resting on his laurels.</p>
He plans to give more details in a strategy presentation next month about his plans to make further cost savings, but yesterday he made a strong statement of his ambitions.</p>
"BP is performing okay now, we are back in the pack and doing fine," he said.</p>
"But there is still a gap between us and the best in the industry and I would observe that the industry itself is not the most efficient I have ever observed. So we think there is a long way to run in terms of overall efficiency that we can drive into BP."</p>
There were no more plans for "further major internal restructuring", he added, saying there had been "a lot to change in a few years".</p>
Instead, he suggested, the focus would be on the supply chain. That would not necessarily mean "putting the squeeze on suppliers", he said, but was about procuring goods and services more efficiently. "There is quite a lot more to go there," he added.</p>
The other focus of the strategy presentation will be on how to deliver on the promise of production growth.</p>
Andy Inglis, BP''s head of exploration and production, pointed to a successful year in winning access to resources. BP has replaced 129 per cent of its production to its reserves, booked under the definitions used by the US Securities and Exchange Commission, and 250 per cent under a looser definition of available resources.</p>
The company had a trumpeted success last year in the Gulf of Mexico, drilling the world''s deepest commercial exploration well to find an oilfield that is likely to be brought into production towards the end of the decade.</p>
It has also signed deals to open up new opportunities in Iraq, Indonesia, Jordan and Egypt.</p>
BP is being cautious about how all this will translate into production, but Mr Inglis says he is more confident about achieving the 1-2 per cent growth objective.</p>
Jason Kenney of ING argues that BP has greater exposure to high-margin oil and gas production than to lower margin refining. And within its production mix it has more "good high-margin barrels" produced in areas such as the Gulf of Mexico. Helped by the planned efficiency gains, that could mean that between 2009 and 2014, BP''s return on capital employed could surpass that of Exxon, for years the industry paragon. As he puts it, "BP could steal Exxon''s crown."</p>
If Mr Hayward succeeds in that, the valuation gap will grow even smaller.</p>
Lex, Page 18 Video: www.ft.com/ukview</p>
Weak refining
</p>
The weakest point in BP''s results was its refining and marketing business, writes Ed Crooks .</p>
Conditions in the industry have been tough, with excess capacity chasing inadequate demand for oil products, and refining margins worldwide have fallen to their lowest level for almost 15 years.</p>
The underlying operating profit in BP''s refining and marketing business was just $15m (9.4m) in the fourth quarter of last year, down from about $600m in the equivalent period of 2008.</p>
That compared with fourth-quarter refining losses of $345m for Chevron and $189m for ExxonMobil.</p>
The market has been hit by the recession and a long-term shift away from oil-based road fuels in developed countries.</p>
Tony Hayward, BP chief executive, says rising standards of fuel economy and the growth of biofuels and electric vehicles will mean demand for petrol in the US and western Europe will probably never rise higher than in 2007-08.</p>
BP''s response is not to get out of the industry, but to trust its relatively large and sophisticated refineries to survive while rivals fail.</p>
But Mr Hayward said margins were "likely to remain depressed for the foreseeable future".</p>
The poor performance of refineries augurs badly for Royal Dutch Shell, which reports full-year results tomorrow.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks" date="February 2, 2010 8:54 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f9f57a2a-1034-11df-841f-00144feab49a.html"><headline>BP sets sights on Exxon''s crown</headline><body><![CDATA[It is a striking fact that BP''s oil and gas production is now greater than that of ExxonMobil, but its market capitalisation is more than 40 per cent smaller.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="February 2, 2010 2:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f85339d0-0f9b-11df-b10f-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon hit by lower refining margins</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil saw its earnings hit sharply by lower refining margins in spite of a rise in production.</p>The world''s largest listed western energy group said fourth-quarter net earnings fell 23 per cent to $6.1bn from the same period a year earlier. Revenues rose 6 per cent to $89.8bn.</p>But earnings per share beat analysts'' expectations, down 18 per cent to $1.27, sending the shares up 3 per cent to $66.33 in early afternoon trading.</p>Exxon''s refining operations slid to a loss of $189m, down $2.6bn from the year-earlier period, dragged down by heavy losses in its US business as demand dropped with the downturn.</p>Oil and gas production increased nearly 2 per cent in the quarter to 2.18m barrels of oil equivalent, helped by production from its liquefied natural gas project in Qatar.</p>Some analysts say the fall in demand might never come back, and companies have responded by shutting down production and refineries. Refiners are also concerned about proposed taxes on carbon emissions being considered by Congress, which could hurt profitability.</p>Chevron, the secondbiggest US oil producer, has announced plans to restructure its refining division but has not given any details as to how extensive the cutbacks will be.</p>But David Rosenthal, vice-president of investor relations at Exxon, said the group was not planning any shake-up of its downstream operations. Exxon has in recent years divested its interests in 10 refineries, 5,000 miles of pipeline, 145 product terminals and 18,000 retail sites, he said.</p>"We don''t see a need right now for any significant restructuring; we''re in pretty good shape right now,'''' Mr Rosenthal said.</p>Exxon raised capital spending by 21 per cent in the quarter to $8.3bn. Spending for the year was up 4 per cent to $27.1bn.</p>Rex Tillerson, Exxon''s chief executive, said the company was "creating sustainable long-term value" with its agreement in December to buy XTO Energy for $41bn and tap into the company''s strong portfolio of onshore US natural gas reserves.</p>Analysts are concerned the XTO deal may not go through, given an exit clause that enables Exxon to walk away if the key technology used in tapping unconventional gas becomes uncommercial.</p>Environmentalists concerned about the impact of the fracturing techniques used to recover the gas are pressing lawmakers to impose regulations that could block the process or make it more uneconomic. Mr Rosenthal said hydraulic fracturing had been used on more than 1m wells in the US and there had been no documented cases of environmental problems.</p>Exxon reported full-year net earnings of $19.3bn, down 57 per cent. Revenues fell from $477.4bn in 2008 to $310.6bn. It raised its full-year dividend by 7 per cent to $1.66 per share.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Samantha Pearson in New York" date="February 1, 2010 9:46 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/670c9fc0-0f37-11df-8a19-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Wall Street given a lift by results from Exxon</headline><body><![CDATA[Positive manufacturing data and encouraging results from ExxonMobil helped to lift Wall Street sharply higher on Monday. </p>
The Institute for Supply Management''s index climbed to 58.4, indicating the strongest level of manufacturing activity since August 2004. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="February 1, 2010 8:28 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/9fc667ba-0f3c-11df-8a19-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon profits fall 23% in fourth quarter</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil saw its earnings hit sharply by lower refining margins in spite of a rise in production.</p>
The world''s largest listed western energy group said fourth-quarter net earnings fell 23 per cent to $6.1bn from the same period a year earlier. Revenues rose 6 per cent to $89.8bn.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="February 1, 2010 2:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e28ff2c4-0ed2-11df-bd79-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon in spotlight over XTO</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil, the US''s biggest oil company, releases its results today, with analysts hoping for updates in two areas - its acquisition of XTO Energy and moves to enter Ghana''s deepwater Jubilee field.</p>
In December, Exxon signalled a shift in strategy with a deal to pay $31bn in stock for XTO Energy, which will give it a large position in the booming domestic natural gas scene.</p>
Analysts said the cash-rich company paid a relatively high price for XTO''s reserves, many of which lie in US shale deposits.</p>
Yet it is a long-term bet on the future. The deal, which includes a further $10bn in XTO debt, gives Exxon an increased foothold in difficult-to-tap gas reserves and greater access to a cleaner-burn- ing alternative to coal.</p>
Nonetheless, the deal came with an exit clause, allowing it to walk away if hydraulic fracturing, the technology used in tapping unconventional natural gas, becomes uncommercial. That technology has enabled the boom in US onshore gas production in recent years, leading estimates of US resources to expand from 30 years'' supply, at current usage rates, to 100 years'' supply. But the process is under scrutiny, with a Congressional hearing held in January, as lawmakers seek to have it regulated by the Environmental Protection Agency, citing potential dangers to drinking water.</p>
The other outstanding issue is Exxon''s bid in October for a stake in Ghana''s Jubilee field , which the industry believes forms part of a newly discovered oil coast stretching off west Africa, from Sierra Leone to Ghana.</p>
Exxon offered to pay $4bn to buy the 23.5 per cent stake in Jubilee currently held by Kosmos, the independent US oil producer backed by private equity groups Blackstone and Warburg Pincus.</p>
The other main stakeholders in Jubilee are Anadarko Petroleum of the US and the UK''s Tullow Oil. But the project has been complicated by the Ghanaian government''s objections to the sale.</p>
The Ghana National Petroleum Corporation wants to buy the stake itself, with backing from a foreign partner. Many oil groups, from China''s CNOOC to the UK''s BP, are thought to be interested in getting into the field.</p>
Exxon is expected to report a drop in earnings, following the other oil groups, given the fall in demand and commodity prices last year from 2008''s highs.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNultyin Houston" date="January 31, 2010 10:19 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/cb161e6c-0eae-11df-bd79-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Exxon in spotlight over XTO</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil, the US''s biggest oil company, releases its results on Monday, with analysts hoping for updates in two areas  its acquisition of XTO Energy and moves to enter Ghana''s deepwater Jubilee field.</p>
In December, Exxon signalled a shift in strategy with a deal to pay $31bn in stock for XTO Energy, which will give it a large position in the booming domestic natural gas scene.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elizabeth Fry in Sydney" date="December 17, 2009 2:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/02962da2-eaae-11de-a9f5-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Exxon agrees finance for gas venture</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil and its joint venture partners in a $15bn liquefied natural gas project in Papua New Guinea have secured $14bn in project financing, and construction is due to begin early next year.</p>
Oil Search, one of the partners, which has a 29 per cent stake in what will be the largest foreign investment in Papua New Guinea, said the financing was more than enough to meet the estimated $13bn of debt required for the project at an agreed 70 per cent gearing.</p>
Oil Search said in a statement to the Australian Securities Exchange it was able to borrow $8.3bn from export credit agencies, tap a syndicate of 17 commercial banks for $1.95bn and secure $3.75bn from ExxonMobil.</p>
The breakdown of credit agencies shows that US Exim, JBIC and Nexi from Japan, China Exim, Sace from Italy and EFIC from Australia are all keen to participate in a project that will treble Papua New Guinea''s exports.</p>
It will also double the nation''s gross domestic product, which stands at about $8bn.</p>
In a note to clients, Macquarie Equities said that not only had the project partners secured more funding than required, but they had done it at better than anticipated interest rates.</p>
The broker said the extra financing capacity did not imply a potential cost overrun, but reflected a move to use cheap sources of funds potentially to accelerate expansion.</p>
"The larger loan balance is due to a significantly bigger commitment from the export credit agencies, $8.3bn versus $6.2bn," it said.</p>
"This in turn has given the joint venture more funds than expected but also has squeezed the commercial banks . . . down to only $1.95bn from previous guidance of $3bn."</p>
It added: "The net result is that we now expect the blended cost of this funding to be 194 basis points over Libor in the early years of the loan''s life rising to 227 basis points post start-up once the recourse is only to the project rather than the joint venture."</p>
Not only have the project partners been able to secure more funding at better rates than anticipated, but the commercial banks have lent without political risk insurance.</p>
This demonstrates the confidence the credit market has in the project and in Papua New Guinea, a traditionally hostile environment.</p>
The Papua New Guinea development is among more than a dozen planned in Australia and the neighbouring South Pacific nation aimed at tapping Asian demand for less-polluting alternatives to coal and oil.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elizabeth Fry in Sydney" date="December 16, 2009 2:29 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b8c3a9bc-e9e9-11de-ae43-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Exxon LNG project arranges $14bn in financing</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil and its joint venture partners in a $15bn liquefied natural gas project in Papua New Guinea have secured $14bn in project financing and construction is due to begin early next year.</p>
Oil Search  which has a 29 per cent stake in what will be the largest ever foreign investment in Papua New Guinea  said the financing was more than enough to meet the estimated $13bn of debt required for the project at an agreed 70 per cent gearing.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty" date="December 16, 2009 2:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/645c845e-e9e2-11de-ae43-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Exxon''s deal for XTO may open floodgates to a round of energy acquisitions</headline><body><![CDATA[Exxon''s move to acquire XTO Energy for $41bn sets the stage for a round of mergers and acquisitions in the energy sector, where the world''s top five super-majors alone are holding cash reserves of over $75bn.</p>
Such activity has been constrained during the past 18 months because of uncertainties over carbon legislation, as well as the economic downturn and credit squeeze. Many industry observers expect business will continue to be slow for a while.</p>
PFC Energy, the consultancy, projects it will take until 2013 for global exploration and production capital spending to return to the 2008 peak of nearly $460bn, and the possibility of a double-dip recession could postpone this further.</p>
Nonetheless, analysts, consultants and energy companies are forecasting that deals across the energy industry will pick up in 2010, as the pressures of the past year continue to build. Several big companies have already said that they would shed assets, and some smaller companies are growing increasingly distressed.</p>
"The main driver for such MA activity lies in the cash strength of probable acquirers - super-majors, Asian national oil companies and large independents," says Jim Dillavou, a partner leading energy MA transaction services at Deloitte  Touche, the accounting firm.</p>
"The world''s top five super-majors have cash reserves of more than $75bn, so the capacity is there for much greater MA activity," he says. "We have a lot of impatient buyers waiting for assets to come on the market."</p>
In October, ConocoPhillips, the third largest US oil company, outlined plans to sell $10bn in assets over the next two years, including its 9 per cent stake in the Syncrude oil sands project in Canada.</p>
In November, Devon Energy, one of the biggest independents, said it wanted to sell its Gulf of Mexico and international assets for up to $7.5bn to pay down debt and focus on the high-return US and Canadian onshore assets.</p>
Executives say the market is swinging towards the buyer, with cash-rich oil companies in no hurry to spend their money and a lot of assets available, with more expected in 2010.</p>
Stephen Chazen, president and chief financial officer at Occidental Petroleum, the US''s fourth biggest oil and gas production company, says acquisitions by his company have "picked up sharply" in the fourth quarter of 2009.</p>
The sellers are individuals or small natural gas producers whose hedges for higher US natural gas prices are running out, with no sign of a return to the record high of $13.694 per million British thermal units seen in 2008. Many overextended themselves as prices rose to that record and have been barely hanging on as prices fell this year to a 7.5-year low.</p>
But deals of the XTO size have been scarce, with overall transactions down about 50 per cent from June 2008 to June 2009, according to Jon McCarter, leader of transaction advisory services for Ernst  Young''s Americas Oil  Gas Centre.</p>
Negotiations began to pick up in July and August, leading Mr McCarter to expect a gradual increase in completed deals in 2010. One difficulty is disagreement on valuations, which has been compounded by uncertainty surrounding carbon legislation.</p>
Joe Stanislaw, head of the JA Stanislaw group, an independent advisory consultancy, said: "People don''t understand the full impact of carbon and the timing of legislation, whether it will come into effect over five or 10 years."</p>
While Holli Nichols, chief financial officer of power producer Dynegy, said consolidation makes sense, given the benefits gained through scale and reducing duplicative efforts. But it remains hard to do a deal.</p>
"With these uncertainties out there, it''s hard for boards and CEOs to pull the trigger," she said.</p>
See Lex</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty" date="December 15, 2009 10:51 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/9d5577d2-e9a8-11de-9f1f-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Exxon''s deal for XTO may open floodgates</headline><body><![CDATA[Exxon''s move to acquire XTO Energy for $41bn sets the stage for a round of mergers and acquisitions in the energy sector, where the world''s top five super-majors alone are holding cash reserves of over $75bn.</p>
Such activity has been constrained during the past 18 months because of uncertainties over carbon legislation, as well as the economic downturn and credit squeeze. Many industry observers expect business will continue to be slow for a while. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Samantha Pearson in New York" date="December 15, 2009 2:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/7e2e03be-e918-11de-a756-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Exxon bid for XTO sends S&amp;P 500 to 2009 peak</headline><body><![CDATA[A multi-billion dollar take-over deal by ExxonMobil helped Wall Street hit fresh highs for the year yesterday.</p>
Abu Dhabi''s announcement that it would provide Dubai with $10bn in bail-out funds also lifted the market from the opening bell.</p>
The SP 500 energy sector gained 0.2 per cent -, even as the price of oil fell for the ninth session in a row - after ExxonMobil announced it would buy XTO Energy in an all-stock deal valued at $41bn. The acquisition of the US natural gas producer includes about $10bn in XTO debt and is the eighth-largest energy deal since records began, according to Thomson Reuters. While XTO shares rose 15.4 per cent to $47.86, Exxon lost 4.3 per cent to $69.69.</p>
The SP 500 closed at its highest level since October last year, climbing 0.7 per cent to 1,114.11. The Dow Jones Industrial Average gained 0.3 per cent to 10,501.05 and the Nasdaq added 1 per cent to 2,212.10.</p>
Citigroup weighed on the market after announcing it would issue $17.5bn in common stock and $3.5bn in tangible equity units in a move to repay government bail-out funds.</p>
In a similar move, Bank of America sold $18.3bn of shares earlier this month to exit the troubled asset relief programme.</p>
Citigroup was down 6.3 per cent at $3.70. After early losses, the financial sector closed 0.6 per cent higher.</p>
Elsewhere, Visa rose 4.2 per cent to $84.77 after the stock was raised from "neutral" to "outperform" at Robert W. Baird  Co. Shares in the world''s largest electronic payments network were also buoyed by the company''s impending inclusion in the SP 500 index. Visa, which has risen more than 60 per cent so far this year, will replace Ciena , the network communications company. Ciena shares fell 4.4 per cent to $10.99 yesterday.</p>
MBIA , the world''s largest bond insurer, will also be dropped from the index and its shares dropped 7.6 per cent at $3.39.</p>
Shares in Brookdale Senior Living rose 6 per cent to $18.37 after Goldman Sachs added the retirement home operator to its "conviction buy" list.</p>
In other deal news, shares of Sun Microsystems jumped 11 per cent to $9.28 after EU regulators said they were optimistic a "satisfactory outcome" over Oracle ''s takeover bid was possible. The $7bn takeover deal has been under scrutiny due to competition concerns.</p>
The European Commission has until January 27 to clear or block the bid. However, last month, Steve Mills, head of IBM''s software division and one of Oracle''s biggest rivals, told the Financial Times that the acquisition did not raise any significant antitrust issues and was likely to close soon. Oracle shares gained 2.3 per cent to $23.31.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty" date="December 15, 2009 2:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/33e93c20-e917-11de-a756-00144feab49a.html"><headline>XTO bid answers questions on Exxon strategy</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil''s move to buy XTO Energy answers the question investors and analysts have been asking about the strategy of the world''s biggest listed oil group over the past couple of years.</p>
The $41bn deal, which includes $10bn of net debt, brings with it a resource base equivalent to 4,500bn cubic feet of gas, mostly unconventional such as that trapped in shale rock, tight sands and coal bed methane. It also complements Exxon''s similar holdings in the US, Canada, Germany, Poland, Hungary and Argentina.</p>
And exploiting that unconventional gas will be a priority. Following completion of the deal, Exxon said it would establish a organisation to manage global development and production of unconventional resources, enabling the rapid development and deployment of technologies and operating practices to increase production.</p>
"This is a significant day for ExxonMobil,'''' said Rex Tillerson, Exxon''s chief executive. "We''re excited about the opportunities.''''</p>
While US natural gas prices are off last year''s highs, Mr Tillerson stressed Exxon is never about the short term: "This is about the next 20-30 years,'''' he said.</p>
Indeed, many forecasts predict that demand for natural gas will grow.</p>
Gas has adequate scale and infrastructure to replace a significant amount of oil use and is about 30 per cent less carbon intensive than oil and about 50 per cent less carbon intensive than coal.</p>
The fuel is gaining support from legislators at a time when the world is looking at ways to reduce carbon emissions.</p>
In October, the Congressional Natural Gas Caucus was launched to develop Congressional policy on the importance of gas in the country''s energy portfolio. Sixty Congressmen have signed on.</p>
Mr Tillerson noted natural gas''s claim as a cleaner form of energy, following criticism of the company in recent years. Some shareholders and industry watchers have urged Exxon to move into wind, solar and biofuels to secure its future in a world many predict will run less on Exxon''s primary commodity - oil.</p>
Indeed, the Rockefeller family, the longest continuous shareholder of Exxon, made a high-profile push for such investment in early 2008, which Exxon thwarted with protestations that it would not invest in areas requiring government subsidies.</p>
Yet even as many in the industry accepted Exxon''s explanations, some wanted it to put its large net cash position - a record $60bn at the end of 2008 - to use. But Exxon continued to focus on buying back shares and funding its capital programme.</p>
Many analysts, nonetheless, predicted this year that Exxon would pick up assets from companies under pressure from the credit squeeze, economic downturn and fall in commodity prices.</p>
But the only other sizeable move by Exxon until now had been its bid in October to move into Ghana. And even that was seen as underwhelming by analysts, given the agreement to acquire a large stake in Ghana''s Jubilee oil field from its private equity owners for about $4bn was uncharacteristically small for Exxon.</p>
Still, completing that deal, which is currently tied up in political wrangling, would give it a toehold into what the industry expects to be one of the most lucrative oil discoveries in the world in recent years.</p>
Yet the bigger focus has been on why Exxon, and the other US majors, were missing out on the unconventional natural gas play in their own backyard.</p>
The small independent oil and natural gas producers, including XTO, have, in the past three years, increased estimates of US supplies from 30 years, at current usage rates, to 100 years supply, mostly by figuring out how to extract gas from shale rock economically.</p>
Meanwhile, the Europeans have got in on the action. BP and BG Group of the UK; StatoilHydro, the Norwegian energy company; and Eni, the Italian oil company, have all bought into the US gas industry in the past year to not only produce but take what they learn about extracting gas from shale rock abroad.</p>
And PFC Energy, a consultancy, estimated the unconventional gas move could be taken global, noting that advancements made by the independents in developing natural gas from shale could, if taken abroad, more than quadruple gas resources, increasing supplies of this alternative option to greenhouse-intensive oil, coal and oil sands fuels.</p>
This makes the XTO purchase a good fit for Exxon, with its international reach. Not only will it give the company access to the US production boom but also brings with it a team that has the expertise and technology to make this a global play.</p>
Still, there are potential pitfalls. Robin West, chairman of PFC Energy, the consultancy, noted the onshore unconventional gas industry has been dominated by smaller players, who specialise in the short-term nature of the business, which requires constant reinvestment and drilling to maintain production.</p>
This is at odds with the traditional Exxon strategy of large, long-term, highly efficient assets. "The success of this investment will depend on whether Exxon can keep the XTO culture in its team,'''' he said. "It''s a different business.''''</p>
www.ft.com/oil www.ft.com/energysource</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty" date="December 14, 2009 9:06 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/746931fe-e8e2-11de-a756-00144feab49a.html"><headline>XTO bid answers questions on Exxon strategy</headline><body /></entry><entry author="By Elizabeth Fry in Sydney" date="December 9, 2009 2:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/7f8535ca-e463-11de-a0ea-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Exxon commits to Papua New Guinea</headline><body><![CDATA[
ExxonMobil and its partners have agreed to press ahead with a $15bn liquefied natural gas project in Papua New Guinea that would represent the largest foreign investment in the country to date.</p>
The US group said that, once completed, the PNG LNG deal would treble Papua New Guinea''s exports and more than double its gross domestic product, which stands at around $8bn.</p>
However, Exxon said the project, which is expected to start early next year, still had to conclude sales agreements and finalise financing arrangements.</p>
Neil Duffin, ExxonMobil Development Company president, said that with demand for LNG forecast to nearly treble by 2030, the project would be important in helping meet it, "particularly for the economies in the fast-growing Asia Pacific region".</p>
The project is the latest in a series being developed in the region as oil and gas groups seek to tap into continued demand from Asia.</p>
In October, a consortium led by Chevron won approval to develop the A$43bn Gorgon LNG project off the western Australian coast.</p>
Last week, Chevron signed a 20-year gas sales agreement to supply 4m tonnes of gas a year from its Wheatstone field in Australia to Japan''s Tokyo Electric Power in a deal worth A$90bn ($82bn).</p>
Andrew Williams, a Credit Suisse oil and gas analyst, said the size and high price of the Tepco/Wheatstone deal was a clear indication of the pressure to secure binding contracts.</p>
The government of Papua New Guinea has a 16.6 per cent stake in the Exxon project.</p>
Exxon holds 33.2 per cent, Nippon Oil has 4.7 per cent and Oil Search and Santos, the Australian listed insurers, have 29 per cent and 13.5 per cent.</p>
PNG LNG has already signed binding agreements for the sale of a combined 3.8m tonnes per annum with China Petroleum  Chemical Corp and Japan''s Tepco.</p>
However, the project consortium has yet to conclude sale contracts for the remaining 6.6m tonnes of capacity with Osaka Gas of Japan and CPC, Taiwan''s state-owned refiner.</p>
Financing for the construction of the pipeline and liquefaction plant - thought to be 70 per cent project financed by US, Japanese and Italian export credit agencies - has not been finalised.</p>
But analysts say that Exxon''s triple A rating, together with a commitment from Japanese buyers, should encourage export credit agencies to step up to the deal.</p>
PNG LNG is considered to be the best underdeveloped gas project outside Qatar.</p>
As the gas fields are situated onshore in the highlands, project partners can use off-the-shelf technology, which is less costly than developing offshore platforms.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elizabeth Fry in Sydney" date="December 8, 2009 4:32 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/df1aede8-e415-11de-bed0-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Exxon commits to Papua New Guinea</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil and its partners have agreed to press ahead with a $15bn liquefied natural gas project in Papua New Guinea that would represent the largest foreign investment in the country to date. </p>
The US group said that, once completed, the PNG LNG deal would treble Papua New Guinea''s exports and more than double its gross domestic product, which stands at around $8bn.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="December 2, 2009 4:16 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/97eb39be-ded4-11de-adff-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Exxon CEO''s bonus cut by 40%</headline><body><![CDATA[Rex Tillerson, the chief executive of ExxonMobil, will receive a 7 per cent increase in salary to $2.2m in 2010, but his year-end bonus for 2009 is to drop by almost half.</p>
Exxon''s board of directors cut his 2009 bonus to $2.4m, down 40 per cent from 2008 after profits were hit by the economic downturn and lower oil prices. The company''s profits were lifted in 2008 by record-high commodity prices.
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Carola Hoyos in London" date="November 6, 2009 2:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/a5f22e10-ca74-11de-a3a3-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Supply hopes boosted after Exxon and Shell win Iraq oil deal</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil and Royal Dutch Shell, the world''s two biggest western oil companies, yesterday won the right to develop Iraq''s giant West Qurna oilfield, raising the prospect of a big jump in Iraqi oil supplies over the coming years.</p>
The agreement is the third such deal this year and marks the first time a US-led consortium will re-enter Iraq''s oil industry in more than 30 years. It is a blow to Lukoil of Russia, which had signed an agreement to develop West Qurna under Saddam -Hussein, former president, and has been lobbying intensely in recent weeks to retain it.</p>
Hussein Shahristani, Iraq''s oil minister, has said he is now confident that within seven to 10 years his country will be able to boost its production of little more than 2m barrels a day to almost 10m b/d, more than 10 per cent of today''s total global oil production.</p>
In the past, analysts doubted the target was achievable, mainly because of Iraq''s difficult security and political climate. But even they agree now that a big increase is feasible.</p>
A recent note by PFC Energy, the industry advisory company, points out that the extra oil that foreign energy companies - such as ExxonMobil, BP and Eni - have promised to tease out of other Iraqi oilfields adds up to about 4.7m b/d, while the fields that are likely to go under the hammer at Iraq''s next oil auction will add at least another 3m b/d.</p>
PFC added that, even well before the middle of the next decade, Iraq will be able to raise its production by so much that the</p>
Organisation of Petroleum Exporting Countries , the oil producers'' cartel, will face a conundrum.</p>
"As prospects increase for Iraq to approach prewar [oil production] levels . . . the issue of re-incorporating Iraq into Opec''s system of production targets will quickly re-emerge as a topic for negotiations," PFC said.</p>
"The process of reaching a negotiated settlement could add further friction to what will already be a difficult process of managing oil markets during the global economy''s weak recovery."</p>
To boost oil prices, which have fallen by almost half since last year, Opec has set a maximum production level for each of its 12 members - except Iraq.</p>
Iraq has been exempt from any quota limits since the UN placed sanctions on the Hussein regime. The exemption continued after the US invasion of Iraq in 2003, to give the country a chance to recuperate.</p>
For years, exempting Iraq was painless because Iraq''s production was constrained and oil prices had been strong, eliminating the need to cut output. But that has changed with the recent fall in the oil price. More Iraqi production will weigh on prices, making Opec''s members'' already slipping compliance with their quotas all the more problematic. Bringing Iraq back into the quota system will be one of the biggest tests of political will that Opec has faced in decades.</p>
Many of Opec''s countries feel the quota system is unfair and want their own production allocation increased. Instead, they will now have to decrease their share of the pie to incorporate Iraq.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Carola Hoyos in London" date="November 6, 2009 2:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/63393d42-ca75-11de-a3a3-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Supply hopes boosted after Exxon and Shell win Iraq oil deal</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil and Royal Dutch Shell, the world''s two biggest western oil companies, yesterday won the right to develop Iraq''s giant West Qurna oilfield, raising the prospect of a big jump in Iraqi oil supplies over the coming years.</p>
The agreement is the third such deal this year and marks the first time a US-led consortium will re-enter Iraq''s oil industry in more than 30 years. It is a blow to Lukoil of Russia, which had signed an agreement to develop West Qurna under Saddam Hussein and has been lobbying intensely for the field in the past weeks.</p>
Hussein Shahristani, Iraq''s oil minister, has said he is now confident that within seven to 10 years his country will be able to boost its production of little more than 2m barrels a day to almost 10m b/d, more than 10 per cent of today''s total global oil production. In the past, analysts doubted the target was achievable, mainly because of Iraq''s difficult security and political climate. But even they agree now that the big increase is feasible.</p>
A recent note by PFC Energy, the industry consultants, points out that the extra oil foreign energy companies, such as Exxon, BP and Eni, have promised to tease out of other Iraqi oilfields adds up to about 4.7m b/d, while the fields that are likely to go under the hammer at Iraq''s next oil auction, will add at least another 3m b/d.</p>
Even well before the middle of the next decade, Iraq will be able to raise its production enough that the Organisation of Petroleum Exporting Countries , the cartel, might have a big conundrum on its hands, PFC said.</p>
"As prospects increase for Iraq to approach prewar [oil production] levels . . . the issue of re-incorporating Iraq into Opec''s system of production targets will quickly re-emerge as a topic for negotiations," PFC said.</p>
"The process of reaching a negotiated settlement could add further friction to what will already be a difficult process of managing oil markets during the global economy''s weak recovery."</p>
To boost oil prices, which have fallen by almost half since last year, Opec has set a maximum production level for each of its 13 members except Iraq.</p>
Iraq has been exempt from any quota limits since the UN put sanctions on Saddam Hussein. The exemption continued after the US invasion of Iraq in 2003 to give the country a chance to recuperate.</p>
More Iraqi production will weigh on prices, making Opec''s members'' already slipping compliance with the quota all the more problematic. But bringing Iraq back into the quota system will be one of the biggest tests of political will Opec has faced in decades.</p>
Many of Opec''s countries feel the quota system is unfair and want their allocation increased. Instead, they will now have to decrease their share of the pie to incorporate Iraq.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty" date="October 30, 2009 2:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/8f4dc076-c4f1-11de-8d54-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Exxon searches for new supplies</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil, the world''s biggest publicly listed oil company, revealed yesterday it had invested $19bn through the first three quarters to develop new energy supplies, as it unveiled a 65 per cent year-on-year slump in quarterly earnings due to falling commodity prices.</p>
The US company reported $4.7bn in earnings, down 65 per cent from the year-earlier quarter, on the fall in commodity prices from last year''s record highs and higher operating costs. It brought in $82.3bn in revenue, down from $137.7bn in the third quarter of 2008.</p>
Sheila McNulty, Houston</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Carola Hoyos in London and Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="October 29, 2009 7:40 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/853f2440-c4be-11de-8d54-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Profits plummet at Shell and Exxon</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil and Royal Dutch Shell, the world''s two largest listed oil companies, reported sharply lower third-quarter profits on Thursday. However, Exxon 
of the US and the Anglo-Dutch Shell have outlined strikingly different approaches to increasing their oil and gas production and tackling lower oil prices.</p>
While Shell announced deep cuts in staffing and costs, 
Exxon said it was maintaining its level of capital expenditure. 
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="October 29, 2009 1:50 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/54c4d924-c48f-11de-912e-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Exxon piles $19bn into fresh supplies</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil, the world''s biggest publicly listed oil company, said on Thursday it had invested $19bn through the first three quarters to develop new energy supplies, as it unveiled a 65 per cent year-on-year slump in quarterly earnings caused by falling commodity prices. 
</p>
The US company reported $4.7bn in earnings, down 65 per cent from the year-earlier quarter, on the fall in commodity prices from last year''s record highs and higher operating costs. It brought in $82.3bn in revenue, down from $137.7bn in the third quarter of 2008. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="October 26, 2009 2:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/85757736-c1ce-11de-b86b-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Focus falls on possible Exxon prey</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil, the US oil major, will report its third-quarter earnings on Thursday, when investors will be looking out for any further indications it is on the acquisition trail.</p>
The world''s biggest publicly listed oil company had a record $60bn in cash flow from operating activities last year - a war chest analysts expected it would spend acquiring assets from groups struggling to cope with dropping demand and plunging commodity prices.</p>
Yet, Rex Tillerson, Exxon''s chief executive, said early this year that the oil group was waiting for the market to settle before making its move.</p>
This month, Exxon struck, agreeing to acquire a large stake in Ghana''s Jubilee oil field from its private equity owners, paying about $4bn to get into one of the world''s most potentially lucrative oil discoveries in recent years.</p>
"This is the first Exxon deal in the public glare that I can remember in some time,'''' said Mark Flannery, oil and gas analyst at Credit Suisse.</p>
Exxon offered to buy the 23.5 per cent stake in Jubilee held by Kosmos, the independent US oil producer backed by private equity groups Blackstone and Warburg Pincus.</p>
The other main stakeholders in Jubilee are Anadarko Petroleum of the US and the UK''s Tullow Oil.</p>
But analysts have found the deal to be an uncharacteristically small one for Exxon.</p>
"The Ghana field in and of itself is not material enough for Exxon,'''' Mr Flannery noted. "It''s hard to see Exxon being satisfied with that one asset. To build a meaningful presence in the area, it couldn''t be the end of the story.''''</p>
But the story might not even start, he notes, given the Ghanaian government''s objections to the sale.</p>
The Ghana National Petroleum Corporation wants to buy the stake itself, with the backing of another foreign partner.</p>
Many oil groups, from China''s CNOOC to the UK''s BP, are thought to be interested in Jubilee, as it forms part of a newly discovered oil coast that stretches off West Africa from Sierra Leone to Ghana.</p>
In a world that has been exploiting its oil assets for some 100 years, such finds are increasingly scarce and are therefore attractive to Exxon, as well as its rivals.</p>
"The Exxon strategy is based on the efficient execution of large, long-life assets,'''' said Robin West, chairman of PFC Energy, the consultancy. "This play [for Jubilee] is absolutely consistent with that strategy.''''</p>
Analysts note that Exxon could go as far as buying the other investors in the Jubilee project, Anadarko and Tullow, in order to gain access to the new oil coast.</p>
"They could have always bought up an Anadarko,'''' Mr West said. "The challenge of the big oil companies is to create repeatable investment opportunities of scale and returns.''''</p>
Such opportunities are few and far between, and that might be the reason Exxon has appeared to hold back so far this year.</p>
Meanwhile, Exxon and other international oil companies have this year been taking on new roles, in managing large operations for the national oil companies that control most of the world''s reserves, such as Exxon''s liquefied natural gas projects in Qatar.</p>
Analysts say the drop in commodity prices and global demand prompted national oil companies to seek their expertise, as they found their fields declining faster than anticipated.</p>
"The national oil companies have suffered without the experience the international oil companies bring,'''' said Gary Adams, vice-chairman of oil and gas at Deloitte, the consultancy.</p>
Oil majors were building large natural gas positions for the long term, he said. Demand for natural gas, extraction of which is far less carbon intensive than oil, was going to rise in the next 20 years, he said. "That''s the long-term play.''''</p>
It might well be the next focus of Exxon''s acquisition strategy.</p>
Other big oil groups to report this week are Conoco-Phillips on Wednesday and Chevron on Friday.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="October 26, 2009 2:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/95d858a0-c1ce-11de-b86b-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Focus falls on possible Exxon prey</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil, the US oil major, will report its third-quarter earnings on Thursday, when investors will be looking out for any further indications it is on the acquisition trail.</p>
The world''s biggest publicly listed oil company had a record $60bn in cash flow from operating activities last year - a warchest that analysts expected it would spend acquiring assets from groups struggling to cope with dropping demand and plunging commodity prices.</p>
Yet Rex Tillerson, Exxon''s chief executive, said early this year that the oil group was waiting for the market to settle before making its move.</p>
This month, Exxon struck, agreeing to acquire a large stake in Ghana''s Jubilee oil field from its private equity owners, paying about $4bn to get into one of the world''s most potentially lucrative oil discoveries in recent years.</p>
"This is the first Exxon deal in the public glare that I can remember in some time,'''' said Mark Flannery, oil and gas analyst at Credit Suisse.</p>
Exxon offered to buy the 23.5 per cent stake in Jubilee currently held by Kosmos, the independent US oil producer backed by private equity groups Blackstone and Warburg Pincus.</p>
The other main stakeholders in Jubilee are Anadarko Petroleum of the US and the UK''s Tullow Oil.</p>
But analysts have found the deal to be an uncharacteristically small one for Exxon.</p>
"The Ghana field in and of itself is not material enough for Exxon,'''' Mr Flannery noted. "It''s hard to see Exxon being satisfied with that one asset. To build a meaningful presence in the area, it couldn''t be the end of the story.''''</p>
But the story might not even start, he notes, given the Ghanaian government''s objections to the sale. The Ghana National Petroleum Corporation wants to buy the stake itself, with the backing of another foreign partner.</p>
Many oil groups, from China''s CNOOC to the UK''s BP, are thought to be interested in Jubilee, as it forms part of a newly discovered oil coast that stretches off West Africa from Sierra Leone to Ghana.</p>
In a world that has been exploiting its oil assets for some 100 years, such finds are increasingly scarce, and are therefore attractive to Exxon, as well as its rivals.</p>
"The Exxon strategy is based on the efficient execution of large, long-life assets,'''' said Robin West, chairman of PFC Energy, the consultancy. "This play [for Jubilee] is absolutely consistent with that strategy.''''</p>
Analysts note that Exxon could go as far as buying the other investors in the Jubilee project, Anadarko and Tullow, in order to gain access to the new oil coast.</p>
"They could have always bought up an Anadarko,'''' Mr West said. "The challenge of the big oil companies is to create repeatable investment opportunities of scale and returns.''''</p>
Such opportunities are few and far between, and that might be the reason Exxon has appeared to hold back so far this year.</p>
Meanwhile, Exxon and other international oil companies have this year been taking on new roles, in managing large operations for the national oil companies that control most of the world''s reserves, such as Exxon''s liquefied natural gas projects in Qatar.</p>
Analysts say the drop in commodity prices and global demand prompted national oil companies to seek their expertise, as they found their fields declining faster than anticipated.</p>
"The national oil companies have suffered without the experience the international oil companies bring,'''' said Gary Adams, vice-chairman of oil and gas at Deloitte, the consultancy.</p>
Oil majors are also building large natural gas positions for the long term, he said. Demand for natural gas, extraction of which is far less carbon intensive than oil, is going to rise in the next 20 years, he said. "That''s the long-term play.''''</p>
It might well be the next focus of Exxon''s acquisition strategy.</p>
Other big oil groups to report this week are Conoco-Phillips on Wednesday and Chevron on Friday.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kate Mackenzie and William Wallis" date="October 24, 2009 3:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/37d8b672-c035-11de-aed2-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Ghana in oil stake talks as Exxon bid runs into trouble</headline><body><![CDATA[Ghana''s national oil company is talking with at least three foreign companies, including BP, who have expressed interest in a stake in the country''s offshore Jubilee field. The talks are being held in anticipation that ExxonMobil''s attempt to buy the stake may fail.</p>
Senior Ghanaian officials say that there is also interest from Total and a Chinese company - understood to be CNOOC - in buying the stake that is now held by Kosmos Energy. Ghana National Petroleum Corporation officials have made it clear they do not approve of an agreement for Exxon to buy Kosmos''s stake.</p>
GNPC itself has expressed interest in Kosmos'' 23.5 per cent stake in Jubilee, which is thought to hold 1.8bn barrels of oil. Company officials say they have raised sufficient funds to buy it, and then sell a portion on to another buyer.</p>
A senior Ghanaian official stressed that Kosmos was under no obligation to sell, but the state-owned company is unhappy with the existing terms of Kosmos''s holding, and wants to have control over who buys into the block.</p>
"The issue is what is in it for Ghana," a source close to GNPC said. "GNPC is now looking to see how to improve the terms for the company for the long-term."</p>
Officials say Kosmos, which discovered the Jubilee field in 2007, has a more favourable contract than the other main stakeholders, American company Anadarko and UK-listed Tullow.</p>
Ghana is under pressure to produce oil from the block quickly to ease the burden of strained finances and the rising cost of importing oil.</p>
Officials are weighing up the relative merits of possible buyers. Western companies, for example, can offer technical expertise while Chinese companies have big cash reserves that could help accelerate development of the block.</p>
Kosmos, which is backed by private equity groups Blackstone and Warburg Pincus, this month agreed to sell its stake to ExxonMobil, in a deal believed to be worth $4bn.</p>
But GNPC officials raised objections to the deal, and accused Kosmos of giving out data belonging to GNPC to 26 prospective buyers without its approval.</p>
Spokespeople at BP and Total declined to comment. BP has oil production operations in Angola, while Total is active in Angola, Nigeria and Democratic Republic of Congo.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kate Mackenzie and William Wallis" date="October 23, 2009 10:27 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/11546486-c00a-11de-aed2-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Ghana in talks as Exxon bid runs into trouble</headline><body><![CDATA[Ghana''s national oil company is talking with at least three foreign companies, including BP, who have expressed interest in a stake in the country''s offshore Jubilee field. The talks are being held in anticipation that ExxonMobil''s attempt to buy the stake may fail.</p>
Senior Ghanaian officials say that there is also interest from Total and a Chinese company  understood to be CNOOC  in buying the stake that is now held by Kosmos Energy. Ghana National Petroleum Corporation officials have made it clear they do not approve of an agreement for Exxon to buy Kosmos''s stake.</p>
]]> </body></entry></news>