
<news>
    <entry author="By Sam Fleming and Philip Stafford" date="September 11, 2014 12:18 am"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/48aa6b02-38f9-11e4-9526-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan tells clearers to build bigger buffers</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Clearing houses  which guarantee the smooth completion of financial transactions ranging from
            derivatives trades to commodities deals  should be required to line up larger financial buffers to
            prevent triggering a future market disaster, a top investment bank has argued. </p>
            JPMorgan Chase is to warn in a forthcoming paper that the current system for dealing with failing clearing
            houses is brittle and opaque, and requires a new resolution framework to tackle major failures. </p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Martin Arnold, Banking Editor" date="August 12, 2014 2:05 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/840e0692-2213-11e4-ad60-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>Sir Win Bischoff to take chairman role at JPMorgan Securities</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Charlie Bibby]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Henny Sender in New York" date="July 28, 2014 2:00 am"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a7392562-15ab-11e4-ae2e-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>Sankaty to buy JPMorgan debt portfolio for $1bn</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Sankaty Advisors, the credit arm of Bain Capital, is paying more than $1bn for the debt portfolio of
            JPMorgan''s principal investment group.</p>
            The sale underscores the extent to which shadow banks are taking over lucrative parts of the operations of
            big commercial banks, which are under pressure to raise capital and play down certain activities to meet new
            Basel requirements and regulatory constraints.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Camilla Hall in New York" date="July 15, 2014 4:53 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/9f00e4aa-0c0c-11e4-a096-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>Dimon reassures investors on cancer as JPMorgan beats estimates</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[EPA]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Josh Noble in Hong Kong" date="July 10, 2014 4:59 am"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/eb932114-07e0-11e4-8e62-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan picks David Li to head probe-hit China division</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Caroline Binham, Legal Correspondent" date="July 6, 2014 1:54 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/32daf9ee-038a-11e4-817f-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>Ex-JPMorgan trader challenges whale'' findings</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[A former JPMorgan Chase trader who faces US criminal charges in the wake of the $6bn London whale
            debacle is challenging civil findings made against the bank by the UK financial watchdog.</p>
            Julien Grout, a French national who worked as a junior credit-derivatives trader at the time of the $6bn
            loss that rocked the bank in 2012, has filed an appeal with a London tribunal taking issue with the UK
            Financial Conduct Authority''s findings against JPMorgan that were part of the bank''s $1bn
            settlement with US and UK authorities last year, according to tribunal records.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Jamil Anderlini in Beijing and Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="May 21, 2014 4:39 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/d62272be-e0f6-11e3-875f-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>Former JPMorgan China banker questioned in HK</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[AFP]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Caroline Binham, Legal Correspondent" date="May 20, 2014 3:21 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c4513c82-e024-11e3-b709-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>London coroner rules JPMorgan manager''s death was suicide</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Reuters<p>William Magee, father of JPMorgan technology expert Gabriel Magee, speaks outside
            Poplar coroner''s court on Tuesday</p>]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Sam Fleming" date="May 12, 2014 10:39 am"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/cee218c0-d9b1-11e3-920f-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>Former Italian finance chief Vittorio Grilli to join JPMorgan</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>Vittorio Grilli, former Italian finance minister</p>]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York, John Paul Rathbone in London and Gina Chon in Washington"
           date="May 6, 2014 5:42 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/3a8f975c-d523-11e3-adec-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan shuts foreign diplomats'' accounts</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>Colombia''s former finance minister Jose Antonio Ocampo</p>]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="fer in London and Richard Milne in Oslo" date="May 4, 2014 5:18 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/d3b8f83a-d224-11e3-8b5b-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>Citi wins Norway fund business from JPMorgan</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Citigroup has been chosen to safeguard the securities of the world''s biggest sovereign wealth fund
            after wooing away one of the largest custodian mandates from its rival JPMorgan.</p>
            The transfer of the Norwegian oil fund''s $865bn portfolio to its US competitor is a setback for
            JPMorgan, which is one of the top three competitors in the rapidly growing custodian business. </p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Henny Sender and Tom Braithwaite in New York and Jamil Anderlini in Beijing"
           date="April 18, 2014 6:36 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e622de5e-c70d-11e3-889e-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan''s head of China Zili Shao moved to fresh role</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan Chase''s head of China is stepping down from the role after a controversial five years
            running a unit that is now mired in the princeling scandal roiling the largest US bank by
            assets.</p>
            Zili Shao''s move from head of China to vice-chairman of Asia Pacific was announced hastily by the bank
            on Friday after enquiries from the Financial Times.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="April 11, 2014 6:59 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/1105852a-c166-11e3-83af-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan misses targets as revenues in fixed income slump</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan Chase had its worst start to the year in fixed income trading since the depths of the financial
            crisis, causing the largest US bank to report a sharp decline in profits.</p>
            Revenues from trading bonds, currencies and commodities fell 21 per cent in the first quarter to $3.8bn,
            compared with the same period in 2013. </p>
            <h3>By the numbers: JPMorgan</h3>]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="April 4, 2014 6:14 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/ddeb2d56-bc07-11e3-a31c-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan''s Masters withdraws from line of fire</headline>
        <body/>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite and Arash Massoudi in New York" date="April 3, 2014 10:47 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e4fbe9ae-bb63-11e3-b2b7-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan restructures unit that housed the London whale''</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan Chase has restructured its chief investment office, the former home of the London whale,
            in a further step away from the risky strategy that caused more than $6bn of losses, according to people
            familiar with the matter.</p>
            The bank said in an internal memo on Monday that it was combining its CIO and treasury in an organisation
            that mirrors the asset and liability management functions of a traditional bank.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Stephen Foley in New York" date="April 3, 2014 8:25 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e4a2a940-bb43-11e3-b2b7-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan deal builds new US pensions challenger to Fidelity</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Bob Reynolds, the former number two at Fidelity, has signalled his ambition to challenge his former firm''s
            dominance of the US pension market with a deal to add JPMorgan Chase''s retirement services business to
            his growing empire at Great-West Financial.</p>
            The acquisition comes just weeks after Great-West merged its US pension administration business with that of
            its sister company, Putnam Investments, and put Mr Reynolds in charge of the combined group. He was hired to
            run Putnam, another subsidiary of Canada''s Great-West Lifeco, in 2008, a year after leaving Fidelity.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="April 2, 2014 8:34 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/6b810e5e-ba89-11e3-8b15-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>Blythe Masters quits JPMorgan after 27 years</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Kathrin Hille in Moscow and Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="April 1, 2014 11:05 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/2603afd6-b9d4-11e3-957a-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>Russian threat to retaliate over JPMorgan block</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Russia has threatened to retaliate against US diplomatic missions after JPMorgan Chase blocked a money
            transfer from a Russian embassy, in the clearest political fallout so far from sanctions imposed over the
            annexation of Crimea last month.</p>
            The Russian foreign ministry said JPMorgan had blocked a transfer by Russia''s embassy in Astana, the
            capital of Kazakhstan, to Sogaz, an insurance company part-owned by Bank Rossiya, one of the targets of US
            sanctions announced on March 20.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite, Anne-Sylvaine Chassany and Henny Sender" date="March 25, 2014 6:48 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/399fffea-b41b-11e3-a102-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan executive Mike Cavanagh quits for Carlyle</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York and Jamil Anderlini in Beijing" date="March 24, 2014 7:29 am"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/5e4f6494-b2ee-11e3-b891-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>Top JPMorgan China banker retires amid hiring probe</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[One of JPMorgan Chase''s top bankers in China is leaving the bank amid an investigation into its
            hiring practices in Asia.</p>
            Fang Fang, JPMorgan''s head of investment banking in China, is retiring after 12 years at the bank,
            according to an internal memo sent to the US bank''s staff on Monday.
            </p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Neil Hume in London and Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="March 19, 2014 6:23 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/4c0894b0-af45-11e3-bea5-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan sells physical commodities unit to Mercuria for $3.5bn</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan Chase has agreed to sell its physical commodities business to Mercuria, the Geneva-based trading
            house, for $3.5bn, becoming the latest investment bank to scale back its activities in the sector.</p>
            The deal, which is expected to close in the third quarter of 2014, will lift privately owned Mercuria into
            upper tier of global commodity traders alongside Vitol, Trafigura, and Gunvor.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Ed Hammond and Arash Massoudi in New York" date="March 12, 2014 5:06 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/65394812-a9f5-11e3-adab-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>Blue Buffalo appoints JPMorgan for listing</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Blue Buffalo, the luxury dog food brand, has hired JPMorgan to lead its initial public offering in a
            listing that is expected to value the business at more than $2bn.</p>
            The company, which has a sideline in cat food products, has also hired Citigroup, Morgan Stanley, Barclays
            and Deutsche Bank for a listing that could come later this year, people familiar with its thinking said.
            </p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="February 25, 2014 10:56 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/41fc7290-9e27-11e3-b429-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan targets $30bn war chest</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[AFP]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="February 24, 2014 11:35 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/6cb50388-9d8e-11e3-a599-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan Chase to cut thousands more jobs</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan Chase is planning more job cuts in its mortgage business on top of the 13,000-15,000 positions
            already due to be slashed because of plunging demand for home loans.</p>
            Several thousand more cuts are planned, according to people familiar with the matter, and could be announced
            at JPMorgan''s annual investor day on Tuesday. They are part of a new efficiency drive at the largest
            US bank by assets that also encompasses staffing branches with fewer employees.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="February 21, 2014 12:50 am"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/aea20e7e-9a8e-11e3-8e06-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan avoids third showdown over Dimon role</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan Chase has avoided a third successive showdown with shareholders at its annual meeting in Florida
            by convincing activists to forgo a vote on whether the bank should split the roles of chairman and chief
            executive.</p>
            Jamie Dimon holds both positions and last year''s meeting in Tampa saw a contentious vote over whether
            to strip him of one of the roles in the wake of the London whale trading fiasco. After
            lobbying from both sides, the bank ultimately quelled revolt over the issue.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Gina Chon in Washington and Kara Scannell in New York" date="February 10, 2014 7:57 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/804b62ee-927f-11e3-9e43-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>Legality of JPMorgan''s $13bn settlement with DoJ tested</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[The US justice department reached a secretive, backroom deal when it agreed to a landmark $13bn settlement
            with JPMorgan Chase to resolve allegations that the bank mis-sold mortgage securities, according to a
            lawsuit filed on Monday. </p>
            Better Markets, a non-profit group that promotes the public interest in financial markets, is asking a court
            to declare the settlement unlawful and issue an injunction to prevent the DoJ from enforcing it until it has
            been reviewed and approved by a judge.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Gregory Meyer and Camilla Hall in New York and Neil Hume in London"
           date="February 5, 2014 6:49 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/8f4711b0-8e8a-11e3-98c6-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan nears commodities sale</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan Chase moved closer to a sale of its physical commodities business on Wednesday, when the bank
            entered exclusive talks with the trading house Mercuria, according to a person close to the situation. </p>
            If a deal is finalised, it will lift the Geneva-based company to the upper tier of global commodities
            traders while sharply curtailing JPMorgan''s presence in the oil, natural gas and coal markets. </p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="fer and Sam Fleming in London" date="January 22, 2014 8:14 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/98af3bb8-8392-11e3-aa65-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan raises alarm over rising euroscepticism in Britain</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan has warned that the UK could lose its clout in transatlantic trade and regulatory disputes if it
            exits the European Union, in the latest example of City alarm about rising euroscepticism in Britain.</p>
            The US bank said in a submission to the UK Treasury that London is more likely to get what it wants in
            negotiations over cross-border rules if it negotiates as part of the EU.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Lina Saigol" date="January 21, 2014 10:12 am"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/894d51f8-8272-11e3-8119-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan rainmaker Klaus Diederichs to retire</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Paul J Davies in Hong Kong" date="January 21, 2014 9:27 am"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e0283bee-826a-11e3-8119-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan bows out of IPO amid Asia hiring probe</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan has bowed out of a potentially lucrative role in the $1bn Hong Kong listing of a Chinese
            chemicals company due to the investigation into the US bank''s hiring of princelings.</p>
            The bank was one of several institutions working with Tianhe Chemicals towards a listing but decided to end
            its involvement when an internal risk review noted that the daughter of the company''s chairman had
            worked at JPMorgan, according to people familiar with the situation. </p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Jane Croft Law Courts Correspondent" date="January 20, 2014 7:44 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/7cdf03b6-81f6-11e3-a600-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>German transport authority claims it was misled'' by JPMorgan</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan Chase knew or ought to have known that a German transport authority
            was naive in the world of complex credit derivatives when the investment bank sold it a
            complex deal, it has been claimed in court documents.</p>
            The court papers relate to a trial in which the US bank is suing Berlin''s transport authority BVG for
            $204m over a collateralised debt obligation which the German authority took out in July 2007.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite" date="January 14, 2014 7:22 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/9711558c-7d45-11e3-a579-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>Muted JPMorgan quarter raises doubts over sector''s health</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite and Camilla Hall in New York" date="January 14, 2014 11:25 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/8a9fde6e-7d12-11e3-81dd-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan profits dragged down by legal bills</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[AP<p>Jamie Dimon, chief executive</p>]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Jane Croft, Law Courts Correspondent" date="January 12, 2014 5:23 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/13f87012-7a03-11e3-8211-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan in $200m lawsuit against Berlin transport authority</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan and BVG, the Berlin transport authority, are set to begin a $200m High Court trial over a complex
            credit default swap arrangement signed before the 2008 financial crisis.</p>
            The case, which is due to last 10 weeks, will be closely watched as it is the first of a number of lawsuits
            to come to trial involving European public authorities that used complex financial instruments before the
            credit crunch.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Guy Chazan" date="January 12, 2014 2:57 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0c510546-7b79-11e3-a2da-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>Ex-JPMorgan dealmaker wins green light for Afghan mine</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[A mining company set up by Ian Hannam, the former JPMorgan dealmaker, has won approval from the Afghan
            government to develop a big copper deposit in the north-west of Afghanistan.</p>
            Afghan Gold and Minerals Company (AGMC) won the licence for the deposit, known as Balkhab, in 2012 but only
            agreed on terms for the contract to develop it with the Afghan Ministry of Mines last October. </p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Ed Hammond, US Mergers and Acquisitions Correspondent" date="January 9, 2014 12:39 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/3c47f030-792a-11e3-91ac-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>Former JPMorgan dealmaker James Woolery to chair Cadwalader</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>James Woolery</p>]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Gina Chon in Washington" date="January 8, 2014 11:02 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e1a7d7ba-7886-11e3-831c-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan hires ex-IMF director to lead Asian regulation strategy</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[
            JPMorgan Chase has hired Anoop Singh, the former director of the International Monetary Fund''s
            Asia-Pacific department, to be head of regulatory strategy in that region.</p>
            The newly created position, which will be announced on Thursday, comes amid a probe into JPMorgan''s
            hiring practices in China and a global investigation into the manipulation of foreign exchange trading that
            has ensnared other banks.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite and Kara Scannell in New York" date="January 7, 2014 11:01 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/bff03342-77af-11e3-807e-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan sets record with $2.6bn Madoff payment</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[EPA]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Gregory Meyer and Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="December 19, 2013 7:02 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/163f28be-68bc-11e3-bb3e-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>Gripes over JPMorgan''s commodities sale</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Bidders for JPMorgan Chase''s physical commodities business have complained that the bank is refusing
            to release enough information for them to value the assets.</p>
            The sale has presented a challenge for bankers running the process as they are negotiating with some of
            their fiercest trading rivals. </p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="December 18, 2013 6:37 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/08da35d2-680e-11e3-8ada-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan shoots the instant messenger</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan Chase''s investment banking co-heads banned their staff from using multi-bank instant
            messaging services on Wednesday, the latest sign of banks clamping down on a tool blemished by its use in
            market manipulation.</p>
            In a memo to staff, Mike Cavanagh and Daniel Pinto said that  effective immediately
             all staff were prohibited from participating in electronic chats or instant messaging groups
            with two or more other banks/dealers.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York and Gina Chon in Washington" date="December 18, 2013 12:21 am"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/bf273aba-6773-11e3-a5f9-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan sues FDIC for more than $1bn</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan Chase sued the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation on Tuesday, striking back against the
            government weeks after agreeing to pay $13bn to resolve claims that it mis-sold mortgage securities.</p>
            The largest bank in the US said it was trying to recover substantially in excess of a billion dollars
            from the FDIC, which managed the receivership of Washington Mutual after the bank failed during the crisis
            and then sold most of its assets to JPMorgan.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Henny Sender and Tom Braithwaite" date="December 16, 2013 6:28 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/268df9d0-6677-11e3-aa10-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan to sell Asia investment business</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan Chase has put up for sale its Global Special Opportunities Group, an Asia-based principal
            investment business, for a valuation likely to be more than $1bn.</p>
            The largest US bank has been talking to numerous private equity firms and credit-focused hedge funds about
            the transaction, as part of an effort to streamline its operations and anticipate regulatory trends,
            according to people familiar with the situation.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Chris Newlands" date="December 15, 2013 7:50 am"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/4b38349a-63fb-11e3-b70d-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan to shut 1bn money fund</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[AFP<p>JPMorgan is to merge its 949m Euro Government Liquidity fund into its 11.1bn
            Euro Liquidity product</p>]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite and Kara Scannell in New York" date="December 12, 2013 3:10 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c64cfc20-6288-11e3-bba5-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan to pay $2bn to settle Madoff claims</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan Chase has tentatively agreed to pay $2bn to settle allegations it failed to inform US authorities
            of suspicious activity from Bernard Madoff, according to people familiar with negotiations between the bank
            and the Department of Justice.</p>
            The Justice Department has accused the bank of failing to pass on concerns about Madoff, who had an account
            with the bank, and was arrested five years ago this week as his $20bn Ponzi scheme came to light.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tracy Alloway in New York" date="December 10, 2013 6:19 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e230307a-61c4-11e3-aa02-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan files patent for Bitcoin-style payment system</headline>
        <body/>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Gregory Meyer in New York and Gina Chon in Washington" date="November 27, 2013 11:31 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a90175ec-57b1-11e3-b615-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan eyed sale of metals unit in 2012</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan Chase drew up plans to sell part of its metals warehousing empire last year as it faced pressure
            to show regulators that the business fitted with the activities of a bank, according to newly released
            documents. </p>
            A letter from the Federal Reserve obtained by the FT shows that the bank was working on the divestiture
            plan, some eight months before it publicly put up for sale its physical commodities business, which includes
            the Henry Bath warehousing unit.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Gina Chon in Washington" date="November 26, 2013 4:20 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/6618cbce-56b0-11e3-8cca-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan woes cause first fall in US bank income in four years</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Kara Scannell and Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="November 19, 2013 11:53 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0a76c1ae-512e-11e3-9651-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan agrees $13bn settlement over mortgage securities</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan Chase agreed on Tuesday to pay $13bn in a landmark settlement with the US Department of Justice
            and state authorities for mis-selling mortgage securities, but fought to contain the damage.</p>
            The size and scope of this resolution should send a clear signal that the justice department''s
            financial fraud investigations are far from over, said Eric Holder, US attorney-general. No
            firm, no matter how profitable, is above the law, and the passage of time is no shield from accountability.</p>
            You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite and Kara Scannell in New York" date="November 18, 2013 11:34 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f11b2e2e-507f-11e3-9f0d-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan agrees to shoulder WaMu bill</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan Chase has conceded it will take responsibility for the past misdeeds of Washington Mutual,
            according to people familiar with the matter, paving the way for the Department of Justice to announce the
            biggest ever settlement with a single company.</p>
            People close to the sometimes fractious talks over the US government''s investigation into mortgage
            securities mis-selling say that the DoJ is poised to announce a $13bn settlement with JPMorgan on Tuesday
            after the bank accepted it would not try to claim back part of the costs from the government-managed
            receivership of WaMu.</p>
            You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="November 15, 2013 10:46 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/566bf510-4e41-11e3-8fa5-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan to pay $4.5bn over mis-selling mortgage securities</headline>
        <body/>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Camilla Hall in New York and Hannah Kuchler in San Francisco" date="November 14, 2013 1:34 am"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/8d3a24dc-4cbf-11e3-958f-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan feels the wrath of Twitter</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan Chase cancelled a planned question and answer session on Twitter after the event attracted
            thousands of verbal attacks, in what may go down as a case study in how not to market on the
            social media website. </p>
            Jimmy Lee, one of the senior bankers that worked on Twitter''s share sale, was set to take over
            JPMorgan''s Twitter handle in an online marketing event on Thursday with the hashtag #AskJPM. </p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite and Shannon Bond in New York" date="November 6, 2013 11:33 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/42819126-4735-11e3-bdd2-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>New York police chief in talks on JPMorgan security role</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Ray Kelly, the uncompromising chief of the New York Police Department, is in talks to join JPMorgan Chase
            in a senior security-related role, according to people familiar with the matter.</p>
            Winning plaudits for the falling New York City murder rate but attracting criticism for the force''s
            stop-and-frisk policy, Mr Kelly would be a controversial choice for JPMorgan. And the bank, which is mired
            in investigations into diverse business practices  including by the Federal Bureau of Investigation
             would be a contentious employer for the police commissioner.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Madison Marriage" date="November 3, 2013 5:35 am"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/6790df8a-42ee-11e3-9d3c-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan succumbs to fee pressure</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Charlie Bibby<p>Nordic investors are demanding lower fees</p>]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Camilla Hall and Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="November 1, 2013 2:43 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/4322095c-4277-11e3-9d3c-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>Citigroup and JPMorgan confirm forex investigations</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York and Gina Chon in Washington" date="October 25, 2013 10:52 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/2d25bf64-3db7-11e3-b754-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan to pay $5bn in FHFA deal</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan Chase agreed to pay $5.1bn in a deal with a government housing regulator, resolving a large part
            of the allegations that it mis-sold mortgage-backed securities in the run-up to the financial crisis.</p>
            The announcement by the Federal Housing Finance Agency on Friday ends one part of protracted legal
            negotiations that are expected to see the largest US bank by assets pay $13bn to the US government.
            </p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Kara Scannell in New York" date="October 25, 2013 6:25 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c6c08974-3d8f-11e3-9928-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan settlement move spurs rivals to act</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Global banks have started to approach New York''s attorney-general about paying billions of dollars
            to settle charges they mis-sold mortgage-backed securities that were at the heart of the financial crisis,
            following JPMorgan Chase''s tentative agreement to a $13bn settlement. </p>
            I have already had expressions of interest from other institutions, Eric Schneiderman, New
            York attorney-general, said in an interview with the Financial Times.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Stephen Foley, Tom Braithwaite and Kara Scannell in New York" date="October 22, 2013 11:48 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/5172a7c4-3b64-11e3-87fa-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan nears $6bn settlement with investors</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan Chase is nearing a $6bn settlement with institutional investors to resolve claims it mis-sold
            mortgage-backed securities, according to people familiar with the matter.</p>
            The settlement discussions started almost two years ago but have accelerated recently. They are separate to
            a $13bn deal that the bank has cut with the Department of Justice to resolve US government claims that the
            bank sold MBS riddled with bad loans in the run-up to the financial crisis.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite, Kara Scannell and Camilla Hall" date="October 20, 2013 8:24 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/72a0044c-39ab-11e3-a3a4-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>Opinion divided on JPMorgan settlement</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[The $13bn settlement JPMorgan Chase has agreed to pay to US state and federal authorities has divided
            opinion in the US.</p>
            Much of Wall Street and many of its lawyers believe the government has pulled off a shakedown, using the
            implicit threat of criminal prosecution to rake in billions of dollars. </p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Kara Scannell and Tom Braithwaite" date="October 19, 2013 8:50 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/5b840688-38f6-11e3-a791-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan reaches $13bn deal with US authorities</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>JPMorgan Chase CEO Jamie Dimon testifies before Senate Banking
            Committee</p>]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Kara Scannell and Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="October 18, 2013 10:39 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/caec3cf2-382e-11e3-8668-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan nears $4bn mortgage claims deal</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan Chase is nearing an agreement to pay $4bn to settle allegations by the Federal Housing Finance
            Agency that it mis-sold mortgage-backed securities, according to people familiar with the matter.</p>
            The negotiations between the bank and the housing regulator are part of broader talks to resolve allegations
            of mortgage wrongdoing that also involve the US Department of Justice and Eric Schneiderman, the New York
            attorney-general.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Kara Scannell and Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="October 16, 2013 6:19 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/04a61436-367c-11e3-aaf1-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>CFTC split over JPMorgan whale'' deal</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[The Commodity Futures Trading Commission split over the $100m London whale settlement with
            JPMorgan Chase with one commissioner insisting that the agency should have tried to prove the bank
            intentionally manipulated a key index.</p>
            In settling with the futures regulator on Wednesday, JPMorgan signed an agreement admitting it was reckless
            when it employed a manipulative device in trading $7bn of credit default swaps in early 2012.
            The bank accepted the CFTC''s version of the facts, but did not admit that it violated the law.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite and Kara Scannell in New York" date="October 16, 2013 12:00 am"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/8663088a-35e6-11e3-b539-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan agrees to $100m CFTC fine over London whale''</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan Chase has agreed to pay $100m and accepted its London whale trading episode had a
            manipulative effect on credit derivatives markets in a settlement with the Commodity Futures
            Trading Commission, according to people familiar with the situation.</p>
            The CFTC was noticeably absent from a $920m settlement between the largest US bank and four regulators in
            the US and UK last month. Until recently talks had floundered over the question of whether the bank would
            admit that it manipulated a credit default index known as the IG9 when trading derivatives at the heart of
            the whale debacle.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite and Kara Scannell in New York" date="October 13, 2013 1:07 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/9b2e8954-33e0-11e3-8f1d-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan''s legal burden sends shivers through the industry</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[<p>A substantial part of JPMorgan''s bill is associated with the activities of Bear Stearns and
            Washington Mutual  companies the US government was delighted to see rescued in 2008</p>]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="October 11, 2013 6:29 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/659e0036-3263-11e3-91d2-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan falls to first loss under Dimon</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan Chase fell to its first loss under Jamie Dimon, after being engulfed in a legal and regulatory
            storm that cost the bank $9.2bn in litigation charges in the third quarter.</p>
            It''s very painful for me personally, said Mr Dimon as he announced the end of an
            unrivalled record of profit since becoming chief executive in 2005.</p>
            <h3>JPMorgan and Wells Fargo</h3>]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Gregory Meyer in New York and Neil Hume in London" date="October 9, 2013 10:23 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0bf81518-3118-11e3-b478-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan draws interest in commodities arm</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[More than two dozen parties, including pension funds and trading houses, have expressed interest in
            JPMorgan Chase''s physical commodities operations following the bank''s decision in July to divest
            the business.</p>
            First round offers for the business, one of Wall Street''s biggest traders of cargoes of oil, coal and
            natural gas, are due before the end of the month, according to people familiar with the situation.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Robert Jenkins" date="October 6, 2013 7:59 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a120e2aa-2d03-11e3-8281-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>Has JPMorgan become an argument for breaking up the banks?</headline>
        <body/>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Ellen Kelleher" date="October 6, 2013 4:50 am"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/241487ee-2c5e-11e3-acf4-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan plans to axe 100 of 650 funds</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan Asset Management plans to axe 100 of the 650 funds in its stable of active funds and plough the
            money it saves into the creation of new products.</p>
            The move to cut as much as 15 per cent of its line-up across Asia and the US comes after JPMorgan opted to
            cull 49 of its funds in Europe by the first quarter of next year.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Rachel Sanderson in Milan" date="October 3, 2013 3:04 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/ab5ef6be-2c25-11e3-acf4-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>Italian prosecutors seek trial for JPMorgan</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Kara Scannell and Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="October 3, 2013 8:24 am"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b2f8c0e2-2bd7-11e3-a1b7-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>US judge holds key to JPMorgan settlement</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[U.S. District Court, SDNY]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Robert Budden, Chief Media Correspondent" date="September 26, 2013 5:39 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b57eca9a-26bf-11e3-bbeb-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>Stephanie Flanders to quit BBC for JPMorgan</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Stephanie Flanders, economics editor at the BBC, is leaving the public service broadcaster after 11 years
            to take up a senior role at JPMorgan Asset Management. </p>
            In November, she will become chief market strategist in the UK and Europe for the US investment bank''s
            fund management arm, bringing to an end a career in journalism that has spanned almost two decades. </p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Kara Scannell and Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="September 24, 2013 11:40 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/7fbe7b88-2554-11e3-9b22-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan eyes $4bn pay for peace'' deal</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Kara Scannell, Tom Braithwaite and Tracy Alloway in New York" date="September 19, 2013 7:23 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b13a4c56-2143-11e3-a92a-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>Rebuke makes grim reading for JPMorgan Chase''s Jamie Dimon</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Reuters<p>Jamie Dimon, JPMorgan''s chief executive</p>]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="fer in London" date="September 19, 2013 5:29 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/69328f6c-2121-11e3-8aff-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>UK flexes regulatory muscle with JPMorgan fine</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan Chase''s $920m settlement over its trading fiasco marks the first time that a London
            authority has been at eye''s level with its transatlantic counterparts in handing out painful fines,
            highlighting a much stricter penalty policy. </p>
            Until recently, UK regulators have lagged behind their US peers in terms of the financial pain they
            inflicted, often handing out fines that were a multiple of 10 smaller than their US counterparts. But the
            137.6m levied by the UK''s new Financial Conduct Authority on Thursday ranks second among the
            four simultaneous penalties slapped on JPMorgan. </p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="fer and Lina Saigol" date="September 19, 2013 3:24 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c652396a-211a-11e3-8aff-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>Regulators highlight JPMorgan deficiencies''</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan Chase on Thursday agreed to a $920m fine from US and UK regulators over last year''s London
            whale credit derivative trading fiasco that caused more than $6bn in losses and severely dented the
            bank''s reputation for savvy risk management. </p>
            You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="fer in London" date="September 19, 2013 4:40 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/11ea2dc4-2125-11e3-a92a-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan hit with $920m in fines over whale'' trade</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[US and UK authorities slammed JPMorgan Chase''s senior management for having deprived its
            board of critical information about the London whale trading fiasco and hit the bank with $920m in
            fines.</p>
            You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite and Kara Scannell in New York" date="September 18, 2013 11:27 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/4eeafc46-20ab-11e3-b8c6-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan braced for action over whale''</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan Chase is expected to be accused of failing to provide accurate and timely information on the
            London whale trading fiasco to regulators, investors and its board, in a transatlantic
            enforcement action due to hit the bank on Thursday.</p>
            You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite and Kara Scannell in New York" date="September 17, 2013 11:22 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/1b6961c2-1f9e-11e3-aa36-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>Jamie Dimon memo outlines simplified JPMorgan structure</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[AP<p>Jamie Dimon, chief executive</p>]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Kara Scannell and Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="September 16, 2013 11:21 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/99cc5d72-1f0c-11e3-b80b-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan in talks to pay $800m whale'' fine</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan Chase is in talks to pay at least $800m to settle with securities and bank regulators over the
            $6bn London whale trading loss, but faces additional fines from US derivatives regulators not
            part of the current pact, people familiar with the matter said. </p>
            The largest bank in the US by assets is expected to admit wrongdoing in settlements with the Securities and
            Exchange Commission, Federal Reserve, Office of Comptroller of the Currency and the UK''s Financial
            Conduct Authority, these people added. </p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite and Stephen Foley in New York" date="September 9, 2013 9:31 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a1ac121e-1960-11e3-83b9-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan appoints Michael Neal and Linda Bammann to board</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan Chase appointed two new board members and strengthened the role of its lead independent director
            but failed to satisfy some of the shareholders agitating for improved corporate governance.</p>
            Michael Neal, former chief executive of GE Capital, and Linda Bammann, former deputy chief risk officer of
            JPMorgan, will join the board in the next few months, the bank said on Monday.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Nick Reeve" date="September 8, 2013 7:28 am"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/5e3b09d2-1626-11e3-a57d-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>Fund focus: USA all the way for JPMorgan</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Fund of funds veteran Tony Lanning is looking to the US stock market to drive the performance of his new
            JPMorgan Fusion product range.</p>
            The five multi-manager funds, which avoid buying individual companies and instead focus on buying other
            funds, were launched in March to cater for a variety of risk appetites.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite and Kara Scannell in New York" date="August 29, 2013 4:46 am"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/7eb4677a-1055-11e3-a258-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan hiring probe expands in Asia</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[An expanding investigation into JPMorgan Chase''s hiring practices in Asia has uncovered internal
            documents that link dozens of new employees with specific deals that the bank was trying to win, according
            to people familiar with the situation.</p>
            JPMorgan''s lawyers are turning over information to the US Securities and Exchange Commission and
            Department of Justice as part of a probe into whether the bank hired the family members of influential
            figures in the Chinese government  and elsewhere in Asia  in an effort to win business.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Kara Scannell and Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="August 27, 2013 7:23 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/423ba922-0f27-11e3-ae66-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan woes deepen as US demands $6bn penalty</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[AFP]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite and Kara Scannell in New York" date="August 27, 2013 7:23 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/ee9e943e-0f33-11e3-ae66-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>Regulator battlesthreatentoswampJPMorgan</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[In April, Jamie Dimon, chief executive of JPMorgan Chase, previously the posterchild of resilience in the
            financial crisis and now the target of more lawsuits and investigations than any other bank, warned: We
            expect we will have more regulatory orders to deal with. His prediction has come true in many areas.</p>
            London Whale
            </p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Kara Scannell in New York and Tobias Buck in Madrid" date="August 27, 2013 3:24 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a0bbb1f0-0f17-11e3-8e58-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>Former JPMorgan banker Javier Martin-Artajo arrested in Spain</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Spanish police on Tuesday arrested Javier Martin-Artajo, the former JPMorgan Chase banker accused of
            hiding hundreds of millions of dollars in losses from the London whale trade, Spain''s
            interior ministry said.</p>
            The arrest comes just 10 days after US authorities charged Mr Martin-Artajo and Julien Grout, a junior bank
            employee, with falsifying bank records by artificially inflating the value of derivative trades to avoid
            losses.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="August 26, 2013 10:46 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b791bd58-0e85-11e3-bfc8-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>Len Blavatnik wins $50m in JPMorgan lawsuit</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>Len Blavatnik, joint defendant with Viktor Vekselberg in action brought by Leonid
            Lebedev</p>]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Kara Scannell and Tracy Alloway in New York" date="August 21, 2013 12:02 am"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/affd3638-09e6-11e3-bc4e-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan hires top law firm over Hong Kong probe</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan Chase has hired a venerable New York law firm to conduct an internal investigation into its
            hiring practices in Hong Kong as the bank struggles to understand the potential depth of the issue. </p>
            Paul, Weiss, Rifkind, Wharton Garrison was retained by the bank, people familiar with the matter said, to
            respond to the Securities and Exchange Commission''s inquiry into the bank''s hiring of a son of a
            former Chinese banking regulator and daughter of a Chinese railway official. </p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tracy Alloway in New York" date="August 20, 2013 7:41 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a90054a4-09a6-11e3-ad07-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan pledges to clean up legal woes</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[When JPMorgan Chase emerged from the financial crisis as one of the stronger banks left in the US
            financial industry, the list of legal proceedings it published as part of its quarterly regulatory filings
            ran to two pages. Fast forward five years and that list has jumped to a startling 10 pages long.</p>
            The bank, now the second-biggest in the US by market capitalisation, has been inundated by a string of
            recent regulatory investigations, ranging from continued fallout over the $6bn London Whale
            trading loss it incurred last year to a new criminal probe related to the sale of mortgage-backed securities
            before the financial crisis.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Sam Fleming and Philip Stafford" date="September 11, 2014 12:18 am"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/48aa6b02-38f9-11e4-9526-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan tells clearers to build bigger buffers</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Clearing houses  which guarantee the smooth completion of financial transactions ranging from
            derivatives trades to commodities deals  should be required to line up larger financial buffers to
            prevent triggering a future market disaster, a top investment bank has argued. </p>
            JPMorgan Chase is to warn in a forthcoming paper that the current system for dealing with failing clearing
            houses is brittle and opaque, and requires a new resolution framework to tackle major failures. </p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Martin Arnold, Banking Editor" date="August 12, 2014 2:05 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/840e0692-2213-11e4-ad60-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>Sir Win Bischoff to take chairman role at JPMorgan Securities</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Charlie Bibby]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Henny Sender in New York" date="July 28, 2014 2:00 am"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a7392562-15ab-11e4-ae2e-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>Sankaty to buy JPMorgan debt portfolio for $1bn</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Sankaty Advisors, the credit arm of Bain Capital, is paying more than $1bn for the debt portfolio of
            JPMorgan''s principal investment group.</p>
            The sale underscores the extent to which shadow banks are taking over lucrative parts of the operations of
            big commercial banks, which are under pressure to raise capital and play down certain activities to meet new
            Basel requirements and regulatory constraints.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Camilla Hall in New York" date="July 15, 2014 4:53 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/9f00e4aa-0c0c-11e4-a096-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>Dimon reassures investors on cancer as JPMorgan beats estimates</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[EPA]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Josh Noble in Hong Kong" date="July 10, 2014 4:59 am"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/eb932114-07e0-11e4-8e62-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan picks David Li to head probe-hit China division</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Caroline Binham, Legal Correspondent" date="July 6, 2014 1:54 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/32daf9ee-038a-11e4-817f-00144feab7de.html">
        <headline>Ex-JPMorgan trader challenges whale'' findings</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[A former JPMorgan Chase trader who faces US criminal charges in the wake of the $6bn London whale
            debacle is challenging civil findings made against the bank by the UK financial watchdog.</p>
            Julien Grout, a French national who worked as a junior credit-derivatives trader at the time of the $6bn
            loss that rocked the bank in 2012, has filed an appeal with a London tribunal taking issue with the UK
            Financial Conduct Authority''s findings against JPMorgan that were part of the bank''s $1bn
            settlement with US and UK authorities last year, according to tribunal records.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Jamil Anderlini in Beijing and Tom Braithwaite in New York" date="May 21, 2014 4:39 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/d62272be-e0f6-11e3-875f-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>Former JPMorgan China banker questioned in HK</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[AFP]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Caroline Binham, Legal Correspondent" date="May 20, 2014 3:21 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c4513c82-e024-11e3-b709-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>London coroner rules JPMorgan manager''s death was suicide</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Reuters<p>William Magee, father of JPMorgan technology expert Gabriel Magee, speaks outside
            Poplar coroner''s court on Tuesday</p>]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Sam Fleming" date="May 12, 2014 10:39 am"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/cee218c0-d9b1-11e3-920f-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>Former Italian finance chief Vittorio Grilli to join JPMorgan</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>Vittorio Grilli, former Italian finance minister</p>]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in New York, John Paul Rathbone in London and Gina Chon in Washington"
           date="May 6, 2014 5:42 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/3a8f975c-d523-11e3-adec-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan shuts foreign diplomats'' accounts</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>Colombia''s former finance minister Jose Antonio Ocampo</p>]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="fer in London and Richard Milne in Oslo" date="May 4, 2014 5:18 pm"
           url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/d3b8f83a-d224-11e3-8b5b-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>Citi wins Norway fund business from JPMorgan</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[Citigroup has been chosen to safeguard the securities of the world''s biggest sovereign wealth fund
            after wooing away one of the largest custodian mandates from its rival JPMorgan.</p>
            The transfer of the Norwegian oil fund''s $865bn portfolio to its US competitor is a setback for
            JPMorgan, which is one of the top three competitors in the rapidly growing custodian business. </p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Henny Sender and Tom Braithwaite in New York and Jamil Anderlini in Beijing"
           date="April 18, 2014 6:36 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e622de5e-c70d-11e3-889e-00144feabdc0.html">
        <headline>JPMorgan''s head of China Zili Shao moved to fresh role</headline>
        <body><![CDATA[JPMorgan Chase''s head of China is stepping down from the role after a controversial five years
            running a unit that is now mired in the princeling scandal roiling the largest US bank by
            assets.</p>
            Zili Shao''s move from head of China to vice-chairman of Asia Pacific was announced hastily by the bank
            on Friday after enquiries from the Financial Times.</p>
        ]]> </body>
    </entry>
</news>