
<news><entry author="By David Gelles in New York and Chris Nuttall in San Francisco" date="June 4, 2013 6:06 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/44801106-cd18-11e2-90e8-00144feab7de.html"><headline>IBM and Salesforce strike cloud computing deals</headline><body /></entry><entry author="By Andrew Edgecliffe-Johnson in New York" date="May 17, 2013 5:25 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/fec143bc-bf05-11e2-a9d4-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Bloomberg names ex-IBM chief to lead independent review</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David Gelles in New York" date="May 1, 2013 11:42 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/63a50a6a-b2a5-11e2-a388-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Price scuppers IBM server sale to Lenovo</headline><body><![CDATA[A deal that would have seen IBM sell parts of its server business to Chinese computer maker Lenovo has broken down on Tuesday night, according to people familiar with the matter. </p>
Talks between the two companies emerged last month, sending shares of Lenovo up 9 per cent. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tim Bradshaw in San Francisco and David Gelles in New York" date="April 18, 2013 9:41 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/8929551e-a866-11e2-b031-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>IBM vows action following rare miss</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By April Dembosky in San Francisco" date="March 13, 2013 4:38 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/baaabe36-8b90-11e2-b1a4-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>IBM eyes big data'' help for brain injury</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM has begun developing data analysis technology to improve the treatment of traumatic brain injury, the latest move in the company''s broader effort to apply its big data software to the healthcare sector.</p>
In partnership with doctors at Ronald Reagan UCLA Medical Center, IBM scientists are mining and analysing huge streams of patient data in order to predict the kind of brain swelling that leads to cognitive damage or death.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By April Dembosky in San Francisco" date="January 24, 2013 7:28 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/aa0a92a8-6652-11e2-b967-00144feab49a.html"><headline>IBM develops gel to fight infections</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM has developed a new antimicrobial gel designed to fight drug-resistant, hospital-acquired infections by replicating the science it uses to produce semiconductors. </p>
Using similar materials that allow for the swift transfer of computing messages, IBM scientists are developing a gel that kills microbes  including those that cause the kinds of intractable staph infections that vex medical experts. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chris Nuttall in San Francisco" date="January 22, 2013 10:05 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e58fd0e8-64dd-11e2-934b-00144feab49a.html"><headline>IBM targeted expansion pays off</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM reported fourth-quarter revenues and profits ahead of Wall Street expectations as its shift to a more software-driven business began to bear fruit.</p>
Revenues of $29.3bn beat an analyst consensus of $29.1bn and earnings per share of $5.39 were ahead of Wall Street expectations of $5.25. For the full year, earnings per share were up 13 per cent on 2011 at $15.25 and ahead of guidance of $15.10. The company expects this to rise to at least $16.70 in 2013, ahead of the consensus of $16.63.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By April Dembosky in San Francisco" date="October 17, 2012 12:47 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/2c1258ca-17d5-11e2-9530-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Currency moves trim IBM revenues</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM reported a drop in sales for the third quarter but increased earnings per share by 10 per cent, beating Wall Street estimates by a penny.</p>
The fall in revenues, down 5 per cent on the same period last year to $24.7bn and below analysts''s expectations, sent the company''s stock down 3.4 per cent in after-hours trading. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Paul Taylor" date="October 9, 2012 8:11 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/4b425952-122b-11e2-b9fd-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>AT&amp;T and IBM launch secure cloud service</headline><body><![CDATA[Despite the cost and flexibility advantages of cloud computing, some companies have held back from using remote cloud-based services because of concerns over transmitting sensitive data over public networks, and many businesses cite security as a key inhibitor to cloud computing adoption.</p>
To address this issue, ATT, the largest US telecommunications group, and IBM plan to offer a highly secure, first-of-its-kind network-enabled cloud service that uses private networks and virtual private network technology rather than the public internet.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Arash Massoudi in New York" date="September 12, 2012 12:18 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/46148a30-fc60-11e1-aef9-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Knight Capital hires IBM after $440m glitch</headline><body><![CDATA[Knight Capital
 has hired IBM to review its product development process after a software glitch caused the electronic trading and brokerage company to suffer a $440m loss last month that left it on the brink of bankruptcy. </p>
The company will also create a new chief risk officer position, according to Thomas Joyce, chief executive, who was speaking at a financial services conference in New York on Tuesday. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David Gelles and Paul Taylor in New York" date="August 27, 2012 6:51 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/ab812884-f057-11e1-b7b2-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>IBM in social business push with Kenexa deal</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM has joined the wave of enterprise technology companies buying into the social business software industry with a $1.3bn deal to acquire Kenexa, a cloud computing recruitment company.</p>
The all cash deal, for $46 per share, will see IBM pay a 42 per cent premium for Kenexa, the Wayne, Pennsylvania-based company which makes cloud-based software designed to help companies recruit and manage talent through online social networking, collaboration and consulting tools.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Vivianne Rodrigues in New York" date="July 25, 2012 11:38 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/dbb26932-d667-11e1-ba60-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Record low cost for IBM debt issue</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM, the computer services company known as a savvy borrower, has raised debt at a record low cost as rock-bottom US interest rates continue to benefit large US corporations.</p>
Companies including 3M and McDonald''s this year have set new lows for corporate bond rates as US Treasury yields, the benchmark for this type of debt, have fallen to historic lows. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="July 18, 2012 11:55 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/721e3122-d117-11e1-8a3c-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>IBM hurt by currency shifts and weak demand</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM''s revenues slid by 3 per cent in its latest quarter as weak economic conditions in the developed world and foreign currency headwinds weighed on its performance.</p>
But earnings topped forecasts as Big Blue benefited from rising profit margins in its global services unit, and the company raised its full-year earnings forecast. The news was enough to extend a stock price rally that had been felt across the technology sector earlier in the day, adding a further 3 per cent to the company''s share price in after-market trading.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Vivianne Rodrigues and Nicole Bullock in New York" date="May 8, 2012 11:21 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/45d3762e-9916-11e1-9da3-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>IBM gets record low rate for US debt</headline><body><![CDATA[
IBM, the computer services group with a reputation for taking advantage of cheap borrowing costs, set a new low at a US debt sale when it sold $600m in seven-year debt with a coupon of 1.875 per cent.</p>
Dealogic, the research group, said the sale was at the lowest interest rate for bonds of that maturity issued in dollars. IBM also issued $900m in three-year notes with a coupon of 0.75 per cent.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Paul Taylor" date="April 26, 2012 11:06 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/9a3f9220-8fe7-11e1-98b1-00144feab49a.html"><headline>IBM moves to tackle big data''</headline><body><![CDATA[Big data  the use of the huge volumes of information generated by companies and other organisations to improve forecasting, spot trends and opportunities or detect fraud  is one of the hottest subjects in corporate computing and it has begun to attract the attention of the major enterprise software providers.</p>
As the price of the hardware needed to store and crunch this data has fallen, business software suppliers including IBM have begun to focus on the software needed to detect patterns and trends in the data generated by their IT networks, point-of-sales (POS) systems and external sources.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters and Chris Nuttall in San Francisco" date="April 17, 2012 11:59 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/dbac6ca2-88cf-11e1-9b8d-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Intel and IBM quarterly results impress</headline><body><![CDATA[Intel and IBM each topped earnings expectations in the first quarter despite weak demand in some parts of their developed-world operations, while also issuing stronger revenue forecasts for the rest of the year.</p>
However, shares in the technology industry bellwethers, both of which had seen strong rallies since the start of the year, fell back by more than 2 per cent in after-market trading as investors waited for clearer evidence that revived growth was taking hold.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="April 6, 2012 9:03 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/73eb8e60-800d-11e1-b4a8-00144feab49a.html"><headline>IBM chief hits glass ceiling in Augusta</headline><body><![CDATA[Three months after rising to one of the top jobs in corporate America, Ginni Rometty
is this weekend coming to terms with a glass ceiling she has been unable to break: membership of Augusta National, the male-only club where the Masters golf tournament reaches its climax on Sunday.</p>
The failure to offer membership to the new chief executive of IBM, the event''s chief sponsor, is a snub that critics say will rebound badly on both the club and the computer company itself, should it fail to take a stand over the issue.</p>
The omission comes despite growing public attention, which late this week included mild rebukes from President Barack Obama and Mitt Romney, his probable Republican rival in November''s election, both of whom seized on the issue as a chance to woo female voters. His personal opinion is that women should be admitted, said Jay Carney, White House spokesman.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By April Dembosky in San Francisco" date="January 19, 2012 11:52 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/ed3fdde2-42f6-11e1-b756-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Software and services drive IBM profits</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM reported fourth-quarter revenues below analysts'' expectations, but still beat forecast profits because of strong margins in its software and services businesses.</p>
Revenues were $29.5bn for the quarter, up 1.6 per cent from the same quarter last year, but missing Wall Street''s anticipated $29.73.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dan McCrum and Johanna Kassel in New York and Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="November 14, 2011 11:08 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/40ae6e94-0ecc-11e1-b83c-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Buffett reveals $10.7bn stake in IBM</headline><body><![CDATA[
Berkshire Hathaway has taken a stake in IBM worth more than $10bn, its first big investment in a sector historically shunned by Warren Buffett.</p>
In a CNBC interview on Monday, the 81-year-old billionaire disclosed that he had secretly amassed a 5.5 per cent stake worth $10.7bn in the US information technology company since March.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters" date=" October 26, 2011 7:52 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/7ac12a42-ffe8-11e0-8441-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Rometty''s rise suggests convergence for IBM</headline><body><![CDATA[Technology companies aren''t, first and foremost, about the technology any more.</p>
That was the lesson from Steve Jobs'' remarkable career at Apple. And it is the unmistakable message from the rise of Ginni Rometty, who has just been anointed as the next chief executive of IBM.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco and Anjli Raval in New York" date="October 26, 2011 9:22 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/c22369d2-ff4c-11e0-9769-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>IBM names Rometty as next chief executive</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM has named Virginia Rometty to succeed Sam Palmisano as its chief executive from the start of next year, making her the first female leader in the 100-year history of the US computing giant and one of only a handful of women to head a large US corporation.</p>
Currently head of sales, marketing and strategy, Ms Rometty is also the first head of IBM not to have run part of its traditional hardware business. At one time she headed the business services unit that accounts for around a third of IBM''s total services division, but has otherwise spent her 30-year career at the company mainly in sales and marketing roles.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chris Nuttall in San Francisco" date="October 18, 2011 12:26 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/9071db88-f90e-11e0-9d4e-00144feab49a.html"><headline>IBM shares fall 4% on flat revenues</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM''s flat performance in major markets and concerns about how poor economic conditions and currency shifts might affect its fourth quarter drove down shares of the technology group.</p>
The shares fell nearly 4 per cent to $179.48 in extended trading in New York on the news, in spite of strong third-quarter growth in emerging markets for the company </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Barker in Brussels" date="September 20, 2011 7:14 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/c2b721e8-e397-11e0-8990-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>IBM offers concessions to EU on mainframes</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM has moved closer to settling a year-long probe by European regulators into its mainframe computer businesses, offering a series of concessions that could spare the US group from a fine.</p>
European Union competition authorities opened two separate antitrust investigations into IBM''s mainframe business last year, examining whether the group was exploiting its dominance in maintenance services or tying hardware to its mainframe operating system.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Maija Palmer and Philip Stafford" date="September 1, 2011 12:25 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/2540eea8-d479-11e0-a42b-00144feab49a.html"><headline>IBM buys Algorithmics for $387m</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM on Thursday said it would buy Algorithmics, a Canadian risk analysis group, in a $387m deal, laying the ground for a new push into assessing risk on behalf of financial services companies. </p>
The acquisition of the Toronto-based company comes a day after the US business and software services group announced a deal to buy the UK''s i2, which provides pattern recognition software for police forces and the military.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Maija Palmer, Technology Correspondent" date="August 31, 2011 7:25 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/1e8e4d60-d3f9-11e0-b7eb-00144feab49a.html"><headline>IBM buys UK crime analytics company i2</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM joined the rush for big data acquisitions on Wednesday when it announced a deal to buy i2, a Cambridge-based company that helps police forces and the military analyse vast amounts of security information. </p>
The deal follows the $11bn acquisition of Autonomy, another Cambridge software company, by Hewlett-Packard in August, and is a further sign of technology companies building up their abilities to sift through large amounts of data. Thanks to the internet and the almost unlimited ability to store computer documents, companies are now faced with a tide of information but struggle to make sense of it. There is a high demand for software that helps organise and search this data. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Barker in Brussels and Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="August 3, 2011 10:39 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/e88e164c-bdf4-11e0-ab9f-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>IBM pressure eases after complaints dropped</headline><body><![CDATA[Antitrust pressures on IBM in Europe eased following news that the three companies whose complaints prompted a European Commission investigation into the US group''s mainframe computer business have dropped their protests.</p>
Although the Commission still has the power to press ahead with both of its probes into IBM, one of which was prompted by the complaints, the decision to withdraw grievances raises the chance of IBM being handed a reprieve in at least one of the cases.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By April Dembosky in San Francisco" date="July 19, 2011 12:59 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/d2ebb3b4-b186-11e0-af96-00144feab49a.html"><headline>IBM lifts profit forecast after sales jump</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM raised its earnings forecast for the year as it reported a 12 per cent surge in second-quarter revenues, surpassing Wall Street expectations.</p>
In the second quarter, our long-term strategic investments in the company''s growth initiatives again helped drive strong revenue performance, said Samuel Palmisano, IBM chief executive, on Monday. Hardware, software and services revenue grew at double digits, and we achieved strong profit and free cash flow growth.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chris Nuttall and Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="April 20, 2011 12:51 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/7abe179a-6adc-11e0-9744-00144feab49a.html"><headline>IT spending rebound lifts Intel and IBM</headline><body><![CDATA[The computing industry has benefited this year from an unexpected rebound in business spending on information technology in the developed world and continued rapid growth in the emerging markets, according to figures released by some of the industry''s leading names late on Tuesday.</p>
The earnings reports from Intel and IBM flew in the face of concerns that sagging consumer spending, flatter PC markets and disruption to supply chains from the disaster in Japan would dent a tech recovery. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Simon Mundy" date="March 20, 2011 10:35 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b84b1ea6-50cd-11e0-9227-00144feab49a.html"><headline>IBM and C&amp;W team up on smart meters</headline><body><![CDATA[The race to provide millions of smart energy meters to UK households has widened with the announcement of a collaboration between IBM and Cable  Wireless Worldwide.</p>
The partnership, to be announced on Monday, pits the companies against rivals including BT, Vodafone and Telefnica O2 UK, which have already unveiled plans to service Britain''s planned smart energy grid. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joseph Menn in San Francisco" date="March 18, 2011 10:22 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/63265324-51ad-11e0-888e-00144feab49a.html"><headline>IBM to pay $10m in SEC bribery case</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM agreed to pay $10m to settle charges by the US Securities and Exchange Commission that it bribed South Korean and Chinese officials to win government contracts. </p>
The SEC accused IBM of multiple violations of the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act in Korea and China in a civil complaint made public on Friday. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="March 13, 2011 9:48 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/27bb8b0e-4db8-11e0-85e4-00144feab49a.html"><headline>IBM lays down challenge to rival</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM is years ahead of rival Hewlett-Packard in building the integrated software and services business needed in a modern IT company, according to one of the top lieutenants to Sam Palmisano, IBM chief executive.</p>
Mike Daniels, head of IBM''s services division and a leading contender to succeed Mr Palmisano, threw down the challenge ahead of a key HP strategy session on Monday in which Lo Apotheker, HP''s new chief, is due to lay out his plans for the company. While Mr Apotheker has made it clear that he plans to boost HP''s presence in software, the IBM executive suggested that focusing on building individual divisions would not be enough to put HP level.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alan Cane" date="January 25, 2011 4:10 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/694c342c-274a-11e0-80d7-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Perspectives: IBM lasts out its stormy century</headline><body><![CDATA[What, goes the familiar business school question is the primary purpose of a business? No, it''s not to make a profit or provide a handsome return for its shareholders, although those are pertinent to the correct answer, which is: to stay in business.</p>
By those lights, International Business Machines, which celebrates its centenary on June 16, is in a class by itself among information technology companies as the only enterprise with roots in the 19th century (the Bundy Manufacturing Company, a distant ancestor, was incorporated in 1889) still extant.</p>
Actually, the company could have chosen any one of a number of dates to celebrate. The one it has picked is the date IBM''s predecessor company Computing-Tabulating-Recording (CTR) was incorporated.</p>
There will be various elements to the celebratory package  a day of service to local communities, academic colloquia and a commemoration of icons of progress among them. The date is something of a surprise.</p>
In the past the company has tended to favour May 14 1914, when Thomas Watson Senior, the man behind IBM''s early success, was appointed CTR general manager. The change of name to IBM took place on February 14 1924. And I''ve always felt there is a case for April 7 1964, the launch of System/360 which heralded the true beginning of the age of business computing, with the availability of a range of compatible hardware and software.</p>
What has given IBM such extraordinary longevity?</p>
Not only has it remained at the forefront, if no longer actually the leader, of the data processing industry for most of its existence, but it has weathered storms that would have destroyed a lesser company  the longest antitrust suite in US legal history and, at the time, the largest single-year corporate loss in US business history.</p>
The corporation lost almost $16bn between 1991 and 1993 after failing to understand the importance of personal computing and client-server systems.</p>
Its survival, in retrospect, seems to have been thanks to three, or four, key attributes.</p>
First, a powerful sense of corporate culture and identity stemming from practices introduced by Thomas Watson Senior, including sales incentives, attention to customer service and an insistence on a smartly dressed, disciplined sales force.</p>
It is easy to sneer now at the songs, corporate band and so on, that were designed to give staff a sense of pride in IBM, but they worked.</p>
Second, an extensive, well-established and mostly faithful customer base.</p>
System/360 fast became the de facto industry standard architecture for business mainframes. It was followed by System/370 which, while not such an innovation, found favour in the marketplace.</p>
By 1990, revenues were almost $70bn and progress to the $100bn mark seemed unstoppable.</p>
That was before IBM fumbled the PC/client-server trends and started to report the kind of losses that led some to wonder if the company could survive as a single entity.</p>
Few other companies could have withstood such thumping losses.</p>
IBM executives knew the writing was on the wall, however, and demonstrated a third survival strategy  a willingness to change rapidly.</p>
A new chief executive, Louis Gerstner, was hired from outside and IBM began its move from computer company to computing services behemoth, incorporating, along the way, the consulting arm of PwC.</p>
A fourth key element, I believe, was its insistence on continuing to invest heavily in research and development, which has guaranteed it is still among the leaders in the kind of complex software that will run the businesses of tomorrow and it is still a leader in supercomputers.</p>
IBM probably deserved many of the brickbats thrown at it over the decades, but has proved its durability.</p>
Today''s business environment is in constant flux, but the attributes that enabled it to survive the past century should see it enjoying a few more anniversaries.</p>
It remains to be seen if any of its present competitors will fare as well.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="January 18, 2011 11:38 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/e1410b18-235a-11e0-8389-00144feab49a.html"><headline>IBM results surge past forecasts</headline><body><![CDATA[A surge in sales from its traditional mainframe hardware business helped IBM top financial forecasts for the final months of last year
, capping a steady progression that saw it emerge as one of the technology world''s most consistent performers during and after the recent recession.</p>
Signs of a broader pick-up in demand from IT buyers, which IBM said it expected to see continue this year, also cheered investors, who pushed the company''s shares up by nearly 3 per cent in after-market trading.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Nikki Tait in Brussels and Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="December 3, 2010 10:19 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/0fe173d8-ff19-11df-956b-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Microsoft buys stake in IBM accuser</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft has made an investment in TurboHercules, a small French software company whose complaint of anticompetitive business practices against IBM helped to stir up a European investigation into the US computer group.</p>
News that the world''s biggest software company has backed a company at the centre of a dispute involving a rival is likely to be watched with interest in Brussels, given a wider pattern that has emerged in investigations involving the technology industry.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Watersin San Francisco" date="November 24, 2010 6:53 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c3e888ba-e521-11df-8e0d-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>IBM in cloud strategy revamp</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM has overhauled its strategy for cloud computing, which involves selling computing services from centralised data centres, in the latest attempt to kickstart a business that it hopes will become a mainstay over the long term.</p>
The move reflects a broader rethink by the tech industry as it tries to make one of the most talked-about IT trends more palatable to large business customers, who have so far held back from cloud computing.</p>
In its latest revamp, IBM said it would sell cloud computing through its services division, which generates nearly 60 per cent of its revenues. </p>
Rather than try to encourage companies to hand all their data to IBM to be stored and processed, the company said it planned to sell individual services from its data centres that could be integrated into a company''s existing IT systems. </p>
We''re trying to play to our strengths, said Mike Daniels, head of IBM''s services division. </p>
The move would leave companies in control of their IT, but was meant to bring greater flexibility and lower cost by standardising particular parts of their processes, he said. </p>
The repositioning echoed IBM''s big strategic shift in the early 1990s, when it first turned to services as a way to protect itself from disruptive changes in the computer hardware business, said Frank Gens, an analystat IDC.</p>
IBM has been through near-death experiences in the past  they''ve worked out that they need to beat the leading edge [of change], but also at the high-value end of the spectrum, he said. </p>
Selling through the services division would giveit an edge over techcompanies that lack a similar capability, and help avoid the commoditisation already coming to some aspects of cloud computing, he added.</p>
As the largest tech company selling mainly to large business and government customers, IBM has made several attempts to build a business around cloud computing, but executives concede these have yet to gain much of a foothold.</p>
Differences of opinioninternally over the direction IBM should take has complicated the search for a comprehensive strategy.</p>
There were as many views as there were people, said Erich Clementi, who was given the job two years ago of setting the company''s cloud computing direction. 
</p>
IBM''s move echoes a wider rethink by tech groups such as Microsoft, as they try to turn cloud computing into a mainstream business. </p>
This year, Microsoft revamped its strategy by selling a new version of Windows Azure, an operating system designed for its own data centres, direct to companies to run their own systems on. </p>
It is going to become an important part of [IBM''s] services business, and over 10 years it''s going to become the dominant part, Mr Gens said. </p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="October 31, 2010 9:33 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/516e15b6-e526-11df-8e0d-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>IBM revamps cloud strategy</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM has overhauled its strategy for cloud computing, which involves selling computing services from centralised data centres, in the latest attempt to kickstart a business that it hopes will become a mainstay over the long term.</p>
The move reflects a broader rethink by the technology industry as it tries to make one of the most talked-about IT trends more palatable to large business customers, which have so far held back from cloud computing.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hannah Kuchler in New York" date="October 19, 2010 10:12 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/3dd2d77c-db89-11df-ae99-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Apple and IBM lead retreat after earnings disappoint</headline><body><![CDATA[Apple
 and IBM
 weighed on US equities after disappointing earnings reports forced their shares to retreat from Monday''s all-time highs.</p>
Both beat analysts'' earnings expectations but their shares fell after statements from the technology groups left the market unsatisfied.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="October 19, 2010 2:28 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/6a639728-db0b-11df-a870-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>IBM plays down decline of contracts'' value</headline><body><![CDATA[A continued decline in the value of new services contracts signed by IBM in its latest quarter left a shadow over otherwise solid earnings and added to lingering unease on Wall Street about the durability of this year''s slow recovery in the information technology industry.</p>
IBM third-quarter results to September 30 2010
Sales
Net profit
Earnings per share
Dividend
$24.3bn
$3.6bn
$2.82
-
 3%
 12%
 18%
-

]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Vijay Govindarajan and Chris Trimble" date="September 29, 2010 11:17 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c114f762-cc0e-11df-bd28-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Case study: IBM''s reputation for innovation</headline><body><![CDATA[

<p>The business is defined by innovation and cuting-edge technology</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Braithwaite in Washington" date="September 22, 2010 2:09 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/98c2f146-c5d4-11df-b53e-00144feab49a.html"><headline>IBM warns of threat to organic growth</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM could have to hold off on acquisitions and see its organic growth stunted if it is included on a list of major derivatives users, the technology group''s director of global funding said.</p>
Large companies in the US are lobbying hard to escape being designated major swap participants by regulators implementing the Dodd-Frank financial reform act. Such a designation will require companies to post margin against derivatives trades.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chris Nuttall in San Francisco" date="September 20, 2010 7:09 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/a568b96c-c4df-11df-9134-00144feab49a.html"><headline>IBM to buy Netezza for $1.7bn in cash</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM on Monday announced an agreement to buy Massachusetts-based Netezza Corporation for $1.7bn in cash, in a deal which adds to recent deal-making momentum in business software and services.</p>
An acquisition by the US technology group of the data warehousing and business analytics company would follow Hewlett-Packard''s victory over Dell this month in the battle to acquire storage technology company 3Par for $2.4bn.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jean Eaglesham in New York" date="September 13, 2010 10:55 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/62df1764-bf6f-11df-965a-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Ex-IBM executive jailed in Galleon case</headline><body><![CDATA[A former senior executive at IBM was sentenced to six months in prison after pleading guilty to charges arising from the Galleon hedge fund insider trading probe.</p>
Robert Moffat, 54, a former senior vice-president of IBM, admitted in March that he provided insider information to Danielle Chiesi, then a consultant at New Castle Partners, an equity hedge fund unit of Bear Stearns Asset Management. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco and Nikki Tait in Brussels" date="July 26, 2010 10:15 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/a660764c-98ee-11df-9418-00144feab49a.html"><headline>IBM hits out at Microsoft over review</headline><body><![CDATA[Behind the formal complaints from small technology companies and trade associations that are often the trigger to antitrust reviews in Brussels, a power game is being played out between some of the industry''s leading household names.</p>
That struggle broke out into the open on Monday as IBM accused Microsoft of orchestrating a campaign against it.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Nikki Tait in Brussels and Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="July 27, 2010 3:35 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/5960b57a-98ba-11df-a0b7-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Brussels to probe IBM mainframe market role</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM on Monday became the latest big US technology group to come under attack from Europe''s top antitrust watchdog with officials at the European Commission launching a formal probe into its behaviour in the multibillion-dollar market for mainframe computers.</p>
The Commission  which has fought long battles with Microsoft and Intel and is also taking a preliminary look at issues surrounding Google  said it was opening two separate cases against IBM.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="July 20, 2010 12:29 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/38bcc114-9375-11df-bb9a-00144feab49a.html"><headline>IBM sales to businesses disappoint investors</headline><body><![CDATA[The recovery in business spending on technology, a key driver of broader economic growth, is taking hold more slowly than many investors had hoped, according to quarterly figures released by IBM on Monday.</p>
Optimism about a quicker rebound was stoked last week by strong earnings from Intel. The chipmaker put its performance down to demand fromcorporate customers, which account for the lion''s share of spending on technology.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Maija Palmer, technology correspondent" date="June 3, 2010 1:04 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/96181994-6efe-11df-a2f7-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>IBM joins chipmakers to boost Linux platform</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM has joined forces with chip companies Arm, Freescale, Samsung, ST-Ericsson and Texas Instruments, to create a company that will accelerate the development of Linux software for devices such as mobile phones, tablet computers and digital televisions. </p>
The move is a challenge to Intel and Microsoft, which are looking to move beyond their dominance of the personal computing market to take a large share of the mobile phone and hybrid device market. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="May 25, 2010 3:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/13efd8ae-6796-11df-a932-00144feab49a.html"><headline>IBM in $1.4bn move for software unit</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM yesterday mounted its biggest acquisition since 2007 as it reversed course and moved back into business-to-business software six years after quitting the market.</p>Big Blue agreed to pay $1.4bn in cash to buy Sterling Commerce from ATT, the US telecommunications company that has owned it for the past decade.</p>Analysts suggested the deal could spark a resurgence of interest among other big software companies in the once-hot "B2B" business, which briefly turned start-ups such as Sterling into some of the hottest properties at the peak of the dotcom bubble.</p>SBC Communications, a predecessor of ATT, paid $3.9bn for Sterling in early 2000. At the time, companies that operated networks that automated transactions between companies were seen as a key piece of the new business architecture taking shape on the web, as companies moved to make their supply chains more efficient.</p>However, IBM quit the business in the middle of the decade after it concluded that B2B networks were becoming a commodity service and profit margins would come under pressure, said Ken Vollmer, a principal analyst at Forrester Research.</p>Sterling claims to handle more than 1bn transactions a year on behalf of 1,800 customers round the world. These range from manufacturers buying raw materials and retailers replenishing stock to banks swapping data about financial transactions.</p>Explaining IBM''s change of stance on the B2B market after its earlier retreat, Kareem Yusuf, an executive in the company''s software division, said: "It was a very different marketplace."</p>Companies now rely far more heavily on linking their business processes to suppliers, customers and other partners, and IBM itself has a wider range of software to take advantage of owning a business like Sterling, he said. IBM added that Sterling sold a wider range of technology than the pure data exchange service that it sold in 2004.</p>The IBM purchase comes as GXS, the largest company in the B2B network business, is waiting for regulatory approval for its own proposed acquisition of the third-largest B2B network company, Inovis, which would further cement its lead over number two player Sterling.</p>With greater consolidation in the business, and IBM betting on closer integration of transaction processing with other parts of corporate systems, rivals such as Oracle and Hewlett-Packard are likely to feel pressure to make B2B acquisitions of their own, said Mr Vollmer. ATT said it expected a $750m pre-tax profit from the deal.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="May 24, 2010 6:55 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/83b80c36-675c-11df-a932-00144feab49a.html"><headline>IBM in $1.4bn move for software unit</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM on Monday mounted its biggest acquisition since 2007 as it reversed course and moved back into business-to-business software six years after quitting the market.</p>
Big Blue agreed to pay $1.4bn in cash to buy Sterling Commerce from ATT, the US telecommunications company that has owned it for the past decade.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David Gelles and Chris Nuttall in San Francisco" date="May 13, 2010 3:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/8fcee812-5e26-11df-8153-00144feab49a.html"><headline>IBM sets out bold buying strategy</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM will spend $20bn on acquisitions over the next five years, Sam Palmisano, chief executive, said yesterday.</p>
"In five years we will spend more in acquisition than we did in the previous 10," Mr Palmisano told analysts gathered for the company''s investor day.</p>
IBM has already stepped up the pace of acquisitions in recent months.</p>
During the first quarter it spent $1bn in cash, buying mostly smaller companies and putting it on track for the $4bn a year it would need to spend to hit Mr Palmisano''s target.</p>
Acquiring new companies would provide IBM with additional paths to growth, good news for a company whose core businesses of consulting and software are largely matured.</p>
Software, analytics and software as a service (SAAS) are expected to be a focus of IBM''s buying spree.</p>
The company talked about its evolving "cloud" strategy at its annual software conference in Las Vegas last week. Its customers are showing more interest in having their applications and services run remotely for them over the web - so-called cloud computing.</p>
Last week, it bought privately held Cast Iron Systems to help integrate different cloud applications and service providers.</p>
A buying spree would also relieve IBM of the more than $14bn in cash and marketable securities it had amassed in recent years.</p>
Other large tech companies, including Microsoft, Cisco and Oracle, have also hoarded cash through the downturn.</p>
Mr Palmisano said the aggressive buying strategy would be made possible by what he expected to be "at least $20" earnings per share by 2015, which would generate $100bn in free cash flow during the same period.</p>
The chief executive''s forecasts were part of a "five-year roadmap" IBM presented to investors that assumed 5 per cent compound revenue growth over the five-year period.</p>
The timeline continues IBM''s habit of making detailed forecasts. In May 2007 it introduced a three-year plan to achieve $10 per share by the end of 2010. It hit that target one year early, at the end of 2009. The group now expects EPS of $11.20 for the full fiscal year.</p>
Mr Palmisano has overseen more than 100 purchases during his time as chief executive. The largest of those was the $3.5bn purchase of PwC Consulting in 2002, a deal that bolstered IBM''s services division but has been marred by choppy integration and a more competitive outsourcing market.</p>
The second-largest purchase under Mr Palmisano was also for a services company, the $1.3bn purchase of Internet Security Systems in 2006.</p>
It spent $1.5bn in the 2009 calendar year, with $1.2bn of that spent on SPSS, the business analytics group.</p>
IBM will be 100 years old next year. From its origins as a vendor of meat slicers and scales, it has become the world''s largest consulting group and third-largest software company.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David Gelles and Chris Nuttall in San Francisco" date="May 12, 2010 8:17 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/6aac605c-5ded-11df-8153-00144feab49a.html"><headline>IBM sets out bold buying strategy</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM will spend $20bn on acquisitions over the next five years, chief executive Sam Palmisano said on Wednesday.</p>
In five years we will spend more in acquisition than we did in the previous 10, Mr Palmisano told analysts gathered for the company''s investor day. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="April 20, 2010 3:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/693266fe-4c13-11df-a217-00144feab49a.html"><headline>IBM says tech rebound is spreading</headline><body><![CDATA[The tech rebound that took hold late last year is spreading beyond consumers and starting to draw in the large corporate buyers who represent the lion''s share of spending on technology, according to the latest earnings released by IBM yesterday.</p>Earnings and revenues from the technology bellwether topped Wall Street''s official forecasts for the first quarter of the year, although they failed to meet the more optimistic estimates that had taken hold in recent days and the company''s shares slipped back by about 2 per cent in after-hours trading.</p>In an uncharacteristic demonstration of confidence that the downturn is over, Sam Palmisano, chief executive officer, raised his forecast for IBM''s earnings per share this year to $11.20, from an estimate given in January of "at least $11".</p>The company also predicted that for the second quarter of this year all its main divisions would return to revenue growth, after taking currency movements into account. The moves are unusual for IBM, which does not normally raise guidance early in the year.</p>While the company''s latest results showed that the declines of last year had come to an end, a return to underlying growth across all its businesses had yet to take hold.</p>Adjusting for currency fluctuations, revenues in the first quarter were unchanged from a year before, although that marked an improvement from the 5 per cent decline seen in the fourth quarter of 2009. On a reported basis, IBM said that revenues grew by 5 per cent, an acceleration from the the 1 per cent of the final months of last year and a turnround from the 8 per cent decline for 2009 as a whole.</p>Underpinning the first-quarter recovery was an 11 per cent increase in revenues from IBM''s software business, its most profitable unit, to $5bn.</p>Adding to IBM''s confidence was the pattern of demand seen so far this year, said Mark Loughridge, chief financial officer. "Our growth rate improved across our brands and across geographies," he said, with the UK leading the way with an 8 percentage point improvement from the year before.</p>Another sign that tech markets were improving, he added, was the 18 per cent increase in new contract signings in IBM''s business consulting division, which saw its strongest growth in three years. Such new business indicated that companies were taking a broader strategic view of their businesses, Mr Loughridge said.</p>However, there were some suggestions that IBM was still facing headwinds. In total, it reported signings of new services contracts of only $12.3bn, some $1.5bn below Wall Street expectations, and its gross profit margin edged up only slightly, to 43.6 per cent.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="April 20, 2010 12:18 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/c9fec044-4bec-11df-a217-00144feab49a.html"><headline>IBM says tech rebound is spreading</headline><body><![CDATA[The tech rebound that took hold late last year is spreading beyond consumers and starting to draw in the large corporate buyers who represent the lion''s share of spending on technology, according to the latest earnings released by IBM on Monday.</p>
Earnings and revenues from the technology bellwether topped Wall Street''s official forecasts for the first quarter of the year, although they failed to meet the more optimistic estimates that had taken hold in recent days and the company''s shares slipped back by about 2 per cent in after-hours trading.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Geoff Nairn" date="April 13, 2010 1:12 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/8de4c1f2-415c-11df-adec-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>IBM and Verizon aim to eradicate truck-based back-ups</headline><body><![CDATA[US telco Verizon has teamed up with IBM to launch a private cloud back-up service for enterprises. The Managed Data Vault service is targeted at businesses that continue to do off-site data back-ups the old-fashioned way  by truck. </p>
The new service offers the security of off-site storage but at online speeds. The service is initially limited to businesses in the New York metropolitan area.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Telis Demos in New York" date="March 30, 2010 3:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/ac59e9ac-3b92-11df-a4c0-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Ex-IBM executive admits to Galleon tip-offs</headline><body><![CDATA[Robert Moffat, a former senior vice-president at IBM, admitted yesterday he provided inside information to a person involved with the Galleon Group hedge fund insider-trading scandal.</p>
"I disclosed material non-public information to Danielle Chiesi, a friend who I knew worked at a hedge fund," Mr Moffat told Frank Maas, the judge in the federal southern district of New York court in Manhattan. "I knew that the information I provided would be helpful to her in performing her job executing securities transactions."</p>
Mr Moffat said that in 2008 he gave Ms Chiesi, then a consultant at New Castle funds, a unit of Bear Stearns Asset Management, information about AMD, Lenovo and his own company that he learnt in the course of his 31-year career in computer hardware.</p>
Ms Chiesi was indicted, along with Galleon''s founder, Raj Rajaratnam, for passing information to the fund, which prosecutors say took in $49m (37m, 33m) trading shares of technology companies based on the tips. Both individuals deny the charges.</p>
Mr Moffat, according to the complaint, told Ms Chiesi of the nature and timing of plans by AMD to sell its manufacturing operations to investors in Abu Dhabi. He also said he told her about disappointing sales at IBM and poor earnings at Lenovo, of which he said he learnt as a nonvoting member of the computer-maker''s board.</p>
The complaint, which investigators assembled through telephone surveillance, also says that Ms Chiesi spoke to an unnamed executive at AMD and at Akamai.</p>
So far 21 individuals have been charged as part of the insider-trading ring, including former executives from other US companies, including McKinsey, the consultancy, and Intel, the chipmaker. It is believed to be the largest insider trading case.</p>
Mr Moffat is the 11th person charged by the US attorney to plead guilty. Eight others have agreed to co-operate with prosecutors.</p>
His attorney, Kerry Lawrence, of firm Briccetti, Calhoun  Lawrence, said in a statement: "While [Mr Moffat] has pleaded guilty, it is also important to understand that he never engaged in any trading . . and received no money or other financial benefit from anyone relating to those transactions."</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Telis Demos in New York" date="March 30, 2010 12:32 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c8573d68-3b82-11df-a4c0-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Ex-IBM executive admits to Galleon tip-offs</headline><body><![CDATA[Robert Moffat, a former senior vice-president at IBM, admitted on Monday he provided inside information to a person involved with the Galleon Group hedge fund insider-trading scandal.</p>
I disclosed material non-public information to Danielle Chiesi, a friend who I knew worked at a hedge fund, Mr Moffat told Frank Maas, the judge in the federal southern district of New York court in Manhattan. I knew that the information I provided would be helpful to her in performing her job executing securities transactions.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kathrin Hille in Beijing" date="March 25, 2010 2:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/ba41d3b4-37ae-11df-88c6-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Censorship fears grow as IBM tool bolsters Chinese spam curb</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM has developed a system for the detection and analysis of spam text messages for China Mobile that would help the world''s largest mobile operator track social networking groups and their messaging habits.</p>
The initiative comes in response to a large-scale government campaign to root out SMS spam and increase monitoring of text messaging flows.</p>
Although IBM said the tool''s purpose is to fight spam, analysts expressed concerns that its design could also make it yet another instrument for censorship.</p>
It is revealed just a day after Google confronted the Chinese government over censorship by redirecting Chinese users to its uncensored Hong Kong website.</p>
Thomas Li, chief technology officer at IBM Greater China and director of IBM Research in China, said China Mobile''s new program relies on the analysis of messaging patterns instead of content filtering.</p>
"Identifying people [as spammers] by content is problematic because there are privacy issues," Mr Li said. "Identifying them by the fact that they are sending mass messages is problematic as well because there can be other reasons for doing that - some social networks do that and Chinese people do that at Lunar New Year and other holidays."</p>
Asked if the software could be used for censorship, Mr Li said the system would be controlled and operated by China Mobile only. He also said censorship would be technically challenging as China Mobile would have to add a content filtering component to the tool.</p>
China Mobile did not respond to a request for comment.</p>
The IBM and China Mobile software analyses other factors such as whether the recipient group replies to a mass message, whether the group is a frequent target and whether there are time patterns in sending.</p>
"So China Mobile first gets a library of existing social networks, and can then analyse it against these factors," Mr Li said.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Nikki Tait in Brussels" date="March 24, 2010 2:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/085a371e-36e5-11df-bc0f-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>IBM faces EU antitrust complaint over ''tying'' claims</headline><body><![CDATA[Antitrust problems for IBM mounted yesterday when a fresh complaint about its business practices was filed with Europe''s top competition regulator.</p>
The new complaint comes from TurboHercules, a French company, which is accusing the US group of refusing to allow customers to run IBM''s mainframe operating systems on anything other than IBM mainframe hardware, an illegal practice known as "tying".</p>
This is the latest in a spate of complaints against the US technology company on both sides of the Atlantic. In Europe, competition officials at the European Commission started to look at IBM''s mainframe activities several years ago, following objections from a small technology company called PSI .</p>
PSI was subsequently bought out by IBM but a second complaint from another smaller rival of IBM''s, called T3 Technologies, followed in January last year. Microsoft, one of IBM''s big rivals, made investments in both PSI and T3 at various stages.</p>
Meanwhile, in the US, the Department of Justice started a preliminary investigation into IBM''s dominance of the mainframe computer market last autumn, sending out requests for information. This appeared to be triggered, at least in part, by a complaint from the Computer and Communications Industry Association, an industry group that includes some large IT companies such as Google and Microsoft, as well as much smaller groups.</p>
The US complaint was said to be somewhat broader than the two original complaints in Europe, for example, citing T3''s experiences but also making allegations about IBM''s behaviour towards Hercules, an open-source product designed to enable IBM''s systems to run on Intel and AMD-based servers and personal computers.</p>
Yesterday''s complainant, TurboHercules, was set up last year to commercialise Hercules''s open-source "emulation" software - which includes disaster recovery products that protect customers'' data if there is a mainframe failure.</p>
The French company claims to have asked IBM to license its mainframe operating systems to customers for use with Hercules - but says it was accused of patent infringement in reply.</p>
When asked to comment on the TurboHercules complaint, IBM said: "We have not been notified of this complaint and are thus unable to comment."</p>
Roger Bowler, TurboHercules''s founder, said his company was "by no means anti-IBM.</p>
In its complaint to the commission, TurboHercules is asking competition officials to order IBM to end the alleged tying and make available its interfaces and protocols.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Nikki Tait in Brussels" date="March 23, 2010 11:27 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/ec2e2b68-3653-11df-8151-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>IBM faces fresh EU antitrust complaint</headline><body><![CDATA[<p>IBM dominates the mainframe computer market</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="January 20, 2010 2:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/4645f966-0574-11df-a85e-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>IBM earnings surge in spite of downturn</headline><body><![CDATA[
IBM said yesterday that its revenues had barely grown in the final quarter of 2009 as customers had held off signing big new contracts, highlighting the slow pace of the hotly expected technology recovery.</p>
In spite of that, the US tech bellwether continued to report surging profits on the back of deep costcutting, capping the seventh consecutive year in which earnings per share grew by at least 10 per cent.</p>
IBM also issued an upbeat assessment of the prospects for a broader-based recovery in the sector this year, while still holding its financial forecasts to relatively conservative levels.</p>
The signs of a turnround were also bolstered by new bookings in its services division of $18.8bn against forecasts of $17bn.</p>
The earnings outperformance and mixed revenue picture were greeted by a 2 per cent decline in IBM''s shares in after-market trading, although a 65 per cent run-up during the past year has made it one of the best performing large technology stocks in that period.</p>
IBM said its revenues had edged up by 0.8 per cent in the fourth quarter to $27.2bn.</p>
They would have fallen by 5 per cent had it not been for favourable movements in exchange rates.</p>
"We saw a lot of large deals roll over to the first quarter, especially in our software business," said Mark Loughridge, chief financial officer.</p>
As a result, IBM''s software division, which was the key factor behind its solid earnings growth during the previous business cycle, recorded a 4 per cent decline in revenues in the latest quarter, after stripping out currency effects.</p>
In spite of that, Mr Loughridge said IBM had seen enough signs of recovery to give it confidence for the rest of this year.</p>
Smaller orders had grown consistently across all parts of the business and the major geographic regions, and such transactions had proved in the past to be "characteristic as a leading indicator", he added.</p>
The IBM finance chief also pointed to a progressive recovery since the middle of last year in the company''s hardware business, which was hardest hit by the downturn.</p>
With revenues little changed, IBM turned to cost-cutting to maintain its earnings growth, slicing $3.7bn from its expenses in the year.</p>
Operating costs in the latest quarter fell by 5 per cent, supporting a 9 per cent increase in after-tax profits, to $4.8bn. At $3.59, earnings per share were up 10 per cent and above the $3.47 most analysts had expected.</p>
Mr Loughridge brushed off suggestions that the company''s forecast of earnings per share of "at least $11" for 2010, compared with Wall Street forecasts of $10.88, was unduly conservative given the recovery in technology spending it believed was taking hold.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="January 20, 2010 12:28 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/cb3461b0-0558-11df-a85e-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>IBM earnings surge on cost-cutting</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM said on Tuesday that its revenues had barely grown in the final quarter of 2009 as customers had held off signing big new contracts, highlighting the slow pace of the hotly expected technology recovery
.</p>
In spite of that, the US tech bellwether continued to report surging profits on the back of deep cost-cutting, capping the seventh consecutive year in which earnings per share grew by at least 10 per cent.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="December 8, 2009 10:55 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/3d4ea3ce-e38e-11de-9f4f-00144feab49a.html"><headline>IBM in $200m Brazil software tie-up</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM on Monday announced a $200m software deal with a technology partner in Brazil, the biggest software deal of its kind this year, in the latest sign that emerging markets remain a notable bright spot for the technology industry.</p>
Speaking in an interview with the Financial Times, Steve Mills, head of IBM''s software division, said that Big Blue was seeing pretty solid single-digit growth in Brazil, India, China and parts of south-east Asia as the year draws to a close. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Geoff Nairn" date="November 10, 2009 1:46 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/8df7600e-cd59-11de-8162-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>IBM analyses types of data together</headline><body><![CDATA[IBM has introduced Cognos Content Analytics, a version of its Cognos business intelligence software designed for the growing amount of unstructured content present in e-mails, websites and portals. </p>
Traditionally, organisations have handled unstructured and structured data separately, but IBM argues they can get greater insight by analysing both types of data together. Big Blue plans versions of Cognos Content Analytics for specific industries and business requirements. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="October 31, 2009 2:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/dacafd26-c5bd-11de-9b3b-00144feab49a.html"><headline>IBM executive leaves after Galleon affair</headline><body><![CDATA[Robert Moffat, the IBM senior executive charged with illegally passing on inside information, yesterday became the first tech industry executive known to have left his job in the wake of the Galleon affair.</p>
His departure, two weeks after charges were filed, brings an end to a 31-year career that took him close to the top of one of the world''s leading companies.</p>
A senior vice-president and trusted lieutenant of Sam Palmisano, IBM''s chief executive, Mr Moffat had himself been mentioned as a possible candidate for the top job.</p>
IBM refused to comment on the circumstances of the departure, confining itself to a brief statement: "Bob Moffat, who had been placed on a leave of absence as a result of a US federal investigation into his personal activities, is no longer an employee of IBM." A spokesman added that the company did not discuss "personal matters regarding employees or former employees".</p>
Kerry Lawrence, Mr -Moffat''s lawyer, said the executive had "retired from IBM, he was not terminated or fired". He had left the company "so he could devote his time and energy to defending himself against the charges", Mr Lawrence added. He reiterated that the former IBM executive was "still asserting his innocence".</p>
Mr Moffat''s quick departure, and IBM''s decision to characterise the matter as a purely personal one, contrasts sharply with the approach taken by other companies whose executives have been drawn into the insider trading case.</p>
An executive at Intel and a partner at McKinsey, who have also denied insider trading charges, are both on administrative leave, according to the companies.</p>
These companies have also been public about launching internal investigations into the affair, as has Akamai, where an executive is alleged to have passed on inside information though not charged.</p>
Some companies caught up in the affair have promised reviews of their ethical codes of conduct for executives. While acting quickly to suspend Mr Moffat after the charges were laid two weeks ago, IBM has not disclosed any other action.</p>
IBM said that Rod Adkins, who had already been named acting head of its hardware and semiconductor operations in place of Mr Moffat, had now taken on the role full time.</p>
For the latest news, go to www.ft.com/galleon</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="October 31, 2009 2:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/ca6f265a-c5bd-11de-9b3b-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Moffat leaves IBM after Galleon affair</headline><body><![CDATA[Robert Moffat, the IBM senior executive charged with illegally passing on inside information, yesterday became the first tech industry executive known to have left his job in the wake of the Galleon affair.</p>
His departure, two weeks after charges were filed, brings an abrupt end to a 31-year career that took him close to the top of one of the world''s best-known companies.</p>
A senior vice-president and trusted lieutenant of Sam Palmisano, IBM''s chief executive officer, Mr Moffat had himself been mentioned as a possible candidate for the top job.</p>
IBM refused to comment on the circumstances surrounding his departure, confining itself to a brief statement: "Bob Moffat, who had been placed on a leave of absence as a result of a US federal investigation into his personal activities, is no longer an employee of IBM." A spokesman added that the company did not discuss "personal matters regarding employees or former employees".</p>
Kerry Lawrence, Mr Moffat''s lawyer, said that the executive had "retired from IBM, he was not terminated or fired". He had left the company "so he could devote his time and energy to defending himself against the charges," Mr Lawrence added. He reiterated that the former IBM executive was "still asserting his innocence".</p>
Mr Moffat''s quick departure, and IBM''s decision to characterise the matter as a purely personal one, contrasts sharply with the approach taken by other companies whose executives have been drawn into the insider trading case.</p>
An executive at Intel and a partner at McKinsey, who have also denied insider trading charges, are both on administrative leave, according to the companies.</p>
These companies have also been public about launching internal investigations into the affair, as has Akamai, where an executive is alleged to have passed on inside information though not charged.</p>
Some of the companies caught up in the affair have also moved to reassure their staff and customers by promising reviews of their ethical codes of conduct for executives.</p>
While acting quickly to suspend Mr Moffat after the charges were laid two weeks ago, IBM has not disclosed any other action.</p>
The decision to depict the matter as a purely personal one and refuse further comment risks falling short of the transparency needed when a scandal hits a company at the highest levels, according to some corporate ethics experts.</p>
IBM said that Rod Adkins, who had already been named acting head of its hardware and semiconductor operations in place of Mr Moffat, had now taken on the role full time.</p>
For the latest news, go to www.ft.com/galleon</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters" date="October 31, 2009 2:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/d534d648-c5bd-11de-9b3b-00144feab49a.html"><headline>IBM executive in insider case quits</headline><body><![CDATA[Robert Moffat, the IBM senior executive charged with illegally passing on inside information, yesterday became the first tech-industry executive known to have lost his job in the wake of the Galleon hedge fund affair.</p>
A senior vice-president and lieutenant of Sam Palmisano, chief executive, Mr Moffat had been tipped as a possible candidate for the top job. He has denied passing on information illegally.</p>]]> </body></entry></news>