
<news><entry author="By Richard Waters" date=" October 16, 2013 7:42 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e3e0da3a-367e-11e3-aaf1-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft and Apple face different challenges to adapt</headline><body><![CDATA[You can always count on Apple to spoil a Microsoft party.</p>
So it is with next Tuesday''s expected unveiling of the latest iPad models  the same day that Microsoft had already earmarked for the launch of its new Surface tablets. It also comes hot on the heels of this Thursday''s release of the upgraded Windows 8.1, as Microsoft makes up for the missteps of last year''s launch of its first touchscreen operating system.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco and Stephen Foley in New York" date="October 3, 2013 12:07 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/74b60e22-2ba8-11e3-a1b7-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft investors wary of Gates'' role in chief executive search</headline><body><![CDATA[Some of Microsoft''s biggest shareholders have expressed concern about the effect that Bill Gates'' outsized influence at the company will have on the search for a replacement to chief executive Steve Ballmer.
</p>
The company needs to take particular care that Mr Gates'' unique role does not deter candidates nor leave questions about who will have the final say over Mr Ballmer''s replacement, said people familiar with the thinking of a number of investors.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Daniel Thomas, Telecoms Correspondent" date="October 2, 2013 7:00 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/4b49dba2-2b73-11e3-bfe2-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Google and Microsoft back UK trial to use white space'' bandwidth</headline><body><![CDATA[Google and Microsoft are backing national trials of mobile services across fallow parts of the broadcast spectrum that could help avert a looming shortage of mobile frequencies.</p>
So-called white space technology allows mobile broadband to be carried over unused, and unlicensed, broadcast frequencies, which could be used by smartphones and tablets as well as a range of business applications.</p>
<h3>Spectrum of opportunity</h3>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Milne in Salo" date="September 25, 2013 8:01 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/feb7ef76-2510-11e3-bcf7-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Hope emerges for Nokia''s future following purchase by Microsoft</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="September 23, 2013 9:18 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/8a0e072c-2462-11e3-a8f7-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft resurfaces with revamped models in tablet wars</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>Microsoft Surface Pro 2 tablet computer</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="September 20, 2013 2:21 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0492a068-2164-11e3-a92a-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft bets on rapid online growth</headline><body><![CDATA[AFP/Getty Images<p>Steve Ballmer</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Milne in Oslo and Daniel Thomas in London" date="September 19, 2013 4:27 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a50a96e6-2131-11e3-8aff-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Nokia''s Stephen Elop given 18.8m to return to Microsoft</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="September 17, 2013 6:58 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/48897be0-1fb9-11e3-aa36-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft''s Office refusal risks opening door to rivals</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft''s refusal to release its Office software for rival tablet computers risks eroding its most profitable product and has inspired a new generation of start-ups that are racing to fill the gap, according to tech executives and analysts.</p>
Microsoft has restricted users of the iPad and tablets running Google''s Android software to an online version of Office that only works when the machines are connected to the internet. The strategy of holding back the full software for Windows tablets has failed to ignite sales, however, forcing the company to take a $900m writedown on its Surface tablet in July.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="September 5, 2013 2:27 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/46d36fce-15c6-11e3-950a-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft wins landmark patent ruling</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft has won the second stage of a landmark patent case against Google''s Motorola unit, as a jury in Seattle concluded that the mobile handset maker had breached some its commitments to technology standards bodies.</p>
The verdict follows a decision that also went in the software company''s favour in the first part of the case, concluded in April. The earlier ruling, which dealt with how royalties payments should be calculated for patents that are included in technology standards, was seen as of far broader significance for the patent disputes that have rocked the smartphone industry.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="September 4, 2013 7:21 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0edebb0c-157e-11e3-b519-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Nokia patents bump up cost for Microsoft</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty<p>The Nokia Lumia 1020, unveiled in July, features a 41-megapixel camera</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters and Richard Milne" date="September 3, 2013 9:53 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/3b79f7f2-14c1-11e3-a2df-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Investors cast doubt on Microsoft deal</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="September 3, 2013 6:40 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/42648092-14b6-11e3-a2df-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Steep hill to climb for Microsoft-Nokia</headline><body><![CDATA[For Steve Ballmer, outgoing chief executive of Microsoft, there was probably no alternative but to risk one final roll of the dice. But the odds are long on his successor wielding the rump of Nokia''s handset business to turn Microsoft into a real contender in what has become the dominant market for personal computing.</p>
That was the knee-jerk verdict of investors and industry analysts on Tuesday, as Microsoft''s stock fell more than 6 per cent  in one fell swoop wiping out the lift the shares had received on the news of Mr Ballmer''s departure only days before.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Milne in Oslo and John Aglionby and Chris Nuttall in London" date="September 3, 2013 6:49 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c8204b3c-1446-11e3-9289-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft in 5.4bn deal with Nokia</headline><body><![CDATA[AFP<p>Nokia chairman Risto Siilasmaa (L) walks past Microsoft CEO Steve Ballmer during the press conference</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="August 30, 2013 11:44 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/d4b2cafa-11c1-11e3-a14c-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft cedes board seat to ValueAct</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft has bowed to pressure from an activist investor, ceding a board seat to ValueAct Capital as it tries to quell unrest on Wall Street.</p>
The pact with ValueAct, disclosed on Friday, comes a week after Steve Ballmer announced his intention to quit as chief executive as soon as a replacement was found. Mr Ballmer denied at the time of his resignation that his departure was linked to pressure from the activist investor, which has become one of Microsoft''s biggest outside shareholders.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters" date="August 29, 2013 7:48 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/4a260082-108b-11e3-b291-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Technology: Microsoft''s outlook</headline><body /></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters" date="August 25, 2013 5:44 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/638de3ac-0d96-11e3-8d9d-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Ballmer resignation unlikely to quell unease over Microsoft</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Robin Kwong and Henry Mance" date="February 4, 2014 4:09 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/527c0cdc-0c1b-11e3-8840-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Timeline: Microsoft through the years</headline><body><![CDATA[Bill Gates has stepped down from his chairmanship at Microsoft after more than 30 years in the role. </p>
The software company also appointed Satya Nadella, president of its cloud computing and enterprise business, as its new chief executive. Mr Nadella takes over from Steve Ballmer, who had been chief executive since 2000.</p>
Mr Gates will remain an important figure at Microsoft  he aims to spend a third of his time at the company helping Mr Nadella as a technology adviser. </p>
Microsoft lost roughly 40 per cent of its market value during Mr Ballmer''s tenure. </p>
The company''s new management will hope to re-establish Microsoft as a technology leader. As Mr Nadella wrote in his first email to employees: We must zero in on what Microsoft can uniquely contribute to the world. The opportunity ahead will require us to reimagine a lot of what we have done in the past for a mobile and cloud-first world, and do new things.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tim Bradshaw in San Francisco" date="August 23, 2013 7:36 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/cc5d4d62-0bf4-11e3-8840-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Ballmer to leave Microsoft within a year</headline><body><![CDATA[Steve Ballmer is stepping down as chief executive of Microsoft after 13 years at the helm in an admission by the PC pioneer that it lacks the leadership needed to steer it into the mobile era.</p>
Shareholders, who have objected to Mr Ballmer''s performance for years, sent shares in the world''s largest software company by market capitalisation up as much as 8.7 per cent on Friday. </p>
<h3>The Ballmer years</h3>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="August 14, 2013 7:40 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/034b04e2-04fa-11e3-9e71-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft to fund remake of BBC''s sci-fi cult classic Blake''s 7''</headline><body><![CDATA[<p>Picture shows L-R: Steven Pacey and Paul Darrow, from Blake''s Seven..</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Paul Taylor" date="August 12, 2013 5:40 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/95297aec-0365-11e3-980a-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Nokia and Microsoft also face tough fight for survival</headline><body><![CDATA[<p>Nokia Lumia 1020</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hannah Kuchler" date="July 22, 2013 12:03 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/792cb988-f219-11e2-8e04-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Google and Microsoft commit to UK''s child pornography crackdown</headline><body><![CDATA[Alamy]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="July 21, 2013 1:37 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/333a0cb8-f0da-11e2-929c-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>More bad news for Microsoft cranks up pressure on Steve Ballmer</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters<p>Steve Ballmer, chief executive of Microsoft</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="July 19, 2013 3:10 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/d0bc3734-efdd-11e2-8229-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft shares down 10% on Windows and Surface tablet woes</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="July 15, 2013 6:54 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/49bf0748-ed71-11e2-8d7c-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>HP bolsters board with former Microsoft strategist Ray Ozzie</headline><body><![CDATA[Ray Ozzie, the former top software strategist at Microsoft, has signed on as a director at Hewlett-Packard as the US technology company seeks to rebuild its board in the wake of the Autonomy debacle.</p>
HP also named former executives from Liberty Media and McDonald''s as new directors on Monday  to add to the financial and corporate turnround experience in its boardroom and bolster chief executive Meg Whitman''s attempt to revive the struggling conglomerate.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="July 11, 2013 7:19 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/3d2a8594-ea4b-11e2-b2f4-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Ballmer in rallying cry at Microsoft</headline><body><![CDATA[It is eight years since Ray Ozzie, the former top software strategist at Microsoft, tried to propel the company deeper into the realm of internet services, with a warning that the rise of companies like Google threatened to overturn its software kingdom.</p>
And it is seven years since chief executive Steve Ballmer indicated that a new focus on hardware devices had become paramount, releasing the ill-fated Zune digital music player to compete with Apple''s iPod.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="July 11, 2013 8:00 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0f60103a-ea3b-11e2-b2f4-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Steve Ballmer shakes up Microsoft structure in battle to compete</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters<p>Steve Ballmer, chief executive of Microsoft</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Henry Mance" date="July 5, 2013 2:48 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/50c385ec-e49c-11e2-a74d-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Microsoft reaches agreement with Sinofsky</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="July 3, 2013 11:17 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/76054914-e42c-11e2-91a3-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Zynga chief lured from Microsoft with $50m pay package</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tim Bradshaw in San Francisco" date="June 28, 2013 5:36 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f087c6f0-e001-11e2-9de6-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Console battle powers up as Microsoft adds Time Warner TV to Xbox</headline><body><![CDATA[AFP]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Waters in San Francisco" date="June 26, 2013 9:38 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/95480f84-de94-11e2-b990-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft touts rapid Windows 8 updates</headline><body><![CDATA[Microsoft on Wednesday promised further rapid improvements to Windows 8 as it showed off a series of upgrades designed to overcome some of the initial poor reception to the operating system.
</p>
The world''s biggest software company also plugged a gaping hole in its arsenal of applications for the new touch-based system with the announcement of an app from Facebook.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chris Nuttall in San Francisco" date="June 19, 2013 11:42 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/955550fe-d92b-11e2-a6cf-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Microsoft to scrap Xbox One restrictions</headline><body><![CDATA[AFP]]> </body></entry><entry author="By James Crabtree in Mumbai" date="September 21, 2014 4:44 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f1309d4a-3fc6-11e4-a381-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney eyes bigger picture with Bollywood link</headline><body><![CDATA[AFP]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Milne, Nordic Correspondent" date="August 12, 2014 5:26 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/55dac920-2224-11e4-ad60-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Jeweller Pandora to sell Disney charms</headline><body /></entry><entry author="By Sarah Mishkin in San Francisco" date="August 10, 2014 9:01 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/1ac477a4-20c2-11e4-b8f4-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney in dispute with Amazon</headline><body><![CDATA[<p>Chris Evans and Scarlett Johansson star in ''Captain America: The Winter Soldier''</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Shannon Bond in New York" date="August 6, 2014 12:13 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/713932be-1ce4-11e4-88c3-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Superheroes pack a punch for Disney</headline><body><![CDATA[<p>Chris Evans and Scarlett Johansson star in ''Captain America: The Winter Soldier''</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="May 6, 2014 11:31 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/93f6d50a-d567-11e3-9bca-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney beats expectations as Frozen'' puts fire into earnings</headline><body><![CDATA[AP]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="March 11, 2014 5:46 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/d7763f10-a942-11e3-9b71-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Disney nears $500m deal to buy Maker Studios</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty<p>Lisa Donovan, co-founder of Maker Studios</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="February 25, 2014 1:05 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/eb452056-9dee-11e3-95fe-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Disney strengthens movie ties with Apple</headline><body><![CDATA[<p>Olaf the snowman in ''Frozen''</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in San Francisco" date="February 5, 2014 10:58 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/06c51b78-8eb4-11e3-98c6-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Disney powered by Frozen'' and Thor''</headline><body><![CDATA[<p>Olaf the snowman in ''Frozen''</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="December 23, 2013 9:18 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/55bfb930-6c14-11e3-85b1-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Twitter''s Dorsey joins Disney board</headline><body><![CDATA[Jack Dorsey, the chairman of Twitter, has been elected to the Walt Disney board, becoming the latest in a succession of Silicon Valley heavyweights to join the media company.</p>
Mr Dorsey, who is also the chief executive of Square, the micropayments company, follows the late Steve Jobs and Facebook''s Sheryl Sandberg on to the Disney board. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Howard Yu and Stefan Michel" date=" December 2, 2013 4:00 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/386e1366-56bd-11e3-ab12-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney rethinks its China strategy</headline><body /></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="November 7, 2013 11:32 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/8a09c35a-47fe-11e3-88be-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Theme parks help lift Disney to record profits</headline><body><![CDATA[Zade Rosenthal]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan" date="October 4, 2013 5:31 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/3fc64512-2ab6-11e3-8fb8-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Walt Disney Concert Hall  10 years on</headline><body><![CDATA[The downtown area of Los Angeles used to be a dangerous, no-go area after dark but a recent gala anniversary concert there featuring the cellist YoYo Ma and installations by the video artist Netia Jones drew a starry crowd.</p>
Downtown Los Angeles has spent the last decade on an upward trajectory, thanks, in part, to a music venue. But then, the Walt Disney Concert Hall, which celebrates its 10th birthday this month under the management of the Los Angeles Philharmonic, is no ordinary venue. Frank Gehry''s shining, cubist masterpiece seems to erupt from the street, its angular, fractured walls curving into the air like sails billowing in the wind. Visually striking and with an auditorium revered for the quality of its sound, the hall has had a catalytic effect on the artistic and cultural life of Los Angeles, according to Eli Broad, the billionaire art collector and philanthropist.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="August 6, 2013 9:51 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/2c703d6a-fed8-11e2-b9b0-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney held back by Lone Ranger'' flop</headline><body><![CDATA[AFP]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in London" date="July 8, 2013 4:06 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/ff6cc34a-e7c8-11e2-9aad-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney saddled with $100m loss</headline><body><![CDATA[AP]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="May 7, 2013 11:17 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/4d3ef28a-b760-11e2-a249-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney shows its muscle as Iron Man 3'' boosts earnings</headline><body /></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="February 6, 2013 12:10 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0c4bee40-6fee-11e2-8785-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Disney eyes UK exit for ESPN</headline><body><![CDATA[Walt Disney is exploring an exit of ESPN from the UK, after the sports network incurred losses and lost key sports rights contacts.</p>
ESPN, the largest sports broadcaster in the US, launched to great fanfare in the UK three years ago and made an immediate impact, buying a package of rights to live Premier League football and setting itself up as an alternative to British Sky Broadcasting, which holds most of the rights.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="December 4, 2012 9:56 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/23aaaca6-3e58-11e2-829d-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Netflix strikes deal for new Disney movies</headline><body><![CDATA[The pay-television industry faces renewed competition from Netflix after the DVD and video streaming operator struck a deal with Walt Disney to become its exclusive TV partner with distribution rights to its hit movies.</p>
Netflix will replace Starz, the cable channel, as Disney''s principal TV partner. The value of the multiyear deal, which starts in 2016, was undisclosed, although Netflix is probably be paying $200m-$300m a year, based on other output deals agreed between studios and pay-TV channels.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="November 8, 2012 11:18 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b310a29e-29f7-11e2-a5ca-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney urges officials to resolve fiscal cliff</headline><body><![CDATA[Walt Disney''s theme parks and cable networks powered fourth-quarter profits at the media group as Bob Iger, chief executive, sounded a warning about the looming fiscal cliff, when spending cuts and tax increases are due to hit the US economy at the beginning of 2013.</p>
My exhortation to our government is don''t even get close to the fiscal cliff, Mr Iger said in an interview with CNBC. Deal with it immediately and deal with it productively. Don''t threaten the country and our economy.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="October 31, 2012 5:35 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b830502e-2346-11e2-a66b-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney plans to exploit Star Wars galaxy</headline><body><![CDATA[In a video message posted online shortly after Walt Disney announced its $4bn purchase of Lucasfilm, Bob Iger, Disney''s chief executive, told viewers what the media group was getting for its money. Seventeen thousand characters that inhabit several thousand planets spanning 20,000 years, he said. </p>
Disney had not just bought the company behind Star Wars, one of the most lucrative film series ever released: it had also acquired a virtual universe of intellectual property.</p>
<h3>Disney Star Wars graphic</h3>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="October 30, 2012 10:36 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c43b6a52-22ce-11e2-938d-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney and Star Wars join forces</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="October 30, 2012 7:48 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/d4912e72-22bb-11e2-938d-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Former Disney executive to run Shine</headline><body><![CDATA[Rich Ross, the former Walt Disney Studios chairman, has been hired by Elisabeth Murdoch to run Shine America, the television production company she sold to News Corp last year.</p>
Mr Ross, who ran Disney Channel for several years before being hired to streamline Disney''s film studio, left the company in the spring after the boxoffice failure of John Carter. In his resignation letter he said he had been the wrong fit for the role.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Roger Blitz, Leisure Industries Correspondent" date="September 18, 2012 11:36 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b4eddc96-01b9-11e2-8aaa-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Relief for Euro Disney over refinancing deal</headline><body><![CDATA[Euro Disney gained some breathing space in its debt arrangements after securing a refinancing deal with the Walt Disney Company, majority shareholders in the Disneyland Paris operator.</p>
Walt Disney, which has a 39.8 per cent stake in Europe''s biggest tourist destination, is taking over the debt facility held by a syndicate of banks. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan" date="August 16, 2012 7:26 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/2/34fe39a6-e79f-11e1-8686-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Superheroes soar above Disney tensions</headline><body><![CDATA[Marvel]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="June 13, 2012 7:18 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/983c034a-b577-11e1-b8d0-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney opening $1.1bn park attraction</headline><body><![CDATA[Walt Disney will step up its competition with rival theme park operators this week when it opens a new $1.1bn attraction at its park in Anaheim, California.</p>
Cars Land, which is based on the company''s hit animated Cars movies, is the centrepiece of a five-year redevelopment of Disney''s California Adventure park, which is next door to the company''s Disneyland park.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="June 5, 2012 6:46 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/cb287040-af2d-11e1-a8a7-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney sets standards for TV food ads</headline><body><![CDATA[Walt Disney has introduced new standards for food advertising on its children''s television programming to promote healthier eating among the young.</p>
The standards follow guidelines at Disney''s theme parks and are aligned with US federal rules on calorie content, sugar and salt. Implementation on Disney''s children''s TV channels and web sites is scheduled by 2015.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="May 31, 2012 10:07 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/add07d42-ab5b-11e1-a2ed-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney appoints new studio chief</headline><body><![CDATA[Walt Disney moved to stabilise the leadership of its movie studio after it appointed Alan Horn as chairman, replacing Rich Ross who recently left the group.</p>
Mr Horn will take over the studio at a time when it is riding high thanks to the global success of The Avengers, a film which has done much to erase the failure of John Carter, which flopped on its release this year.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="May 8, 2012 11:30 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/24268ebe-995a-11e1-9a57-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Walt Disney puts faith in superheroes</headline><body /></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="April 20, 2012 7:18 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e8f08b40-8b0f-11e1-912d-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Disney parts company with Ross</headline><body><![CDATA[Walt Disney is searching for a new studio chairman after parting company with Rich Ross, the former head of Disney Channel, whose tenure will be best remembered for the recent box office bomb John Carter
.</p>
Mr Ross was appointed by Disney almost three years ago to streamline and shake up the studio, the company''s oldest and most prestigious business. He oversaw a restructuring of the division to better equip it for a home entertainment landscape inexorably changed by the collapse of DVD sales. But he failed to make his mark with box office hits.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="March 19, 2012 11:19 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/d4e15530-720f-11e1-90b5-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Disney in $200m writedown for John Carter''</headline><body><![CDATA[Walt Disney will incur a $200m writedown on John Carter, the action film based on the Edgar Rice Burroughs novel which has failed at the box office despite a $300m production budget and an extensive global marketing campaign.</p>
The film about an American civil war hero who journeys to Mars is shaping up to be one of Hollywood''s costliest flops. It has generated $184m in global ticket sales but with about half its takings going to cinema chains, Disney has had to adjust its earnings guidance for the quarter to reflect the film''s performance.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="February 7, 2012 11:48 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a67538ee-51e2-11e1-a30c-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney performs despite fewer films</headline><body><![CDATA[A strong showing from its television networks and theme park division propelled Walt Disney''s first quarter profits past analyst estimates even though revenues were lower than expected because the company''s film studio released fewer movies.</p>
Three of Disney''s five operating divisions reported increased profits, led by the theme parks unit, which was boosted by higher guest spending, a sign of a strengthening consumer economy.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="January 31, 2012 11:46 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0e127f70-4c5c-11e1-bd09-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney completes acquisition of India''s UTV</headline><body><![CDATA[Walt Disney has completed its acquisition of UTV
, paying $454m for the shares in the Indian media group that it did not already own, as it seeks to expand in one of the world''s fastest-growing film and television markets.</p>
Disney plans to delist UTV from the Indian stock exchange and is creating Walt Disney Company India, a new holding company that will manage UTV alongside its other assets in the country.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan" date=" January 26, 2012 7:30 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/1c3a52de-4744-11e1-b646-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>When Disney dreams became a nihilistic nightmare</headline><body><![CDATA[Post-punk nihilists and Mickey Mouse are not natural bedfellows. </p>
When you think of Walt Disney, you might think of all things sunny and wonderful, childhood dreams, fairies and innocence. At any rate, you are unlikely to think of the angst-ridden, bass-heavy, industrial sound of Manchester band Joy Division  named after the prostitution wing of a Nazi concentration camp. The band''s lead singer, Ian Curtis, suffered from depression and killed himself.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David Gelles in New York and Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="January 4, 2012 10:32 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/3564c23c-370c-11e1-96bf-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Comcast strikes 10-year deal with Disney</headline><body><![CDATA[Comcast, the largest cable operator in the US, has struck a deal with Disney that will significantly boost its digital offerings and guarantee it access to ABC, ESPN and other television networks for at least another 10 years. </p>
The value of the deal was not disclosed, however television networks in recent years have demanded sharply higher fees from cable operators.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Edgecliffe-Johnson in New York" date="November 11, 2011 12:25 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c1a3b828-0bf3-11e1-9861-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney chief backs emerging markets push</headline><body><![CDATA[Bob Iger, chairman and chief executive of Walt Disney, has reaffirmed the US entertainment group''s international ambitions, saying it was imperative to this company to plant a number of seeds in the emerging world to find faster growth. </p>
Three months on from earnings that fell uncharacteristically short of analysts'' expectations, Disney reported record revenue, net income and earnings per share for its full fiscal year to October. Net income rose 21 per cent to $4.81bn on a 7 per cent rise in revenues to $40.9bn, driven by strength in its largest divisions, cable networks and parks and resorts. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles and Courtney Weaver in Moscow" date="October 27, 2011 3:43 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/95a09354-00a4-11e1-930b-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney expands free TV channel to Russia</headline><body><![CDATA[Walt Disney will begin broadcasting a free-to-air television channel in Russia next year after striking a deal with UTH, the media group, to buy a 49 per cent stake in Seven TV.</p>
Seven TV will be rebranded as The Disney Channel upon completion of the deal, which was announced as Bob Iger, Disney''s chief executive, met Vladimir Putin, the Russian prime minister, in Moscow.</p>
The price was not disclosed, although people familiar with the matter said it was worth about $300m. The deal will ensure Disney programming is available to 75 per cent of the country''s measured broadcast audience: Disney said the channel would reach about 40m households and be available in Moscow, St Petersburg and hundreds of towns and cities through other distribution agreements.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="October 23, 2011 3:21 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/bd48bb5a-fd59-11e0-a9db-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Turkey to get Disney free-to-air TV</headline><body><![CDATA[Walt Disney is launching the Disney Channel on free-to-air television in Turkey in a move that will increase the channel''s distribution to more than 100m homes across Europe, Africa and the Middle East.</p>
The Disney Channel is typically limited to pay-TV services but in 2008 the company launched a free-to-air service in Spain. Turkey is the second market chosen by Disney for free-to-air distribution and by using the Free Sat platform the company will have access to 60 per cent of homes in the country from January 2012.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By James Fontanella-Khan and Neil Munshi in Mumbai" date="October 9, 2011 7:11 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f53c7f8a-f25d-11e0-931e-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Reliance set to strike deal with Disney''s UTV</headline><body><![CDATA[Mukesh Ambani, India''s wealthiest man, is set to sign a deal with Walt Disney''s Indian subsidiary that will provide his Reliance Industries with the content for its next generation of mobile telecoms, people close to the matter said.</p>
The deal, expected to be sealed in the coming weeks, is between Reliance and UTV, one of Bollywood''s largest entertainment groups, which Disney controls with a 50.44 per cent stake and is in the process of buying fully.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Edgecliffe-Johnson and David Gelles in New York" date="October 7, 2011 7:24 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f0c9e31a-f10a-11e0-b56f-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Disney extends Iger contract until 2016</headline><body><![CDATA[Bob Iger, chief executive of Walt Disney, will take on the role of chairman and extend his contract with the company from 2013 to 2016, the studio owner said on Friday as it set out the terms of a staggered succession plan. </p>
The board of Disney, which also owns theme parks, the ABC television network and the ESPN sports channel, said John Pepper had announced his intention to retire as chairman at its 2012 annual meeting, after five years in the position.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="September 20, 2011 9:49 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/df60d45e-e3c1-11e0-bd3d-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney to create Avatar'' theme park</headline><body><![CDATA[Walt Disney has struck a deal with James Cameron and Fox Filmed Entertainment to develop a new theme park inspired by the filmmaker''s blockbuster film, Avatar.</p>
The new land, which will form part of Walt Disney World in Florida, will cost an estimated $400m to construct, according to people familiar with the deal. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="September 15, 2011 6:14 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a35d4372-dfb4-11e0-b1db-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney axing local language film unit</headline><body><![CDATA[Walt Disney has pulled the plug on its local language film unit just two years after commissioning a range of movies from producers in fast growing cinema markets in China, Russia and the Middle East. </p>
The company had moved into local production to diversify its movie studio revenues and capitalise on a multiplex cinema boom in emerging markets. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Nicole Bullock in New York" date="August 17, 2011 11:34 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e783a456-c916-11e0-bc80-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney takes advantage of low bond rates</headline><body><![CDATA[Walt Disney on Wednesday sold its first 30-year bonds in nearly a decade, paying historically low rates in a sign that top US companies can get cheap funding in spite of the recent turmoil in the global financial markets.</p>
The amount of additional yield that investment-grade companies have to pay versus US Treasuries, known as the spread, on their bonds has risen in recent weeks. But that comes against a plunge in benchmark Treasury yields, keeping corporate borrowing costs low. Highly rated companies also are being judged as a relatively safe place to invest, notwithstanding these low rates.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="August 12, 2011 12:36 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/984f9ba8-c469-11e0-ad9a-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>SEC charges Disney intern''s boyfriend</headline><body><![CDATA[The Securities and Exchange Commission has charged the boyfriend of a former Walt Disney intern with insider trading, alleging that he used price-sensitive information to cash in on the company''s $4bn takeover of Marvel in 2009.</p>
The SEC alleges that Toby Scammell, an investment fund adviser, bought call options in Marvel after learning that Disney was planning to acquire the comic book publisher in the summer of 2009. He learnt of the deal by overhearing one or more of his girlfriend''s conversations concerning the deal or by seeing electronic or paper documents in her possession, the SEC alleged.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="August 9, 2011 11:13 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/2305228a-c2d1-11e0-8cc7-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Sports network boosts Disney''s performance</headline><body><![CDATA[An improving consumer environment helped Walt Disney deliver a stronger-than-expected performance from its theme parks and cable networks, which powered the media group''s third-quarter profits past analysts'' expectations.</p>
Revenues for the three months to July 2 increased from $10bn to $10.7bn, while net income rose from $1.33bn to $1.47bn.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By James Fontanella-Khan in Mumbai and Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="July 26, 2011 8:37 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/d676ef94-b799-11e0-8523-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney looks to expand in India</headline><body><![CDATA[Walt Disney has bid $454m for the stake in India''s UTV Software Communications, one of Bollywood''s largest entertainment groups, that it does not already own, as it seeks to strengthen its position in one of the world''s fastest growing media markets.</p>
Disney, which already controls 50.44 per cent of UTV, said on Tuesday that it would delist the company from Indian exchanges, making it a local subsidiary of the US group.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="June 7, 2011 1:12 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/89e956bc-9093-11e0-9531-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Disney to cut 200 jobs because of lower DVD sales</headline><body><![CDATA[Walt Disney is cutting about 200 jobs from its film studio in response to the worldwide slowing of DVD sales, in a move that is likely to be followed by other studios across Hollywood.</p>
The company declined to comment but people familiar with the situation said the job cuts were in response to wider structural changes that have wreaked havoc on entertainment industry business models.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="May 11, 2011 2:02 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/71b34e28-7b5c-11e0-ae56-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney profits hit by Japan quake</headline><body><![CDATA[The devastating earthquake in Japan and one of Walt Disney''s biggest box-office flops combined to hit the media group''s second-quarter profits.</p>
The earthquake forced the temporary closure of Disney''s Tokyo theme park and its retail stores in the country while the very disappointing release of Mars Needs Moms provided a $90m blow to the group''s operating profit.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="ByPatti Waldmeir in Shanghai" date="April 8, 2011 7:14 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e0f7e0cc-61bd-11e0-88f7-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Disney breaks ground on Shanghai park</headline><body><![CDATA[<p>Disney chief executive Bob Iger says the park will be both authentically Disney and distinctly Chinese</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in New York" date="March 18, 2011 8:10 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f87cad5a-519a-11e0-888e-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Disney closes Tokyo stores</headline><body><![CDATA[Walt Disney has temporarily closed its stores in Tokyo and suspended its administrative operations in the city following last week''s devastating earthquake and tsunami and uncertainty over radiation levels.</p>
The company employs 2,200 people in Tokyo and the surrounding areas, but has told them not to come into work. Our top priority is the well-being of our employees and their families during this challenging time and we will continue to closely monitor the situation as it develops, the company said in a statement.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="February 8, 2011 11:45 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a5cc821e-33dc-11e0-b1ed-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Theme parks lift Disney results</headline><body><![CDATA[A stronger advertising market, improved attendance at its theme parks and global demand for Toy Story 3 merchandise powered Walt Disney''s first-quarter profits past expectations.</p>
Net income for the three months to January 1 rose from $844m to $1.3bn on revenues that increased from $9.7bn to $10.7bn. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Emiko Terazono" date="November 19, 2010 1:03 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/4a5653d0-f36b-11df-b34f-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Disney dreams</headline><body><![CDATA[ITV chief Adam Crozier used his platform at the Morgan Stanley TMT conference in Barcelona to pass Richard Desmond, the new Channel 5 proprietor, a backhanded compliment.</p>
I think for Channel 5, I have no doubt Richard will turn that around and turn it into a profitable station, Mr Crozier said. He''s a very good operator. I don''t think it''s an issue for ITV1. I think they will stray into some of the areas that we are in on ITV2.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="November 12, 2010 12:40 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/adca35a8-edf3-11df-8616-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Toy Story 3 and ABC help lift Disney</headline><body><![CDATA[The box-office performance of Toy Story 3 and an advertising rebound at its ABC television network lifted Walt Disney''s full-year earnings. However, the media group missed expectations for the fourth quarter due to a timing shift in the recognition of revenues at its ESPN sports channel. </p>
Net income for the 12 months to October 2 rose from $3.6bn to $4.3bn, with revenues rising from $36.1bn to $38.1bn. But fourth-quarter net income slipped from $1.1bn to $966m on revenues that fell from $9.9bn to $9.7bn.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ben Fenton in London" date="November 10, 2010 8:28 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/8498a39c-ed06-11df-9912-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Disney chief with golden touch</headline><body><![CDATA[Full-year earnings due to be released by Walt Disney 
on Thursday are likely to show Rich Ross as a man with a golden touch. </p>
Three-quarters of the way through his first year in charge of Walt Disney Studios, the global group''s most visible division, revenues were up 30 per cent to $1.6bn and operating profit had rocketed from $188m to $589m.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="October 31, 2010 10:35 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/bed78a04-e523-11df-8e0d-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney seeks Oscar for Toy Story 3''</headline><body><![CDATA[<p>Toy Story 3'' was the latest critical and commercial success from Disney''s Pixar stable</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="October 19, 2010 2:30 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/520fc796-db0b-11df-a870-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney deal on super hero movies</headline><body><![CDATA[Walt Disney has struck a $115m deal with Paramount Pictures to transfer the distribution of upcoming Marvel films The Avengers and Iron Man 3 to Disney, allowing the media group to exploit the super hero films earlier than expected.</p>
Disney acquired Marvel for $4bn at the end of last year, gaining the right to the company''s library of characters, which include the Incredible Hulk, the Fantastic Four and Daredevil. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles and Andrew Edgecliffe-Johnson in New York" date="September 24, 2010 7:35 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/112816d6-c79f-11df-8683-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Disney interactive chief to step down</headline><body><![CDATA[Steve Wadsworth, one of Walt Disney''s longest-serving senior executives, is to resign as head of the company''s interactive media group after more than a decade running the unit.</p>
Since Mr Wadsworth became president of Disney''s internet group in 1999, it has become one of the most closely watched units in a company that has vast operations in film-making, broadcasting and theme parks.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Scheherazade Daneshkhu in Paris" date="September 14, 2010 5:55 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/801681de-c01c-11df-b77d-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Euro Disney signs expansion deal</headline><body><![CDATA[Lossmaking Euro Disney has been given more time by the French government to develop a third theme park, after signing a new 20-year pact with public authorities that own the undeveloped land east of Paris.</p>
The agreement, signed on Tuesday, gives Euro Disney until 2030 to build a third park in the Marne-la-Valle region to add to the Disneyland Paris park, opened in 1992, and the adjoining Walt Disney Studios, a smaller film-themed park, which opened 10 years later.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kenneth Li in New York" date="August 30, 2010 10:25 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/95d96fa2-b466-11df-8208-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney close to internet fees agreement</headline><body><![CDATA[Disney is close to an agreement to renew running its television channels on Time Warner Cable, the fourth-largest US pay-TV operator, after the companies wrangled over payments for Disney''s ESPN broadband network, according to people familiar with the talks.</p>
TV channel contract renewal negotiations, once almost invisible from public view, have become more fraught in recent years as the economics of TV suffer from the rise of digital alternatives such as Hulu and Netflix.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="August 11, 2010 1:31 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/49e171e8-a4d1-11df-8d8c-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Box-office hits bolster Disney profits</headline><body><![CDATA[The box-office success of Alice in Wonderland, Iron Man 2 and Toy Story 3 boosted Walt Disney''s third-quarter profits while the popularity in the US of the football World Cup lifted advertising returns at ESPN, the media group''s sports network.</p>
Walt Disney third-quarter results - three months to July 3 2010 
Sales
Net profit
Earnings per share
Dividend
$10bn
$1.33bn
$0.67
-
 16%
 40%
 31%
-

]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kenneth Li and Alan Rappeport in New York" date="July 30, 2010 6:55 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/79d354c0-9bb7-11df-9ebd-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Disney sells Miramax films for $660m</headline><body><![CDATA[Walt Disney has agreed to sell the Miramax film studio to a group of investors led by Ron Tutor, a construction magnate, and Colony Capital for $660m as the entertainment conglomerate turns its focus to the digital arena.</p>
The deal will turn over a library of 700 film titles including Shakespeare in Love and Pulp Fiction to Mr Tutor, Colony and businessman Tom Barrack, who reportedly put up $100m each. The rest of the purchase will be financed by other partners, with a portion also in debt. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David Gelles in San Francisco" date="July 28, 2010 2:03 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a92771cc-99d5-11df-a0a5-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Disney clicks in to buy Playdom for $563m</headline><body><![CDATA[Walt Disney on Tuesday agreed to buy Playdom, which makes social games for Facebook, a move that sets the stage for Mickey Mouse and Iron Man to feature in games on the world''s largest social networking site. </p>
Disney paid up to $763.2m for the two-year-old company  $563.2m in mostly cash plus a performance based earn-out as high as $200m. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="July 18, 2010 9:24 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/3c4d3702-92a6-11df-9142-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Toy Story 3 set to break Disney records</headline><body><![CDATA[<p>Toy Story 3'' featuring, from left, Jessie, Woody and Buzz Lightyear, is set to be the biggest grossing animated film by Walt Disney</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="July 8, 2010 1:56 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/5ee8a20a-8a1e-11df-bd30-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Disney loses Millionaire'' case to Celador</headline><body><![CDATA[Walt Disney has lost a long-running court case against the UK creator of Who Wants to Be a Millionaire?, with a jury in a Calfornia court awarding Celador Entertainment damages of $270m following a dispute over profits from the hit game show.</p>
The defeat in a battle that lasted six years is a blow to Disney, which plans to appeal against the ruling. It said the verdict was fundamentally wrong, adding that it would seek to have it reversed.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan and Annie Saperstein in Los Angeles" date="July 6, 2010 11:00 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/4d6cfd1a-8932-11df-8ecd-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Disney to expand language schools in China</headline><body><![CDATA[Mickey Mouse might not be the most obvious choice as a language teacher but he and Donald Duck are being put to work in China by Walt Disney as part of a rapid expansion of a schools programme that aims to teach English to 150,000 children a year by 2015.</p>
Disney, which has identified Shanghai as the location of its next theme park, is the first western media company to operate schools in China. It owns a handful in Shanghai and recently opened its first in Beijing.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles and Joseph Menn in San Francisco" date="July 2, 2010 3:42 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c0c818b4-856b-11df-aa2e-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney deal aims to tap apps market</headline><body><![CDATA[Walt Disney has taken a significant step into the Apple iPhone applications business, buying Tapulous, a Silicon Valley start-up that makes mobile music games.</p>
The deal, which will be announced imminently, is for an undisclosed sum and is the first of its kind for Disney, which is keen to expand its presence in mobile games. The company has already acquired two development studios  one based in China and one in the Czech Republic  but the Tapulous deal is the first to involve a developer of applications  popularly known as apps.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles and Joseph Menn in San,Francisco" date="July 2, 2010 3:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/3ff892d0-8571-11df-aa2e-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney deal aims to tap apps market</headline><body><![CDATA[Walt Disney has taken a significant step into the Apple iPhone applications business, buying Tapulous, a Silicon Valley start-up that makes mobile music games.</p>
The deal, which will be announced imminently, is for an undisclosed sum and is the first of its kind for Disney, which is keen to expand its presence in mobile games. The company has already acquired two development studios - one based in China and one in the Czech Republic - but the Tapulous deal is the first to involve a developer of applications - popularly known as "apps".</p>
The Tapulous deal validates an economic model that did not exist until two years ago, when Apple launched the App Store. Since then, thousands of programmers have tried to get their wares distributed on the platform, which has close to 100m users.</p>
Big media companies such as Disney are monitoring the apps industry with increasing interest, competing with games companies, such as Electronic Arts, for popular developers.</p>
With initial public offerings of mobile games developers still rare, the interest of Disney and its rivals broadens the number of potential exits for investors in apps companies.</p>
Tapulous makes mobile games in the vein of Activision''s Guitar Hero . Its most popular title, Tap Tap Revenge,  allows players to tap their iPhone to the beat of a song. Tapulous generates revenues from a range of sources: its games are free but players pay to buy particular songs.</p>
The Disney deal will see Bart Decrem, founder of Tapulous, join Disney to help manage its mobile games division. The deal was struck by Disney''s Interactive Media Group.</p>
Bob Iger, Disney''s chief executive, has taken a great interest in the iPad and hailed it as a potential "game-changer" for the media industry.</p>
The Disney ABC Player app has been downloaded more than 850,000 times since the iPad was launched in April, with more than 4.5m episodes of ABC programmes played on the device.</p>
The studio''s latest film, The Sorcerer''s Apprentice,  is the first new release to be offered via its movies app, along with other Disney movies that are already in cinemas. "The Disney movie app provides fans with a dynamic and engaging experience," said Greg Brandeau, chief technology officer of Walt Disney Studios.</p>
The app can also connect consumers directly to online retailers such to purchase Disney movies on Blu-ray or DVD.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="May 27, 2010 3:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/970f4d3c-6926-11df-aa7e-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Pair on Disney insider charges</headline><body><![CDATA[A Walt Disney employee and her boyfriend have been charged with insider trading by the Securities and Exchange Commission after it was alleged they offered to sell price sensitive information about the media group to a group of hedge funds.</p>The SEC claims Bonnie Hoxie, an assistant in Disney''s corporate communications team, and her boyfriend, Yonni Sebbag, anonymously contacted more than 20 hedge funds in the US and Europe offering pre-release results of the company''s second-quarter earnings in return for payment.</p>But some of the hedge funds alerted the SEC, which in turn brought in the Federal Bureau of Investigations and the US Attorney''s Office to investigate.</p>The FBI set up an undercover sting operation and began receiving e-mails from Mr Sebbag after its agents began posing as investment managers.</p>It is alleged that Mr Sebbag promised to share insider information on a regular basis. "I don''t think we will get caught if we stay discrete and careful," he wrote in one e-mail.</p>He claimed that Bob Iger, Disney''s chief executive, was in "serious and advanced negotiations with two private equity firms to sell them the ABC network but no price has been determined yet".</p>Disney said it had been "fully co-operating with this investigation". It added that the reference in the complaint to conversations regarding ABC "were and are false".</p>In another e-mail Mr Sebbag allegedly discussed the payment he wanted in return for the information: "$15k sounds great and $30k even better as I hope you will make a killing from Q2 earnings."</p>The SEC alleges that Mr Sebbag e-mailed the undercover agents a confidential 107-page report two days before the recent quarterly earnings announcement. It contained details about Disney''s quarterly performance and future prospects for its various business divisions, the SEC said.</p>Mr Sebbag met the undercover agents in person on May 14 in New York to collect his payment. He allegedly asked for their advice on how to open an offshore account. He left the meeting with an envelope containing $15,000 and was arrested yesterday. Ms Hoxie was also arrested for her role.</p>"Hoxie and Sebbag stole Disney''s confidential pre-release earnings information and put it up for sale," said Robert Khuzami, director of SEC enforcement.</p>Ms Hoxie and Mr Sebbag could not immediately be reached for comment.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="May 26, 2010 8:17 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/7571ada6-68f8-11df-910b-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Disney pair charged with insider trading</headline><body><![CDATA[A Walt Disney employee and her boyfriend have been arrested and charged with offering to sell price- sensitive information about the US media group to hedge funds.</p>
US prosecutors allege Bonnie Hoxie, an assistant in Disney''s corporate communications team, and her boyfriend, Yonni Sebbag, anonymously contacted more than 20 hedge funds in the US and Europe offering pre-release results of the company''s second-quarter earnings, up to April 3, in return for payment.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="May 12, 2010 3:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/3834bc8e-5d5f-11df-8373-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Disney''s box-office hit lifts profits</headline><body><![CDATA[The box-office performance of Alice in Wonderland powered Walt Disney to a second quarter that beat expectations, with Tim Burton''s 3D release becoming one of the company''s biggest hits.</p>The film''s $962m haul was a big factor in Disney''s profits, which rose to $998m from $653m last time on earnings per share of $0.48 that exceeded the consensus estimate of $0.45.</p>Disney''s films are on a box-office winning streak. The release of Iron Man 2 , owned by the company following last year''s $4bn purchase of Marvel Entertainment, has generated $334m in its first week on release.</p>The group has a number of "franchise films" in the works, with sequels to Cars , Pirates of the Caribbean  - Disney''s most lucrative series - and Monsters, Inc.  due in the next two years.</p>"When a franchise film is successful at Disney, many of our businesses benefit, driving superior returns," Bob Iger, chief executive, said.</p>The second-quarter profits jump would have been more pronounced were it not for the performance of Disney''s broadcasting business.</p>Operating income at the division, which includes the ABC network, fell from $162m to $123m, reflecting lower prime time and news advertising revenues.</p>Disney had more encouraging news about the advertising market. Jay Rasulo, chief financial officer, said last-minute advertisement sales were running 35 per cent above rates set in the "upfront period", when most US television advertising is sold.</p>Advertising revenues at TV stations owned by ABC were up 20 per cent, driven by healthy spending in the automotive, political and retail categories, while advertising in the third quarter was running 30 per cent above upfront rates, he said.</p>Profits were up at ESPN, Disney''s sports cable channel, although its performance was hit by higher programming costs associated with the group''s purchase of rights to screen English Premier League football.</p>"ESPN has invested in the world''s most exciting sports events and presents them in an integrated and engaging way," Mr Iger said, adding that the channel''s "innovation and emphasis on quality continue to drive strong ratings".</p>At Disney''s theme parks and cruise lines business, operating income slipped from $171m to $150m, reflecting increased fuel costs at the cruise line.</p>Mr Rasulo said the group had not hedged its fuel costs in the quarter, unlike the prior year when it was able to offset price increases.</p>Disney''s second-quarter revenues rose from $8.1bn to $8.6bn.</p>The shares were down $1.16, or about 3 per cent, at $34.64 in after-hours trading.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan" date="May 12, 2010 3:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/7973d00a-5d5e-11df-8373-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Box-office hit powers Disney</headline><body><![CDATA[The bumper box-office performance of Alice in Wonderland powered Walt Disney to a second quarter that beat expectations, with Tim Burton''s 3D release becoming one of the group''s biggest hits.</p>
The film''s $962m haul was a big factor in Disney''s profits, which rose to $998m from $653m last time on earnings per share of $0.48 against a consensus estimate of $0.45.</p>
Disney''s films are on a box-office winning streak: the release of Iron Man 2 , owned by the company following last year''s $4bn purchase of Marvel Entertainment, has generated $334m in its first week on release.</p>
The company has a number of "franchise films" in the works, with sequels to Cars , Pirates of the Caribbean and Monsters, Inc.  due in the next two years.</p>
Matthew Garrahan, Los Angeles</p>]]> </body></entry></news>