
<news><entry author="By Carola Hoyos in London" date="October 13, 2009 3:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/a473c1d6-b78f-11de-9812-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Ghana moves to block Exxon bid</headline><body><![CDATA[Ghana''s national oil company is threatening to scupper ExxonMobil''s bid to buy a stake in the country''s Jubilee field, the largest deepwater oilfield in Africa.</p>
The national oil company is pushing CNOOC, the Chinese state-owned oil company, to make a counterbid for Kosmos, the small US-based company that ExxonMobil last week decided to acquire by signing an exclusive binding agreement worth more than $4bn (2.7bn, 2.5bn).</p>
Kosmos, which discovered the oilfield during the previous Ghanaian presidency, has fallen out of favour with the government, according to industry insiders. It is backed by Blackstone and Warburg Pincus, the private equity groups, which stand to generate a fourfold return on the deal.</p>
GNPC''s decision runs the risk of undermining the reputation of Ghana as one of west Africa''s more stable and transparent countries for investors, analysts said. Robin West, chief executive of PFC Energy, the consultancy, said: "The Ghanaians run a serious risk if they disrupt this sales process. It could delay projects and chill investments."</p>
Several international and national oil companies bid for Kosmos. But, CNOOC was not among them, people close to the Chinese company said. Instead, CNOOC conducted parallel talks with GNPC, which hired Morgan Stanley to advise it. Meanwhile, the sale of Kosmos was delayed by several months.</p>
Joseph Oteng-Adjei, Ghana''s energy minister, told the Financial Times at the time he had not wanted to block the sale process and that he had wanted to protect Ghana''s interests "without cheating or dec-eiving anyone who has benefited the country by investing in our oil industry".</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Carola Hoyos in London" date="October 12, 2009 10:15 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/f322f0f8-b763-11de-9812-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Ghana tries to block Exxon bid for Kosmos</headline><body><![CDATA[Ghana''s national oil company is threatening to scupper ExxonMobil''s bid to buy a stake in the country''s Jubilee field, the largest deepwater oilfield in Africa. </p>
The national oil company is pushing CNOOC, the Chinese state-owned company, to make a counterbid for Kosmos, the US-based company that Exxon last week decided to acquire by signing an exclusive binding agreement worth more than $4bn (2.7bn, 2.5bn). </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Martin Arnold and Carola Hoyos in London" date="October 7, 2009 3:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/0f69aaba-b2da-11de-b7d2-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Exxon nears $4bn Ghana deal</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil has agreed to pay $4bn to acquire a stake in Ghana''s Jubilee field, the biggest deepwater oil field in Africa.</p>
The largest western oil group is buying Kosmos Energy, the stake holder that is backed by Blackstone and Warburg Pincus, the private equity groups. The deal would generate about a four times return for the pair, which invested $800m in Kosmos.</p>
The Kosmos sale was first mooted at the end of last year and attracted interest from many of the world''s big oil groups. But the deal was delayed by Ghana, which felt left out of the sale process.</p>
The country''s national oil company had tried to mount a bid for Kosmos, people close to the Ghanaian government said, but it has failed to raise the capital or push down the price.</p>
Exxon''s offer still needs the approval of the Ghanaian government and details of the deal have not yet been disclosed.</p>
The Jubilee field, discovered in 2007 off the coast of Ghana, is divided into two licence areas. Kosmos has a stake of almost 31 per cent in one, and 18 per cent in the other. Anadarko of the US and the UK''s Tullow are the other big shareholders.</p>
Dallas-based Kosmos was founded by Jim Musselman and Brian Maxted, two former executives of Triton Energy, which discovered the Ceiba Field in Equatorial Guinea, before being sold for $3.2bn to Amerada Hess in 2001.</p>
Kosmos wrote to all bidders on Monday night telling them the sale process had ended after it reached an "exclusive binding agreement" with Exxon.</p>
Analysts have been expecting ExxonMobil, with its large cash position, to make acquisitions since the economic and credit crisis began. But it has said it was waiting for prices to stabilise. The deal also underscores a growing interest in west Africa by the oil majors, which have been limited in their ability to expand by rising resource nationalism in places such as Russia and Venezuela.</p>
But Neil McMahon, analyst at Sanford C. Bernstein, questioned the deal''s logic, given that it does not give it a majority stake, operatorship or the potential to make greater profits through further exploration. He called it "an odd deal". "What''s the up side? It makes it feel like they are betting on the oil price upside and Exxon never bets on the oil price," he said.</p>
Anadarko''s shares traded up 4.8 per cent at $64.62 yesterday afternoon, while Tullow''s shares traded up 8.4 per cent at pence at 12.09.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward, Pharmaceuticals Correspondent" date="September 11, 2014 7:28 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f7f00654-39ca-11e4-83c4-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer says window still open'' for tax inversions</headline><body><![CDATA[You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward and Arash Massoudi in London" date="August 24, 2014 11:43 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/ee806732-2b6d-11e4-b052-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer weighs options on AstraZeneca bid</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward, Pharmaceuticals Correspondent" date="August 4, 2014 1:13 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b69c8a70-1bab-11e4-adc7-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>AstraZeneca chairman Leif Johansson defends Pfizer rebuff</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward, Pharmaceuticals Correspondent" date="July 29, 2014 7:28 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b494286e-171e-11e4-b0d7-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer refuses to rule out tax inversion deals</headline><body><![CDATA[Pfizer has called for fundamental reform of the US tax system  but said it was still interested in acquisitions that would allow it to put offshore revenues beyond the reach of the US taxman in the absence of change. 
</p>
Ian Read, chief executive, said Pfizer was lobbying in Washington for an overhaul of tax rules that he argued put US companies at a disadvantage. His comments coincided with moves by senior Democrats in both chambers of Congress to cut off more companies that change their domicile from lucrative federal contracts.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jonathan Guthrie" date="Last updated: July 8, 2014 8:27 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/67f7ba6c-0688-11e4-ba32-00144feab7de.html"><headline>AbbVie avoids Pfizer errors in bear hug against Shire</headline><body><![CDATA[My pals are bigger than your pals. AbbVie has resorted to an old playground intimidation tactic, by implying a majority of shareholders back its revised 30bn proposal to buy Shire for 51.15 per share. </p>
Investors, who are constitutionally committed to being non-committal, are shrugging off the impertinence. Their bigger worry is that the US drugs group could bungle the bid, as Pfizer did in pursuing AstraZeneca.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alison Smith and Arash Massoudi" date="May 29, 2014 10:31 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/154ea340-e74b-11e3-88be-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>UK lesson for Stryker and Pfizer</headline><body><![CDATA[Twice in two weeks, US companies interested in buying UK groups have walked away after coming up against British takeover rules.</p>
On Wednesday, Stryker, the medical device maker, said it did not intend to make an offer for Smith  Nephew. Just days earlier Pfizer had abandoned efforts to engage with AstraZeneca on its 55 per share approach to the British pharma group.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Adam Bogdanor" date="May 28, 2014 5:20 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a476fdf0-e5bc-11e3-a7f5-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>The regulators were right to force Pfizer''s hand</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward, Pharmaceuticals Correspondent" date="May 26, 2014 3:32 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/418ce3cc-e4b7-11e3-9b2b-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer admits defeat in AstraZeneca bid</headline><body><![CDATA[Pfizer has admitted defeat in its pursuit of AstraZeneca, bringing an end to a month-long takeover battle that pitted two of the world''s biggest drugmakers against each other and stirred political controversy on both sides of the Atlantic.</p>
The US company officially abandoned its 69.4bn offer for its British rival two hours before the 5pm Monday deadline for a deal to be struck under UK takeover rules.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Peggy Hollinger" date="May 25, 2014 2:58 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/9a1a854c-e298-11e3-a829-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer strategy revives fears for future of life sciences in UK</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward" date="May 23, 2014 7:39 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/4666c62c-e293-11e3-a829-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>How Pfizer snatched defeat from victory</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lina Saigol" date=" May 23, 2014 6:45 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f9dd5cec-e271-11e3-a829-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>A quick guide to put Pfizer top of the Takeover Panel''s class</headline><body><![CDATA[
After a five-month pursuit of AstraZeneca, Pfizer''s bid this week all but fell apart when the UK drugmaker rejected the US group''s final 69.4bn offer, with blame attributed equally between Pfizer boss Ian Read, his investment bankers at Bank of America Merrill Lynch, JPMorgan and Guggenheim Partners, and his PR guru Sir Alan Parker.
</p>
Team Pfizer clearly did not do enough studying, misreading the political sentiment and miscalculating the price they needed to pay to seal the deal.
 They now have three months to revise before they can try again. With some shareholders rooting for them, they could pass the resit with flying colours. To help them prepare, the Financial Times has devised a quick study guide.
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward, Arash Massoudi and Miles Johnson in London" date="May 22, 2014 7:59 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a5658c12-e1cb-11e3-b7c4-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Big AstraZeneca investors push for further talks with Pfizer</headline><body><![CDATA[Big shareholders in AstraZeneca have told the UK drugmaker they want the board to reopen takeover talks with Pfizer as early as August, after accepting that a deal is unlikely to be agreed with its US rival before Monday''s bid deadline.</p>
BlackRock and Schroders are among those that have told AstraZeneca they want the company to take a fresh look at a possible deal after the three-month cooling-off period required under UK takeover rules.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By James Politi in Wilmington, Delaware" date="May 22, 2014 7:37 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c194e85e-dd40-11e3-8546-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Delaware fears job losses if Pfizer returns to chase AstraZeneca</headline><body><![CDATA[AFP]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Arash Massoudi and Andrew Ward in London" date="May 21, 2014 7:33 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/4d6fba64-e108-11e3-b59f-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>AstraZeneca deal in injury time'' after final Pfizer offer</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward, Miles Johnson and Arash Massoudi in London" date="May 21, 2014 4:07 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/d4f46e04-e0f3-11e3-a934-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>AstraZeneca battles to shore up support for Pfizer rejection</headline><body><![CDATA[AstraZeneca is battling to shore up shareholder support for its decision to resist Pfizer''s 69.4bn takeover approach as the US drugmaker makes a last-ditch push to revive the stalled deal.</p>
Both companies were engaged in intensive lobbying of investors on Wednesday with just five days to go before the deadline for Pfizer to secure AstraZeneca''s backing for a deal or walk away.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward, Pharmaceuticals Correspondent" date="May 20, 2014 7:32 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/05e0389c-e039-11e3-9534-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer strategy in spotlight after failure of AstraZeneca deal</headline><body><![CDATA[EPA<p>Ian Read, Chairman and Chief Executive of Pfize</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sam Fleming" date="May 20, 2014 1:47 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/01eee76e-e012-11e3-b709-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Q&amp;A: Pfizer clarifies bid intentions on AstraZeneca</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward and Arash Massoudi in London and Ed Hammond in New York" date="May 21, 2014 12:29 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/05a84e26-e004-11e3-b709-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer scrambles to keep Astra bid alive</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Miles Johnson and Andrew Ward in London" date="May 19, 2014 8:45 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/af8237fc-df70-11e3-8842-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Astra investors split on Pfizer''s rejection</headline><body><![CDATA[Shareholders in AstraZeneca were split by the company''s decision to reject a final 69bn offer from Pfizer, with some arguing that ts management had betrayed investors while others praised the board''s faith in its long term prospects.</p>
As AstraZeneca''s shares tumbled following the rejection statement, some large investors argued that Pascal Soriot, chief executive, should have allowed them to make up their own mind over the latest offer.
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward and Miles Johnson in London and Ed Hammond in New York" date="May 19, 2014 7:30 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/dab786fa-df77-11e3-8842-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer snub triggers recrimination at Astra</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Arash Massoudi and Andrew Ward in London and Ed Hammond in New York" date="May 19, 2014 6:35 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f0e0e56c-df76-11e3-8842-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>AstraZeneca and Pfizer: High-stakes brinkmanship ends with recriminations</headline><body><![CDATA[When Ian Read flew back across the Atlantic on Thursday evening after a four-day stay in London, he was feeling cautiously optimistic about pulling off one of the biggest pharmaceuticals deals in history.</p>
The chairman and chief executive of Pfizer had survived two days of hostile questioning about his takeover proposal from UK lawmakers and meetings with shareholders in AstraZeneca had left him confident they were open to a deal. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elizabeth Rigby, Deputy Political Editor" date="May 19, 2014 3:36 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/bfcaeabe-df57-11e3-86a4-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Labour keeps up pressure on PM over Pfizer</headline><body><![CDATA[Labour on Monday welcomed AstraZeneca''s rejection of Pfizer''s final 69bn bid approach as the opposition party again criticised Prime Minister David Cameron for acting as a cheerleader for the US drugmaker. </p>
Chuka Umunna, shadow business secretary, said the UK pharmaceutical company''s decision to reject the improved offer vindicated Labour''s misgivings over the deal, as he accused the prime minister of failing to act to protect British science and jobs. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sam Fleming and Lindsay Whipp" date="May 19, 2014 12:27 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/907ff28e-df31-11e3-86a4-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Q&amp;A: Is the possibility of a Pfizer-AstraZeneca deal now dead?</headline><body><![CDATA[Pfizer is redefining final by making its second final offer to acquire AstraZeneca, which the UK company has rejected. Does this mean that the possibility of a Pfizer-AstraZeneca combination is now dead? </p>
The US pharmaceutical company''s 55-a-share proposal did not meet AstraZeneca''s demand that any offer is more than 10 per cent above the level contained in Pfizer''s Friday proposal of 53.50 a share. It represented a 45 per cent premium from its undisturbed share price on May 2. </p>
Pfizer''s proposal for AstraZeneca in numbers

Offer
Amount per share
Values Astra at...
% higher than final'' offer 1
Composition

Final'' offer 1
53.50
67.5bn
N/A
Cash: 21.57 (40%)</p>
Pfizer Shares: 1.845 (60%)</p>

Final'' offer 2
55.00
69.4bn
2.8%
Cash: 24.76 (45%)</p>
Pfizer Shares: 1.747 (55%)</p>

*Astra''s demands
More than 58.85
74.3bn
More than 10%
Not made explicit
Current valuation
N/A
About 52bn following a 13% intraday decline in its share price on Monday
N/A
N/A


]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward, Pharmaceuticals Correspondent" date="May 19, 2014 9:33 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/9762b966-df26-11e3-86a4-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Timeline: How Pfizer''s approach for AstraZeneca unfolded</headline><body><![CDATA[November 25 2013: Ian Read, Pfizer''s chairman and chief executive, makes the first contact with Leif Johansson, chairman of AstraZeneca, expressing interest in a deal to create the world''s biggest pharmaceuticals group. Mr Johansson expresses confidence in AstraZeneca''s prospects as a standalone company but agrees to meet for exploratory talks.</p>
January 5 2014: Mr Johansson and Pascal Soriot, AstraZeneca chief executive, lead a small delegation to New York. At this meeting, Mr Read makes a preliminary offer worth 46.61 a share, 30 per cent in cash and the rest in Pfizer shares.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward, Miles Johnson and Arash Massoudi in London and Ed Hammond in New York" date="May 19, 2014 1:06 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/41e4cb30-df23-11e3-86a4-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>AstraZeneca shares tumble as it snubs Pfizer''s final'' bid</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>Pascal Soriot, AstraZeneca CEO, and Ian Read, CEO of Pfizer</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Hammond in New York and Andrew Ward and Arash Massoudi in London" date="May 19, 2014 2:28 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/3b5e8122-ded1-11e3-9640-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>AstraZeneca prepares to reject Pfizer''s final'' 69bn offer</headline><body><![CDATA[AstraZeneca is preparing to reject a 69bn takeover bid by rival drugmaker Pfizer just hours after its US suitor said it would walk away if its offer were rebuffed, putting into doubt a deal that would be the largest foreign takeover of a UK company.</p>
The 55-per-share bid, upped from 50 two weeks ago, was viewed by key members of AstraZeneca''s management team and its board of directors as falling short of properly valuing the company, according to people familiar with the matter. </p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward in New York and Arash Massoudi in London" date="May 16, 2014 11:17 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c1c90cca-dd3f-11e3-8546-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer seeks breast cancer drug approval</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By George Parker and Caroline Binham in London and Andrew Ward in New York" date="May 16, 2014 8:10 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/82af4d74-dd0d-11e3-8546-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Labour raises political stakes with threat to block Pfizer bid</headline><body><![CDATA[<p>Shadow business secretary Chuka Umunna</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elizabeth Rigby and George Parker in London and Alex Barker in Brussels" date="May 15, 2014 8:34 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/d7447bc4-dc41-11e3-a33d-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Cameron faces strategy test on Pfizer bid</headline><body><![CDATA[Britain has been scathing about the French government''s new decree allowing it to defend strategic industries from foreign takeovers; David Cameron''s government is about to be tested on whether it has a better approach.</p>
After a week of intense political activity at Westminster, Mr Cameron is braced for what the market widely believes is inevitable: a formal bid by Pfizer, the US pharmaceuticals group, for Britain''s AstraZeneca.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Milne, Nordic Correspondent" date="May 15, 2014 2:05 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/143ea146-dc27-11e3-8511-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Swedish leader speaks out against Pfizer approach for AstraZeneca</headline><body><![CDATA[Simon Hoegsberg<p>Stefan Lfven</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Hammond in New York and Elizabeth Rigby and Miles Johnson in London" date="May 14, 2014 8:14 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/407afc08-db89-11e3-a460-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>AstraZeneca investors express interest in higher Pfizer offer</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>Pascal Soriot, AstraZeneca CEO, and Ian Read, CEO of Pfizer</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Jack and Elizabeth Rigby" date="May 14, 2014 8:37 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/4b0a73d6-db45-11e3-94ad-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer says takeover would not delay drug development</headline><body><![CDATA[The chief executive of Pfizer has said drugs development would if anything be accelerated if his company took over AstraZeneca, rejecting criticism from the UK drugmaker that a takeover could cost lives by delaying the launch of new medicines. </p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By James Politi in Washington" date="May 14, 2014 3:16 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/32ca5d36-db09-11e3-9a27-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Top Republican rebuffs quick Pfizer tax legislation</headline><body><![CDATA[The top Republican tax writer in the US Senate has quashed the idea of a quick move in Congress targeting tax inversion deals in the wake of Pfizer''s $106bn bid for AstraZeneca, saying the problem should be solved through broader tax reform.</p>
Orrin Hatch of Utah, his party''s senior member on the Senate finance committee, on Tuesday sent the clearest signal yet that Republicans will not embrace proposals by congressional Democrats and the White House to enact legislation that would make it much harder for companies such as Pfizer to redomicile overseas for tax reasons.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward and Elizabeth Rigby" date="May 13, 2014 8:32 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/dfadf9f4-dab9-11e3-9a27-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer''s AstraZeneca bid: How MPs probed proposed deal</headline><body><![CDATA[PA<p>Pfizer chief Ian Read gives evidence to the Commons business committee on Tuesday</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Brian Groom, Business and Employment Editor" date="May 13, 2014 6:39 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/6da9f32c-daae-11e3-9a27-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Unions call on ministers to block Pfizer bid for AstraZeneca</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty<p>Shut the front door: Jefferies analyst Jeffrey Holford characterised the overly optimistic'' AstraZeneca revenue forecasts on Tuesday as an obvious defence tactic''</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward, Elizabeth Rigby and Miles Johnson" date="May 13, 2014 3:36 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/10c51cec-daa7-11e3-a448-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer says AstraZeneca merger would cut R&amp;D budgets</headline><body><![CDATA[Pfizer has admitted its proposed 63bn takeover of AstraZeneca would result in cuts to research and development budgets and has refused to rule out job cuts.</p>
Ian Read, Pfizer''s chairman and chief executive, emerged relatively unscathed from a grilling by MPs about his plans for the UK''s second-biggest pharmaceuticals company. </p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jonathan Guthrie" date="Last updated: May 13, 2014 8:11 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/1a7d9198-da8d-11e3-8273-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer tries to sedate 12 angry MPs</headline><body><![CDATA[No revival of Twelve Angry Men has taken such liberties with an original script as the version performed by MPs on Tuesday. Actor-director Adrian Bailey has relocated the jury room drama to the Commons business select committee and placed the defendant  absent in the 1954 teleplay  centre stage in the form of the boss of vast pharmaceuticals group Pfizer.</p>
Another difference (spoiler alert!) is that suspicions of jurors intensify rather than diminish. Under cross-examination, the tycoon dodges commitments to fixed levels of UK research spending if he buys AstraZeneca, a cosy Mom n'' Pop drugs multinational.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elizabeth Rigby and Andrew Ward" date="May 13, 2014 8:18 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c455ba94-da9f-11e3-a448-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer concedes AZ takeover means cuts to jobs and R&amp;D</headline><body><![CDATA[PA<p>Pfizer chief Ian Read gives evidence to the Commons business committee on Tuesday</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andy Sharman and Richard Milne" date="May 13, 2014 8:39 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/66acf760-da66-11e3-a448-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer disappointed at AstraZeneca''s lack of engagement</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By James Politi in Washington" date="May 13, 2014 1:07 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/61b0a974-da29-11e3-920f-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer declines to commit over US jobs</headline><body><![CDATA[Pfizer declined on Monday to offer firm guarantees to the governors of Maryland and Delaware that it could protect AstraZeneca''s 5,000-strong US workforce in the two states, saying it was premature to judge the impact on jobs of the $106bn takeover bid for its UK rival.</p>
In a letter to Martin O''Malley, Maryland governor, and Jack Markell, Delaware governor, sent on Monday night, Pfizer chairman Ian Read said his company would continue to have research, operational and manufacturing activity in the US with a significant number of employees.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward, Pharmaceuticals Correspondent" date="May 12, 2014 7:21 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/d8da97b2-d9d9-11e3-b3e3-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Drug output at heart of Pfizer deal debate</headline><body><![CDATA[At the heart of debate over the future of AstraZeneca is a simple question: In whose hands would the pharmaceutical company''s laboratories produce the most valuable drugs?</p>
UK lawmakers will be probing for an answer on Tuesday when Ian Read, chairman and chief executive of Pfizer, is quizzed by the House of Commons'' business committee over its 63bn approach for its British rival.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Milne, Nordic Correspondent" date="May 11, 2014 7:55 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/fd358e4c-d901-11e3-837f-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer bid for AstraZeneca revives painful memories for Sweden</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward and Helen Warrell in London and Richard Milne in Oslo" date="May 11, 2014 12:30 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b6439a54-d8f9-11e3-837f-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>David Cameron cautions against intervention on Pfizer deal</headline><body><![CDATA[David Cameron has warned that Britain must not pull up the drawbridge against foreign investors as Downing Street pushed back against pressure from the opposition Labour party to intervene in Pfizer''s proposed 63bn takeover of AstraZeneca.</p>
The prime minister said the UK benefited massively from its economic openness and insisted the government was making very good progress in seeking job assurances from Pfizer, even without seeking new powers to intervene formally.</p>
His comments came as Ian Read, chairman and chief executive of the US drugmaker, prepared to fly to London on Monday to be quizzed by MPs on his plans for what would be the biggest foreign takeover in UK history.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Milne, Nordic Correspondent" date="May 11, 2014 12:09 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/22dc41dc-d780-11e3-a47c-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Swedish research bodies worried'' over Pfizer bid for AstraZeneca</headline><body><![CDATA[The two leading research bodies in Sweden have spoken out against Pfizer''s $110bn bid for AstraZeneca, criticising mergers in the pharmaceutical sector and the US company''s previous form.</p>
The head of the Karolinska Institutet, a Stockholm university that accounts for almost half of the medical research in Sweden, and the chairman of the body behind the Nobel Prizes told the Financial Times of their concerns, in their first public comments on a takeover offer for the Anglo-Swedish company that has raised heckles on both sides of the Atlantic.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward, Pharmaceuticals Correspondent" date="May 10, 2014 12:51 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/deff4618-d823-11e3-93c7-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer launches fight back against AstraZeneca takeover critics</headline><body><![CDATA[Corbis]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elizabeth Rigby and George Parker" date="May 9, 2014 8:57 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/5a12c48e-d788-11e3-80e0-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Political headwinds change for Pfizer chief</headline><body><![CDATA[FT]]> </body></entry><entry author="By James Politi in Washington and Andrew Ward and George Parker in London" date="May 9, 2014 8:43 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/1cb1ae3a-d755-11e3-a47c-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>US politicians step up Pfizer scrutiny over deal for AstraZeneca</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elizabeth Rigby, Andrew Ward and Miles Johnson" date="May 8, 2014 11:13 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/08accbb0-d6cc-11e3-b95e-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Wellcome Trust raises concerns'' over Pfizer bid for AstraZeneca</headline><body><![CDATA[Britain''s biggest medical research foundation has told the government it has major concerns over Pfizer''s 63bn offer for AstraZeneca, as the Wellcome Trust became the latest powerful voice to weigh in over the mooted deal.</p>
Sir William Castell, the chair of the world''s third largest charitable foundation, and Jeremy Farrar, director of Wellcome Trust, outlined their concerns in a private letter to George Osborne last Friday as the US drugmaker made its opening offer for the UK firm.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By James Politi in Washington" date="May 8, 2014 8:50 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a7ff8f52-d679-11e3-907c-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Senator takes aim at tax inversion deals like Pfizer-AstraZeneca</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Vanessa Houlder" date="May 7, 2014 8:48 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/51344ff4-d5f3-11e3-a239-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer case stirs unease at UK tax haven charges</headline><body><![CDATA[PA]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elizabeth Rigby, Andrew Ward and David Oakley" date="May 7, 2014 2:22 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a116ada0-d5df-11e3-83b2-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Cameron wants more commitments from Pfizer on AstraZeneca deal</headline><body><![CDATA[David Cameron has told Pfizer he wants stronger assurances of its commitment to UK science as he left open the option of extending government powers to intervene in the US drugmaker''s 63bn takeover approach for AstraZeneca.</p>
In a hardening of Downing Street''s attitude towards the deal, the prime minister indicated Pfizer needed to do more to win the government''s blessing for what would be the biggest foreign takeover of a British company.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By James Politi and Richard McGregor in Washington" date="May 7, 2014 11:34 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/2c643a12-d586-11e3-9bca-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Collective shrug to Pfizer bid reflects Congress stalemate</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Milne in Oslo, Andrew Ward in London and Alex Barker in Brussels" date="May 6, 2014 11:00 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e156005e-d531-11e3-adec-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Sweden offers cautionary tale to UK over potential Pfizer deal</headline><body><![CDATA[Pfizer''s bid for AstraZeneca has so far drawn the most scrutiny in the UK. But the company''s other home market  Sweden  offers a lesson in what can happen when big drug companies are sold to foreign rivals.</p>
Sweden oversaw the sale of both Astra and Pharmacia  the crown jewels of its pharmaceutical industry  at the end of the 1990s, losing the headquarters of both. Pharmacia was eventually bought by Pfizer in a $60bn deal in 2002, but still some rancour lingers.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Barker in Brussels and Andrew Ward and Elizabeth Rigby in London" date="May 6, 2014 8:31 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/749be8ac-d531-11e3-adec-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Swedish minister warns over Pfizer''s plans for AstraZeneca</headline><body><![CDATA[Shut the front door: Jefferies analyst Jeffrey Holford characterised the overly optimistic'' AstraZeneca revenue forecasts on Tuesday as an obvious defence tactic''Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elizabeth Rigby, Andrew Ward and Kiran Stacey" date="May 6, 2014 8:20 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/37a8cf50-d545-11e3-adec-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>David Cameron''s party advisers had been paid by Pfizer</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jonathan Guthrie" date=" May 6, 2014 11:02 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/00450d32-d502-11e3-adec-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer''s 2014 tax cut matters more than AZ''s 2023 sales</headline><body><![CDATA[It is safe to predict that 2023 will be a landmark year for Lombard, as for AstraZeneca, which forecasts revenues will be 76 per cent higher at $45bn. Following a buyout, this column will have become a multinational media empire run from a yacht moored in Bora Bora, while this columnist will have mastered cold fusion and regrown a full head of hair. </p>
The safeness of these predictions resides not in their accuracy, but in the low probability that anyone will remember them nine years from now and complain if they were wrong. So sales estimates published by the Anglo-Swedish drugmaker are best interpreted as an artefact of its battle to make would-be acquirer Pfizer offer more money or sling its hook.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sam Fleming" date="May 5, 2014 8:52 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c959a6e8-d3ad-11e3-8d23-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer faces trickier takeover rules</headline><body><![CDATA[In its pursuit of its quarry, Pfizer will have to negotiate UK takeover rules that have become trickier to navigate since the start of the decade. </p>
The political controversy over Kraft''s takeover of Cadbury, the confectioner, in 2010, and a subsequent speech by the UK company''s former chairman Sir Roger Carr, led to revisions of the Takeover Code in 2011 to strengthen the position of target companies and force bidders to put more information into the public domain. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By George Parker, Political Editor" date="May 5, 2014 6:38 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/47071158-d466-11e3-bf4e-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Downing St under pressure to recalibrate reaction on Pfizer bid</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By George Parker and Andrew Ward" date="May 5, 2014 7:57 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0ca7ff46-d44c-11e3-a122-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>AstraZeneca urges David Cameron to be neutral over Pfizer bid</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward" date="May 4, 2014 6:39 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/ba383d00-d399-11e3-b0be-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer break-up may follow AstraZeneca deal</headline><body><![CDATA[Pfizer has spent the past week setting out its vision to create a transatlantic pharmaceuticals powerhouse through its proposed 63bn takeover of AstraZeneca.</p>
Yet many analysts and investors believe the US group''s interest in its UK rival is less about empire-building and more about fattening up Pfizer for a break-up.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jim Pickard and Andrew Ward in London" date="May 4, 2014 7:13 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c4157c5c-d36c-11e3-b0be-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Political row intensifies over Pfizer bid for AstraZeneca</headline><body><![CDATA[Newscast]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Jack and Clive Cookson" date="May 2, 2014 11:01 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/6f71c502-d20e-11e3-97a6-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Bid puts Pfizer''s DNA under microscope</headline><body><![CDATA[If companies could be said to have DNA, then Pfizer''s could be encoded with the message acquire to survive. While other pharmaceutical groups have grown through developing and commercialising their own products, the US giant has maintained its leading position in large part through takeovers.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By George Parker and Jim Pickard" date="May 2, 2014 6:45 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/aecffcc0-d202-11e3-8b5b-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Cameron green flag for Pfizer''s proposed AstraZeneca purchase</headline><body><![CDATA[David Cameron on Friday effectively raised a green flag for Pfizer''s proposed purchase of AstraZeneca, in a sign to his critics that he has no intention of closing Britain''s doors to 63bn of potential inward investment.</p>
Lord Heseltine, the former Tory deputy prime minister, has argued that Britain needs to build up its legal defences against foreign takeovers, after the Pfizer bid served as a reminder that the UK has few national interest get-outs to stop such bids.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jonathan Guthrie" date=" May 2, 2014 12:17 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/7c426aba-d1e7-11e3-8ff4-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Yours noncommittally, Pfizer</headline><body><![CDATA[FT City columnist Lombard imagines the comfort letter Ian Read, straight-talking boss of Pfizer, might have sent to David Cameron about his bid for AstraZeneca if PR experts had not edited it first.
</p>
Dear Prime Minister,</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By George Parker, Political Editor" date="May 2, 2014 10:40 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/7fac26e2-d1d7-11e3-8ff4-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>David Cameron welcomes Pfizer assurances on UK jobs and research</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jim Pickard, Chief Political Correspondent" date="May 2, 2014 9:13 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/908da0c2-d1cc-11e3-8ff4-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chuka Umunna attacks Pfizer for record of asset-stripping''</headline><body><![CDATA[Chuka Umunna, the shadow business secretary, has stepped up his criticism of the potential purchase of AstraZeneca and attacked US bidder Pfizer''s record of asset-stripping in previous takeovers.</p>
Pfizer has a very poor record on previous acquisitions, he said. There is its acquisition of Warner-Lambert in 2000 in the US; Pharmacia in Sweden in 2003; and Wyeth in the US in 2000, and that led to deep cuts in the research facilities, it led to intellectual asset-stripping and look at the RD, because RD is absolutely crucial here.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward, David Oakley and George Parker" date="May 2, 2014 10:56 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f7be0938-d1bf-11e3-8ff4-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>AstraZeneca rejects Pfizer''s sweetened bid</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward and Elizabeth Rigby in London and Ed Hammond in New York" date="May 1, 2014 6:29 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f1c22f12-d14e-11e3-81e0-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer plans to raise AstraZeneca offer</headline><body><![CDATA[Pfizer is planning to sweeten its 60bn takeover approach for AstraZeneca in an attempt to increase pressure on its UK rival to enter talks to create the world''s biggest drugmaker. </p>
Ian Read, Pfizer''s chairman and chief executive, returned to New York on Thursday to plot his next move after two days of meetings in London aimed at winning support from the UK government and the City for the biggest foreign takeover of a UK company in history.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jonathan Guthrie" date=" May 1, 2014 11:19 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/fa7f29bc-d111-11e3-bdbb-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer''s Read revives vision of all-conquering corporate</headline><body><![CDATA[Britain''s science base would be devastated if Pfizer bought AstraZeneca, according to Lord Sainsbury. But that is nothing to how devastated many investors would feel if Pfizer walked away, now that the US drugs group has proposed paying 50 per share in cash and stock. They will be grateful the government does not have the reserve powers to block foreign takeovers proposed by Lord Heseltine, an adviser to David Cameron.</p>
Financial and political arguments interweave in the debate over the prospective $100bn-plus drugs sector takeover. These highlight the resurgence of the footloose multinational as a force to be reckoned with after a post-crash hiatus when the state reasserted its power.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Delphine Strauss" date="May 1, 2014 8:14 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/7b96d6e2-d0fb-11e3-9f90-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Why the Pfizer bid is propelling the pound</headline><body><![CDATA[Should currency investors care about corporate mergers and acquisitions? The pound''s bounce week suggests at least some of them do. Despite the hurdles Pfizer has to overcome in its pursuit of the UK''s AstraZeneca, confirmation of its interest helped to propel sterling to a near five-year high.</p>
The announcement effect was clear in Monday''s trading, even though opinion is split over the extent to which the last big deal involving a UK company  Vodafone''s sale of its stake in US Verizon Wireless, completed two months ago  may have influenced the exchange rate.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elizabeth Rigby, Deputy Political Editor" date="April 30, 2014 10:44 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/d0ae969c-d088-11e3-8b90-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>UK premier picks top dealmakers for Pfizer-AstraZeneca talks</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward, David Oakley and Elizabeth Rigby" date="April 30, 2014 7:24 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b45b749e-d077-11e3-9a81-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>AstraZeneca''s Johansson hits at Pfizer big is better'' bid</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Gordon, Europe business editor" date=" April 30, 2014 3:09 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/d2103d8e-d046-11e3-af2b-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer-AstraZeneca marriage divides opinion</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Vanessa Houlder" date="April 29, 2014 8:30 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c7dc2092-cfb7-11e3-a2b7-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Patent box holds key to Pfizer-AZ deal''s attraction</headline><body><![CDATA[The patent box  a big UK tax break for innovative companies  is an important part of the attraction for Pfizer as it stalks AstraZeneca and eyes a move of its tax domicile to Britain.</p>
Announced in the 2012 budget, the government measure aims to stimulate research and development in the UK by offering a special 10 per cent tax rate on profits earned from patents. The relief is being phased in over four years from April 2013.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward, Pharmaceuticals Correspondent" date="April 29, 2014 7:54 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/ce653d6c-cfb3-11e3-9b2b-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer chief executive pins faith on its powers of persuasion</headline><body><![CDATA[Newscast]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward and George Parker" date="April 29, 2014 9:35 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e354386e-cfa3-11e3-9b2b-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer flies in to clear path for 60bn AstraZeneca takeover</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>Ian Read, Pfizer CEO</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward and Vanessa Houlder in London and Barney Jopson in Washington" date="April 28, 2014 7:23 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0cad0dd4-ce9c-11e3-ac8d-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer ignites pharma takeover battle</headline><body><![CDATA[
Reuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Hammond in New York and Andrew Ward in London" date="April 27, 2014 11:54 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c6b1c44a-ce3d-11e3-9dfd-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer renews bid interest in AstraZeneca</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward and Jim Pickard" date="April 21, 2014 6:54 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/5dfe4752-c974-11e3-89f8-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer approach raises questions over UK''s takeover stance</headline><body><![CDATA[AstraZeneca''s products may not have the same emotional appeal to Britons as Dairy Milk chocolate, but any takeover of the drugmaker could have more far-reaching implications than Kraft''s 11.6bn acquisition of Cadbury in 2010.</p>
That deal prompted intense debate over whether UK takeover rules left British companies too open to foreign takeover.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward in London and Ed Hammond in New York" date="April 22, 2014 9:07 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/27fbd07c-c94a-11e3-bba1-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>AstraZeneca US shares jump as details of Pfizer talks revealed</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>Pascal Soriot, AstraZeneca chief</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Eric Platt in New York" date="April 7, 2014 10:13 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/bbc23aa6-be70-11e3-a1bf-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer falls as treatment trial disappoints</headline><body><![CDATA[Pfizer, the US pharmaceuticals group, weakened on Monday after results of a mid-stage experimental breast cancer treatment trial disappointed investors, despite meeting the primary goal of the study.</p>
The trial of palbociclib, an oral medication, has been closely watched by market participants, many of whom believe it could top $5bn in sales at its peak if approved.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Eric Platt in New York" date="February 3, 2014 9:47 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/6707fd3a-8cf6-11e3-8b82-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Pfizer bucks declines on cancer drug trial hopes</headline><body><![CDATA[Shares in US pharmaceuticals group Pfizer rallied on Monday after a mid-stage drug trial of an experimental breast cancer treatment successfully met its goals of delaying the progression of symptoms in women with locally advanced or newly diagnosed metastatic cancer.</p>
The trial of palbociclib, an oral medication, has been closely watched by investors and analysts who believe it could top $5bn in sales if approved. Analysts at Morgan Stanley have said palbociclib could top Pfizer''s blockbuster Lipitor drug at its peak if successful.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward, Pharmaceuticals Correspondent" date="January 28, 2014 6:54 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e35c47a6-8841-11e3-85a2-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Pfizer sales decline on increased competition from generics</headline><body><![CDATA[Pfizer reported better than expected fourth-quarter profit on Tuesday, but revenues fell as the maker of Lipitor and Viagra faced increased competition from cheaper generic medicines.</p>
Investors are awaiting progress reports on a series of new drugs under development by the biggest US pharmaceuticals group as it scrambles to offset the loss of patent protection on some of its blockbuster brands.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Jack" date="October 29, 2013 6:49 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/d4c34b5e-40c5-11e3-8775-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer to publish separate results for its 3 business units</headline><body><![CDATA[Pfizer confirmed it is to separately publish the financial results of its three business divisions from the first quarter of next year, in a move further fuelling speculation that the US pharmaceutical company is exploring a sale or spin-off of some operations.</p>
In a commitment seen by some analysts as a precursor to a divestment  notably of its established business of off-patent products  it will begin releasing separate results for the units, creating the option of a quoted spinout by as soon as 2017 following the requirement for three years of financial data.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Jack" date="July 30, 2013 11:28 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a5732036-f962-11e2-86e1-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer finalises overselling settlement</headline><body><![CDATA[Pfizer has finalised a criminal and civil settlement worth $491m with US authorities for alleged overselling of a transplant drug produced by Wyeth, the company it acquired in 2009.</p>
The US pharmaceutical group agreed a $234m fine and asset forfeiture with the Department of Justice as well as $247m in civil penalties, for which it had made a provision late last year.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Jack in London" date="July 30, 2013 4:10 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/971cdea8-f914-11e2-a6ef-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer earnings hit by sales drop</headline><body><![CDATA[Pfizer reported earnings a share down 5 per cent in the second quarter on sales down 7 per cent following patent expirations, as it 
revealed 
details of plans to split reporting into three separate business units from next year.</p>
The US pharmaceutical group maintained guidance, despite the loss of exclusivity in many markets of Lipitor, its cholesterol-lowering blockbuster treatment. It reported earnings down to $0.56 a share on the same period last year, on sales of $13bn.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward, Pharmaceuticals Correspondent" date="September 11, 2014 7:28 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f7f00654-39ca-11e4-83c4-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer says window still open'' for tax inversions</headline><body><![CDATA[You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward and Arash Massoudi in London" date="August 24, 2014 11:43 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/ee806732-2b6d-11e4-b052-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer weighs options on AstraZeneca bid</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward, Pharmaceuticals Correspondent" date="August 4, 2014 1:13 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b69c8a70-1bab-11e4-adc7-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>AstraZeneca chairman Leif Johansson defends Pfizer rebuff</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward, Pharmaceuticals Correspondent" date="July 29, 2014 7:28 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b494286e-171e-11e4-b0d7-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer refuses to rule out tax inversion deals</headline><body><![CDATA[Pfizer has called for fundamental reform of the US tax system  but said it was still interested in acquisitions that would allow it to put offshore revenues beyond the reach of the US taxman in the absence of change. 
</p>
Ian Read, chief executive, said Pfizer was lobbying in Washington for an overhaul of tax rules that he argued put US companies at a disadvantage. His comments coincided with moves by senior Democrats in both chambers of Congress to cut off more companies that change their domicile from lucrative federal contracts.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jonathan Guthrie" date="Last updated: July 8, 2014 8:27 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/67f7ba6c-0688-11e4-ba32-00144feab7de.html"><headline>AbbVie avoids Pfizer errors in bear hug against Shire</headline><body><![CDATA[My pals are bigger than your pals. AbbVie has resorted to an old playground intimidation tactic, by implying a majority of shareholders back its revised 30bn proposal to buy Shire for 51.15 per share. </p>
Investors, who are constitutionally committed to being non-committal, are shrugging off the impertinence. Their bigger worry is that the US drugs group could bungle the bid, as Pfizer did in pursuing AstraZeneca.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alison Smith and Arash Massoudi" date="May 29, 2014 10:31 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/154ea340-e74b-11e3-88be-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>UK lesson for Stryker and Pfizer</headline><body><![CDATA[Twice in two weeks, US companies interested in buying UK groups have walked away after coming up against British takeover rules.</p>
On Wednesday, Stryker, the medical device maker, said it did not intend to make an offer for Smith  Nephew. Just days earlier Pfizer had abandoned efforts to engage with AstraZeneca on its 55 per share approach to the British pharma group.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Adam Bogdanor" date="May 28, 2014 5:20 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a476fdf0-e5bc-11e3-a7f5-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>The regulators were right to force Pfizer''s hand</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward, Pharmaceuticals Correspondent" date="May 26, 2014 3:32 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/418ce3cc-e4b7-11e3-9b2b-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer admits defeat in AstraZeneca bid</headline><body><![CDATA[Pfizer has admitted defeat in its pursuit of AstraZeneca, bringing an end to a month-long takeover battle that pitted two of the world''s biggest drugmakers against each other and stirred political controversy on both sides of the Atlantic.</p>
The US company officially abandoned its 69.4bn offer for its British rival two hours before the 5pm Monday deadline for a deal to be struck under UK takeover rules.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Peggy Hollinger" date="May 25, 2014 2:58 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/9a1a854c-e298-11e3-a829-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Pfizer strategy revives fears for future of life sciences in UK</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Ward" date="May 23, 2014 7:39 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/4666c62c-e293-11e3-a829-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>How Pfizer snatched defeat from victory</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lina Saigol" date=" May 23, 2014 6:45 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f9dd5cec-e271-11e3-a829-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>A quick guide to put Pfizer top of the Takeover Panel''s class</headline><body><![CDATA[
After a five-month pursuit of AstraZeneca, Pfizer''s bid this week all but fell apart when the UK drugmaker rejected the US group''s final 69.4bn offer, with blame attributed equally between Pfizer boss Ian Read, his investment bankers at Bank of America Merrill Lynch, JPMorgan and Guggenheim Partners, and his PR guru Sir Alan Parker.
</p>
Team Pfizer clearly did not do enough studying, misreading the political sentiment and miscalculating the price they needed to pay to seal the deal.
 They now have three months to revise before they can try again. With some shareholders rooting for them, they could pass the resit with flying colours. To help them prepare, the Financial Times has devised a quick study guide.
</p>
]]> </body></entry></news>