
<news><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="May 12, 2010 1:05 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/84a71e52-5d52-11df-8373-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Disney''s box-office hit lifts profits</headline><body><![CDATA[The box-office performance of Alice in Wonderland powered Walt Disney to a second quarter that beat expectations, with Tim Burton''s 3D release becoming one of the company''s biggest hits.</p>
The film''s $962m haul was a big factor in Disney''s profits, which rose to $998m from $653m last time on earnings per share of $0.48 that exceeded the consensus estimate of $0.45.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Justine Lau in Hong Kong" date="March 20, 2010 2:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e94e9878-33c0-11df-8b99-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Ocean Park has local edge over Disney rival</headline><body><![CDATA[When Allan Zeman became chairman of Hong Kong''s Ocean Park in 2003, he took over the running of a weather-beaten business on the brink of bankruptcy. That same year, Disney also began construction in Hong Kong of its first theme park on Chinese soil, presenting the biggest threat to the home-grown park since it was founded in 1977.</p>
Seven years later, Mr Zeman, a leisure industry veteran known for developing the city''s Lan Kwai Fong bar area, has managed to defy the doubters.</p>
Mainland Chinese visitors to Ocean Park and its trademark dolphin shows have been steadily increasing, while Disney''s cartoon characters have struggled to win them over.</p>
In January this year, Hong Kong Disneyland disclosed its financial details for the first time, revealing a net loss of HK$1.3bn in its last financial year. Although attendance rose slightly to 4.6m in the year to October 3, 2009, it was far short of its original projection of up to 5.6m visitors annually.</p>
By contrast, Ocean Park received 4.8m people in the 12 months to June 2009 and reported a net profit of HK$98.6m. Back in 2003, its attendance was 2.9m and it made a net loss of HK$4.1m.</p>
"We couldn''t compete against Disney with the money they had. We needed to find a way to make us relevant," says Mr Zeman.</p>
"The first thing we realised was that Ocean Park was a local park with local brand awareness."</p>
With that in mind, it began a series of special events during popular festivals such as Chinese New Year and Halloween. It also drew up a HK$5.6bn (US$715m) redevelopment plan that would double the number of shows and rides by 2013, build three on-site hotels and distinguish itself from other theme parks by expanding its animal collection.</p>
"Understanding the culture and coming with the events that are relevant to the local culture is our strength," says Mr Zeman, in the park''s Panda Cafe.</p>
When Disney opened its Hong Kong magic kingdom in 2005, Mr Zeman was prepared for a huge drop in attendance.</p>
Many tourists from mainland China, which since 2004 had become a major source of visitors to Hong Kong, timed their holidays that year to catch the launch of Disneyland.</p>
But due to marketing glitches and complaints about its small size, Hong Kong Disneyland has failed to become the intimidating rival that Ocean Park once feared.</p>
While the tale of a home-grown theme park beating an internationally known name is spectacular, the success of Ocean Park is also unusual as it is not controlled by a cash-rich conglomerate, but wholly-owned by the government.</p>
Video: Allan Zeman , Ocean Park chairman, discusses competing with Walt Disney and Hong Kong''s future as a cultural hub: www.ft.com/zeman</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Justine Lau in Hong Kong" date="March 19, 2010 7:48 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/178698d4-337c-11df-9223-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Ocean Park has local edge over Disney rival</headline><body><![CDATA[When Allan Zeman became chairman of Hong Kong''s Ocean Park in 2003, he took over the running of a weather-beaten business on the brink of bankruptcy. That same year, Disney also began construction in Hong Kong of its first theme park on Chinese soil, 
presenting the biggest threat to the home-grown park 
since it was founded in 1977.</p>
You need JavaScript active on your browser in order to see this video.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kenneth Li in New York" date="March 8, 2010 2:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/6a5fcfa0-2a51-11df-b940-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney cuts off 3m New York viewers on day of Oscars</headline><body><![CDATA[Walt Disney pulled its ABC television stations from 3m Cablevision customers in New York just hours before its exclusive broadcasting of the Academy Awards yesterday.</p>
The two media groups failed to reach an agreement over carriage fees paid to Disney by Cablevision. This is the third such failure in the industry in recent months and underscores the shifting economics of the TV industry.</p>
Free-to-air networks such as ABC and News Corp''s Fox have begun to demand fees from distributors to address the shrinking business of broadcast TV. In the past big station owners such as Disney have taken payment for their cable networks but not for their free-to-air stations.</p>
Carriage discussions are typically tense affairs that last up to the final hours of contract expirations. But recent tussles between networks and carriers have taken on a desperate tone and led to the threat of blackouts of stations.</p>
"It is now painfully clear to millions of New York area households that Disney CEO Bob Iger will hold his own ABC viewers hostage in order to extract $40m in new fees from Cablevision," said Cable-vision. "We call on Bob Iger to immediately return ABC to Cablevision customers while we continue to work to reach a fair agreement."</p>
Disney has demanded an extra $40m in fees, or about $1 a subscriber, on top of the $200m Cablevision pays the network for its roster of popular cable offerings that include the ESPN sports network, which commands the highest fees in the US cable sector.</p>
Fox, which had demanded fees of $1 a subscriber, and Time Warner Cable averted a blackout over the new year after negotiations led to a pact.</p>
"Cablevision has once again betrayed its subscribers by losing ABC7 . . . [following] two years of negotiations, during which we worked diligently, up to the final moments, to reach an agreement," said Rebecca Campbell, president and general manager of WABC-TV, a Disney-owned station, in an online appeal to consumers.</p>
Disney''s saveabc7.com provided contact information for Verizon, DirecTV and ATT so viewers in the region could switch pay TV providers.</p>
John Kerry, the senator who chairs the commerce subcommittee on communications, technology and the internet, last week wrote to Julius Genachowski, chairman of the Federal Communications Commission, to urge the FCC to help resolve the dispute.</p>
"When pulling a signal becomes the nuclear option in negotiation, it inflicts collateral damage on consumers who pay their bills and have done nothing wrong," Mr Kerry wrote in a letter to the two companies this weekend.</p>
"If a true impasse is reached, then I urge the parties to seek the assistance of the FCC."</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kenneth Li in New York" date="March 8, 2010 3:26 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/41db79f2-2a11-11df-b940-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney restores Oscars broadcast to 3m viewers</headline><body><![CDATA[<p>Clean sweep: preparing for last night''s Academy Awards</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="February 18, 2010 2:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/fe246d32-1c2c-11df-86cb-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Disney film faces Europe boycott</headline><body><![CDATA[Several large European cinema chains have threatened to boycott Alice in Wonderland , Walt Disney''s forthcoming release, after Disney announced it planned to bring forward the DVD release of the film.</p>
Disney wants to accelerate the release of the DVD by a month, from 17 weeks after the theatrical opening to 13 weeks.</p>
The aim is to bolster DVD sales, which have been in decline, by allowing the studio to take advantage of marketing to promote the film in cinemas.</p>
But cinema chains are concerned the early DVD release will eat into ticket sales for Alice in Wonderland , a 3D fantasy directed by Tim Burton.</p>
"Disney is not keeping its part of the bargain," Youry Bredewold, a representative for Pathe and the Dutch National Board of Cinema Owners, told AFP.</p>
"There is an agreement between movie distributors and cinema owners that there must be a window of at least four months between the cinema release and the DVD release."</p>
He said that cinema chains representing 80 per cent of the Dutch market would not show the film.</p>
"We will lose money due to our decision," he said. "We expected this to become one of the most popular movies of 2010.</p>
"But we decided we need to send a message to the whole industry: if you don''t accept our terms we will never show your movies again."</p>
As Europe''s largest theatrical market, any boycott in the UK could also have serious repercussions for Disney and the film''s global box office performance.</p>
There are strong ties between the film, which has a large English cast, and the UK: Tim Burton lives in London and the film''s global premiere will be held there on March 5 with Prince Charles as the guest of honour.</p>
No UK cinema chain has yet publicly backed a boycott of the film but there is growing concern about the longer-term implications of the possible shortening of the theatrical release window.</p>
Phil Clapp, chief executive of the Cinema Exhibitors Association in the UK, told the Financial Times that the average release window of about four months had "served both the industry and, more importantly, the customer exceptionally well, evidenced by record cinema admissions and box office".</p>
He said: "The CEA would be concerned by negative impacts arising from any moves to alter that position."</p>
Disney has moved to assuage exhibitors'' fears. "It is important for us to maintain a healthy business on the exhibition side and a healthy business on the home video side," said Bob Chapek, its president of distribution.</p>
"We remain committed to theatrical windows, with the need for exceptions to accommodate a shortened time frame on a case-by-case basis."</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="February 18, 2010 12:21 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/bf14b5f0-1c06-11df-a5e1-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Disney''s film faces boycott in Europe</headline><body><![CDATA[<p>In a hole: Disney''s move to speed the DVD release of Tim Burton''s Alice in Wonderland'' has angered cinema chains. Alice is played by Mia Wasikowska</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="February 10, 2010 2:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/7d31d8da-15e3-11df-b65b-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Disney chief hails potential of iPad</headline><body><![CDATA[Bob Iger, chief executive of Walt Disney, delivered a ringing endorsement of Apple''s iPad yesterday and said that the media company was developing content and special features for the new device as it released flat first-quarter earnings that nevertheless beat expectations.</p>
Mr Iger said the iPad could be a "game changer" and would enable Disney to create new forms of content from ESPN, its sports cable network, and ABC, its broadcast network that is home to programmes such as Lost .</p>
"The interactivity that it will allow as a portable device with such a high-quality screen will enable us to develop product that''s different to what we see on internet connected computers and TVs," he said.</p>
Disney, which has a close relationship with Apple - Steve Jobs, Apple''s chief executive, is one of Disney''s biggest shareholders - has been developing "digi-books" for children that Mr Iger said would be well suited to the iPad. "This device . . . makes the interactivity that we''re going to provide come to life."</p>
Disney''s results were boosted by its film studio, where the company trimmed marketing costs and scored hits in home entertainment with The Proposal  and Up .</p>
Rich Ross, the head of Disney Channel, was recently appointed to run the studio and has begun to restructure the unit. Mr Iger said the studio would "produce, market and distribute movies more efficiently in light of the challenges the movie business is facing".</p>
International subscriber growth buoyed the performance of Disney Channel, while ESPN continued to defy the economic downturn with improved advertising revenue, which was offset by higher programming costs.</p>
There has been little sign of an advertising rebound at ABC, with the company similarly downbeat about future prospects at its theme parks, where forward bookings lag behind the same period last year by 10 per cent. Profits at Disney''s parks for the quarter were hit by falling attendance at Disneyland Paris.</p>
"Advertisers and consumers are making their buying decisions at the last minute," said Jay Rasulo, chief financial officer. He added: "We expect the operating environment to remain challenging in the coming quarters."</p>
Revenues for the three months to January 2 rose from $9.6bn to $9.7bn. Net income slipped from $851m to $844m. Diluted earnings per share were 44 cents compared with 45 cents last time. The shares were up 0.4 per cent at $29.96 in after-market trading.</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan" date="February 10, 2010 2:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/9ce1a7d2-15e3-11df-b65b-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Disney chief hails Apple''s iPad</headline><body><![CDATA[Bob Iger, chief executive of Walt Disney, delivered a ringing endorsement of Apple''s iPad yesterday and said the media company was developing content and special features for the new device as it released flat first-quarter earnings that nevertheless beat expectations, writes Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles .</p>
Mr Iger said the iPad could be a "gamechanger" and would enable Disney to create new forms of content from ESPN, its sports cable network, and ABC, its broadcast network.</p>
"The interactivity that it will allow . . . with such a high-quality screen will enable us to develop product that''s different to what we see on internet connected computers and TVs," he said.</p>
Disney, which has a close relationship with Apple - Steve Jobs, Apple''s chief executive, is one of Disney''s biggest shareholders - has been developing "digi-books" for children that Mr Iger said would be well-suited to the iPad.</p>
The results were boosted by improvements at its movie studio, which trimmed marketing costs and scored home entertainment hits with The Proposal  and Up .</p>
Revenues for the three months to January 2 rose from $9.6bn to $9.7bn. Net income slipped from $851m to $844m. Diluted earnings per share were 44 cents compared with 45 cents last time. The shares were up 0.4 per cent, to $29.96 in after-market trading.</p>
www.ft.com/media</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="February 10, 2010 12:31 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/cda11c7c-15d9-11df-b65b-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Disney chief hails potential of iPad</headline><body><![CDATA[Bob Iger, chief executive of Walt Disney, delivered a ringing endorsement of Apple''s iPad on Tuesday and said the media company was developing content and special features for the new device as it released flat first-quarter earnings that nevertheless beat expectations. </p>
Mr Iger said the iPad could be a game changer and would enable Disney to create new forms of content from ESPN, its sports cable network, and ABC, its broadcast network that is home to programmes such as Lost.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Justine Lau in Hong Kong" date="January 19, 2010 10:30 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/920689e2-04de-11df-9a4f-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Disney''s HK theme park makes loss</headline><body><![CDATA[Walt Disney''s struggling Hong Kong theme park made public its financial details for the first time on Tuesday, revealing it made a net loss of HK$1.32bn (US$170m) last financial year. </p>
The Hong Kong government, which has a 52 per cent stake in the park, said attendance grew 2 per cent to 4.6m in the year to October 3 2009, well short of its original projection of up to 5.6m annually. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christian Sylt" date="January 18, 2010 2:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/9b4208d2-03d1-11df-a601-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>The job: David Minichiello, Disney</headline><body><![CDATA[Imagineers are responsible for the creation and construction of Disney''s theme park rides and shows. We also develop resorts, cruise ships and real estate.</p>
If we are designing a new attraction for an existing park, there is usually a business reason behind it. A park may need more attractions geared towards a younger audience.</p>
In Paris, you are so close to incredible chteaux that we took the fantasy touches to the next level. There are details like stained glass windows and tapestries. We make sure we cater to guests'' needs so we have a big Alice in Wonderland presence in Paris because we knew how much the British would be visiting.</p>
Projects generally last two to five years and we do cost estimates all along. You can do the same story at different budgets but the important thing is that the story is done well and there is a clear message guests understand and enjoy.</p>
New technologies may become available to allow you to improve something and sometimes we will be asked to look at older attractions like Pirates of the Caribbean to freshen them up. Children today grew up with the movies so we put animatronic models of the characters from the movies in the ride in Florida. As Walt Disney said: "It is kind of fun to do the impossible."  As told to Christian Sylt</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="January 6, 2010 2:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/78e16552-fa63-11de-beed-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Disney and rivals square up in new movie distribution battle</headline><body><![CDATA[
Hollywood loves a format war. First VHS saw off Betamax in the great home video battle of the 1980s. More recently, Blu-ray won the right to succeed the DVD when it was preferred by film studios to rival HD-DVD technology.</p>
However, as Hollywood looks to the digital era, the industry is split on how to manage the distribution of movies to TVs, computers and hand-held devices, setting the stage for its next great technological tussle.</p>
In one corner is Walt Disney and its Keychest product, which it describes as "enabling technology" that allows consumers to buy or rent a film and then view it on any device they choose.</p>
In the opposing corner is Digital Entertainment Content Ecosystem, a coalition of retailers, hardware makers and film companies, including Hewlett-Packard, Netflix and Sony.</p>
Although DECE has taken a slightly different approach to Disney, the two sides essentially have the same goal: to thwart piracy at a time when DVD sales are in decline, and to boost digital sales of movies.</p>
Each camp has publicly played down talk of rivalry. "We''re trying to solve two different problems," says Kelly Summers, vice-president of digital distribution at Walt Disney Studios. "DECE wants to create a new format . . . Keychest isn''t a format. It''s an enabling technology that helps different platforms communicate with each other."</p>
However, analysts and rival studio executives say the absence of Apple from DECE is a telling indication of the fight that may lie ahead. Apple''s iTunes store is the dominant online retailer, responsible for more than 80 per cent of all film download sales, while Steve Jobs, Apple''s chief executive, is Disney''s biggest individual shareholder.</p>
Disney''s decision to go it alone raised eyebrows in Hollywood although the company insists it wanted to move as quickly as possible at a time when digital sales were being held back by online piracy.</p>
In a demonstration for the Financial Times, Arnaud Robert, senior vice- president of distribution technology - and the inventor of the Keychest concept - showed how the "rights locker" concept would work: a consumer could buy a movie via an online retailer and then watch it, within seconds, on a mobile phone or television set.</p>
Disney is in discussion with online retailers and cable TV companies about adopting Keychest. "We need a critical mass to make this work," said Ms Summers. "There''s a competitive reason [for these companies] to be part of this because it increases the utility of devices that are already out there."</p>
Keychest uses all existing digital rights management technologies. DECE, by contrast, has approved five different formats and also agreed on a "common file format" which will be used by all of its members.</p>
Mitch Singer, president of DECE, told the FT that the absence of Apple from the consortium, which also includes Microsoft, Toshiba, Samsung and Intel, would not hold it back. "The digital market is very young and very small . . . change is inevitable. I don''t think any one player controls it in a way that''s going to be [relevant] tomorrow."</p>
Opening up online access so that a single copy of a film could be stored remotely and streamed, regardless of the device, would benefit hardware makers, as well as retailers and film studios, he added.</p>
Disney and DECE will both be at the Consumer Electronics Show, which starts today in Las Vegas, where the two approaches will face further scrutiny from possible partners. "The Keychest-DECE battle is going to be the definitive format war for the digital era," says Arash Amel, senior analyst with Screen Digest, the research firm. "Forget about Blu-ray and DVDs . . this is about who controls digital formats of the next 15-20 years."</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="January 6, 2010 12:26 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c1f1279e-fa56-11de-beed-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Disney and rivals square up in format war</headline><body><![CDATA[Hollywood loves a format war. First VHS saw off Betamax in the great home video battle of the 1980s. More recently, Blu-ray won the right to succeed the DVD when it was preferred by film studios to rival HD-DVD technology.</p>
However, as Hollywood looks to the digital era, the industry is split on how to manage the distribution of movies to TVs, computers and hand-held devices, setting the stage for its next great technological tussle. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="December 24, 2009 2:00 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/811cf2be-f02b-11de-833d-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Facebook chief operating officer joins board at Disney</headline><body><![CDATA[
Sheryl Sandberg, the chief operating officer of Facebook, is to join Walt Disney as an independent director, bolstering the media company''s board at a time when it is exploring a range of new digital business models.</p>
Assuming her nomination is approved, she will join Steve Jobs as a non-executive director of the company, which has led its rivals in Hollywood in making content available on new digital platforms.</p>
As chief operating officer of Facebook, a position she has held since March 2008, Ms Sandberg is responsible for building the social network''s global operations and managing its sales, marketing, business development, privacy and communications functions.</p>
Facebook has 350m members and is firmly established as the world''s largest online social network since overtaking News Corporation''s MySpace last year.</p>
"Sheryl has been at the forefront of a technological revolution that''s opened up a world of new possibilities for consumers and which has greatly affected the way we do business," said Bob Iger, Disney''s chief executive. "Her unique insight, borne of great practical experience, will be of considerable value to Disney''s shareholders."</p>
Mr Iger has made no secret of his desire to produce content that can be distributed wherever consumers want to view it.</p>
He counts Mr Jobs, the chief executive of Apple, among his most trusted advisers and is keen to explore social networking opportunities for the company, which is where Ms Sandberg''s expertise will come in useful.</p>
The company is currently working on Key Chest, a digital rights management project that will eventually allow consumers to watch Disney content on an array of devices wherever they are.</p>
Disney also operates its own social network for children - Club Penguin - which it acquired two years ago.</p>
Before joining Facebook, Ms Sandberg, who is also on the Starbucks board, was vice-president of global online sales and operations at Google.</p>
She said it was a "tremendous honour" to be nominated to the Disney board, adding that the company had "remained an entertainment icon around the world for over 80 years by enthusiastically embracing change and new technologies".</p>
John Pepper, Disney''s chairman, said that Ms Sandberg had "great expertise in the online world, considerable international experience and a deep understanding of consumer behaviour".</p>
Ms Sandberg is a former chief of staff of the United States Treasury Department.</p>
Her previous posts also include serving as a management consultant with McKinsey and working as an economist with the World Bank.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan in Los Angeles" date="December 24, 2009 1:02 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/85183616-f013-11de-833d-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Facebook chief operating officer joins Disney</headline><body><![CDATA[Sheryl Sandberg, the chief operating officer of Facebook, is to join Walt Disney as an independent director, bolstering the media company''s board at a time when it is exploring a range of new digital business models.</p>
Assuming her nomination is approved, she will join Steve Jobs as a non-executive director of the company, which has led its rivals in Hollywood in making content available on new digital platforms.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Garrahan" date="December 17, 2009 8:09 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/78b3b8bc-eade-11de-a0e1-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Veteran of Disney''s boardroom battles</headline><body><![CDATA[For much of his life, Roy Disney, who died on Wednesday of stomach cancer aged 79, was overshadowed by his uncle Walt, the animation genius who revolutionised American cinema with classics such as Snow White and Pinocchio. </p>
But the younger man left his own legacy on the company due to his role in two boardroom battles that unseated established executives and led to an improvement in the group''s fortunes.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael Kavanagh in London" date="August 1, 2014 3:36 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/8ba11378-197f-11e4-8730-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron boosted by strong crude demand</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>Aerial view of the Gorgon site on Barrow Island in Western Australia</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York" date="May 7, 2014 6:30 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b97116bc-d5fb-11e3-a017-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Patton Boggs to pay $15m to settle Chevron pollution case</headline><body><![CDATA[Patton Boggs, the leading Washington law and lobbying firm, has agreed to pay $15m to Chevron, the oil group, to settle a long-running legal battle over allegedly fraudulent damages claims for pollution in Ecuador.</p>
The law firm, one of the most prestigious in the US, has also issued a highly unusual statement of regret over its involvement in the case, and committed not to benefit from any future damages awards.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York" date="May 2, 2014 2:43 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c3dc47bc-d1fe-11e3-8ff4-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Weaker oil prices and output disruption hurt Chevron profits</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron, the US oil group, suffered a 27 per cent drop in post-tax profits in the first quarter, hit by weaker oil prices and disruption to production caused by bad weather in Kazakhstan.</p>
The earnings were below the average analysts'' expectations, and Chevron shares were about 0.5 per cent lower when trading opened in New York before improving slightly.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks" date="March 24, 2014 8:23 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/5ff0a564-b36c-11e3-bc21-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>BullishChevrontooutspendExxon</headline><body><![CDATA[Beacon of light: although Chevron ranks second to Exxon in the US in terms of market capitalisation, the oil major is planning to outspend its larger rival in a bet on the continuing high oil priceReuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York" date="March 11, 2014 5:50 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/13240d08-a943-11e3-9b71-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Chevron raises projection for oil price</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron, the US oil group, has raised sharply its expectation of future oil prices and cut its target for production growth, as it highlighted the steep rise in costs in the industry.</p>
John Watson, the chief executive, told analysts at a meeting in New York that the company was bullish on oil because of output declines at mature fields, political constraints on production in many parts of the world, and the rising cost of finding and developing new oilfields. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in Houston" date="March 4, 2014 8:23 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/74676d8c-a3c9-11e3-aa85-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Chevron wins case over Ecuador pollution</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>Employee Brandon Scully works on a Chevron Corp. sign at a gasoline station in San Francisco</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York" date="January 31, 2014 3:05 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/7e687dbc-8a83-11e3-9c29-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Chevron misses revenue expectations as earnings drop 31%</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron, the US oil and gas group, reported a 31 per cent drop in earnings for the fourth quarter of 2013 after being hit by higher costs, lower production, and lower margins at refineries.</p>
Earnings per share were $2.57 for the quarter, in line with analysts'' forecasts, but revenues were about $5bn lower than expected at $56.2bn, down 7 per cent.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Guy Chazan" date="November 22, 2013 1:56 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/756edfba-536c-11e3-b425-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron raises doubts over 6bn North Sea oil project</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg<p>Employee Brandon Scully works on a Chevron Corp. sign at a gasoline station in San Francisco</p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Mark Rachkevych in Kiev and Neil Buckley in London" date="November 5, 2013 8:07 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/699fdb58-461a-11e3-9487-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Ukraine signs shale gas deal with Chevron</headline><body><![CDATA[Ukraine on Tuesday signed a deal worth up to $10bn with Chevron to exploit its shale gas reserves  one of the biggest such agreements in Europe to date  as it steps up efforts to break free from its reliance on Russian gas.</p>
In what is Ukraine''s second such deal this year, Chevron will gain the rights to explore and eventually produce hydrocarbons in two western Ukrainian regions. They hold an estimated 2.98tn cubic metres of gas reserves, making them among the largest in Europe.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York" date="November 1, 2013 2:36 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/7661fe3a-42f9-11e3-9d3c-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron hit by refining profitability drop</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="o Paulo" date="September 13, 2013 11:39 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/08f2b6b2-1cc2-11e3-a8a3-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Chevron to settle $17.5bn Brazilian oil spill suits</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron is on track to resolve civil lawsuits totalling R$40bn ($17.5bn) brought against the US energy group and its drilling contractor Transocean by Brazilian prosecutors over an oil spill in November 2011.</p>
The Rio de Janeiro branch of Brazil''s federal public prosecutors'' office said it had reached an accord with Chevron to take preventive measures that would likely lead to the lawsuits being dropped.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael Kavanagh" date="August 2, 2013 3:14 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0a9eb34a-fb79-11e2-8650-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron joins oil majors with weaker results</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Miles Johnson in Madrid" date="July 24, 2013 8:49 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/2172c414-f47e-11e2-a62e-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Repsol attacks Chevron over scandalous'' Argentina investment</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ben Bland in Surabaya and Taufan Hidayat in Jakarta" date="July 18, 2013 4:42 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/fc76fe62-ef9d-11e2-a237-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron employees sentenced in Indonesia corruption case</headline><body><![CDATA[Two environmental managers at Chevron, the US oil and gas group, have been jailed for two years on corruption charges in Indonesia in a hotly-contested case that has compounded investor concerns about legal uncertainty in the vital energy sector.</p>
Jakarta''s corruption court found Endah Rumbiyanti and Kukuh Kertasafari guilty of corruption in separate verdicts handed down on Wednesday and Thursday, part of a complex, ongoing series of trials related to an environmental clean-up project.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jude Webber in Buenos Aires and Ed Crooks in New York" date="July 17, 2013 12:20 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/cb5d67de-ee5e-11e2-a325-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron back in Argentina with $1.2bn deal</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ben Bland in Jakarta" date="July 9, 2013 7:11 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/fb57b71c-d984-11e2-98fa-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Chevron Indonesia graft case spooks investors</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jude Webber in Buenos Aires and Andres Schipani in Bogot" date="June 5, 2013 7:13 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/945c6cea-cdfb-11e2-8313-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Argentina lifts freeze on Chevron assets in Lago Agrio case</headline><body><![CDATA[Getty]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jude Webber in Buenos Aires" date="May 12, 2013 10:27 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/3153596a-bb09-11e2-b289-00144feab7de.html"><headline>Legal sanctions force Chevron into Argentina rethink</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron has been forced to retool a partnership to develop massive shale oil reserves in Argentina because of legal sanctions in Ecuador. </p>
Chevron''s plans to develop the giant Vaca Muerta shale formation with Argentine energy group YPF had been thrown into question by a legal judgment freezing Chevron''s Argentine assets. But Miguel Galuccio, chief executive of YPF, has told the Financial Times the two companies are close to agreement on a new plan to get around the asset freeze. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ben Bland in Jakarta" date="May 8, 2013 2:06 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b0d4a994-b7cd-11e2-bd62-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron hits out at Indonesian court for jailing of contractor</headline><body><![CDATA[US oil and gas group Chevron has attacked an Indonesian court''s decision to jail one of its subcontractors for five years on hotly contested corruption charges, calling the trial process flawed and warning that it would undermine the investment climate in one of Asia''s hottest emerging markets.</p>
Ricksy Prematuri, a director of Green Planet Indonesia, was convicted of corruption late on Tuesday night for his role in an environmental project at a Chevron oilfield in Sumatra and fined Rp200m ($20,500) in addition to his jail sentence.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York" date="April 26, 2013 3:07 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e457abce-ae75-11e2-bdfd-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron''s oil and gas output rises</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron, the second-largest US oil group by market capitalisation, has reported a 5 per cent drop in post-tax profits to $6.18bn for the first quarter.</p>
The results were in line with the flat profits reported by ExxonMobil and ConocoPhillips, Chevron''s two leading rivals, but significantly ahead of analysts'' expectations.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York" date="March 27, 2013 11:23 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c5deb188-972d-11e2-8950-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron cuts senior executives'' pay</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York" date="March 17, 2013 5:03 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/85dbd552-8bac-11e2-b001-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron powers quietly up the oil ranks</headline><body><![CDATA[Earlier this year, Chevron quietly passed a milestone: it overtook Royal Dutch Shell in terms of market capitalisation.</p>
With a market value of about $230bn compared with Shell''s $212bn, Chevron is on that measure the western world''s second-largest oil company, behind its US rival ExxonMobil.</p>
<h3>Oil majors</h3>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York and Jude Webber in Buenos Aires" date="March 13, 2013 5:00 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a0ff7e1a-8bf2-11e2-8fcf-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron challenges Argentina over YPF</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron, the US oil group, has taken a tough line with Argentina, saying it will not make any progress on an agreed joint venture with YPF, the country''s national oil company, until a court threat to its assets has been lifted.</p>
The US company''s stance is a blow to the Argentine government''s hopes of forming a partnership with a leading international oil company to help develop its vast shale reserves.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York" date="March 12, 2013 7:31 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/aaa61d84-8b3e-11e2-b1a4-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron explores first Canada gas exports</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron is in talks with potential buyers for Canada''s first exports of liquefied natural gas, paving the way for a $15bn project that would open up a new route for North American gas to Asia.</p>
The planned Kitimat LNG plant on Canada''s west coast would export shale gas from fields in British Columbia that hold an estimated 50tn cubic feet of gas: enough to meet China''s entire 2012 gas demand 10 times over.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Neil Hume in Sydney" date="February 25, 2013 7:46 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b9e4ffb0-7f16-11e2-89ed-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron adds heft to Australian shale</headline><body><![CDATA[Australia''s fledging unconventional gas industry received a big vote of confidence on Monday when Chevron, the second-biggest oil company in the US, agreed to pay up to $349m for stakes in two shale prospects being developed by Adelaide-based Beach Energy.</p>
Chevron is the latest international energy company to invest in Australia''s emerging shale gas sector. Earlier this month, PetroChina announced a deal with ConocoPhillips to explore for gas in Western Australia, which is estimated to have the fifth-largest reserves of shale gas in the world, according to the US Energy Information Agency.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jude Webber in Buenos Aires" date="February 13, 2013 5:12 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/364e2f30-751d-11e2-8bc7-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron hit by Argentine legal quagmire</headline><body><![CDATA[Reuters]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York" date="February 1, 2013 3:14 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/aaa7e1cc-6c7c-11e2-b774-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Chevron asset sales offset fall in profits</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron, the second-largest US oil group by market capitalisation, reported a better than expected 3 per cent drop in annual net income, supported by a gain from asset sales that offset declining production and weak natural gas prices.</p>
Post-tax earnings were $26.6bn, including the $1.4bn from selling assets in Australia, giving diluted earnings per share down 1 per cent from 2011, at $13.32, but ahead of analysts'' expectations of about $12.30.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jude Webber in Buenos Aires" date="January 30, 2013 9:27 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c55d8f38-6b1b-11e2-8017-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Chevron loses environment case appeal</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron has lost its appeal in Argentina against asset freezes to enforce an Ecuadorean judgment for the oil major to pay record $19bn damages for environmental pollution and must spell out the impact in its results statement on February 1 or risk violating SEC rules, a lawyer for the Amazonian plaintiffs said.</p>
Enrique Bruchou, an Argentine lawyer for the plaintiffs, said the three-judge appeals panel in Buenos Aires made public their unanimous ruling on January 30. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jude Webber in Buenos Aires" date="December 19, 2012 9:03 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c1df6d7c-4a14-11e2-a7b1-00144feab49a.html"><headline>YPF and Chevron agree $1bn drilling deal</headline><body><![CDATA[YPF, the Argentine oil company, has signed a $1bn deal with Chevron of the US to drill 100 pilot wells in the Vaca Muerta shale oil formation next year in the first partnership it has signed since being renationalised by the South American country.</p>
Miguel Galuccio, YPF''s chief executive, and Ali Moshiri, president of Chevron for Latin America and Africa, signed an agreement of terms and conditions at the US oil major''s headquarters in Houston. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York" date="November 20, 2012 11:50 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/85508a08-3344-11e2-aa83-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron seeks probe over Ecuador case</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron, the US oil group, has filed a complaint calling for an investigation of the comptroller of New York state, alleging that he acted improperly in urging the company to settle a $19bn claim for environmental damage in Ecuador.</p>
The company alleges that Thomas DiNapoli, who as comptroller is the administrator of the state''s employees'' pension funds, backed shareholders'' resolutions and made public statements to put pressure on Chevron, as an apparent quid pro quo exchange for campaign contributions.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jude Webber in Buenos Aires" date="November 9, 2012 10:54 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0d6b7240-2abc-11e2-99bb-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron units appeal Argentine asset freeze</headline><body><![CDATA[Two units of Chevron, the US oil major, have filed an appeal to overturn a $19bn asset freeze in Argentina ordered this week to enforce an Ecuadorean judgment awarding record damages to Amazonian villagers for environmental contamination.</p>
Chevron Corp, the sole judgment debtor, has no assets in Argentina. All operations in Argentina are conducted by subsidiaries that have nothing to do with the fraudulent judgment in Ecuador, the company said in a statement. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jude Webber in Buenos Aires" date="November 7, 2012 11:08 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/97cd6506-2927-11e2-86d7-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Argentine judge freezes Chevron assets</headline><body><![CDATA[An Argentine judge has ordered the immediate freeze of the assets of Chevron, the US oil major, in the South American country to enforce an Ecuadorean court order awarding $19bn in damages to Amazonian villagers over environmental contamination.</p>
Enrique Bruchou, a lawyer for the plaintiffs, said all per cent of Chevron Argentinas stock, worth some $2bn, all of its dividends, its entire 14 per cent stake in Oleoductos del Valle, an oil pipeline company, 40 per cent of revenue from oil sales and 40 per cent of its Argentine bank accounts were covered by the court order.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York" date="November 2, 2012 7:33 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/df2f036c-250f-11e2-86fb-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron profits tumble on lower oil prices</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron reported a sharper than expected fall in its earnings and a drop in its production, but held outthe prospect of longer-term growth as large new projects come on stream.</p>
Unlike some of its competitors, the second-largest US oil group by market capitalisation also reported a steep fall in profits from its refining business, in part because of a fire in August at its refinery in Richmond, California.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jude Webber in Buenos Aires" date="October 31, 2012 11:20 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/cb91619e-2396-11e2-a46b-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Claimants to pursue Chevron''s LatAm assets</headline><body><![CDATA[The assets of US oil major Chevron could be frozen in Argentina and Colombia as plaintiffs seek to collect on a $19bn settlement ordered by a court in Ecuador in the world''s biggest environmental damages suit.</p>
Claimants filed similar suits this year in Canada and Brazil. The formal request to execute the freeze on Chevron assets in Argentina and Colombia will be filed as early as tomorrow [Thursday], said Enrique Bruchou, a lawyer representing plaintiffs, noting that the two South American countries and Ecuador were signatories to a treaty allowing assets to be seized abroad.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ben Bland in Jakarta" date="September 27, 2012 10:08 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/54d74ace-0874-11e2-b57f-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron staff arrested in Indonesia</headline><body><![CDATA[Four Indonesian employees of Chevron, the US oil and gas group, have been arrested in connection with an investigation into alleged corruption at an environmental remediation project in Sumatra.</p>
The Indonesian attorney-general''s office alleges that the project, which is designed to remove toxic substances secreted into the soil after drilling by Chevron, has not been carried out properly and that contractors were not appointed in the correct manner.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jude Webber in Buenos Aires" date="September 14, 2012 11:48 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/2e0d1e42-feaf-11e1-a2e2-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>YPF signs with Chevron for shale fields</headline><body><![CDATA[YPF, the nationalised Argentine energy company, has reached a deal with Chevron of the US to develop shale oilfields in Argentina in a significant step forward for its plans to exploit the reserves discovered in the country in recent years.</p>
However, Repsol of Spain, which lost control of YPF in May when the Argentine government forcibly bought most of its stake, immediately announced it would take legal action against the agreement.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jude Webber in Buenos Aires" date="August 24, 2012 6:07 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e7807812-edf5-11e1-a9d7-00144feab49a.html"><headline>YPF moves towards tie-up with Chevron</headline><body /></entry><entry author="By Guy Chazan" date=" August 2, 2012 3:30 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/51e88976-da35-11e1-b03b-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Chevron bets on the Goldilocks'' of gas</headline><body><![CDATA[Bloomberg]]> </body></entry><entry author="o Paulo" date="August 1, 2012 11:42 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/99bbe7d0-dc1e-11e1-86f8-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Chevron ordered to halt Brazil operations</headline><body><![CDATA[A Brazilian court has ordered Chevron and its drilling partner Transocean to suspend operations in the country within the next month in the latest twist of a long-running legal battle over last November''s oil spill off the coast of Rio de Janeiro.</p>
The public prosecutor''s office said on Wednesday that failure to comply with the order, which could still be overturned in the courts, would result in fines of up to R$500m ($245m) per day.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael Kavanagh" date="July 27, 2012 6:26 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/a7bede68-d805-11e1-9980-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Refining business boosts Chevron</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron, the second-largest US oil group by market value, narrowly beat market expectations even though second-quarter net income in the three months to June fell from $7.7bn a year earlier to $7.2bn.</p>
Revenues at the company sank from $66bn to $60bn in the quarter and from $125bn to $119bn for the half year, as crude oil and gas prices fell.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael Kavanagh" date="July 24, 2012 5:52 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/570981f2-d5a4-11e1-af40-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Iraq bans Chevron over Kurdistan deal</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron has been banned from bidding for exploration licences by Iraq''s federal government following its acquisition of oil interests in the semi-autonomous Kurdistan region of the country last week.</p>
In a statement, Iraq''s oil ministry said Chevron''s investment in the Kurdistan region of Iraq was illegal and illegitimate as it announced the disqualification of Chevron company from doing business in the south and centre of the country and barred it from signing any deals with the federal oil ministry and its companies.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Naomi Mapstone in Lima" date="May 31, 2012 2:20 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e0933b16-aaa7-11e1-9331-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron sued in Canada over Ecuador case</headline><body><![CDATA[Plaintiffs who won an $18.2bn environmental damages case against oil major Chevron in Ecuador after 19 years of litigation have turned to Canada to enforce the ruling.</p>
In the first of several actions expected to be launched worldwide, lawyer Alan Lenczner filed a suit in the Superior Court of Justice in Ontario on Wednesday seeking the seizure of shares and assets of Chevron Canada.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Roman Olearchyk in Kiev and Guy Chazan in London" date="May 10, 2012 6:18 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/2dd0ffae-9a7b-11e1-83bf-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron and Shell near Ukraine gas deals</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron and Royal Dutch Shell are set to be awarded the rights to explore for unconventional gas in Ukraine, potentially catapulting it to the forefront of Europe''s fledgling shale gas industry as it seeks to reduce its dependence on neighbouring Russia.</p>
Ukraine sits along one of the main transport routes for natural gas from Russia to Europe. The country''s often tense negotiations over the price it pays Moscow for its own gas imports have in the past prompted Russia to cut off supplies in winter, hitting households across Europe as well as Ukrainians.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Guy Chazan" date="April 27, 2012 3:15 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/2d64ffbc-906b-11e1-8adc-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Chevron profit rescued by higher oil prices</headline><body><![CDATA[Higher oil prices and improved refining margins helped Chevron, the second-largest US oil group by market value, to post a small rise in first-quarter profit, despite a fall in production.</p>
The company said profit rose 4 per cent to $6.5bn, or $3.27 per share, from $6.2bn a year ago, roughly in line with market expectations. Earnings were boosted by the sale of the company''s Spanish fuels-marketing business. Revenues rose nearly 1 per cent to $60.7bn. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks" date="April 26, 2012 1:52 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/4e918a68-8f29-11e1-ab32-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Exxon and Chevron raise dividends</headline><body><![CDATA[ExxonMobil and Chevron, the two largest US oil companies by market capitalisation, have sharply increased their dividends in a sign of confidence in future earnings. Exxon raised its quarterly dividend by 21 per cent, and Chevron by 11 per cent.</p>
Exxon, which reports first-quarter earnings on Thursday, declared a dividend of 57 cents a share for the second quarter, up from 47 cents in the first quarter.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="o Paulo" date="April 4, 2012 1:47 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/efed0806-7ddb-11e1-bfa5-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Chevron and Transocean sued over second leak</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron and Transocean now face charges of R$40bn ($22bn) in Brazil after a federal prosecutor filed another civil lawsuit against the companies for a second leak off the coast of Rio de Janeiro this year.</p>
Prosecutor Eduardo Santos de Oliveira has already submitted an $11bn lawsuit and criminal charges against the companies for their oil spill in November last year, estimated at between 2,400 and 3,000 barrels.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="o Paulo" date="April 1, 2012 2:32 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/22f84182-798d-11e1-b87e-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Second lawsuit adds to Chevron''s Brazil woes</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron''s oil leak off the coast of Rio de Janeiro last November was less than a thousandth of the size of the 2010 Gulf of Mexico spill, but it could still cripple the company''s Brazilian business and prompt wider regulatory changes, lawyers and government officials have said.</p>
Brazil''s largest oil workers'' union on Wednesday became the latest group to mount an attack on Chevron and its drilling contractor Transocean, filing a civil lawsuit that called for their expulsion from the country''s lucrative oilfields.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="o Paulo" date="March 28, 2012 6:05 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e9e736fe-78f2-11e1-88c5-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Chevron faces new suit over Brazil spill</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron and Transocean are facing further legal battles in Brazil''s promising oil market after the industry''s largest workers'' union filed a civil lawsuit against the companies for last year''s spill off the coast of Rio de Janeiro.</p>
The US oil company and its drilling partner are already facing a R$20bn (US$11bn) lawsuit and criminal charges for the leak at Chevron''s Frade field last November, which was small by industry standards at no more than 3,000 barrels.</p>
FUP, Brazil''s oil workers'' federation, said on Wednesday it had filed a civil lawsuit at a federal court in Rio de Janeiro requesting the cancellation of the companies'' rights to operate in the lucrative offshore field.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="o Paulo" date="March 23, 2012 4:48 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/9c20f3ac-74ff-11e1-ab8b-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Chevron charges risk Brazil operations</headline><body><![CDATA[A Brazilian prosecutor this week filed criminal charges against 17 Chevron and Transocean
 employees for their role in a recent oil spill off the coast of Rio de Janeiro, raising the prospect of a lengthy and damaging trial.</p>
The US oil company and its drilling contractor already face a R$20bn ($11bn) civil lawsuit for the incident last November, when up to 3,000 barrels of oil leaked from Chevron''s lucrative Frade field.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="o Paulo" date="March 22, 2012 12:11 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e21a62f6-739e-11e1-94ba-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Chevron staff charged over Brazil spill</headline><body><![CDATA[Brazilian prosecutors have filed criminal charges against 17 Chevron and Transocean employees for an oil spill last year in Rio de Janeiro, raising concerns over the role of the companies in the country''s booming oil industry.</p>
In a statement on Wednesday, prosecutors said that George Buck, the head of Chevron''s Brazil operations, should face 31 years in jail for what they declared to be a contamination time bomb. Five other Americans, two Frenchmen, two Australians, a Canadian and a British worker were also named.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks" date="March 18, 2012 8:11 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/60ee64d6-6f87-11e1-b3f9-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Chevron puts damper on shale gas hopes</headline><body><![CDATA[Shale gas projects in Europe and China are not guaranteed to succeed and may not come into first production until the next decade, Chevron, the US oil and gas group, has warned.</p>
George Kirkland, Chevron''s head of oil and gas production, told the Financial Times that it would be three to five years before the company could decide whether it would be worth starting up any shale projects outside America, and late this decade or early next before it could be producing gas.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="o Paulo" date="March 18, 2012 6:24 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e7e1b98c-7123-11e1-a7f1-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Passports of Chevron execs held in Brazil</headline><body><![CDATA[A Brazilian court is seeking to bar 17 executives of US oil major Chevron and oil services company Transocean from leaving Brazil pending criminal charges related to an oil spill at Chevron''s Frade field off the coast of Rio de Janeiro last year.</p>
A federal judge in Rio de Janeiro has granted a request from the prosecutor''s office to withhold the passports of the executives, who include George Buck, the head of Chevron in Brazil, Reuters reported.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York and Ben McLannahan in Tokyo" date="March 18, 2012 5:36 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/dc83a2ba-6f72-11e1-9c57-00144feab49a.html"><headline>China key to Chevron''s LNG investment</headline><body><![CDATA[Shale gas may have revolutionised the US energy market, but Chevron is counting on it not having the same effect in Asia, at least for a while yet.</p>
The company is investing a planned $39bn in Gorgon and Wheatstone, two huge gas projects off the coast of Western Australia to produce liquefied natural gas for Asian markets. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="o Paulo" date="March 16, 2012 2:48 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/c3c921b0-6f0d-11e1-afb8-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Chevron finds fresh oil leak in Brazil</headline><body><![CDATA[Oil companies operating in Brazil will probably be forced to increase spending on safety measures after Chevron, already facing an $11bn lawsuit for an oil spill in Rio de Janeiro, reported a second leak at the same oilfield.</p>
The US company, which ranks as Brazil''s third-biggest oil producer by volume, announced on Thursday it would suspend drilling at its offshore Frade project after detecting a small new seep in the field and subsidence in the area.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York" date="March 13, 2012 10:44 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/03da616c-6d2c-11e1-ab1a-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Chevron chief criticises Obama over oil price</headline><body><![CDATA[The chief executive of Chevron, the US oil group, has criticised the Obama administration over the rising price of fuel, arguing that there is much more that the government could do to help bring it down.</p>
John Watson urged the administration to open up more of the US coast for oil development, speed up approvals of drilling permits and hold back from the tax increases on oil companies that have been proposed by President Barack Obama.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York" date="January 27, 2012 7:02 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/7888277c-48f3-11e1-974a-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron seeks to be treated fairly'' by Brazil</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron, the second-largest US oil company by market capitalisation, has asked to be treated fairly in Brazil over its offshore oil spill last November.</p>
Federal prosecutors in Brazil have filed a case for civil damages of about $11bn, and Chevron may also face criminal charges.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York" date="January 12, 2012 2:21 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/39e7a27c-3caa-11e1-9bcc-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Refining slump dents Chevron''s profits</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron, the second-largest US oil company by market capitalisation, warned that its earnings for the fourth quarter of last year would be significantly below the third quarter''s, as a result of a slump in refining profits of about $2bn and adverse exchange rate effects.</p>
Shares fell by 2 per cent on Thursday morning to $105.54.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Naomi Mapstone in Lima" date="January 6, 2012 1:06 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/61da3020-3858-11e1-9f07-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron to fight Ecuador ruling</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron vowed to continue to fight an $18bn damages ruling for pollution in Ecuador after an appeals court this week upheld a 2011 ruling against the oil major.</p>
After 18 years of battle and 40 years of suffering, finally there will be justice and hopefully repair to the Amazon, said Pablo Fajardo, lawyer for the plaintiffs.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks in New York and Naomi Mapstone in Lima" date="January 4, 2012 11:25 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/86d1169c-36ef-11e1-b741-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron''s Ecuador case takes new twist</headline><body><![CDATA[Lawyers acting for plaintiffs suing Chevron, the US oil group, over pollution in Ecuador plan to pursue the American company with legal actions in other countries after an Ecuadorean court upheld an $18bn damages award.
</p>
Pablo Fajardo, an Ecuador-based lawyer representing the 30,000 plaintiffs suing over environmental damage in the Amazon region, said: It''s not going to be easy to enforce this judgment, but even if hell freezes over we''re going to do it.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Naomi Mapstone in Lima" date="January 4, 2012 4:19 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/e2404598-367c-11e1-a3fa-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Ecuador court upholds $18bn Chevron ruling</headline><body><![CDATA[An Ecuadorean appeals court has upheld an $18bn ruling against Chevron for pollution in the remote pocket of the Amazon where the country''s oil industry was founded.</p>
The damages bill represents about one-third of Ecuador''s gross domestic product, making it the most expensive environmental suit in history, although the BP Gulf of Mexico oil spill is expected to overtake it.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="o Paulo" date="December 2, 2011 12:11 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/5463a67c-1c76-11e1-9b41-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Brazil orders Chevron to shut well</headline><body><![CDATA[The Brazilian government has ordered Chevron to shut one of its 11 production wells in an important offshore field where the company suffered an oil leak last month.</p>
Chevron said the decision by the Brazilian regulator, the National Petroleum Agency, followed a safety audit last week of its Frade offshore oil platform amid reports the authorities were unhappy that the company did not report the presence of hydrogen sulphide in crude at the facility. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="o Paulo" date="November 25, 2011 4:53 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/5eebe5fa-177b-11e1-b00e-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron banned and fined over oil spill</headline><body><![CDATA[Brazil''s government this week banned Chevron from drilling in its waters in the latest twist of an increasingly politicised saga over the US company''s oil spill off the coast of Rio de Janeiro.</p>
On Monday, state authorities said they would block Chevron''s drilling contractor, Transocean, which also operated the drill that caused the huge Gulf of Mexico oil spill last year, from operating in the region.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="o Paulo" date="November 24, 2011 1:39 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/2d1d203e-163b-11e1-b4b1-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Brazil suspends Chevron over oil spill</headline><body><![CDATA[Brazil has temporarily banned Chevron from drilling in the country after it caused an oil spill off the coast of Rio de Janeiro, raising doubts about the company''s role in one of the industry''s biggest investment programmes.</p>
ANP, Brazil''s oil and gas regulator, accused the US company of negligence late on Wednesday, announcing it would suspend all of Chevron''s drilling until it clarified the reasons for a spill that released almost 3,000 barrels of oil into the sea earlier this month.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="o Paulo" date="November 21, 2011 10:37 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/8852123a-1478-11e1-85c7-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron faces possible ban over Brazil leak</headline><body><![CDATA[Brazil said it could ban Chevron from drilling in its lucrative deepwater oilfields as well as imposing heavy fines for a leak off the coast of Rio de Janeiro, sending a warning signal to foreign companies looking to profit from the country''s oil boom.</p>
Chevron''s drilling contractor, Transocean, which operated the drill that caused the huge Gulf of Mexico oil spill last year, will be banned from operating in Rio and possibly in the rest of Brazil, the state government said on Monday.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="o Paulo" date="November 17, 2011 11:17 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/22aeeafa-1169-11e1-9d04-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Brazil probes Chevron over spill</headline><body><![CDATA[Brazilian regulators are investigating Chevron over an oil spill off the coast of Rio de Janeiro, sending off warning signals about the country''s ambitious deepwater drilling plans.</p>
The US energy group has rushed to concrete over one of its wells at its Frade project, 230 miles north of Rio, which it has said was responsible for releasing as much as 650 barrels of oil into the sea.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="October 28, 2011 3:12 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/22719532-016b-11e1-ae24-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron reports drop in production</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron, the second-biggest oil company in the US by market capitalisation, followed the industry trend in reporting a drop in production even as its third-quarter earnings more than doubled on higher prices for crude oil and refined products.</p>
Chevron''s global net oil-equivalent production was 2.6m barrels per day in the third quarter, down from 2.74m bpd in the same period last year, on maturing fields and maintenance-related downtime.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Peter Smith in Sydney and Sylvia Pfeifer in London" date="September 26, 2011 4:34 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/bf12c3aa-e813-11e0-9fc7-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Chevron approves A$29bn Australia LNG project</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron, the US oil and gas group, has given the official go-ahead for one of Australia''s largest natural gas ventures by formally approving a A$29bn (US$28bn) investment in the Wheatstone project.</p>
Wheatstone, situated off the Western Australian coast, is the latest Australian LNG project to be given final investment approval this year, with more than A$50bn being spent on ventures in Queensland''s emerging coal-seam gas to the LNG industry alone. Analysts predict the Wheatstone project and others already planned will enable Australia eventually to become the world''s largest producer of LNG, eclipsing Qatar, currently the number one. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="September 20, 2011 4:38 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b539cb66-e328-11e0-bb55-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Court allows pursuit of Chevron in Amazon case</headline><body><![CDATA[A US appeals court has thrown out an order blocking the enforcement of a multibillion dollar ruling against Chevron outside of Ecuador, cancelling out a previous victory for the company in its long-running legal battle over environmental damage in the Amazon.</p>
In February, an Ecuadorean court issued the award against Chevron following allegations of oil pollution in the Amazon by Texaco, which Chevron took over in 2001. Chevron has not paid the damages as it is appealing the verdict.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="September 7, 2011 12:12 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/f0c36990-d8d7-11e0-aff1-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron announces Gulf of Mexico oil find</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron, the second-largest US oil group by market capitalisation, has announced a potentially large discovery in the deep waters of the Gulf of Mexico, confirming the region''s high potential after the problems that followed BP''s Deepwater Horizon disaster last year.</p>
The find is good news for BP, which like Chevron has 43.75 per cent of the project. BP is the junior partner, however; Chevron, as operator, is in charge of drilling and other decisions about the well.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sylvia Pfeifer in London" date="July 29, 2011 3:47 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/2d5fef02-b9ea-11e0-8171-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron earnings jump on high oil prices</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron has become the latest leading company to announce a jump in second-quarter earnings on the back of higher energy prices.</p>
The second-biggest oil company in the US reported net income of $7.7bn for the period, up 43 per cent from the same period the year before, beating estimates as strong oil prices and higher refining margins offset a fall in output. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Mark Wembridge" date="June 3, 2011 7:56 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/3a8df396-8dac-11e0-a0c4-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Chevron to probe Wales refinery blast</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron has launched an inquiry into an explosion and fire at its oil refinery in south-west Wales that killed four people and seriously injured another.</p>
The US oil major said on Friday it would examine the circumstances of the blast at its 220,000 barrel a day Pembroke Dock refinery.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="April 29, 2011 3:45 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/883edea0-7265-11e0-96bf-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron profits jump 35% on high oil prices</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron reported a 35 per cent rise in first-quarter net profit on higher prices for crude oil and refined products even as it suffered a slight drop in production. </p>
The US''s second-largest oil company by production said on Friday it earned $6.2bn, or $3.09 per share, in the first quarter of 2011, compared with $4.6bn, or $2.27 per share, in the same quarter last year. 
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sylvia Pfeifer in London" date="April 20, 2011 6:38 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/8a581a0a-6b60-11e0-9be1-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Chevron''s vote of confidence in deepwater drilling</headline><body><![CDATA[Last autumn, while the US government''s moratorium on deepwater drilling was still in place in the Gulf of Mexico following the BP spill, Chevron took an unusual decision. </p>
In spite of the standstill, the second-biggest oil group in the US sanctioned investment into three major projects in the gulf.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sylvia Pfeifer" date="April 17, 2011 11:13 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/0d048202-693d-11e0-9040-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Chevron hits at North Sea oil tax rise</headline><body><![CDATA[The head of Chevron, the second-largest oil company in the US, has attacked the UK government''s recent tax increase on oil and gas production in the North Sea, warning there may be unintended consequences from the decision.</p>
When you increase taxes every few years, particularly without consulting with industry, there will be unintended consequences of that in terms of where we choose to invest, John Watson, Chevron chairman and chief executive, told the Financial Times during a visit to London. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Peter Smith in Perth and Sylvia Pfeifer in London" date="April 10, 2011 7:41 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/2c50ca8a-6357-11e0-bd7f-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Shell takes stake in Chevron gas project</headline><body><![CDATA[Royal Dutch Shell has struck a deal with US rival Chevron to take an equity stake in a $25bn Western Australian natural gas project that is due to be given the investment go ahead later this year.</p>
The Chevron-operated Wheatstone project is one of nearly a dozen large liquefied natural gas projects in Australia that Shell and other big oil and gas companies are developing to satisfy demand from China and other energy-hungry markets in Asia.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Naomi Mapstone in Lima and Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="February 15, 2011 1:50 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/1f7969a8-3872-11e0-959c-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron faces $8.6bn damages bill</headline><body><![CDATA[An Ecuadorean court has ordered Chevron to pay up to $8.6bn in damages for environmental damage dating back to the start of the Opec nation''s oil industry 40 years ago.</p>
Judge Nicholas Zambrano of Nueva Loja court in Lago Agrio handed down a 187-page ruling that splits damages between $6.4bn for a soil and water clean-up and $2.2bn for a local healthcare system.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="February 2, 2011 3:05 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/3e106720-2e6f-11e0-8733-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron sues defendants in Ecuador case</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron has filed a civil lawsuit against the trial lawyers and consultants heading the long-running Ecuador case against the company, charging them of leading a fraudulent litigation. </p>
The lawsuit, filed on Tuesday before the US District Court of the Southern District of New York, was under the Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organizations (RICO) Act, as well as other federal and state laws. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="January 28, 2011 8:33 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/75921ad4-2af2-11e0-a2f3-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Chevron impatient over Gulf drilling barriers</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron, the US'' second biggest oil company, is growing impatient with regulatory barriers to drilling in the deepwater Gulf of Mexico following the Macondo disaster.</p>
We just think the unprecedented step of just shutting down a business has reached the point of diminishing returns, John Watson, Chevron''s chief executive, said on Friday.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jamie Etheridge" date="December 20, 2010 5:14 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/3f27a94c-0c56-11e0-8408-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron builds up steam in the Middle East</headline><body><![CDATA[At OPEC''s 50th anniversary summit in October, Ali Al-Naimi, Saudi Arabia''s powerful oil minister, was at pains to denounce the idea that the era of easy oil  that is, cheap to extract oil  has passed. </p>
How can you say that easy oil is over, when we still have over 88bn [barrels] in the Ghawar field? That is more than many countries in the world, said Mr Naimi, referring to the world''s largest oilfield.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston" date="December 10, 2010 2:59 am" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/b0e4eb84-03f1-11e0-8dd2-00144feabdc0.html"><headline>Chevron sets out $26bn spending plan for 2011</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron, the US''s second biggest oil company, will boost capital expenditure to $26bn in 2011, putting its spending near that of industry leader ExxonMobil. </p>
The spending plan, a $4.4bn increase from 2010, marks the most Chevron has ever budgeted for capital expenditure. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheila McNulty in Houston and Leslie Hook in Beijing" date="December 3, 2010 5:35 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/9f01eba2-fe91-11df-845b-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Chevron sells 18% gas field stake to Sinopec</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron is selling an 18 per cent stake in its Indonesian deepwater gasfields to Sinopec for $680m.</p>
Sinopec, the Chinese oil and gas group, has been expanding its global reach this past year, signing deals with Petrobras of Brazil, Statoil of Norway and Sonagol of Angola.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hannah Kuchler in New York" date="November 9, 2010 9:55 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/1d36b0c6-ec12-11df-b50f-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Chevron boosts natural gas sector</headline><body><![CDATA[Shares in natural gas producers rose after Chevron
 bought Atlas Energybut the deal failed to excite the wider market, which was led lower by the financial sector. </p>
Atlas Energy
 soared 34 per cent to $42.50 after Chevron said it would buy the natural gas producer. But shares in Chevron slid 1.5 per cent to $83.56. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ed Crooks and Alan Rappeport in New York" date="November 9, 2010 6:45 pm" url="http://www.ft.com/cms/s/0/46b6bd82-ec04-11df-b50f-00144feab49a.html"><headline>Chevron in $4.3bn shale gas Atlas deal</headline><body><![CDATA[Chevron, the second-largest US oil group, has joined the rush into North American unconventional gas assets with an agreed $4.3bn deal to buy Atlas Energy, a company with a strong position in a key shale field 
in Pennsylvania.
</p>
The deal follows a succession of acquisitions by large international oil groups of North American unconventional gas reserves, such as shale gas, which have been made financially viable by new production techniques and falling costs.</p>
]]> </body></entry></news>