
<news><entry author="By Elizabeth Dexheimer" date="Mar 04, 2013 12:34 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-04/goldman-joins-citigroup-in-expanding-cyber-threat-lists.html"><headline>Goldman Joins Citigroup in Expanding Cyber Threat Lists</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) and Citigroup Inc. (C) stepped up warnings to shareholders about cyber attacks as the U.S. prodded banks and government agencies to bolster their defenses. </p> <p>Online and mobile banking give new points of entry that can be used to disrupt or penetrate operations, the two New York- based firms said last week in annual regulatory filings. The companies said they''re vulnerable to tactics that overload websites to shut off public access, such as assaults that disrupted the nation''s largest lenders late last year. </p> <p>U.S. banks are speculating that foreign nations, organized crime or terrorists are behind efforts to cripple their websites and warning that costs to keep intruders at bay will rise. President Barack Obama directed the government on Feb. 12 to develop voluntary security standards for companies running vital infrastructure and is pushing Congress to set formal rules. </p> <p>We are going to see more disclosures, and that''s a warning sign that things are really getting bad, said Lawrence Ponemon, chairman of Ponemon Institute LLC, a Traverse City, Michigan-based security research firm, which predicts a 30 percent increase in expenses tied to cyber intrusions this year. </p>




Photographer: Jin Lee/Bloomberg

<p>
U.S. banks speculate that foreign nations, organized crime or terrorists are behind efforts to cripple their websites and warn that costs to keep intruders at bay will rise. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Aoife White" date="Mar 04, 2013 11:51 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-04/microsoft-may-get-eu-fine-this-week-on-browser-choice-mlex-says.html"><headline>Microsoft May Get EU Fine This Week on Browser Choice, MLex Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) may be fined by
European Union regulators as soon as March 6 for violating a
settlement to give users a choice of web browsers, MLex reported
today without saying where it got the information. </p>
<p>Antoine Colombani, a spokesman for the European Commission,
declined to comment on the report. EU Competition Commissioner
Joaquin Almunia will hold a press conference on Wednesday on an
unspecified matter, he said. </p>
<p>Robin Koch, a spokesman for Microsoft, declined to comment. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Cristiane Lucchesi" date="Mar 05, 2013 10:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-05/goldman-brazil-investment-bank-chairman-wainstein-said-to-leave.html"><headline>Goldman''s Brazil Investment-Bank Chairman Said to Depart</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Daniel Wainstein, chairman of
Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)''s Brazil investment-banking business,
will leave the company, two people with direct knowledge of the
matter said. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs has been discussing the changes with
Wainstein for the past several months, according to a person at
the New York-based firm who asked not to be identified because
the decision hasn''t been announced. Wainstein, 42, and Andre Laport Ribeiro are Goldman Sachs''s only partners in Brazil. </p>
<p>Wainstein asked to leave after working at the firm since
2000, one of the people said. He was appointed chairman of
Brazil investment banking in April 2012, when Antonio Pereira
and Fabio Bicudo were named co-chief operating officers. The
bank ranked sixth in equity underwriting in Brazil last year,
with $732 million in transactions, data compiled by Bloomberg
show. It was No. 8 among merger advisers with $14.3 billion in
deals, the data show. </p>
<p>Michael DuVally, a spokesman for Goldman Sachs, declined to
comment on Wainstein''s departure. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs said in October it would double capital in
Brazil to 800 million reais ($407 million) while closing its
asset-management business in the country. </p>
<p>The firm, which doesn''t disclose Brazil revenue or profit,
named Paulo Leme as chairman for the country a year ago. Goldman
Sachs has said its strategy in Brazil is to focus on complex
products with higher profit margins, such as convertible debt
and receivables securitization. </p>
<h2>Local Competition </h2>
<p>U.S. and international banks are competing against Brazil-
based companies such as Bradesco BBI SA, Banco Itau BBA SA and
Banco BTG Pactual SA, which have used their stronger local
contacts to squeeze out foreign firms. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs completed its strategy to become a full-
service bank in Brazil in 2009, after two failed attempts to buy
local firms. In 1998, Goldman Sachs tried to buy Banco de
Investimentos Garantia SA, which was acquired by Credit Suisse
Group AG. </p>
<p>Seven years later it sought to purchase Banco Pactual SA,
an investment bank later acquired by UBS AG. Pactual was sold
back to BTG Partners in 2009 and is now Banco BTG Pactual SA.
BTG went public last year in a $1.94 billion initial offering
that Goldman Sachs helped underwrite. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Mar 05, 2013  6:23 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-05/jpmorgan-seeks-bigger-payout-with-smaller-buyback-cfo-lake-says.html"><headline>JPMorgan Seeks Bigger Payout With Smaller Buyback, CFO Lake Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the largest
U.S. bank, asked regulators to approve a higher quarterly
dividend and reduced stock buyback after suffering its biggest
trading loss ever last year. </p>
<p>We know that we would like to increase our dividend,
Chief Financial Officer Marianne Lake told investors during a
Boston investor conference sponsored by Citigroup Inc. We did
ask for buybacks, but lower than last year. </p>
<p>The Federal Reserve forced JPMorgan to suspend a $15
billion share repurchase program last year after the lender
disclosed derivatives losses that eventually swelled to more
than $6.2 billion. JPMorgan''s board of directors cut Chief
Executive Officer Jamie Dimon''s pay for 2012 in half after a
review of the so-called London Whale episode held him partly
responsible for the botched trades. </p>
<p>Dimon previously told analysts that JPMorgan reduced its
2013 buyback target by at least 20 percent to less than $3
billion per quarter. The bank is projected to raise its 30-cent
quarterly dividend to 35 cents a share, according to analysts
surveyed by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>The entire capital plan needs Fed approval as part of the
central bank''s annual review of the biggest U.S. lenders, with
an answer expected by mid-March. </p>
<p>We''re going to find out over the course of the next week
or so whether or not we get our capital plan approved, Lake
said today. </p>
<h2>Stress Test </h2>
<p>While JPMorgan executives want to return more capital to
shareholders, next year''s payouts will depend on new
international capital rules and how they affect the Fed''s so-
called stress test, Lake said. </p>
<p>We''ll make our decision when we know how things shake out
toward the end of this year, Lake said. And we''d like to
return capital back to shareholders. So we hope to have a chance
to do that. </p>
<p>JPMorgan purchased $1.6 billion shares before its buyback
program was shut down last year. The Fed later approved the
repurchase of $3 billion in additional shares in this year''s
first quarter, leaving $10.4 billion of the original amount
still unused. </p>
<p>Dimon has said he''s inclined to buy back shares when the
price falls below tangible book value, a theoretical measure of
what the company would be worth in a liquidation. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Camila Russo" date="Mar 05, 2013  2:12 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-05/jpmorgan-expanding-argentine-business-after-barclays-leaves.html"><headline>JPMorgan Expanding Argentine Business After Barclays Leaves</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) is expanding
its business in Argentina as the country remains a ''''key'''' market
in the region, the bank''s senior country officer said. </p>
<p>JPMorgan, the largest U.S. bank, is leasing an additional
three floors in its headquarters in Buenos Aires and hiring
about 15 people this year, Facundo Gomez Minujin said. The New
York-based bank has operated its local investment unit in
Argentina since 1985, according to its website. </p>
<p>Argentina remains a key element of our JPMorgan franchise
in Latin America, Gomez Minujin wrote in an e-mail. In the
last 12 months we have increased our headcount. </p>
<p>JPMorgan is expanding in South America''s second-largest
economy even as competitors have cut staff and closed divisions
amid a tightening of currency controls and financial oversight
by President Cristina Fernandez de Kirchner''s government.
Barclays Plc (BARC) closed its wealth management office in Buenos Aires
in January 2012 for strategic reasons while Exotix, a
brokerage, last year transferred some staff to New York and
London due to regulations. </p>
<p>Gomez Minujin denied a report published today from Buenos
Aires-based newspaper Clarin that the bank was leaving the
country by the end of the month. </p>
<p>We''re maintaining our presence Argentina just like we
always have, he said in a telephone interview. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andra Timu and Irina Savu" date="Mar 05, 2013  1:28 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-05/jpmorgan-sees-limited-additional-demand-for-romanian-local-debt.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sees Limited Extra Demand for Romania Debt on Index</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Extra demand for Romanian debt
stemming from inclusion in an emerging-market bond index will be
limited as investors have already boosted their holdings by $3.5
billion through January, JPMorgan  Chase  Co. (JPM) said. </p>
<p>The U.S. bank, which will incorporate three Romanian leu-
denominated fixed-income securities in its GBI-EM index over
three months starting March 1, had estimated total inflows of $2
billion amid the inclusion, according to a research note sent to
clients today. </p>
<p>Investors have already increased their exposure to
Romanian bonds and we expect extra demand from index inclusion
to be limited, JPMorgan said in the note. The potential
future inclusion of additional Romanian bonds in the index,
which depends on liquidity, may add to further demand. </p>
<p>Leu-denominated bonds and the currency have rallied since
January after JPMorgan said three of the country''s local notes
are eligible for index inclusion. Eleven Romanian notes are also
eligible for entry to a Barclays Plc (BARC) emerging-market index,
according to e-mailed comments from Societe Generale SA. (GLE) </p>
<p>The leu strengthened 0.3 percent to 3.3428 per euro by 7:53
p.m. in Bucharest. It has gained 2.1 percent against Europe''s
common currency this year, the seventh-best performance among
more than 20 emerging-market currencies tracked by Bloomberg.
The yield on Romania''s January 2016 bonds slid to 5.73 percent
at an auction on Feb. 14, compared with a rate of 6.03 percent
at a similar-maturity sale on Jan. 10. </p>
<h2>Foreign Holders </h2>
<p>Foreign investors'' holding of Romanian debt rose to more
than 20 percent in February from 5 percent in November,
according to JPMorgan. </p>
<p>The increased interest from international investors helped
the Finance Ministry raise a record 11.4 billion lei ($3.4
billion) of local debt in January in addition to 503 million
euros ($655 million) of bonds also sold domestically. It also
raised 4.03 billion lei last month, more than the 3.7 billion
lei planned. </p>
<p>Romania''s October 2015, January 2016 and July 2017 leu
bonds are eligible for the JPMorgan index, phased in over a
three-month period concluding on May 1, JPMorgan said in the
note. Their final expected weight in the GBI-EM Global
Diversified index is 0.87 percent, it said. </p>
<p>That compares with the country''s current weight of 0.29
percent, Patrick Burton, a spokesman for the bank, said in an e-
mailed response to questions from Bloomberg News. </p>
<p>JPMorgan raised its estimate for Romania''s economic growth
to 1.5 percent this year from 0.8 percent, adding that it sees
risks from the uncertainty around a new deal with the
International Monetary Fund. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Paul Armstrong and Esteban Duarte" date="Mar 05, 2013 11:41 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-05/morgan-stanley-leads-busiest-day-for-bank-bonds-in-2-months-1-.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Leads Busiest Day for Bank Bonds in 2 Months</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) led the busiest day
for bank bond issuance in Europe in almost two months as lenders
took advantage of borrowing costs that remain near the lowest in
five years. </p>
<p>The New York-based owner of the largest brokerage sold 1.25
billion euros ($1.6 billion) of notes due March 2018, its first
benchmark issue in euros since September, according to data
compiled by Bloomberg. Spain''s Banco Bilbao Vizcaya Argentaria
SA (BBVA) priced its second senior, unsecured deal of the year, while
Credit Agricole SA (ACA) in Paris raised its first funds in the
currency since October, people with knowledge of the
transactions said. </p>
<p>Bank bond issuance tumbled 80 percent to 12.8 billion euros
in February from the previous month as the euro-region economy
shrank the most since 2009 and Italy''s deadlocked election made
investors wary of all but the safest government securities.
Standard Chartered Plc was the last of the 10 biggest European
banks to report earnings today, removing one hurdle to lenders
wanting to raise cash. </p>
<p>Issuance is taking off as the earnings season is
ending, said Serafi Rodriguez, an Andorra-based fixed-income
trader at Morabanc, which manages 6.4 billion euros of assets.
He said he may buy the BBVA bonds. The Italian political
issues are far from being solved, so it makes sense for
financials to take advantage of the market opportunities to get
funding at historical low levels. </p>
<h2>Existing Bonds </h2>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s deal is its first in the currency since
issuing 1 billion euros of 3.75 percent senior, unsecured notes
due 2017 on Sept. 17, data compiled by Bloomberg show. The new
securities were priced to yield 145 basis points more than the
mid-swap rate, compared with the 134 basis-point spread of the
existing bonds. Larissa Haida, a London-based press officer at
Morgan Stanley, declined to comment. </p>
<p>It''s the busiest day for benchmark issuance since Jan. 23,
when Commonwealth Bank of Australia, UniCredit SpA (UCG)''s Austrian
unit and Deutsche Pfandbriefbank AG sold a total of 1.6 billion
euros of bonds, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>The extra yield that investors demand to hold European
financial company bonds instead of benchmark government debt
widened six basis points since the results of the Italian
election on Feb. 25 to 160 basis points, according to Bank of
America Merrill Lynch''s Euro Banking Index. The spread compares
with a five-year low of 150 basis points on Jan. 14. </p>
<h2>First Sale </h2>
<p>BBVA''s 1.5 billion-euro sale of March 2016 bonds is its
first senior, unsecured benchmark note issue since it sold 1.5
billion euros of 3.75 percent securities due 2018 on Jan. 3,
Bloomberg data show. </p>
<p>BBVA, as always, is taking advantage of opportunities to
tap the markets as they arise, said Paul Tobin, a Madrid-based
spokesman at the lender. </p>
<p>Spain''s second-biggest bank priced the notes at a yield of
273 basis points more than the benchmark swap rate, a person
familiar with the matter said. That compares with the 270 basis-
point spread on the lender''s existing 605 million euros of 4.875
percent April 2016 senior notes. </p>
<p>Credit Agricole sold its first senior, unsecured fixed-rate
bonds in the common currency since it issued 1.25 billion euros
of 1.875 percent notes due 2017 in October. The yield on those
bonds is 70 basis points over the swap rate, compared with the
85 basis-point spread on its new March 2018 securities, a person
with knowledge of the transaction said. </p>
<p>France''s third-biggest bank also increased the size of its
1.25 billion euros of floating-rate notes maturing January 2015,
first sold in December, by 750 million euros. </p>
<p>Anne-Sophie Gentil, a Paris-based official at Credit
Agricole, didn''t respond to a phone call seeking comment. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Susan Decker" date="Mar 05, 2013 10:04 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-05/pfizer-sues-teva-mylan-to-delay-generic-celebrex-until-2015.html"><headline>Pfizer Sues Teva, Mylan to Delay Generic Celebrex Until 2015</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE) said it filed patent-
infringement lawsuits today against generic-drug makers
including Teva Pharmaceutical Industries Ltd. (TEVA) to prevent them
from selling a low-cost version of the painkiller Celebrex until
December 2015. </p>
<p>Pfizer had won a ruling in 2008 that prevents Teva from
entering the market until May 2014. In that case, an appeals
court invalidated a patent that expires in December 2015. Pfizer
said today it had persuaded the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office
to reissue that patent with changes. </p>
<p>Celebrex, also known by the active ingredient celecoxib,
generated $1.75 billion in U.S. sales last year, the company
said Jan. 29. Each day that Pfizer can delay generic competition
means about $5 million in revenue for the New York-based
company. </p>
<p>The reissued patent covers methods of treating
osteoarthritis with celecoxib. In addition to Petach Tikva,
Israel-based Teva, the world''s largest generic-drug maker,
Pfizer said it sued Mylan Inc., Actavis Inc. (ACT), Lupin Ltd. (LPC) and
Apotex Inc. in federal court in eastern Virginia. </p>
<p>Continued development of new medicines that enhance
patient lives is supported by protecting intellectual property
and innovation, Pfizer General Counsel Amy Schulman said in a
statement. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lucy Meakin and Emma Charlton" date="Mar 05, 2013  7:35 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-05/morgan-stanley-lazard-recommend-italian-spanish-bonds.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley, Lazard Recommend Italian, Spanish Bonds</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>European bond investors from Lazard
Asset Management and Pioneer Investments recommend investing in
Italian and Spanish government debt this year. </p>
<p>It''s risk-on with regard to peripheral bond markets,
Christian Eckert, head of European fixed income at Lazard, which
oversees the equivalent of $9.7 billion, said today at the
Euromoney Bond Investors Congress in London. </p>
<p>Italy''s 10-year government bond yields have jumped about 70
basis points since reaching 4.07 percent, the lowest in more
that two years, on Jan. 25, as inconclusive elections threatened
to derail austerity measures designed to control the nation''s
debt and counter Europe''s financial crisis. They''re still almost
2 percentage points lower than they were in July, before
European Central Bank President Mario Draghi pledged to do
whatever it takes to hold the euro area together. </p>
<p>Glenn Hadden, head of European fixed income at Morgan
Stanley, told the conference that he favors investing in the
policy of the ECB to drive down the yields of the region''s
peripheral debt. </p>
<p>At 5.06 percent, Spain''s 10-year bonds yield 362 basis
points more than benchmark German bunds. </p>
<p>The risk premium on peripherals is very competitive,
said Cosimo Marasciulo, head of government bonds and currencies
at Pioneer. Buying the bonds of the nations is a compelling
trade, though investors need to be wary of volatility, he said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri" date="Mar 06, 2013  4:03 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-06/disney-shareholders-reject-call-to-split-chairman-ceo-job.html"><headline>Disney Shareholders Reject Call to Split Chairman-CEO Job</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS) investors turned
back calls for a future split of the two top jobs held by
Chairman and Chief Executive Officer Robert Iger, rejecting the
demands of three state pension funds. </p>
<p>Sixty five percent of shareholders voting opposed the
split, Disney said today at its annual meeting in Phoenix. The
company''s executive compensation and bonus plans passed, and
Iger was re-elected to the board with 98 percent support. </p>
<p>Investors in Disney, the world''s largest entertainment
company, were considering a proposal by the Connecticut
Retirement Plans  Trust Funds to split the roles of chairman
and CEO going forward. Iger, who plans to step down as CEO in
March 2015, led Disney to a 76 percent total shareholder return
for the fiscal year ended in September, the company has said. </p>
<p>He''s had phenomenally good performance, said Kannan
Ramaswamy, a professor of management at the Thunderbird School
of Global Management in Glendale, Arizona, who spoke before the
meeting. Shareholders should be happy. This was not the most
opportune time to pick a fight. </p>
<p>Disney reached an all-time closing high yesterday of
$56.48. The shares fell 0.2 percent to $56.36 at the close today
in New York. </p>




Photographer: Victor J. Blue/Bloomberg

<p>
Walt Disney Co. reached an all-time closing high yesterday of $56.48. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chris Dolmetsch" date="Mar 06, 2013  3:23 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-06/morgan-stanley-seeks-dismissal-of-metlife-mortgage-suit.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Seeks Dismissal of MetLife Mortgage Suit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley asked a judge to
dismiss a suit filed by MetLife (MET) Inc. over mortgage-backed
securities, saying the insurer knew the U.S. housing market was
starting to deteriorate before it bought most of them. </p>
<p>MetLife had invested about $56.5 billion in residential
mortgage-backed securities before 2008, making it a
sophisticated investor, and the insurer that same year
bought the mortgage unit of First Horizon National Corp., which
had originated loans for securities in the case, lawyers for
Morgan Stanley said today during a hearing before New York State
Supreme Court Justice Eileen Bransten in Manhattan. </p>
<p>The New York-based insurer knew that underwriting standards
for mortgages had started to deteriorate and had already begun
to reduce its exposure to mortgage-backed securities by mid-
2007, before it made 36 of the 52 purchases at issue in the
case, Morgan Stanley (MS) attorneys said in a court filing. </p>
<p>Not only did MetLife invest more than $50 billion in
mortgage-backed securities, one of their affiliates originated
the mortgages that are alleged to be fraudulent in this case,
James P. Rouhandeh of Davis Polk  Wardwell LLP, an attorney for
New York-based Morgan Stanley, said during today''s hearing. </p>
<h2>Fraud Claim </h2>
<p>MetLife, the largest U.S. life insurer, sued Morgan Stanley
in April, accusing the investment bank of fraud and other claims
involving $757 million in residential mortgage-backed securities
purchased in 2006 and 2007. </p>
<p>MetLife said Morgan Stanley told it that the loans backing
the securities were originated based on specific underwriting
guidelines and collateralized by properties that had been
accurately appraised. </p>
<p>The case is Metropolitan Life Insurance Co. v. Morgan
Stanley, 651360/2012, New York State Supreme Court, New York
County (Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Aoife White" date="Mar 06, 2013 12:03 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-06/microsoft-fined-731-million-by-eu-for-violating-browser-accord.html"><headline>Microsoft Fined $731 Million by EU Over Browser Accord</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) was fined 561
million euros ($731 million) by European Union regulators for
violating the terms of a settlement to give users a choice of
web browsers aside from its Internet Explorer. </p>
<p>Today''s fine -- about 1 percent of the company''s 2012
revenues -- brings to 2.24 billion euros the penalties imposed
on Microsoft in its EU antitrust clashes over the past decade,
including an initial 899 million-euro fine for failing to obey
an order to share data with competitors. </p>
<p>The world''s largest software maker agreed in 2009 to offer
access to other browsers as a part of a settlement to repair its
relationship with the bloc''s regulators. The company said last
July it only learned that month that it didn''t offer its browser
choice software on some 28 million computers running Windows 7
Service Pack 1, or 10 percent of the computers that should have
received it. </p>
<p>This is a big fine, but it''s a big company and a
sophisticated company that made a commitment and they failed to
honor it, said Charles Whiddington, a lawyer at Field Fisher
Waterhouse LLP in London. Commitments are really important to
the commission because they lubricate the efficiency of its
policing of the rules. </p>
<p>Microsoft took full responsibility for the technical
error that caused this problem and have apologized for it, the
company said in an e-mailed statement. </p>
<h2>Candid Assessment'' </h2>
<p>We provided the commission with a complete and candid
assessment of the situation, and we have taken steps to
strengthen our software development and other processes to help
avoid this mistake -- or anything similar -- in the future,
Microsoft said. </p>
<p>The Redmond, Washington-based company fell 1.3 percent to
$27.98 at 12:02 p.m. in New York. </p>
<p>Microsoft Chief Executive Officer Steve Ballmer''s yearly
bonus was cut last year to $620,000, partly as a result of the
company''s browser problems with the EU and also due to the
disappointing performance of its online services unit. </p>
<p>Microsoft ended more than 10 years of EU antitrust
investigations with its 2009 pledge to give consumers who bought
personal computers using its software a choice of the 12 most
widely used browsers to install in addition to, or instead of,
Internet Explorer. The company told regulators in December 2011
that it was complying with its commitment to display a browser-
choice screen to Windows operating system users. The new fine
marks the first time a company has been sanctioned for failing
to stick to the terms of a legally binding settlement. </p>
<h2>Think Twice </h2>
<p>EU Competition Commissioner Joaquin Almunia said regulators
were more naive than today in letting Microsoft monitor its
own compliance. In the future, the EU will detail what they
expect from a trustee appointed to monitor a settlement and
check reports more carefully, he said. </p>
<p>I hope this decision will make companies think twice,
Almunia told reporters today. We trusted in the reports about
the compliance. </p>
<p>Google Inc. (GOOG) is negotiating its own settlement with EU
regulators to end a probe into claims it discriminates against
competitors in its search results. Microsoft, the operator of
the Bing search engine, is one of several companies that have
complained about Google''s behavior. Almunia said last month that
an accord could be finalized later this year. </p>
<h2>Fourth Penalty </h2>
<p>The penalty is the fourth levied on Microsoft since it was
fined 497 million euros in 2004 for abusing its position as the
world''s largest supplier of desktop software to hinder rivals
for server and media programs. It was fined 280.5 million euros
in 2006 and another 899 million euros in 2008 for not supplying
interoperability information to server rivals on fair terms. </p>
<p>The 899 million-euro penalty was reduced to 860 million
euros by the EU''s General Court last year. That fine is only
exceeded by a 1.06 billion-euro sanction against Intel Corp.
which is also being challenged in court. </p>
<p>Mozilla Corp. General Counsel Harvey Anderson said in an
October blog post that daily downloads of his company''s Firefox
browser fell by 63 percent prior to Microsoft fixing the
browser-choice issue and that the company may have lost as many
as 9 million potential downloads as a result of the glitch. </p>
<p>Microsoft was also warned by the EU last year to modify how
it presents Internet Explorer in Windows 8 to avert another
antitrust clash. </p>
<p>Google''s Chrome was the most popular web browser globally
in February, with 37 percent of market share, according to
statistics from web analytics firm StatCounter. Microsoft''s
Internet Explorer followed with 30 percent, while Mozilla''s
Firefox accounted for just over a fifth of users. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Cristiane Lucchesi" date="Mar 06, 2013 11:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-06/goldman-s-bicudo-pereira-to-co-head-brazil-investment-bank-1-.html"><headline>Goldman''s Bicudo, Pereira to Head Brazil Investment Bank</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)''s Fabio Bicudo and Antonio Pereira will become co-heads of the Brazil
investment-banking business after Daniel Wainstein retired from
the firm. </p>
<p>Bicudo and Pereira are currently co-chief operating
officers of the business, the New York-based firm said today in
internal memos. The contents of the memos were confirmed by a
Goldman Sachs spokesman. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs had been discussing the changes with
Wainstein for the past several months, a person at the firm said
yesterday, asking not to be identified because the decision
hadn''t yet been announced. Wainstein, 42, and Andre Laport Ribeiro are Goldman Sachs''s only partners in Brazil. </p>
<p>Wainstein, who asked to leave after working at the firm
since 2000, was appointed chairman of Brazil investment banking
in April 2012, when Pereira and Bicudo were named co-COOs. The
bank ranked sixth in equity underwriting in Brazil last year,
with $732 million in transactions, data compiled by Bloomberg
show. It was No. 8 among merger advisers with $14.3 billion in
deals, the data show. </p>
<p>Bicudo and Pereira are members of the board of Goldman
Sachs Bank in Brazil and serve on the company''s management
committee for the country. Bicudo joined Goldman Sachs in 1999
and stayed until 2006. He came back to the company in 2010.
Pereira joined the firm in 1996 in New York. </p>
<h2>Paulo Leme </h2>
<p>The company, which doesn''t disclose Brazil revenue or
profit, named Paulo Leme as chairman for the country a year ago.
Goldman Sachs has said its strategy in Brazil is to focus on
complex products with higher profit margins, such as convertible
debt and receivables securitization. </p>
<p>U.S. and international banks are competing against Brazil-
based companies such as Bradesco BBI SA, Banco Itau BBA SA and
Banco BTG Pactual SA, which have used their stronger local
contacts to squeeze out foreign firms. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs completed its strategy to become a full-
service bank in Brazil in 2009, after two failed attempts to buy
local firms. In 1998, Goldman Sachs tried to buy Banco de
Investimentos Garantia SA, which was acquired by Credit Suisse
Group AG. </p>
<p>Seven years later it sought to purchase Banco Pactual SA,
an investment bank later acquired by UBS AG. Pactual was sold
back to BTG Partners in 2009 and is now Banco BTG Pactual SA.
BTG went public last year in a $1.94 billion initial offering
that Goldman Sachs helped underwrite. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Victoria Slind-Flor" date="Mar 06, 2013 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-06/pfizer-astrazeneca-lvmh-ikos-intellectual-property.html"><headline>Pfizer, AstraZeneca, LVMH, Ikos: Intellectual Property</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE) said it filed patent-
infringement lawsuits yesterday against generic-drug makers
including Teva Pharmaceutical Industries Ltd. (TEVA) to prevent them
from selling a low-cost version of the painkiller Celebrex until
December 2015. </p>
<p>Pfizer won a ruling in 2008 preventing Teva from entering
the market until May 2014. In that case, an appeals court
invalidated a patent that expires in December 2015. Pfizer said
yesterday that it had persuaded the U.S. Patent and Trademark
Office to reissue that patent with changes. </p>
<p>    Celebrex, also known by its active ingredient
celecoxib, generated $1.75 billion in U.S. sales last year, the
company said Jan. 29. Each day that Pfizer can delay generic
competition means about $5 million in revenue for the New York-
based company. </p>
<p>The reissued patent -- RE44084 -- covers methods of
treating osteoarthritis with celecoxib. In addition to Petach
Tikva, Israel-based Teva, the world''s largest maker of generic
drugs, Pfizer said it sued Mylan Inc., Actavis Inc. (ACT), Lupin Ltd. (LPC)
and Apotex Inc. in federal court in Virginia. </p>
<p>Continued development of new medicines that enhance
patient lives is supported by protecting intellectual property
and innovation, Pfizer General Counsel Amy Schulman said in a
statement. </p>
<h2>AstraZeneca Says Australian Court Invalidated Crestor Patents </h2>
<p>AstraZeneca Plc (AZN), maker of the Nexium ulcer drug and the
Xylocaine topical anesthetic, said an Australian court found
three patents protecting its Crestor anti-cholesterol drug to be
invalid. </p>
<p>In a March 5 statement, the London-based pharmaceutical
company said the Federal Court of Australia invalidated one
patent covering Crestor''s formulation and two others related to
the use of the compound in the treatment of high blood
cholesterol. </p>
<p>Annual sales of the drug in Australia have reached about
A$350 million ($359 million), according to the statement.
AstraZeneca said it''s evaluating options, including filing an
appeal. The Australian patents were challenged by Apotex Pty
Ltd., Watson Pharma Pty Ltd. and Ascent Pharma Pty Ltd. </p>
<p>In December, a federal appeals court in the U.S. issued a
ruling blocking generic versions of the drug from coming onto
the U.S. market until July 2016. The drug generated $2.3 billion
in sales in the U.S. in the first nine months of 2012, and
accounts for 22 percent of the company''s revenue. </p>
<p>For more patent news, click here. </p>
<h2>Trademark </h2>
<h2>Louis Vuitton Tells Chinese Hairdresser His Furniture Infringes </h2>
<p>LVMH Moet Hennessy Louis Vuitton SA (MC), the French luxury-
brand company, accused the owner of a Hong Kong-area beauty
salon of trademark infringement for using a covering on its
chairs that the company says infringes its mark, the South China
Morning Post reported. </p>
<p>The salon owner said the luxury-goods company is demanding
a published apology and money damages, according to the
newspaper. </p>
<p>The furniture came from Shenzhen, in China''s Guangdong
Province, and the salon owner said he was unaware the pattern
belonged to Louis Vuitton, the newspaper reported. </p>
<p>He told the newspaper he couldn''t afford to pay what Louis
Vuitton is seeking, even after the luxury-goods company cut its
damages request in half, and that he may have to close. </p>
<p>Philips Wins Challenge to Spectrum''s Steam Glide'' Trademark </p>
<p>Royal Philips Electronics NV (PHIA) successfully challenged a U.K.
trademark belonging to Spectrum Brands Holdings Inc. (SPB)''s Russell
Hobbs Ltd. unit. </p>
<p>The European Union''s Court of Justice affirmed a lower-
court holding that the Steam Glide trademark registered by
Salton Europe in 2008 for use with irons was too generic to be
afforded protection. </p>
<p>Salton changed its name in 2009 to Russell Hobbs, which
merged with Spectrum Brands Holdings Inc. of Madison, Wisconsin,
in 2010. </p>
<p>Russell Hobbs argued that the combination of steam and
glide acts to stimulate the imagination to create a mental
image of suspension and hovering, which does not in fact
exist. </p>
<p>The court disagreed, saying the smooth movement of an
iron across clothes, which results from the steam, corresponds
to what the consumer may expect from a product of that type, the
description of that movement by the word in question thus does
not conjure up'' an image of hovering but is clearly descriptive
of a very real characteristic of the goods in issue. </p>
<p>The court said there was nothing unusual about combining
the two English words, and there is no perceptible difference
between the expression steam glide'' and the mere sum of the
words of which it is composed. </p>
<p>Spectrum''s appeal was dismissed and the court said the
Madison-based company had to pay its own costs, the costs of the
European trademark authority and Philips. </p>
<p>The case is Spectrum Brands (UK) Ltd. v. Office for the
Harmonization of the Inner Market (Trademarks and Designs), T
544/11, General Court, European Court of Justice. </p>
<p>For more trademark news, click here. </p>
<h2>Copyright </h2>
<h2>Ikos Co-Founder Coward Sues Hedge Fund Over Software Copyright </h2>
<p>Martin Coward, the co-founder of Ikos Asset Management
Ltd., sued his estranged wife''s businesses in a U.K. court over
ownership of copyrights to software that runs the hedge fund''s
trading platform. </p>
<p>Coward was the architect of the bedrock of the family
business, he created with Elena Ambrosiadou, his lawyers said
at the start of a three-week trial in London yesterday. </p>
<p>Practically all of the financial markets expertise at
Ikos resided in Coward, said Michael Bloch, his lawyer. </p>
<p>Ikos, a hedge fund with $1.36 billion in assets under
management that uses computer algorithms to spot profitable
futures markets trades, has been embroiled in litigation
involving Coward and other former employees around the globe.
The estranged couple, who started divorce proceedings in Greece
in 2009, have filed more than 40 lawsuits against each other in
at least four countries. </p>
<p>Ambrosiadou, who was dropped as a defendant in the suit and
is expected to testify this week, has denied Coward''s version of
events -- dating back to how the company was formed in 1995. The
couple''s relationship has turned toxic, Bloch told the
court. </p>
<p>Coward, who left Ikos in 2009, paid 50,000 pounds ($75,800)
in damages and apologized to Ambrosiadou in January for
providing divorce papers containing personal information to
journalists. </p>
<p>Ambrosiadou has tried to get Coward sent to prison, for
allegedly copying software, put tracking devices on his car and
wire-tapped their family home, Bloch said. </p>
<p>Coward, who faces criminal charges in Monaco and Cyprus,
was caught red-handed stealing the software, lawyers for
Ikos said in documents filed at the London court. </p>
<p>Ikos counter-sued Coward for copyright infringement and
breach of confidence for downloading the software, described as
the fund''s crown jewels, on which the entire business is
based, according to the filings. </p>
<p>Electronic-theft laws need to be introduced in U.K. and
Europe, Ambrosiadou said in response to an e-mail requesting
comment. </p>
<p>The case is Coward v Phaestos Limited, U.K. High Court of
Justice, Chancery Division, case no. HC10C02788 </p>
<h2>EU to Quiz Germany Over Draft Rules for Google''s News Clips </h2>
<p>Germany will be questioned by European Union regulators
over a draft law that limits what Google Inc. (GOOG) and other so-
called aggregators can use to bundle news clips on the Internet. </p>
<p>EU regulators analyzed the bill passed by German
parliamentarians last week and will seek further information
from the country''s government, Carlo Corazza, a spokesman for
the European Commission, said in an e-mail. The Brussels-based
authority received complaints over the draft law on ancillary
copyright, he said. </p>
<p>Google and others may continue to show short news items on
their websites without being required to pay, German lawmakers
decided in last week''s parliamentary vote. German publishers
including Axel Springer AG (SPR) and Bertelsmann SE, which face
falling revenue from newspapers and magazines, have argued that
search engines and aggregators like Google News should pay for
displaying short excerpts from news stories. </p>
<p>Publishers would retain the exclusive right of use for any
content exceeding single words or very small text excerpts,
under the draft agreed last week. The bill by Germany''s Justice
Ministry gives publishers one year during which they have the
sole rights to commercially use their journalistic content. The
draft needs to be approved by Germany''s upper house before it
can enter into force. </p>
<p>Al Verney, a spokesman for Google in Brussels, declined to
comment. Mountain View, California-based Google said last week
in response to the German vote that ancillary copyright in its
most damaging form has been stopped and the best outcome for
Germany would be no new legislation that may threaten
innovation. </p>
<p>Google, which doesn''t display ads on its news aggregator
pages in Europe, argued that its so-called snippets are actually
helping publishers by driving traffic to their sites. </p>
<p>Corazza referred to EU rules that seek to cut technical
standards set by one country which may hamper trade across the
27-nation bloc. He didn''t say who complained to the EU
regulator. </p>
<p>For more copyright news, click here. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Earle and Don Jeffrey" date="Mar 07, 2013  3:14 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-07/exxon-mobil-had-no-alternative-to-mtbe-witness-says.html"><headline>Exxon Mobil Had No Alternative to MTBE, Witness Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. lacked viable
options to adding MTBE to gasoline, a witness told a New
Hampshire jury that will decide whether the company is liable
for contaminating drinking water with the chemical. </p>
<p>The Irving, Texas-based oil company is trying to persuade a
jury that federal law required the use of the additive, methyl
tertiary butyl ether, to combat air pollution and that it didn''t
harm anyone in New Hampshire. The company began presenting its
case March 4 in Concord. The trial started Jan. 14. </p>
<p>Thomas Eizember, an Exxon Mobil executive who was in charge
of dealing with U.S. Environmental Protection Agency regulations
in the 1990s, said it had to blend MTBE with gasoline because
other companies were adopting the chemical. </p>
<p>In the Northeast in particular we don''t control our
proprietary distribution system, Eizember told the jury today.
We share a lot of terminals. We share almost all the
pipelines. Sharing the facilities greatly increases the
reliability, but it means I can''t do something different
necessarily than someone else is doing. </p>
<p>Cross-examining Eizember, Jessica Grant, a lawyer for the
state, asked if he had been aware that another Exxon Mobil (XOM)
executive had warned the company in a report that if MTBE leaked
into the groundwater the costs of monitoring and cleaning it up
would be high. </p>
<p>No, I was led to believe the opposite, Eizember said.
I wasn''t aware of any information that said we needed to take
increased remediation costs into consideration. </p>
<h2>Adequate Warnings </h2>
<p>Victor Dugan, a former Exxon employee, testified March 5
that MTBE was extensively researched before it was added to fuel
and that its benefits outweighed the risks. He also said
gasoline dealers and distributors were given adequate warnings
about the hazards of gasoline and how to deal with leaks. </p>
<p>Exxon Mobil is the last defendant in the state''s
$818 million lawsuit alleging oil companies knew MTBE would
contaminate groundwater and didn''t alert the state to the risks.
New Hampshire seeks damages based on the company''s share of
gasoline sales in the state, which an economist said was about
30 percent. With an estimated cost of $818 million to test,
monitor and clean up wells, New Hampshire might be seeking at
least $245 million from the company. Exxon Mobil said using
refinery data would have shown a market share as low as 6.9
percent. </p>
<h2>Underground Leak </h2>
<p>In Maryland on Feb. 26 a court of appeals reversed two jury
verdicts against Exxon Mobil. The plaintiffs won $1.65 billion
in two cases alleging financial and property damage from an
underground leak in 2006 that released MTBE into the water. The
appeals court said Exxon Mobil hadn''t made fraudulent statements
and the plaintiffs failed to show physical harm. </p>
<p>New Hampshire''s suit is one of scores of cases involving
MTBE filed since 2000 against refiners, fuel distributors and
chemical makers. Other MTBE lawsuits were consolidated in
federal court in New York for pretrial evidence-gathering and
motions. In 2009, a federal jury ordered Exxon Mobil to pay New
York City $104.7 million after finding it liable for polluting
wells in the city. Exxon Mobil has appealed. </p>
<p>In 2003, New Hampshire sued Exxon Mobil, Shell Oil Co.,
Sunoco Inc., ConocoPhillips (COP), Irving Oil Ltd., Vitol SA, Hess
Corp. (HES) and Citgo Petroleum Corp. All except Exxon Mobil reached
settlements with the state. </p>
<h2>Reduce Pollution </h2>
<p>Exxon Mobil has argued in court that in adding MTBE to
gasoline it was complying with federal regulations, which pre-
empt state law. The additive was used to make gasoline burn more
thoroughly to reduce air pollution, as required under the 1990
Clean Air Act. </p>
<p>Studies by the American Petroleum Institute were cited in
court showing that at mid-to-high levels of ingestion or
inhalation MTBE elevated the risk of brain tumors, liver cancer,
blood cancer and kidney cancer in mice and rats. Exxon Mobil
said there has been no evidence that MTBE causes illness in
humans. </p>
<p>There is simply no MTBE crisis, Charles Engelmann, an
Exxon Mobil spokesman, said in an e-mail. MTBE hasn''t been
used in the state since 2005 and there is not a single personal
injury being claimed in this lawsuit. </p>
<p>MTBE is highly soluble in water and can be carried great
distances from the source of leaks. It leaked from gas stations,
vehicle junkyards, underground storage tanks and pipe fittings,
the state said. </p>
<p>The state estimated that about 40,000 New Hampshire wells
are contaminated with MTBE and that 5,590 have levels determined
to be unfit for drinking. </p>
<p>The case is New Hampshire v. Hess Corp., 03-C-0550, New
Hampshire Superior Court, Merrimack County (Concord). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Leising" date="Mar 07, 2013  2:54 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-07/jpmorgan-sees-profit-gain-in-helping-clients-follow-new-rules.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sees Profit Gain in Helping Clients Follow New Rules</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The biggest overhaul of financial
regulation since the 1930s is creating one of the largest
sources of revenue growth for JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), according to
managing director Carlos Hernandez. </p>
<p>The bank said it expects the investor-services unit, one of
three parts of the corporate and investment bank, to boost
return on equity by about 4 percentage points in coming years as
the firm helps customers comply with rules governing how swaps
trades are executed, collateralized and cleared. That compares
with drops of about 2 percentage points in the CIB''s banking
section and 3 percentage points for the markets unit. </p>
<p>The secular trend for these clients is the constant need
to reduce execution costs, Hernandez, global head of investor
services, said in an interview at his office in New York. It''s
creating pressure from our clients to become more efficient. </p>
<p>The swaps market is being regulated for the first time
after some contracts helped to amplify the credit crisis and
made it more difficult for international regulators to know how
interconnected banks had become following the 2008 failure of
Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. Mandatory swaps clearing begins
March 11 for dealers including JPMorgan and their largest
customers. </p>
<h2>Revenue Tailwinds </h2>
<p>The rules may cost JPMorgan $1 billion to $2 billion in
revenue, according to a Feb. 26 presentation. To reduce this
loss, the fees it can charge customers to help them trade, clear
and collateralize swaps may produce new revenue of $300 million
to $500 million by 2015, the bank said. </p>
<p>There will be other parts of the house that are
impacted, such as the swaps-trading desks that will see
compression in bid-offer spreads, Hernandez said, referring to
the difference in what the bank charges to buy and sell a swap.
The headwinds in some businesses are the tailwinds for our
investor-services business. </p>
<p>JPMorgan earned $5 billion in 2008 trading over-the-counter
fixed-income derivatives, including swaps, as the collapse of
Lehman Brother Holdings Inc. that year widened bid-ask spreads. </p>
<p>Those days are unlikely to return as rules meant to add
transparency to swaps prices allow investors to know levels at
which derivatives are trading before they buy or sell. </p>
<p>Standardizing contract terms so they can be processed by
clearinghouses and requiring trades to be done on regulated
exchanges or similar systems will further cut dealer profits by
more closely aligning trading with the futures market, where
banks earn smaller fees for executing and clearing trades for
clients. </p>
<h2>Dodd-Frank </h2>
<p>Hernandez''s group will offer trade execution, collateral
management, clearing services, prime brokerage and fund
financing and administration, he said. The unit acts only as an
agent for its clients and doesn''t trade directly with them,
Hernandez said. </p>
<p>I tell everybody it''s like flying a plane with one
passenger or 200 passengers, he said. Because of the fixed
costs associated with an airplane, the marginal cost of those
199 people is low. </p>
<p>The Dodd-Frank Act is requiring most swaps trades in the
U.S. to be backed by clearinghouses, which require upfront
collateral. Global bank regulations are compelling lenders to
keep more cash and easy-to-liquidate investments on hand to
protect against losses. That may boost demand for high-grade
assets by $2 trillion to $4 trillion, according to an April 2012
report from the International Monetary Fund. </p>
<h2>Transforming Collateral </h2>
<p>As much as $6.7 trillion in additional collateral may be
needed to satisfy new bank capital rules and swaps-clearing
mandates, securities-industry consultant Finadium LLC said in
December. </p>
<p>Scarcity of cost-effective assets to back swaps trades has
led some market users to engage in so-called collateral
transformation, in which lower-rated securities are exchanged
for cash or highly rated securities. The extent of that
transformation will depend on whether banks and money managers
believe too few assets are available to cover their swaps
positions, Finadium said. </p>
<p>Fees for collateral transformation are included in the $300
million to $500 million revenue estimate JPMorgan made last
month. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Salma El Wardany" date="Mar 07, 2013 11:51 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-07/exxon-mobil-s-egypt-country-head-released-safe-after-kidnapping.html"><headline>Exxon Mobil''s Egypt Country Head Released Safe After Kidnapping</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM), the world''s
largest energy company by market value, said the head of its
Egypt and Cyprus unit was released safely with his wife after
being held briefly by kidnappers in Egypt. </p>
<p>Andy Wells and his wife were held by gunmen in Sinai
earlier today demanding the release of defendants in an arms
smuggling case, Mahmoud El-Hifnawy, head of security in South
Sinai, said by phone. Exxon Mobil said the couple were released
without being harmed, according to Alan Jeffers, a company
spokesman, in an e-mailed statement. </p>
<p>Sinai has been the site of several kidnappings of tourists
since the start of the uprising that ousted Hosni Mubarak in
2011, highlighting the diminished ability of the country''s
police force to provide security. Two Americans and their
Egyptian tour guide were taken hostage in the peninsula for four
days in July before being released safely. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore and Stephanie Ruhle" date="Mar 07, 2013 11:04 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-07/goldman-sachs-to-name-new-managing-directors-every-two-years.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs to Name New Managing Directors Every Two Years</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), the fifth-
largest U.S. bank by assets, will name new managing directors
every two years instead of annually as it overhauls a process
adopted 17 years ago. </p>
<p>After recipients are announced at the end of 2013, the firm
won''t select managing directors until 2015, the firm wrote in an
internal memo. David Wells, a spokesman for the New York-based
bank, confirmed the contents of the memo. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs created the managing director title in 1996
to recognize top employees who weren''t yet partners. The firm
promoted 266 employees to managing director in 2012, up from 261
a year earlier. About 7.2 percent of the bank''s employees hold
the title. </p>
<p>A biennial process will allow us to invest more in the
managing-director selection process so that it will continue to
be a disciplined and rigorous exercise, the bank said in the
memo. This will help to ensure that the managing director
title remains as aspirational as it should be for our top
performers. </p>
<p>Business Insider reported the change earlier today. </p>
<p>Managing directors typically receive a base salary of
$500,000, lower than the $900,000 granted to partners. Both also
get bonuses that can boost their total compensation into the
millions of dollars. </p>
<p>The first class of 87 managing directors included William C. Dudley, now president of the Federal Reserve Bank of New
York; Clifford S. Asness, who left in 1998 to start hedge fund
AQR Capital Management LLC; and Richard J. Gnodde, who was named
co-head of global investment banking at Goldman Sachs in May
2011. </p>
<p>The number of managing directors at Goldman Sachs has
grown as a percentage of our population since the first class,
reflecting the growth of our business and the expansion of our
global footprint, the firm said in the memo. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Cathy Chan" date="Mar 07, 2013  2:06 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-07/goldman-hires-morgan-stanley-asia-investment-bank-head-richdale.html"><headline>Goldman Hires Morgan Stanley Asia Banking Head Kate Richdale</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) hired Kate Richdale from Morgan Stanley (MS) to head investment banking services
for Asia excluding Japan as the Wall Street firm looks to
strengthen client relationships in the region. </p>
<p>The 13-year Morgan Stanley veteran will be responsible for
covering clients, according to a memo obtained by Bloomberg
News. Richdale, who was head of investment banking for Asia-
Pacific at Morgan Stanley, was also made a partner at Goldman
Sachs, according to the document. Edward Naylor, a Hong Kong-
based spokesman at the bank, confirmed the memo''s contents. </p>
<p>Richdale''s departure follows Morgan Stanley''s deferral of
bonuses for some senior bankers and traders over three years, a
person briefed on the matter said in January. Goldman Sachs paid
employees more in 2012 than the previous year on average, as
revenue surged 19 percent and it cut staff by 3 percent. </p>
<p>She will report to Dan Dees and Matthew Westerman, Goldman
Sachs co-heads of investment banking for the region, according
to the memo. Tim Leissner, former Asia head of investment
banking services, was promoted to vice chairman of investment
banking for the region, Naylor said. </p>
<p>Richdale will join the firm in June and be based in Hong
Kong, according to the memo. She had been head of Asian
investment banking at Morgan Stanley since March 2011 and her
previous roles at the New York-based bank included chief
executive officer for Southeast Asia, the document showed. </p>




Photographer: Daniel Acker/Bloomberg

<p>
A Goldman Sachs Group Inc. logo hangs on the floor of the New York Stock Exchange in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Pringle" date="Mar 08, 2013  5:51 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-08/goldman-s-mossavar-rahmani-recommends-energy-bank-stocks.html"><headline>Goldman''s Mossavar-Rahmani Recommends Energy, Bank Stocks</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>(Corrects to remove reference to energy shares in the
second paragraph.) </p>
<p>Investors should favor U.S. equities
over European or emerging-market shares, according to Sharmin Mossavar-Rahmani, chief investment officer for Goldman Sachs
Group Inc.''s private wealth-management unit. </p>
<p>She said she''s bullish on bank shares because they are
cheap even after the industry in the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index
rallied 8.1 percent this year. The group has a price-earnings
ratio of 11, compared with 15.3 for the U.S. equity benchmark,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>U.S. equities, in the long-run, are the place where
clients should have their core assets, relative to Europe or
emerging markets, Mossavar-Rahmani said in an interview with
Bloomberg Television. </p>
<p>Mossavar-Rahmani recommended investors underweight
government bonds and predicted inflation will remain low.
Investors shouldn''t expect stocks to return as much as they have
in the past few years, she said. The SP 500 is up 129 percent
since March 9, 2009. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Frier" date="Mar 08, 2013  4:43 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-08/ibm-ceo-says-big-data-will-be-company-s-top-priority-this-year.html"><headline>IBM CEO Says Big Data'' Is Company''s Top Priority This Year</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM) Chief Executive Officer Ginni Rometty sees big data
services, which let customers mine vast troves of information to
make better decisions, as the company''s biggest focus this year. </p>
<p>It''s certainly everything around big data and
analytics, Rometty said in a brief interview last night when
asked about IBM''s priority in 2013. She had just given a speech
in front of the Council on Foreign Relations in New York, where
she emphasized that data will give companies and governments a
competitive advantage. </p>
<p>I want you to think about data as the next natural
resource, she told the audience of business and political
leaders. Data-based insight helped reduce crime by 30 percent in
Memphis, Tennessee, and correctly predicted the outcome of swing
states for President Barack Obama''s campaign, she said. </p>
<p>For IBM, the capabilities are helping it break into new
overseas markets and sell services covering a wider range of
tasks -- from traffic management to weather monitoring to
payroll. About 80 percent of growth is coming from outside the
U.S., she said. </p>
<p>IBM increased its 2015 sales forecast for data analytics to
$20 billion last week, from an earlier goal of $16 billion.
Revenue from the category in 2010, when IBM first set he goal,
was about $10 billion. Since 2005, IBM has spent more than $16
billion on 35 acquisitions to boost its analytics capabilities. </p>
<p>Shares of the Armonk, New York-based company climbed 0.5
percent to $210.38 at the close in New York. The stock has risen
9.8 percent this year. </p>
<h2>Monitoring Workers </h2>
<p>Businesses are using analytics to track individual employee
performance and treat customers based on personal preference,
she said. That means they don''t have to make as many blanket
assumptions. </p>
<p>You will see the death of the average, Rometty said. </p>
<p>Analytics also will help companies fight the mounting
threat of cybercrime by predicting where the next attack might
happen, Rometty said. She called on countries to work together
on a data-based strategy, instead of individual legal
approaches. </p>
<p>If every country tries to regulate this themselves, you
will have a standstill and a great vulnerability, she said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Carroll" date="Mar 08, 2013  4:11 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-08/exxon-at-least-25-years-away-from-making-fuel-from-algae.html"><headline>Exxon at Least 25 Years Away From Making Fuel From Algae</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM)''s $600 million
foray into creating motor fuels from algae may not succeed for
at least another 25 years because of technical hurdles, Chairman
and Chief Executive Officer Rex Tillerson said. </p>
<p>So far, scientists haven''t been able to develop a strain of
algae that reproduces quickly enough and behaves in a manner
that would produce enough raw material to supply a refinery,
Tillerson said in an interview that aired yesterday on PBS
television''s Charlie Rose show. </p>
<p>We''ve come to understand some limits of that technology,
or limits as we understand it today, which doesn''t mean it''s
limited forever, Tillerson said. The venture is probably
further than 25 years away from successfully developing fuels. </p>
<p>Exxon, the world''s biggest maker of gasoline and diesel,
has been studying the potential for algae-based fuels for 3 1/2
years in a joint venture with J. Craig Venter''s Synthetic
Genomics Inc. When the project was announced in July 2009, Exxon
predicted it could produce fuels in five to 10 years. </p>
<p>Exxon gained 0.3 percent to $88.97 at the close in New
York. The shares have increased 2.8 percent this year. </p>
<p>Exxon and Synthetic Genomics announced plans in 2009 to
build a greenhouse near San Diego to test various algae strains.
The goal was to produce a new source of oil, Emil Jacobs,
Exxon''s vice president of research, said during a July 14, 2009,
conference call. </p>
<h2>Basic Science </h2>
<p>Venter, best known for his role in the sequencing of the
human genome in the 1990s and early 2000s, said during the same
call that algae ponds would produce 10 times as much fuel as the
ethanol fed by corn fields covering the same amount of space. </p>
<p>What we''ve come to understand is the hurdle is pretty
high and the hurdle seems to exist at the basic science level,
which means it''s even more difficult to solve, Tillerson said
yesterday. These are very challenging problems. </p>
<p>The scientific barriers to cultivating the sort of super
algae Exxon sought have induced the industry to focus on
robust, cheap local strains of algae that aren''t exotic,
said Riggs Eckelberry, chairman and CEO of OriginOil Inc. (OOIL), a Los
Angeles-based algae-extraction company. </p>
<p>Algae may turn out to be better suited to use as a polymer
precursor and a blending agent that will boost the energy
content of fuels made from waste products such as sawdust,
rather than as a replacement for crude, Eckelberry said in a
telephone interview today. </p>
<p>OriginOil rose 4.5 percent to 55 cents. The stock lost 69
percent of its value in the past year. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ye Xie" date="Mar 08, 2013 12:10 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-08/jpmorgan-downgrades-emerging-dollar-debt-as-yields-fall.html"><headline>JPMorgan Downgrades Emerging Dollar Debt as Yields Fall</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) cut its
recommendation on emerging market dollar-denominated government
bonds to neutral, as investors withdraw funds and falling yields
limit returns. </p>
<p>JPMorgan downgraded the debt from overweight, analysts led
by Joyce Chang wrote in a report dated yesterday. The New York-
based bank kept a buy recommendation on local-currency bonds in
developing nations and advised clients to maintain bets on gains
in emerging-market currencies, including the South Korean won,
the Indian rupee and South African rand. </p>
<p>Funds focused on emerging-market dollar debt experienced
outflows in three of the past five weeks, a scenario last seen
in May, according to the JPMorgan report. The bank''s EMBI Global
Index of developing-country dollar notes has dropped 1.7 percent
this year, as yields fell to a record-low 4.4 percent in
January, cutting their advantage over U.S. Treasuries. </p>
<p>We believe the market may be due for some consolidation,
with the most crowded positions appearing more vulnerable, the
analysts wrote. Return opportunities for investment-grade
emerging-market sovereign debt are more limited. </p>
<p>Investors in emerging markets will continue to shift funds
out of sovereign dollar debt and into local-currency and
corporate bonds because of the higher returns, the analysts
said. Emerging dollar debt yielded 4.84 percent yesterday,
compared with 5.51 percent on local-currency notes and the 4.58
percent yield for corporate bonds, according to JPMorgan''s
indexes. </p>
<p>A JPMorgan survey last month showed investors reduced
holdings of emerging-market government debt to the lowest level
since October 2008 as rising U.S. Treasury yields eroded the
allure of the assets. </p>
<h2>Venezuelan Debt </h2>
<p>Yields on 10-year U.S. Treasuries touched 2.08 percent
today, the highest level since April 2012 based on closing
prices, after a government report showed U.S. employers added
more jobs than forecast and the unemployment rate in the world''s
largest economy unexpectedly fell to four-year low. </p>
<p>JPMorgan recommends investors retain an overweight position
in Venezuelan bonds, as the yields, currently at 9.67 percent,
are high enough to compensate investors amid uncertainty over
the political climate following President Hugo Chavez''s death
this week. </p>
<p>Investors should be underweight Argentinean debt, JPMorgan
says, citing legal risks as the government fights a group of
bondholders demanding payments on securities related to the
nation''s 2001 default in a U.S. court. High-yielding corporate
bonds from companies including Petroleos de Venezuela SA and
Mexico''s Cemex SAB de CV (CEMEXCPO), as well as Russian financial companies
will probably gain, according to the report. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Maria Kolesnikova" date="Mar 08, 2013  5:44 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-08/goldman-raises-3-month-forecast-for-commodities-to-overweight-.html"><headline>Goldman Raises 3-Month Forecast for Commodities to Overweight''</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) raised its
three-month outlook for raw materials to overweight after
prices declined. </p>
<p>The Standard  Poor''s GSCI Enhanced Commodity Index will
advance 3 percent in 12 months, led by gains of 7 percent in
industrial metals, 5 percent in livestock and 3 percent in
energy, the bank said in its monthly asset allocation report
dated yesterday. On Feb. 8, Goldman forecast a 1 percent return. </p>
<p>The recent sell-off in commodities on worries about
Chinese growth is overdone in our view and we upgrade to
overweight on a 3-month horizon, Jeffrey Currie, head of
commodities research in New York at the bank, said in the
report. </p>
<p>The SP GSCI Enhanced gauge slid 5.6 percent the past four
weeks and is down about 0.5 percent this year. Hard red winter
wheat traded in Kansas City is down the most, at 12 percent this
year and copper fell 2.9 percent. </p>
<p>Goldman forecasts copper will rise to $9,000 a metric ton
in six months as demand from top consumer China picks up both
seasonally and on the back of continued growth in construction
completions, property sales and power infrastructure related
demand, Currie said in the report. Prices will fall to $8,000
a ton in 12 months as Chinese construction completions diminish,
the bank said. </p>
<p>Copper for delivery in three months fell 0.5 percent to
$7,729 a ton by 10:19 a.m. in the London Metal Exchange. Brent
oil for April delivery dropped 0.6 percent to $110.52 a barrel
on the London-based ICE Futures Exchange. </p>
<p>Limited supplies of oil will support front-month prices
near current levels, while longer-dated Brent pries will be
well-anchored at about $90 a barrel, Goldman said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Mar 11, 2013  5:03 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-11/morgan-stanley-hires-cnbc-s-kaminsky-for-wealth-management-role.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Hires CNBC''s Kaminsky for Brokerage Position</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS), owner of the
world''s largest brokerage, hired CNBC''s Gary Kaminsky as a vice
chairman in wealth management. </p>
<p>Kaminsky, who was the cable television network''s capital-
markets editor, will work with Morgan Stanley''s financial
advisers on client development, Greg Fleming, 50, president of
the brokerage unit, wrote today in a memo to employees, a copy
of which was obtained by Bloomberg News. Jim Wiggins, a
spokesman for the New York-based bank, confirmed the memo''s
contents. </p>
<p>Kaminsky will continue to be a CNBC contributor, according
to the memo. He previously helped manage an investment portfolio
of more than $12 billion at Neuberger Berman Group LLC, where he
worked from 1999 to 2008, according to the memo. Neuberger
Berman was part of Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc., which
collapsed in 2008 amid the financial crisis. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley is seeking to improve profitability at its
brokerage, which has 16,780 advisers and $1.78 trillion of
client assets, the company said in January. The firm set a goal
for the unit of a 15 percent pretax profit margin by the middle
of this year, after posting a 12 percent margin in 2012. </p>
<p>We thank Gary for all his contributions to CNBC over the
years and we look forward to seeing him on our air as a
contributor, said Jennifer Dauble, a CNBC spokeswoman. </p>
<p>Fox Business Network reported earlier today that Morgan
Stanley was considering hiring Kaminsky. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Frier" date="Mar 11, 2013  4:05 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-11/ibm-s-rometty-earns-16-2-million-in-total-compensation-in-2012.html"><headline>IBM''s Rometty Gets $16.2 Million in Compensation Last Year</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM) Chief Executive Officer Ginni Rometty, who took the job in
January 2012, earned $16.2 million in compensation last year,
including $9.26 million in stock awards. </p>
<p>The total figure was almost double the $8.3 million she
made the previous year, when she was a senior vice president in
charge of sales at IBM, the company said today in a filing. The
pay package included $1.5 million in salary and $3.92 million in
non-stock incentive pay. </p>
<p>Rometty has overseen IBM during a period of profit growth,
even as sales remain sluggish. The Armonk, New York-based
company said in January that earnings would be at least $16.70 a
share in 2013, beating analysts'' estimates and sending the stock
on its biggest one-day gain in a year. </p>
<p>Rometty runs the ninth-largest company by market value and
has emerged as one of the best-paid female leaders in corporate
America, topping the level of Meg Whitman and other high-profile
CEOs. Whitman earned $15.4 million at Hewlett-Packard Co. in
2012 -- only 70 percent of her targeted compensation because the
struggling company missed its goals for the year. PepsiCo Inc.''s
Indra Nooyi, meanwhile, received $17.1 million in 2011. Her pay
for last year hasn''t been released yet. </p>




Photographer: Graham Carlow/IBM via Bloomberg

<p>
International Business Machines Corp. Chief Executive Officer Ginni Rometty took the helm earlier in the year and became IBM''s ninth CEO and its first female leader. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Edward Klump and Dan Murtaugh" date="Mar 13, 2013  8:24 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-13/exxon-sees-north-america-exporting-15-of-gas-5-of-oil-by-2040.html"><headline>Exxon Sees North America Exporting 15% Gas, 5% Oil by 2040</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM), the largest
U.S. oil company, said North America may be able to export 15
percent of its natural gas output and 5 percent of oil by 2040
as the region''s production surges and demand stalls. </p>
<p>North America probably will become a net energy exporter by
about 2025, after importing 35 percent of its oil in 2010,
Irving, Texas-based Exxon said in an energy outlook report
released today. Asia Pacific countries may import almost 40
percent of their total energy needs by 2040 as demand increases. </p>
<p>After decades of relatively flat production, output of
oil and other liquid fuels in North America is projected to rise
by about 40 percent from 2010 to 2040, Exxon said in the
report. Meanwhile, overall U.S. energy consumption is expected
to gradually plateau and then decline by about 5 percent from
2010 to 2040. </p>
<p>Technological advances have helped tap oil and gas from
shale-rock formations, as well as extracting it from oil sands
and deep-water prospects in North America. Monthly U.S. oil
production exceeded 7 million barrels a day in November, for the
first time in 20 years. The International Energy Agency said in
November the U.S. is poised to surpass Saudi Arabia as a crude
producer in the next decade. </p>
<p>U.S. liquefied natural gas exports will stay below 10
billion cubic feet a day, Bill Colton, Exxon''s vice president
for corporate strategic planning, said during a presentation on
the outlook at Rice University in Houston. </p>
<h2>Emissions Price </h2>
<p>Exxon assumes that at some point in the next 30 years
governments around the world will begin putting a price on
carbon emissions, Colton said. Exxon sees a possible price of
$60 a ton of carbon dioxide emitted in the U.S. in 2030. </p>
<p>Under that circumstance, the price to burn coal to generate
electricity jumps well above gas, which has about 50 percent
fewer emissions, Colton said. </p>
<p>Coal''s got a lot of environmental pushback, wind and
solar are growing but they''re limited from a practical
standpoint, nuclear is also limited from practical and political
considerations, he said. That provides this huge opening for
natural gas as sort of the fuel of choice for the future. </p>
<p>More use of gas instead of coal and increased output from
nuclear and renewable energy sources will reduce U.S.
greenhouse-gas emissions, Exxon said. Carbon-dioxide emissions
may drop more than 25 percent by 2040 to the lowest levels since
the 1970s, the company said. </p>
<h2>Blend Wall </h2>
<p>Exxon wants the U.S. government to revise its rules for
blending ethanol into gasoline to cap the level at 10 percent of
total gasoline consumption, Colton said. </p>
<p>Automobile manufacturers aren''t comfortable with ethanol
making up more than 10 percent of fuel blend, he said.
Government regulations are calling for the total amount of
ethanol to be blended into gasoline this year to be greater than
10 percent of total expected gasoline demand. </p>
<p>We call it the blend wall, Colton said. The problem
is, when they set those mandates and they have them growing, I
don''t think they realized demand for gasoline would be
shrinking. </p>
<p>It''s just another reason why it''s difficult to make
gasoline, and frankly it puts cost pressures on making
gasoline, he said. So we think it''s in the general good to
cap it at 10 percent, and even less would be a bonus for
consumers. </p>
<p>In December, Exxon released a broader report with its
global energy outlook, boosting its long-term estimate for
worldwide demand growth to 35 percent from 32 percent as
expanding populations in Africa and India use more electricity. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Frier" date="Mar 13, 2013  5:02 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-13/ibm-s-stock-climbs-into-record-territory.html"><headline>IBM''s Stock Climbs Into Record Territory</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM) shares reached an all-time high, valuing the world''s
largest provider of computer services at $236.3 billion. </p>
<p>IBM gained 0.7 percent to $212.06 today in New York, the
highest level on record. Shares of the Armonk, New York-based
company have climbed 11 percent this year. </p>
<p>The company has propelled its stock price by boosting
earnings per share, divesting underperforming units and moving
into higher-margin software businesses such as data analysis.
IBM has said it will deliver at least $20 in earnings per share
in 2015, compared with $15.25 last year. It also has set aside
$50 billion for share repurchases and $20 billion for dividends
between the end of 2010 and 2015. </p>
<p>IBM last reached a record closing high of $211 on Oct. 16.
After the markets closed that day, IBM reported third-quarter
revenue that fell short of analysts'' estimates, causing the
shares to slump for the next month. </p>
<p>Even with the recent gains, the shares trade at a 10
percent price-to-earnings discount to the Standard  Poor''s 500
Index. IBM has a PE ratio of 13.9, compared with 15 for the SP
500 information-technology index, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. </p>
<p>In the past month, IBM has said its data-analysis business
will perform better than expected, adding $20 billion in revenue
in 2015. That compares with an earlier goal of $16 billion. The
company also said it will double investment in mobile
technologies this year. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Zeke Faux and Kevin Dugan" date="Mar 13, 2013  4:50 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-13/morgan-stanley-s-barany-leaves-as-co-head-of-global-structuring.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley''s Barany Leaves as Co-Head of Global Structuring</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Jeff Barany, Morgan Stanley (MS)''s co-
head of a group that creates fixed-income securities for
institutions and wealthy individuals, has left the bank and the
business will be run by Davide Menini, his counterpart in
London. </p>
<p>Barany, a managing director in New York, confirmed his
departure yesterday in a telephone interview. He joined the bank
in 1999, according to online records of the Financial Industry
Regulatory Authority. </p>
<p>Menini, who was co-head with Barany, will now lead global
macro structuring on his own, said two people with knowledge of
the moves who asked not to be identified because they haven''t
been announced publicly. </p>
<p>Lauren Onis, a spokeswoman for Morgan Stanley in New York,
and Menini declined to comment. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley is the top issuer of structured notes in the
U.S. this year, selling $1.16 billion of the securities,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Banks create structured notes by packaging debt with
derivatives to offer customized bets to retail investors while
earning fees and raising money. Derivatives are contracts whose
value is derived from stocks, bonds, commodities and currencies,
or events such as changes in interest rates or the weather. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore and Dakin Campbell" date="Mar 14, 2013  8:32 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-14/goldman-jpmorgan-ordered-to-fix-capital-planning-by-fed.html"><headline>Goldman, JPMorgan Ordered to Fix Capital Planning by Fed</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and JPMorgan Chase  Co., the world''s biggest trading firms, must submit new capital plans to regulators to address weaknesses the Federal Reserve found in their planning processes. </p> <p>The central bank didn''t object to the capital plans of the two New York-based companies, and approved proposals from 14 other banks, the Fed said yesterday in a report. Capital plans submitted by Ally Financial Inc. and BBT Corp. were rejected, while American Express Co., the biggest U.S. credit-card issuer by customer spending, revised its submission to win approval. </p> <p>The deficiencies found at Goldman Sachs and JPMorgan related to projections of losses and revenue, according to a Fed official. While the two firms can immediately implement dividend and buyback plans, they must fix the weaknesses and resubmit their proposals by the end of the third quarter, the official said. Regulators, intent on preventing a repeat of the 2008 financial crisis, have run annual stress tests to see how the largest lenders would fare in a recession or economic shock to ensure that banks don''t jeopardize the financial system. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs and JPMorgan exhibited weaknesses in their capital planning that were significant enough to require immediate attention, even though those weaknesses do not undermine the quantitative results of the stress tests for that firm or the overall reliability of the firm''s capital-planning process, the Fed said in a report on the test results. </p>




Photographer: Peter Foley/Bloomberg

<p>
Traders work at the Goldman Sachs Group Inc. booth on the floor of the New York Stock Exchange. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Cheyenne Hopkins" date="Mar 14, 2013  7:31 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-14/jpmorgan-hid-trades-banned-by-volcker-rule-senate-probe-finds.html"><headline>JPMorgan Hid Trades Banned by Volcker Rule, Senate Probe Finds</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) engaged in
high-risk proprietary trading under the guise of ordinary
hedging, said Senate investigators, who urged U.S. regulators to
strengthen the proposed ban on such trades known as the Volcker
rule. </p>
<p>Regulators should require banks that hold federally insured
deposits to explicitly link positions in derivatives to the
underlying risk they are hedging, the Senate''s Permanent
Subcommittee on Investigations recommended in a 300-page report
released yesterday. </p>
<p>The issue of which trades are hedges and which are risky
bets that could destabilize a bank is the crux of a stalemate
over the Volcker rule, which was adopted as part of the 2010
Dodd-Frank Act designed to rein in systemic risks. The rule,
which is in the final stage of drafting by five U.S. regulators,
would restrict the kinds of trades permitted by banks holding
deposits insured by taxpayers. </p>
<p>Banks have lobbied heavily against the Volcker rule,
arguing that it will restrict market-making and other standard
banking practices. </p>
<p>The report and its recommendations, issued jointly by the
committee''s Democrats and Republicans, is expected to increase
pressure on regulators to tighten exemptions in the draft
Volcker rule. The Volcker rule was one of the most controversial
provisions of the Dodd-Frank Act, generating more than 18,000
comment letters from the industry. </p>
<p>Bank officials and regulators are scheduled to be
questioned on the report''s findings in a hearing today. </p>
<h2>Increased Risk'' </h2>
<p>JPMorgan''s chief investment office increased risk by
mislabeling the synthetic portfolio as a risk-reducing hedge
when it was really involved in proprietary trading, said
Senator John McCain of Arizona, the panel''s top Republican. </p>
<p>Subcommittee Chairman Carl Levin, a Democrat from Michigan
who sponsored the Volcker rule, said regulators should close a
loophole in an early draft of the rule that would permit broad
portfolio hedges. </p>
<p>We''re going to continue to work very hard for a final
rule that does not allow the kind of manipulation, the kind of
concoctions that were created here by the bank to be accepted in
the name of hedging, Levin said in a news conference. </p>
<p>The subcommittee released the panel''s findings after a
nine-month probe into JPMorgan''s record trading losses that came
to light when Bloomberg News first reported them on April 5. The
flawed bet on credit derivatives by a trader in London
eventually cost the company more than $6.2 billion and stained
Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon''s 31-year Wall Street
career. The trader was dubbed the London Whale because the
derivatives positions were so large they moved credit markets. </p>
<h2>Significant Mistakes'' </h2>
<p>While we have repeatedly acknowledged significant
mistakes, our senior management acted in good faith and never
had any intent to mislead anyone, Mark Kornblau, a spokesman
for JPMorgan, said in an e-mail. </p>
<p>Levin and Senator Jeff Merkley, a Democrat from Oregon,
sponsored the measure that eventually became known as the
Volcker rule in honor of its original proponent, former Federal
Reserve Chairman Paul Volcker, and was included in the Dodd-
Frank Act. The law bars federally insured banks from proprietary
trading, or trading for their own account, while allowing
regulators to make exemptions for market-making and hedging. </p>
<p>The subcommittee found that officials at the bank''s main
regulator, the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency,
expressed skepticism that the trades were a hedge. In a May 2012
internal e-mail, an OCC examiner referred to synthetic credit
portfolio as a make believe voodoo magic composite hedge''. </p>
<h2>OCC Misinformed'' </h2>
<p>Bryan Hubbard, a spokesman for the OCC, said the agency
continues to investigate the matter. As a result of the report''s
findings on regulators'' shortcomings, the OCC has taken steps to
improve its supervision, he said. </p>
<p>We are very disappointed that the bank misinformed the
OCC which hampered our supervisory efforts, Hubbard said in an
e-mailed statement. We will take additional action as
appropriate. </p>
<p>The subcommittee said the investigation uncovered evidence
that bank officials portrayed the losing trades as a hedge when
internal communications suggested otherwise. </p>
<p>For instance, in an April 13, 2012, earnings call, former
Chief Financial Officer Douglas Braunstein called the positions
consistent with the Volcker rule. However, two months
earlier, the bank made the opposite assessment, the report said. </p>
<h2>Proprietary Trading </h2>
<p>On Feb. 13, 2012, the bank submitted an official comment
letter to its regulators, including the OCC, expressing concern
that the credit derivatives trading might be prohibited by the
Volcker rule. In the letter, Barry Zubrow, a former risk officer
who retired in December, wrote that under the proposed Volcker
rule this activity could have been deemed proprietary
trading. </p>
<p>Also, Ina Drew, former chief investment officer for the
bank, told Braunstein the day before the April earnings call
that the Volcker rule was a poor fit with the CIO''s credit
derivatives trading; Braunstein said the opposite on the call
the next day. </p>
<p>Mr. Braunstein''s optimistic assessment during the April
13 earnings call may have reassured investors, but that is no
justification for misinforming the public about the bank''s
official position that the Volcker rule might prohibit the SCP
as an example of high-risk proprietary trading, the
subcommittee report stated, referring to the bank''s synthetic
credit portfolio. </p>
<h2>Volcker Violation </h2>
<p>The report said that Braunstein should have known that his
comments contradicted the bank''s own 68-page Volcker rule
comment letter. </p>
<p>In addition, the investigation found that the bank
considered the unit a proprietary trading operation as early as
2007. In November of that year, the bank''s internal audit group
issued a report characterizing the CIO''s credit-trading
activities as proprietary position strategies executed on
credit- and asset-backed indices. The report didn''t mention
hedging as a purpose of the unit. </p>
<p>JPMorgan officials told the subcommittee that the trades
were intended to function as insurance or to hedge against
credit risks. Although the original document seeking approval
for the synthetic credit portfolio outlined hedging as a goal,
the bank was unable to produce documentation over the next five
years detailing its hedging objectives, strategies, assets,
risks or events it was supposed to hedge. </p>
<p>The bank was also unable to explain why the SCP''s hedges
were treated differently from other types of hedges within the
CIO, the subcommittee report. </p>
<h2>Regulatory Action </h2>
<p>Levin said the findings call for regulators to quickly
complete the Volcker rule and strengthen it. Specifically, he
said any allowance for banks to hedge should be documented and
tied to a specific risk. </p>
<p>We cannot allow the argument of the banks that they can
hedge their entire inventory somehow where we get global
hedges, Levin said at the news conference. If they are going
to claim that trades are a hedge, they''ve got to be able to
identify what is being hedged against, what are the assets being
hedged and what is the proof that it is a hedge. </p>
<p>JPMorgan''s loss re-ignited the debate in Congress over
whether aggregate portfolio hedging is appropriate at all and
how to define and spot these trades. </p>
<p>It has made regulators take another look at hedging and
what constitutes appropriate hedging and what may fit within the
Volcker rule limits, Satish Kini, co-chair of the Debevoise 
Plimpton LLP''s Banking Group, said in advance of the report''s
release. </p>
<h2>Ill-Advised Loopholes'' </h2>
<p>After the bank disclosed its losses May 10, Levin and
Merkley sent a letter to five federal regulators urging them to
remove ill-advised loopholes from the Volcker draft;
regulators have yet to finalize the rule. </p>
<p>Merkley said the PSI report is another reminder for
regulators to complete a strong, simple Volcker firewall. </p>
<p>JPMorgan''s huge losses continue to cast a whale-sized
shadow over these extended delays, and remind us once again just
how important it is to separate risky, hedge-fund-style trading
from the banking system that Main Street depends on, Merkley
said in a statement. </p>
<p>Comptroller of the Currency Thomas Curry said in a June
2012 hearing that the JPMorgan incident was a risk-management
issue, regardless of whether or not the Volcker rule was in
play. </p>
<p>I think our experience here, as it unfolds with JPMorgan
Chase, would help inform our views in the final rule-making,
Curry said. </p>
<p>The subcommittee will hold a hearing on the findings today
with witnesses from the bank, including Drew and Braunstein, and
from the OCC, including Curry. </p>
<p>The investigation of our Permanent Subcommittee on
Investigations into the JPMorgan whale trades opens a window
into the hidden world of high-stakes derivatives trading by a
major bank, Levin said. We found a trading operation that
piled on risk, ignored limits on risk taking, hid losses, dodged
oversight and misinformed the public. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Cliff Edwards" date="Mar 14, 2013  6:19 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-14/microsoft-sells-302-000-xbox-consoles-in-february.html"><headline>Microsoft Sells 302,000 Xbox Consoles in February</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) said U.S. retailers
sold 302,000 Xbox 360 games consoles in February, citing data by
NPD Group Inc. </p>
<p>It was the 26th consecutive month Redmond, Washington-based
Microsoft led console sales, it said in a statement. Its
machines account for 41 percent of current-generation console
sales. Microsoft sold 426,000 Xbox 360 units a year ago. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Noah Buhayar" date="Mar 14, 2013  6:06 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-14/jpmorgan-boosts-payout-more-than-expected-after-fed-approval.html"><headline>JPMorgan Boosts Payout More Than Expected After Fed Approval</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the biggest
U.S. bank, raised its quarterly dividend more than most analysts
estimated to 38 cents and expanded stock buybacks after the
Federal Reserve conditionally approved the firm''s proposal to
return more of its profit to shareholders. </p>
<p>JPMorgan''s new dividend for the second quarter beat the 36-
cent average prediction of analysts surveyed by Bloomberg. The
New York-based bank said in a statement today it would buy back
as much as $6 billion more of its own stock, after scaling back
a $15 billion repurchase program approved last year. </p>
<p>Regulators intent on preventing a repeat of the 2008
financial crisis have run annual stress tests on the largest
lenders to see how they might fare in a recession or economic
shock. JPMorgan was among the bottom four performers last week
in the Fed''s initial test of strength, which showed the bank had
submitted more optimistic estimates of its capital levels in a
severe recession. </p>
<p>While that was still good enough to pass, the Fed also
required the 18 firms to submit plans for managing their
capital, which could include buying back shares and boosting
payouts. The central bank then gauged how strong each firm would
be with the funds that remained. </p>
<p>Today''s approval indicates JPMorgan''s capital may stay
above the minimum 5 percent threshold after accounting for
proposed dividends and buybacks. Chief Executive Officer Jamie
Dimon and Chief Financial Officer Marianne Lake had signaled the
bank would request a higher dividend and lower buyback amount
earlier this year. </p>
<h2>Planning Weakness </h2>
<p>The central bank said in a report today that JPMorgan and
Goldman Sachs Group Inc.''s plans were conditionally approved
because of weaknesses in their planning processes. Projections
of losses and revenue were the issue, according to a Fed
official. The banks can immediately implement dividend and
buyback plans, and must fix the weaknesses and resubmit by the
end of the third quarter, the official said. </p>
<p>JPMorgan Chase is fully committed to meeting all of the
Fed''s requirements, Dimon said in the statement. </p>
<p>JPMorgan fell 2.5 percent to $49.75 at 5:08 p.m. in New
York. The lender had gained 17 percent in the year through the
close of normal trading today, compared with the Standard 
Poor''s 500 Index''s 12 percent advance. </p>
<p>JPMorgan projected its key capital ratio wouldn''t fall
below 7.6 percent, compared with 6.3 percent estimated by the
Fed. The lender said pretax losses through 2014 would total $200
million while the Fed said they would be $32.3 billion. </p>
<h2>Net Revenue </h2>
<p>The bank also was more optimistic than the central bank in
estimating net revenue, loan losses and provisions it would need
to cover those losses. </p>
<p>The Fed''s decision gives a boost to Dimon, 57, whose
reputation suffered during last year''s London Whale episode in
which JPMorgan''s U.K.-based chief investment office lost more
than $6.2 billion with a wrong-way bet on credit derivatives. </p>
<p>Former Chief Investment Officer Ina Drew and other current
and former executives are scheduled to testify tomorrow at the
Senate Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations about the loss. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Frier" date="Mar 14, 2013  5:26 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-14/ibm-puts-its-researchers-to-work-on-consulting-tasks.html"><headline>IBM Puts Its Researchers to Work on Consulting Tasks</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM)''s Bridget Van Kralingen, its head of business services, is
pulling more of the company''s thousands of researchers out of
isolated labs and having them tackle customer problems, a bid to
give it an edge in data-intensive consulting projects. </p>
<p>One out of every four IBM researchers are now helping
automate tasks such as marketing, sales or services for clients,
rather than sticking to behind-the-scenes work on software or
engineering, Van Kralingen said in an interview. Customers can
come to a new lab that combines consulting with research, or
researchers are getting sent out on client projects to study
analytical questions that haven''t been answered before. </p>
<p>IBM is trying to capitalize on its brain trust at a time
when its consulting work is getting increasingly complex. The
company has 3,000 researchers across 12 labs, and they''re
weighing questions ranging from replicating the human brain to
predicting traffic patterns. By putting more of them in touch
with customers, IBM looks to improve its business analytics --
the ability to mine corporate data to discover patterns or make
better decisions. </p>
<p>There will be increasing fusion between the skills of a
consultant, who is practical, and the skills of a researcher,
who I think is more analytical and future-oriented, Van
Kralingen said. Working on new ways for businesses to reach
customers requires more of an analytical research-oriented and
experimental mindset, she said. </p>
<h2>Revenue Goal </h2>
<p>IBM is aiming for $20 billion in sales from business
analytics by 2015, more than double the 2010 figure. IBM has
hired or shifted 8,100 people to solving data-analysis issues in
the last three years, Chief Executive Officer Ginni Rometty said
in an annual letter to shareholders. IBM also has the largest
private mathematics department in the world and has devoted 400
of those staffers to data analysis. </p>
<p>Two decades ago, 70 percent of our researchers were
working in materials science, hardware and related technology,
Rometty said in the letter. Even the one in 10 working in
software were focused on operating systems and compilers. </p>
<p>The new customer-focused lab was started with a joint
investment from Van Kralingen''s division and the research side
of the company that will total in the hundreds of millions, IBM
said. The company shifted 100 scientists and more than 200
consultants to the project. Armonk, New York-based IBM spends
about $6 billion a year in total on research and development. </p>
<h2>Share Gains </h2>
<p>IBM''s analytics prospects have helped fuel a stock rally
this year, sending the shares into record territory. The shares
rose 1.8 percent to $215.80 at the close today in New York,
bringing their year-to-date gain to 13 percent. </p>
<p>Grupo Financiero Banorte SAB, a Mexican bank, signed a $1
billion deal to work with IBM''s new lab over the next 10 years
on customer-experience technology. The companies said this week
that the project will increase the bank''s return on equity to
more than 20 percent. Shares of the Mexican company jumped 3.6
percent to 98.93 pesos today, reaching a record high. </p>
<p>The bank was looking to differentiate its offering from
competition, especially on mobile, CEO Alejandro Valenzuela said
in an interview. </p>
<p>If this platform was just the next best thing, we would
be out of business really fast, he said. </p>
<p>IBM also has researchers collaborating with customers in
one of its most intensive projects -- the effort to
commercialize its Watson artificial-intelligence system for use
in the health and finance fields. Watson helps answer questions
about diagnosing cancer, for example, based on the millions of
pages of medical journals and case studies it has stored. </p>
<p>It gives us a level of evidence and confidence around
very complex challenges, Anne Altman, a general manager at
IBM, said today at a Bloomberg Link Big Data conference in
Washington. The approach lets businesses study giant sets of
information, rather than having to focus on a specific
categories or geography. </p>
<p>We are no longer going to be thinking in terms of
segments, Altman said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Mar 14, 2013  5:14 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-14/morgan-stanley-will-buy-rest-of-brokerage-following-fed-approval.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Will Buy Rest of Brokerage Following Fed Approval</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS), owner of the
world''s biggest brokerage, will buy the remaining 35 percent of
its wealth-management venture with Citigroup Inc. (C) after winning
Federal Reserve approval in the regulator''s annual stress test. </p>
<p>The purchase is subject to other regulatory approvals, the
New York-based bank said today in a filing. Morgan Stanley would
have a 5.62 percent Tier 1 common ratio in the most adverse
economic scenario even after buying the stake, above the 5
percent minimum, the Fed said today. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer James Gorman, 54, already has set a
price with Citigroup to purchase the rest of the brokerage
venture, which was created in 2009. Morgan Stanley said in
January that it will pay $4.7 billion for the last piece, which
will place demands on an additional $400 million of capital. </p>
<p>The Federal Reserve''s non-objection to our capital plan
is another important step towards full ownership of our wealth-
management business, which has been one of the Firm''s key
strategic priorities since 2009, Gorman said in a statement.
We look forward to completing the acquisition of the remaining
35 percent stake in our wealth-management joint venture. </p>
<p>Gorman has staked his strategy in large part on buying all
of the brokerage and increasing profitability at the unit.
Morgan Stanley has said it will earn about $400 million in 2013
from buying the rest of the venture as the company eliminates
non-controlling interest payments to Citigroup and benefits from
more retail orders and deposits. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley didn''t ask the Fed to approve any additional
return of capital to shareholders through dividends or share
repurchases. </p>
<h2>First Priority'' </h2>
<p>There''s a time for returning capital, but given the
importance of the wealth-management joint venture, that''s our
first priority, Chief Financial Officer Ruth Porat said in a
January interview. Longer-term, we are focused on returning
capital to shareholders, whether in the form of share
repurchases or dividends. </p>
<p>The Fed began annual stress tests in 2009 to evaluate the
health of the U.S. banking system. In 2011, the central bank
adopted an approach known as Comprehensive Capital Analysis 
Review, or CCAR, which focused on lenders'' capital plans,
assessing how dividend increases or share buybacks would affect
them. Those results were announced today. </p>
<p>Regulators subject bank portfolios, capital levels and
profit-making potential to conditions that simulate an economic
recession or financial shock. This year''s stress tests involved
three scenarios, including two stressed situations. In one, the
economy contracts for six quarters and inflation and interest
rates rise sharply. In the other, unemployment climbs above 12
percent and stocks fall 52 percent. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Maria Kolesnikova, Chanyaporn Chanjaroen and Whitney McFerron" date="Mar 14, 2013  1:31 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-14/goldman-ranked-no-1-in-commodities-in-2012-jpmorgan-second-1-.html"><headline>Goldman Ranked No. 1 in Commodities in 2012, JPMorgan Second</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) ranked
No.1 in commodities revenue in 2012, according to analytics
company Coalition. </p>
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) had the second-biggest revenues from
commodities and Morgan Stanley (MS) came third, London-based
Coalition said in a report e-mailed today. Spokesmen for the
three banks declined to comment. Barclays Plc and Bank of
America Merrill Lynch were the strongest performers when
measured against 2011 returns, according to the report. </p>
<p>Commodities revenue at the 10 largest banks slumped 24
percent last year to $6 billion, Coalition estimated in
February. The Standard  Poor''s GSCI Spot Index of raw materials
climbed less than 0.3 percent in 2012, the worst performance in
four years, and is little changed in 2013. The gauge''s 100-day
historic volatility fell to as low as 14.1 percent in May, from
as much as 23.8 percent in January 2012, data compiled by
Bloomberg show. </p>
<p>Low volatility and reduced client activity spurred a
drop in commodity revenues in 2012, Coalition said in a report
last month. Increasing concerns about regulation and capital
sensitivity also led banks to re-examine commodity strategies,
it said. The Volcker rule ban on proprietary trading and rules
designed to increase transparency in derivatives markets are
among regulations mandated by the Dodd-Frank Act awaiting
completion by U.S. authorities. </p>
<h2>Tier Two </h2>
<p>Deutsche Bank AG, Barclays and UBS AG were among tier
two performers, rated No. 4 to No. 6 for commodity revenues,
Coalition said today without providing the banks with specific
rankings. BofAML, Citigroup Inc. (C) and Credit Suisse were in
tier three, and Royal Bank of Scotland Group Plc wasn''t
ranked, it said. </p>
<p>Barclays said in February it would shut its speculative
agricultural trading, Deutsche Bank has cut power and natural
gas traders in the U.S. and Europe, and UBS is ceasing to trade
oil, industrial metals and agricultural products. </p>
<p>JPMorgan was the largest investment bank, with $24.1
billion in revenue and $14.4 billion in fixed income, currencies
and commodities, Coalition said. Goldman Sachs was the second-
largest investment bank, followed by Citi, BofAML and Deutsche
Bank tied for the third-largest ranking, according to the
report. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chris Spillane and Neil Callanan" date="Mar 14, 2013 12:07 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-14/goldman-sachs-london-office-project-wins-planners-support.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs'' London Office Project Wins Planners'' Support</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) won
planner''s support to develop an office building that may become
its new European headquarters. </p>
<p>Officials recommended that the City of London financial
district approve the project near the company''s current Fleet
Street base, according to documents posted on the borough''s
Website. The council is set to vote on the plan on March 22. </p>
<p>The building at 70 Farringdon Street will have around
78,000 square meters (840,000 square feet) of internal office
space, according to the application letter. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs was given permission in September to move a
set of protected murals from the building, helping to clear the
way for the redevelopment. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bloomberg News" date="Mar 14, 2013 12:01 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-14/morgan-stanley-favors-convertibles-in-growth-bet-china-credit.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Favors Convertibles in Growth Bet: China Credit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The China fund management ventures
of Morgan Stanley (MS) and Schroders Plc (SDR) are bullish on the nation''s
convertible bonds, predicting the world''s second-biggest economy
can ride out a stock-market slump. </p>
<p>Chinese debt that can be exchanged into shares lost 1.3
percent in March, set for a second monthly decline, according to
the SP China Convertible Bond Index. Comparable notes in the
U.S. gained 2.5 percent, a Bank of America Merrill Lynch index
showed. The Shanghai Composite Index (SHCOMP) of equities tumbled 5
percent since Feb. 1, after rising 20 percent in the previous
two months, on concern limits on real-estate investment will
slow economic growth. </p>
<p>Even though it''s a weak recovery, those property curbs
will make it healthier and more sustainable, said Lin Hongjun,
a Shanghai-based bond fund manager at Bank of Communications
Schroders Fund Management Co., which oversees a total of 64.4
billion yuan ($10.4 billion) of assets. China''s long-term
fundamental is good for convertible bonds this year. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley Huaxin Fund Management Co. says the
combination of the protected returns of a bond and potential for
equity-like gains is well-suited to the nation''s weak
economic rebound. China''s leaders announced on March 5 a target
of 7.5 percent for growth this year at the annual congress
meeting after expansion slowed to 7.8 percent in 2012, the least
in 13 years. </p>
<h2>Holding Gains </h2>
<p>Exchangeable bonds have still climbed 5.8 percent this
year, after a 7.6 percent rally in January. That beat the 0.8
percent advance in the SP China Government Bond Index and the
1.8 percent gain in the SP China Corporate Bond Index. </p>
<p>Confidence in China''s economy is improving. Five-year
credit-default swaps protecting sovereign notes against non-
payment fell five basis points last month to 64 in New York and
were recently at 63, according to data provider CMA, which is
owned by McGraw-Hill Cos. and compiles prices quoted by dealers
in the privately negotiated market. The yuan gained 0.2 percent
this year to 6.2155 per dollar in Shanghai. </p>
<p>Convertible bonds are worth investing in this year,
said Hong Tianyang, a Shenzhen-based bond fund manager at Morgan
Stanley Huaxin, which oversees 13.2 billion yuan of assets.
There is a big probability that we will have a weak recovery,
mild inflation and moderately loose liquidity this year, which
is good for both stocks and bonds, especially convertible
bonds. </p>
<h2>Earnings Outlook </h2>
<p>The yield on Bank of China Ltd.''s 1.1 percent convertible
bond due June 2016 has risen 33 basis points this month to 2.18
percent, according to exchange data. The stock trades at 2.94
yuan, versus its conversion price of 3.44. The rate on China
Shipbuilding Industry Co.''s 0.5 percent note due June 2018
climbed 77 basis points to minus 1.75 percent, exchange data
showed. That reflects a share price of 5.07 yuan that is above
the conversion price of 4.93. </p>
<p>Yields on benchmark 10-year government notes have risen 2
basis points this year to 3.59 percent as of March 13, after
climbing to as high as 3.61 percent on Jan. 29. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley Huaxin''s Hong prefers convertible bonds
issued by banks because of their good earnings outlook. He also
likes military suppliers because their stock prices are
volatile, increasing the value of the exchange option. </p>
<p>China Minsheng Banking Corp (600016) will sell 20 billion yuan of
six-year convertible bonds today, according to a statement to
the Shanghai Stock Exchange on March 12. Guotai Junan Securities
Co. estimated that the sale may draw bids worth about 450
billion yuan. </p>
<h2>Minsheng Sale </h2>
<p>Demand for the Minsheng convertible will be strong,
said Zhang Yongmin, Beijing-based executive president of the
asset management department at Qilu Securities Co. The U.S.
economy is stabilizing and Europe''s will stabilize soon, which
will help China''s rebound. Stocks will rise, and so will
convertible bonds. </p>
<p>China''s exports climbed 21.8 percent in February from a
year earlier, the customs bureau said on March 8. That compared
with a median estimate of 8.1 percent in a Bloomberg News
survey. The nation''s economy will grow 8.1 percent this year,
according to the median of 45 estimates in a Bloomberg survey. </p>
<p>Data for last month was mixed. Industrial production rose
9.9 percent in the first two months of this year and retail
sales increased 12.3 percent, the lowest in the same period
since 2009, official data showed on March 9. </p>
<p>Electricity consumption in January and February climbed 5.5
percent from a year earlier, the National Energy Administration
said yesterday. Growth was 6.7 percent in the first two months
of last year and 12.3 percent in 2011. </p>
<h2>Slower Recovery </h2>
<p>The economy is recovering at a slower pace than
expected, said Wang Shen, a bond analyst at Sinolink
Securities Co. in Shanghai. We should be cautious on
convertible bonds and stocks through April, even though their
performance will be better than bonds this year. </p>
<p>Consumer prices climbed 3.2 percent in February, the
fastest pace in 10 months, the statistics bureau said on March
9. The government''s annual target is 3.5 percent this year, down
from 4 percent in 2012. Bocom Schroders'' Lin said inflation
won''t be a problem in the first half and may drop to 2.5
percent in March. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley Huaxin''s Hong said the limited number of
convertible bonds also increase the securities'' attractiveness.
There are about 120 billion yuan of convertible bonds
outstanding, according to Guotai Junan Securities. </p>
<p>While there are 2,400 stocks, only more than 20
convertible bonds are traded, said Morgan Stanley Huaxin''s
Hong. On one hand, the number of convertibles is still
decreasing because some debt will be converted into stocks. On
the other hand, most local funds can buy convertible bonds. This
imbalance in demand and supply adds value to convertibles. </p>
<p>--Judy Chen. Editors: Robin Ganguly, Sandy Hendry </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Agnieszka Troszkiewicz" date="Mar 14, 2013 10:16 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-14/goldman-sachs-copper-trader-david-freeland-said-to-leave-bank.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Copper Trader David Freeland Said to Leave Bank</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>David Freeland left his job as a
copper trader at Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), according to a person
with direct knowledge of the matter. </p>
<p>Freeland left this week, said the person, who asked not to
be identified because the information hasn''t been made public.
Freeland joined Goldman more than a year ago from Trafigura
Beheer BV. </p>
<p>Sophie Bullock, a spokeswoman for Goldman in London,
declined to comment. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Stephanie Bodoni" date="Mar 14, 2013  7:07 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-14/mobile-apps-put-users-privacy-at-risk-eu-regulators-say.html"><headline>Mobile Apps Put Users'' Privacy at Risk, EU Regulators Say</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Applications for smartphones and
tablets can pose significant privacy risks for consumers if
they aren''t aware of how their personal data is used, European
Union privacy regulators said. </p>
<p>Although app developers want to provide new and
innovative services, the apps may have significant risks to the
private life and reputation of users of smart devices if they do
not comply with EU data-protection law, the EU''s 27 data-
protection watchdogs said in a joint opinion, according to a
statement on the Irish Data Protection Commissioner''s website. </p>
<p>The EU regulators said users must be in control of their
own personal data and informed how it''s used when they
download an app. Everyone involved in developing mobile software
programs has a set of important responsibilities to create a
safe, secure and data-protection-compliant app environment,
said the Article 29 Data Protection Working Party, the umbrella
group for national privacy authorities in the EU. </p>
<p>EU Justice Commissioner Viviane Reding said earlier this
month that U.S.-based technology giants such as Google Inc.,
Facebook Inc., Apple Inc. and other non-European companies that
offer services in the European Union must abide by the bloc''s
overhauled data-protection rules. Google and Facebook are among
several U.S. Internet companies that have faced scrutiny in the
EU for possible privacy-rule violations over their use of
personal data. </p>
<p>While the Article 29 group has no powers to enforce its
opinions directly, national data-protection regulators in Europe
have varying levels of power to take action, including the
levying of fines, against companies. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sonia Sirletti and Francesca Cinelli" date="Mar 14, 2013  2:41 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-14/generali-reports-fourth-quarter-loss-after-writedowns-increase.html"><headline>Generali Reports Fourth-Quarter Loss After Writedowns Increase</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Assicurazioni Generali SpA (UCG), Italy''s
biggest insurer, reported a loss for the fourth quarter after
1.3 billion euros ($1.7 billion) of writedowns on equity
holdings, including a stake in Telecom Italia SpA. (TIT) </p>
<p>The net loss of 1.04 billion euros compared with a profit
of 31 million euros a year earlier, the Trieste, Italy-based
insurer said in a statement today. The average estimate of six
analysts surveyed by Bloomberg was for a loss of 203 million
euros. Generali kept its dividend unchanged at 20 cents a share. </p>
<p>The impairments follow the completion of the prudent and
detailed asset review and incorporate the impact of the group''s
decision to align its impairment criteria with international
best practice, the company said in the statement. The firm
took a 148 million-euro writedown on Telecom Italia stake and
792 million euros on assets available for sale, it said. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Mario Greco, who took over in
August, is seeking to convince investors he can revive profit
and boost capital by cutting costs, selling non-strategic assets
and targeting faster-growing emerging markets. The company is
selling its U.S. life reinsurance business and Swiss asset-
management unit BSI Group as part of a plan approved in January. </p>
<p>Fourth-quarter operating income rose 12 percent to 928
million euros from a year earlier, boosted by the non-life
insurance segment. Non-life operating profit rose 41 percent to
505 million euros in the quarter. Operating income at its life
business declined to 462 million euros from 564 million euros. </p>
<p>Generali''s solvency ratio, a measure of an insurer''s
capacity to absorb losses, rose to 150 percent as of Dec. 31
from 140 percent at the end of September. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri" date="Mar 14, 2013 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-14/disney-delays-infinity-video-game-system-by-two-months.html"><headline>Disney Delays Infinity Video-Game System by Two Months</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS) pushed back the
release of its Infinity video-game system by two months,
postponing a potential source of profit at its interactive unit. </p>
<p>Disney, the world''s largest entertainment company, unveiled
the Infinity platform in January, saying it would reduce costs
and boost earnings at the unit. The platform, which incorporates
characters from multiple Disney films in the same game, was to
hit store shelves in June. </p>
<p>We have moved the launch date for Disney Infinity to
August 18 to capitalize on the critical fall retail season,
John Pleasants, co-president of Disney Interactive, said in a
statement yesterday. </p>
<p>The interactive unit makes video games and designs websites
based on Disney content. In the quarter ended Dec. 29, it posted
its first profit since Disney began breaking out results in
2009. Bob Iger, chairman and chief executive officer of the
Burbank, California-based company, has pledged the division will
be profitable this year. </p>
<p>The delay in the release of the Infinity system will
definitely impact our goal of achieving profitability for the
year at the unit, Pleasants said, according to an earlier New
York Times report, citing an interview. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Heather Perlberg" date="Mar 15, 2013  4:26 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-15/jpmorgan-sees-home-prices-up-14-as-bofa-touts-party.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sees Home Prices Up 14% as BofA Touts Party</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Ben S. Bernanke''s efforts to revive
housing are making real estate bulls even more bullish. </p>
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) more than doubled its forecast for
U.S. home price gains in 2013 to 7 percent this week, and
predicts a more than 14 percent increase through 2015. Bank of
America Corp. (BAC) said last week property values will jump 8 percent
this year, up from a prior estimate of 4.7 percent in a report
titled Someone say house party? </p>
<p>The two biggest U.S. banks are predicting an accelerating
rebound as homebuyers and investors rush to acquire a dwindling
supply of properties and the Federal Reserve pushes down
borrowing costs by buying mortgage bonds. That''s strengthening
the economy and sustaining a rally in homebuilder shares after
the stocks more than doubled since the end of 2011. </p>
<p>We still think we are in the early innings of a prolonged
recovery in housing and the economy, said Samantha McLemore, a
money manager for Bill Miller''s $1.2 billion Legg Mason Capital
Management Opportunity Trust, which has a range of holdings tied
to a housing rebound and has gained 20 percent this year besting
99 percent of rivals. </p>
<p>Home prices rose 6.8 percent in December from the year
earlier, the biggest gain since 2006, according to the SP/Case-
Shiller home-price index of 20 cities. The measure is still 29
percent below the peak that year after soaring homeowner
defaults helped trigger the global financial crisis. </p>




Photographer: Sam Hodgson/Bloomberg

<p>
The two biggest U.S. banks are predicting an accelerating rebound as homebuyers and investors rush to acquire a dwindling supply of properties and the Federal Reserve pushes down borrowing costs by buying mortgage bonds. That''s strengthening the economy and sustaining a rally in homebuilder shares after
the stocks more than doubled since the end of 2011. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Clea Benson, Dawn Kopecki and Mary Childs" date="Mar 15, 2013 11:53 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-15/jpmorgan-s-bacon-says-onus-is-on-us-as-bank-tarnished.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Bacon Says Onus is on Us'' as Bank Tarnished</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) needs to win
back public trust after losses on a derivative portfolio swelled
to more than $6.2 billion and eroded confidence in the largest
U.S. bank, a company risk manager told lawmakers. </p>
<p>This whole thing is regrettable and unacceptable,
Ashley Bacon, acting chief risk officer of the bank, told the
Senate Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations today in
Washington. The onus of proof is on us now to demonstrate how
this can''t happen in other places, how we weathered the
financial crisis well everywhere else, and how we can make the
entire firm a safer place to the satisfaction of you, everybody
else and our regulators. </p>
<p>JPMorgan is seeking to restore confidence in a company that
withstood the 2008 housing crisis better than most rivals and
then stumbled last year with losses on bets by U.K. traders. The
Senate panel released a report yesterday saying the New York-
based bank hid losses and dodged regulators. </p>
<p>You had to figure Congress would hold JPMorgan to the
fire, Adrian Miller, director of fixed-income strategies at
GMP Securities LLC in New York, said by e-mail. The bank and
Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon are thought to be the best
in the business in managing a global bank and the risks that
come with it. So when high expectations come up short, Wall
Street and Washington demand answers, he said. Someone was
going to be taken to task. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
Ashley Bacon, acting chief risk officer with JPMorgan Chase  CO., at the Senate Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations hearing in Washington on March 15, 2013. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki and Zachary Tracer" date="Mar 15, 2013 11:53 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-15/jpmorgan-s-weiland-tells-senate-garbage-risk-remark-was-error.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Weiland Tells Senate Garbage'' Risk Remark Was Error</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Former JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) market-
risk executive Pete Weiland told lawmakers he erred last year
when dismissing internal loss estimates on botched trades as
garbage before they proved prescient. </p>
<p>Yes, I acknowledge it now, with all the information we
have today, that was correct, Weiland said today in testimony
to the Senate Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations. The
panel had quoted his garbage remark in a 301-page report
yesterday on JPMorgan''s so-called London Whale bets, which lost
$6.2 billion in last year''s first nine months. </p>
<p>As the trades soured in the bank''s chief investment office
last February, an internal JPMorgan metric known as the
comprehensive risk measure showed the portfolio might suffer a
$6.3 billion annual loss, lawmakers found. Weiland was the
unit''s chief market risk officer at the time. </p>
<p>We got some CRM numbers and they look like garbage as far
as I can tell, Weiland wrote in an e-mail dismissing the
estimates'' accuracy. He stepped down later in the year. </p>
<p>The CIO''s then-chief, Ina Drew, also doubted the accuracy
of the estimates, the senators'' investigation found. By the time
she believed it, it was too late, they wrote in their
report. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Laura Marcinek and Dawn Kopecki" date="Mar 15, 2013  9:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-15/jpmorgan-pay-fueled-risk-amid-london-whale-loss-report.html"><headline>JPMorgan Pay Fueled Risk Amid London Whale Loss: Report</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) (JPM), the biggest U.S. bank by assets, compensated chief investment office traders in a way that encouraged risk-taking before the unit amassed losses exceeding $6.2 billion, a Senate committee said. </p> <p>Pay that rewarded effective risk management would have suggested the synthetic credit portfolio functioned as a hedge, the Senate Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations said yesterday in a report on the New York-based bank''s so-called London Whale loss. Instead, compensation practices suggest the bets functioned more as a proprietary-trading operation. </p> <p>Executives including Ina Drew, 56, former head of the CIO, are scheduled to testify today at a subcommittee hearing on the London Whale. The bank endured 41 days of trading losses last year as it worked to stabilize bets tied to credit derivatives. The board cut Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon''s 2012 pay by 50 percent to $11.5 million, saying he bears ultimate responsibility for the failures that led to the losses. </p> <p>The lender awarded Achilles Macris, 51, the trader behind the expansion into credit trading, $31.8 million in the two years before the firm racked up the CIO losses, making him among the highest-paid employees at the firm, the report said. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
An exhibits folder for the Senate Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations hearing titled ''JPMorgan Chase Whale Trades: A Case History of Derivatives Risks and Abuses'' arrives to the hearing room in Washington on March 15, 2013. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Adam Haigh and Susan Li" date="Mar 15, 2013 12:26 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-15/goldman-s-o-neill-says-s-p-500-beyond-1-600-needs-growth.html"><headline>Goldman''s O''Neill Says S&amp;amp;P 500 Beyond 1,600 Needs Growth</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>U.S. economic growth will have to accelerate to ridiculously strong levels to justify any advance for the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index (SPX) above 1,600, said Jim O''Neill, chairman of Goldman Sachs Asset Management. </p> <p>After gaining 9.6 percent this year, the SP 500 is trading at 1,563.23, less than 2 points from a record and within 3 percent of 1,600. O''Neill, who coined the term BRIC in describing the rise of Brazil, Russia, India and China, has an estimate of 1,575 for the U.S. equity benchmark this year. The world''s biggest economy is forecast to grow 1.9 percent in 2013 and 2.7 percent next year. </p> <p>In order to justify the SP above 1,600, we''d have to see growth expectations go to something like 4 percent and beyond, O''Neill said in a Bloomberg Television interview in Singapore. I don''t see persistent upside from those kind of levels without some more evidence that the economy would be growing by ridiculously strong levels. </p> <p>The SP 500, which has more than doubled from its bottom in 2009, will trade in a range between 1,500 and 1,600, O''Neill said, without specifying a time period. The 55-year-old economist is stepping down this year after about 18 years at the New York-based investment bank. </p>




Photographer: Thomas Lee/Bloomberg

<p>
Jim O''Neill, chairman of Goldman Sachs Asset Management, introduced the term BRIC in a 2001 report predicting that Brazil, Russia, India and China would account for a greater share of world growth. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christine Harper and Laura Marcinek" date="Mar 15, 2013 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-15/jpmorgan-s-macris-was-paid-more-than-his-boss-before-whale-loss.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Macris Was Paid More Than His Boss Before Whale Loss</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) paid Achilles Macris $31.8 million in the two years before the firm racked up at least $6.2 billion of losses on a portfolio he oversaw, more than his boss Ina Drew and among the most at the bank. </p> <p>Macris''s total compensation was $14.5 million for 2011 and about $17.3 million for 2010, according to a presentation in the Senate Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations report released yesterday. Drew, the former chief investment officer who lost her job because of the bad trades, forfeited her pay for those two years, a total of $29 million. </p> <p>Macris, a Greek national and U.S. citizen, was behind the expansion into credit trading at the chief investment office, which approved his new business initiative in May 2006, according to the report. That led to the creation of a synthetic credit portfolio that caused last year''s losses tied to Bruno Iksil, the derivatives trader dubbed the London Whale for the size of his position in the market. </p> <p>Drew, 56, is scheduled to testify today before the Senate panel, discussing the loss in her first public appearance since her May 14 exit. JPMorgan, the biggest U.S. bank by assets, has said that it recovered about two years of pay from the traders who oversaw the money-losing bets. </p>




Source: JPMorgan Chase  Co. via Bloomberg

<p>
Ina R. Drew, former chief investment officer at JPMorgan Chase  Co., is scheduled to testify today before the Senate panel, discussing the loss in her first public appearance since her May 14 exit. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elisa Martinuzzi" date="Mar 16, 2013 10:53 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-16/generali-ceo-mario-greco-sees-first-quarter-similar-to-fourth.html"><headline>Generali CEO Mario Greco Sees First Quarter Similar'' to Fourth</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Assicurazioni Generali SpA (G) Chief
Executive Officer Mario Greco said he''s counting on a quarter
very similar to the fourth and numbers that continue to be
positive. </p>
<p>France is giving results and Germany continues to
perform well, Greco said in an interview with Class CNBC
published by MF-today. A Generali spokesman confirmed the
comments to Bloomberg News today. </p>
<p>Greco said he continues to see economic difficulties in
Spain and Italy affecting Generali, Italy''s biggest insurer,
while the year has started in line with expectations. The
executive, who started in August, is seeking to revive profit
and boost capital by cutting costs, disposing of assets and
targeting faster-growing emerging markets. The Trieste-based
company is selling its U.S. life-reinsurance business and Swiss
asset-management unit BSI Group as part of a plan approved in
January. </p>
<p>Generali on March 14 said its fourth-quarter operating
profit climbed 12 percent from a year earlier to 928 million
euros ($1.2 billion), boosted by the non-life insurance
business. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Mark Chediak" date="Mar 17, 2013  5:35 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-17/exxon-agrees-to-buy-oklahoma-shale-for-147-5-million-from-bnk.html"><headline>Exxon Agrees to Buy Oklahoma Shale for $147.5 Million From BNK</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) agreed to buy
most of the Tishomingo Field assets in Oklahoma from BNK
Petroleum Inc. (BKX) for $147.5 million, expanding shale exploration
in the state. </p>
<p>Exxon Mobil''s XTO Energy unit will acquire BNK''s Woodford
shale fields in a transaction expected to close in late April,
Camarillo, California-based BNK said today in a statement. BNK
will keep its rights in the Caney and upper Sycamore formations
in the field, the company said in the statement. </p>
<p>Exxon Mobil spokesman Alan Jeffers confirmed the sale in an
e-mail statement. </p>
<p>BNK will use the funds from the sale to increase drilling
of wells in the Caney Field and to pursue exploration in Europe
on its own or with partners, the company said in the statement.
The proceeds will also be used to repay a credit facility. </p>
<p>BNK is setting up another drilling rig for its next planned
Caney well and has contracted the rig for two wells with the
option for an additional two wells, the company said. </p>
<p>Macquarie Capital Markets Canada Ltd. was the lead
financial adviser to BNK. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Mary Childs" date="Mar 18, 2013  8:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-18/jpmorgan-s-whale-advocated-young-trader-who-later-took-his-job.html"><headline>JPMorgan Whale Pushed for Young'' Trader Who Later Took His Job</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Bruno Iksil, the trader whose wagers cost JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) $6.2 billion and led to his ouster, may have unwittingly helped pick his replacement. </p> <p>Henry Kim, then trading high-yield indexes for the market- making desk at the firm''s investment bank, is very young and very talented and should be considered for a post in the chief investment office, Iksil said in a Jan. 30, 2012, e-mail to supervisor Javier Martin-Artajo, according to documents accompanying a report last week by the U.S. Senate Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations. </p> <p>Kim would like to know whether there is some opportunity for him here at CIO be it New York or London, Iksil wrote. I thought maybe he could try to meet with you while you are in New York even informally. </p> <p>Iksil wrote the message months before his souring bets spiraled into a public spectacle that Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon, 57, attributed to egregious, self-inflicted mistakes. The e-mail, included among 598 pages of documents accompanying the Senate report, shows Iksil''s interest in taking talent from the company''s investment bank -- a division that CIO employees came to suspect of undermining the trades. </p> <p>As the losses mounted, CIO traders started deviating from their traditional practice of pricing their positions at or near market midpoints, the Senate report shows. The CIO began to suspect and then blame the market-making desk for assigning prices that hurt the CIO''s trades and leaking information to the market, according to the report. </p>




Photographer: Simon Dawson/Bloomberg

<p>
The offices of JPMorgan Chase  Co. are seen in the business and financial district of Canary Wharf in London. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Inyoung Hwang" date="Mar 18, 2013  5:03 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-18/goldman-sachs-morgan-stanley-raise-s-p-500-forecasts-for-2013.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs, Morgan Stanley Raise S&amp;amp;P 500 Forecasts</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The two biggest U.S. equity bears
in 2012 see the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index rising more than 12
percent this year to at least 1,600, as strong economic data
point to higher corporate earnings. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)''s chief U.S. equity strategist,
David Kostin, raised his target today for the benchmark stocks
gauge by 3.2 percent to 1,625 from 1,575. Adam Parker of Morgan
Stanley (MS) boosted his 2013 estimate by 12 percent to 1,600 from
1,434. They join strategists at Deutsche Bank AG, Credit Suisse
Group AG (CSGN) and Jefferies Group LLC in increasing their targets for
U.S stocks in the last week. </p>
<p>The 2013 U.S. equity market story is becoming one of
improving business activity accompanied by increased CEO
confidence, Kostin wrote in a report. Recent economic data
has been strong as employment growth, ISM surveys and retail
sales have all posted positive surprises. The sequester'' has
begun, and the federal government is still functioning. </p>
<p>The rally in U.S. equities has pushed bearish strategists
to capitulate in 2013 after being conservative last year, when
stock seers forecast the smallest gain in seven years for the
SP 500. (SPX) Kostin and Parker estimated the SP 500 would fall in
2012 to 1,250 and 1,167, respectively, making them the two most
bearish strategists among the 14 surveyed by Bloomberg. The
equity index surged 13 percent to 1,426.19 in 2012. </p>
<p>The SP 500 closed within two points of its all-time record
of 1,565.15 on March 14, as better-than-estimated retail sales
and jobless claims data boosted optimism in the world''s largest
economy. The data helped offset concerns over automatic federal
spending cuts that started March 1. </p>
<h2>Manufacturing Data </h2>
<p>On March 5, the Institute for Supply Management''s non-
manufacturing index reading for February unexpectedly increased.
A week earlier, ISM factory data showed the fastest pace of
manufacturing since June 2011, as orders climbed the most in
almost two years. </p>
<p>The SP 500 has surged 21 percent since its low last year
in June amid corporate earnings that have exceeded analysts''
estimates and stimulus measures by global central banks. The
gauge has added 8.8 percent this year. It slid 0.6 percent to
1,552.10 in New York today and would need to add 3.1 percent to
reach 1,600. </p>
<p>Following the latest upward revisions, the average
strategist forecast for the SP 500 at the end of 2013 is 1,571,
data compiled by Bloomberg show. The figure has risen 2.3
percent since starting the year at 1,534. </p>
<h2>Faster Growth </h2>
<p>Kostin, the New York-based chief U.S. equity strategist at
Goldman, lifted his estimate for combined earnings by companies
in the SP 500 this year by $1 to $108 a share. Goldman expects
U.S. economic growth to reach 3 percent in the first quarter and
2 percent in the second three months of the year, he said. </p>
<p>He also said financials stocks should outperform those from
other industries in 2013, citing faster economic growth, rising
interest rates and higher dividends and share buybacks. </p>
<p>Morgan''s Parker, who is based in New York, increased his
projection for SP 500 profit to $103.20 from $98.71. </p>
<p>We see improving fundamentals in the second half of the
year and into next year, Parker said in today''s note. A
number of things have been responsible for the recent multiple
expansion, but perhaps a major contributor was quantitative
easing, which encompasses Fed and ECB policy. </p>
<p>Jefferies'' Sean Darby increased his target by 6.9 percent
to 1,673 on March 12, making him the most bullish strategist in
Bloomberg''s survey. The Hong Kong-based chief global equity
strategist said earnings will continue to surpass estimates and
investors will shift money to stocks from bonds. </p>
<h2>Equity Strategists </h2>
<p>Credit Suisse''s Andrew Garthwaite raised his target to
1,640 from 1,550, the second-highest in the survey. More
aggressive central bank actions and inflows into equities were
among the reasons the SP 500 warranted a higher forecast, he
said in a March 15 note. </p>
<p>David Bianco, Deutsche Bank''s New York-based chief U.S.
equity strategist, raised his 2013 target to 1,625 from 1,600,
citing positive economic data in a March 16 note. </p>
<p>Wells Fargo  Co.''s Gina Martin Adams is the most bearish
strategist, projecting the SP 500 will fall to 1,390. That
would require a 10 percent drop from today''s level. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Brian Louis" date="Mar 18, 2013  4:32 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-18/morgans-hotel-s-largest-shareholder-seeks-board-overhaul.html"><headline>Morgans Hotel''s Largest Shareholder Seeks Board Overhaul</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgans Hotel Group Co.''s (MHGC) largest
shareholder said it is seeking to overhaul the board, aiming to
return the company to profitability or have it pursue strategic
alternatives. The stock rose the most in 16 months. </p>
<p>OTK Associates, the owner of 4.5 million Morgans shares, or
a 13.9 percent stake, plans to nominate seven directors to the
boutique-hotel operator''s board, the investor said in a
statement today. The current board has engaged in a number of
self-serving deals and questionable employment decisions,
the company said. </p>
<p>OTK has observed as various management teams and board
members squandered resources and failed to capitalize on the
extraordinary brand value of the company, OTK said in a letter
to shareholders, included in the statement. The board has
allowed management to pursue a litany of transactions that have
destroyed significant equity capital and collectively generated
negative returns to stockholders. </p>
<p>Morgans, based in New York, has reported losses for every
quarter since 2007, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. The
shares have fallen 56 percent in the past five years, compared
with a 2 percent decline in the Bloomberg U.S. Lodging Index. </p>
<p>The stock gained 11 percent today to $5.67, the biggest
increase since Oct. 27, 2011. </p>
<p>A telephone message left with Rich Szymanski, chief
financial officer of Morgans, wasn''t returned. The company
operates properties such as the Mondrian in Los Angeles and the
Delano South Beach in Florida. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Mary Childs and Elizabeth Dexheimer" date="Mar 18, 2013 10:44 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-18/jpmorgan-loss-drove-cio-rift-as-whale-sought-peace-call-shows.html"><headline>JPMorgan Loss Led CIO Rift as Whale Sought Peace, Call Shows</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Bruno Iksil, the JPMorgan Chase 
Co. (JPM) trader known as the London Whale, had an e-mail sent to
about 20 colleagues last year estimating almost double the daily
losses his book had shown thus far. Then the phone rang. </p>
<p>Why did you do that? his supervisor, Javier Martin- Artajo, said at the start of the March 20 call. The position was
failing to recover, Iksil explained. </p>
<p>Okay, Okay, listen you''ve done it, Martin-Artajo said,
according to a transcript. You think that this is right. This
is not what I would have done but you''ve done it so I''m okay
with this. </p>
<p>The exchange is among numerous snapshots of life inside
JPMorgan as the London Whale trades unraveled, resulting in more
than $6.2 billion in losses for the biggest U.S. bank. The
conversations were revealed last week as the U.S. Senate
Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations released a 301-page
report on the botched derivatives bets, as well as almost 600
pages of e-mails, phone-call transcripts and other records. </p>
<p>While lawmakers used the documents to bolster their
findings that the New York-based company and its executives
misled investors and regulators, the tome also provides a rare
look at how traders and their bosses grappled with stress and a
growing sense that they wouldn''t be able to contain the damage. </p>




Photographer: Simon Dawson/Bloomberg

<p>
Pedestrians walk past the offices of JPMorgan Chase  Co., center left, in the business and financial district of Canary Wharf in London. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Camila Russo" date="Mar 18, 2013  9:57 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-18/goldman-bearish-gold-call-overrun-by-inflation-argentina-credit.html"><headline>Goldman Bearish Gold Call Overrun by Inflation: Argentina Credit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Argentines are buying more gold
than ever to protect their savings from the Western Hemisphere''s
fastest inflation as the country''s bonds suffer the worst
returns in developing nations. </p>
<p>While Goldman Sachs Group Inc. called for gold prices to
peak last month and billionaire George Soros cut his stake by
more than half, Banco de la Ciudad de Buenos Aires, Argentina''s
only gold trader, is talking with mining companies to buy the
metal directly as surging demand exhausts its supply of scrap.
The bank began marketing gold to individuals after the nation
tightened currency controls in October 2011, selling 280 kilos
in its first year for 102.6 million pesos ($20 million). </p>
<p>Argentines are turning to the precious metal to preserve
the value of their savings as economists forecast the peso will
lose more value than any currency in the world and President
Cristina Fernandez de Kirchner bans most dollar purchases. The
nation''s estimated inflation rate of 26 percent is also eroding
the value of fixed-income securities, causing Argentina''s peso-
denominated bonds to lose 5.5 percent this year versus a 2.2
percent gain in emerging markets, according Barclays Plc. </p>
<p>I''m buying gold every chance I get, Guillermo Acosta, a
27-year-old security guard, said inside a branch of Banco Ciudad
in downtown Buenos Aires. With this inflation, I feel like my
savings will evaporate if I keep them in pesos. </p>
<h2>Dollar Bonds </h2>
<p>Acosta''s initial investment of 10 grams of gold in February
last year has returned 47 percent as the price per gram rose to
381.5 pesos from 260 pesos. </p>
<p>Argentina''s government dollar-denominated bonds fell an
average 14.3 percent in that span, according to JPMorgan Chase 
Co.''s EMBI global index, and the peso weakened 15 percent. </p>
<p>The nation hasn''t borrowed money from overseas debt markets
since its $95 billion default in 2001 and Fernandez''s increasing
influence over the economy since her re-election in 2011 has
pushed up the interest that bond investors demand to 13.9
percent, or three times the average in emerging markets. </p>
<p>With Argentina printing pesos to finance itself, the amount
of pesos in the economy has increased 38 percent in the past
year, leading analysts to anticipate that the currency will
depreciate 12.9 percent through year-end, the most among
currencies tracked by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Banco Ciudad is the only bank left that trades the metal
after Fernandez in July banned the purchase of certified 99.99
percent pure gold for savings. The bank sells it at 99.96
percent purity, according to Carlos Leiza, who oversees the
lender''s gold trading. </p>
<h2>Keep Up'' </h2>
<p>The boom goes in hand with the inability to buy
dollars, he said in an interview at his office in Buenos
Aires. People are looking for alternatives that at least
implicitly hold the value of the dollar. The demand has been
strong for over a year now. We can barely keep up. </p>
<p>The extra yield that investors demand to hold Argentine
government dollar-denominated debt instead of Treasuries widened
two basis points, or 0.02 percentage point, to 1,185 basis
points at 9:55 a.m. in New York, according to JPMorgan''s EMBI
Global index. </p>
<p>The cost of protecting $10 million of Argentine government
debt against default for five years with credit-default swaps
rose 88 basis points to 3,121 basis points, data compiled by
Bloomberg show. </p>
<p>Last year, Banco Ciudad limited purchases to 100 grams per
person per day in direct sales to individuals. Investors who
want to speculate on the price of gold without actually owning
the metal are also buying record amounts of futures contracts. </p>
<h2>Good Option'' </h2>
<p>The number of open futures contracts due in June in the
Rosario Futures Exchange, where they are traded locally, climbed
183 percent in the past year to 14,508, and reached an all-time
high of 15,276 on Jan. 29. </p>
<p>Faced with the inability to buy foreign currency,
investors are seeing gold futures as a good option to dollarize
their portfolios, said Sebastian Porcel, director of Buenos
Aires-based futures brokerage Global Agro. The fact that
people are going through the burden of owning actual gold bars
shows the huge need they have to protect savings. </p>
<p>While demand for gold is rising in Argentina, Goldman Sachs
last month cut its three-month target to $1,615 an ounce from
$1,825, and also chopped its six- and 12-month forecasts. The
bank said the cycle for gold prices, which has climbed for 12
straight years, has probably turned as the recovery in the U.S.
economy gathers momentum and investments decrease. </p>
<p>Soros reduced his stake in the SPDR Gold Trust, the biggest
gold exchange-traded fund, by 55 percent in the fourth quarter,
filings showed last month. </p>
<h2>Prices Drop </h2>
<p>Gold futures traded in New York have fallen 11 percent in
the past six months. </p>
<p>The difference between the prices to buy and sell gold is
greater than the gap when trading futures, meaning investors are
more at risk of losing money when they need to sell, according
to Claudio Burelli, the head of the currency trading desk at
Buenos Aires-based brokerage Puente Hermanos Sociedad de Bolsa. </p>
<p>There is a 35 percent difference between the prices to buy
and sell gold at Banco Ciudad, while there''s no premium to sell
the country''s benchmark 2017 dollar bond in the local market,
according to the Buenos Aires-based Open Electronic Market,
known as MAE. </p>
<p>There''s a big spread in prices, so to make money, not
only does the price of gold have to rise, you have to beat that
gap, said Burelli, who sold gold before it was restricted. </p>
<h2>Exchange Rate </h2>
<p>Gold sold by Banco Ciudad also isn''t recognized
internationally, making it more difficult to determine its
value, he said. </p>
<p>The cost of 100 grams of gold in Argentina as of last week
was 36,646 pesos. In New York, the same amount based on the
benchmark troy ounce (31 grams) sold for about $5,126. </p>
<p>The bank multiplies that price by 0.95 to account for the
lower quality of the gold to get a dollar price of $4,870. </p>
<p>While the implied exchange rate of 7.5 pesos per dollar is
higher than the official rate of 5.09, it''s still better than
the rate of 8 pesos per dollar in the black market. </p>
<p>Historically, gold has been seen as a store of value, so
as long as options for doing that in Argentina are limited,
people are going to keep buying it, Banco Ciudad''s Leiza said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Greg Stohr" date="Mar 18, 2013  9:33 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-18/goldman-sachs-rejected-by-court-on-mortgage-securities.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Rejected by Court on Mortgage Securities</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The U.S. Supreme Court turned away
an appeal by Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) in an investor lawsuit
over mortgage-backed securities whose value plummeted during the
2008 financial crisis. </p>
<p>The justices today left intact a federal appeals court
ruling that partially backed the NECA-IBEW Health and Welfare
Fund, which is pressing the case. </p>
<p>At issue was whether NECA, which bought certificates from
two of 17 disputed Goldman Sachs trusts, had legal standing
to sue on behalf of investors in the other 15 offerings. </p>
<p>The New York-based 2nd U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals said
NECA''s claims were similar to those stemming from five other
offerings, all of which contained loans made by a Wells Fargo 
Co. (WFC) unit and GreenPoint Mortgage Funding Inc. The appeals court
said NECA had standing to press those claims, though not any
claims concerning the other 10 trusts. </p>
<p>The standing issue is separate from the question of class
action status, which the lower courts haven''t yet considered. </p>
<p>The case is Goldman Sachs v. NECA-IBEW Health and Welfare
Fund, 12-528. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Greg Quinn" date="Mar 19, 2013  5:41 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-19/jpmorgan-sees-50-60-chance-macklem-is-next-boc-governor.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sees 50%-60% Chance Macklem Is Next BOC Governor</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Bank of Canada Senior Deputy
Governor Tiff Macklem''s chances of replacing Mark Carney as the
central bank''s top official are between 50 percent and 60
percent, according to analysts at JPMorgan Chase  Co. </p>
<p>The second-most likely candidate is Stephen Poloz, chief
executive at Export Development Canada, according to a report
today by Kevin Hebner and Sandy Batten in New York. Macklem''s
promotion isn''t certain because the last two selections skipped
over the top deputy while Finance Minister Jim Flaherty has
suggested he wants someone with deep financial market
experience, according to the report. </p>
<p>The market may be underestimating the possibility of a
surprise, wrote Hebner, a foreign-exchange strategist and
Batten, a senior economist. Choosing Macklem would represent
an endorsement of existing BoC policy, which has been to
maintain a tightening bias in the face of deteriorating economic
conditions, even as central bank policy makers in other G-7
countries add stimulus. However, we think a surprise
announcement would likely be interpreted dovishly and may
weaken the Canadian dollar, they said. </p>
<p>Canada''s benchmark interest rate has been 1 percent for
more than two years. Policy makers in the world''s 11th largest
economy are grappling with a strong currency and sluggish global
demand that''s hampering exports, record consumer-debt loads
impinging spending and inflation averaging below the Bank of
Canada''s 2 percent target. </p>
<p>Governor Carney is leaving the Ottawa-based central bank on
June 1 to take over the Bank of England a month later. </p>
<p>Front-runner Macklem is well-liked and supported within
the Bank, and we think he certainly has the qualifications to be
Governor, Hebner and Batten wrote in the report. </p>
<p>Other candidates to replace Carney include deputy governors
Timothy Lane and Agathe Cote along with former deputy governor
Jean Boivin who now works at the finance department, the report
said. The job could also go to Bank of Montreal (BMO) Vice Chairman
Kevin Lynch or Julie Dickson, the country''s top banking
regulator, Hebner and Batten wrote. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Phoebe Sedgman" date="Mar 19, 2013  1:43 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-19/goldman-reduces-iron-ore-forecast-as-global-demand-growth-slows.html"><headline>Goldman Cuts Iron-Ore Forecast as Global Demand Growth Slows</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. cut its
estimate for iron-ore prices this year on expectations demand
will moderate and steel production will slow in China, the
world''s largest buyer. </p>
<p>Iron ore may average $139 a metric ton, compared with a
previous estimate of $144, analysts Christian Lelong and Jeffrey Currie wrote in a report today. The bank has a neutral outlook
on the commodity and prices may be supported at about $140 by
the need for high-cost Chinese mine production to balance the
market in 2013, the report showed. </p>
<p>Prices have dropped 7.2 percent in 2013 as China''s
industrial output had the weakest start to a year since 2009 and
concern rose that curbs on construction in the country will
reduce demand for the steelmaking material. Iron ore has peaked
and will decline over the rest of the year, Morgan Stanley said
March 7, joining analysts from Deutsche Bank AG to Credit Suisse
Group AG in forecasting lower prices. </p>
<p>We expect global seaborne iron-ore demand to revert back
to its historical growth rate of 2 percent per annum, Goldman
Sachs said. Steel production growth has slowed in China and we
expect it will remain below GDP growth rates in the future. </p>
<h2>Rio, BHP </h2>
<p>Rio Tinto Group, the world''s second-largest iron-ore
exporter, fell the most in 16 months in London trading after
Goldman cut the stock to conviction sell from neutral. London-
based Rio slumped 5.2 percent to close at 3,107 pence. BHP
Billiton Ltd. (BHP) dropped 3.5 percent after Goldman lowered its
rating to neutral from buy. </p>
<p>Iron ore with 62 percent content delivered to the Chinese
port of Tianjin slipped 0.2 percent to $134.40 a dry ton today,
according to the Steel Index Ltd. Swaps are trading at $132 a
ton for April, $127.50 for the second quarter and $121.25 for
the third, according to SSY Futures Ltd., a broker. </p>
<p>China will expand 8.1 percent this year and 8 percent in
2014 after the weakest annual growth in 13 years in 2012,
according to the median estimate of analysts compiled by
Bloomberg. The nation''s new leadership is focusing on building a
consumer-led economy as a construction boom wanes. </p>
<p>New iron-ore supplies and slower growth in steel demand
will weigh on prices during the second half, Greg Lilleyman, Rio
Tinto (RIO)''s president of Pilbara operations, said today. Steel
demand growth in China slowed to 2.1 percent last year from 20
percent in 2010, according to Citigroup Inc. </p>
<h2>Chinese Measures </h2>
<p>Steel production is exceeding China''s domestic consumption
and will probably decline in the near term, Commodore Research 
Consultancy said in a report today. China''s cabinet on March 1
introduced measures to ease house prices and ordered stricter
enforcement of taxes on sales as authorities step up a three-
year campaign to cool the real-estate market. </p>
<p>China''s domestic iron-ore production may also be more
resilient than expected, Goldman Sachs said. Continued
investment in large-scale mines is likely to offset the loss of
marginal mines and moderate future demand for imports, it said. </p>
<p>The country imported 56.4 million tons of ore in February,
compared with 65.5 million tons a month earlier, according to
the customs administration. Idled Chinese mines with capacity of
100 million tons a year will return to the market from March
after the winter ends, Macquarie Research said in a Feb. 22
report. </p>
<p>Iron ore is measured in dry tons, or metric tons less
moisture. At Tianjin port, moisture can account for 8 percent to
10 percent of the ore''s weight. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ilya Khrennikov" date="Mar 19, 2013 10:58 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-19/mobile-telesystems-beats-estimates-as-users-spend-more.html"><headline>Mobile TeleSystems Beats Estimates as Users Spend More</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>OAO Mobile TeleSystems (MBT), Russia''s
largest wireless-service provider, boosted fourth-quarter profit
by 39 percent, beating analysts'' estimates as subscriber numbers
increased and customers spent more browsing the Web. </p>
<p>Net income rose to $547 million from $394 million a year
earlier, the company, known as MTS, said today in a statement.
Analysts projected $466 million, the average of estimates
compiled by Bloomberg. Sales gained about 6 percent to $3.17
billion, also beating estimates. </p>
<p>MTS, controlled by billionaire Vladimir Evtushenkov, added
1.8 million subscribers for a total of 101 million, and data
revenue in Russia rose by about a third. The company wants to
improve its profit margin after it fell below the level of its
peers in the fourth quarter. </p>
<p>The margin for operating income before depreciation and
amortization shrank by 2.1 percentage points to 40.7 percent of
sales as the company invested in expansion of its retail network
and shut operations in Uzbekistan. Rival OAO MegaFon had a 43.9
percent Oibda margin in the fourth quarter, while VimpelCom Ltd. (VIP)
had 41.1 percent. </p>
<p>MTS said it''s targeting a margin of 41 percent to 42
percent in 2013 to 2015. The operator wants to boost revenue
5 percent to 7 percent in local currencies this year from the
equivalent of $12.4 billion last year and plans capital spending
of 20 percent of sales, it said. </p>
<p>The stock rose as much as 2.4 percent and was up 2 percent
at $20.40 per American depositary receipt at 10:55 a.m. in New
York. That extended the gain this year to 9.4 percent. </p>
<p>The board will meet in April to determine the size of 2012
dividends, Chief Financial Officer Alexey Kornya told reporters
in Moscow today. Management will propose paying dividends of at
least 18.3 rubles (59 cents) a share, or $1.2 billion in total,
he said. </p>
<p>MTS posted net income of $1 billion last year. Excluding
impairment costs and court claims in Uzbekistan, profit was $2
billion, according to the statement. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Laura Marcinek and Serena Saitto" date="Mar 19, 2013 10:45 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-19/goldman-names-fisher-head-of-technology-equity-capital-markets.html"><headline>Goldman Names Fisher to Head Tech Equity Capital Markets</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) named Andy Fisher head of technology equity capital markets, effective
immediately, according to a memo to employees. </p>
<p>Fisher will report to David Ludwig, who leads technology,
media and telecom equity capital markets, the firm''s executives
wrote in the memo today, a copy of which was obtained by
Bloomberg News. Michael DuVally, a spokesman for the New York-
based bank, confirmed the memo''s contents. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs earned $987 million in equity underwriting
revenue last year, a 9 percent decline from 2011, the firm said
in January. For the fourth quarter of 2012, that revenue surged
59 percent to $304 million from a year earlier. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs has enjoyed significant momentum in
technology equity, the bank said in the memo. Andy was a key
part of that success, having led many of our most important and
meaningful transactions for the firm. </p>
<p>Fisher, based in San Francisco, joined Goldman Sachs in
2005, according to Financial Industry Regulatory Authority
records. He previously worked at Credit Suisse Group AG, the
records show. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Mar 19, 2013  9:35 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-19/jpmorgan-restores-website-after-solving-technical-glitch.html"><headline>JPMorgan Restores Website After Solving Technical Glitch</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the largest
U.S. bank, has restored its consumer website after a technical
glitch yesterday left some customers unable to access their
balances and full transaction histories. </p>
<p>We have a technology problem regarding customers'' balance
information that we''ve resolved, the bank today said in an e-
mailed statement. </p>
<p>The cause was an internal technical issue unrelated to
cyberattacks that left Chase.com customers unable to access
their accounts for several hours on March 12, the bank said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Mar 19, 2013  9:33 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-19/morgan-stanley-said-to-shut-princeton-move-workers.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Said to Shut Princeton, Move Workers</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS), owner of the
world''s largest brokerage, is closing its Princeton, New Jersey,
office and will move the location''s 95 employees elsewhere,
according to a person briefed on the matter. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley filed a notice with the New Jersey labor
department this month alerting it of the decision. The New York-
based bank is offering the staff, most of whom work in
technology and data, roles in other locations, said the person, 
who asked not to be named because the moves haven''t been 
publicly announced. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer James Gorman, 54, has pledged to
cut $1.6 billion in costs over the next two years as he seeks to
double return on equity even without an improvement in markets.
The firm last year expanded its space in lower Manhattan''s 1 New
York Plaza to consolidate operations that were previously spread
over Brooklyn, Manhattan and Jersey City, New Jersey. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ilya Khrennikov" date="Mar 19, 2013  9:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-19/mobile-telesystems-beats-estimates-as-mobile-users-spend-more.html"><headline>Mobile TeleSystems Beats Estimates on More Subscribers, Data</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>OAO Mobile TeleSystems (MBT), Russia''s
largest wireless-service provider, boosted fourth-quarter profit
by 39 percent, beating analysts'' estimates as subscriber numbers
increased and customers spent more browsing the Web. </p>
<p>Net income rose to $547 million from $394 million a year
earlier, the company, known as MTS, said today in a statement.
Analysts projected $466 million, the average of estimates
compiled by Bloomberg. Sales gained about 6 percent to $3.17
billion, also beating estimates. </p>
<p>MTS, controlled by billionaire Vladimir Evtushenkov, added
1.8 million subscribers for a total of 101 million and data
revenue in Russia rose by about a third. The company wants to
improve its profit margin after it fell below the level of its
peers in the fourth quarter. </p>
<p>The margin for operating income before depreciation and
amortization shrank by 2.1 percentage points to 40.7 percent of
sales as the company invested in expansion of its retail network
and shut operations in Uzbekistan. Rival OAO MegaFon had a 43.9
percent Oibda margin in the fourth quarter, while VimpelCom Ltd. (VIP)
had 41.1 percent. </p>
<p>MTS said it''s targeting a margin of 41 percent to 42
percent in 2013 to 2015. The operator wants to boost revenue 5
percent to 7 percent in local currencies this year from the
equivalent of $12.4 billion last year and plans capital spending
of 20 percent of sales, it said. </p>
<p>The board will meet in April to determine the size of 2012
dividends, Chief Financial Officer Alexey Kornya told reporters
in Moscow today. Management will propose paying dividends of at
least 18.3 rubles (59 cents) a share, or $1.2 billion in total,
he said. </p>
<p>MTS posted net income of $1 billion last year. Excluding
impairment costs and court claims in Uzbekistan, profit was $2
billion, according to the statement. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jody Shenn" date="Mar 20, 2013  3:56 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-20/jpmorgan-to-sell-bonds-backed-by-616-million-of-mortgages.html"><headline>JPMorgan to Sell Mortgage Debt With Weaker Repurchase Rules</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) is planning to
sell securities backed by $616 million of new U.S. home loans
that don''t have government support, its first offering in the
so-called non-agency market since the financial crisis. </p>
<p>The bonds are made riskier by the New York-based bank and
other originators of the mortgages offering weaker promises to
repurchase misrepresented loans than those on similar deals,
Fitch Ratings said today in an e-mailed report. Lenders and bond
sponsors have been seeking to trim potential liabilities in such
deals as the market revives after suffering billions of dollars
of losses from debt sold before the collapse in home prices. </p>
<p>The value of the so-called representations and warranties
in the JPMorgan transaction is significantly diluted by
qualifying and conditional language that substantially reduces
lender loan breach liability and the inclusion of sunsets for a
number of provisions including fraud, New York-based Fitch
analysts including Roelof Slump wrote in the presale report. </p>
<p>The classes of the deal expected to receive top credit
ratings carried loss buffers of 7.4 percent as Fitch said it
adjusted its analysis to reflect the greater investor dangers
created by the weaker contracts, according to the report. That
compares with so-called credit enhancement, created by items
such as other bonds being first in line to absorb losses of the
underlying loans, of 7.05 percent in a Credit Suisse Group AG (CSGN)
deal in February and 6.5 percent in a transaction last month by
Redwood Trust Inc. (RWT), according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<h2>Jumbo Loans </h2>
<p>Jennifer Zuccarelli, a JPMorgan spokeswoman, didn''t
immediately return a telephone message seeking comment on the
transaction. </p>
<p>The JPMorgan securities are backed by high-quality prime
mortgages, with average balances of $819,495, according to the
Fitch report. That suggests that the loans are so-called jumbo
mortgages as such big loans dominate the revival in the non-
agency bond market led by Redwood and Credit Suisse. </p>
<p>Those two firms, the only previous issuers since the market
revived in 2010, have completed deals backed by about $2.1
billion of new mortgages this year, compared with $3.5 billion
in all of last year, according to data compiled by Bloomberg.
Issuance peaked at $1.2 trillion in both 2005 and 2006 before
collapsing as prices tumbled amid soaring foreclosures and
plunging real-estate values. </p>
<h2>Kroll Grades </h2>
<p>Jumbo home loans are larger than allowed in government-
supported programs, currently as much as $729,750 for single-
family properties in some areas. For Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac
loans with the lowest costs for borrowers using 20 percent down
payments, limits range from $417,000 to $625,500. </p>
<p>Kroll Bond Rating Agency plans to assign similar grades to
the JPMorgan bonds as Fitch, according to a report today. </p>
<p>While it also saw the representation and warranty
provisions as a credit negative, those features were
mitigated by the debt''s high quality and reviews of all of their
files by a third-party firm, Kroll said in its presale report. </p>
<p>If similar provisions were present in a transaction that
had lower quality collateral, was subjected to less robust third
party diligence review or had a higher proportion of originators
that were potentially financially weaker, Kroll Bond Rating
Agency might forecast higher expected loss levels or consider a
downward adjustment of its ratings, the firm said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Eliot Caroom" date="Mar 20, 2013  1:15 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-20/chevron-pascagoula-said-to-plan-six-weeks-of-hydrotreater-work.html"><headline>Chevron Pascagoula Said to Plan Six Weeks Hydrotreater Work</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX) plans to shut a
hydrotreater at its Pascagoula refinery in Mississippi in the
first week of April for six weeks of maintenance, according to a
person familiar with the work. </p>
<p>The refinery''s coker is still shut following about six
weeks of maintenance and may restart next week, said the person,
who asked not to be identified because the information isn''t
public. Recent turnaround work also took place on a crude
distillation unit and vacuum distillation unit, another person
familiar with the work said. </p>
<p>The Pascagoula plant has the capacity to process 330,000
barrels of crude a day, according to data compiled by Bloomberg.
It produces 39 percent gasoline, 23 percent diesel and 15
percent jet fuel, according to Chevron''s website. </p>
<p>A hydrotreater removes sulfur, metal and other impurities
from refined products. </p>
<p>Sean Comey, a San Ramon, California-based spokesman for
Chevron, said the company doesn''t comment on routine maintenance
and will continue to supply customers with products without
interruption. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Mark Drajem" date="Mar 20, 2013  1:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-20/chevron-green-groups-agree-set-standards-for-shale-gas.html"><headline>Chevron, Green Groups Agree Set Standards for Shale Gas</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX) joined natural gas
producers and environmental groups to form an independent center
that will set standards for drilling by hydraulic fracturing in
the U.S. Appalachian region. </p>
<p>Gas output in Pennsylvania, Ohio and West Virginia is
booming as drillers unlock shale deposits using the process,
also called fracking, that shoots water, sand and chemicals
underground to crack rock and free trapped gas. The process has
spurred complaints from landowners and environmental groups
about increased air pollution and water contamination. </p>
<p>Shale gas has transformed our nation''s energy mix, while
both offering environmental benefits and posing serious
environmental challenges, Fred Krupp, president of the
Environmental Defense Fund, a group that''s part of the venture,
said today in a statement. </p>
<p>The Center for Sustainable Shale Development, being formed
today in Pittsburgh, will provide independent evaluations of gas
producers that join the effort. The center''s standards will
limit flaring, encourage maximum water recycling and reduce the
toxicity of the fracking fluid. </p>
<p>Domestic production of natural gas has boosted the U.S.
economy by lowering the cost of the fuel used in manufacturing.
The Marcellus Shale, which runs along the Appalachian Mountains
from New York to Virginia, is the nation''s largest-producing gas
field, according to energy company Range Resources Corp. (RRC) </p>
<p>Industry groups for chemical, fertilizer and steel
companies are touting economic gains as natural gas supplies
become more accessible. Low-cost natural gas could generate $72
billion in capital investment as petrochemical companies
relocate or boost investments in the U.S., according to the
American Chemistry Council. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jason Corcoran" date="Mar 20, 2013 12:26 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-20/goldman-sachs-said-to-hire-ubs-s-jordan-to-be-moscow-co-head.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Said to Hire UBS''s Jordan to Be Russia Co-Head</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) hired Nick Jordan from UBS AG (UBSN) as co-head of its operations in Moscow in the
fourth overhaul of its leadership in the country in as many
years, according to two people with knowledge of the move. </p>
<p>Jordan, a 53-year-old, Russian-speaking American, will work
alongside Paolo Zannoni, who was named country chief last year,
said the people, who asked not to be identified as the move
hasn''t been made public. Jordan, the former chief of Lehman
Brothers Holdings Inc.''s Russian unit, was named head of UBS''s
local operations in 2010. </p>
<p>UBS was too small for Nick taking into account its
limited commitment to Russia, Ilya Scherbovich, founder of
investment firm United Capital Partners, who worked with him at
Deutsche UFG, said in an e-mail today. Nick is the most
experienced banker on the Russian market by far and he was
involved in dozens of very important transactions in Russia. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs is adding staff after the government hired it
last month to advise it on attracting more institutional
investors. The Wall Street firm is also one of 23 foreign and
domestic banks selected to advise Russia on its 1 trillion-ruble
($33 billion) privatization program. </p>
<h2>Job Cuts </h2>
<p>Monika Schaller, a Goldman Sachs spokeswoman in Frankfurt,
and Dominik Von Arx, a UBS spokesman in London, declined to
comment. UBS, Switzerland''s biggest bank based in Zurich, has
been scaling back its investment bank, cutting 10,000 jobs over
three years and exiting most debt-trading businesses to focus on
money management and boost its return on equity. </p>




Photographer: Andrey Rudakov/Bloomberg

<p>
Nicholas Jordan, chief executive officer of UBS AG Russia. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Donal Griffin" date="Mar 20, 2013 10:31 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-20/visa-purchae-of-visa-europe-seen-as-positive-by-jpmorgan.html"><headline>Visa Purchae of Visa Europe Seen as Positive by JPMorgan</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Visa Inc. (V), the world''s biggest
payment network, would benefit from buying Visa Europe Ltd.
because creating a single global business would outweigh
regulatory risk, JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) said. </p>
<p>Visa Europe, a London-based network owned by banks, has a
put option giving it the right to require Foster City,
California-based Visa to purchase its shares. </p>
<p>Our longstanding view on the put being exercised is
positive, as we believe a consolidated global network is
stronger than a split network, Tien-tsin Huang, a JPMorgan
analyst who has an overweight rating on Visa shares, said in a
note to clients. </p>
<p>Lenders that own Visa Europe are considering requiring Visa
to make the purchase, the Wall Street Journal reported
yesterday. Visa Chief Executive Officer Charles Scharf is vying
with competitors MasterCard Inc. (MA) and China UnionPay for a share
of the payment-processing market amid a global shift from cash
to plastic. </p>
<p>Visa Europe split from Visa prior to its initial public
offering in 2008. While purchasing the company could introduce
new risks tied to European Union regulations, it would add about
$1.2 billion to Visa''s annual revenue, Huang wrote. </p>
<p>Visa gained 1 percent to $1.58 at 10:12 a.m. in New York.
The shares are up 4 percent this year. </p>
<p>The deal could cost Visa between $3 billion and $11
billion, according to the Wall Street Journal, which attributed
the information to people familiar with the matter and analysts''
projections. Huang said the deal might cost more than $4.6
billion. </p>
<p>We have a strong and productive relationship with Visa
Europe, Will Valentine, a Visa spokesman, said in a phone
interview. He declined to comment further. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Mar 20, 2013  8:37 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-20/jpmorgan-makes-it-easier-to-fight-payday-lender-abuses.html"><headline>JPMorgan Makes It Easier to Fight Payday-Lender Abuses</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the largest
U.S. bank, is making it easier for customers to fight payday-
lending abuses. </p>
<p>JPMorgan will stop processing multiple requests for payment
on checks that have already been returned due to insufficient
funds when payday lenders and other billers are suspected of
seeking inappropriate payments, the New York-based company
said today in a statement. </p>
<p>The change, which takes effect in May, is intended to
address payday lenders and others who present repeated payments
to customers that are not in the spirit of their signed
agreement with the customer, JPMorgan said in the statement. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Frier" date="Mar 21, 2013  6:01 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-21/ibm-works-for-free-to-build-relationships-with-african-cities.html"><headline>IBM Works for Free to Build Relationships With African Cities</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM), which makes most of its money from high-end technology
contracts, is betting that some of its growth will come from
customers who don''t pay anything -- yet. </p>
<p>The company has developed an application to track the water
system in Tshwane, South Africa, where more than half the
population lives in slums that often aren''t connected to
plumbing. IBM is letting the community use the app for free,
after it sent a team of executives to evaluate the system as
part of a corporate service project in October. </p>
<p>The benefit to IBM is it can use the city as a testing
ground for the application, while gaining favor with the local
government. It also may catch the attention of other cities with
similar problems. Relationships are key to building the
company''s business in Africa, where it now has offices in more
than 20 countries, compared with just four in 2006. </p>
<p>We''re not just walking in and saying, Throw us our
money,'' said Perry Hartswick, an architect of IBM''s Smarter
Planet program, which tries to fix civic problems with tracking
technology. We''re walking in to say we''re here to be a part of
Africa. That''s a very important part of the way we approach any
new geography. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
IBM has deployed almost 100 teams of employees in Africa as part of a corporate-service program, working on everything from infant mortality to cleanliness of water, Chief Executive Officer Ginni Rometty said this month at the Council on Foreign Relations. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jonathan Levin" date="Mar 21, 2013  4:46 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-21/jpmorgan-said-to-hire-former-morgan-stanley-mexico-chief.html"><headline>JPMorgan Said to Hire Former Morgan Stanley Mexico Chief</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) hired Felipe
Garcia-Moreno, the former head of Morgan Stanley''s (MS) Mexico
office, to oversee investment banking and corporate lending in
the country, a person with knowledge of the matter said. </p>
<p>Garcia-Moreno will start on April 1 and be based in Mexico
City, said the person, who asked not to be named because the New
York-based company hasn''t announced the hire publicly. </p>
<p>John Murray, a spokesman for JPMorgan in Mexico, declined
to comment on Garcia-Moreno''s appointment. </p>
<p>Mary Claire Delaney, a Morgan Stanley spokeswoman in New
York, declined to comment on Garcia-Moreno''s move. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jack Kaskey" date="Mar 21, 2013  3:31 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-21/exxon-says-dow-lng-export-plan-would-mean-gas-pr.html"><headline>Exxon Says Dow LNG Export Plan Would Mean Gas Pr</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM), the biggest U.S.
oil producer, said efforts by Dow Chemical Co. (DOW) to limit the
country''s natural gas exports would create a price cap for the
commodity. </p>
<p>Dow is a member of America''s Energy Advantage, a group of
manufacturers and gas distributors that says unfettered exports
of liquefied natural gas may undermine the benefits of rising
output from shale rock. Companies such as Dow want a return to
government controls on gas prices that ended in the 1980s, said
Stephen Pryor, president of Irving, Texas-based Exxon''s chemical
business. </p>
<p>That''s what they are calling for, Pryor said yesterday
in an interview in Houston. It''s basically a price cap. </p>
<p>Dow isn''t seeking a cap, said Kevin Kolevar, the Midland,
Michigan-based company''s vice president for government affairs
and public policy. The Department of Energy needs to consider
effects on manufacturing, consumers and energy security before
approving LNG exports, he said by telephone today. Dow isn''t
calling for gas prices to be a trigger in the decision-making
process, he said. </p>
<p>Exxon is considering exporting U.S. gas from LNG terminals
in Alaska and Texas. Pryor said most studies forecast exports
equal to 5 percent to 15 percent of U.S. gas demand, consistent
with Exxon''s outlook. Production will rise with exports to keep
price increases moderate, he said. He declined to provide a
specific price forecast. </p>
<h2>Public Interest </h2>
<p>We must oppose protectionism in our home countries,
Pryor said yesterday at the IHS World Petrochemical Conference
in Houston. These proposals to block LNG investments,
justified by artificial price caps, represent a selective and
harmful departure from free-market and free-trade principles. </p>
<p>LNG exports may contribute to a gas shortage by 2030 that
would triple prices, according to a study by Charles River
Associates posted on the America''s Energy Advantage website. </p>
<p>Export applications before the DOE would, if approved,
collectively export gas equal to more than half of current U.S.
consumption, Dow''s Kolevar said. While not all those projects
will ultimately proceed, gas demand may still exceed production
later this decade if some are approved without considering the
public interest, something the government is legally bound
to do, he said. </p>
<p>We do have concerns that there is a tipping point at
which LNG exports turn from a net positive for this nation to a
net negative, Kolevar said. The problem is, once you hit
that point, it''s too late to go back. </p>
<p>Dow, which plans to spend $4 billion on new chemical plants
on the Texas coast, uses gas to run its factories and as a raw
material for making plastics and other materials. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Duane D. Stanford" date="Mar 21, 2013 11:55 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-21/coca-cola-to-fire-750-workers-after-paring-distribution-regions.html"><headline>Coca-Cola to Fire 750 Workers After Paring Distribution Regions</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Coca-Cola Co. (KO), the world''s largest
soft drink maker, plans to fire 750 employees in its U.S.
division following a February decision to pare its distribution
regions from seven to three. </p>
<p>The cuts in the coming months will represent about 1
percent of jobs in Coca-Cola''s North American unit, which covers
the U.S. and Canada, Scott Williamson, a spokesman, said today
in an interview. A quarter of the job losses will be in Atlanta,
where Coca-Cola is headquartered, he said. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Muhtar Kent has worked to
restructure distribution in the U.S. since buying the North
American operations of Coca-Cola Enterprises Inc. (CCE) in 2010. Coca-
Cola, which now bottles about 80 percent of its drinks volume
sold in the U.S., said in February it was paring the
distribution regions to improve efficiency and cut costs. </p>
<p>The Coca-Cola Refreshments bottling unit now includes East,
Central and West divisions. </p>
<p>The shares rose 1.3 percent to $40.37 at 11:45 a.m. in New
York. Coca-Cola had gained 10 percent this year through
yesterday compared with a 9.3 percent increase for the Standard
 Poor''s 500 Index. </p>
<p>The job cuts were reported earlier by the Atlanta Journal-
Constitution. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tara Patel" date="Mar 21, 2013  8:55 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-21/exxon-s-unit-halves-2012-dividend-on-french-oil-inventory-tax.html"><headline>Exxon''s Unit Halves 2012 Dividend on French Oil Inventory Tax</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Esso SAF, the French refinery
operator owned by Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM), cut its 2012 dividend in
half because of a tax on oil inventories. </p>
<p>Esso will propose a payout of 2 euros a share compared with
4 euros a share for 2011, according to a statement. The dividend
has dropped steadily from 8.5 euros a share in 2009. </p>
<p>France imposed a one-time 4 percent levy on the value of
fuel inventories held by refiners, distributors and other
businesses last year to raise about 550 million euros ($710
million). The move, part of President Francois Hollande''s bid to
lower the deficit, was criticized by industry lobby Union
Francaise des Industries Petrolieres for hurting the
competitiveness of local refineries. </p>
<p>The tax is unfair and aberrant, Francis Duseux, chief
executive officer of Esso SAF (ES), said today at a press conference
in Paris. We would probably have kept the dividend at the same
level as 2011 if it hadn''t been for the tax. </p>
<p>The tax cost Esso, which operates two refineries in France
as well as a service-station network, 33 million euros last year
while dividend payments for 2012 will amount to 26 million
euros, he said. </p>
<p>The Port-Jerome-Gravenchon refinery halted units with total
capacity of about 70,000 barrels a day, or about a third of the
plant, at the end of February for six or seven weeks of
maintenance, Duseux said. The site had a utilization rate of 74
percent last year, compared with 90 percent at Fos-sur-Mer,
because of maintenance work. </p>
<p>Esso reported a net profit of 63 million euros last year
compared with 46 million euros in 2011, according to the
company. Refining margins averaged 34 euros a metric ton,
ranging from 14 to 63 euros a ton in the period, according to
French environment ministry data. </p>
<p>Esso is seeking to sell its service stations to more
agile operators through a type of franchise system, retaining
supply contracts for 10 years, Duseux said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bryan Bradley" date="Mar 21, 2013  8:05 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-21/chevron-lithuania-shale-gas-deal-delayed-to-may-for-law-changes.html"><headline>Chevron Lithuania Shale-Gas Deal Delayed to May for Law Changes</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Lithuania will wait to sign a
shale-gas exploration agreement with Chevron Corp. (CVX) until
Parliament amends laws to strengthen environmental regulations,
Prime Minister Algirdas Butkevicius said. </p>
<p>We''ll sign the agreement after Parliament adopts the
legislation, which in the best case could be three weeks after
Easter, Butkevicius told reporters today in Vilnius, the
capital. Hopefully in early May we can start getting ready for
actual exploration. </p>
<p>Chevron, a U.S. energy company, last year bought half of
the Lithuanian oil and gas recovery company LL Investicijos and
in January submitted the only bid in a tender for shale-gas
exploration rights in the Baltic nation. Two parliamentary
committees this week urged the government to ban exploration
until laws regulating such activity are strengthened. </p>
<p>Butkevicius said he subsequently agreed with lawmakers that
the government will rush to prepare draft legislation and
parliament will give the matter fast-track treatment. </p>
<p>The main change would be a new requirement for an
environmental impact study of exploration, separate from the
study required for potential later production of any shale gas
that is found. </p>
<p>The delay will let political passions subside and will
give us more time to assuage concerns of residents of the
areas where exploration is planned, he said. In any case, we
have to find out what resources lay beneath our land. </p>
<p>The prime minister said shale gas should get a chapter of
its own in a national energy strategy that the government is
preparing, since it may help reduce dependence on imports of
natural gas from Russia. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christie Smythe" date="Mar 22, 2013  7:49 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-22/morgan-stanley-faces-class-action-bid-in-pinnacle-suit.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Faces Class-Action Bid in Pinnacle Suit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A group of Singapore investors
asked to sue Morgan Stanley (MS) on behalf of all entities that lost
money in synthetic collateralized debt obligations allegedly
rigged to fare poorly. </p>
<p>Singapore Government Staff Credit Cooperative Society Ltd.
and several individuals filed papers today in Manhattan federal
court seeking establish a class of all investors in the CDOs
issued from Aug. 1, 2006, to the end of 2007. </p>
<p>Investors in Morgan Stanley''s Pinnacle Notes lost
$154.7 million reinvested by the bank into CDOs tied to
companies such as Fannie Mae, Freddie Mac, Lehman Brothers
Holdings Inc. and Washington Mutual Inc., plaintiffs alleged in
their lawsuit. Morgan Stanley meanwhile set up a swap that
allowed it to profit when the CDOs failed, according to the
suit. </p>
<p>The crux of the action is that defendants engaged in a
uniform scheme to defraud the Pinnacle Notes investors, the
Singapore plaintiffs said in a court filing today. When the
underlying assets suffered losses, as intended, the investors''
funds were ''swapped'' to defendants. </p>
<p>The Singapore investors filed their suit in October 2010
accusing the bank of fraud, negligent misrepresentation and
other claims. Morgan Stanley is the largest U.S. wealth
management firm by market capitalization. </p>
<p>The case is Dandong v. Pinnacle Performance Ltd., 10-cv-
08086, U.S. District Court, Southern District of New York
(Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Steve Dickson" date="Mar 22, 2013  3:24 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-22/jpmorgan-clawed-back-more-than-100-million-tied-to-cio-loss.html"><headline>JPMorgan Clawed Back More Than $100 Million Tied to CIO Loss</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co., the biggest
U.S. bank, clawed back more than $100 million in compensation
awards from company executives responsible for a $6.2 billion
loss at the chief investment office in London. </p>
<p>JPMorgan invoked comprehensive clawbacks of previously
granted outstanding awards and/or repayment of previously vested
awards subject to clawbacks for those with primary
responsibility, the New York-based bank said today in a
regulatory filing. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Neil Callanan" date="Mar 22, 2013  9:06 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-22/goldman-sachs-wins-approval-for-london-banking-factory-1-.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs'' Wins Approval for London ''Banking Factory''</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) won
approval from the City of London borough council for a plan to
develop an office building that may become its new European
headquarters. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs'' affiliates Farringdon Street Partners Ltd.
and Farringdon Street (Nominee) Ltd. plan to demolish the
existing properties and develop a new Kohn Pedersen Fox-designed
glass-fronted and curved building on the site. Goldman didn''t
immediately return phone calls and an e-mail seeking comment. </p>
<p>The building at 70 Farringdon Street and Shoe Lane will
have about 111,300 square meters (1.2 million square feet) of
internal office space, according to the application letter. It''s
about a minute''s walk from Goldman''s current headquarters
buildings on Fleet Street and construction work is set to
begin almost immediately, City of London planning officer
Peter Rees said at today''s meeting. </p>
<p>It''s a banking factory. Let''s make no bones about it,
Rees told the borough''s members. If there''s an area where
we''re going to accommodate groundscrapers this is probably the
best place, he said. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs, the fifth-biggest U.S. bank by assets, was
given permission in September to move a set of protected murals
from the building, helping to clear the way for the
redevelopment. </p>
<p>The New York-based investment bank''s London Property unit
had assets of 73.7 million pounds ($112 million) through
December 2011 and paid 103.4 million pounds for a development
site last year, according to a filing with Companies House in
August. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Peter Eichenbaum" date="Mar 25, 2013  4:16 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-25/visa-at-new-highs-as-nomura-sees-western-union-value-trap.html"><headline>Visa at New Highs as Nomura Sees Western Union Threats</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Visa Inc. (V) climbed to a record high
after Nomura Holdings Inc. said a long-term global shift away
from cash would help the bank-card network at Western Union
Co.''s expense. </p>
<p>Visa advanced $3.91, or 2.4 percent, to $164 in New York,
the highest since the Foster City, California-based company''s
March 2008 initial public offering. Western Union, the world''s
largest money-transfer business, climbed 2 cents to $14.66 and
has dropped 18 percent in the past year. </p>
<p>Visa continues to thrive in a world of electronic
payments, Bill Carcache and Tulu Yunus, Nomura analysts, said
today in a research note. Threats from Visa and other
established competitors, and new ones such as Xoom Corp. (XOOM), an
online money-transfer firm, will pressure Western Union''s
revenue as demand erodes for its primary business of helping
people send money from agent locations, they wrote. </p>
<p>Worldwide purchases with credit and debit cards are
projected to surpass $21.3 trillion in 2016, a 73 percent
increase from 2011, according to the Nilson Report, an industry
newsletter. Visa, the world''s biggest payments network, posted a
$1.29 billion profit in the fiscal first quarter ended Dec. 31,
a 26 percent increase from a year earlier, as card spending
climbed 8.7 percent. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
Visa Inc., the world''s biggest payments network, posted a $1.29 billion profit in the fiscal first quarter ended Dec. 31, a 26 percent increase from a year earlier, as card spending climbed 8.7 percent. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Emery" date="Mar 25, 2013  2:47 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-25/exxon-apache-looking-to-bid-on-peru-s-offshore-oil-gas-blocks.html"><headline>Exxon, Apache Looking to Bid on Peru''s Offshore Oil, Gas Blocks</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM), Apache Corp. (APA),
and other U.S. companies are looking to acquire offshore blocks
in Peru this year in the country''s first bidding round since
2010, a government official said. </p>
<p>The government will also auction Argentine firm Pluspetrol
SA''s Block 1-AB, Peru''s largest oilfield, as it''s due to expire
in 2015, said Luis Ortigas, president of state oil-contracting
agency Perupetro. State oil company Petroperu will take an
approximate 25 percent stake in all blocks, he said. </p>
<p>Companies have shown increasing interest following
offshore discoveries by BPZ and Savia, Ortigas told reporters
in Lima. We need to increase the number of exploration wells
being drilled to 40 or 50 a year from about six now. </p>
<p>Peru, which produced 173,600 barrels of oil and gas liquids
a day through February, has lined up $20 billion in energy
projects through 2018 in a bid to double oil and gas output,
according to the Energy Ministry. Crude oil output has dropped
20 percent over the past decade as oilfields are depleted. </p>
<p>Alan Jeffers, an Exxon Mobil spokesman, didn''t immediately
repond to telephone calls and e-mails seeking comment. </p>
<p>Apache is always scrutinizing exploration possibilities
worldwide, John Roper, an Apache spokesman, wrote in an e-
mailed response to questions. We don''t publicly discuss what
prospects we are considering or their locations. </p>
<p>Peru plans to put up for bids 36 new oil and gas blocks
after the government completes consultations with indigenous
groups in the highlands and Amazon jungle, Ortigas said. </p>
<p>The government may extend for another 10 years as many as
seven expiring contracts with companies including Interoil
Exploration and Production ASA and China National Petroleum
Corp. in exchange for higher investment, minimum 20 percent
royalties and taking on Petroperu as a partner, he said. </p>
<p>Oil for May delivery rose 89 cents, or 0.9 percent, to
$94.60 a barrel at 12:50 p.m. on the New York Mercantile
Exchange. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Mar 25, 2013  1:22 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-25/goldman-rejects-proposal-that-firm-run-for-elected-office.html"><headline>Goldman Rejects Proposal That Firm Run for Elected Office</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), the
investment bank nicknamed Government Sachs because of senior
executives who have moved into public posts, won''t be entering
politics itself. </p>
<p>A shareholder proposal that the New York-based company run
for office instead of funding political campaigns was discarded,
according to a letter last month from the Securities and
Exchange Commission, which agreed the firm can exclude the
measure from its annual meeting. </p>
<p>Harrington Investments Inc. President John Harrington
submitted the proposal last year, saying the $6.39 million in
2012 political contributions from the firm''s employees risks
doing more harm to its reputation. He said the bank should
explore running for office, using a U.S. Supreme Court ruling
that corporations have similar political rights to individuals. </p>
<p>It would be less damaging to the integrity of our
political system and our company, for our corporation to
directly run for office as a person under federal or state law,
than to continue in the current form of political
participation, Harrington wrote in the proposal. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs said in a letter to the SEC that it
currently has no involvement, never has had any involvement,
and has no plans to become involved in the business of running
for political office. </p>




Photographer: Ralph Orlowski/Bloombeg

<p>
European Central Bank President Mario Draghi is among Goldman Sachs Group Inc. alumni now setting monetary policy. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Anthony Aarons" date="Mar 26, 2013  9:40 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-26/microsoft-sends-eu-report-questioning-google-results.html"><headline>Microsoft Sends EU Report Questioning Google Results</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) consultant
questioned the impartiality of Google Inc. (GOOG)''s search results as
European Union regulators are trying to end an antitrust probe
of the operator of the world''s biggest search engine that is
in its third year. </p>
<p>Internet traffic can be diverted by manipulating the order
of search results, said Susan Athey, a professor of economics at
Stanford University''s Graduate School of Business and a Microsoft
consultant, in a blog post on Microsoft''s website. When a site is
moved from the first position to the 10th position in a series
of search results, it typically will lose about 85 percent of its
traffic, she said. </p>
<p>Impartiality of search results will become all the more
important in the years to come, given that screen sizes on
smartphones and tablets are smaller than on traditional PCs,
Athey said. Smaller screens mean there is even less room for
competing services to appear in Google''s mobile search. </p>
<p>EU Competition Commissioner Joaquin Almunia has sought a
deal with Google to end the antitrust probe without imposing
fines, while competitors such as Microsoft and TripAdvisor Inc. (TRIP)
have tried to pressure regulators to force Mountain View,
California-based Google to change its business practices. The
U.S. ended an investigation into Google in January, saying there
was no evidence the company''s actions harmed consumers. </p>
<p>We continue to work cooperatively with the European
Commission, Al Verney, a Brussels-based Google spokesman, said
in an e-mailed statement. </p>
<p>The EU in 2010 began investigating claims Google
discriminated against other services in its search results and
stopped some websites from accepting competitors'' ads after
receiving complaints from Microsoft and others. </p>
<p>While Microsoft and partner Yahoo! Inc. (YHOO) have about a
quarter of the U.S. Web-search market, Google has almost 95
percent of the traffic in Europe, Microsoft said in a blog post
in 2011, citing data from regulators. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Mar 27, 2013  6:04 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-27/jpmorgan-s-credit-outlook-raised-to-stable-from-negative-by-s-p.html"><headline>JPMorgan Outlook Raised by S&amp;amp;P as London Whale Fades</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), still shaken
by the fallout from last year''s record trading loss, was
upgraded to stable from negative by Standard  Poor''s as the
credit firm''s doubts about the London Whale episode eased. </p>
<p>The bank has successfully addressed our concerns
regarding risk-management missteps in its chief investment
office portfolio, SP said in a statement today about
JPMorgan''s credit outlook. Corrective actions should prevent
additional issues from arising. </p>
<p>Chairman and Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon and other
top executives misled investors and dodged regulators as losses
escalated on a monstrous derivatives bet, according to a
301-page report released this month by the Senate Permanent
Subcommittee on Investigations. Bruno Iksil, the U.K. trader
behind the bets, was nicknamed the London Whale because his
positions were so huge. </p>
<p>The biggest U.S. bank mischaracterized high-risk trading
as hedging, and withheld key information from its primary
regulator, sometimes at Dimon''s behest, investigators found.
Managers manipulated risk models and pressured traders to
overvalue positions to hide growing losses, the panel said. </p>
<p>The Senate probe could help regulators make a case that
JPMorgan executives broke the law, drawing on the report, more
than 90,000 e-mails and documents, 200 transcribed telephone
calls and 25 interviews with bank officials. The report may also
ratchet up pressure on Dimon, 57, to surrender his role as
chairman of the New York-based company to improve governance. </p>




Photographer: Simon Dawson/Bloomberg

<p>
A London taxi passes the offices of JPMorgan Chase  Co. on Victoria Embankment in London. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Mar 28, 2013  6:44 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-28/morgan-stanley-pays-kelleher-fleming-8-6-million-each-for-2012.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Pays Kelleher, Fleming $8.6 Million Each for 2012</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley gave Colm Kelleher
and Greg Fleming, the leaders of its two businesses,
compensation packages of $8.6 million each for 2012, a decline
of 7 percent from a year earlier. </p>
<p>Kelleher, president of the investment banking and trading
division, received $2.41 million of deferred cash in addition to
$2.41 million of options, the New York-based firm said yesterday
in a filing. Fleming, who runs the brokerage and asset-
management unit, was awarded $2.43 million of deferred cash and
$2.43 million of options. Both men got a $3 million long-term
incentive award in addition to their salaries. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s fixed-income trading unit lost market
share in 2012 as clients shied away from trading with the bank
during a credit-rating review by Moody''s Investors Service in
the second quarter. The brokerage division posted a 12 percent
pretax margin, below Chief Executive Officer James Gorman''s
long-term goal of 20 percent. </p>
<p>Still, the firm''s shares jumped 26 percent last year and
profitability improved, excluding accounting charges related to
its own debt. Kelleher, 55, won out over rival Paul J. Taubman
to lead the investment bank, and met goals for reducing risk-
weighted assets in fixed-income trading a year ahead of
schedule. Fleming, 50, boosted the brokerage''s profit margin in
the fourth quarter above his target for the middle of 2013. </p>
<p>I am proud of the work we have done to lay a strong
foundation for Morgan Stanley''s future, Gorman wrote in his
annual letter to shareholders. While we sometimes wish that
markets were faster to recognize our progress, we are pleased
that equity investors appear to have taken notice of our
momentum. </p>
<h2>Almost Doubling </h2>
<p>Gorman, 54, received a package of $9.75 million -- a 7.1
percent decrease from 2011 -- that included a $3.75 million
long-term incentive disclosed in January. His salary is almost
doubling this year to $1.5 million from $800,000 in 2012. </p>
<p>Gorman''s pay, excluding the long-term incentive, was 40
percent below his target for the year, the firm said in a
presentation urging shareholders to approve the pay packages in
an advisory vote. The board''s compensation committee took into
account the firm''s subpar financial performance and its
significant strategic progress in setting the awards,
according to the presentation. </p>
<p>Chief Financial Officer Ruth Porat received $8 million of
total compensation for 2012, compared with $8.75 million a year
earlier. Porat, 55, has informed the White House that she''s no
longer interested in serving as deputy secretary of the U.S.
Treasury Department after being a candidate for the role, people
familiar with the matter said. </p>
<h2>Annual Savings </h2>
<p>Taubman, who has announced plans to leave the firm later
this year, also received $8.6 million. He got the same breakdown
of awards as Fleming in addition to a $750,000 salary. </p>
<p>The bank eliminated 1,700 jobs in January as Gorman pursues
$1.6 billion of annual savings during the next two years. Morgan
Stanley (MS) is deferring all bonuses for employees who have both
total pay of more than $350,000 and incentive compensation of at
least $50,000, a person briefed on the matter said in January. </p>
<p>After reducing our headcount by more than 6,000 since the
end of 2011, we believe our firm is sized appropriately for the
operating and regulatory environment as we currently see it,
Gorman wrote in his letter. The firm had 55,358 employees after
the January cuts, according to a presentation that month. </p>
<p>The bank disclosed that China Investment Corp. cut its
stake in the bank by 25 million shares to 125 million shares.
CIC owned 6.4 percent of Morgan Stanley as of Dec. 31, according
to the filing. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Laura Marcinek" date="Mar 28, 2013  5:58 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-28/jpmorgan-urged-by-ctw-to-change-risk-committee-after-whale-loss.html"><headline>JPMorgan Urged by CtW to Change Risk Committee After Whale Loss</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the biggest
U.S. bank, shouldn''t re-nominate three risk committee members
after disclosing more than $6.2 billion in losses on derivatives
trades last year, CtW Investment Group said. </p>
<p>CtW will oppose the re-election of David Cote, Ellen Futter
and committee Chairman James Crown because they lack
professional experience relevant to overseeing risk management
at a large financial institution that undertakes significant
trading activity, the investment firm said today in a letter
to New York-based JPMorgan. </p>
<p>The so-called London Whale trades were the subject of a
report this month by the U.S. Senate Permanent Subcommittee on
Investigations, which found that Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon, 57, misled investors and dodged regulators as the losses
mounted. The bank piled on risk and ignored limits on
risk-taking, said committee Chairman Carl Levin, a Michigan
Democrat. </p>
<p>Both regulators and JPMorgan Chase senior executives
recognize that serious deficiencies in risk-management practices
and internal controls have existed for some time and require
prompt corrective action, CtW wrote in the letter. </p>
<p>Cote, 60, is chairman and CEO of Honeywell International
Inc. (HON), and Crown, 59, is president of Chicago-based Henry Crown 
Co. and lead director of defense contractor General Dynamics
Corp. (GD) Futter, 63, a former president of Barnard College in New
York, joined JPMorgan''s board in 1997. </p>
<p>Joe Evangelisti, a JPMorgan spokesman, declined to comment
on the letter. Rob Ferris, a spokesman for Cote at Honeywell,
didn''t immediately comment. Futter and Crown didn''t immediately
return messages seeking comment. </p>
<p>In August, JPMorgan assigned former KPMG International
Chairman Timothy Flynn to its risk committee after an internal
probe blamed lax controls for the trading loss. </p>
<p>The Wall Street Journal reported on CtW''s letter earlier
today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hans Nichols and Michael Moore" date="Mar 28, 2013 12:59 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-28/morgan-stanley-s-porat-no-longer-interested-in-treasury-post.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley''s Porat No Longer Interested in Treasury Post</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Ruth Porat, chief financial officer
at Morgan Stanley (MS), has informed the White House that she is no
longer interested in serving as deputy Treasury secretary,
according to two people familiar with the matter. </p>
<p>As one of the highest-ranking women on Wall Street, Porat''s
decision was influenced by the improving conditions at Morgan
Stanley and the acrimonious confirmation process of Treasury
Secretary Jack Lew, said the people, who requested anonymity to
discuss personnel matters. </p>
<p>Lew was confirmed for his post 71-26 after facing questions
about his compensation from New York University and a bonus
payment he received while working at Citigroup Inc. (C) at the time
the bank was receiving federal bailout funds. </p>
<p>Porat was awarded $8.75 million in compensation for 2011,
and $11.5 million for 2010, according to company filings. </p>
<p>The White House declined to comment. </p>
<p>Porat''s decision will force the Obama administration to
restart its search, giving other potential candidates, including
those with financial services backgrounds, an opportunity to
join the Treasury Department. In December, before Porat became
the leading candidate, Blair Effron, a partner and co-founder of
Centerview Partners LLP, and Ralph Schlosstein, chief executive
officer at Evercore Partners Inc. (EVR), had been considered for the
post, said one of the people. </p>




Photographer: Jin Lee/Bloomberg

<p>
Morgan Stanley Chief Financial Officer Ruth Porat''s decision will force the Obama administration to restart the search process, giving other potential candidates, including those with financial services background, an opportunity to join the Treasury department. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Naureen S. Malik" date="Mar 31, 2013  5:36 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-03-31/exxon-to-excavate-pegasus-crude-pipeline-to-find-cause-of-leak.html"><headline>Exxon to Excavate Pegasus Crude Pipeline to Find Cause of Leak</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM)''s Pegasus crude
oil pipeline, which was shut on March 29 after a leak was
detected in Arkansas, will need to be excavated as the company
looks to determine what caused the breach, a spokeswoman said. </p>
<p>I can''t speculate on when excavation will happen,
Kimberly Brasington, a spokeswoman for the company, said in an
e-mail. Excavation is necessary as part of an investigation to
determine the cause of the incident. </p>
<p>The 20-inch pipeline, which originates in Patoka, Illinois,
and carries crude oil to the Texas Gulf Coast, was carrying
Wabasca Heavy Crude from Western Canada, she said. </p>
<p>About 12,000 barrels of oil and water have been collected
so far near Mayflower, Arkansas, after a few thousand barrels
were observed in the area, the Mayflower Incident Unified
Command Joint Information Center, which includes Exxon, Faulkner
County and the city of Mayflower, said in a statement today. </p>
<p>The U.S. Environmental Protection Agency classifies any
spill of more than 250 barrels as a major spill, the command
said. </p>
<p>Crews are steam-cleaning oil from property, according
to the joint statement. No oil has reached Lake Conway, and
clean-up crews have deployed 3,600 feet of boom as a precaution,
the command said. </p>




Photographer: Jeff Kowalsky/Bloomberg

<p>
Exxon Mobil Corp.''s Pegasus crude oil pipeline, which originates in Patoka, Illinois, and carries crude oil to the Texas Gulf Coast, was carrying Wabasca Heavy Crude from Western Canada. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry></news>