
<news><entry author="By Nariman Gizitdinov" date="May 24, 2007  8:46 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-05-24/chevron-to-sell-gas-to-kazakh-petrochemical-complex-update2-.html"><headline>Chevron to Sell Gas to Kazakh Petrochemical Complex</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A Chevron Corp. (CVX) unit that produces
about a quarter of Kazakhstan''s oil will provide 7 billion cubic
meters of gas a year to the country''s first ''''world-scale''''
petrochemical complex when it opens in 2011. </p>
<p>The Chevron unit, Tengizchevroil LLP, and Kazakhstan
Petrochemical Industries signed an agreement today to supply gas
from the Tengiz field to the petrochemical complex planned in
western Kazakhstan, the state-run news agency Kazinform reported
from Atyrau. </p>
<p>''''The memorandum of understanding is an important milestone
in our discussions with Kazakhstan Petrochemical Industries, a
demonstration of the progress made,'''' Tengizchevroil said by an
e-mail. </p>
<p>''''Tengizchevroil and KPI have worked to outline terms for
the sales of feedstock to KPI for their planned petrochemical
facilities,'''' Chevron''s venture said. It gave no financial
details of the agreement. </p>
<p>Kazakhstan Petrochemical Industries is a venture between a
publicly traded subsidiary of KazMunaiGaz National Co., the
state-owned oil and gas company, and Sat  Co., a privately
owned Kazakh industrial company. </p>
<h2>Tengizchevroil''s Supplies </h2>
<p>Tengizchevroil will supply 7 billion cubic meters of dry
gas and 550,000 tons of liquid propane to the plant, Shukhrat
Danbay, KazMunaiGaz National''s executive director of refining
and petrochemicals, said in a phone interview today. The complex
will be built in 2010 and 2011, and it will buy gas at an
''''acceptable price,'''' he said. </p>
<p>The petrochemical complex will include refineries to
process gas from the Tengiz field, and later from the Kashagan
and Karachaganak fields, all of which are being developed by
foreign-led ventures. Basell Holdings NV, the world''s largest
producer of polypropylene, used to make car fenders, will help
build and manage the refineries. </p>
<p>The partners also have an agreement with an Eni SpA-led
group to provide supplies of 3 billion cubic meters of dry gas
from the Kashagan field, according to the Energy Ministry''s May
17 statement. Eni expects to start production in 2010 at
Kashagan, the largest discovery worldwide in the past 30 years. </p>
<p>Chevron''s venture plans to nearly double oil production to
550,000 barrels a day after building a $5.5 billion gas-processing plant and gas-injection system for oil extraction in
2008, TengizChevroil said in January. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry></news>