<?xml version='1.0' encoding='us-ascii'?>
<news><entry author="By Daniela Silberstein" date="Jan 21, 2009  5:19 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-01-21/u-s-stock-index-futures-rise-citigroup-ibm-advance-in-europe.html"><headline>U.S. Stock-Index Futures Rise; Citigroup, IBM Advance in Europe</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;U.S. stock-index futures gained,
indicating the Standard  Poor&#8217;s 500 Index will rebound from a
two-month low, on speculation a bank-rescue plan from President
Barack Obama will boost financial companies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citigroup Inc. (C) and Bank of America Corp (BAC), the biggest U.S.
banks by assets, rose more than 2 percent in Germany.
International Business Machines Corp. (IBM) climbed 4 percent after its
2009 profit forecast topped analysts&#8217; estimates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;U.S. stocks sank yesterday, sending the Dow Jones Industrial
Average to its worst Inauguration Day decline, as speculation
banks must raise more capital pushed financial shares to an
almost 14-year low. The SP 500 is off to its worst start to a
year, shattering the biggest rally since World War II as analysts
cut earnings estimates by a record 83 percentage points and
companies signal worse to come. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Obama&#8217;s plan is a pacifier,&#8221; said Roger Kunz, head of
investment strategy at Clariden Leu in Zurich, which has about
$120 billion in assets. &#8220;The optimism of Americans is a plus and
an opportunity to get the situation under control but we have to
give him some time.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Futures on the SP 500 (SPX) expiring in March rose 0.3 percent to
808.1 at 10:17 a.m. in London. Dow futures added 0.2 percent to
7,964. Nasdaq-100 Index futures fell 0.1 percent to 1,146.25. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe&#8217;s Dow Jones Stoxx 600 Index dropped 2.1 percent, led
by financial companies amid speculation banks may need to raise
more capital. The MSCI Asia Pacific Index (MXAP) slid 1.9 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bank Rescue &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obama meets with his economic advisers today. The new
president&#8217;s team is pushing to complete a bank-rescue plan that
can be twinned with the $825 billion stimulus package being
negotiated with Congress to alleviate the deepening financial
crisis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While full details of the rescue haven&#8217;t been settled yet,
people familiar with the deliberations said the package is likely
to include a $50 billion-plus program to stem foreclosures, fresh
injections of capital into the banks and steps to deal with toxic
assets clogging lenders&#8217; balance sheets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citigroup, the U.S. bank that received a government-backed
capital injection of $20 billion in November, surged 4.3 percent
to $2.92. Bank of America, the biggest U.S. lender by assets,
rose 2.4 percent to $5.22. JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) advanced 2.9
percent to $18.62 in Europe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM added 4 percent to $85.25. The biggest computer-services provider posted fourth-quarter profit of $4.43 billion,
or $3.28 a share, surpassing analysts&#8217; estimates, as the top
provider of computer services coped with a worldwide technology
slump by cutting overhead costs and adding products. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forest Laboratories Inc. (FRX) fell 2.1 percent to $24.99. Goldman
Sachs group Inc. downgraded the drugmaker to &#8220;sell&#8221; from
&#8220;neutral.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ford Motor Co. (F), the second-largest U.S. automaker, added 1.4
percent to $2.16 and Lear Corp. (LEA), the world&#8217;s second-largest maker
of automotive seats, rallied 5.7 percent to $1.12 in Europe. The
two companies were upgraded to &#8220;hold&#8221; from &#8220;sell&#8217; at Deutsche
Bank AG. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investors will also watch a report on mortgage applications
scheduled for 7 a.m. in Washington today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Daniela Silberstein in Zurich at 
dsilberstei2@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Daniel Hauck at  dhauck1@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Alexander Ragir" date="Jan 27, 2009 12:42 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-01-27/buy-mexico-puts-on-u-s-slowdown-oil-reliance-goldman-says.html"><headline>Buy Mexico Puts on U.S. Slowdown, Oil Reliance, Goldman Says</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Investors should take advantage of
Mexico&#8217;s &#8220;sensitivity&#8221; to U.S. growth and oil prices by buying
put options in the country&#8217;s U.S.-traded stock index while
selling Brazilian puts, Goldman Sachs Group Inc. said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman Sachs strategists recommended buying June $26 puts
on iShares MSCI Mexico Investable Market Index Fund while selling
June $26 puts for iShares MSCI Brazil Index Fund. Brazil&#8217;s U.S.-
traded index has fallen 53 percent over the past year, while the
exchange-traded fund for Mexico slid 46 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Our economists see a challenging 2009 outlook for Brazil
and Mexico as commodity prices and demand for non-commodity
exports weaken and capital flows slow,&#8221; New York-based
derivatives strategist Stuart Kaiser wrote in a note. &#8220;However,
Brazil is much better positioned to mitigate the impact of these
external shocks given less reliance on foreign trade and stronger
cyclical position at the start of the crisis.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mexico will enter a recession this year, while Brazil&#8217;s
economy may grow 1.25 percent, said Goldman Sachs. Oil prices are
51 percent lower than a year ago and Mexico relies on Petroleos
Mexicanos, the state-owned oil company, for 40 percent of its
budget. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mexican Finance Minister Agustin Carstens said on Jan. 9
that the economy will contract in the first half of this year and
have no growth in 2009. Brazil&#8217;s economy will expand 2 percent
this year, according to the median forecast in a central bank
survey published yesterday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investors should buy March $12.50/$17.50 put spreads on NII
Holdings Inc., the provider of mobile-phone services in Latin
America, to &#8220;hedge&#8221; against slowing growth in the region,
according to the Goldman note dated today. The bank advised
buying April $15 puts on Brazil&#8217;s Empresa Brasileira de
Aeronautica SA, the world&#8217;s fourth-largest aircraft maker. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Real May Gain &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trading these ETFs, denominated in dollars, is also a bet
that the Brazilian real will outperform the Mexican peso the next
six months, the strategist wrote. Puts give the right to sell a
security for a certain amount, the strike price, by a given date. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brazil&#8217;s real fell 32 percent against the dollar in the past
six months, while the peso dropped 28 percent, according to
Bloomberg data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Alexander Ragir in Rio de Janeiro at 
aragir@bloomberg.net; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
David Papadopoulos at 
papadopoulos@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Elizabeth Amon" date="Jan 27, 2009  7:13 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-01-27/madoff-dow-socgen-dupont-pfizer-in-court-news-update1-.html"><headline>Madoff, Dow, SocGen, DuPont, Pfizer in Court News</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;PricewaterhouseCoopers LLP and Citco
Group Ltd. were sued by a Texas-based trust for their respective
roles as auditor and administrator of a feeder fund that invested
almost all its holdings with alleged fraudster Bernard Madoff. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Philip Stephenson Revocable Living Trust in April
invested $60 million with Greenwich Sentry LP, according to the
complaint filed yesterday in federal court in New York. Greenwich
Sentry is a fund of Fairfield Greenwich Group, Walter Noel&#8217;s
hedge-fund firm that had $7.5 billion with Madoff. Madoff was
arrested Dec. 11 after he allegedly admitted to running a
$50 billion Ponzi scheme. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trust&#8217;s &#8220;investment has been essentially, and
unnecessarily (but for the failures of defendants), wiped out,&#8221;
trustee G. Philip Stephenson wrote in the complaint. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Madoff, 70, was charged with one count of securities fraud
for allegedly using billions of dollars from new investors to pay
off older ones. He told authorities that investors may have lost
$50 billion, U.S. prosecutors said. He hasn&#8217;t yet formally
responded to the charge. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Madoff, Greenwich Sentry and Fairfield Greenwich aren&#8217;t
named as defendants in the case. The trust is asking for
compensatory and triple punitive damages. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The suit names as a defendant Pricewaterhouse&#8217;s Ontario
partnership. Carolyn Forest, a spokeswoman for the auditing firm
in Canada, didn&#8217;t return a call for comment. A message left at
Citco (Canada) Inc., also a defendant, wasn&#8217;t immediately
returned. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Stephenson v. Citco Group Ltd., 09-cv-716, U.S.
District Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dow Chemical Sued by Rohm  Haas Over Delayed $15 Billion Union &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rohm  Haas Co. sued Dow Chemical Co. claiming the company
breached a merger agreement and should be forced to complete a
planned $15.4 billion acquisition. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dow Chemical confirmed yesterday that it won&#8217;t close the
proposed acquisition on or before yesterday as required by the
merger accord. The company cited &#8220;uncertainties&#8221; in funding as
a result of the global financial crisis. Rohm  Haas&#8217;s complaint,
filed yesterday in Delaware Chancery Court in Wilmington, seeks a
judge&#8217;s order to enforce the buyout. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Dow&#8217;s obligation to complete the merger is not conditioned
on financing of any kind,&#8221; Rohm  Haas said in the complaint.
&#8220;Dow&#8217;s refusal to close, therefore, is without any legal
justification.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The merger agreement requires that Midland, Michigan-based
Dow Chemical close the deal by yesterday now that all required
regulatory approvals have been received, Philadelphia-based Rohm
 Haas said yesterday in a statement. Dow Chemical cited a
decision by the Kuwait government canceling a planned $9 billion
joint venture last month as a reason for the delay. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;The failure of the K-Dow venture does not provide Dow with
a basis for refusing to close,&#8221; lawyers for Rohm  Haas alleged
in the lawsuit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Rohm and Haas Co. v. Dow Chemical Co. CA4309,
Delaware Chancery Court (Wilmington). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To read more of this story, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Citibank Sued Over &#8216;Illegal&#8217; Reduction of Home Credit Loans &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citigroup Inc., the bank that received $45 billion in U.S.
government funds, was sued over claims it illegally reduced
credit limits of loans made against homes to shield itself from
the declining U.S. housing market. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lawsuit was brought by David Levin and seeks class-action, or group, status for people who took the home-equity
lines of credit from Citibank, a unit of New York-based
Citigroup. The company reduced credit lines for borrowers whose
homes hadn&#8217;t significantly declined in value, according to the
complaint that Levin&#8217;s lawyer, Jay Edelson, said he filed
yesterday in federal court in Oakland, California. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Royal Bank of Canada Sued Over Collapse of Olympus United Funds &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Royal Bank of Canada, the country&#8217;s biggest bank by assets,
was sued by investors in Olympus United Funds who claim they lost
more than $90 million in the funds&#8217; collapse. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Royal Bank, based in Toronto, &#8220;secretly managed&#8221; the
funds, according to a complaint filed Jan. 23 in U.S. District
Court in Manhattan. The funds&#8217; parent company Norshield Financial
Group filed for receivership in June 2005 amid probes by
securities regulators. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;In its dealings and relationships with Norshield, Royal
Bank of Canada (RY) assumed control of investments, exercised
discretion in key areas and thus became liable for my clients&#8217;
losses,&#8221; Lee Squitieri, a lawyer for the investors, said in an
interview. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defendants allegedly overstated the funds&#8217; assets, breached
their fiduciary duties to investors, committed fraud and
misrepresented material facts, the investors said in the
complaint. They seek unspecified damages. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jackie Braden, a spokeswoman for Royal Bank, didn&#8217;t respond
to an e-mail and phone call requesting comment. Among the
investors suing are Balanced Return Fund Ltd., Mendota Capital
and Commax Investors Services Ltd. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Squitieri filed an identical lawsuit last May, he said. The
parties agreed to resolve the matter privately, after which he
withdrew the suit with the option to refile it later, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;We did not reach a satisfactory resolution,&#8221; Squitieri
said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Balanced Return Fund v. Royal Bank, 09-cv-695,
U.S. District Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more new suits news from yesterday, click here. For copies of
recent civil complaints, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Litigation/Pretrial &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Kerviel Probe Is Completed by French Judges, Prosecutor Says &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paris judges finished an investigation into Jerome Kerviel,
blamed last year by Societe Generale SA (GLE) for its record
4.9 billion euro ($6.4 billion) trading loss, a spokeswoman for
prosecutors said yesterday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The judges &#8220;transmitted the file to the prosecutors this
afternoon,&#8221; Isabelle Montagne, a spokeswoman for the Paris
prosecutors&#8217; office said in a telephone interview. She declined
to comment on the contents of the report. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kerviel is under investigation for breach of trust,
falsifying documents and hacking into the bank&#8217;s computers. He
has admitted to lying, faking authorizations and using others&#8217;
logins and computers. He said he gained nothing for himself,
which the bank hasn&#8217;t disputed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The prosecutors will have &#8220;several months&#8221; to review the
report by Montagne said. Kerviel and his former assistant, Thomas Mougard, remain the only two named defendants in the probe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 32-year-old Kerviel met with judges Renaud Van Ruymbeke
and Francoise Desset, for a final time on Jan. 22. He asked them
to continue investigating his assertion that Societe Generale
knew of his trading activities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lawyers for the bank and the two men didn&#8217;t return calls for
comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more lawsuits news from yesterday, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Trials/Appeals &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Worker Retaliation Suits Allowed by U.S. High Court &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Supreme Court ruled that federal law protects
workers from retaliation after they cooperate with an employer&#8217;s
investigation into allegations of harassment or discrimination. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The justices yesterday unanimously allowed a retaliation
lawsuit by a woman who was fired as head of a Tennessee school
district&#8217;s payroll division after telling human resources
officials that a coworker had engaged in lewd behavior. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ruling reaffirms worker protections now in place in most
of the U.S. and overturns a lower court ruling that had afforded
more limited employee rights. Yesterday&#8217;s decision is a setback
for business groups, including the U.S. Chamber of Commerce,
which urged tighter restrictions on worker lawsuits. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vicky S. Crawford was fired in January 2003, several months
after she met with in-house investigators looking into
allegations that the school district&#8217;s employee relations
director, Gene Hughes, had harassed other women in the office. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crawford says she and two other women told the investigators
that Hughes had made a number of sexually explicit comments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crawford&#8217;s former employer, the Metropolitan Government of
Nashville and Davidson County, said it fired her upon discovering
numerous improprieties, including the mishandling of employee
contributions to retirement plans and her failure to file timely
tax returns. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Crawford v. Metropolitan Government, 06-1595,
U.S. Supreme Court (Washington). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;DuPont Rejected by U.S. Supreme Court on Pension Plan Challenge &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Supreme Court rejected an appeal by DuPont Co. (DD),
clearing the way for a union challenge to changes the chemical
company made in 2006 to cut the costs of its retirement benefits. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The justices, without comment, left intact a ruling favoring
a union that represents 1,000 workers at a DuPont fibers plant in
Richmond, Virginia. A federal appeals court said the union could
press ahead before an arbitrator with its complaint that the
changes violate a collective bargaining agreement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DuPont announced the changes in August 2006, saying they
would boost per-share profit by 3 cents in 2007 and 5 cents in
2008. The plan called for tens of thousands of workers to be
shifted out of traditional pensions and into 401(k) plans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steelworker unions representing workers in Delaware, New
Jersey and New York are also challenging the changes in separate
litigation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is E.I. du Pont de Nemours v. Ampthill Rayon
Workers, 08-699, U.S. Supreme Court (Washington). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;USEC, U.S. Government Win Supreme Court Uranium Fight &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Supreme Court, ruling in favor of American nuclear
fuel producer USEC Inc. (USU), upheld antidumping duties imposed by the
Bush administration in 2002 on enriched uranium imported by
France&#8217;s Areva SA. (AREVA) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The justices unanimously rejected Area&#8217;s contentions that
U.S. antidumping law doesn&#8217;t apply because the company provides
enrichment services, rather than a product. U.S. nuclear power
companies backed Areva in the case, as did Alcoa Inc. (AA), perhaps
the country&#8217;s largest nongovernmental consumer of electricity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decision overturns a ruling that the Bush administration
had said &#8220;threatened the ongoing economic viability of USEC,&#8221;
the only U.S. company that enriches uranium. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Commerce Department concluded in 2001 that Areva, the
world&#8217;s largest maker of nuclear reactors, was selling enriched
uranium in the U.S. at less than fair value. The following year,
the U.S. International Trade Commission said that Areva&#8217;s actions
were harming USEC, clearing the way for the Commerce Department
to impose an import duty. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Court of International Trade then overturned the ITC
ruling, and the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit in
Washington agreed with that conclusion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is United States v. Eurodif, 07-1059, and USEC v.
Eurodif, 07-1078, U.S. Supreme Court (Washington). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To read more of this story, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more trial and appeals news from yesterday, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Verdicts/Settlements &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pfizer to Pay Record $2.3 Billion to Settle U.S. Drug Probe &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer Inc. (PFE), the world&#8217;s largest drugmaker, took a
$2.3 billion charge for a record settlement of U.S.
investigations into improper marketing of its Bextra painkiller
and other drugs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer reached an agreement with the U.S. Attorney in
Massachusetts to &#8220;resolve previously disclosed investigations&#8221;
regarding Bextra and &#8220;other open investigations,&#8221; the New York-based company said yesterday in a statement. Pfizer didn&#8217;t
disclose details. Pfizer&#8217;s earnings dropped 90 percent because of
the charge taken in the fourth quarter, the company said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The settlement is the largest for claims of off-label
marketing practices, dwarfing the previous record of
$1.42 billion paid earlier this month by Eli Lilly  Co. (LLY) over its
antipsychotic drug Zyprexa, said Patrick Burns of Taxpayers
Against Fraud, a Washington advocacy group. The settlement
foreshadows resolutions of other pending claims against other
drugmakers, Burns said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer spokesmen Christopher Loder and Ray Kerins didn&#8217;t
return calls for comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christina DiIorio-Sterling, spokeswoman for Michael Sullivan, the U.S. Attorney for Massachusetts, declined to
comment. &#8220;We&#8217;re not even confirming that there was a
settlement,&#8221; she said in a telephone interview. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To read more of this story, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ex-Peregrine Systems Vice President Pleads Guilty to Wire Fraud &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A former Peregrine Systems Inc. vice president, accused of
participating in the fraud that destroyed the software company
once valued at $4.72 billion, changed his plea to guilty six
weeks before he was scheduled for trial. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeremy R. Crook, 55, pleaded guilty to one count of wire
fraud, according to an e-mailed statement from Debra Hartman,
spokeswoman for U.S. Attorney Karen Hewitt in San Diego. Crook&#8217;s
sentencing is scheduled for May 4. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Crook admitted that, in order to inflate the company&#8217;s
revenues, he participated with other Peregrine executives in the
fraudulent booking of revenue from a proposed 10 million pound
transaction with British Telecom Plc,&#8221; according to the
statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prosecutors charged 18 people in a multimillion-dollar
accounting scam to falsely inflate profits and boost Peregrine&#8217;s
stock that sent the company into bankruptcy in 2002. Fourteen
have now pleaded guilty, including former Chief Executive Officer
Stephen Gardner, former President Gary L. Lenz and former Chief
Financial Officer Matt Gless. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Benjamin L. Coleman, a lawyer for Crook at San Diego&#8217;s
Coleman  Balogh LLP, declined to comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is U.S. v. Gardner, 04-cr-2605, U.S. District
Court, Southern District of California (San Diego). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Zumwinkel to Pay EU1 Million; Gets Suspended Sentence &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Former Deutsche Post AG (DPW) Chief Executive Officer Klaus Zumwinkel received a two-year suspended sentence and must pay a
1 million-euro ($1.29 million) penalty after a German court
convicted him in a tax evasion scandal involving Liechtenstein. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zumwinkel, 65, &#8220;knowingly, meticulously, enduringly and,
thus, criminally evaded taxes,&#8221; Presiding Judge Wolfgang Mittrup
said yesterday when delivering the verdict. Part of the
1 million-euro penalty must be paid to charities, the judge said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zumwinkel confessed last week to charges that he avoided
about 970,000 euros ($1.3 million) in taxes by depositing money
in a foundation in Liechtenstein without declaring the proceeds
as income. The case, which featured Zumwinkel&#8217;s arrest at his
home broadcast live on television, is one of hundreds involving
German residents&#8217; use of Liechtenstein accounts to avoid taxes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sentence is the same as that sought by the prosecution.
Zumwinkel&#8217;s defense attorney, Hanns Feigen, had asked the court
to impose a &#8220;considerably&#8221; lower sentence. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is LG Bochum, 12 KLs 350 Js. 1/08. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more verdict and settlement news from yesterday, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Litigation Departments &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Former Howrey Law Firm Chair Joins Axinn, Veltrop  Harkrider &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John DeQ Briggs, a former chairman of law firm Howrey LLP&#8217;s
antitrust group, moved to Axinn, Veltrop  Harkrider LLP as
managing partner of the firm&#8217;s office in Washington. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Briggs is a trial lawyer with experience in monopolization
cases, merger clearance, class actions, price discrimination
litigation and antitrust issues in intellectual property claims,
Axinn, Veltrop  Harkrider said in an e-mailed statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more litigation department news from yesterday, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;On the Docket &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Evraz Goes to Court to Challenge Coking-Coal Antitrust Fines &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Evraz Group SA, Russia&#8217;s second-largest steelmaker, has
filed a court challenge to antitrust fines on coking-coal sales
and an order to reduce prices for the steelmaking ingredient. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Moscow arbitration court will hear the case Feb. 6,
Russia&#8217;s Federal Antimonopoly Service said yesterday on its Web
site. Evraz paid 149 million rubles ($4.5 million) in fines,
lowered coal prices and signed long-term contracts with major
buyers after an investigation found that the company had abused
its market position, the watchdog said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bloomberg Law Reports &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Minimizing Discovery Costs: Federal Rule of Evidence 502 &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scope of the new Federal Rule of Evidence 502 is the
focus of an article in the Bloomberg Weekly Litigation Report by
three Jenner  Block lawyers. David M. Greenwald, co-chair of the
firm&#8217;s reinsurance practice, commercial litigators Robert R.
Stauffer and Erin R. Schrantz discuss the ways in which lawyers
can use the rule to minimized cost and avoid pitfalls. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;The adoption of Rule 502 provides an excellent opportunity
for counsel to work with their clients at the outset of
litigation to conduct a cost-benefit analysis of various
discovery approaches, including use of iterative privilege search
protocols and quality assurance testing in lieu of document-by-document review,&#8221; they write. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To read more of &#8220;New Federal Rule of Evidence 502: A Tool
for Minimizing the Cost of Discovery&#8221; and the entire Weekly
Litigation Report, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Bloomberg articles by lawyers on litigation topics, click
here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For news about bankruptcy litigation, click here. For news about
intellectual property litigation, click here. For news about
securities and compliance litigation, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Elizabeth Amon in Brooklyn, New York, at 
eamon2@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
David E. Rovella at  drovella@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Dermot Doherty and Caroline Hyde" date="Jan 30, 2009  1:32 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-01-30/roche-in-talks-with-citigroup-jpmorgan-ubs-socgen-for-debt.html"><headline>Roche in Talks With Citigroup, JPMorgan, UBS, SocGen for Debt</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Roche Holding AG (ROG) is in talks with at
least four banks to finance its hostile takeover bid for
Genentech Inc., according to people involved in the negotiations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The banks include Citigroup Inc., JPMorgan Chase  Co., UBS
AG and Societe Generale SA, said the people, who declined to be
identified because no agreement has been reached. Roche said the
transaction would be financed with a mixture of cash in hand,
commercial paper, bonds and bank loans. The Basel, Switzerland-based pharmaceutical company&#8217;s bid comes as Pfizer Inc. (PFE) borrows a
$22.5 billion 364-day bridge loan from five banks to help fund
its Wyeth purchase. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;It&#8217;s impressive that Roche has been able to launch a
hostile bid for Genentech in this environment and demonstrates
that the banking markets have improved,&#8221; said Philip Keevil,
senior partner at London-based financial advisory firm Compass
Advisers LLP. Pfizer&#8217;s loan &#8220;may have acted as some sort of
catalyst&#8221; for a Roche financing, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roche is making a $86.50-a-share bid for Genentech after six
months of talks with the U.S. developer of the cancer drug
Avastin failed. The offer is subject to the financing being
provided and the majority of outstanding shares being tendered.
The Swiss pharmaceuticals company already owns 55.8 percent of
Genentech. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer&#8217;s takeover of Wyeth had no influence on the decision
to pursue a hostile bid for Genentech, Roche Chairman Franz B. Humer said on a conference call, adding that he&#8217;s &#8220;confident&#8221;
of getting the funding to back the bid. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporters on this story:
Dermot Doherty in Geneva at 
ddoherty9@bloomberg.net;
Caroline Hyde in London 
chyde3@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Paul Armstrong at 
Parmstrong10@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry></news>