
<news><entry author="By Jonathan Weil" date="Mar 03, 2010  9:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-03-03/goldman-s-reputation-is-blankfein-s-job-no-1-jonathan-weil.html"><headline>Goldman''s Reputation Is Blankfein''s Job No. 1: Jonathan Weil</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Bashing Goldman Sachs Group Inc. has
been elevated from a national pastime to something far more
serious: a bona fide threat to the company''s operations. Don''t
just take my word for it, though. We have it from Wall Street''s
highest authority. That would be Goldman Sachs itself. </p>
<p>Among the new items in the investment bank''s latest annual
report is a 219-word risk-factor disclosure, cautioning that the
constant drumbeat of criticism is taking its toll. This isn''t to
say Goldman is acknowledging there might be something wrong with
the way it does business. That would be a wholly unnatural act. </p>
<p>Rather, the problem as identified by Goldman is the way
other people have chosen to respond to its existence. So many
critics are popping off in the press. So many government
investigations are being launched in response. And there''s so
little precious time for Goldman''s leaders to deal with it all. </p>
<p>The financial crisis and the current political and public
sentiment regarding financial institutions has resulted in a
significant amount of adverse press coverage, as well as adverse
statements or charges by regulators or elected officials,
Goldman said in the annual report it filed March 1. </p>
<p>Press coverage and other public statements that assert
some form of wrongdoing, regardless of the factual basis for the
assertions being made, often results in some type of
investigation by regulators, legislators and law enforcement
officials or in lawsuits. </p>
<p>Responding to such matters is time consuming and
expensive and can divert the time and effort of our senior
management from our business, Goldman said. It concluded by
saying: Adverse publicity, governmental scrutiny and legal and
enforcement proceedings can also have a negative impact on our
reputation and on the morale and performance of our employees,
which could adversely affect our businesses and results of
operations. </p>
<p>Thanks, Guys </p>
<p>With that disclosure, wittingly or not, Goldman''s
management team paid the news media the highest possible
compliment, while simultaneously admitting a major failure of
its own. The message for the press is: How flattering! Goldman
says we matter! For Goldman Chief Executive Officer Lloyd Blankfein, it''s this: My bank, on my watch, has let its good
name be put in danger. </p>
<p>A Goldman spokesman, Ed Canaday, declined to comment. </p>
<p>While commercial brilliance and a rising stock price have
their place, the paramount job of the people who run Goldman is
to protect the firm''s reputational value. Take away the public''s
trust, and there would be no Goldman: Counterparties wouldn''t
trade with it, governments and corporations wouldn''t hire it,
and talented people wouldn''t work for it. </p>
<p>Gray Matter </p>
<p>Goldman, which earned $13.4 billion last year and paid its
employees $16.2 billion, used to receive the benefit of a doubt
from the public when its conduct came into question. Nowadays,
it''s the gray areas that often generate the most outrage. </p>
<p>Is Goldman to blame for helping Greece mask some of its
debt? Nowhere near as much as the Greek government is, but the
work Goldman performed looks dodgy anyway. Did Goldman force the
U.S. government to bail out American International Group Inc.?
No, but Goldman benefited just the same when AIG used taxpayer
money to pay the obligations it owed Goldman at 100 cents on the
dollar. </p>
<p>Was Goldman running the Treasury Department when its former
CEO, Hank Paulson, was in charge there? Officially, no; however,
it sure did seem that way at times. Does Goldman manipulate
markets or front-run its customers'' trades? While there hasn''t
been any proof it does, it certainly could were it so inclined. </p>
<p>Too Much, Too Soon </p>
<p>Ultimately, what bothers the general public most is how much
money the bank and its employees have made, so soon after the
government invested trillions of dollars to rescue the financial
system -- including Goldman Sachs. Yet even today, the company''s
executives remain arrogant enough to claim that Goldman doesn''t
have a too-big-to-fail guarantee from the government, not even
an implicit one. </p>
<p>There are precedents for the sort of risk-factor disclosure
Goldman made. One company that jumps to mind is Halliburton Co.,
the oilfield-services giant that morphed into a national pariah
soon after its former CEO, Dick Cheney, became U.S. vice
president. Halliburton cited its former relationship with Cheney
as a risk factor during the run-up to the 2004 presidential
election. It, too, said the problem was that the company had
become a target for reasons beyond its own behavior. </p>
<p>To the extent we or our subcontractors make mistakes in
our government contracts operations, even if unintentional,
insignificant or subsequently self-reported to the applicable
government agency, we will likely be subject to intense
scrutiny, the company said in a 2004 SEC filing. Some of
this scrutiny is as a result of the vice president of the United
States being a former chief executive officer of Halliburton. </p>
<p>Something Drastic </p>
<p>By 2007, Halliburton had spun off its Kellogg Brown  Root
division, whose Defense Department contracts in Iraq triggered
Justice Department investigations. Since then, both Halliburton
and KBR largely have faded from the national spotlight. </p>
<p>While breaking up Goldman wouldn''t be as simple, at some
point the bank may have to try something just as drastic if it
can''t find a way to detoxify its reputation. Restoring Goldman''s
public standing should be Blankfein''s top priority. Yet there''s
no indication he has any idea how to accomplish this. </p>
<p>Truth is, it might no longer be possible. </p>
<p>(Jonathan Weil is a Bloomberg News columnist. The opinions
expressed are his own.) </p>
<p>Click on Send Comment in the sidebar display to send a
letter to the editor. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sara Gay Forden" date="Mar 09, 2010 10:34 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-03-09/morgan-stanley-said-to-hire-pearson-for-car-research-update2-.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Said to Hire Pearson for Car Research</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) has hired Credit
Suisse''s Stuart Pearson to head its European automobile equity
research team in London, according to two people familiar with
the situation. </p>
<p>Pearson, 32, resigned yesterday after 2 1/2 years at Credit
Suisse and will start his new job in June, said the people, who
asked not to be identified because the appointment hasn''t been
made public. Pearson will replace Adam Jonas, who is moving to
the U.S. to oversee the bank''s global automotive research team,
one of the people said. </p>
<p>Pearson will work with Edoardo Spina at Morgan Stanley, the
person said. At Credit Suisse, Pearson covered European
automotive companies including Fiat SpA (F), Renault SA (RNO) and
Continental AG. (CON) His recommendations on PSA Peugeot Citroen''s
stock generated a return of 57 percent in the past 12 months,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. The Bloomberg EMEA Auto
Manufacturers Index rose 11 percent in that period. </p>
<p>Credit Suisse''s Arndt Ellinghorst, who is in charge of the
investment bank''s global automotive research team, said in a
telephone interview today that he will take over coverage of
Pearson''s companies until he is replaced. A Morgan Stanley
spokesman declined to comment, as did Pearson. </p>
<p>Before joining Credit Suisse, Pearson, who is from London,
worked as a research analyst for Citigroup, where he followed
the automotive sector starting in 2003. He previously covered
utilities stocks. </p>
<h2>Stock Picks </h2>
<p>Pearson confirmed a market weight recommendation on the
automotive sector in a March 2 Credit Suisse note to investors.
The direction of auto stocks is being dictated by credit
conditions, the analyst said, with a decline in share prices
being prevented only by the plentiful liquidity on hand at
most manufacturers, he said. </p>
<p>The analyst advised buying the stock of carmakers Daimler
AG, Fiat and Renault, and had an underweight recommendation
on Peugeot as well as parts suppliers Autoliv Inc. and Michelin
 Cie. Peugeot shows the greatest cash-flow sensitivity and
potential consensus downgrade risk among European automakers,
he wrote in the note. </p>
<p>Fiat and Daimler may exceed company forecasts for earnings
before interest and taxes this year even if European car sales
fall 16 percent, Pearson said. </p>
<p>An honors graduate in mechanical engineering from the
University of Bristol, Pearson also has a degree from the
University of Bath and trained as an engineer at Ford Motor Co.
He has been recognized as a Chartered Financial Analyst by the
CFA Institute since 2005. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elizabeth Stanton" date="Mar 16, 2010  4:51 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-03-16/general-electric-intel-popular-wyndham-u-s-equity-movers.html"><headline>General Electric, Intel, Popular, Wyndham: U.S. Equity Movers</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Shares of the following companies
had unusual moves in U.S. trading. Stock symbols are in
parentheses. Prices are as of 4 p.m. in New York. </p>
<p>Real Estate companies had the second-biggest gain among 24
industries in the SP 500 rising 2.5 percent after billionaire
investor Sam Zell said real estate investment trusts will have
enough cash to boost dividends in the future and also that he
expects more takeovers in the industry. A gauge of SP 500 REITS
rallied 2.7 percent. </p>
<p>Equity Residential (EQR) , the largest publicly traded
U.S. apartment owner, surged 3.3 percent to $39.37. ProLogis (PLD)
 gained 3 percent to $14.21. Kimco Realty Corp. (KIM) 
rose 3.2 percent to $15.57. </p>
<p>Arthrocare Corp. (ARTC US) rose 5.9 percent to $28.91, the
highest price since October 2008. The surgical-tool maker
reported fourth-quarter earnings excluding some items of 21
cents a share, more than double the average analysts'' estimate
in a Bloomberg survey. </p>
<p>Athenahealth Inc. (ATHN)  gained 6.5 percent, the most
since June 25, to $39.71. The provider of Internet-based
services completed an accounting review, and the adjustments
appear to be minor and contained, Thomas Weisel Partners
Group Inc. said in a note dated yesterday. </p>
<p>Benihana Inc. (BNHNA US) rose 7.7 percent to $6.01,
rallying for a second day. The Japanese steakhouse chain is
being pursued by former Icahn Associates executive Russell
Glass, who has offered $7 a share, a premium of about 19
percent, the New York Post reported, citing a person familiar
with the offer. </p>
<p>China Fire  Security Group Inc. (CFSG US) declined 7.8
percent, the most since Nov. 9, to $14.28. The maker of safety
products posted fourth-quarter profit of 10 cents a share,
missing the average analyst estimate by 13 percent. </p>
<p>Cliffs Natural Resources Inc. (CLF)  gained 4.9 percent to
$66.27, the highest price since September 2008. North America''s
biggest iron-ore producer had its share-price estimate increased
to $85 from $65 by Deutsche Bank AG. </p>
<p>DSW Inc. (DSW)  declined 11 percent, the most since May
28, to $26.33. The footwear retailer with 306 stores in 39
states posted fourth-quarter profit of 30 cents a share,
trailing the average analyst estimate by 1 cent. </p>
<p>Emeritus Corp. (ESC)  fell 8.3 percent, the most since
Nov. 12, to $18.71. The provider of housing services for senior
citizens posted a fourth-quarter loss excluding some items of 33
cents a share, 40 percent wider than the average analyst
estimate. </p>
<p>General Electric Co. (GE)  rose 4.5 percent, the most in
the Dow Jones Industrial Average, to $18.07. The world''s biggest
maker of jet engines and medical imaging machines has earnings
momentum slowly building, and for the first time in over 10
years, the pieces are in place for earnings upside, JPMorgan
Chase  Co. said in a note to clients. </p>
<p>Genpact Ltd. (G)  fell 6.7 percent to $14.91 for the
biggest retreat in the Russell 1000 Index. The outsourcing
company spun off by General Electric Co. (GE US) said its
shareholders plan to sell 28 million shares and it expects sales
of $285 million to $290 million in the current quarter. The
revenue was short of the average analyst estimate of $293.6
million, according to a Bloomberg survey. </p>
<p>Harley-Davidson Inc. (HOG)  gained 7 percent, the most
since Sept. 8, to $28.35. The biggest U.S. motorcycle maker
rallied on renewed speculation it may be acquired. We''ve been
seeing rumors of a leveraged buyout, said Patrick Mortimer,
director of options trading at Pipeline Trading Systems LLC in
New Hope, Pennsylvania. Bob Klein, a Harley-Davidson spokesman,
couldn''t be reached for comment. </p>
<p>Intel Corp. (INTC)  rose the most since Aug. 18, climbing
4 percent to $22.01. The world''s largest semiconductor maker
said it already has shipped more than 100,000 units of its Xeon
5600, a server chip that officially goes on sale today. </p>
<p>Lexicon Pharmaceuticals Inc. (LXRX)  dropped 9.9 percent
to $1.28, the lowest price since Aug. 17. The biotechnology
company said it priced 87.7 million shares at $1.15 each and
agreed to sell an additional 59.3 million shares to its largest
stockholder Invus LP. </p>
<p>Limited Brands Inc. (LTD US) rose 4.2 percent to $24.71,
the highest price since July 2007. The owner of the Victoria''s
Secret and Bath  Body Works chains said its board approved a
dividend of $1 per share and authorized a $200 million share
repurchase program. </p>
<p>Movado Group Inc. (MOV)  sank 19 percent, the most since
March 2000, to $11.42. The Paramus, New Jersey-based watchmaker
said preliminary results showed it had a loss excluding some
items of at least 28 cents a share. That''s wider than the 25-cent loss estimate by analysts in a Bloomberg survey. </p>
<p>Popular Inc. (BPOP)  rose 13 percent, the most since Aug.
28, to $2.56. The Federal Deposit Insurance Corp. is seeking
buyers for three rival banks in Puerto Rico, the Wall Street
Journal reported, citing two people familiar with the matter. </p>
<p>Republic First Bancorp Inc. (FRBK)  had the biggest
decline in Russell 2000 Index, tumbling 27 percent to $3.22. The
holding company of First Republic Bank and Republic First Bank
of Delaware scrapped plans to merge with Metro Bancorp Inc.,
citing uncertainties over regulatory approval. </p>
<p>Sequenom Inc. (SQNM)  dropped 22 percent, the most since
Sept. 29, to $6.08. The biotechnology company posted a fourth-quarter loss excluding some items of 30 cents a share, 21
percent wider than the average analyst estimate. </p>
<p>Sonic Corp. (SONC)  rose 5.6 percent to $11.08, the
highest price since Oct. 20. The largest U.S. chain of drive-in
restaurants was raised to overweight from underweight at
Piper Jaffray by equity analyst Nicole Miller Regan. </p>
<p>Town Sports International Holdings Inc. (CLUB)  had the
third-biggest gain in Russell 2000 Index, jumping 17 percent to
$3.90. The owner of New York Sports Clubs posted earnings
excluding some items of 2 cents a share in the fourth quarter.
Analysts, on average, forecast a loss of 10 cents, according to
a Bloomberg survey. </p>
<p>Wyndham Worldwide Corp. (WYN)  fell 2.8 percent to $24.07
for the biggest decline since Feb. 4. The franchiser of Days Inn
hotels and Super 8 motels was lowered to neutral from
buy at Goldman Sachs Group Inc. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Vines" date="Mar 18, 2010  9:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-03-18/morgan-stanley-woman-becomes-iron-chef-after-meeting-ramsay.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Woman Becomes ''Iron Chef'' After Meeting Ramsay</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>It''s a fast-paced environment
where orders are shouted, politeness is a luxury and a split-
second decision can mean the difference between success and
failure. </p>
<p>Yes, I''m talking about the professional kitchen, but I
might equally be describing the trading floor. </p>
<p>Judy Joo, 35, knows both. The Columbia engineering
graduate interned at Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and spent more
than four years with Morgan Stanley in New York and San
Francisco before trading her derivatives-saleswoman''s hat for a
chef''s toque. </p>
<p>"I worked pretty long hours on Wall Street," Joo said in
an interview at the luxurious apartment, near London''s Bond
Street, that she shares with her husband, David Allen, who
works at Canada Pension Plan Investment Board. "Particularly
when you''re there doing your two-year analyst program, you''re
there almost all the time and you''re pulling all-nighters. I
decided after a while I just wanted to follow my passion." </p>
<p>Joo, who was born to Korean parents in Summit, New Jersey,
married, quit business and went to study at the French Culinary
Institute in New York. Her big break came after she moved to
London and went to eat at Restaurant Gordon Ramsay. </p>
<p>"My husband got transferred and I was eating at Gordon
Ramsay Restaurant and the big man Gordon was there himself,"
Joo said. "I told him I was a chef and he said, ''Well, when
are you going to start working for me?'' The next thing I know,
I was in the kitchen and I was there for about two and a half
years." </p>
<p>So how did she find the work compared with Wall Street? </p>
<p>''Testosterone Arenas'' </p>
<p>"It''s different but there are definite similarities,"
Joo said. "Both are testosterone arenas and time is always of
the essence and there are very few women and lots of shouting
and yelling. It''s very much like trading. But at the end of the
day you always have to take it with a grain of salt because in
the kitchen it''s just food. You''re not going to collapse the
economy or bankrupt an entire sovereign nation or a bank or
something. </p>
<p>"And the kitchen is different because you don''t ever
shout back when a superior yells at you, you just take it. You
say, ''Yes chef, yes chef, yes chef.'' Whereas on the trading
floor, if someone has a problem with you, you probably have a
problem with them back and you''re very welcome to voice that
opinion." </p>
<p>Who is tougher: chefs or traders? </p>
<p>Tough Traders </p>
<p>"Probably traders I''d say," Joo said. "I''ve dealt with
many, many big egos and you get two managing directors who are
both running their own books and getting in a fight and I''ve
witnessed some pretty epic things on the floor back in my
day." </p>
<p>Joo takes her home cooking seriously, too. She has a
Molteni cooking range that was designed by Annabella Nassetti
and cost 96,350 pounds ($146,700). It was so large and heavy
that Joo got it into the apartment with a crane at 5 a.m. after
getting her floor strengthened to support it. </p>
<p>Since leaving Ramsay, where she was a pastry chef, Joo has
worked as a freelance food writer and has helped another Ramsay
chef, Jason Atherton, with his book projects. Now, she may be
on the brink of celebrity herself: She''s one of four Britons
selected to appear on the U.K. version of "Iron Chef," the
television cooking program whose U.S. incarnation has featured
a show from the White House starring Michelle Obama. </p>
<p>Joo joins Tom Aikens, Martin Blunos and Sanjay Dwivedi in
facing challenges from cooks who reckon they can beat the
resident chefs in preparing dishes based on a secret
ingredient. The series, hosted by Olly Smith, is scheduled to
be shown on Channel 4 next month and was shot in Glasgow by IWC
Media. </p>
<p>How did she feel as the only woman among the chefs? </p>
<p>"I''m pretty competitive," she said. "I''m used to being
able to run with the big boys and holding my own ground.
Otherwise, you''re just going to sink. I thrive in environments
like trading floors and in the kitchen, as well as in ''Iron
Chef.''" </p>
<p>(Richard Vines is the chief food critic for Bloomberg
News. Opinions expressed are his own.) </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tasneem Brogger" date="Mar 26, 2010  5:30 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-03-26/jpmorgan-says-east-europe-currencies-keep-rates-low-update1-.html"><headline>JPMorgan Says East Europe Currencies Keep Rates Low</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Currency gains in central and
eastern Europe, led by a 18 percent rise in the zloty against
the euro since March 30 last year, may delay monetary tightening
and extend easing cycles as policy makers try to cap exchange
rate strengthening, JPMorgan Chase  Co. said. </p>
<p>We expect further appreciation, London-based JPMorgan
economist Miroslav Plojhar said in an interview. This is
slowing inflation and making central bankers more dovish. The
risk to the outlook is that rate cutting cycles in Romania and
Hungary will be rather deeper and that rate hiking cycles in
Poland and the Czech Republic will start rather later. </p>
<p>The zloty, the forint, the leu and the koruna are poised to
rise further this year as the countries'' current accounts
improve and because exchange rates don''t yet reflect the
region''s growth potential, Plojhar said. Currencies in the four
European Union states also benefit from fiscal health relative
to Greece, Portugal, Ireland and Spain, he said. That leaves
central banks little choice but to base decisions on exchange
rate moves. </p>
<p>For the chicken-and-egg question of whether central
bankers are driving currencies or currencies are driving central
bankers in the region, the answer is more that central
bankers are responding more to the currencies, Plojhar said. </p>
<p>The Czechs may delay tightening from 1 percent until the
first quarter and Poland may not raise from 3.5 percent until
the fourth quarter, he said. Hungary may keep cutting to 5
percent or below and Romania may go as low as 5 percent.
JPMorgans''s official forecast is for the Poles and the Czechs to
start tightening in the third and fourth quarters and for the
Hungarians and Romanians to stop at 5.5 percent. </p>
<h2>Regional Reward </h2>
<p>The region is also being rewarded for its austere fiscal
policies, including International Monetary Fund-led programs in
Hungary and Romania, reducing pressure on central bankers to
resort to monetary tightening or rein in the scope of easing. </p>
<p>Standard  Poor''s Analyst Frank Gill says responsible
programs probably will continue even as elections loom that may
oust governments. Hungarians go to the polls on April 11 and 25,
while the Czechs vote on May 28-29. </p>
<p>Hungary''s Fidesz Party, which has promised tax cuts and
said the budget deficit may be twice as wide as the government
now estimates, won''t dare deploy policies that are hostile to
investors, according to Tim Ash, head of emerging market
research at Royal Bank of Scotland Plc. Fidesz is more than 30
points ahead of the ruling Socialists in the polls. </p>
<p>Anyone who steps out of line is going to get smacked by
the market, Ash said. </p>
<h2>Safe Haven'' </h2>
<p>Euro area debt as a percentage of gross domestic product
will average 84 percent this year and may be 125 percent in
Greece, the European Commission estimates. In emerging EU, only
Hungary will exceed the 60 percent limit, at 79.8 percent. On
average, euro area deficits will be 6.9 percent, more than twice
the EU''s threshold. Hungary, Romania and the Czech Republic will
all have smaller deficits than the currency bloc''s average. </p>
<p>Czech bonds and the koruna are a safe haven as the
country''s borrowing level makes it less likely to face a Greek-style crisis, Danske Bank A/S said in a report yesterday. </p>
<p>Standard  Poor''s is fairly confident the next
Hungarian government will continue to pursue policies to
reduce public sector borrowing needs, Gill said in an
interview. The country''s growth prospects also underline its
fiscal recovery, he said. </p>
<h2>Fiscal Math </h2>
<p>Hungary will converge back to growth rates of 3 percent
between 2011 and 2012, Gill said. The fiscal mathematics
will begin to become far more benign than it has been over the
last several years. </p>
<p>In Hungary, where exports make up almost 80 percent of GDP,
the forint has gained 15 percent per euro since March 30 even as
the benchmark was lowered 3.75 points to 5.75 percent. The bank
last month said gradual rate cuts may end in the next few
meetings. </p>
<p>In Romania, where the benchmark matches a 2007 record low
of 7 percent, a strong leu helped slow inflation to 4.5 percent
last month from 5.2 percent in January. </p>
<p>Poland, the only EU member to have avoided a recession
during the credit crisis, is likely to continue to outperform
the rest of the region, Plojhar said. Looking further ahead,
it''s likely the Czechs and the Hungarians will see a much
stronger relative acceleration in GDP growth than Poland because
they''re recovering from a slower growth pace. </p>
<p>SP''s Gill said the Czech Republic is potentially very
well positioned to leverage off a euro-zone recovery if there is
one. </p>
<p>Not everyone is convinced about the growth outlook as the
export-reliant east awaits a sustainable rebound in demand from
western Europe. In Germany, investor confidence dropped for a
sixth month in March, suggesting the EU''s biggest economy is
struggling to expand, the ZEW Center for European Economic
Research said. </p>
<p>Funding doesn''t seem to be the problem, but everyone''s
assuming there''s going to be a rebound and that growth comes
back, RBS''s Ash said. But that''s a big question mark, given
a very weak western European story. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ye Xie" date="Mar 31, 2010  7:01 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-03-31/goldman-sachs-recommends-chinese-hong-kong-listed-shares-as-top-trade-.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Recommends Chinese Hong Kong-Listed Shares as `Top Trade''</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>China''s Hong Kong-listed companies
are a "new top trade" at Goldman Sachs Group Inc., which said
the Hang Seng China Enterprises Index will climb at least 20
percent on valuation and the outlook for economic growth. </p>
<p>"We are recommending a new top trade," Dominic Wilson, an
economist at Goldman Sachs in New York, wrote in a report e-
mailed yesterday. "We sense that Chinese equities have fallen
off investors'' radars somewhat, positioning is light, and
sentiment is, at best, skeptical, making us all the more keen to
get involved." </p>
<p>The recommendation is Goldman Sachs''s ninth top trade for
the year. The other top trades include owning Russian stocks,
favoring the British pound against the New Zealand dollar, and
the Polish zloty against the Japanese yen, according to a
separate note e-mailed yesterday. </p>
<p>The H-share index has dropped 10 percent from a 17-month
high in November, compared with a 2.8 percent gain for the MSCI
Emerging Markets Index, on concern policy makers will curb bank
lending and raise interest rates to slow growth. The H-share
index''s 3.1 percent loss this year compares to a 4.9 percent
gain in the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index of U.S. stocks and 2.1
percent advance in the MSCI Emerging Markets Index of 22
developing-nation stocks. </p>
<p>''Long Position'' </p>
<p>The "underperformance" of China''s H shares left their
valuation at "undemanding" levels, Goldman Sachs said. The H-
share index is priced at 17.8 times the reported earnings of its
companies, an 11 percent discount to the MSCI Emerging Markets
Index, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs recommended a "long position" in H shares as
the index that tracks their performance rises to 15,000 from
12,397.59 yesterday. China''s economy, the third largest in the
world, will expand more than 11 percent this year, Goldman Sachs
predicts, more than the 9.6 percent median forecast of 22
analysts surveyed by Bloomberg. Goldman Sachs''s portfolio
strategists predict the H shares index will climb to 17,000 by
year-end, a 37 percent jump from yesterday''s close. </p>
<p>"Economic growth has stayed robust and broad based,"
Goldman Sachs wrote. "While interest rates will likely rise
soon," the risk from policy tightening "is much better flagged
than before." </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Martin" date="Mar 31, 2010  8:38 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-03-31/electric-car-demand-means-polypore-s-battery-parts-outpace-wind-and-solar.html"><headline>Electric Car Demand Means Polypore''s Battery Parts Outpace Wind and Solar</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Polypore International Inc., which
makes one of the key components of electric-car batteries, is
climbing faster than most alternative energy stocks this year as
investors bet on a global shift to low-polluting automobiles. </p>
<p>The company based in Charlotte, North Carolina, is about to
finish the first quarter with a 46 percent increase to $17.34 a
share, the top gainer on the WilderHill New Energy Global
Innovation index. The benchmark of 86 clean-energy stocks sank
10.2 percent in the period, pulled lower by Vestas Wind Systems
A/S, the biggest wind-turbine maker, and German solar developer
Solarworld AG. </p>
<p>"Polypore is positioned to take a solid chunk of the
growth in electric vehicles," said Bryan Drab, an analyst at
William Blair  Co. in Chicago who has a "outperform" rating
on the stock. "They supply to most, if not all, the major
makers of lithium batteries that are going into electric cars." </p>
<p>The company is the world''s biggest producer of porous
membranes used in traditional lead-acid batteries for cars. It
also makes the chemical separators for more potent lithium
batteries used in electric vehicles made by General Motors Co.,
Toyota Motor Corp. and Volkswagen AG. </p>
<p>The separators keep apart positive and negative charged
electrodes while allowing the ions powering the battery to move
within the unit. </p>
<p>This month, the company forecast electric vehicles will
make up 3 percent of global car sales by 2012, and 6 percent by
2015, compared with about 2 percent now. </p>
<p>Investment Plan </p>
<p>Polypore plans to spend $102 million over two years to
double production of separators for lithium cells. It competes
with Asahi Kasei Corp. and TonenGeneral Sekiyu K.K., the
Japanese unit of Exxon Mobil Corp. TonenGeneral and Asahi Kasei
shares both have risen 10 percent since the beginning of March.
Polypore gained 14.8 percent this month. </p>
<p>The three together provide 90 percent of the market for
lithium separators, said Polypore Chief Financial Officer Lynn
Amos. Polypore is also increasing output in Korea for cell-phone
sized separators. </p>
<p>Founded in 1994, Polypore sold its shares at $19 in June
2007, rose as high as $29.26 in August 2008, and dropped to as
low as $2.38 in March 2009 during the credit crisis and
recession. </p>
<p>Another drag on Polypore''s shares was ruling from the U.S.
Federal Trade Commission recommending the company divest most of
its Microporous unit, the only maker of rubber-based membranes
for lead-acid batteries. Polypore is appealing the ruling. </p>
<p>"The FTC complaint came out in September 2008, and we were
concerned we''d be forced to sell at a loss during the banking
meltdown," Amos said in a March 26 interview. "At this point,
we could probably make some money if we had to sell." </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley increased its stake in Polypore to 1.48
million shares as of Dec. 31, or 3.3 percent of the company''s
outstanding stock, according to data compiled by Bloomberg.
Morgan Stanley funds control 2 percent of the company. The bank
holds the rest for Van Kampen Investments Inc., the data show. </p>
<p>Erica Platt, a Morgan Stanley spokeswoman, declined to
comment on the holdings. </p>
<p>Polypore also benefited from the extension of a contract
with one of its largest customers, Drab said. </p>
<p>On Jan. 19, Exide Technologies renewed a contract that
expired last year. Polypore plants have supplied the Milton,
Georgia-based battery maker for more than 40 years, and the
agreement extends the contract for three years. </p>
<p>Of the nine analysts following the stock, four rate it a
"buy" and four a "hold," while one has a "sell"
recommendation, according to Bloomberg data. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Susan Decker" date="Apr 01, 2010  8:17 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-04-01/microsoft-sues-datel-for-infringing-patents-on-xbox-360-video-controllers.html"><headline>Microsoft Sues Datel for Infringing Patents on Xbox 360 Video Controllers</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp., the world''s biggest
software maker, sued Datel Design  Development Ltd., claiming
the U.K. company is infringing design patents for controllers
used with the Xbox 360 video-game system. </p>
<p>In a lawsuit filed in federal court in Seattle today,
Microsoft is seeking damages and a court order that would halt
sales of Datel''s TurboFire and WildFire controllers. Microsoft
also sued Datel in the U.K. and filed a complaint with the U.S.
International Trade Commission in Washington, seeking to block
U.S. imports of the controllers made in China. </p>
<p>The game controllers provide "a firepower advantage that
can make all the difference," Datel, based in Staffordshire,
England, said on its Web site. They can turn a single-shot
pistol in the "Call of Duty" into "lethal, fully automatic
weapons that can empty a clip on an enemy in a second." </p>
<p>The patent complaints "appear retaliatory," Datel lawyer
Martin Glick said in a telephone interview. "They said the
controller would interfere with the fair play of games and then
they licensed a controller that did exactly that." </p>
<p>Glick, of Howard Rice in San Francisco, said he hadn''t
reviewed the complaints so couldn''t comment on the specific
allegations. </p>
<p>Unfair Advantage </p>
<p>Microsoft has said in court filings that the accessories
give their users an unfair advantage in multiplayer gaming. The
TurboFire and WildFire controllers copy unique designs protected
by six U.S. patents, Microsoft said in the complaint. </p>
<p>More than 74 million Xbox 360 game controllers have been
sold worldwide since 2005, including about 40 million in the
U.S., according to the ITC complaint. </p>
<p>"The designs of the WildFire Controller are the same or
substantially the same to the eye of the ordinary observer as
the ornamental designs claimed in the Microsoft patents,"
Microsoft said. </p>
<p>Datel also sells a memory card that it says is four times
as powerful as the one that Microsoft offers. In October,
Microsoft deployed what it called a "dashboard update" that
disabled Datel''s memory cards. </p>
<p>Datel filed an antitrust lawsuit in November against
Microsoft, claiming the Redmond, Washington-based company seeks
to monopolize the markets for multiplayer online gaming systems
and for accessories not sold directly with the Xbox. </p>
<p>Memory Cards </p>
<p>Glick, who called the update a "downgrade," said it was
designed to shut down Datel because the memory cards were
driving down the price of Microsoft''s. </p>
<p>Microsoft has asked that the antitrust suit be dismissed,
saying Datel isn''t legally entitled to sell "accessories that
open the door for cheating that harms the Xbox 360 ecosystem." </p>
<p>Microsoft said in the ITC complaint it has sold or licensed
more than $7 billion worth of products that use the patents at
issue in the case. "U.S. sales and licensing revenue for Xbox
360 gamepads alone account for more than $100 million," the
company said in the complaint. </p>
<p>"The success of Microsoft''s Xbox 360 has not gone
unnoticed by others who seek to gain from Microsoft''s
investment, creativity and goodwill," the company said in the
filing. </p>
<p>The new case is Microsoft Corp. v. Datel Design and
Development Ltd., 10cv562, U.S. District Court for the Western
District of Washington (Seattle). The antitrust case is Datel
Holdings Ltd. v. Microsoft Corp., 09cv5535, U.S. District Court
for the Northern District of California (San Francisco). </p>
<p>The ITC case is In the Matter of Game Controllers,
Complaint No. 2722, U.S. International Trade Commission
(Washington). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Peter Burrows" date="Apr 01, 2010  7:10 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-04-01/microsoft-won-t-make-office-for-ipad-says-google-is-no-software-threat.html"><headline>Microsoft Won''t Make Office for IPad, Says Google Is No Software Threat</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp., the world''s largest
software maker, has no plans to make a version of its Office
suite of programs to run on Apple Inc.''s iPad, said Stephen
Elop, president of Microsoft''s business division. </p>
<p>Elop said the company would take a "wait and see"
approach to tailoring software for the iPad, which goes on sale
on April 3. He also said Google Inc. hasn''t made any headway
against Microsoft in the business software market. </p>
<p>"We haven''t heard anything about Google making inroads
against Office, because they''re not," Elop said today in an
interview. Office includes word-processing, spreadsheet and
other business-productivity programs. </p>
<p>Microsoft will begin selling the next version of the
product, dubbed Office 2010, on May 12. The debut comes as
Google and other Web companies are pushing alternatives that
cost less or are even free. Office brings in about 90 percent of
the revenue of Elop''s division, which is the company''s largest
and one of its most profitable. </p>
<p>The version of Office 2010 that goes on sale on May 12 is
designed for businesses. A version for consumers will be
available by late June. By then, the company also will introduce
stripped-down versions of Word and the spreadsheet program Excel
that are accessible free over the Web. </p>
<p>Demand looks promising, particularly from companies, and 6
million people have downloaded a prerelease "beta" version of
the product, Elop said. That''s twice as many as downloaded the
beta version of Office 2007, the last upgrade. </p>
<p>Of those beta users polled by Microsoft, 80 percent said
they would recommend Office 2010 to friends, and 90 percent said
the software made them more productive, he said. </p>
<p>Cloud Computing </p>
<p>Elop said corporate buyers are less interested in
discussing Google and other competitors and more concerned about
whether to move to new "cloud"-based versions of Microsoft
software. Customers who choose this route don''t run the software
on their own computers, instead paying a monthly fee to
Microsoft to deliver it over the Internet from the company''s
massive data centers. </p>
<p>"We never say never, but we have no current plans" to
develop a version of Office for the Apple iPad, Elop said. Last
year Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft said it would create a
version to work on Nokia Oyj''s smartphones, since millions of
Office users already own those devices. </p>
<p>An iPad edition of Office would likely be built by a unit
within Microsoft''s consumer business that creates versions of
Office that work with Apple''s Macintosh personal computers.
Kristen Woody, a spokesman for that unit, says it "doesn''t have
anything to share at this time." </p>
<p>Microsoft fell 13 cents to $29.16 at 4 p.m. New York time
on the Nasdaq Stock Market. After gaining 57 percent last year,
the shares have slipped 4.3 percent in 2010. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Susan Decker" date="Apr 01, 2010  1:15 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-04-01/microsoft-loss-in-i4i-patent-case-will-stand-appeals-court-in-u-s-says.html"><headline>Microsoft Loss in I4i Patent Case Will Stand, Appeals Court in U.S. Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. failed in its bid to
have a U.S. appeals court take a second look at a patent-
infringement case that forced it to change its popular Word
software and resulted in a damage award that''s grown to more
than $290 million. </p>
<p>The U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit today
rejected a request that the Dec. 22 ruling won by closely held
I4i LP of Toronto be heard by the full 12-member court. The
decision was announced in a notice on the court''s Web site. </p>
<p>Microsoft has called the case the largest patent-
infringement verdict ever upheld on appeal. The request for a
rehearing centered on testimony related to damages, whether
Microsoft''s infringement was intentional, and whether Microsoft
should have been forced to remove what the company called an
"obscure functionality" or stop selling Word. </p>
<p>I4i''s invention is related to customizing extensible markup
language, or XML, a way of encoding data to exchange information
among programs. Microsoft issued an update to Word to comply
with the court order. </p>
<p>Word is part of Microsoft''s Office software, used by more
than 500 million people. Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft is
testing Office 2010 with customers. The completed version is
scheduled to be released by June. The unit that sells Office is
Microsoft''s biggest, with $18.9 billion in sales in the year
ended June 30. </p>
<p>XML is a common way of encoding data, and nothing in the
order prevented Microsoft from continuing to offer that feature
in Word, or for allowing customized XML when it''s used in plain
text. The disputed feature is one used by large companies to add
special data to Word files, such as information in forms
submitted by customers. I4i''s patent was issued in 1998. </p>
<p>The case is I4i LP v. Microsoft Corp., 2009-1504, U.S.
Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit (Washington). The
lower-court case is I4i LP v. Microsoft Corp., 07-cv-113, U.S.
District Court, Eastern District of Texas (Tyler). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Apr 01, 2010 10:06 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-04-01/jpmorgan-s-dimon-regrets-using-government-guarantee-program-to-issue-debt.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Dimon Regrets Using Government Guarantee Program to Issue Debt</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. Chief Executive
Officer Jamie Dimon said he regrets using the Federal Deposit
Insurance Corp.''s guarantee program to issue $40 billion in
unsecured debt during the height of the financial crisis. </p>
<p>"We didn''t need it," Dimon, 54, said in his annual letter
to shareholders, which was released yesterday. "And it just
added to the argument that all banks had been bailed out and
fueled the anger directed toward banks." </p>
<p>Dimon said the New York-based company was "highly
criticized" for issuing debt backed by the FDIC and for
accepting $25 billion from the Troubled Asset Relief Program.
The company repaid all TARP funds in June, stopped using the
FDIC''s program last April and shunned participation in other
federal programs "to avoid the stigma," he said. </p>
<p>JPMorgan, which ranks second behind Bank of America Corp.
in deposits and assets among U.S. lenders, remained profitable
through the crisis with combined net income of $17.3 billion in
the last two years. The company issued $20.8 billion in FDIC-
guaranteed long-term debt in 2008, and $19.7 billion in 2009. </p>
<p>"It was not a question of access or need," Dimon said of
the FDIC program, whose government backing helped keep interest
rates low. "The markets always were open to us, but the program
did save us money." </p>
<p>FDIC Program </p>
<p>FDIC spokesman Andrew Gray declined to comment. About 6,500
eligible institutions opted out of the Temporary Liquidity
Guarantee Program. More than 80 banks and thrifts used the
program to issue debt, about $305.4 billion of which was still
outstanding as of Feb. 28, according to FDIC data. </p>
<p>Dimon apologized for what he said were the bank''s mistakes.
He said the two biggest were lowering mortgage underwriting
standards and making too many leveraged loans that "may have
contributed to the financial crisis." At the same time, he
claimed some credit for helping to stabilize markets through
JPMorgan''s purchases of Bear Stearns Cos. and Washington Mutual. </p>
<p>He also sought to deflect some of the public anger toward
financial companies and to correct the perception that all banks
would have failed if the federal government hadn''t intervened. </p>
<p>"We should acknowledge that the worst offenders among
financial companies no longer are in existence," Dimon said.
"And while it is true that some of the surviving banks would
not, or might not, have survived, not all banks would have
failed." </p>
<p>Dimon, who took over as CEO in 2005, said his "No. 1
priority" this year is to find his successor. </p>
<p>Internal Candidates </p>
<p>"Poor CEO succession has destroyed many a company," Dimon
said, adding that the board believes there are several strong
internal candidates that could "do my job today." He said
JPMorgan will continue rotating senior staff across the business
to ensure they could smoothly take over the company. </p>
<p>The company also intends to expand retail banking, which
accounted for $97 million of JPMorgan''s $11.7 billion in net
income last year. Dimon said the bank will add 2,700 personal
bankers, 400 investment sales representatives and 120 more
branches this year, even though consumer lending lost $3.8
billion in 2009. The bank plans to ramp up its branch expansion
in California and Florida over the next two years, building on
its acquisition of Washington Mutual, he said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bill Rochelle" date="Apr 01, 2010 10:06 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-04-01/general-growth-lehman-accredited-home-tribune-lyondell-bankruptcy.html"><headline>General Growth, Lehman, Accredited Home, Tribune, Lyondell: Bankruptcy</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Shopping mall owner General Growth
Properties Inc. filed definitive documents last night to raise
$6.55 billion in new equity from three investors in return for
65 percent of the stock. General Growth is setting up a bidding
procedure where other investors could end up being the equity
sponsors. </p>
<p>In return for agreeing to be the so-called stalking-horse,
the three investors -- Fairholme Capital Management LLC,
Pershing Square Capital Management LP, and Brookfield Asset
Management Inc. -- will be given warrants for 120 million shares
exercisable at $15 a share. General Growth said in its court
filing last night that the warrants are worth $520 million. </p>
<p>Combined with $1.5 billion through a new debt offering or
reinstatement of existing debt, General Growth says it will have
enough capital to confirm a plan at the holding company level.
Only $1 billion in debt at the property-owning level remains to
be formally reorganized through confirmation of reorganization
plans. </p>
<p>General Growth says the plan will be sufficient to pay
unsecured creditors in full with interest. </p>
<p>At an April 29 hearing, General Growth will ask the
bankruptcy judge to approve the warrants to the stalking-horse
investors and a schedule for wrapping up the case. General
Growth wants the first round of bids submitted by April 19, even
before the judge has approved procedures. </p>
<p>General Growth is offering as much as $1 million in expense
reimbursement for anyone who participates in the bidding
process. </p>
<p>The second round of bids would be due June 2, if the judge
agrees with the schedule. General Growth and representatives of
existing stockholders will then compare the bids, negotiate
further, and select the winning investors in time for filing a
reorganization plan and disclosure statement on July 2. </p>
<p>The hearing for approval of the disclosure statement would
take place July 30, followed by a confirmation hearing for
approval of the plan on Sept. 30. </p>
<p>Assuming there are no other bids, Fairholme would end up
with 28 percent of the new stock for a $2.8 billion investment.
Pershing Square is in line for 11 percent for $1.1 billion, and
Brookfield would receive 26 percent for $2.625 billion. </p>
<p>Existing shareholders will retain 34 percent of the stock
through the Chapter 11 plan. Existing equity holders will also
receive 80 percent of the equity in a new company to own non-
core assets. </p>
<p>General Growth also filed an operating report yesterday
showing $70.1 million in operating income during February on
revenue of $204.5 million. Interest expense in the month was
$91.7 million. </p>
<p>The month produced $208.6 million in net income thanks to a
$222.9 million gain on reorganization items. In February, the
loss before  taxes, non-controlling interests and reorganization
items was $21.6 million. </p>
<p>In seven batches of confirmations since December, General
Growth has formally reorganized property-owning subsidiaries
holding all except $1 billion on debt below the holding
companies. </p>
<p>General Growth began the largest real estate reorganization
in history by filing under Chapter 11 in April 2009. The books
of Chicago-based General Growth had assets of $29.6 billion and
total liabilities of $27.3 billion as of Dec. 31, 2008. It owns
or manages more than 200 shopping-mall properties. </p>
<p>The case is In re General Growth Properties Inc., 09-11977,
U.S. Bankruptcy Court, Southern District of New York
(Manhattan). </p>
<p>Updates </p>
<p>Crescent Selects UBS and Aladdin as Lead Arrangers </p>
<p>Real estate developer Crescent Resources LLC jilted RBS
Securities Inc. and instead intends on marrying itself to other
arrangers for a $125 million secured financing to aid in an exit
from bankruptcy reorganization. Creditors are voting on the
Crescent Chapter 11 plan in advance of a May 20 confirmation
hearing. </p>
<p>Although the bankruptcy court already approved using RBS to
serve as lead arranger, Crescent said in a March 30 bankruptcy
court filing that UBS Securities LLC and Aladdin Capital LLC
made a better offer that has a "higher likelihood of success"
and contains "more favorable terms for the debtors." </p>
<p>Crescent arranged an April 5 hearing for approval of the
agreement with UBS and Aladdin. For other Bloomberg coverage,
click here. </p>
<p>Crescent''s disclosure statement tells holders of $1.55
billion in pre-bankruptcy loans that they stand to recover 38
percent by receiving all the new stock and $265 million in two
tranches of second-lien notes. </p>
<p>General unsecured creditors with almost $305 million in
claims are to be given the senior interest in a litigation
trust. The pre-bankruptcy lenders will have a subordinate
interest in the trust. The disclosure statement doesn''t specify
the percentage recovery unsecured creditors are to receive. </p>
<p>Secured lenders with mortgages against specific projects
are being paid in full, in some cases by receiving their
collateral. </p>
<p>Charlotte, North Carolina-based Crescent filed under
Chapter 11 in June with commercial, residential and multifamily
projects in 10 southeastern and southwestern states. It listed
assets of $2.2 billion against debt totaling $1.9 billion,
including almost $1.5 billion on pre-bankruptcy credit
agreements. Crescent is a joint venture between Duke Energy
Corp. and Morgan Stanley Real Estate Fund. </p>
<p>The case is In re Crescent Resources LLC, 09-11507, U.S.
Bankruptcy Court, Western District Texas (Austin). </p>
<p>Lehman Proposes Buying Up Notes Underlying Flip Deals </p>
<p>Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. filed a motion asking for
authority to extricate itself from derivate and swap agreements
where there are disputes about Lehman''s rights. </p>
<p>Many of the transactions involve a so-called flip clause in
a swap where collateral ordinarily would go first to a Lehman
subsidiary as the swap counterparty. Under the flip clause, the
bankruptcy of the swap counterparty or an affiliate would have
the collateral go first to noteholders and only to Lehman after
the noteholders were fully paid. </p>
<p>The bankruptcy judge gave Lehman a victory when he ruled on
Jan. 25 in one of the transactions that the flip clause violates
a provision in bankruptcy law prohibiting so-called ipso facto
clauses where someone loses rights simply for filing in
bankruptcy or becoming insolvent. </p>
<p>Despite Lehman''s victory, the liquidating broker said the
counterparties aren''t settling and in some cases are asserting
rights under foreign law where the result might follow an
English decision upholding the flip clause. </p>
<p>To short circuit the third parties, Lehman is asking for
authority to buy up enough notes so it can force the liquidation
of collateral in particular transactions. Given Lehman''s success
in litigation, the motion says that the notes are often trading
for less than market value. </p>
<p>By buying up enough notes in a transaction, Lehman says it
may also have power in some cases to force settlement. Lehman
believes that buying notes will bring a quicker result than
litigating each transaction separately. </p>
<p>If the bankruptcy judge grants the motion at an April 20
hearing, Lehman could buy as much as $25 million in notes in any
particular transaction so long as a creditors'' committee
financial professional does not object within six hours. For
individual purchases more than $25 million, the judge must
approve if the creditors'' committee doesn''t consent. </p>
<p>To read about the January decision regarding flip
transactions, click here and look for the Advance Sheets item in
the Feb. 1 Bloomberg bankruptcy report. </p>
<p>More than 20 financial institutions and creditors objected
to Lehman''s proposal for alternative dispute resolution of
claims. Wells Fargo Bank NA, for example, contends that the
three-step process is too time consuming and expensive for
creditors. The bank, as trustee in securitization trusts,
objects to how Lehman can name four mediators from which the
creditors must select one. </p>
<p>The bank wants the ability to make counter proposals when
Lehman submits a settlement offer in advance of mediation. The
bank wants the right to attend mediation through teleconference
rather than being required to be present in person in New York. </p>
<p>Wells Fargo and others want the ability to compel Lehman to
produce information in advance of mediation. </p>
<p>The hearing for approval of mediation procedures is on the
bankruptcy court calendar for consideration at an April 14
hearing. </p>
<p>Weil Gotshal  Manges LLP, Lehman''s chief bankruptcy
counsel, disclosed in a bankruptcy court filing this week that
its top partners are charging $990 an hour. The least-expensive
partner''s hourly rate is $725. The top rate for associates is
$695. The top rate for a partner from a foreign office $1,000. </p>
<p>From the inception of the Chapter 11 case in September 2008
through February, Weil Gotshal charged Lehman $157.5 million. To
read other Bloomberg coverage, click here. </p>
<p>The Lehman holding company filed under Chapter 11 in New
York on Sept. 15, 2008, and sold office buildings and the North
American investment banking business to London-based Barclays
Plc one week later. The Lehman brokerage operations went into
liquidation on Sept. 19, 2008, in the same court. The brokerage
is in the control of a trustee appointed under the Securities
Investor Protection Act. </p>
<p>The Lehman holding company Chapter 11 case is In re Lehman
Brothers Holdings Inc., 08-13555, while the liquidation
proceeding under the Securities Investor Protection Act for the
brokerage operation is Securities Investors Protection Corp. v.
Lehman Brothers Inc., 08-01420, U.S. Bankruptcy Court, Southern
District New York (Manhattan). </p>
<p>Accredited Home at Impasse with Lone Star on Plan </p>
<p>Accredited Home Lenders Holding Co., a home mortgage
originator and securitizer prior to the Chapter 11 filing in
May, says negotiations on a Chapter 11 plan are at "impasse." </p>
<p>The indenture trustee for junior subordinated noteholders
sued the owner Lone Star Funds, alleging fraudulent
representations were made in connection with the $300 million
acquisition in 2007. Since then, there were negotiations on a
Chapter 11 plan that failed, Accredited Home said in a March 29
motion for an extension of the exclusive right to propose a
Chapter 11 plan. </p>
<p>The company says that the noteholders asked to hold up the
plan process for at least three months. To accommodate the
request, the company is asking to stretch out the exclusive
plan-filing right until Nov. 1. </p>
<p>A hearing on the exclusivity motion will take place April
21. </p>
<p>In the motion, Accredited Home said it filed a tax return
in February asking for a $57 million refund. The refund hasn''t
yet been received. </p>
<p>The creditors'' committee already has a motion on the April
21 calendar for authority to bring claims on behalf of the
company against Dallas-based Lone Star. </p>
<p>Accredited sold the mortgage servicing business in July
after the Chapter 11 filing in May. Most of the mortgage loans
were sold later. Lone Star also owns Bruno''s Supermarkets LLC
and Bi-Lo LLC, two grocery retailers in Chapter 11. </p>
<p>The Chapter 11 petition said assets are less than $50
million while debt exceeds $100 million. </p>
<p>The case is In re Accredited Home Lenders Holding Co., 09-
11516, U.S. Bankruptcy Court, District of Delaware (Wilmington). </p>
<p>Still No LBO Settlement and No Reorg Plan for Tribune </p>
<p>Newspaper publisher Tribune Co. is asking for a fifth
extension of the exclusive right to propose a Chapter 11 plan. </p>
<p>The creditors'' committee supports extending the deadline by
one month, to April 30. Tribune is aiming for an April 13
hearing on the so-called exclusivity motion. </p>
<p>Tribune filed an operating report yesterday showing a $2.7
million net profit in February on $221.8 million in revenue. </p>
<p>The case remains stuck in disputes over whether the $13.8
billion leveraged buyout led by Sam Zell in December 2007
resulted in fraudulent transfers. Tribune reiterated its belief
that settling the claims through a plan is the best outcome. </p>
<p>Tribune said it couldn''t provide details on negotiations
due to "confidentiality concerns." It promised to make more
disclosures before the April 13 hearing. </p>
<p>The operating report has a $16.4 million operating profit
in February. Reorganization costs that cut into net profit
totaled $7.4 million. </p>
<p>Creditors are working on the theory that the LBO was a
fraudulent transfer because operating subsidiaries put liens on
their assets to finance the Zell acquisition while not receiving
commensurate value in return. </p>
<p>Tribune is the second-largest newspaper publisher in the
U.S. Tribune listed $13 billion in debt for borrowed money and
assets of $7.6 billion in the Chapter 11 reorganization begun in
December 2008. It owns the Chicago Tribune, Los Angeles Times,
six other newspapers and 23 television stations. </p>
<p>The case is In re Tribune Co., 08-13141, U.S. Bankruptcy
Court, District Delaware (Wilmington). </p>
<p>Lyondell Settles Environmental Claim to Ease Confirmation </p>
<p>Chemical producer Lyondell Chemical Co. negotiated a
settlement of $5.5 billion in environmental claims, in the
process removing an obstacle to approval of the reorganization
plan at the April 23 confirmation hearing. </p>
<p>Under the plan and the settlement, Lyondell will transfer
specific environmentally impaired properties it owns to a trust
along with cash to perform a cleanup. </p>
<p>All together, the U.S. government and seven states will
have approved unsecured claims aggregating $1.18 billion. In
addition, Lyondell will contribute $108.4 million cash to the
trust and pay another $61.6 million to settle other claims. </p>
<p>The settlement will be up for approval at the April 23
confirmation hearing. To read other Bloomberg coverage, click
here. </p>
<p>Financing for Lyondell''s plan includes a backstopped $2.8
billion equity rights offering plus $5 billion in debt financing
via an asset-backed facility, a note offering, and a term loan. </p>
<p>To read about the plan and the settlement with the
unsecured creditors'' committee, click here and look for the
Lyondell item in the March 9 Bloomberg bankruptcy report. </p>
<p>Lyondell and affiliate Equistar Chemicals LP, together
making up the third-largest independent producer of chemicals,
filed under Chapter 11 in January 2009, listing assets of $33.8
billion and debt totaling $30.3 billion. The parent
LyondellBasell Industries AF SCA filed under Chapter 11 in
April. Including the parent and European subsidiaries, the
assets were $40 billion in September 2008. Total revenue in 2007
was $44 billion. The Lyondell petition says its assets are $27.1
billion against $19.3 billion in debt while Equistar listed
assets and debt both totaling $9 billion. </p>
<p>The case is Lyondell Chemical Co., 09-10023, U.S.
Bankruptcy Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). </p>
<p>Madoff Trustee Changing Market-Maker Business Sale </p>
<p>The trustee for Bernard L. Madoff Investment Securities
Inc. agreed to modify the contract with Castor Pollux Securities
LLC, which purchased the Madoff market-making business in June
2009 for $1 million cash plus as much as another $24.5 million
based on gross revenue through December 2013. Without modifying
the contract, the trustee said in his March 30 bankruptcy court
filing that Castor Pollux, now formally named Surge Trading
Inc., would go out of business. </p>
<p>So far, Surge has paid the upfront price plus $3.39 million
on the earnout. Surge''s problems arise from the remainder of the
earnout that represents a contingent liability precluding the
company from compliance with net capital requirements and
blocking the auditor from certifying the 2009 financial
statements. </p>
<p>To solve the problem, the Madoff trustee agreed that Surge
could transfer the business to a newly formed subsidiary not
directly liable for the earnout. The trustee said he negotiated
provisions in the agreement "to mitigate" the possibly of not
being paid. </p>
<p>The agreement will come to bankruptcy court for approval at
an April 16 hearing. </p>
<p>The Madoff firm began liquidating in December 2008 with the
appointment of a trustee under the SIPA. Madoff himself went
into an involuntary Chapter 7 liquidation in April. His
bankruptcy case was consolidated with the firm''s liquidation. </p>
<p>The liquidation case is Securities Investor Protection
Corp. v. Bernard L. Madoff Investment Securities Inc., 08-01789,
U.S. Bankruptcy Court, Southern District New York (Manhattan).
The criminal case is U.S. v. Madoff, 09-cr-00213, U.S. District
Court for the Southern District of New York (Manhattan). </p>
<p>BankUnited Wants Exclusivity until Tax Return Filed </p>
<p>BankUnited Financial Corp., the holding company whose bank
was taken over and sold by regulators in May, is proposing a
novel approach for a deadline on the exclusive right to propose
a Chapter 11 plan. </p>
<p>BankUnited says that tax attributes are among the "most
valuable assets." The holding company is currently in the
process of selecting tax advisers to prepare the return for the
period ended in September. </p>
<p>The tax attributes include net operating loss carrybacks,
refund rights and loss carryforwards. </p>
<p>BankUnited says that a plan can''t be worked out until there
is a good picture of the tax situation. Therefore, the holding
company wants so-called exclusivity extended until 90 days after
the tax return is filed. </p>
<p>A major issue in the case is the $4.9 billion claim filed
by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corp. as receiver for the
failed bank subsidiary. While BankUnited believes a
"substantial portion" of the claim is "simply invalid,"
leaving the claim untouched would "dominate the distribution
scheme under any plan and significantly dilute the return
available to other creditors." </p>
<p>BankUnited filed lists of assets and creditors, showing
$557 million owing to unsecured creditors. There are no secured
claims. Assets were listed for $21 million. </p>
<p>The bank''s failure cost the FDIC $4.9 billion. It had
deposits of $8.6 billion and $12.8 billion in assets. Debt of
the Coral Gables, Florida-based holding company includes $120
million on convertible senior notes, $12.5 million of junior
subordinated debentures, $184 million in mandatorily convertible
senior notes known as HiMeds, and $237 million in trust
preferred securities. </p>
<p>The case is In re BankUnited Financial Corp., 09-19940,
U.S. Bankruptcy Court, Southern District Florida (Miami). </p>
<p>Control of W Hotel Union Square Thrown into Doubt </p>
<p>Whether one of three mezzanine lenders to the W New York
Union Square hotel had the right to file a Chapter 11 petition
on March 23 was thrown into doubt yesterday in a lawsuit filed
in bankruptcy court by Union Square Real Holding Corp., the new
owner of a mezzanine loan on the hotel. </p>
<p>In the complaint, USRHC is asking the bankruptcy judge to
prevent the bankrupt mezzanine lender, Hotels Union Square Mezz
1 LLC, from putting the hotel itself into Chapter 11. </p>
<p>USRHC explains in the complaint how the $285 million
acquisition of the hotel in October 2006 was financed by a $115
million first mortgage, three mezzanine loans totaling $117
million, and a $53 million equity investment by an affiliate of
Dubai World. </p>
<p>USRHC spent $3.6 million on March 9 to buy a second $37
million mezzanine loan. USRHC made the new investment to protect
its $53 million investment in the hotel. </p>
<p>Exercising rights under a pledge agreement, USRHC alleges
that on March 22 it removed all of the officers of Hotels Union
Square Mezz 1 LLC. Nonetheless, according to the complaint, the
incumbent officers went ahead and authorized the Chapter 11
filing on March 23. </p>
<p>The complaint says that Hotels Union Square Mezz 1 LLC has
a pledge of the ownership interest in the hotel itself. USRHC
said it will ask the bankruptcy judge to block a Chapter 11
filing for the hotel itself. </p>
<p>A date for a hearing on a motion for a temporary injunction
hadn''t been set by yesterday afternoon. HSRHC wants to prevent a
bankruptcy by the hotel to fend off a default on the $115
million first mortgage which is current. USRHC says income is
sufficient to pay operating expenses and debt service the first
mortgage. </p>
<p>The case is In re Hotels Union Square Mezz 1 LLC, 10-10971,
U.S. Bankruptcy Court, District of Delaware (Wilmington). </p>
<p>Neenah Submits Plan Negotiated Before February Filing </p>
<p>Neenah Foundry Co., a producer of cast-iron products such
as manhole covers and sewer grates, filed a reorganization plan
and explanatory disclosure statement designed to bring
conclusion to the second venture into Chapter 11. </p>
<p>Neenah filed under Chapter 11 on Feb. 3 after hashing out
agreement on a plan with holders of 55 percent of secured notes
and all the subordinated notes. </p>
<p>The hearing for approval of the disclosure statement is
scheduled for April 27. </p>
<p>The plan would exchange the $237.5 million outstanding on
9.5 percent senior secured notes for 97 percent of the new stock
plus a new $50 million secured loan. Tontine Capital Partners
LP, the controlling shareholder and holder of the $88.7 million
in 12.5 percent senior subordinated notes, is to have 3 percent
of the new equity plus warrants to purchase 10 percent. </p>
<p>The draft disclosure statement has blanks where senior and
subordinated creditors ultimately will be told the predicted
percentage recovery. </p>
<p>The $55.2 million secured working capital loan is to be
paid in full or reinstated. </p>
<p>Trade suppliers are to be paid in full. The petition listed
assets of $287 million against debt totaling $449.1 million. </p>
<p>Neenah was in Chapter 11 before. The company confirmed a
prepackaged plan in September 2003 that had been filed the
previous month. The plan exchanged senior subordinated notes for
$100 million in new subordinated debt, $30 million cash and half
of the stock. Trade creditors were paid in full. </p>
<p>Neenah, from a Wisconsin town of the same name, reported a
$150 million net loss for the Sept. 30 fiscal year on net sales
of $333 million. In fiscal 2008, net sales were $511 million,
and the net loss was $12 million. </p>
<p>The case is In re Neenah Enterprises Inc., 10-10360, U.S.
Bankruptcy Court, District of Delaware (Wilmington). </p>
<p>Lake at Las Vegas Scheduled for June 21 Confirmation </p>
<p>Lake at Las Vegas Joint Venture LLC scheduled a June 21
confirmation hearing for approval of the Chapter 11 plan when
the bankruptcy judge this week approved the explanatory
disclosure statement. </p>
<p>The committee representing unsecured creditors supports the
plan following an agreement with secured lenders owed $626
million. The committee believes that the plan has a better
outcome than success in a lawsuit against the lenders. </p>
<p>The plan for the master developer of the Lake Las Vegas
Resort 17 miles from the Las Vegas Strip allows a lawsuit go to
forward against Sid Bass, Lee Bass and other former owners of
the project. Creditors drop the suit the committee began in July
against an affiliate of Credit Suisse Group AG, which was a
secured lender and agent for the secured creditors. </p>
<p>The plan is to convert the secured lenders'' $127 million
loan for the reorganization into 94 percent of the new equity.
For their more than $627 million in pre-bankruptcy secured
claims, the lenders will take 1 percent of the new equity,
warrants that currently would have no value, and 80 percent of
net recoveries from the lawsuit against the insiders. </p>
<p>Unsecured creditors are expected to recover 4.5 percent
from a $1 million cash fund plus 20 percent of lawsuit
recoveries. </p>
<p>Lot owners will waive claims in return for remapping
properties so they will have marketable title. </p>
<p>The disclosure statement says that the plan is better for
unsecured creditors than victory in the lawsuit because the
creditors find no defects in the $127 million secured claim
financing the reorganization. The disclosure statement says that
the property is not worth enough to pay off the so-called DIP
loan. </p>
<p>The suit contended that the loan from Credit Suisse in 2004
was a fraudulent transfer because all but $100 million from the
$560 million loan went directly to the owners. </p>
<p>The formal lists of assets and liabilities showed $719
million in claims belonging to secured creditors, with the first
mortgage totaling $671 million. </p>
<p>The development is a 3,600-acre master-planned community
with a 320-acre man-made lake next to the Lake Mead National
Recreational Area. It has three golf course, two hotels, a
casino, retail stores and more than 1,600 completed residential
units. The Chapter 11 filing was in July 2008. </p>
<p>The case is Lake at Las Vegas Joint Venture LLC, 08-17814,
U.S. Bankruptcy Court, District of Nevada (Las Vegas). </p>
<p>Hawaii Medical Taps Gemino for Possible Financing </p>
<p>Hawaii Medical Center LLC, the operator of two hospitals in
Honolulu, filed a motion on March 30 along with the creditors''
committee for authority to pay $75,000 in fees so Gemino
Healthcare Finance LLC will undertake the financial
investigation necessary to commit to provide $10 million in
financing for the hospitals'' reorganization plan. </p>
<p>Three plans have been competing for the right to reorganize
the hospitals. The bankruptcy judge already approved a
disclosure statement explaining the Chapter 11 plan proposed by
St. Francis Healthcare System of Hawaii. The St. Francis plan is
scheduled for a May 24 confirmation hearing. </p>
<p>The bankruptcy judge has yet to give formal approval for
the disclosure statements accompanying the plans proposed by the
hospitals and the official creditors'' committee. </p>
<p>The hospitals say they need financing from Gemino to be in
place by May 23 so their plan could be confirmed instead of the
St. Francis plan on May 24. </p>
<p>The hospitals originally filed for Chapter 11
reorganization in Delaware in August 2008. The cases were moved
to Hawaii in September 2008. The hospitals have 342 beds in
total. </p>
<p>The case is CHA Hawaii LLC, 08-01369, U.S. Bankruptcy
Court, District of Hawaii (Honolulu). </p>
<p>New Filings </p>
<p>Medical Imaging Developer Eigen Files in Delaware </p>
<p>Eigen Inc., a developer of technology to view and biopsy
prostate glands using three-dimensional ultrasound, filed a
Chapter 11 petition on March 30 in Delaware. </p>
<p>The Grass Valley, California-based company owes more than
$20 million to the secured lender Kazi Management IV LLC.
Unsecured creditors are owed $1 million, with half representing
a claim held by General Electric Capital Corp. </p>
<p>Before bankruptcy, Kazi was foreclosing. The foreclosure
was enjoined by a state court in California by former employees,
bankruptcy court papers say. </p>
<p>Kazi is providing $2 million of new money financing for the
Chapter 11 case. </p>
<p>The case is In re Eigen Inc., 10-11061, U.S. Bankruptcy
Court, District of Delaware (Wilmington). </p>
<p>U.S. to Help Grant Forest Sale to Georgia-Pacific </p>
<p>Grant Forest Products Inc., a Canada-based producer of
oriented strand board, filed a Chapter 15 petition late
yesterday in Delaware for protection from creditors in the U.S. </p>
<p>Grant filed for reorganization in Ontario Superior Court in
June. The company has plants in Ontario, Alberta and South
Carolina. </p>
<p>The petition said assets and debt both exceed $500 million.
Debt includes $398 million on first-lien obligations and $150
million on second-lien claims. </p>
<p>The court in Canada already approved a sale of assets to
Georgia-Pacific LLC. The Chapter 15 case in part would assist in
implementation of the sale. </p>
<p>If the bankruptcy judge in Delaware concludes that Canada
is home to the "foreign main proceeding," he will permanently
halt creditor actions in the U.S. and assist in implementation
of the Canadian reorganization. Most unsecured creditors in the
U.S. are not to be affected by the reorganization. </p>
<p>The case is In re Grant Forest Products Inc., 10-11132,
U.S. Bankruptcy Court, District of Delaware (Wilmington). </p>
<p>Watch List </p>
<p>Oil Producer Petroflow Has Problems with Lenders </p>
<p>Petroflow Energy Ltd., an oil and natural gas production
company from Denver, was unable to sell the Oklahoma properties
by March 7. As a result, a forbearance agreement ended with bank
lenders, the company said in a statement yesterday. </p>
<p>As a result, the banks terminated Petroflow''s hedging
positions, generating $4.75 million that paid down the bank debt
to $98.75 million. The company said that the banks took
operational control of the primary operating accounts. </p>
<p>Compounding the problems, Petroflow said a farmout
agreement was terminated for an alleged default. As a result,
purchasers are holding back payments, and liens have been placed
against the wells. </p>
<p>Petroflow has yet to file audited financial statements for
2008 and 2009. The company said in the statement that the new
auditors expect to complete the filings in Canada by April 9. </p>
<p>Petroflow said there is no assurance it can continue as a
going concern. </p>
<p>The closing high for Petroflow''s stock in the last two
years was $9.11 on June 17, 2008. In trading yesterday before
the announcement, the stock was above 26 cents. After the
announcement, the stock traded as low as 19 cents and closed at
22 cents, down 5 cents for the day. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jef Feeley and Janelle Lawrence" date="Apr 02, 2010  2:06 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-04-02/pfizer-agrees-to-first-settlement-of-a-neurontin-related-suicide-lawsuit.html"><headline>Pfizer Agrees to First Settlement of a Neurontin-Related Suicide Lawsuit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. agreed to pay about
$400,000 to settle a lawsuit mid-trial that blamed its Neurontin
epilepsy medicine for helping cause a Massachusetts man''s
suicide, two people familiar with the accord said. </p>
<p>It''s the first settlement over a Neurontin-related suicide
claim. Pfizer, the world''s largest drugmaker, agreed yesterday
to resolve allegations by Hartley Shearer''s family in Boston
federal court that its Warner-Lambert unit knew the drug posed a
suicide risk and failed to disclose it to patients and doctors. </p>
<p>Pfizer agreed to settle the case for less than its
defense costs remaining in this case, said Rob Haralson, a
spokesman for New York-based Pfizer. Pfizer maintains that it
has strong defenses to each of plaintiff''s claims. </p>
<p>Pfizer faces more than 1,000 lawsuits accusing it of
illegally promoting Neurontin for unapproved uses and helping to
cause some users'' suicides. The settlement comes a week after
another Boston jury ordered Pfizer to pay more than $140 million
in damages to an insurer over the drug. Pfizer has denied any
wrongdoing in connection with its handling of Neurontin. </p>
<p>Its Warner-Lambert subsidiary pleaded guilty in 2004 to
criminal charges filed by the Justice Department in connection
with allegations it illegally marketed Neurontin and paid a
$430 million fine. Pfizer acquired Warner-Lambert in 2000. </p>
<p>For 16 Months </p>
<p>The 57-year-old Shearer, a part-time lecturer at Williams
College in Williamstown, Massachusetts, took Neurontin for 16
months before killing himself, according to court filings. </p>
<p>Shearer''s family contends his doctor wasn''t aware of
Neurontin''s suicide risk when he prescribed the drug to help
deal with pain generated by a 1999 stroke. </p>
<p>Pfizer argued Shearer battled depression for most of his
life and was taking a dozen prescription drugs, including an
anti-depressant, when he shot himself to death with a .357
Magnum handgun in 2002. </p>
<p>The drugmaker''s lawyers also noted Shearer argued with his
wife the day he killed himself and left a suicide note saying it
was the last time she would leave me powerless. </p>
<p>Ron Rosenkranz, a lawyer for the Shearers, declined to
comment when contacted yesterday evening. Today, he told U.S.
District Judge William G. Young at a hearing in Boston that the
amount of the settlement, while confidential, is substantially
less than the amount reported. </p>
<p>An Iffy Case'' </p>
<p>This is an iffy case, Young told jurors after
announcing the accord. This is why they settled. Iffy on both
sides. The people who said the settlement was about $400,000
declined to be identified because the terms are confidential. </p>
<p>By prescribing Neurontin as a painkiller, Shearer''s doctor
was recommending a so-called off-label use of the drug. While
doctors may prescribe a medicine for uses not approved by the
U.S. Food and Drug Administration, companies are barred from
promoting products for off-label uses. </p>
<p>Dr. Charles King, a former Harvard University business
professor, told jurors in the Shearer case yesterday that
Warner-Lambert officials used illegal off-label marketing
tactics to turn Neurontin into a blockbuster drug. </p>
<p>They took a drug that was expected to generate
$500 million over its lifetime and turned it into a drug that
sold roughly $10 billion, said King, an economist who
testified for the Shearers as an expert on pharmaceutical-
industry marketing practices. </p>
<p>The Shearer suit was the second product-liability case over
Neurontin to go to trial. </p>
<p>In July 2009, a Peabody, Massachusetts, family dropped its
suit over the suicide of a woman who was taking the drug. The
family was in the second day of trial in federal court in Boston
when it decided to dismiss the case. </p>
<p>Misleading Doctors </p>
<p>Another jury in Boston''s federal court March 25 said Pfizer
must pay Kaiser Foundation Health Plan Inc. $47.4 million for
misleading doctors on whether Neurontin was effective for
illnesses such as migraines and bipolar disorder. </p>
<p>The jury found the drugmaker violated the federal Racketeer
Influenced and Corrupt Organizations Act, or RICO, and
California''s Unfair Competition Law. </p>
<p>The Oakland, California-based insurer is a unit of Kaiser
Permanente, the largest U.S. nonprofit health maintenance
organization. Under RICO, the amount of actual damages will be
tripled to $142.1 million. </p>
<p>Pfizer bought Warner-Lambert for $120 billion in 2000 and
Pharmacia for $54 billion three years later. </p>
<p>$430 Million Settlement </p>
<p>Along with the $430 million settlement of allegations over
Neurontin, Pfizer also paid $2.3 billion in October 2009 to
resolve U.S. Justice Department allegations it illegally
marketed the painkiller Bextra and three other drugs. </p>
<p>When you acquire Warner-Lambert you get Neurontin, and
when you acquire Pharmacia you get Bextra, and some of these
problems came with the acquisitions, Jeffrey Kindler, Pfizer''s
chief executive officer told the New York Times March 31. It
doesn''t change the facts or our responsibility for them. </p>
<p>The Shearer case is Shearer v. Pfizer Inc., 07-cv-11428-
PBS, U.S. District Court, District of Massachusetts (Boston). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Katherine Burton" date="Apr 02, 2010  1:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-04-02/goldman-fund-buys-into-ganek-s-4-billion-hedge-fund.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Buyout Firm Acquires Stake in Ganek''s $4 Billion Hedge Fund</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A Goldman Sachs Group Inc. buyout
firm bought a minority stake in David Ganek''s $4 billion Level
Global Investors LP, adding a hedge fund that can bet on rising
as well as falling stock prices globally. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs''s Petershill Fund Offshore LP, a $1 billion
fund set up to buy minority stakes in hedge funds, won''t get any
management or investment decision-making role with the
acquisition, according to a letter Ganek sent to clients
yesterday. New York-based Level Global said it will use the
proceeds from the sale to help attract and retain top talent. </p>
<p>We believe this investment by Petershill is an important
milestone in the continued development of Level Global''s
investment management platform as an institutional quality
business, Ganek and managing partner Anthony Chiasson said in
the letter, a copy of which was obtained by Bloomberg News. </p>
<p>Ganek, an alumnus of Steven A. Cohen''s Stamford,
Connecticut-based SAC Capital Advisors LLC, founded Level Global
in 2003. The firm has 64 employees, of which 25 are investment
professionals. Petershill has interests in three London-based
funds, Capula Investment Management LLP, Winton Capital
Management Ltd. and Trafalgar Asset Managers Ltd., as well as in
Greenwich, Connecticut-based Shumway Capital Partners LLC. </p>
<p>Andy Merrill, a spokesman for Level Global, and Melissa
Daly, a spokeswoman for New York-based Goldman Sachs, declined
to comment. </p>
<p>Hedge funds are loosely regulated private partnerships that
can bet on rising or falling prices of any securities. </p>
<p>For Related News and Information:
Today''s top fund stories: TOP FUND GO
Hedge-fund rankings: WHF GO
Hedge-fund flows: TNI HEDGE FLOWS GO
Most-read hedge fund news: MNI HEDGE GO
Hedge Fund Home Page: HFND GO
Hedge Fund Holdings: FLNG GO </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki and Ian Katz" date="Apr 02, 2010  1:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-04-02/jpmorgan-goldman-sachs-resist-nuns-proposal-for-greater-swaps-disclosure.html"><headline>JPMorgan, Goldman Sachs Resist Nuns'' Proposal for Greater Swaps Disclosure</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and
JPMorgan Chase  Co. aren''t doing "God''s work" when it comes
to derivatives, according to investor groups of nuns and
priests. </p>
<p>Shareholders will vote starting this month on proposals
sponsored by the Sisters of Charity of Saint Elizabeth and 14
other religious organizations, asking Goldman Sachs, JPMorgan,
Citigroup Inc. and Bank of America Corp. to give more
information on the collateral used in their derivatives trading. </p>
<p>It''s the first time the four banks, among the largest U.S.
swaps dealers, will put to a nonbinding vote a call to explain
how collateral of derivatives customers is used and to keep it
from other accounts. Congress is considering bills that would
require more derivatives deals be processed through
clearinghouses, privately owned third parties that guarantee
transactions and keep track of collateral and margin. </p>
<p>"The use of these instruments, if they''re not disclosed by
the dealers and the information made available, by their very
nature can contribute to systemic risk," said Father Seamus
Finn, a director with the Missionary Oblates of Mary Immaculate
in Washington, D.C., one of the co-sponsors of the resolutions. </p>
<p>The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission, in February
and March decisions, backed the religious groups'' bid to put the
proposal up for a vote by shareholders of JPMorgan, Bank of
America and Citigroup. New York-based Goldman Sachs, the most
profitable firm in Wall Street history, agreed separately to add
the resolution to its proxy statement. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs Chief Executive Officer Lloyd Blankfein''s
remark in November that he''s a banker doing "God''s work" was
an "inscrutable comment," Finn said. "He was part of a group
of very senior people from the banking sector who appeared to
have been advised by their PR people to acknowledge their
mistakes but more pointedly assert the uprightness of their
intentions." </p>
<p>The ICCR </p>
<p>Blankfein, 55, didn''t mean for the remark to be taken
seriously, Goldman Sachs spokesman Lucas van Praag said that
month. </p>
<p>The religious groups, members of the Interfaith Center on
Corporate Responsibility, hold shares in the four banks ranging
from 100 at Goldman Sachs to 63,977 at Citigroup. The New York-
based ICCR''s 300 members include money managers for various
religious organizations, including Jewish and Buddhist, and
pension and mutual funds that oversee $100 billion in assets,
according to the organization''s Web site. </p>
<p>"The immorality of the financial crisis is rooted in the
fact that these derivatives contracts weren''t based on creating
value and didn''t create incentives for people to keep their
promises," said Laura Berry, a former large-cap portfolio
manager for Citigroup who is executive director of the ICCR,
which is coordinating the proxy votes for the religious groups. </p>
<p>200 Proposals </p>
<p>ICCR''s members have placed 200 social and environmental
measures on proxy ballots this year, including the use of
antibiotics in animal feed at Tyson Foods Inc. and carbon
emissions at Wal-Mart Stores Inc., Berry said. The organization
filed its first shareholder resolution in 1971, pressuring
General Motors Corp. to divest from South Africa because of what
was then the country''s apartheid policy of racial segregation. </p>
<p>"They do very good work," said Charles Elson, director of
the John L. Weinberg Center for Corporate Governance at the
University of Delaware. "I don''t always agree with them, but
some of the stuff they''ve done is quite good." </p>
<p>JPMorgan, Bank of America, Goldman Sachs, Citigroup and
Morgan Stanley were parties to 96 percent of the $293 trillion
in over-the-counter derivatives trades made by the top 25 U.S.
bank-holding companies as of Dec. 31, according to the Office of
the Comptroller of the Currency. The religious groups didn''t
seek to place a resolution on Morgan Stanley''s proxy because
none have held the bank''s shares long enough, said Finn. </p>
<p>Banks Say Reject </p>
<p>The religious organizations want the four broker-dealers to
disclose internal policies on how the collateral posted by
derivatives customers is used. They''re also asking the lenders
to segregate the collateral from other accounts, which would
prohibit it from being used for anything else. </p>
<p>"We were very much concerned about where''s the collateral,
is this all recorded, do we know who the second or third party
is to this, the counterparties and so on," said Sister Barbara
Aires, coordinator of corporate responsibility at the Sisters of
Charity of Saint Elizabeth, in Convent Station, New Jersey. </p>
<p>The banks have urged shareholders in their proxy
statements to reject the proposal. JPMorgan said that
segregating assets could expose it to price volatility and
potential losses "when the firm needs to liquidate collateral
quickly upon a default." </p>
<p>JPMorgan spokeswoman Jennifer Zuccarelli, Goldman Sachs
spokesman Michael DuVally, Bank of America spokesman Scott
Silvestri and Citigroup spokesman Stephen Cohen declined to
comment beyond the companies'' proxy statements. </p>
<p>Proposals focusing on specific business issues like
derivatives trading "tend not to do well" in shareholder
votes, said Elson. "They''re really issues of the board. But in
this climate, you can''t say anything is for sure." </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry></news>