
<news><entry author="By Hui-yong Yu, Daniel Taub and Brian Louis" date="Apr 17, 2009  2:40 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-04-17/general-growth-s-bankruptcy-may-let-rivals-buy-malls-update1-.html"><headline>General Growth''s Bankruptcy May Let Rivals Buy Malls</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>When General Growth Properties Inc. (GGP)
bought Rouse Co. for $11.3 billion in 2004, then-Chief Executive
Officer John Bucksbaum said the deal amounted to five years
worth of acquisitions in one fell swoop. Now the challenge
will be keeping those assets. </p>
<p>Purchasing Rouse gave General Growth malls including
Boston''s Faneuil Hall, New York''s South Street Seaport and the
Woodlands in Houston. It also added almost $10 billion in debt
to its balance sheet and led the second-largest U.S. mall owner
to file for Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection yesterday. </p>
<p>Paying the highest price was not the fatal flaw, said
Jim Sullivan, head of retail real estate investment trust
research at Green Street Advisors, a Newport Beach, California-based property research company. The fatal flaw was financing
this giant purchase exclusively with debt. </p>
<p>Mall owners Simon Property Group Inc. (SPG), Macerich Co. (MAC),
Vornado Realty Trust and Taubman Centers Inc. (TCO) rallied yesterday
on speculation the biggest real estate bankruptcy in the U.S.
will allow competitors to buy General Growth''s assets at a
discount. </p>
<p>Hedge fund manager William Ackman, whose firm owns about 25
percent of General Growth, said he doesn''t think the real estate
investment trust will have to resort to a fire sale. </p>
<p>The probability of Simon or the other mall REITs buying
any of General Growth Properties on the cheap is zero, Ackman
said in a telephone interview. They''re not going to be forced
to do anything because they''re in bankruptcy. </p>
<h2>Credit Crunch </h2>
<p>The Rouse acquisition gave General Growth, the owner or
manager of about 200 properties in 44 states, premier malls with
strong occupancy rates and tenants. The company already has
tried to sell South Street Seaport as well as Las Vegas assets
such as Fashion Show Mall and The Shoppes at the Palazzo. </p>
<p>Now that it''s gone Chapter 11, the playbook starts from
scratch, said Jonathan Miniman, senior analyst at ING Clarion
Real Estate Securities, which manages $10.8 billion. This
could be a huge opportunity for the Simons or Vornados of the
world to buy some trophy assets at some pretty good prices. </p>
<p>Indianapolis-based Simon, the largest U.S. shopping mall
owner, has stakes in 386 properties. Vornado Realty Trust (VNO), one
of the country''s biggest office landlords, also owns or manages
more than 31 million square feet of retail properties in the
U.S. and Puerto Rico. ING Clarion is Simon''s seventh-largest
shareholder, with 9 million shares, or 3.7 percent, on Dec. 31. </p>
<h2>High Debt </h2>
<p>The Rouse portfolio for the most part was a really high-quality portfolio, said James S. Corl, managing director for
distressed real estate investments at private-equity firm
Siguler Guff  Co. in New York. Still, with the price General
Growth paid, there was a reason why they were the winning
bidder. They weren''t disciplined on the acquisition front, and
certainly not on the financing front. </p>
<p>The Chicago-based company was blocked by the global credit
freeze from refinancing some of the $27.3 billion of debt it
amassed over the years. General Growth''s debt-to-asset ratio was
92 percent at the time it sought protection, according to the
filing. </p>
<p>The bankruptcy may remake the nation''s mall business and
allow Simon to strengthen its position as the No. 1 mall owner,
said Dan Fasulo, managing director at real estate research firm
Real Capital Analytics. </p>
<h2>Distress'' Cycle </h2>
<p>General Growth''s filing is the beginning of the distress
cycle, Fasulo said, and may lead other companies to fail. </p>
<p>General Growth''s competitors may not have an easy or
immediate way to capitalize on its woes. The company said it
wants to stay intact. Its success may depend on convincing the
bankruptcy judge to consolidate its debts until credit markets
recover. </p>
<p>General Growth on March 23 said that a deadline for
bondholders to agree to new terms for $2.25 billion in debt
expired without the minimum number of holders accepting the
agreement. General Growth said on March 30 it was continuing to
negotiate with creditors. </p>
<p>We''re not looking for wholesale sales of assets,
General Growth President Thomas Nolan said yesterday in an
interview with Bloomberg Television. We intend to emerge as a
leaner company. </p>
<p>Ackman, whose Pershing Square Capital Management LP will
provide General Growth with $375 million in financing to help
run the company during the Chapter 11 process, may join the
board after the court approves the interim financing. Pershing
is the company''s third-largest shareholder. </p>
<h2>Low-Leverage Competition </h2>
<p>Financing for acquisitions remains scarce and some of
General Growth''s individual assets are debt-laden, making them
potentially less attractive to an acquirer. </p>
<p>The nine regional mall owners tracked by Green Street have
an average leverage to asset ratio of 75 percent, according to a
March report by the firm. </p>
<p>CBL  Associates Properties Inc. (CBL) of Chattanooga, Tennessee,
Glimcher Realty Trust (GRT) of Columbus, Ohio and Philadelphia-based
Pennsylvania Real Estate Investment Trust (PEI) have the highest
leverage ratios, at more than 90 percent. Only companies with
relatively low debt ratios, such as Sydney-based Westfield at 56
percent, and Simon and Taubman, each at 60 percent, will likely
have the financial wherewithal to buy assets from General
Growth, said Sullivan. </p>
<h2>No Thaw </h2>
<p>There''s very little sign that the real estate capital
markets are unfreezing in a huge way, said Sullivan. Even
for those raising equity, it''s been very expensive. </p>
<p>Simon on March 20 sold 15 million shares at $31.50 each,
raising $472.5 million, and $650 million of 10-year notes. The
notes were priced to yield 10.75 percent. By comparison, last
May, Simon sold 10-year bonds that were priced to yield 6.14
percent. </p>
<p>They have some very good assets, Stephen E. Sterrett,
Simon''s chief financial officer, said yesterday in a telephone
interview. Some of them would probably fit very well in our
portfolio, but now is probably not the right time to talk about
that. </p>
<p>General Growth in October put three Las Vegas properties up
for sale, the Fashion Show Mall, the Grand Canal Shoppes and the
Shoppes at the Palazzo. Simon''s Forum Shops at Caesars is next
to the Caesars Palace hotel and casino on the Las Vegas Strip. </p>
<p>The issue with the Vegas assets was they were extremely
overleveraged, said Miniman. Fashion Show is one of the best
assets in the country but you couldn''t refinance it. </p>
<h2>No Sale </h2>
<p>General Growth last month received offers of almost $400
million for properties including Faneuil Hall and the South
Street Seaport, according to a person familiar with the matter.
More than 10 bids were received. It didn''t sell. </p>
<p>By going the Chapter 11 route, it helps them maximize
asset values, said Miniman. I think the courts will force
them to sell assets to pay down some of the debt and emerge as a
smaller, better, re-equitized company. </p>
<p>After trying for seven months to refinance its debt,
General Growth filed for bankruptcy, listing $29.5 billion in
assets and debts of about $27.3 billion. General Growth will
continue operating. The company previously suspended its cash
dividend and cut its workforce by 20 percent. </p>
<p>The Rouse transaction sealed the company''s fate, said
Sullivan of Green Street. </p>
<p>General Growth bought Rouse after a bidding contest with
Simon, Westfield and others in what was then the largest
takeover of a real estate investment trust. </p>
<h2>Missed Chance </h2>
<p>By the time some of the debt came due, the credit crunch
halted bank lending and pushed the U.S. into a recession that
cut consumer spending and property values. Commercial real
estate prices in the U.S. dropped 15 percent last year,
according to Moody''s Investors Service. Retail sales in the U.S.
fell in March as job losses forced consumers to pull back. </p>
<p>General Growth had chances to refinance since 2004 and
didn''t take advantage of them, said Sullivan. Now it faces the
prospect of emerging from bankruptcy a smaller player in an
industry that has consolidated to the point where an
oligopoly of publicly traded REITs own about 80 percent of
the country''s malls, he said. </p>
<p>Bigger is better in the mall business, said Sullivan.
The more malls you own, the stronger the relationship is with
your tenants. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Carla Main" date="Apr 20, 2009  8:47 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-04-20/general-growth-abitibi-dayton-superior-bankruptcy-update1-.html"><headline>General Growth, Abitibi, Dayton Superior: Bankruptcy</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>General Growth Properties Inc. (GGP)
agreed to pay a $15 million commitment fee to William Ackman''s
Pershing Square Capital Management LP under an agreement for a
$375 million bankruptcy loan. </p>
<p>The loan is to fund General Growth''s operations during a
Chapter 11 case that it filed on April 16, as well as to pay off
about $210 million in existing debt owed to Goldman Sachs Group
Inc., according to court papers. </p>
<p>General Growth, which has about $27 billion in debt, will
pay an interest rate of the London Interbank Offered Rate plus
12 percentage points, according to a regulatory filing on April
17 by Pershing Square. </p>
<p>It is anticipated that William A. Ackman will join the
board of directors of General Growth once the loan is approved
by the bankruptcy court, though the loan isn''t contingent on his
appointment, the SEC filing said. </p>
<p>U.S. Bankruptcy Judge Allan Gropper scheduled another
hearing in the case for May 8. </p>
<p>Pershing Square also will receive warrants to buy 4.9
percent of the Chicago-based real estate investment trust''s new
equity when it emerges from bankruptcy, the filing said. General
Growth also has the option under certain circumstances to use a
put option that will require Ackman to convert some or all of
the outstanding balance of the loan to equity, according to the
filing. </p>
<p>A lawyer representing the company told Gropper at an April
16 hearing that the opportunity to convert the loan to equity
was an important inducement to the company in taking the loan. </p>
<p>The U.S. Trustee''s Office, the arm of the Justice
Department that monitors bankruptcy cases, has scheduled an
April 24 meeting at the New York Marriott Marquis to form an
unsecured creditors'' committee in the case. </p>
<p>Gropper on April 16 gave General Growth the right to use
so-called cash collateral owed to lenders to continue operating
its business until he decides on the bankruptcy loan. According
to court papers filed with the company''s Chapter 11 petition,
the company will have about $122.4 million in cash on hand at
the end of this week and expects that amount to rise to $238.7
million by July. </p>
<p>The case is In re General Growth Properties Inc., 09-11977,
U.S. Bankruptcy Court, Southern District of New York. </p>
<p>For more, click here. </p>
<h2>General Growth''s Reliance on Debt May Allow Rivals to Buy Malls </h2>
<p>General Growth Properties Inc.''s purchase of Rouse Co. for
$11.3 billion in 2004 added almost $10 billion in debt to its
balance sheet and led the second-largest U.S. mall owner to file
for Chapter 11 bankruptcy protection April 16, according to
analysts. </p>
<p>Purchasing Rouse gave General Growth malls including
Boston''s Faneuil Hall, New York''s South Street Seaport and the
Woodlands in Houston. Chief Executive Officer John Bucksbaum
said the deal amounted to five years worth of acquisitions in
one fell swoop. </p>
<p>The fatal flaw was financing this giant purchase
exclusively with debt, said Jim Sullivan, head of retail REIT
research at Green Street Advisors, a Newport Beach, California-based property research company. </p>
<p>Mall owners Simon Property Group Inc. (SPG), Macerich Co. (MAC) and
Taubman Centers Inc. (TCO) rallied April 16 on speculation that the
biggest real estate bankruptcy in the U.S. will allow
competitors to buy General Growth assets at a discount. </p>
<p>William Ackman, whose firm owns about 25 percent of General
Growth, said he doesn''t think the real estate investment trust
will have to resort to a fire sale. </p>
<p>The Rouse acquisition gave General Growth, the owner of
about 200 properties in 44 states, premier malls with strong
occupancy rates and tenants. The company already has tried to
sell South Street Seaport as well as Las Vegas developments like
Fashion Show and the Shoppes at the Palazzo. </p>
<p>The Chicago-based company was blocked by the global credit
freeze from refinancing some of the $27.3 billion of debt.
General Growth''s debt-to-asset ratio was 92 percent at the time
it sought protection, according to the filing. </p>
<p>The bankruptcy may remake the nation''s mall business and
allow Simon to strengthen its position as the No. 1 mall owner,
said Dan Fasulo, managing director at real estate research firm
Real Capital Analytics. </p>
<p>For more, click here. </p>
<h2>New Filings </h2>
<p>Abitibi-Consolidated Files for Bankruptcy in U.S. </p>
<p>Abitibi-Consolidated Inc., a Canadian unit of
AbitibiBowater Inc., sought bankruptcy protection in the U.S.
after lenders refused to accept a proposed debt restructuring. </p>
<p>Abitibi-Consolidated listed assets and debt of more than $1
billion in a Chapter 15 petition filed April 17 in U.S.
Bankruptcy Court in Wilmington, Delaware. Chapter 15 allows a
company to seek protection from creditors in the U.S. while its
primary bankruptcy case is pending in another country. Abitibi-Consolidated Co. of Canada also sought protection. </p>
<p>The newsprint company said April 18 in a statement that
both courts granted the requests it made April 17 and it will be
able to keep paying employees and fulfilling customer orders.
Also, Abitibi-Consolidated will be allowed to enter into debtor-in-possession financing commitments totaling about $200 million
for certain subsidiaries. </p>
<p>The company said its shares will be delisted from the New
York and Toronto stock exchanges. </p>
<p>AbitibiBowater, North America''s biggest newsprint maker,
sought bankruptcy protection in the U.S. and Canada after
lenders refused to accept a proposed debt restructuring. </p>
<p>For a related story on the AbitibiBowater Inc. bankruptcy,
see Other Updates section below. </p>
<h2>Dayton Superior Files Chapter 11 Bankruptcy Gets Credit Line </h2>
<p>Dayton Superior Corp., a maker of metal forms used in
concrete construction, filed for Chapter 11 bankruptcy
protection and received a $165 million credit line. </p>
<p>Dayton Superior listed assets of $286 million and
liabilities of $413 million in a filing in U.S. Bankruptcy Court
in Wilmington, Delaware, the company said in a statement April
19. </p>
<p>The Dayton, Ohio-based company also said it had received a
one-year, debtor-in possession credit line from General Electric
Co. (GE)''s GE Capital unit to be used to fund operations while the
company reorganizes. </p>
<h2>Washington Gaming Files for U.S. Bankruptcy Protection </h2>
<p>Washington Gaming Inc., a non-hotel gaming and recreation
company, sought protection in a U.S. bankruptcy court in Seattle
on April 15. </p>
<p>The company filed under Chapter 15 of the bankruptcy code,
which lets foreign companies reorganize outside the U.S. while
protecting them from U.S. lawsuits and creditor claims.
Washington Gaming''s main foreign proceeding is in the Supreme
Court of British Columbia in Vancouver, according to papers
filed in the bankruptcy court in Seattle. </p>
<p>Washington Gaming has assets of $1 million to $10 million
and debts of $10 million to $50 million, court papers said.
Washington Gaming''s foreign representative is Deloitte  Touche
LLP. </p>
<p>The U.S. bankruptcy case is In re Washington Gaming, 09-13568, Bankruptcy Court, U.S. District Court, Western District
of Washington (Seattle). The Canadian case is S-092767, In the
Matter of Evergreen Gaming Corp. (TNA) and Washington Gaming Corp., in
the Supreme Court of British Columbia, Vancouver Registry. </p>
<h2>Watch List </h2>
<h2>News-Journal Exploring Chapter 11 Reorganization, Paper Says </h2>
<p>The News-Journal Corp. is seeking to cut its ties with Cox
Enterprises by hiring a bankruptcy lawyer so the company may
explore reorganizing its debt, the paper reported. </p>
<p>The potential bankruptcy filing was mentioned during a
court hearing by Bruce A. Hanna, an attorney representing the
newspaper in a civil suit, the paper said. </p>
<p>Hanna said a Chapter 11 filing would allow the Daytona
Beach, Florida-based paper to continue operating and save
several hundred jobs, the News-Journal reported April 17. </p>
<p>Cox Enterprises Inc. owns 47.5 percent of the newspaper the
paper said. </p>
<h2>GM Is Still Working on New Plan With U.S. to Avoid Bankruptcy </h2>
<p>General Motors Corp. (GM) is still working with U.S. Treasury
officials on its restructuring plan and trying to avoid
bankruptcy, Chief Executive Officer Fritz Henderson said on a
conference call on April 17. He described the process as much
like a private-equity due-diligence process. </p>
<p>The Obama administration said last month that GM''s initial
plan to cut costs and keep a government loan isn''t sufficient.
Henderson says talks continue with debt holders and unions to
get deeper cuts. The company is operating with $13.4 billion in
U.S. loans and probably still will need $4.6 billion in
additional aid this quarter, Henderson said. </p>
<p>No decision has been made on the amount or timing of
additional federal loans beyond the $13.4 billion GM has
borrowed so far, Henderson said. GM initially had asked for as
much as $16.6 billion in additional loans. Henderson didn''t
specify timing for when funding would be needed. </p>
<p>The Detroit automaker has decided to keep its AC Delco
parts unit and has about three bidders for its Hummer brand,
Henderson said. GM also said it has several parties interested
in buying its Saturn and Saab brands and investing in its German
Opel unit. </p>
<p>GM has received expressions of interest for a stake in its
Opel division from well more than six investors, including
financial companies and manufacturers, Henderson said on a
conference call. </p>
<p>To stay out of court protection, Henderson needs agreements
from unions and debt holders for savings beyond GM''s Feb. 17
proposal for slashing $47 billion in unsecured claims by 59
percent. </p>
<p>GM plans to make a formal offer to bondholders by April 27
to exchange their $27.5 billion in claims for equity, according
to a person with knowledge of the discussions. President Barack Obama''s automotive task force told GM to try to restructure its
debt out of court, people familiar with the matter said. </p>
<h2>Notes on Public Companies </h2>
<h2>Unisys Reviews Debt Options as Credit Line Expires Next Month </h2>
<p>Unisys Corp. (UIS), with more than $2 billion of losses in the
past four years, may lose its line of credit next month, making
it harder and more costly to pay off its 2010 notes as sales
dwindle in the recession. </p>
<p>The computer-services manager for the U.S. government
probably won''t be able to renew a $275 million credit line that
expires May 31, according to a filing last month. The line is
provided by banks led by Bank of America Corp. Unisys, which
ended last year with $544 million in cash and has $300 million
of debt due in March, said it''s reviewing options to pay off the
notes. </p>
<p>Unisys had $62.1 million outstanding from the credit line
at the end of last year. </p>
<p>Sales at Unisys have fallen as customers switch to servers
from the mainframe computers that once were its main business.
The company now relies on services such as managing clients''
computer networks for more than 80 percent of sales. </p>
<p>Unisys debt is rated junk, or below investment grade, and
has a negative outlook from Fitch, Moody''s Corp. and Standard 
Poor''s. As of April 16, its borrowing costs were about 12 times
higher than those of Affiliated Computer and 48 times industry
leader IBM, based on debt yields. </p>
<p>For more, click here. </p>
<h2>Six Flags Offers Debt For Equity Exchange on Senior Notes </h2>
<p>Six Flags Inc. (SIX), the New-York based owner of amusement
parks, said it is offering to exchange $588.3 million of its
senior notes for equity. Bond holders would receive about 19
shares for each $1,000 in principle, as well as accrued and
unpaid interest through June 25 on senior notes due 2010, 2013,
and 2014, the company said April 17 in a statement. The proposal
requires 95 percent of the holders to accept the offer and their
tenders would eliminate restrictive covenants and events of
default in the current bond agreement. Six Flags, which missed a
$7 million interest payment, seeks to restructure before a
mandatory Aug. 15 redemption of $287.5 million of Preferred
Income Equity Redeemable Shares, known as PIERS. A Fitch analyst
described this type of offer as a coercive debt exchange. </p>
<p>For more, click here. </p>
<h2>Lender Processing Trades Halted on Inquiry News; Bankruptcy Link </h2>
<p>Lender Processing Services Inc. stock trading was halted on
the morning of April 17 after Dow Jones News Service reported
that the company is being investigated by the U.S. Department of
Justice. The probe is linked to evidence that emerged in a U.S.
Bankruptcy Court. </p>
<p>Federal prosecutors are probing whether Lender Processing''s
automated mortgage systems provided inaccurate information to
lawyers who rely on it for court evidence, Dow Jones said. </p>
<p>The company''s stock plunged as much as 37 percent after Dow
Jones News Service reported that the company was the subject of
an inquiry by the U.S. Trustees Office, an arm of the Justice
Department that monitors bankruptcy courts. </p>
<p>A ruling by Judge Diane Weiss Sigmund in U.S. Bankruptcy
Court in Philadelphia questioned inaccurate court filings made
by HSBC Mortgage Corp. in a personal bankruptcy case. HSBC
relied on electronic information from a Lender Processing system
that manages foreclosure data. Sigmund''s 58-page decision,
released April 16, said the homes of poor and unfortunate
debtors threatened with foreclosure were at issue. </p>
<p>Lender Processing, based in Jacksonville, Florida, runs an
automated system to track mortgage payments and defaults and as
recently as 2007 was used by 39 of the country''s 50 largest
banks, according to Sigmund''s ruling. </p>
<p>Lender Processing issued a statement on PRNewswire saying
it was unaware of an investigation and has voluntarily
cooperated with the U.S. Trustee''s office. </p>
<p>For more, click here. </p>
<h2>Other Updates </h2>
<h2>BearingPoint Gets Approval to Sell Most Assets to Deloitte </h2>
<p>BearingPoint Inc., the bankrupt provider of computer
services to the U.S. Navy, won permission to sell most of its
assets to Deloitte LLP for about $350 million. In approving the
sale, a bankruptcy judge overruled concerns that the sale gutted
the estate to the detriment of many creditors. </p>
<p>U.S. Bankruptcy Judge Robert Gerber said in Manhattan court
on April 17 that BearingPoint can proceed with the sale to New
York-based Deloitte 60 days into its reorganization, after
receiving no competing bids. </p>
<p>Business partners objected to the way the sale might treat
intellectual property. Bondholders, unsecured creditors and
noteholders objected to the sale. Concerns were also raised that
the sale would cut off the right to pursue claims in lawsuits.
Gerber told the parties to amend the sale agreement to resolve
objections. </p>
<p>Gerber was concerned that a delay might decrease the value
of BearingPoint''s assets as its liquidity dwindles. He also
ruled April 17 that BearingPoint''s managers and directors acted
in good faith in deciding to make the sale, a finding that
would shield them from lawsuits claiming otherwise. </p>
<p>The case is In re BearingPoint Inc., 09-10691, U.S.
Bankruptcy Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan) </p>
<p>For more, click here. </p>
<h2>Delphi Corp. Drops Claim Against Tepper''s Appaloosa Management </h2>
<p>Delphi Corp. dropped a part of its complaint against
Appaloosa Management LP that claimed the hedge fund worked to
scuttle the auto-parts maker''s bankruptcy exit loan and sold
short Delphi securities while saying it would support the
company''s emergence from Chapter 11. </p>
<p>U.S. Bankruptcy Judge Robert Drain gave Delphi permission
to amend its complaint at a hearing April 17 in New York. Delphi
chose to drop a portion of the complaint because it was having
difficulty collecting sufficient evidence to show willful
misconduct, according to court papers. </p>
<p>Troy, Michigan-based Delphi sued after an Appaloosa-led
group of investors backed out of a $2.55 billion deal to buy
equity in its reorganized business in April 2008 on the day
Delphi planned to exit bankruptcy. Appaloosa said Delphi didn''t
meet the deal''s terms and was relying too heavily on former
parent General Motors Corp. for financial support. Delphi said
it complied with the terms of the deal. </p>
<p>A trial is planned for mid-June. </p>
<p>The bankruptcy case is: In re Delphi Corp., 05-44481, U.S.
Bankruptcy Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). The
adversary case is Delphi v. Appaloosa Management LP, 08-1232,
U.S. Bankruptcy Court, Southern District of New York
(Manhattan). </p>
<h2>AbitibiBowater May Get Loans of Up to $600 Million, Globe Says </h2>
<p>AbitibiBowater Inc., North America''s biggest newsprint
maker, which filed for Chapter 11 protection April 16, may get
loans of as much as $600 million from Avenue Capital Group and
Canada''s Fairfax Financial Holdings Ltd. (FFH) to help the company
restructure debt, the Globe and Mail reported. </p>
<p>The two firms, which agreed to give AbitibiBowater a $206
million emergency loan to help the company reorganize, could win
$42 million in fees if the total $600 million is allocated, the
report said, citing court documents. </p>
<p>GE Capital withdrew its bid to be one of AbitibiBowater''s
lenders in the restructuring process, the Globe reported, citing
people it didn''t identify. </p>
<p>In other news about AbitibiBowater, credit-default swap
traders set a value of 3.25 cents on the dollar for bonds of
Abitibi-Consolidated Inc. </p>
<p>The price means sellers of default protection on the
AbitibiBowater Inc. unit will pay 96.75 cents on the dollar to
settle the contracts. </p>
<p>Eleven dealers, including JPMorgan Chase  Co., Barclays
Plc and Morgan Stanley, bid in the auction, administered by
Markit Group Ltd. and broker Creditex Group Inc. </p>
<h2>Briefly Noted </h2>
<p>American Sterling Bank of Sugar Creek, Missouri, became the
24th U.S. bank to fail this year, as a recession drives up
unemployment and makes it harder for homeowners to pay off
loans.  American Sterling, with assets of $181 million and total
deposits of $171.9 million, was closed April 17 by the Office of
Thrift Supervision, and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corp. was
named receiver, according to a statement from the regulators.
Metcalf Bank of Lee''s Summit, Missouri, will assume deposits of
the closed bank. Metcalf Bank will buy about $173.6 million in
assets, with the FDIC sharing the losses on $100 million of
them. The cost to the agency''s insurance fund is estimated to be
$42 million. American Sterling''s three offices in the Kansas
City area will open as Metcalf branches tomorrow, and its other
two branches, in Carefree, Arizona, and Foothill Ranch,
California, will open April 20. </p>
<p>MGM Mirage (MGM) and Dubai World are near agreement on terms of a
proposal to lenders that would secure funding for CityCenter,
their joint Las Vegas Strip development, three people with
knowledge of the talks said April 17. MGM Mirage, the biggest
casino owner on the Strip, and state-owned Dubai World are
asking banks to amend terms of a $1.8 billion loan needed to
complete CityCenter, said the people, who declined to be named
because talks are private. Investors Carl Icahn and Oaktree
Capital Management LLC own MGM Mirage bonds and have suggested
to the company that it file for bankruptcy, the Wall Street
Journal reported April 16. </p>
<p>For more, click here. </p>
<p>Magna Entertainment, Inc., the bankrupt owner of racetracks
and related pari-mutuel establishments, will ask the bankruptcy
court in Delaware today for permission to proceed with plans to
sell most of the racetracks it owns, the Wall Street Journal
reported. The Canada-based company plans to sell Maryland''s
Pimlico Race Course, where the Preakness Stakes is run, and
California''s Santa Anita Park, where the Breeder''s Cup takes
place, in addition to five other properties, the newspaper said.
Magna wants to have an auction without a so-called stalking
horse, or pre-arranged lead bidder, the paper said. </p>
<p>The case is In re Magna Entertainment, 09-10720, U.S.
Bankruptcy Court, District of Delaware (Wilmington). </p>
<h2>Downgrades </h2>
<h2>Headwaters'' Corporate Family Rating Downgraded by Moody''s </h2>
<p>Headwaters Inc. (HW), converter of fossil fuels and other
resources into alternative energy, had its corporate family
rating downgraded to Caa1 from B2 by Moody''s Investors Service
April 17, the ratings company said in a statement. </p>
<p>Moody''s also downgraded the company''s senior secured credit
facility to B1 from B2 and the probability of default rating was
lowered to Caa1/LD, the statement said. The LD denoted a
limited default according to the statement. </p>
<p>The downgrade reflects earnings pressure on Headwaters
businesses due to weaknesses in the housing and commercial
construction sectors, Moody''s said in the statement. Moody''s
also noted concern that the company had not replaced or
extended its revolving credit facility, which matures in early
September, 2009 and is the company''s primary source of
liquidity, the statement said. </p>
<h2>Mega Brands, Toymaker, Sees Moody Downgrade Its Ratings </h2>
<p>Mega Brands, Inc., worldwide maker and marketer of toys,
had its ratings and those of its guaranteed subsidiaries
downgraded by Moody''s Investors Service April 17, according to a
statement issued by the ratings company. </p>
<p>Moody''s downgraded the corporate family rating to Ca from
Caa2 and the probability of default rating to Caa3 from Caa2,
the statement said. The ratings outlook is negative, according
to the statement. </p>
<p>Moody''s said the ratings downgrades reflect the fact that
financial flexibility of the company deteriorated further in the
fourth quarter of 2008 due both to lower than expected sales and
high costs, the statement said. Moody''s noted that the company
faces challenges that include risks specific to the toy industry
and general risks of the retail business. </p>
<h2>MetoKote, Industrial Coating Maker, Downgraded by SP </h2>
<p>MetoKote Inc., a maker of industrial coating for autos,
appliances and other applications, saw its corporate credit
rating downgraded to CCC+ from B by Standard  Poor''s Ratings
Services on April 17, a statement by the ratings service said. </p>
<p>SP said in the statement the outlook is developing. </p>
<p>SP also lowered the issue-level rating on the company''s
senior secured debt to CCC+ from B+, revising its recovery
rating to 3 from 2, indicating its expectation of meaningful
recovery for lenders in the event of a payment default, the
statement said. The ratings were removed from CreditWatch, where
they had been placed with negative implications on Nov. 13,
according to the statement. </p>
<p>The downgrade reflect SP''s view that declining light-vehicle sales and production in North America and Europe during
2009 will continue to lower the company''s profitability and cash
flow generation, the statement said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Holger Elfes" date="May 02, 2009  8:37 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-05-02/general-motor-s-opel-to-talk-to-potential-investors-update1-.html"><headline>General Motor''s Opel to Talk to Potential Investors</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Opel, General Motor Corp. (GM)''s German
unit, will talk to several potential investors interested in
buying a stake in the carmaker. </p>
<p>The talks with a couple of interested parties will be
held in the coming days, Joerg Schrott, a spokesman for the
company, said in a telephone interview today. He declined to
identify the potential investors. </p>
<p>Sueddeutsche Zeitung reported today that additional
investors from Russia were interested in buying a stake in Opel.
The newspaper didn''t identify the parties and didn''t say where
it got the information. </p>
<p>Schrott and a Fiat spokesman, who didn''t want to be
identified, declined to comment on German media reports that
Fiat SpA (F)''s Chief Executive Officer Sergio Marchionne will travel
to Berlin on May 4 for talks with the German government and
offer less than 1 billion euros ($1.33 billion) for a stake in
Opel. </p>
<p>Fiat, which signed a partnership agreement with Chrysler
LLC on April 30 after five months of negotiations, has said
repeatedly it is also interested in Opel. The German carmaker
needs to find an investor because it''s running out of cash as
its parent faces potential bankruptcy by June 1. </p>
<p>Now we have to concentrate on Opel, Marchionne said in
an interview with La Stampa. They are our ideal partners. </p>
<p>Besides Fiat, North America''s largest auto-parts maker
Magna International Inc. and unidentified financial investors
are vying for stakes in Opel, which sells cars in the U.K. under
the Vauxhall brand. Detroit-based GM, surviving on U.S. loans,
can''t provide financial support to Opel and is looking to sell a
stake in the carmaker to secure 3.3 billion euros in European
state aid. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry></news>