
<news><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Nov 05, 2012  9:35 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-05/morgan-stanley-s-taubman-to-leave-as-kelleher-s-duties-expand.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley''s Kelleher Faces Profit Task Solo as Taubman Goes</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Colm Kelleher, who will take over as
sole head of Morgan Stanley''s (MS) investment bank as his counterpart
and past rival Paul J. Taubman exits, now faces the challenge of
improving returns at the firm''s biggest business. </p>
<p>Taubman will retire at the end of the year, the New York-
based bank said yesterday in a statement. The move concludes an
almost three-year dual-leadership role marked by enmity between
Kelleher, 55, a gregarious former fixed-income salesman, and
Taubman, 51, a reserved investment banker. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer James Gorman is relying on Kelleher
to help improve earnings as the stock has traded below book
value for most of Gorman''s tenure. Morgan Stanley''s investment
bank has posted a return on equity, a measure of profitability,
of less than 4 percent in the first nine months of the year,
trailing competitor JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s 17 percent. In 2006,
ROE at Morgan Stanley''s investment bank was 30 percent. </p>
<p>We must continue our intense focus on improving ROE,
Gorman, 54, said in an internal memo obtained by Bloomberg News.
Aligning sales trading more closely with investment banking
and capital markets will allow us to explore and extract new
revenue opportunities within institutional securities and better
manage our costs. </p>
<p>Kelleher and Taubman disagreed over how aggressively to
push clients for additional business on the back of capital-
markets deals, three former colleagues told Bloomberg News in
2011. Gorman, who met with the executives last year to settle
tensions, recently decided that the division would win more of
those deals with Kelleher running the entire unit, a person
briefed on the decision said. </p>
<h2>Pushing Products </h2>
<p>While Kelleher won out over Taubman, he may face more
obstacles in seeking to persuade bankers to push more products. </p>
<p>I understand the motivation of a head of trading to
encourage investment bankers to attempt to use their contacts
with corporate treasurers to originate trades and hedging,
Brad Hintz, an analyst at Sanford C. Bernstein  Co. and a
former Morgan Stanley treasurer, said in an e-mail. But if
faced with the tradeoff between asking for an MA engagement and
a swap, the MA pitch will win every time. </p>
<p>Investment banks sometimes pitch clients to win derivatives
business related to a stock or bond sale, such as an interest-
rate or currency swap. While the secondary deal can boost
trading revenue, it can also make the bank a counterparty to a
client it had just advised. </p>
<h2>Alienating Clients </h2>
<p>With Kelleher looking to secure more deals to increase
trading revenue and Taubman seeking to avoid alienating clients,
Morgan Stanley, the sixth-largest U.S. bank by assets, has
lagged behind rivals, the former colleagues said last year. </p>
<p>The interaction between trading and banking may become more
of a focus as Morgan Stanley and competitors seek to produce
more revenue with fewer people and using less capital. The firm
has said it intends to pare 4,000 positions this year through
job cuts and unit sales. In September, Chief Financial Officer
Ruth Porat laid out a plan to reduce the fixed-income trading
unit''s risk-weighted assets under Basel III rules by at least 35
percent from the third quarter of 2011 through the end of 2014. </p>
<p>One area of collaboration will be corporate lending, which
is likely to expand once Morgan Stanley purchases Citigroup
Inc.''s remaining stake in a brokerage joint venture and gains
control of more than $50 billion in deposits. </p>
<h2>Goldman''s Success </h2>
<p>Investors may struggle to gauge progress as firms don''t
disclose the amount of trading revenue derived from investment-
banking relationships. Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) sought to
demonstrate its success on that front in its 2009 annual report,
telling shareholders that revenue in risk- management
solutions offered to investment-banking clients climbed 32
percent annually from 2005 through 2009. </p>
<p>Our advisory business serves as our primary point of
contact with our clients and is often the genesis for sourcing
other opportunities to serve them, Goldman Sachs CEO Lloyd C. Blankfein, 58, wrote in the report. </p>
<p>Gorman told both men about the decision more than a week
ago and the announcement was delayed because of Hurricane Sandy,
according to the person who was briefed. </p>
<p>After being informed of Gorman''s decision to have Kelleher
take over as sole head, Taubman decided to retire from the firm,
according to the person, who declined to be identified because
the discussions were private. The pair have been seen by
colleagues as potential successors to the CEO. Taubman didn''t
return a phone call seeking comment. </p>
<h2>Collective Talent'' </h2>
<p>It''s unfortunate that Morgan Stanley couldn''t derive the
benefits of the collective talent of Colm and Paul, said Jay Dweck, 57, who led Morgan Stanley''s strats and modeling group
until 2011. Paul brought an enlightened client-focused view to
the institutional-sales division, which will be sorely missed. </p>
<p>Mark Eichorn and Franck Petitgas were named global co-heads
of investment banking, the area that Taubman oversaw, the firm
said in yesterday''s statement. The pair will report to Kelleher,
who has overseen trading. </p>
<p>While Kelleher ran the larger trading businesses, the
investment-banking unit that Taubman led performed better.
Morgan Stanley ranked fourth in investment-banking revenue among
its largest global rivals in the first nine months of this year,
the same place it held in 2011 and 2010, according to data
compiled by Bloomberg. The firm is seventh in trading revenue
this year, compared with sixth in 2011 and eighth in 2010. </p>
<h2>Facebook IPO </h2>
<p>Morgan Stanley ranks second among advisers on global
mergers and acquisitions so far this year and first among
managers of global equity issues, the data show. Both of those
businesses were under Taubman''s leadership. The firm, which has
57,726 employees, has also faced investor complaints over its
handling of Facebook Inc. (FB)''s initial public offering in May,
after shares of the social-network operator slid. </p>
<p>Kelleher, who was the firm''s CFO during the financial
crisis, has worked in the investment-banking and trading
divisions during more than 20 years at Morgan Stanley. Taubman
has only been an investment banker since joining the company in
1982. </p>
<p>Kelleher had made progress in reaching Gorman''s goal of an
8 percent market share for Morgan Stanley''s fixed-income unit.
The firm had a 7 percent share last year, up from as low as 5
percent in previous years, Kelleher said in March. </p>
<p>That progress slowed this year as the bank''s share fell to
about 6.5 percent. The decline was driven by a drop in revenue
in the second quarter as clients stepped back from trading with
Morgan Stanley amid a credit-rating review by Moody''s Investors
Service. Moody''s cut the firm''s grade two levels in June. The
next month, Gorman announced that he was shrinking the fixed-
income unit. </p>
<h2>Warmed Up'' </h2>
<p>Kelleher''s promotion also sets up a management structure
similar to when Gorman ran wealth and asset management and Walid Chammah headed institutional securities under then-CEO John Mack. Gorman beat out his fellow co-president for the top job in
2009, while Chammah became chairman of the international
business before retiring this year. </p>
<p>Greg Fleming, 49, who runs the brokerage and asset-
management units, and Kelleher now both oversee businesses that
have contributed half of the bank''s revenue this year. Gorman,
who is also chairman, said in March that he''s just getting
warmed up and plans to be in the job for a bunch of years.
He has no plans to name a president in the near term, according
to a person briefed on his thinking, who asked not to be
identified because the information isn''t public. </p>
<p>Fleming and Kelleher each face challenges in improving
returns. Fleming has promised a 15 percent pretax margin in the
brokerage business by the middle of 2013, up from 10 percent
this year. </p>
<h2>Public Jokes </h2>
<p>Eichorn and Petitgas, 51, will have responsibilities for
global client coverage, mergers and acquisitions and capital
markets. Eichorn will join the bank''s management committee along
with Jeff Holzschuh, 52, who was named chairman of institutional
securities and will focus on client relationships. Petitgas is
already a member of the committee. </p>
<p>Taubman and Kelleher''s relationship had shown signs of
improving after Gorman met with the pair together and separately
after last year''s Bloomberg News article, according to two
people who work with them. Enmity between Kelleher and Taubman
had become a source of public jokes. </p>
<p>So how''s that co-head thing going? mergers chief Robert Kindler asked at a 2010 meeting of more than 100 managing
directors at the Ritz-Carlton Battery Park hotel in New York,
drawing laughter as he gestured at Kelleher and Taubman. Neither
responded. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Patricia Hurtado" date="Nov 05, 2012  5:20 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-05/jpmorgan-loses-bid-to-dismiss-fhfa-mortgage-suits.html"><headline>JPMorgan Loses Bid to Dismiss FHFA Mortgage Suits</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) lost a bid to
have a U.S. judge dismiss lawsuits filed by the Federal Housing
Finance Agency against 16 U.S. banks over mortgage-backed
securities. </p>
<p>JPMorgan, Bank of America Corp. and Citigroup Inc. (C) were
among the lenders sued last year for allegedly misleading Fannie
Mae and Freddie Mac about the soundness of loans underlying
billions of dollars of residential mortgage-backed securities.
JPMorgan served as the lead underwriter for 30 out of the 103
securitizations at issue in this case. </p>
<p>U.S. District Judge Denise Cote in Manhattan today rejected
a bid to throw out the FHFA''s complaint, overruling arguments
that the agency lacked factual support that the loans underlying
the securitizations weren''t underwritten in accordance with the
guidelines set out in the offering documents. </p>
<p>The agency''s reliance on this information is not, as the
defendants allege, an effort to argue fraud by hindsight'';
rather the amended complaint suggests that these market events
are telltale signs of defects that were present in the
securitizations all along, albeit, unbeknownst to the public,
the judge wrote. </p>
<p>FHFA may be wrong of course; a jury will decide, Cote
said. But the claim is not an implausible one. </p>
<h2>Total Collapse'' </h2>
<p>Cote said that the plaintiffs'' amended complaints includes
allegations of a total collapse in credit ratings and claims
the banks had made false statements of material facts in
registration statements, which directly caused Fannie Mae and
Freddie Mac to suffer billions of dollars in damages. The
plaintiffs also claim the loans underlying the securities
experienced defaults and delinquencies at a much higher rate
than they would have if the loan originators had adhered to
underwriting guidelines. </p>
<p>Cote cited evidence provided by the plaintiffs in the
amended complaint that included statements or two confidential
witnesses who were personally involved in the origination and
underwriting of JPMorgan''s EMC unit. </p>
<p>She also said the plaintiffs included testimony from
witnesses who described being pressured by supervisors to
approve loans in disregard of their expressed concerns about
potentially fraudulent documentation and cited other evidence
provided by plaintiffs involving Washington Mutual Inc. </p>
<h2>Wild West'' </h2>
<p>As one appraiser who did business with WaMu during the
relevant period described the bank''s origination practices: It
was the Wild West ... if you were alive, they would give you a
loan, Actually, I think if you were dead, they would still give
you a loan,'' Cote said in her ruling, citing the witness''s
statements. </p>
<p>WaMu, based in Seattle, filed for bankruptcy on Sept. 26,
2008, the day after its banking unit was taken over by
regulators and sold to JPMorgan Chase  Co. for $1.9 billion. </p>
<p>The defendants argued the plaintiffs had failed to provide
sufficient evidence to support their claims. </p>
<p>Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac have operated under U.S.
conservatorship since 2008, when they were seized amid subprime
mortgage losses that pushed them toward insolvency. </p>
<p>Cote did narrow the case, dismissing some claims alleging
violations of the Virginia Securities Act as well as fraud
claims regarding the owner-occupancy and loan-to-value ratio of
the securities for which New York-based JPMorgan served as lead
underwriter. </p>
<h2>Amended Complaint </h2>
<p>She cited the amended complaint filed by the plaintiffs,
including statements made by JPMorgan Chief Executive Officer
Jamie Dimon criticizing the quality of loans originated by Chase
Home Finance LLC, a unit of the bank. The judge said the amended
complaint also mentioned the $5.3 billion settlement JPMorgan
reached this year with state and local authorities. </p>
<p>Joe Evangelisti, a spokesman for JPMorgan, declined to
comment on the ruling. </p>
<p>Also sued by the FHFA were Barclays Plc (BARC), Nomura Holdings
Inc. (8604), HSBC Holdings Plc (HSBA), Societe Generale SA (GLE), Morgan Stanley (MS),
Ally Financial Inc. (ALLY), Royal Bank of Scotland Group Plc, Credit
Suisse Group AG (CSGN), Deutsche Bank AG (DBK) and First Horizon National
Corp. (FHN) </p>
<p>The case is Federal Housing Finance Agency v. JPMorgan
Chase  Co., 11-CV-6188, U.S. District court, Southern District
of New York (Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christine Harper" date="Nov 05, 2012  4:57 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-05/goldman-sachs-adds-aia-group-ceo-tucker-to-board-of-directors.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Adds AIA Group CEO Tucker to Board of Directors</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), the fifth-
biggest U.S. bank by assets, expanded its board of directors to
12 members by adding Mark Edward Tucker, the chief executive
officer and president of AIA Group Ltd. (1299) </p>
<p>Tucker, 54, will become Goldman Sachs''s 10th independent
board member and will join all of the board''s committees, the
New York-based firm said today in a statement. </p>
<p>With his nearly three decades of leadership in the
insurance and banking sectors, Mark has a proven understanding
of effective risk management, Lloyd C. Blankfein, 58, Goldman
Sachs''s chairman and CEO, said in the statement. </p>
<p>Tucker was group chief executive at Prudential Plc (PRU) before
becoming CEO and president of Hong Kong-based AIA, the third-
largest Asia-based insurer. From 2009 until this year he was a
non-executive director of the so-called Court of the Bank of
England, which provides the central bank with non-monetary
advice, and a member of its financial stability committee and
audit and risk committee, according to the statement. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs last month named Adebayo Bayo Ogunlesi,
managing partner and chairman of Global Infrastructure Partners,
as an independent board member. The investment bank said in
September that Chief Financial Officer David A. Viniar will
retire at the end of January and join the board as a non-
independent member. </p>
<p>AIA was sold by American International Group Inc. (AIG) in a
$20.5 billion public offering in October 2010 that was the
world''s third-largest at the time. Goldman Sachs was one of the
banks involved in managing the offering. </p>
<p>British-born Tucker, who was a professional soccer player
in his youth, was a mentor to Tidjane Thiam and handed Thiam the
CEO job at Prudential in 2009. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Charles Mead" date="Nov 05, 2012 12:55 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-05/microsoft-plumbs-yield-depths-with-aaa-issue-corporate-finance.html"><headline>Microsoft Plumbs Yield Depths With AAA Issue: Corporate Finance</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), the world''s largest
software maker, is proving the value of an AAA rating. </p>
<p>The designer of Windows operating systems with a credit
grade that Standard  Poor''s deems better than the U.S.
government''s sold $2.25 billion of bonds last week at tighter
relative yields than a year ago, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. Spreads widened in the same period for corporate
bonds globally of all types, Bank of America Merrill Lynch index
data show. </p>
<p>The supply of top-rated corporate bonds has tumbled 64
percent as firms from General Electric Co. (GE) to billionaire Warren
Buffett''s Berkshire Hathaway Inc. lost their AAAs after the 2008
collapse of Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. ignited the worst
financial crisis in eight decades. Redmond, Washington-based
Microsoft''s balance sheet has since strengthened, with a record
$67 billion of cash and short-term investments. </p>
<p>Microsoft carries a certain level of cachet in this
market as a highly defensive and economic resilient borrower,
said Thomas Chow, a money manager at Delaware Investments in
Philadelphia with about $170 billion under management. It''s as
strong and well recognized of an issuer as one can expect. </p>
<h2>Tighter Spreads </h2>
<p>The least-leveraged software maker sold $600 million of
0.875 percent, five-year notes on Nov. 2 that yielded 27 basis
points more than similar-maturity Treasuries, $750 million of
2.125 percent, 10-year securities at a 47 basis-point spread and
$900 million of 3.5 percent, 30-year bonds at 67 basis points,
Bloomberg data show. </p>
<p>The new bonds paid less relative to government securities
than when Microsoft issued an equal amount of similar-maturity
notes on Feb. 3, 2011, even after relative corporate yields
worldwide increased 19 basis points to 227 basis points, or 2.27
percentage points. That similarly sized sale included 2.5
percent, five-year notes yielding 38 basis points more than
Treasuries, 4 percent, 10-year bonds at 48 basis points and 5.3
percent, 30-year securities at 68 basis points. </p>
<p>Six months later, SP cut America''s credit grade to AA+.
Moody''s Investors Service ranks the U.S. as Aaa. </p>
<p>An average coupon of 2.34 percent on Microsoft''s new bonds
compares with a 3.2 percent rate that it paid on $12 billion of
outstanding securities before last week''s sale, $2.25 billion of
which mature next year, Bloomberg data show. </p>
<h2>Very Attractive'' </h2>
<p>It''s not particularly compelling from a spread point of
view, but from the point of view of increasing credit quality,
it''s very attractive, said Bonnie Baha, head of global
developed credit at Los Angeles-based DoubleLine Capital LP,
which oversees more than $45 billion. </p>
<p>All three issues rose in secondary trading today. The five-
year notes gained 0.1 cent on the dollar to 99.6 cents for a
yield of 0.96 percent at 11:26 a.m. in New York, the 10-year
debt rose 0.6 cent to 99.86 cents to yield 2.14 percent, and the
30-year bonds rose 0.6 cent to 99.1 cents to pay 3.55 percent. </p>
<p>Microsoft''s debt has never exceeded its earnings before
interest, taxes, depreciation and amortization. Its current
leverage of 0.41 times is the least among publicly traded
software firms with at least $1 billion of debt, including
Oracle Corp. (ORCL) and SSC Technologies Holdings Inc. (SSNC), which carry a
median debt load of 1.68 times earnings, Bloomberg data show. </p>
<p>Peter Wootton, a spokesman for Microsoft, declined to
comment on the company''s finances. Proceeds from the new bonds
may be used to buy stock, fund acquisitions or repay existing
debt, the company said last week in a regulatory filing. </p>
<h2>Global Growth </h2>
<p>Investors are seeking bonds of the most-creditworthy
borrowers as the International Monetary Fund lowers its global
growth forecast to the slowest pace since the 2009 recession. </p>
<p>The IMF on Oct. 9 predicted 3.3 percent growth this year
and 3.6 percent in 2013, compared with July predictions of 3.5
percent for 2012 and 3.9 percent next year. The lender now sees
alarmingly high risks of a steeper slowdown, with a one-in-
six chance of growth slipping below 2 percent. </p>
<p>The face value of outstanding corporate debt worldwide
that''s ranked AAA has plummeted to $158 billion last week from
$445 billion in May 2008, according to Bank of America Merrill
Lynch index data. </p>
<p>There''s not enough AAA paper to go around right now,
Jody Lurie, a corporate credit analyst at Janney Montgomery
Scott LLC in Philadelphia, said in a telephone interview. That
helps Microsoft, which is the type of name that institutional
investors need in their portfolio, she said. </p>
<p>The biggest holders of Microsoft bonds include Vanguard
Group Inc., the largest U.S. mutual-fund firm, and BlackRock
Inc., which manages more financial assets than any other
company, data compiled by Bloomberg show. </p>
<h2>Free Cash </h2>
<p>Of the four non-financial U.S. companies rated AAA by SP
or Aaa by Moody''s, Microsoft is the most profitable. </p>
<p>Its gross margin of 74 percent leads Johnson  Johnson (JNJ),
Exxon Mobil Corp. and Automatic Data Processing Inc. It''s 33
percent operating margin, also the highest, compares with a 22
percent average, Bloomberg data show. </p>
<p>That''s helped Microsoft generate more free cash than 99
percent of SP 500 stock index members. </p>
<p>The company earned $29 billion of funds in its last fiscal
year that it can use to reward shareholders through dividends or
stock buybacks, to reinvest in the company or to pay down debt,
more than any non-financial firm except Apple Inc. (AAPL), which
doesn''t have debt and isn''t rated by Moody''s or SP. </p>
<p>Because of how stable their cash flow is, there''s
generally a lot of demand, Greg Tornga, head of fixed income
at Edge Asset Management in Seattle, which manages about $22
billion and owns Microsoft debt, said in a telephone interview.
It''s a very stable investment from a bond standpoint. </p>
<h2>Mobile Phone </h2>
<p>Microsoft''s bond sale comes with the personal-computer
industry forecast to have its worst year since 2001 as consumers
switch purchases to tablet machines like Apple''s iPad and
smartphones. Microsoft is responding with the release of its
first computer hardware device, the Surface tablet, and a new
version of Windows overhauled to add touch controls. </p>
<p>The company is also making plans for a possible mobile
phone of its own, according to people with knowledge of the
matter who asked not to be identified. </p>
<p>While the company''s free cash flow at more than double its
$12 billion of total debt has helped bolster the balance sheet,
about 87 percent of its cash and equivalents were held overseas
and subject to repatriation taxes as of Sept. 30, according to a
quarterly regulatory filing. </p>
<h2>Cheap Financing'' </h2>
<p>That raises the chances that Microsoft, which had about
$7.2 billion remaining in its share buyback program, will use
borrowed money to repurchase stock, according to Alan Shepard of
Madison, Wisconsin-based Madison Investment Holdings Inc. </p>
<p>Under current law, American companies can defer federal
income taxes on most overseas earnings indefinitely. When they
do return to the U.S., they''re taxed at the corporate rate of 35
percent -- with credits for foreign income taxes paid. Companies
paying little overseas face higher U.S. tax bills upon
repatriation and may save money by borrowing instead. </p>
<p>My feeling is that they''re using cheap financing to move
funds back to the U.S., which may be used for repurchases,
Shepard, whose firm oversees about $16 billion and owns
Microsoft debt, wrote in an e-mail. It''s a shareholder-
friendly move, but it should have no effect on the company''s
overall credit quality. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Drew Armstrong" date="Nov 06, 2012  5:23 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-06/pfizer-s-arthritis-treatment-wins-approval-from-u-s-fda.html"><headline>Pfizer''s Arthritis Treatment Wins Approval From U.S. FDA</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE)''s experimental rheumatoid arthritis pill won U.S. regulatory approval and will compete directly with Abbott Laboratories (ABT)'' top-selling injection Humira. </p> <p>The Food and Drug Administration cleared Pfizer''s treatment, tofacitinib, to be sold as Xeljanz, for adults with moderate to severe rheumatoid arthritis who don''t respond well to other drugs, the agency said today in a statement. </p> <p>Xeljanz inhibits part of the immune system that can cause rheumatoid arthritis. It may generate $2.3 billion in annual sales for New York-based Pfizer by 2018, estimated Seamus Fernandez, an analyst with Leerink Swann  Co. in Boston. It would compete with Humira and Johnson  Johnson (JNJ)''s Remicade. </p> <p>Xeljanz provides a new treatment option for adults suffering from the debilitating disease of RA who have had a poor response to methotrexate, Badrul Chowdhury, the FDA''s director of the Division of Pulmonary, Allergy, and Rheumatology Products, said in the statement. </p> <p>Rheumatoid arthritis patients typically start therapy on methotrexate, a generic medicine, before moving to the Humira and JJ drugs. The FDA''s approval would put Xeljanz into direct competition with those drugs, among the top-selling therapies in the U.S., rather than as an option to be used after they fail. Pfizer had said in May that it expected the drug to be used at first mostly in patients who failed the JJ and Abbott products. Humira had $7.9 billion in 2011 sales, Abbott has reported. </p>




Photographer: Michele Tantussi/Bloomberg

<p>
Pfizer Inc. headquarters in Berlin. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Patrick Cole" date="Nov 06, 2012  1:20 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-06/goldman-jpmorgan-springsteen-robin-hood-aid-victims.html"><headline>Goldman, JPMorgan, Springsteen, Robin Hood Aid Victims</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>After Hurricane Sandy ravaged his
home state of New Jersey last week, rock star Jon Bon Jovi cut
short a London press tour and flew to New York, where he
performed in a live telethon to support the storm''s victims. </p>
<p>Rock and pop royalty quickly signed up to participate in
the NBC television benefit Hurricane Sandy: Coming Together,
including Briton Sting; Staten Island-born Christina Aguilera;
Bruce Springsteen, another New Jersey native; and Long Islander
Billy Joel. </p>
<p>The show last Friday raised $23 million for the American
Red Cross, adding to about $35 million in donations the
organization has already received, said spokeswoman Karen
Stecher. </p>
<p>Artists, entertainers, corporations and the financial-
services industry have contributed or pledged talent, work and
money to recovery efforts for Sandy victims, as the death toll
has risen to at least 177, and property damage totals about $50
billion, according to Moody Analytics Inc. </p>
<p>I''ve never seen a time like this, said Kathleen
DiChiara, president and founder of the Community FoodBank of New
Jersey which she launched from the trunk of her car in 1975.
When I was handing out sandwiches on Sunday, a woman told me
that she and her sister take turns letting their cats sit on
their laps to keep to them warm because they have no
electricity. The food need is huge. </p>
<p>Jefferies Group Inc. (JEF), the New York-based investment-banking
firm, said it would donate $1 million and all net trading
commissions earned tomorrow to the Hurricane Sandy relief
effort. Its more than 3,800 employees can also donate their
salary for the day to charity. </p>
<p>Citigroup Inc. (C)''s Citi Foundation donated $1 million to the
Red Cross. Morgan Stanley (MS) and its employees will contribute $1
million to $2.5 million (depending on employee contributions) to
the recovery effort, according to an internal memo obtained by
Bloomberg News. </p>
<p>The Robin Hood Foundation, the New York-based poverty-
fighting charity supported largely by Wall Street donors, said
it will hand out about $3 million by today for the purchase of
food and blankets and for emergency cash grants. The nonprofit
has raised more than $9 million since last Friday for its relief
fund. </p>
<h2>Small Gifts </h2>
<p>Our experience after 9/11 has shown that small cash
disbursements -- as little as $100 or $200 -- can be critical to
needy families in the days following a catastrophic event, Lee Ainslie III, Robin Hood''s board chairman and fund manager at
Maverick Capital Management LP, said in an e-mail to donors last
week. </p>
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) offered $5 billion in capital for
lending to small and midsize businesses affected by the storm.
The company''s foundation will also give $5 million to the relief
effort. That figure includes $2 million to the Red Cross
emergency response, $1 million in matching funds for employee
donations to the Red Cross, United Way and World Vision, and as
much as $2 million to local agencies for recovery efforts. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) said it would match $5 million in
funding for small business pledged by New York City Mayor
Michael Bloomberg to provide loans. (Bloomberg is the founder
and majority owner of Bloomberg News parent Bloomberg LP.) </p>
<h2>Fast Access'' </h2>
<p>Many small businesses in our communities have been
devastated by this disaster, and fast access to capital will
help them get back on their feet more quickly, Lloyd Blankfein, Goldman''s chairman and chief executive, said in a
release. </p>
<p>The investment bank and its Goldman Sachs Gives, a donor-
advised fund to which the company''s partners contribute, also
will donate as much as $5 million to Sandy''s clean-up and
recovery effort. </p>
<p>The Red Cross has provided shelter to about 9,000 people at
113 facilities in nine states, Stecher said. It''s also deployed
more than 4,000 disaster workers in the region and 240 response
vehicles, or more than two-thirds of its U.S. fleet, she said. </p>
<p>The United Way of New York City has received about $2
million from corporations including JPMorgan, Bank of America
Corp., Deloitte LLP, Federal Express Corp. and Starbucks Corp. (SBUX)
More donations will be required to help the needy over the
coming months, said Sheena Wright, United Way''s chief executive
officer. </p>
<h2>Immediate Support'' </h2>
<p>There is certainly a huge need for immediate support,
said Stacey D. Stewart, president of United Way U.S.A., based in
Alexandria, Virginia. What we experience time and time again
is that it takes quite a while to recover, and it''s the United
Way that will be there for the long haul. </p>
<p>The Union, New Jersey-based Salvation Army chapter has
spent more than $50,000 to help those without shelter, food or
electricity and needs more donations. </p>
<p>When the sun came out and the water went away after
Hurricane Irene last year, a lot of people who weren''t impacted
went about their daily lives, and you can''t blame them, Brenda
Beavers, the state director of human services for the Salvation
Army New Jersey, said by phone. But we still have people in
New Jersey who have yet to recover from that storm. </p>
<p>Muse highlights include Martin Gayford on art, Richard
Vines on dining. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hugh Son and Dawn Kopecki" date="Nov 07, 2012  4:52 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-07/morgan-stanley-goldman-drop-as-europe-s-crisis-drags-on-germany.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Leads Slump as Elections, Europe Hit Banks</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) and Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) dropped the most in the last 12 months as Europe''s debt crisis reignited and investors speculated that President Barack Obama''s re-election means tighter curbs on banks. </p> <p>The two securities firms led U.S. financial stocks lower after Obama defeated Mitt Romney and European Central Bank President Mario Draghi said the region''s crisis is hurting Germany, its biggest economy. Goldman Sachs fell 6.6 percent to $117.98 at 4:15 p.m. in New York and Morgan Stanley tumbled 8.6 percent to $16.63. Bank of America Corp. (BAC) dropped 7.1 percent. </p> <p>Bankers were hoping Romney would win and give them more sympathetic regulators or that Republicans would take the Senate and they could rewrite Dodd-Frank, said Edward Mills, a bank policy analyst at FBR Capital Markets and former aide on the House Financial Services Committee. The floodgate is going to open for the final rules under Dodd-Frank, he said, referring to the 2010 law designed to overhaul banking rules. </p> <p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the biggest U.S. lender by assets, fell 5.6 percent. That was the most in six months, since the day after disclosing a $2 billion trading loss in a London unit. </p> <h2>More Misery'' </h2> <p>Citigroup Inc. (C), ranked third, declined 6.3 percent. It''s based in New York along with JPMorgan, Goldman Sachs and Morgan Stanley. San Francisco-based Wells Fargo  Co. (WFC), the biggest U.S. home lender, fell 3.5 percent. Bank of America is ranked second by assets and based in Charlotte, North Carolina. </p> <p>Obama''s win and the election of industry critics such as Elizabeth Warren to a Democrat-controlled Senate signal more misery ahead for financial firms, according to David Trone of JMP Securities LLC. </p> <p>Investors had bought shares in the five biggest U.S. banks amid hope that a Romney White House and a divided Senate would repeal some of the burdensome costs that Obama championed, Trone wrote to clients. These included bigger capital buffers, more compliance programs and less fee revenue, he wrote. </p> <p>With the House still under Republican control, lawmakers and the Obama administration may fight brutally over a solution to the so-called fiscal cliff, and tax increases and spending cuts could trigger a U.S. recession, Trone wrote. </p> <h2>Romney Premium </h2> <p>Warren, a Harvard University professor, unseated Massachusetts Republican Senator Scott Brown. She will serve with Republicans who previously made clear they would block any attempt by Obama to appoint her to lead the new Consumer Financial Protection Bureau, which she helped establish over objections of bankers. </p> <p>U.S. banks outperformed the Standard  Poor''s 500 in six out of the last eight trading sessions leading up to Election Day, and closed near their highest levels for the year yesterday, said Jason Goldberg, senior banking analyst at Barclays Capital. </p> <p>The market was pricing in an increasingly higher chance that Romney would win, Goldberg said. Investors thought if Romney was elected, the path to interest rates would be higher and that would be good for banks, Goldberg said. Romney also would have been kinder in drafting new rules required by the Dodd-Frank overhaul, he said. </p> <p>Bloomberg''s Europe Banks and Financial Services Index, which tracks 38 companies in the region, dropped the most in almost three weeks, sliding 1.9 percent. Germany''s 2013 growth forecast was cut to 0.8 percent from 1.7 percent amid a slowdown in the continent''s economy, the European Commission said today. </p> <p>Germany has so far been largely insulated from some of the difficulties elsewhere in the euro area, Draghi said today at a Frankfurt conference. The latest data suggest that these developments are now starting to affect the German economy. </p> <h2>Fierce'' Advocate </h2> <p>Banks spent millions of dollars lobbying to block or dilute new rules that cut into their profit. With Obama''s election, FBR''s Mills said, the industry has gone from a posture of trying to delay to now where they are going to be pushing for certainty. </p> <p>Warren isn''t the first pro-consumer lawmaker in Congress, but no other consumer advocate has been able to capture the attention of the nation and take on Wall Street and win, and she''s likely to sit on the Senate Banking Committee, Mills said. Not only do Democrats hold the Senate, they now have a fierce defender in the Senate to any potential change to Dodd- Frank. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Nov 07, 2012  4:03 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-07/microsoft-to-invest-100-million-on-research-startups-in-brazil.html"><headline>Microsoft to Invest $100 Million on Research, Startups in Brazil</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), the world''s largest
software maker, said it will invest $100 million in research,
development and entrepreneurial programs in Brazil. </p>
<p>The company will establish its fourth Microsoft Research
Advanced Technology Laboratory in Rio de Janeiro. Microsoft will
also set up a center for work on its Bing search engine and a
business accelerator to support 15 startups over the next 24
months, according to a post on its website. </p>
<p>Microsoft, based in Redmond, Washington, is chasing growth
in emerging markets as personal-computer sales increase at a
faster rate in those countries than in the U.S. and Western
Europe. The software maker will incorporate an investment fund,
which will be wholly owned by Microsoft Brazil, to invest in
startups. </p>
<p>Microsoft declined 2.6 percent to $29.08 at the close in
New York. The stock is up 12 percent this year. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Anto Antony" date="Nov 07, 2012  6:24 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-07/morgan-stanley-said-to-sell-india-wealth-management-business.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Said to Sell India Wealth Management Business</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) may sell its wealth-
management unit in India after a review of the business, said a
person with knowledge of the matter. </p>
<p>The four-year-old business is headed by Executive Director
Himanshu Bhagat based in Mumbai. A final decision on the sale
will be taken in two months, according to the person, who
declined to be identified as the plan isn''t public. </p>
<p>Reuters reported on the proposal earlier. Morgan Stanley
declined to comment on the report in an e-mail. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Nov 07, 2012 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-07/morgan-stanley-posts-loss-on-eight-trading-days-in-third-quarter.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Posts Loss on Eight Trading Days in Third Quarter</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS), the Wall Street bank
with the biggest trading-revenue increase last quarter, lost
money in that business on eight days in the period, down from 31
days a year earlier. </p>
<p>Traders generated more than $100 million on nine days in
the period, compared with two days in the third quarter of 2011,
the New York-based company said yesterday in a regulatory
filing. None of the daily losses exceeded the bank''s so-called
value-at-risk, an estimate of potential trading losses. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley had a 40 percent quarter-over-quarter
increase in trading revenue, excluding accounting charges, led
by an 89 percent jump in fixed-income revenue. Chief Financial
Officer Ruth Porat, 54, said last month that clients returned to
dealing with the firm after shying away in the second quarter as
Moody''s Investors Service reviewed its ratings. Moody''s cut the
bank''s credit grade two levels in June. </p>
<p>Colm Kelleher, who runs Morgan Stanley''s trading business,
will take over the investment-banking unit as Paul J. Taubman,
Kelleher''s co-president of institutional securities, leaves at
year-end. The company announced plans to reduce so-called risk-
weighted assets in the fixed-income trading unit by at least 35
percent from the third quarter of 2011 through the end of 2014. </p>
<p>Bank of America Corp. (BAC), the second-largest U.S. lender, said
in a filing last week that it had one day of trading losses,
which were less than $1 million, and one day of revenue of more
than $100 million. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Nov 08, 2012 10:11 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-08/jpmorgan-posts-trading-loss-on-10-days-as-derivative-bet-unwinds.html"><headline>JPMorgan Posts Trading Loss on 10 Days as Derivative Bet Unwinds</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s traders lost
money on 10 days during the third quarter, down from 28 in the
prior three months when the largest U.S. bank struggled to
unwind a wrong-way bet on credit derivatives. </p>
<p>Losses occurred on 39 days in the first nine months of this
year, compared with 18 days during the same period of 2011, New
York-based JPMorgan said today in a regulatory filing. Traders
earned more than $200 million on seven days in the first nine
months, including five in the third quarter, the bank said. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon, 56, ousted traders and
managers and overhauled senior management amid more than $6.2
billion in losses at the chief investment office in London. The
affair prompted the retirement of Chief Investment Officer Ina Drew, spurred lawsuits from shareholders and drew civil and
criminal probes by at least three U.S. agencies. </p>
<p>Value-at-risk, or VaR, which measures the most the bank
might lose on 95 percent of its trading days, increased to $162
million during the first nine months of this year from an
average of $97 million in the same period last year. </p>
<p>The results aren''t directly comparable because the firm
used a new formula in the third quarter as it tried to improve
accuracy. Investigators focused attention on VaR because the
model was altered in January before some of the errant trades
were placed and may have obscured the mounting losses. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc., the New York-based investment
bank that made 55 percent of its revenue this year from sales
and trading, recorded losses from that business on two days in
the third quarter, down from 21 days in the same period last
year. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s traders lost money on eight days during
the third quarter, the New York-based company said in a Nov. 7
filing. Charlotte, North Carolina-based Bank of America Corp.,
the second-largest U.S. lender, said last week it had one day of
trading losses, which were less than $1 million, and one day of
revenue with more than $100 million. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Zachary Tracer" date="Nov 08, 2012  8:58 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-08/jpmorgan-reaches-agreement-to-settle-sec-mortgage-probes.html"><headline>JPMorgan Reaches Agreement to Settle SEC Mortgage Probes</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the biggest
U.S. bank, reached a settlement with regulators to resolve
claims tied to its home-loan business and said it would buy back
as much as $3 billion of shares. </p>
<p>The agreement in principle with the U.S. Securities and
Exchange Commission covers two investigations related to
mortgage-backed bonds handled by JPMorgan and Bear Stearns Cos.,
which the bank acquired in 2008, New York-based JPMorgan said
today in a filing. </p>
<p>The firm has reached an agreement in principle with the
staff of the SEC to resolve some claims, JPMorgan said in the
filing. The agreement in principle is subject to approval by
the SEC, as well as court approval. </p>
<p>The SEC has issued notices to banks including JPMorgan in
probes focusing on mortgage securities and whether lenders
failed to disclose underlying credit weaknesses. Goldman Sachs
Group Inc. paid $550 million in 2010 to settle SEC claims that
it misled investors on a mortgage-linked investment in 2007. In
that case, Goldman Sachs said it made a mistake in omitting
disclosures. </p>
<p>One investigation related to delinquency disclosures in a
single mortgage-backed security deal, JPMorgan said in today''s
filing. The other involved claims against the lender and Bear
Stearns over disclosures of settlements of disputes against
originators of loans included in Bear Stearns securitizations. </p>
<h2>SEC Warning </h2>
<p>The SEC warned JPMorgan in January that it may bring
complaints related to mortgage securitizations, the company said
in February. Goldman Sachs and Wells Fargo  Co. also said they
were facing U.S. scrutiny over mortgages. </p>
<p>Regulators are still examining how banks packaged and sold
home loans to investors more than four years after mounting
mortgage defaults prompted unprecedented government bailouts of
the financial system. </p>
<p>JPMorgan also won Federal Reserve approval to reinstate a
$3 billion buyback of common shares in next year''s first
quarter, according to today''s filing. The Fed notified the bank
Nov. 5 that it reviewed the firm''s capital plan and wouldn''t
object, the bank said. </p>
<p>JPMorgan announced a $15 billion repurchase program in
March and suspended it in May after uncovering a trading loss at
its chief investment office that eventually swelled to more than
$6.2 billion. The bank was scheduled to spend as much as $12
billion on buybacks this year and up to $3 billion in the first
three months of 2013. </p>
<h2>Good News'' </h2>
<p>We regard this as very good news that will likely lift
all money center banks today as it appears the Fed is still
quite open to allowing stock repurchases, Ed Najarian, an
analyst at International Strategy  Investment Group LLC, wrote
in a note to clients today. </p>
<p>JPMorgan rose 1.9 percent to $41.26 at 8:52 a.m. in New
York. The shares have risen 22 percent this year. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon said in August that he
intended to resume repurchases in the first quarter. Doing so
depended on the Fed and on the board''s completion of work on the
CIO''s wrong-way bets, he said at the time. </p>
<p>The timing and amount of common stock and warrant
repurchases depends on market conditions, JPMorgan said today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Nancy Kercheval" date="Nov 08, 2012 12:49 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-08/walt-weiss-returns-to-colorado-rockies-as-club-s-sixth-manager.html"><headline>Walt Weiss Returns to Colorado Rockies as Club''s Sixth Manager</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Weiss will return to the
Colorado Rockies as the Major League Baseball''s team sixth
manager in franchise history. </p>
<p>Weiss, 48, played shortstop for the Rockies from 1994-98
and was a special assistant to the general manager for seven
seasons from 2002-08, the team said on its website. </p>
<p>Weiss, the 1988 American League Rookie of the Year,
replaced Jim Tracy, who quit Oct. 7 after the Rockies finished
in last place in the National League West with a 64-98 record. </p>
<p>Last season, Weiss was head coach of the Regis Jesuit High
School baseball team in Aurora, Colorado, which went 20-6 and
reached the semifinals of the state championship. </p>
<p>Weiss, who played parts of 14 seasons with Oakland, Miami,
Colorado and Atlanta, earned a batting average of .258 with 25
home runs and 386 runs batted in. He also recorded 96 stolen
bases, 658 walks and 658 strikeouts in 1,495 games. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass and Aaron Ricadela" date="Nov 09, 2012  5:44 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-09/microsoft-says-it-will-replace-defective-surface-tablet-covers.html"><headline>Microsoft Says It Will Replace Defective Surface Tablet Covers</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) said a small number
of covers for its Surface tablet computer are prone to splitting
after two weeks or less in users'' hands and that it''s replacing
the defective ones. </p>
<p>The company is aware of a small number of instances of
material separation of the cover accessory, Redmond,
Washington-based Microsoft said in an e-mailed statement. The
cover serves a protective jacket for the Surface, the tablet
computer released last month. Microsoft makes every effort to
ensure our customers receive a high quality product. </p>
<p>Surface, which went on sale Oct. 26, represents Microsoft''s
first foray into the computer-hardware market. The world''s
largest software company built the device, which runs its new
Windows 8 operating system, to operate as a touch-screen tablet
that doubles as a small notebook computer. </p>
<p>Users can engage a stand to prop Surface on a table, then
fold out the Touch Cover to use it as a notebook. The Surface
starts at $499 for a 32-gigabyte tablet and the Touch Cover
costs an additional $120. Microsoft also sells the two combined. </p>
<p>The defects with the Touch Cover, which users said had
begun to split apart at the seams, were reported earlier on
technology industry websites. </p>
<p>Shares of Microsoft climbed less than 1 percent at $28.83
at the close in New York. The shares have gained 11 percent this
year. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christie Smythe" date="Nov 09, 2012  2:15 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-09/visa-mastercard-7-25-billion-fee-deal-wins-approval.html"><headline>Visa, Mastercard $7.25 Billion Fee Deal Wins Approval</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Visa Inc. and MasterCard Inc. (MA)''s
proposed $7.25 billion settlement of a merchant fee price-fixing
case received preliminary approval by a federal judge in
Brooklyn, New York. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Pablo Gonzalez" date="Nov 09, 2012  1:54 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-09/chevron-seeks-lifting-of-argentina-court-order-clerk-correct-.html"><headline>Chevron Seeks Lifting of Argentina Court Order: Clerk</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX), the U.S. oil producer
considering investing in Argentina''s shale oil fields, is
seeking to revoke a court embargo on its assets in the country
related to a $19 billion award over pollution in Ecuador. </p>
<p>Two units of the San Ramon, California-based company filed
the motion at a Buenos Aires civil court today, Chevron said in
an e-mailed response to questions. Judge Adrian Elcuj Miranda
ordered 40 percent of Chevron''s Argentina bank accounts to be
held in escrow, Enrique Bruchou, an Argentine attorney
representing the Ecuadoreans, said on Nov. 7. </p>
<p>The plaintiffs are seeking to enforce a $19 billion award
against Chevron, which they say is responsible for destroying
the environment in the Lago Agrio region, damaging living
conditions of 30,000 inhabitants. Chevron, which signed on Sept.
14 a memorandum of understanding to help develop Argentina''s
Vaca Muerta shale formation, says the Ecuador judgment is
illegitimate and the embargo is improper. </p>
<p>The plaintiffs'' lawyers have no legal right to embargo
subsidiary assets in Argentina and should not be allowed to
disrupt Argentina''s pursuit of its important energy resources,
Kent Robertson, a Chevron spokesman, said by e-mail. </p>
<p>The Ecuadoreans'' attorneys said Oct. 31 that they were
filing an attachment order in Buenos Aires in line with an
international treaty signed by Ecuador, Argentina and Colombia.
Julio Cesar Rivera, an Argentine attorney who represents
Chevron, declined to comment from the tribunal today. </p>
<h2>More Seizures </h2>
<p>Judge Elcuj Miranda declined to comment on the case today
after receiving eight Chevron attorneys in his Buenos Aires
office. Rivera, who led the group, declined to comment when
asked if a check he was carrying was to pay court fees or to
cover the attachments. Under Argentine law, attachments are
ruled in an inaudita parte basis, meaning the judge orders an
embargo on assets without hearing the other party''s arguments. </p>
<p>Chevron on Oct. 9 lost a U.S. Supreme Court bid to block
the judgment imposed by an Ecuadorean court. The highest U.S.
court let stand a federal appeals court ruling against Chevron
that the Ecuadoreans can''t be barred from seeking to collect the
award anywhere in the world. </p>
<p>On Oct. 31 Bruchou estimated Chevron''s assets in Argentina
worth $2 billion. </p>
<p>Chevron will face more attachment requests in Europe, Asia
and Oceania, Bruchou said Nov. 7 to obtain the total award from
Ecuador. </p>
<p>Another related lawsuit was filed by the Ecuadoreans in the
Ontario Superior Court of Justice in Toronto on May 30. Chevron
Canada Ltd. will have a hearing on the lawsuit Nov. 28. </p>
<p>The Ecuadoreans'' plaintiffs filed in the Superior Tribunal
of Justice in Brazil''s capital of Brasilia on June 27, Karen
Hinton, a spokeswoman for the Ecuadoreans, said today in an e-
mailed statement. </p>
<p>We expect that Chevron''s attempt to undo the freeze order
in Argentina will fail, Hinton said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Blake Schmidt" date="Nov 09, 2012 10:54 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-09/goldman-vindicated-as-swaps-traders-capitulate-on-rates.html"><headline>Goldman Vindicated as Swaps Traders Capitulate on Rates</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Swaps traders are capitulating to
Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) as bigger-than-forecast declines in
wholesale prices prompts them to push out their bets on when the
central bank will raise interest rates. </p>
<p>Traders who wagered in October that the bank would boost
rates from a record low 7.25 percent as soon as April now
predict there won''t be an increase before July. Policy makers
cut the target rate for a 10th straight meeting on Oct. 10 and
said they would keep the borrowing costs stable for a
sufficiently prolonged period to revive the slowest growth
among the biggest emerging-market economies. </p>
<p>While the largest rate cuts among Group of 20 nations has
kept inflation above policy makers'' target of 4.5 percent for 26
months, the biggest decline in an index of producer prices in
three years is supporting an Oct. 26 call by Goldman Sachs''s
Brazil chairman Paulo Leme, who said the central bank won''t
raise rates before 2014. Barclays Plc (BARC) says lower producer prices
will ease pressure on inflation as speculation increases
President Dilma Rousseff''s government will turn to the exchange
rate and fiscal policy to keep consumer prices in check. </p>
<p>The new normal is low rates for a long period of time,
Marcelo Salomon, the New York-based co-chief of Latin American
economics at Barclays, who like Leme expects stable rates to
2014, said in a telephone interview. You do tax exemptions on
the fiscal side instead of stimulating consumption and create an
environment so you don''t need to hike rates in 2013. There''s
less inflation pressure. </p>




Photographer: Dado Galdieri/Bloomberg

<p>
Goldman Sachs''s Brazil Chairman Paulo Leme said developed nations face a long and painful deleveraging process that will weigh on global growth and provide room for Brazil to keep rates at record lows. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sonia Sirletti and Francesca Cinelli" date="Nov 09, 2012  8:44 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-09/generali-third-quarter-net-income-rises-on-fewer-writedowns.html"><headline>Generali Third-Quarter Net Income Rises on Fewer Writedowns</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Assicurazioni Generali SpA (UCG), Italy''s
biggest insurer, said third-quarter profit jumped after year-
earlier writedowns of Greek bonds and stakes in Italian
companies weren''t repeated. </p>
<p>Net income rose to 291 million euros ($369 million) from 20
million euros a year earlier, when the insurer booked 289
million euros of writedowns, the company based in Trieste said
in a statement. Net income missed the 351.5 million-euro
estimate of 13 analysts surveyed by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Third-quarter operating income rose 43 percent to 948.5
million euros, boosted by the life insurance segment. </p>
<p>Generali''s figures were in line at the operating level,
analysts at French brokerage Natixis wrote in a note to clients
today. The financial strength of the group benefited from the
decline in the spread on the Italian sovereign debt, while net
income suggests a lower dividend yield for this year compared
with its peers, they said. </p>
<p>Mario Greco, who took over as chief executive officer in
August, is reviewing the insurer''s strategy as he focuses on
bolstering profit and strengthening capital. Generali is selling
its U.S. life reinsurance business and Swiss asset-management
unit BSI Group because they aren''t strategic assets, Greco said
on a conference call today. </p>
<p>Generali has hired Citigroup Inc. to advise on the sale of
Generali USA Life Reassurance Co. and the unit may be worth $800
million to $1 billion, people familiar with the matter have
said. </p>
<h2>Investor Presentation </h2>
<p>Any other sale or exiting from businesses will be
reviewed over the period, considering its capital efficiency and
capital absorption, said Greco, who will outline his strategy
to investors in London on Jan. 14. </p>
<p>Generali''s agreement with PPF, a private-equity group
controlled by Czech billionaire Petr Kellner, hasn''t changed
after Moody''s Investors Service downgraded the insurer, Chief
Financial Officer Alberto Minali said on the conference call,
denying Italian press reports that PPF may exercise a put option
before 2014. </p>
<p>Generali and Amsterdam-based PPF formed a joint venture in
2007, combining their insurance assets in eastern Europe to
create a company with 9 million customers in 12 countries.
Generali has to buy the 49 percent stake if its partner
exercises the option. </p>
<p>The Italian company reiterated today that it expects non-
life premiums to climb, while life premiums will match last
year''s level. The insurer is targeting net inflow of 2 billion
euros in 2012. </p>
<p>The shares fell 2.4 percent to 12.10 euros at 2:39 p.m. in
Milan, giving the company a market value of 18.8 billion euros.
The Bloomberg Europe 500 Insurance Index (BEINSUR), which was down 2
percent today, has risen 24 percent this year, compared with
Generali''s 4 percent increase. </p>
<h2>Profit Target </h2>
<p>We are confident of achieving a 2012 operating result in
excess of 4 billion euros, in line with our previously announced
target, Greco said. Generali said earlier this year that
operating profit would be in a range of 3.9 billion euros to 4.5
billion euros in 2012. </p>
<p>Shareholders equity rose to 19.2 billion euros from 17.4
billion euros at the end of June, helped by the recovery of
Italian government bonds and equity markets. </p>
<p>The company''s strategy this year was to reduce its equity
and bond holdings in peripheral euro-area countries such as
Portugal in order to reduce risk, Minali said. </p>
<p>Non-life operating profit fell 2 percent to 403.5 million
euros in the quarter. Claims and costs as a proportion of
premiums, known as the combined ratio, was unchanged at 96.6
percent in the first nine months. </p>
<p>Generali''s solvency ratio, a measure of its capacity to
absorb losses, rose to 140 percent at the end of September from
130 percent at the end of June. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Zijing Wu and Jonathan Browning" date="Nov 09, 2012  5:07 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-09/goldman-sachs-southeast-asia-chairman-entwistle-to-retire.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Southeast Asia Chairman Entwistle to Retire</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>L. Brooks Entwistle, Goldman Sachs (GS)
Group Inc.''s chairman for Southeast Asia, is retiring after two
decades at the New York-based bank, according to an internal
memo obtained by Bloomberg News. </p>
<p>Entwistle, 45, will retire at the end of the year and
become an advisory director, according to the memo. He set up
Goldman Sachs''s wholly-owned India business in 2006 and remained
country head until early 2011 when he moved to Singapore for the
current role. Entwistle joined the bank in 1989 as an analyst
and was named partner in 2008, the document shows. </p>
<p>Connie Ling, a Hong Kong-based spokeswoman at the bank,
confirmed the contents of the memo and declined to elaborate. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs ranks second in advising mergers and
acquisitions in Southeast Asia this year, trailing only Morgan
Stanley, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. It ranked
fifth during the same period last year, the data show. </p>
<p>An increasing number of senior executives are leaving
investment banking as compensation in the industry falls.
Goldman Sachs''s Yusuf Alireza, who was co-president of
operations for the Asia-Pacific region outside Japan, left late
last year. A month later Mark Machin, the bank''s vice-chairman
for the region also departed. </p>
<p>Alireza is now chief executive officer of Hong Kong-based
Noble Group Ltd., while Machin heads the Asia-Pacific unit of
Canada Pension Plan Investment Board. Gaby Abdelnour, CEO of
JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s Asia-Pacific business left that bank
earlier this year to pursue personal interests. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs, which is scheduled to announce its new class
of partners next week, has 407 members of that group, 31 fewer
than nine months ago, according to a company filing. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Cliff Edwards" date="Nov 12, 2012  4:25 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-12/microsoft-s-halo-4-tops-220-million-in-franchise-record-2-.html"><headline>Microsoft''s Halo 4'' Tops $220 Million in Franchise Record</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Halo 4, the latest installment
in Microsoft Corp. (MSFT)''s video-game franchise, took in more than
$220 million in its first 24 hours on sale, setting a record for
the title. </p>
<p>The game, a sci-fi shooting adventure, will surpass the
previous Halo record of $300 million in worldwide sales in
its first week, Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft said today
in an e-mailed statement. </p>
<p>Halo, exclusive to the company''s Xbox 360 console,
ranks among the 10 top-grossing video-game franchises of all
time. Various versions have generated more than $3 billion in
revenue, according to Microsoft, and have helped the company
weather an industry drop in sales of games at retail. The Xbox
has been the No. 1 console in the U.S. for almost two years,
according to researcher NPD Group Inc. </p>
<p>Microsoft, which released the first Halo'' title in
November 2001, fell 2.1 percent to $28.22 at the close in New
York. The shares are up 8.7 percent this year. </p>
<p>Halo 4'' faces competition tomorrow from Activision
Blizzard Inc. (ATVI), which releases the next installment of another
all-time leader, the Call of Duty'''' shooter game. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Nov 12, 2012  3:35 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-12/microsoft-says-ceo-called-surface-distribution-modest-.html"><headline>Microsoft Says CEO Called Surface Distribution Modest''</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) said Chief Executive
Officer Steve Ballmer described the company''s approach to
supplying and distributing the Surface tablet as modest,
countering reports that suggested he was referring to sales of
the device. </p>
<p>Ballmer made the comments in an interview with French
publication Le Parisien, according to a statement from
Microsoft. The executive also described the reception to the
device, the first computer built by Microsoft, as fantastic,
the company said in the statement. </p>
<p>U.S. publications such as Pocketnow, Cnet and Gizmodo,
using a translation of the Le Parisien article on the French
publication''s website, reported that Ballmer had said sales were
modest. The translation has now been altered to remove
references to the executive discussing modest sales, according
to Pocketnow. </p>
<p>When asked about Surface, Steve''s use of the term
modest'' was in relation to the company''s approach in ramping up
supply and distribution of Surface with Windows RT, which has
only been available via our online store and Microsoft retail
and holiday stores in the U.S. and Canada, Microsoft said in
the statement. While our approach has been modest, Steve notes
the reception to the device has been fantastic'' which is why he
also stated that soon, it will be available in more countries
and in more stores.'' </p>
<p>Surface went on sale on Oct. 26, at the same time as the
new version of Windows, called Windows 8. Surface is currently
available only with the Windows RT iteration of Windows 8, which
runs on processors with ARM Holdings Plc (ARM)''s technology. A Surface
with an Intel Corp. chip is set to go on sale early next year. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elisha Bala-Gbogbo" date="Nov 12, 2012  9:09 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-12/exxon-mobil-cleaning-up-oil-spill-on-nigerian-coast.html"><headline>Exxon Mobil Cleaning Up Oil Spill on Nigerian Coast</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (CVX)''s Nigerian unit
said it began cleaning up part of the nation''s southeast coast
after a pipeline from an offshore facility spilled at least 200
barrels of crude at the end of last week. </p>
<p>Exxon Mobil shut the pipeline on Nov. 10 and is
investigating the cause of the spill in the state of Akwa Ibom,
the company said late yesterday in a statement from Lagos, the
commercial capital. Dispersants and booms are now being deployed
in work involving more than 100 personnel. </p>
<p>The nation''s authorities don''t yet have an estimate for the
amount of crude released. An aerial inspection will be carried
out before an estimate on volumes is made, Peter Idabor,
director-general of National Oil Spill Detection and Response
Agency, said today by phone from Abuja, the Nigerian capital. </p>
<p>It is not enough for Mobil to say they are cleaning up;
they have to tell us what dispersants they are using, Nnimmo
Bassey, executive director of Environmental Rights Action, an
affiliate of Friends of the Earth, said today by phone from
Benin City, Nigeria. Their continuous spilling in the area has
destroyed the fisheries economy and general livelihoods of the
people. </p>
<p>Exxon Mobil, the second-largest producer in Nigeria, is the
operator of a joint venture in which it holds a 40 percent
stake, with state-owned Nigerian National Petroleum Corp.
holding the rest. The company was involved in Nigeria''s worst
offshore spill that dumped an estimated 40,000 barrels into the
sea from its Idoho platform in January 1998. </p>
<p>Our teams are being mobilized to clean up the area,
Mark Ward, managing director of Exxon''s Nigerian unit, said in
the statement. The company regrets this incident and apologized
for the inconvenience it has caused, he said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Nov 13, 2012  6:47 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-13/microsoft-says-andy-lees-to-head-corporate-development-strategy.html"><headline>Microsoft Says Lees to Head Corporate Development, Strategy</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) said Andy Lees was
named head of corporate development and strategy, part of a push
by Chief Executive Officer Steve Ballmer to step up growth and
fend off competitors led by Apple Inc. </p>
<p>Lees, who assumed the new job last month, reports to Chief
Financial Officer Peter Klein and handles a role that''s been
vacant since Hank Vigil left the company in 2011. Since being
replaced as president of the Windows Phone division last year,
Lees has overseen Microsoft''s investment in a Barnes  Noble
Inc. (BKS) subsidiary. </p>
<p>Ballmer moved Lees out of Windows Phone in December after
the product failed to gain mobile market share following a
complete overhaul. Though Lees was allowed to retain his
president title, he was given a vague job description that
Ballmer called working for me on a time-critical opportunity
focused on driving maximum impact in 2012 with Windows Phone and
Windows 8. </p>
<p>Lees wound up leading a deal with Barnes  Noble that had
Microsoft investing $300 million in a new subsidiary that
combines the bookseller''s Nook digital reader and college
businesses in order to bolster Microsoft''s access to book
content it can offer on new Windows tablet devices. </p>
<p>The job change was announced by Redmond, Washington-based
Microsoft in an e-mailed statement today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Nadja Brandt" date="Nov 13, 2012  5:34 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-13/goldman-provides-1-85-billion-in-debt-for-kyo-ya-hotels.html"><headline>Goldman Provides $1.85 Billion in Debt for Kyo-Ya Hotels</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) provided
$1.85 billion in new debt for hotels owned by Kyo-Ya Hotels 
Resorts LP, including the Sheraton Waikiki in Hawaii and the
Palace Hotel in San Francisco. </p>
<p>The debt, provided by Goldman Sachs Mortgage Co., includes
first mortgage and mezzanine loans, the New York-based company
said in a statement today. </p>
<p>Cerberus Capital Management LP, which owns Kyo-Ya, in May
was seeking to replace debt amassed in 2006, three people
familiar with the transaction said at the time. A deal struck
with Goldman Sachs failed to close last year. </p>
<p>Five of the Kyo-Ya hotels are in Hawaii, including the
Westin Moana Surfrider and Sheraton Princess Kaiulani in
Honolulu. Oahu has been outperforming other U.S. markets. This
year through September, hotel occupancies on the island climbed
to 86 percent, the highest of 25 U.S. markets tracked by Smith
Travel Research Inc., based in Hendersonville, Tennessee. That''s
up from 81 percent a year ago, the firm said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michelle Kaske and Elise Young" date="Nov 13, 2012  4:29 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-13/jpmorgan-to-buy-any-unsold-new-jersey-debt-in-biggest-note-deal.html"><headline>JPMorgan to Buy Any Unsold New Jersey Debt in Biggest Note Deal</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Not enough buyers for $2.6 billion
of New Jersey notes? No problem. </p>
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), underwriter for the sale, will
purchase any unsold debt from the state''s tax-and-revenue
anticipation note deal set to price Nov. 15, according to bond
documents. It''s New Jersey''s largest-ever short-term debt sale
and will repay a loan from Bank of America Merrill Lynch. </p>
<p>JPMorgan will price the notes at a yield of 0.35 percent or
less, with the bank buying any remaining debt. </p>
<p>The underwriter will purchase any unsold Series C notes,
at a yield agreed upon with the state which shall not exceed
thirty-five basis points, according to bond documents. </p>
<p>Andy Pratt, a spokesman for New Jersey Treasurer Andrew Sidamon-Eristoff, didn''t immediately respond to voicemail and e-
mail requests for comment. </p>
<p>Elizabeth Seymour, spokeswoman for JPMorgan, confirmed the
bank''s obligation to buy any residual notes. </p>
<p>JPMorgan''s commitment to buying any remaining debt was
first reported by Dow Jones Newswires. </p>
<p>The state originally planned to sell the short-term debt,
which matures June 2013, through competitive bid last month.
Superstorm Sandy changed those plans. The storm slammed into New
Jersey on Oct. 29 with hurricane-force winds and surging
floodwaters, leaving half the state in the dark. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Gopal Ratnam" date="Nov 13, 2012  2:25 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-13/general-allen-under-investigation-for-e-mails-to-petraeus-friend.html"><headline>General Faces Inquiry on E-Mails to Petraeus Friend</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The U.S. Marine general in charge of allied forces in Afghanistan is under investigation after the FBI found e-mails showing inappropriate communication with a woman whose harassment complaint triggered the resignation of CIA Director David H. Petraeus, a U.S. defense official said. </p> <p>General John Allen, who was nominated last month to become NATO''s Supreme Allied Commander, is being investigated by the Pentagon''s inspector general after the Federal Bureau of Investigation found e-mails between him and Jill Kelley, according to the official, who was on a military plane and spoke to reporters on condition of anonymity. </p> <p>The FBI has handed over 20,000 to 30,000 pages of documents, most of them e-mails, the official said. President Barack Obama has put on hold Allen''s nomination to head U.S. forces in Europe at the request of Defense Secretary Leon Panetta, Tommy Vietor, spokesman for the National Security Council, said in an e-mailed statement. </p> <p>Kelley is the Florida woman whose complaint to the FBI led to a probe that uncovered an affair between Petraeus, a retired Army general, and his biographer Paula Broadwell, U.S. officials have said. FBI agents last night searched Broadwell''s North Carolina home as U.S. lawmakers questioned the handling of the investigation that led to Petraeus''s resignation as head of the Central Intelligence Agency on Nov. 9. </p>




Photographer: Brendan Hoffman/Bloomberg

<p>
Army General David Petraeus, the top U.S. commander in Afghanistan, left, and Lt. Gen. John R. Allen, deputy commander of the U.S. Central Command, listen as U.S. President Barack Obama announces a reshuffling of his national security team at the White House in Washington, D.C., U.S., on Thursday, April 28, 2011. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore and Christine Harper" date="Nov 13, 2012  1:22 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-13/goldman-s-risk-weighted-assets-seen-jumping-67-under-new-rules.html"><headline>Goldman''s Risk-Weighted Assets Seen Jumping Under New Rules</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), the fifth-
biggest U.S. bank by assets, would have $728 billion in risk-
weighted assets under new capital rules, a 67 percent jump from
the amount it had under earlier regulations. </p>
<p>The investment bank plans to cut the figure to $700 billion
by the end of next year, Chief Executive Officer Lloyd C. Blankfein, 58, said today at an investor conference in New York
sponsored by Bank of America Corp.''s Merrill Lynch unit. About
$18 billion of the reduction will come from cutting credit risk,
and $11 billion from market risk, Blankfein said in his seventh
straight appearance at the annual event. </p>
<p>The comments mark Goldman Sachs''s first public estimate of
how new Basel III rules have increased the risks the firm must
assign to its assets, a factor in determining the size of the
company''s capital buffer. While larger banks such as Citigroup
Inc. and JPMorgan (JPM) Chase  Co. face a smaller jump in RWAs, they
will have to hold more capital against those assets based on
their size and business mix. </p>
<p>For more than a decade, larger size and complexity were
viewed entirely as synergistic and virtuous, Blankfein said.
For the first time it''s clear that size and complexity come
with a higher cost. </p>
<h2>Capital Buffer </h2>
<p>Earlier this month, the Financial Stability Board disclosed
capital surcharges for the largest global banks. New York-based
Goldman Sachs is required to hold a 1.5 percent capital
surcharge above the 7 percent minimum. That equals the 8.5
percent ratio the firm estimated it had under the new rules at
the end of the third quarter. The bank probably will maintain a
1-percentage-point buffer above the requirement, Blankfein said. </p>
<p>JPMorgan and Citigroup, along with Deutsche Bank AG and
HSBC Holdings Plc (HSBA), face surcharges of 2.5 percent as they are
deemed more systemically important. </p>
<p>Many of our investment-banking competitors also have
sizable commercial and consumer businesses, Blankfein said.
Any synergy from housing multiple businesses together must be
weighed against the requirements for more capital and
liquidity. </p>
<p>The need to boost the proportion of equity capital has
pressured return on equity, a measure of profitability. Goldman
Sachs generated an 8.8 percent return on common shareholder
equity in the first nine months of this year, down from 19.2
percent in the same period of 2009. </p>
<h2>Nature Rules'' </h2>
<p>Banks have sought to cut holdings of assets with high risk
weightings to reduce capital needs for trading businesses and
improve returns. Goldman Sachs traders have been adjusting their
positions to the new rules since about June, according to
Blankfein''s presentation. </p>
<p>We''ve found that risk-weighted assets have started to
drop already, he said. Nature rules in our firm. If we give
people information and put a charge on something or a cost on
something, that incentive structure will get people going places
much faster than we otherwise would have gotten by fiat or
instruction. </p>
<p>Changes in Basel III rules have a greater impact on Goldman
Sachs''s holdings than those of competitors. The firm''s risk-
weighted assets were 67 percent higher than under Basel I rules,
a greater difference than Citigroup (C)''s 27 percent or JPMorgan''s
28 percent. </p>
<p>Of Goldman''s $728 billion of risk-weighted assets as of
Sept. 30, $250 billion are related to market risk, according to
Blankfein''s presentation. Credit risk from derivatives account
for $125 billion. Credit risks from principal investments make
up $121 billion and other credit risks constitute $186 billion.
The firm''s operational risk contributed $47 billion. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore and Christine Harper" date="Nov 13, 2012  9:27 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-13/goldman-s-blankfein-says-slumps-sometimes-last-very-long-time-.html"><headline>Goldman''s Blankfein Says Slumps Sometimes Last Very Long Time''</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) Chief
Executive Officer Lloyd C. Blankfein, grappling with a market
slump that is putting trading earnings under pressure, said
sometimes cycles can last a very long time. </p>
<p>Still, history shows that New York-based Goldman Sachs
shouldn''t go overboard in reacting to downturns, Blankfein,
58, said today at the Bank of America Merrill Lynch 2012 Banking
and Financial Services Conference in New York. Wall Street has
made past mistakes by cutting too many employees at the bottom
of cycles and over-hiring at the top, he said. </p>
<p>It''s Blankfein''s seventh straight appearance at the annual
event sponsored by Charlotte, North Carolina-based Bank of
America Corp. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Seonjin Cha" date="Nov 13, 2012  4:49 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-13/goldman-sachs-said-to-plan-exit-from-korea-asset-management-1-.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Said to Plan Exit From Korea Asset Management</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) plans to
exit the South Korean asset management business amid sluggish
global stock markets, according to three people with knowledge
of the situation. </p>
<p>The Wall Street firm will probably take steps to protect
customers of its Goldman Sachs Asset Management Korea Co. unit,
said two of the people, who asked not to be named as the matter
is private. They didn''t specify the timing of an exit. </p>
<p>Our expectations for the local Korean asset management
business have not been met, Niklas Ekholm, a London-based
spokesman for Goldman Sachs Asset Management, said in an e-
mailed statement. </p>
<p>Combined operating income at 82 South Korean asset
management firms fell 21 percent in the quarter ended June from
a year earlier as declining asset values hampered fee income,
Financial Supervisory Service data show. </p>
<p>MoneyToday, a Korean-language Internet news provider,
reported the planned withdrawal earlier today. Deutsche Bank AG,
Fidelity Investments and ING Groep NV are also considering
selling some of their South Korean asset management businesses,
MoneyToday reported. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs Asset Management Korea had 40 employees and
six directors as of June 30, according to data on its website.
It began operations after Goldman Sachs bought Macquarie IMM
Asset Management Co. in September 2007, the website shows. </p>
<p>The unit posted a net loss of 7.27 billion won ($6.7
million) for the year ended March, according to the website. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elizabeth Amon" date="Nov 13, 2012 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-13/morgan-on-leucadia-wachtell-o-melveny-business-of-law.html"><headline>Morgan on Leucadia, Wachtell, O''Melveny: Business of Law</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Leucadia National Corp. (LUK) agreed to
buy the portion of Jefferies Group Inc. (JEF) it doesn''t already own
for about $2.76 billion. </p>
<p>Morgan, Lewis  Bockius LLP acted as legal advisers to
Jefferies, and Wachtell, Lipton, Rosen  Katz acted as legal
advisers to the Transaction Committee. Weil Gotshal  Manges LLP
acted as legal advisers to Leucadia, and Proskauer Rose LLP
acted as legal advisers to the Leucadia Board of Directors. </p>
<p>Morgan Lewis''s team was led by R. Alec Dawson, Sheryl Orr
and Robert Robison and included Stephen Farrell, Kenneth Kail,
tax and Richard Petretti, finance. </p>
<p>Weil advised Leucadia and the team was led by mergers and
acquisitions partners Andrea Bernstein and Matthew Gilroy and
also included tax partners Mark Hoenig and Chayim Neubort. </p>
<p>The Proskauer partners advising the Board of Directors of
Leucadia National Corp. on the deal are Martin Bienenstock and
Lorenzo Borgogni. </p>
<p>Wachtell Lipton''s team is led by corporate partners Edward D. Herlihy and David E. Shapiro. It also includes partners:
Jeannemarie O''Brien, executive compensation and benefits; and
Jodi S. Schwartz and Joshua M. Holmes, tax. </p>
<p>Cleary Gottlieb Steen  Hamilton LLP is advising Citigroup
Global Markets, financial adviser to the Transaction Committee
of Jefferies Group Inc. The Cleary Gottlieb corporate team
includes partner Victor Lewkow. </p>
<p>Investors will receive 0.81 Leucadia share for each
Jefferies share they own, the companies said yesterday in a
statement, valuing the entire company at $3.59 billion, based on
data from the company''s most recent 10-Q regulatory filing.
Jefferies management will run the firm, according to the report. </p>
<p>Leucadia, which already holds about 28.6 percent of New
York-based Jefferies, boosted its stake in November as
Jefferies''s stock slid on investor concern it may be burned by
Europe''s sovereign-crisis. The combined firm, to be led by
Jefferies Chief Executive Officer Richard Handler, will make the
investment bank''s balance sheet more resilient, helping it
weather and take advantage of market turmoil, the firms said. </p>
<p>For Jefferies, the deal may allow them to grow and invest
without market pressures in the short term, said Christopher Wheeler, an analyst at Mediobanca SpA in London. </p>
<p>The deal values Jefferies about 24 percent higher than its
closing price on the New York Stock Exchange on Nov. 9.
Jefferies has climbed 3.8 percent this year, after dropping 48
percent in 2011. Leucadia has declined 4.1 percent this year. </p>
<p>Handler also will remain CEO of Jefferies as the
transaction with New York-based Leucadia is completed in the
first quarter, the companies said. </p>
<p>For more, click here. </p>
<h2>Sherwin-Williams to Buy Paint Maker Comex for $2.34 Billion </h2>
<p>Jones Day is advising Sherwin-Williams Co. (SHW), the largest
U.S. paint retailer, in its agreement to acquire closely held
Consorcio Comex SA de CV for about $2.34 billion including debt
to gain Mexico''s largest paint maker. </p>
<p>The Jones Day deal team is led by Cleveland mergers and
acquisitions partner James Dougherty. The team also includes
partners Javier Martinez del Campo, mergers and acquisitions;
and Jose Estandia, mergers and acquisitions/energy. </p>
<p>Sherwin-Williams will fund the all-cash deal by selling $2
billion in 5-, 10- and 30-year bonds, the Cleveland-based
company said in a presentation yesterday on its website. It
didn''t specify how much debt it''s assuming. The acquisition
would be the biggest takeover in Mexico by a U.S. company since
2004, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Sherwin-Williams Chairman and Chief Executive Officer
Christopher M. Connor is adding to the company''s 3,500 North
American stores after an improving North American housing market
led to record earnings in the third quarter. Comex, which has
exclusive sales to 3,300 paint stores in Mexico, generated two-
thirds of its $1.4 billion of revenue last year in Latin
America, Sherwin-Williams said in the presentation. </p>
<p>While the financial details remain unclear, we view the
deal as strategically accretive to the Sherwin-Williams
franchise as it extends the company''s already impressive
distribution network to Mexico and Latin America, Ghansham Panjabi, a New York-based analyst at Robert W. Baird  Co. who
rates the shares neutral, or the equivalent of hold, said in a
report yesterday. </p>
<p>For more, click here. </p>
<h2>Precision Castparts to Acquire Simmons''s Timet for $2.9 Billion </h2>
<p>Precision Castparts Corp. (PCP), the maker of metal forgings for
jet engines, agreed to buy Texas billionaire Harold Simmons''s
Titanium Metals Corp. (TIE) for $2.9 billion in its largest
acquisition in almost two decades. </p>
<p>Weil, Gotshal  Manges LLP provided outside legal counsel
to Titanium Metals and Glenn West led the team. Additional
partners on the deal included Greg Danilow, litigation; Jay Tabor, corporate; Jared Rusman, tax; Michael Kam, benefits;
Douglas Nave, antitrust; P.J. Himelfarb, public company advisory
group. </p>
<p>O''Melveny  Meyers LLP and Stoel Rives LLP advised
Precision. </p>
<p>Titanium Metals stockholders will get $16.50 a share, 44
percent more than the Dallas-based company''s closing price on
Nov. 8, according to a statement. Entities controlled by Simmons
have agreed to sell their 45 percent stake in the company, known
as Timet, Precision Castparts said. </p>
<p>The deal, Precision''s largest since at least 1995, extends
an acquisition spree under Chief Executive Officer Mark Donegan,
who has overseen more than two dozen purchases in the past
decade, data compiled by Bloomberg show. Planemakers Boeing Co. (BA)
and Airbus SAS have urged suppliers to consolidate to help
support record increases in jet output. </p>
<p>Donegan said in a July interview that he foresaw at least
$1 billion in merger opportunities in the next 16 months.
Portland, Oregon-based Precision agreed last month to acquire
pipe processor Texas Honing Inc., and said in July it was buying
four factories from Canadian landing-gear maker Heroux-Devtek
Inc. (HRX) to expand in the aviation-parts industry. </p>
<p>For more, click here. </p>
<h2>Firm News </h2>
<h2>Ashurst Opens Middle East Office in Jeddah, Saudi Arabia </h2>
<p>Ashurst LLP is starting a Jeddah, Saudi Arabia, office by
establishing an association with Saudi partner Faisal Adnan
Baassiri, the head of legal at SEDCO, a Saudi, Shari''ah-
compliant wealth-management company. </p>
<p>The firm will focus on energy, transport and infrastructure
matters and offer corporate services in the region, especially
in Jeddah. </p>
<p>Baassiri, who joins Ashurt as a partner, is a general
practice lawyer, with expertise in general corporate work, real
estate and funds, the firm said. </p>
<p>The economy in Saudi Arabia is undergoing significant
expansion, which is set to continue over the next few years.
There are substantial business opportunities that fit well with
our regional strategic focus on the energy, transport and
infrastructure industries, Joss Dare, head of Ashurst in the
Middle East, said in a statement. This is the first step for
us in the Kingdom and we are confident that our offering will
grow in breadth and depth. </p>
<p>Ashurst has over 1,700 lawyers in 24 offices in 14
countries around the world. </p>
<h2>O''Melveny  Myers Opens Office in Seoul </h2>
<p>O''Melveny  Myers LLP opened an office in Seoul yesterday,
the firm''s 16th office worldwide. </p>
<p>Korea practitioners Jinwon Park and Sungyong Kang will be
residents of the Seoul office. Los Angeles-based partner Joseph Kim, head of the firm''s Korea practice, will work with Kang and
Park as well as other O''Melveny attorneys who work on Korea-
related matters. </p>
<p>O''Melveny has advised Korean clients on antitrust and
patent litigation, among other matters. The firm represented
Asiana Airlines, which had an antitrust claim dismissal affirmed
by the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit. O''Melveny
led the briefing and argued on behalf of about two dozen
airlines, including Asiana, that were accused of conspiring to
fix air cargo rates, the firm said. </p>
<p>Seoul will be O''Melveny''s seventh Asia office, along with
locations in Shanghai, Hong Kong, Beijing, Singapore, Tokyo, and
Jakarta (in an association with Indonesian law firm Tumbuan 
Partners). The firm has about 130 legal professionals resident
in its Asia offices. O''Melveny has 800 lawyers in 16 offices
worldwide. </p>
<h2>Moves </h2>
<h2>Cozen O''Connor Hires Former Pennsylvania Attorney General </h2>
<p>Cozen O''Connor hired Jerry Pappert, who was the executive
vice president, general counsel and secretary of
biopharmaceutical company Cephalon Inc., as a commercial
litigation partner in Philadelphia. </p>
<p>He is the former Pennsylvania Attorney General and current
chairman of the Pennsylvania Banking and Securities Commission.
He will work with Cozen O''Connor Public Strategies, the firm''s
ancillary government relations firm. </p>
<p>Pappert will assist clients with government investigations,
white collar criminal matters, corporate compliance, government
relations and strategy, and general commercial litigation. </p>
<p>At Cephalon, he was responsible for directing company legal
matters, including the sale of the company to Teva
Pharmaceutical Industries Ltd. Pappert was Attorney General of
Pennsylvania from 2003 to 2005. From 1997 to 2003, he was
Pennsylvania''s First Deputy Attorney General. He started his
career as a summer associate at Cozen O''Connor. </p>
<p>Cozen O''Connor has 575 attorneys at 21 offices in the U.S.,
Toronto and London. </p>
<h2>Squire Sanders Hires IP and Technology Litigation Head </h2>
<p>Squire Sanders LLP hired Steven M. Auvil as a partner and
head of the intellectual property and technology group''s
litigation practice in the U.S. He joins from Benesch,
Friedlander, Coplan  Aronoff LLP, where he was chairman of its
intellectual property practice group, the firm said. He will
split his time between the Cleveland and Washington offices. </p>
<p>Steve is held in high regard by his clients and by the IP
litigation bar, he has a consistent history of winning tough
cases, and he has an enviable track record as a practice group
leader, David S. Elkins, global chairman of Squire Sanders''
intellectual property and technology practice group said in a
statement. </p>
<p>Auvil has been first chair in patent, trade secret,
copyright and trademark/trade dress cases in district courts as
well as disputes before U.S. administrative agencies. He has
also argued patent-related appeals before the U.S. Court of
Appeals for the Federal Circuit. He is also a patent lawyer
admitted to practice before the U.S. Patent  Trademark Office,
and has experience counseling clients on IP portfolio
developments; patent preparation and prosecuting; freedom to
operate, infringement and invalidity opinions; and IP-related
deals, the firm said. </p>
<p>Squire Sanders has more than 1,300 lawyers in 37 offices in
18 countries. </p>
<h2>Litigation </h2>
<h2>Mariner Health Sues Law Firm Troutman Sanders Over Sale Payment </h2>
<p>Mariner Health Care Inc., the nursing-home operator, sued
its former law firm for allegedly allowing $40 million from an
asset sale to go to another client and trying to paper over the
payment after the fact. </p>
<p>The money, from the $50 million sale of a medical-supply
unit to Omnicare Inc. (OCR), wound up going to Rubin Schron, an
investor who bought some of Mariner''s real estate through a
company he controlled, according to a complaint filed Nov. 9
against the law firm, Troutman Sanders LLP, in Georgia state
court in Atlanta. Mariner and Schron''s company were both
represented by lawyers who eventually joined Troutman Sanders,
according to the complaint. </p>
<p>Mariner received $10 million directly for the medical-
supply sale, while the rest was to be paid through an
intermediary. The lawyers didn''t complete documents recording
payment for the Omnicare deal until after they got a subpoena
from the U.S. Justice Department, which was investigating the
transaction for possible violation of kickback laws, Mariner
alleged. </p>
<p>If Troutman could account for the missing $40 million
payment on paper,'' then Schron could avoid the risk of being
found guilty of violating the Anti-Kickback Statute, according
to the complaint. Atlanta-based Mariner is seeking $40 million
and punitive damages. </p>
<p>This isn''t the only lawsuit involving Schron and Troutman
Sanders. He sued in New York state court 2010, accusing the law
firm of breaching fiduciary duties. That case is pending. Schron
isn''t a defendant in the Mariner lawsuit. </p>
<p>Troutman Sanders yesterday issued a statement calling
Mariner''s claims without merit and saying the firm will
fight the Georgia lawsuit. Steve A. Engel, an attorney for
Schron, called the Georgia lawsuit baseless. </p>
<p>The law firm of Jenkens  Gilchrist represented Schron in
the 2004 purchase of the Mariner real estate, according to the
Georgia complaint. A few months later, most of the firm''s New
York office left to join Troutman Sanders, according to the
complaint. Atlanta-based Troutman Sanders was Mariner''s
outside general counsel from April 2005 to April 2012,
according to the complaint. </p>
<p>L. Lin Wood, an attorney for Mariner, said yesterday in a
phone interview that the sale of Mariner Medical Supply to
Omnicare wasn''t a disguised kickback. Mariner Medical Supply
was not a shell company, Wood said. It was a fair price
for the company and Mariner is owed the $40 million. </p>
<p>The case is Mariner Health Care Inc. v. Troutman Sanders
LLP, State Court of Fulton County, Georgia (Atlanta). </p>
<p>For more, click here. </p>
<h2>CME Lawsuit Over CFTC''s Swap-Database Rule Faulted by DTCC </h2>
<p>CME Group Inc. (CME)''s lawsuit over U.S. Commodity Futures
Trading Commission swap-data rules will undermine efforts to
boost transparency following the 2008 credit crisis, the
Depository Trust  Clearing Corp. said. </p>
<p>The suit, filed in federal court on Nov. 8, threatens to
dismantle and disrupt the entire regulatory regime statutorily
mandated by the Dodd-Frank Act in order to preserve CME''s
exclusive access to data that it acquires through its role as a
derivatives clearing organization, DTCC General Counsel Larry E. Thompson said in a letter to the CFTC Nov. 11. </p>
<p>CME, the Chicago-based exchange operator that runs a swaps
clearinghouse, is seeking an injunction against CFTC rules for
reporting private trade information, claiming that submissions
to so-called swap-data repositories would be redundant. DTCC,
based in New York, is one of the firms given CFTC approval to
run data repositories for interest rate and credit-default
swaps, among other types of trades. </p>
<p>Dodd-Frank, the 2010 financial-regulation overhaul,
directed the CFTC and Securities and Exchange Commission to
write rules for swap-data repositories to give regulators a
better view on prices and volume in a $648 trillion market
dominated by banks including Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), JPMorgan
Chase  Co. (JPM) and Deutsche Bank AG. (DBK) </p>
<p>The CFTC has granted provisional registration to DTCC Data
Repository LLC and ICE Trade Vault LLC, a repository operated by
Atlanta-based Intercontinental Exchange Inc. for information on
energy, interest rate, credit and other swaps. </p>
<p>One of the essential parts of financial reform is
promoting transparency; transparency both to the public and to
regulators, CFTC Chairman Gary Gensler said in a Sept. 20
interview after the agency announced DTCC''s registration. </p>
<p>Steve Adamske, the CFTC''s spokesman, didn''t respond to
telephone and e-mail requests for comment while U.S. government
offices are closed for observance of Veterans Day. </p>
<p>The case is Chicago Mercantile Exchange Inc. v. U.S.
Commodity Futures Trading Commission, 12-cv-01820, U.S. District
Court, District of Columbia (Washington). </p>
<p>For more, click here. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christine Harper" date="Nov 14, 2012  7:56 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-14/goldman-sachs-names-70-partners-fewest-as-public-company.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Names 70 Partners, Fewest as Public Company</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) named 70 employees to join its so-called partnership, the fewest in the firm''s 13 years as a public company, as sluggish revenue growth pressures expenses. </p> <p>The promotions to partner, which take place every two years, are down from 110 in 2010 and 94 in 2008. Partners, known as participating managing directors, typically receive a $900,000 salary, up from $600,000 two years ago, and a cut of a special bonus pool that''s awarded primarily in stock, according to a person with knowledge of the firm''s policies. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs, the fifth-biggest U.S. bank by assets, confers the status on a group of employees to continue a tradition from the firm''s 130 years as a private partnership, which ended with a 1999 public offering. The designation places an employee among an elite at a company whose alumni include two former U.S. Treasury secretaries and the president of the European Central Bank. </p> <p>Other than billionaire, partner at Goldman Sachs is probably the most coveted status on Wall Street, said Gregory Cresci, an executive recruiter at Odyssey Search Partners in New York. It commands respect. </p> <h2>Adding Women </h2> <p>Fourteen percent of the new partners are women, the highest percentage since at least 2006, according to Michael DuVally, a spokesman in New York. About 59 percent are based in the Americas, with 29 percent based in Europe, the Middle East and Africa and 13 percent in Asia, DuVally said. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
A pedestrian passes in front of 200 West Street, which houses the headquarters of Goldman Sachs Group Inc., in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Charles Mead" date="Nov 15, 2012  5:42 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-15/goldman-sachs-said-to-plan-benchmark-sale-of-three-year-bonds.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Sells $1.75 Billion of Fixed-, Floating-Rate Bonds</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) raised
$1.75 billion in a sale of fixed- and floating-rate notes after
relative yields on bank bonds declined by more than half this
year. </p>
<p>The lender issued $1.25 billion of 1.6 percent debt
maturing in November 2015 that yields 130 basis points more than
similar-maturity Treasuries and $500 million of two-year
floating-rate securities that pay 100 basis points more than the
three-month London interbank offered rate, according to data
compiled by Bloomberg. The bonds are expected to be rated A3 by
Moody''s Investors Service, Bloomberg data show. </p>
<p>Yields on Goldman Sachs''s $2.25 billion of 3.3 percent
securities maturing in May 2015 have declined about 178 basis
points to 1.41 percent yesterday since the New York-based lender
issued the notes six months ago, according to Trace, the bond-
price reporting system of the Financial Industry Regulatory
Authority. The yields of those debentures traded yesterday at
107.9 basis points more than Treasuries. A basis point is 0.01
percentage point. </p>
<p>The extra yield investors demand to hold debt of Goldman
Sachs instead of government securities has dropped by about half
this year to 213 basis points yesterday, from 421 at year-end,
according to Bank of America Merrill Lynch index data. The
average spread on bank debt in the U.S. has tightened 207 basis
points to 177 in the same period. The measure reached 164 basis
points on Oct. 17, the tightest since 2007, the index data show. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christine Harper" date="Nov 15, 2012  1:45 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-15/goldman-names-266-managing-directors-in-annual-promotion.html"><headline>Goldman Names 266 Managing Directors in Annual Promotion</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) promoted 266 employees to managing director, up from 261 last year, as the fifth-biggest U.S. bank seeks to reward staff even as it pares expenses. </p> <p>The annual promotions, which take effect Jan. 1, come one day after New York-based Goldman Sachs named 70 people to its so-called partnership, the fewest since the firm became a public company in 1999. Partners, also called participating managing directors, receive a higher salary than managing directors and share in a special bonus pool. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs, led by Chief Executive Officer Lloyd C. Blankfein, has undertaken a $1.9 billion expense-reduction effort since the middle of last year as higher capital requirements and weak revenue growth cut return on equity. The company employed 32,600 people at the end of September, 3,100 fewer than at the end of 2010. </p> <p>The investment bank expects that 7.2 percent of employees will be managing directors at the start of 2013, unchanged from a year earlier, according to Michael DuVally, a Goldman Sachs spokesman. Managing directors typically receive a base salary of $500,000, lower than the $900,000 granted to partners. Both also get bonuses that can boost their total compensation into the millions of dollars. </p> <h2>Geographical Mix </h2> <p>The number of employees named managing director is down from a record 321 in 2010. About 58 percent of those just promoted are based in the Americas, 26 percent in Europe, Middle East and Africa, and 17 percent in Asia, DuVally said. Last year, about 46 percent were in the Americas, 30 percent in EMEA and 23 percent in Asia. </p> <p>Women comprise 23 percent of the incoming class of managing directors, up from 19 percent in 2011 and down from 24 percent in 2010. The firm said yesterday that 10 of the 70 new partners, or 14 percent, are women. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs, which announced today''s promotions in a statement, created the non-partner managing director title in 1996 to recognize top employees who weren''t yet partners. That first class of 87 managing directors included William C. Dudley, now president of the Federal Reserve Bank of New York; Clifford S. Asness, who left in 1998 to start hedge fund AQR Capital Management LLC; and Richard J. Gnodde, who was named co-head of global investment banking at Goldman Sachs in May 2011. </p> <p>The company names managing directors every year and elects new partners every other year. The following is a list of the new managing directors: </p> <p> *Employee of Goldman Sachs Gao Hua Securities Company Limited **Employee of Beijing Gao Hua Securities Company Limited </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tanya Angerer" date="Nov 15, 2012 10:20 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-15/goldman-sachs-says-asian-bond-demand-surge-may-cause-bubble.html"><headline>Goldman Says Asian Bond Market May Face Bubble on Inflows</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Asia''s bond market is facing a
possible bubble after capital inflows surged this year,
according to Goldman Sachs Asset Management Co. </p>
<p>Bond funds in emerging Asia took in a net $11.45 billion
this year as of Oct. 31, an 85 percent increase from $6.2
billion for the whole of 2011, according to EPFR Global. Yield
premiums on Asia''s BBB rated sovereign bonds have fallen 71
basis points this half to 173 basis points more than Treasuries
as of Nov. 14, compared with a 52 basis point slide to 164 for
similar-rated countries globally. </p>
<p>If bond demand continues at these levels and distorts
prices for a long period of time, the likelihood of asset
bubbles increases, Owi Ruivivar, a Singapore-based senior
fixed income portfolio manager at Goldman''s asset management
firm, said in a telephone interview. The main issue with this
increased flow of funds chasing emerging market bonds is that
prices do not fully reflect economic fundamentals. </p>
<p>Dollar- and local currency-denominated bond offerings in
Asia surged to records this year as low interest rates in the
U.S. and Europe heightened the appeal of the higher-yielding
assets. Investors are demanding less of a premium for dollar
notes in Asia even as the region''s growth is likely to slow to
5.4 percent this year from 5.8 percent in 2011, according to the
International Monetary Fund. Yields on local currency debt fell
to a record low of 3.56 percent on Nov. 13, according to HSBC
Holdings Plc indexes. </p>
<h2>Spreads Narrow </h2>
<p>Supply and demand have become the dominant drivers of
bond valuations rather than economic fundamentals, Ruivivar
said. </p>
<p>Spreads on dollar bonds in Asia have narrowed 128 basis
points this year to 247.2 basis points more than Treasuries on
Oct. 19, the smallest gap since since April 2010, HSBC Indexes
show. </p>
<p>Asia''s resilience during the global financial crisis is a
big factor attracting overseas bond investors, according to
Ruivivar. </p>
<p>Offerings from Asia outside Japan of $113.4 billion this
year have eclipsed the previous annual record of $73.3 billion
in 2010, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. Local currency
bond sales are at the equivalent of $203.9 billion this year,
surpassing the previous record of $195.7 billion in 2011. </p>
<h2>Debt Purchases </h2>
<p>Debt-buying by the U.S. Federal Reserve and the European
Central Bank in September to support the economy have caused
yield premiums to decrease, triggering a surge in issuance. The
U.S. central bank said at the time that it will probably hold
the federal-funds rate near zero until at least mid-2015. </p>
<p>If an environment where no real interest rates continue,
this will push investors to look for higher yields and yields in
the entire fixed income complex will move even lower, said
Ruivivar. </p>
<p>The influx into fixed income, particularly in emerging
markets including in Asia, is understandable due to the dearth
of investment opportunities in higher-yielding products,
according to Desmond Soon, Singapore-based senior portfolio
manager at Western Asset Management. </p>
<p>Global sales of debt backed by commercial loans has fallen
to $121.2 billion from a record $335 billion in 2007, Bloomberg
data show. </p>
<p>Prior to Lehman Brothers, there were a lot more dollar
spread products to invest in such as mortgage-backed securities
and commercial mortgage-backed securities, Soon said. These
have all fallen away or have ended up in the balance sheet of
the Federal Reserve. So, while we are seeing record issuances of
Asian and emerging market corporate bonds in 2012, the reality
is that the universe for dollar spread investors has shrunk
dramatically compared to before 2008. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Frier" date="Nov 15, 2012  6:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-15/ibm-to-offer-4-billion-in-client-financing-through-partners.html"><headline>IBM to Offer $4 Billion in Client Financing Through Partners</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM), the largest computer-services provider, is loaning $4
billion through business partners to encourage client spending,
with terms including no interest for the first year. </p>
<p>To encourage lending, IBM developed an application for
iPads and smartphones that will allow partners to approve their
clients for contracts of as much as $500,000 in minutes, the
company said today in a statement. IBM will administer the loans
over the next 12 months through its global financing unit, which
managed $36 billion in assets as of last year. </p>
<p>Businesses both large and small are having tough times
with this tight credit market, said Mark Hennessy, general
manager of IBM''s global business partners and midmarket, in an
interview. This is an enhanced focus on supporting our
partners taking our solution to market. </p>
<p>Clients will come to IBM for simpler, more flexible loans
because banks don''t necessarily understand this space as
well, Hennessy said. The loans will make it easier for
business partners to sell their own technology combined with IBM
hardware or cloud computing and analytics products, with some
financing offered interest-free for 12 months with no money
down, according to the statement. </p>
<p>In cloud computing, companies hire providers such as IBM to
store data and applications remotely. </p>
<p>IBM''s global financing unit has operated since 1981 and
uses standard industry tools to evaluate default risk, the
company said. Hewlett-Packard Co. (HPQ) and Cisco Systems (CSCO) Inc. have
similar loan options. IBM issued $1 billion in loans to small
and medium-size businesses through its partners in 2011, the
company said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Aaron Ricadela" date="Nov 15, 2012  4:34 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-15/microsoft-s-ballmer-says-company-must-combine-hardware-software.html"><headline>Microsoft''s Ballmer Says Company Must Combine Hardware, Software</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) Chief Executive
Officer Steve Ballmer said the maker of Windows programs must
exploit the opportunity to combine hardware and software as it
challenges Apple Inc. (AAPL)''s iPad with the Surface tablet computer. </p>
<p>Microsoft, the world''s largest software maker, won''t cede
that market to competitors even as partners build the lion''s
share of devices using Windows in the next five years, Ballmer
said yesterday during an address at the Churchill Club speaker
series in Santa Clara, California. The company recognizes
there''s an innovation opportunity by collaborating across
hardware and software, he said. </p>
<p>Microsoft is undertaking an overhaul of its product line
meant to keep it relevant in the post-PC era. The company
dominated the technology landscape during the heyday of the
personal computer in the 1990s and much of the last decade, yet
has been eclipsed in influence by a resurgent Apple and the rise
of mobile devices taking the place of PCs that run Microsoft''s
flagship Windows operating system. </p>
<p>We really reimagined Windows, he said at the on-stage
discussion with Reid Hoffman, the chairman and co-founder of the
online business network LinkedIn Corp. The distinction between
a PC and a tablet I think, at least in our ecosystem, completely
goes away. </p>
<h2>Sinofsky Departure </h2>
<p>Microsoft pushed out Windows division chief Steven Sinofsky
this week as Ballmer pushes for more cross-product coordination
to fight back against Apple and other mobile-device makers,
people with knowledge of the matter said. Ballmer is putting in
place a new team to start work on the next generation of
products after the release of Windows 8, the Surface and mobile-
phone software last month. </p>
<p>Sinofsky''s duties were reassigned to Julie Larson-Green,
who will take charge of all software and hardware for Windows,
and Tami Reller, who adds oversight of the Windows business to
her marketing and finance responsibilities. </p>
<p>The new team is fantastic, Ballmer said. </p>
<p>On the Web, Google Inc. (GOOG) has made its pages hubs for many of
Internet users'' activities, and its Android operating system
powers many of the world''s mobile phones and tablet computers,
markets Microsoft has tried for years to penetrate. Ballmer, 56,
is trying to adapt in a computer industry landscape vastly
changed from when he took over as CEO from co-founder Bill Gates
in 2000. </p>
<h2>HP, Dell </h2>
<p>In response to shifting trends, the Redmond, Washington-
based company last month released Windows 8 -- the biggest
change to its flagship product in nearly two decades -- designed
around a revamped home screen featuring colorful tiles that
launch programs and update users with current information from
the Internet. </p>
<p>With technology companies, you either move forward or you
die, Ballmer said. </p>
<p>On Oct. 26, the same day Windows 8 went on sale, Microsoft
started selling Surface, its first foray into the computer
market. The tablet, featuring attachable keyboards that double
as covers, was designed by Microsoft and runs Windows RT, a
special version for chips from ARM Holdings Plc -- and a break
from the company''s traditional PC partners Hewlett-Packard Co. (HPQ),
Dell Inc. (DELL) and Intel Corp. (INTC) </p>
<h2>Seminal Moment'' </h2>
<p>Ballmer said in an Oct. 25 interview with Bloomberg TV''s
Cory Johnson that the release of Windows 8 and Surface is one of
three seminal moments in his 32-year Microsoft career,
standing alongside releasing Windows 95 and the advent of
International Business Machines Corp.''s first PC in 1981. </p>
<p>Microsoft is relying on the new operating system to revive
interest in the personal computer. The PC market will contract
by 1.2 percent to 348.7 million units this year, according to
IHS ISuppli. That would be the first annual decline since 2001. </p>
<p>Surface is a best-in-class product and sets a high bar
for PC makers to clear, said Rick Sherlund, an analyst at Nomura
Holdings Inc. in New York. Sherlund, who recommends buying
Microsoft shares, estimates the company can sell 2 million
Surface computers in the fourth quarter. </p>
<p>Shares of Microsoft have underperformed the broader stock
market the past five years, losing 21 percent of their value
compared with a 6.6 percent drop in the Standard  Poor''s 500
Index and an 11 percent gain for the SP 500 Information
Technology Index. Fiscal first-quarter sales for the period
ended in September fell 8 percent as sales of Windows and Office
both declined. </p>
<h2>Wild'' Android </h2>
<p>Apple''s Macs, iPads and iPhones are replacing many of the
jobs once done by Windows machines, and Apple has supplanted
Microsoft as the center of gravity for outside software
developers whose products make each platform more compelling.
Apple said Nov. 5 it sold 3 million fourth-generation iPads and
iPad mini models during their debut weekend. </p>
<p>Smartphone versions of Windows held just 2 percent of the
market in the third quarter, dwarfed by the 75 percent share of
Google''s Android and 14.9 percent for Apple''s iOS. </p>
<p>Microsoft is making plans for the possible creation of its
own smartphone, according to people with knowledge of the
company''s plans. The company on Oct. 29 introduced the latest
version of its Windows Phone software that relies on the same
underlying code as desktop and tablet Windows. </p>
<p>Microsoft, which has single-digit market share in
smartphones, wants to get 10 percent to 15 percent share as its
next step, Ballmer said. Windows-based smartphones have an
opportunity to stand out because all these phones look the
darned same, he said. </p>
<p>Ballmer said there''s an opportunity for Windows on
smartphones and tablets since Android is wild and the iOS
ecosystem is controlled and high-priced. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Nov 16, 2012  3:35 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-16/morgan-stanley-creates-middle-market-fixed-income-sales-group.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Creates Middle-Market Fixed-Income Sales Group</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) created a fixed-
income sales group to focus on middle-market clients as it
transfers some investment bank customers to its wealth-
management division. </p>
<p>The group will consist of 50 to 75 salespeople, Eric Benedict, head of capital markets for Morgan Stanley Wealth
Management, said today in an interview. It will be run by Tom Driscoll, who will report to Benedict, and serve more than 1,500
middle-market clients, about 1,000 of which will be transferred
from the firm''s fixed-income division in its investment bank,
according to an internal memo. </p>
<p>It''s freeing up salespeople to cover these accounts
better, Benedict said. We''re putting this platform on the
wealth-management side of the business, where we think we can
better cover these clients, and with that, there are revenue
benefits to both. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer James Gorman is relying more on the
wealth-management business as he aims to buy the rest of a
brokerage joint venture from Citigroup Inc. (C) Gorman has
identified collaboration with the firm''s investment bank as one
of the five ways Morgan Stanley''s wealth-management division
will reach its goal of a 15 percent pretax margin by the middle
of next year. </p>
<p>The margin was 13 percent in the third quarter, excluding
one-time charges, the highest since the joint venture was formed
in 2009. Gorman had previously expected the margin to hit 15
percent by the end of 2010. </p>
<h2>Perfect Parallel'' </h2>
<p>Andy Saperstein, who became head of the investment products
and services division within wealth management in June, brought
Benedict over from Morgan Stanley''s equity capital markets unit
in September to help build more connections with the investment
bank. Last month, the bank announced a structured-products group
that was a joint effort from the institutional and wealth-
management divisions. </p>
<p>The fixed-income division, run by Ken deRegt and overseen
by Colm Kelleher, will share revenue from the new middle-market
unit with wealth management, which is overseen by Greg Fleming,
Saperstein said in an interview. The middle-market group will
serve wealthy individuals in addition to small and midsize
companies, he said. </p>
<p>The firm has had a middle-market equities sales group, run
by Trey Thomas, for about three years, Benedict said. </p>
<p>This is the perfect parallel to the system we have for
equities, which is working extremely well, Saperstein said.
We''re segmenting clients, pooling resources and sharing the
revenue. </p>
<h2>Shrinking Assets </h2>
<p>The move will allow the fixed-income unit to deepen its
relationships with and grow the wallet share of the largest
institutional clients by concentrating the amount of resources
dedicated to this objective, according to the memo, which was
sent by Saperstein, Michael Heaney, global head of credit, and
Rob Rooney, head of fixed income for Europe, the Middle East and
Africa. </p>
<p>Gorman announced in July that the firm would shrink assets
within its fixed-income division in order to improve returns as
the bank faces new capital requirements. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dakin Campbell" date="Nov 16, 2012  5:03 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-16/visa-receives-ftc-letter-tied-to-possible-violations-of-durbin.html"><headline>Visa Receives FTC Letter Over Possible Violations of Durbin</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Visa Inc. (V), the world''s largest
payments network, said it will provide documents to the U.S.
Federal Trade Commission after the agency asked for information
on a debit-card service that may have violated the Durbin
amendment. </p>
<p>U.S. antitrust regulators asked Visa in a Sept. 21 letter
to voluntarily hand over documents related to its PIN Debit
Gateway Service, the Foster City, California-based company said
today in a filing. Visa said it''s cooperating with the U.S. and
responding to its requests for information, and that the revenue
in question isn''t material. </p>
<p>The gateway is optional and provided by Visa to merchant
acquirers that want to route transactions to other networks, but
do not have connections to those networks, Darrin Peller, a
New York-based analyst at Barclays Plc, wrote in a note today.
We suspect that the FTC''s focus is driven by the recent
regulations and the increased use of the service given that
there are now greater PIN debit routing options, he wrote. </p>
<p>The request is another in a line of lawsuits and document
requests faced by Visa and newly named Chief Executive Officer
Charles Scharf as the firm seeks to defend its leading market
share in worldwide payments. In May, the company said it was the
subject of a U.S. antitrust probe into its pricing for debit-
card transactions. Visa continues to provide information to the
U.S. in that investigation, according to today''s filing. </p>
<h2>Merchant Agreement </h2>
<p>The Durbin amendment, named after U.S. Senator Richard Durbin, an Illinois Democrat, is a provision of the Dodd-Frank
Act that limits the amount of swipe fees, or interchange, Visa
and MasterCard Inc. (MA) can charge on debit-card transactions. The
companies collect the money and remit it to their member banks. </p>
<p>Earlier this year Visa, MasterCard and the banks reached a
proposed $6.6 billion settlement with merchants over credit-card
transaction fees after seven years of litigation. </p>
<p>Visa rose 1.9 percent to close at $142.71 in New York. The
shares have climbed 41 percent this year, the fifth most in the
70-company Standard  Poor''s 500 Information Technology Index,
which has gained 7.6 percent. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jef Feeley and Margaret Cronin Fisk" date="Nov 16, 2012  4:22 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-16/pfizer-ceo-must-testify-in-chantix-trial-lawyer-says.html"><headline>Pfizer CEO Must Testify in Chantix Trial, Lawyer Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc.''s top executive must
testify in court about claims the company''s anti-smoking drug
Chantix causes depression and other psychiatric disorders, a
lawyer for an Alabama man suing over the medication said. </p>
<p>Attorneys for Billy Bedsole have subpoenaed Ian Read,
Pfizer''s chief executive officer, and two other officials to
testify live at the trial of Bedsole''s claims that the anti-
smoking drug caused his breakdown and forced him to be
institutionalized, said Ernest Cory, one of Bedsole''s lawyers.
U.S. District Judge Inge Johnson has denied Pfizer''s request to
throw out the subpoenas, Cory added. </p>
<p>The trial, which would be the first patient lawsuit over
Chantix to be heard by a jury, is slated for Jan. 22, 2013, in
federal court in Florence, Alabama, according to court records. </p>
<p>I think the jury will look forward to having Mr. Read
testify in Alabama and he should look forward to defending
Chantix, Cory said in an interview today. </p>
<p>Last month, New York-based Pfizer, the world''s biggest
drugmaker, reached a confidential settlement with the widow of a
Minnesota man who killed himself after taking Chantix. The case
on behalf of the family of Mark Alan Whitely had been slated to
begin Oct. 22 in Florence. </p>
<p>Chris Loder, Pfizer''s spokesman, declined to immediately
comment on the subpoenas for the executives. </p>
<h2>Erratic Behavior'' </h2>
<p>Read, along with Pfizer executives Diana Hughes and Carl
Wilbanks, had been subpoenaed in the Whitely case before it
settled. The same three executives have been called to testify
in Bedsole''s case, Cory said. </p>
<p>Bedsole, an employee with a local power company, took
Chantix in 2007 in hopes of being able to quit smoking, Cory
said. Instead, the drug caused him to develop suicidal thoughts,
memory loss, depression, erratic behavior, mood swings,
anxiety and hospitalization, according to court filings. </p>
<p>Bedsole''s case and other lawsuits have been combined in a
multidistrict litigation before Johnson in Alabama for pretrial
evidence-gathering and the first trials. </p>
<p>The suits claim Chantix causes depression and other
psychiatric disorders, some so severe that patients attempt or
commit suicide. The plaintiffs allege that Pfizer knew of a link
between Chantix and suicide and failed to sufficiently warn
patients. </p>
<p>Pfizer has denied that Chantix was the cause of Bedsole''s
ailments or that the company withheld information about the
drug. The company provided warnings on the drug''s package insert
of reports of suicidal thoughts since 2006, its lawyers have
said in court filings. </p>
<p>The consolidated cases are In re Chantix (Varenicline)
Products Liability Litigation MDL 2092, 09-cv-2039 U.S. District
Court, Northern District of Alabama (Florence). Bedsole''s case
is Billy G. Bedsole Jr. v. Pfizer Inc. (PFE), 09-cv-2051 U.S. District
Court, Northern District of Alabama (Florence). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Nov 16, 2012  3:35 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-16/morgan-stanley-creates-middle-market-fixed-income-sales-group.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Creates Middle-Market Fixed-Income Sales Group</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) created a fixed-
income sales group to focus on middle-market clients as it
transfers some investment bank customers to its wealth-
management division. </p>
<p>The group will consist of 50 to 75 salespeople, Eric Benedict, head of capital markets for Morgan Stanley Wealth
Management, said today in an interview. It will be run by Tom Driscoll, who will report to Benedict, and serve more than 1,500
middle-market clients, about 1,000 of which will be transferred
from the firm''s fixed-income division in its investment bank,
according to an internal memo. </p>
<p>It''s freeing up salespeople to cover these accounts
better, Benedict said. We''re putting this platform on the
wealth-management side of the business, where we think we can
better cover these clients, and with that, there are revenue
benefits to both. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer James Gorman is relying more on the
wealth-management business as he aims to buy the rest of a
brokerage joint venture from Citigroup Inc. (C) Gorman has
identified collaboration with the firm''s investment bank as one
of the five ways Morgan Stanley''s wealth-management division
will reach its goal of a 15 percent pretax margin by the middle
of next year. </p>
<p>The margin was 13 percent in the third quarter, excluding
one-time charges, the highest since the joint venture was formed
in 2009. Gorman had previously expected the margin to hit 15
percent by the end of 2010. </p>
<h2>Perfect Parallel'' </h2>
<p>Andy Saperstein, who became head of the investment products
and services division within wealth management in June, brought
Benedict over from Morgan Stanley''s equity capital markets unit
in September to help build more connections with the investment
bank. Last month, the bank announced a structured-products group
that was a joint effort from the institutional and wealth-
management divisions. </p>
<p>The fixed-income division, run by Ken deRegt and overseen
by Colm Kelleher, will share revenue from the new middle-market
unit with wealth management, which is overseen by Greg Fleming,
Saperstein said in an interview. The middle-market group will
serve wealthy individuals in addition to small and midsize
companies, he said. </p>
<p>The firm has had a middle-market equities sales group, run
by Trey Thomas, for about three years, Benedict said. </p>
<p>This is the perfect parallel to the system we have for
equities, which is working extremely well, Saperstein said.
We''re segmenting clients, pooling resources and sharing the
revenue. </p>
<h2>Shrinking Assets </h2>
<p>The move will allow the fixed-income unit to deepen its
relationships with and grow the wallet share of the largest
institutional clients by concentrating the amount of resources
dedicated to this objective, according to the memo, which was
sent by Saperstein, Michael Heaney, global head of credit, and
Rob Rooney, head of fixed income for Europe, the Middle East and
Africa. </p>
<p>Gorman announced in July that the firm would shrink assets
within its fixed-income division in order to improve returns as
the bank faces new capital requirements. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Brian Wingfield" date="Nov 16, 2012  2:44 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-16/jpmorgan-s-trades-ensnared-by-post-enron-regulator-zeal.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Trades Ensnared by Post-Enron Regulator Zeal</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Millions of dollars in penalties
slapped on some of the world''s biggest banks, including JPMorgan
Chase  Co. (JPM), by U.S. regulators are the result of policing
powers established after the 2001 collapse of Enron Corp. </p>
<p>Within the past month, the Federal Energy Regulatory
Commission, acting on recommendations from a 200-person
enforcement unit assembled in the past three years, proposed
fines on Barclays Plc (BARC) and Deutsche Bank AG (DBK) for manipulating
energy trades. The agency this week revoked J.P. Morgan Ventures
Energy Corp.''s right to trade power for six months next year --
the first such sanction for an active market participant. </p>
<p>I wouldn''t say that we''re picking on the banks, FERC
Chairman Jon Wellinghoff said in an interview. We''re going
after anybody who''s involved in manipulative or fraudulent
activity in these markets. </p>
<p>FERC didn''t always wield such muscle. Its authority
expanded after the California power crisis of 2000-2001, when
Enron traders'' actions triggered rolling blackouts. In 2005
Congress enacted a sweeping energy law that gave the FERC the
ability to go after fraud and manipulation. It also gave the
agency the authority to impose fines as high as $1 million a day
for those who tamper with electric-grid reliability. </p>
<h2>Build Up'' </h2>
<p>The FERC enforcement unit is led by Norman Bay, a former
U.S. attorney in New Mexico, and includes a former general
counsel for the Federal Bureau of Investigation as well as about
40 analysts who focus on market-manipulation violations. </p>
<p>A lot of people think you put a law in place and you''re
ready to go the next day, Wellinghoff said in a Nov. 7
interview. Unfortunately it''s not quite like that. It takes a
substantial period of time to build up a team and to build up
the expertise and the resources necessary to utilize the tools
that Congress gave us. </p>
<p>Researching cases also takes time, and much of the office''s
efforts in recent years are now coming to fruition. Since
January 2011, the FERC announced 11 cases of alleged market
manipulation in the electricity and natural gas markets, and
this year settled with Constellation Energy Group Inc. for $245
million. </p>
<p>The cases have been developed over years. Barclays'' alleged
violations, which drew a proposed record fine on Oct. 31, took
place from 2006 to 2008. Barclays, which said its trading
complied with the law, has vowed to fight the $469.9 million
penalty. </p>
<h2>Deutsche Bank </h2>
<p>Deutsche Bank Energy Trading LLC on Nov. 5 said it was
protesting FERC''s proposed penalties of $1.6 million for alleged
misconduct during early 2010, saying the agency''s legal position
is radical. The agency is punishing JPMorgan for producing
incorrect documents in a manipulation investigation. </p>
<p>A spokeswoman for JPMorgan, which has apologized for what
it has said was an inadvertent mistakes, said it is reviewing
the decision and its next steps. </p>
<p>This is a novel use of FERC''s authority over market-based
rates and is unsupported by FERC''s own regulations, Jennifer Zuccarelli said in an e-mail. </p>
<p>While the violations during the Enron era involved traders
using illegal practices to drive up prices which led to
blackouts, the commission has seen a different type of
manipulation violation in recent years, in which traders try to
play one market off the other, Wellinghoff said. </p>
<h2>Without Hedging </h2>
<p>Traders might take a loss in the physical energy markets,
where electricity is bought and sold, in order to make money on
financial exchanges without any legitimate hedging purpose,
he said. FERC alleges that this is what happened in the Barclays
case. Wellinghoff said energy companies also are reporting
misconduct by calling an agency telephone hotline. </p>
<p>We''re getting substantial information from other market
participants who may be losing money at a competitor''s
expense, he said. </p>
<p>Even though Wellinghoff denied FERC is targeting financial
companies, the investigations are evidence that Wall Street
firms have the savvy to game the system, according to Tyson Slocum, director of the energy program at Public Citizen, a
Washington-based consumer group. </p>
<p>It appears as though Wall Street is playing a significant
role in exploiting overly complex market rules, Slocum said in
an interview. Regulators should revoke energy-trading privileges
for all companies accused of alleged market manipulation, he
said. That''s the most significant club that FERC can wield. </p>
<h2>California Market </h2>
<p>Separately, the California Independent System Operator
complained to the FERC yesterday that the JPMorgan unit, which
controls electric generators in Huntington Beach, is using its
stake to block changes to plants that will be needed by the
state next year. </p>
<p>The grid operator is seeking the FERC''s permission to move
ahead with the project, by removing JPMorgan''s right to object
to the changes. Asked about the filing to FERC, Zuccarelli in an
e-mail today said: J.P. Morgan''s goal is to work cooperatively
to help to find an economic and efficient way to make generation
available in California. </p>
<p>Wellinghoff said he expects market-manipulation violations
to decline as traders realize that the agency''s enforcement
division is operating at full speed. </p>
<p>The message is going to transfer through the industry
that if you engage in this kind of activity you''re going to get
caught, he said. If you get caught you''re going to pay. </p>
<p>Wellinghoff said the FERC plans to go after individual
traders as well as specific companies. And he''s not concerned
about whether this may spook the financial sector. </p>
<p>Have you ever met any traders? he said to reporters
after the commission''s monthly meeting yesterday. Very few of
them are scared or intimidated by anything. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Russell Ward" date="Nov 16, 2012  5:28 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-16/jpmorgan-faces-order-on-anti-money-laundering-systems-wsj-says.html"><headline>JPMorgan Faces Order on Anti-Money Laundering, WSJ Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) is expected to
receive an order from regulators to bolster anti-money
laundering systems and examine past transactions, the Wall
Street Journal reported, citing people familiar with the matter. </p>
<p>The Office of the Comptroller of the Currency will give the
cease-and-desist order amid a wider crackdown on the nation''s
largest banks, the people said, according to the newspaper.
JPMorgan spokeswoman Kate Haywood in London declined to comment,
as did a spokeswoman in Hong Kong. </p>
<p>Authorities and lawmakers in the U.S. have been increasing
scrutiny of banks'' money-laundering controls. HSBC Holdings Plc (HSBA)
said this month that it''s likely to face criminal charges and
the cost of a settlement may significantly exceed the $1.5
billion the London-based bank has set aside. U.K. rival Standard
Chartered Plc (STAN) paid $340 million in August to settle a New York
regulator''s claim it broke Iranian sanctions rules. </p>
<p>The comptroller last week told banks including New York-
based JPMorgan to expect more enforcement actions and fines for
possible violations of money-laundering procedures, the Journal
said, citing banking industry officials it didn''t identify. </p>
<p>JPMorgan fell 1 percent to $39 by 11:21 a.m. in Germany
from $39.39 at the close of trading on the New York Stock
Exchange yesterday. </p>
<p>The OCC in April ordered Citigroup Inc. (C) to improve
compliance with the Bank Secrecy Act requiring safeguards
against money laundering. Deficiencies prevented New York-based
Citigroup from identifying risky customers and monitoring client
relationships, the regulator said at the time. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bryan Bradley" date="Nov 16, 2012  3:23 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-16/ibm-stops-work-at-lithuanian-research-center-verslo-says.html"><headline>IBM Stops Work at Lithuanian Research Center, Verslo Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM) has stopped working at a research center it set up with
the Lithuanian government in 2010 as the European Union refused
to help finance the initiative, Verslo Zinios reported. </p>
<p>IBM put participation in the project on hold several months
ago as Lithuania failed to get financing from the EU to match
the company''s contributions, the newspaper said, citing Vice
Minister of Economy Adomas Audickas. </p>
<p>Lithuania is negotiating with the EU about funding
possibilities and with IBM about reducing the government''s
commitments, the newspaper cited him as saying. </p>
<p>IBM may cancel its five-year contract with Lithuania by the
end of this year if no agreement is reached, Audickas said,
according to the newspaper. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Nov 19, 2012  8:15 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-19/jpmorgan-appoints-marianne-lake-to-replace-braunstein-as-cfo.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Marianne Lake to Succeed Braunstein as CFO</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) named Marianne Lake to succeed Chief Financial Officer Doug Braunstein,
extending an overhaul of senior leadership at the largest U.S.
bank by assets. </p>
<p>Lake, 43, will assume the new role in the first quarter as
Braunstein, 51, becomes a vice chairman, the company said
yesterday in a statement. Lake most recently was CFO of the New
York-based firm''s consumer and community banking business. </p>
<p>Braunstein is relinquishing oversight of the bank''s
finances after Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon, 56, shuffled
other top managers in the wake of more than $6.2 billion of
losses linked to a trader nicknamed the London Whale. Braunstein
had reported to Dimon until July when Matt Zames, 42, the
executive assigned to clean up the bad trades, became his boss
as co-chief operating officer. </p>
<p>There''s been a lot of change recently, somewhat driven by
the Whale, but that''s life, and we tried to do the right thing
there and we''re doing fine, Dimon said in an interview.
JPMorgan is basically done with the management overhaul that
began in May after the bank disclosed initial losses on a
credit-derivatives portfolio. I hope we''re back to what I call
a steady state, he said. </p>
<p>Lake has been CFO of the consumer and community banking
business since 2009. The unit, with 160,000 employees and 50
million customers, offers services including banking, loans,
credit cards, mortgages and wealth management. </p>
<h2>Accounting Background </h2>
<p>Lake, who has a bachelor''s degree in physics, said it was
surreal to see her name on television after yesterday''s
announcement. She started out as an accountant for
PricewaterhouseCoopers in London and Sydney when she was 21
years old and has worked in finance and accounting for more than
two decades. She''s the first JPMorgan CFO with a background
focused on those areas since Dina Dublon left in 2004. </p>
<p>It''s not at the top of my mind to make sweeping changes
right now, Lake said in an interview. It''s a well-run
function that I have been a part of. I have huge amounts of
respect for Doug, and the people who worked with him. </p>
<p>The appointment comes two months after Goldman Sachs Group
Inc., the fifth-biggest U.S. bank and one of JPMorgan''s main
investment-banking rivals, named Harvey M. Schwartz to succeed
David A. Viniar as CFO at the end of January. Schwartz will
assume the role after a career spent primarily in sales and
trading, a contrast to Lake''s credentials and Viniar''s
experience overseeing treasury and the firm''s controllers. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Shaji Mathew and Mahmoud Kassem" date="Nov 19, 2012  6:26 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-19/goldman-sachs-buys-40-million-of-warrants-in-drake-scull.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Buys $40 Million of Warrants in Drake &amp;amp; Scull</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. bought
warrants representing about 8.5 percent of the market value of
Drake  Scull International PJSC, (DSI) a Dubai-based supplier of
engineering services to the construction industry. </p>
<p>The warrants have a notional value equal to 147 million
dirhams ($40 million) with a five-year maturity and can be
exercised after two years, Drake  Scull said today in a
statement to the Dubai stock market. </p>
<p>The company, whose shareholders include HSBC Private Bank,
reported a 93 percent drop in third-quarter profit, missing
analysts'' estimates. Drake  Scull said on Nov. 14 that it
obtained a $120 million loan, coordinated by Goldman Sachs, (GS) to
help it pursue growth plans in North Africa, Asia and other
growth markets and provide the liquidity to capitalize on
various private public partnership projects. </p>
<p>Third-quarter profit retreated to 3.92 million dirhams,
from 57.5 million dirhams a year earlier as contracting revenue
dropped 26 percent, the company said in a statement yesterday. 
The median estimate of four analysts was for a profit of 37.8
million dirhams, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. The 
decline reflected a slowdown in the construction industry, 
according to the company. </p>
<p>Productivity rates dropped across projects in the Gulf
Cooperation Council countries and Africa, while the procurement
cycle dipped because of the summer holiday season, Chief
Financial Officer Osama Hamdan said in the statement. Drake 
Scull has an order backlog of 7.5 billion dirhams, it said. </p>
<p>Drake  Scull fell 4.3 percent to 71.8 fils at 1:59 p.m. in
Dubai today. The stock declined 4.3 percent this year compared
with a 17 percent advance for the benchmark DFM General Index. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Nariman Gizitdinov" date="Nov 20, 2012  4:45 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-20/exxon-shell-said-to-face-delay-on-kashagan-output-boost.html"><headline>Exxon, Shell Said to Face Delay on Kashagan Output Boost</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM), Royal Dutch Shell
Plc (RDSA) and their partners in Kazakhstan''s Kashagan oil field face a
delay of at least two years on a plan to boost output 20
percent, reducing the time they have to recoup costs in the $46
billion project that''s already running eight years late,
according to two people with knowledge of the matter. </p>
<p>Kazakhstan has told the partners to put the $5 billion
step-up plan, taking output to as much as 450,000 from 370,000
barrels day, on hold until they study how the start of
production next year affects the deposit, the people said,
asking not to be identified because the information is private. </p>
<p>After costing almost double early estimates, Kashagan
output may start in March. The Caspian Sea field, a high-
pressure reservoir with lethal levels of hydrogen sulfide lying
70 kilometers (44 miles) from shore, is one of the world''s
biggest finds of the past four decades. </p>
<p>North Caspian Operating Co., Kashagan''s operator, is
working on the development of the gas re-injection project,
NCOC, as the venture is known, said in an e-mailed response to
questions. Exxon, Shell, Eni SpA (ENI) and ConocoPhillips (COP) referred
questions to NCOC, while shareholders Total SA (FP) and state-owned
KazMunaiGaz National Co. didn''t reply to e-mailed requests. </p>
<h2>Force Oil </h2>
<p>Exxon and Shell are seeking operational control as the
venture weighs an even more expensive second phase to take
production to 1 million barrels a day, 54 percent of
Kazakhstan''s 2011 crude output. </p>
<p>Work on the interim project, which involves injecting
natural gas back into the field to help force out more oil, was
due to start this year. </p>
<p>President Nursultan Nazarbayev urged the nation to tap
domestic gas output to walk away from dependence on imports
in a January speech. In September, he called for a review of
Kashagan''s further expansion plans. </p>
<p>The partners plan to build a system to pump gas back into
the field, pushing oil output to as much as 450,000 barrels a
day, according to the website of Eni, the operator until
Kazakhstan tightened control over the project in 2008. In
October of last year, Oil and Gas Minister Sauat Mynbayev said
the field may reach that level of production in 2016. </p>
<h2>Gas Demand </h2>
<p>Kazakhstan''s demand for gas is set to double by 2030 from
12.1 billion cubic meters this year, according to the Oil and
Gas Ministry. KazMunaiGaz National and China National Petroleum
Corp. plan to complete the first part of a pipeline in the
fourth quarter of next year that may carry as much as 10 billion
cubic meters from Kazakhstan''s oil-rich west to its highly
populated southern region. </p>
<p>Before the step-up program can begin, the reinjection
technology must be tested and the Kashagan partners must
determine how much it will accept, how engineering
infrastructure will behave, KazMunaiGaz Chief Executive
Officer Lyazzat Kiinov said on Oct. 2. All these are big,
complex questions. </p>
<p>Shell and Exxon are negotiating to gain operating control
and boost their shares of Kashagan, to ensure it will be
profitable before embarking on the second phase, people said in
August. The companies have warned they may exit the project
unless Kazakhstan extends the venture''s production-sharing
agreement, or PSA, by 20 years beyond its 2041 deadline. The
accord allows the investors to recoup costs before the
government takes its share of oil revenue. </p>
<p>Discussions are ongoing with the PSA authority, NCOC
said by e-mail. Kazakhstan''s Oil and Gas Ministry oversees the
Kashagan agreement. </p>
<h2>Fiscal Environment </h2>
<p>The second phase was suspended about 18 months ago because
the fiscal environment didn''t support the investment, Shell
Chief Financial Officer Simon Henry said Nov. 1 on a conference
call. Shell urged the partners to agree on terms for the second
phase, according to statement that day. </p>
<p>Shell, Exxon, Eni, Total and KazMunaigaz each hold 16.8
percent of Kashagan, after the international partners agreed in
2008 to cut their stakes in favor of the state. Japan''s Inpex
Corp. (1605) has 7.56 percent. </p>
<p>ConocoPhillips is considering a sale of its 8.4 percent
stake in Kashagan, Mynbayev, who is also KazMunaiGaz chairman,
said last month. ConocoPhillips declined to comment on a
potential sale, John McLemore, a spokesman for the company, said
by e-mail. </p>
<p>The budget for the first phase may almost double to $46
billion by the time oil is exported, a person with knowledge of
the matter said in January. An early cost estimate put the tab
at about $24 billion. </p>
<p>-- Editors: Torrey Clark, Will Kennedy </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dakin Campbell and Tim Higgins" date="Nov 21, 2012  7:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-21/general-motors-agrees-to-buy-ally-s-international-finance-units.html"><headline>GM to Buy Non-U.S. Units From Ally in $4.2 Billion Deal</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>General Motors Co. (GM) agreed to purchase Ally Financial Inc. (ALLY)''s international auto-finance businesses in a $4.2 billion deal that will give the carmaker an opportunity to expand outside North America. </p> <p>The sale includes operations in Europe and Latin America as well as Ally''s 40 percent stake in an auto-lending joint venture in China, the Detroit-based companies said yesterday in separate statements. The China business wasn''t among non-U.S. assets that Ally said in May it was seeking to divest. </p> <p>GM, which counts the U.S. government as its biggest shareholder, is seeking to reverse losses in Europe and a turnaround for its South American results after a $122 million operating loss in that region last year. The automaker, led by Chief Executive Officer Dan Akerson, relies on North America for most of its earnings and is looking to diversify revenue sources. The deal also bolsters GM''s in-house financing arm. </p> <p>The acquisition is great for GM, Matthew Stover, an analyst at Guggenheim Securities LLC, said before the agreement was announced. Regardless of what auto companies say when they sell their captive finance arms, having a captive finance arm allows you to be much more flexible, responsive, profitable and competitive when you play in the market. </p>




Photographer: Nelson Ching/Bloomberg

<p>
The sale includes operations in Europe and Latin America as well as Ally''s 40 percent stake in an auto-lending joint venture in China. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David McLaughlin and Dawn Kopecki" date="Nov 21, 2012  4:35 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-21/jpmorgan-turned-cio-into-prop-trading-desk-pensions-say.html"><headline>JPMorgan Turned CIO Into Prop-Trading Desk, Pensions Say</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) turned its
chief investment office into a secret hedge fund that caused
more than $6.2 billion in losses, pension funds said in a
revised complaint in their lawsuit against the bank. </p>
<p>JPMorgan represented that the office''s primary role was
managing risk when in fact it was engaging in trades to generate
profit for the New York-based bank, the funds said in an amended
complaint filed yesterday in Manhattan federal court. </p>
<p>JPMorgan Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon secretly
transformed the CIO from a risk management unit into a
proprietary trading desk whose principal purpose was to engage
in speculative, high-risk bets designed to generate profits,
the plaintiffs said. </p>
<p>U.S. District Judge George Daniels ruled in August that
lawsuits against JPMorgan, the biggest U.S. bank by assets,
should be consolidated into a class action. The pension funds
allege that they incurred losses in their holdings because of
trades by the chief investment office and Bruno Iksil, known as
the London Whale. </p>
<p>The lead plaintiffs include the Arkansas Teacher Retirement
System, the Ohio Public Employees Retirement System, and the
state of Oregon. They claim JPMorgan''s statements about the CIO
and the bank''s risk-management practices misled investors. </p>
<h2>Bank Shareholders </h2>
<p>The complaint was filed on behalf of JPMorgan shareholders
who bought stock between Feb. 24, 2010, when the company filed
its 2009 earnings report with regulators, and May 21, 2012, when
the bank announced it was halting a $15 billion share buyback
program until it could control the losses. </p>
<p>Joe Evangelisti, a JPMorgan spokesman, declined to comment
on the complaint. </p>
<p>The plaintiffs claim that bank executives decided against
establishing a so-called liquidity reserve for Iksil''s portfolio
in 2010 -- despite an internal report that said the bank needed
$2 billion to $4 billion in reserves in case markets became
illiquid and the company was forced to sell his positions. </p>
<p>Because the company never took the liquidity reserve it
was required to have taken, the company''s net income was
overstated by at least $2 billion each quarter during the class
period, rendering JPMorgan''s financial statements materially
false, according to the complaint. </p>
<p>In addition to Dimon, 56, the investors are suing Michael Cavanagh, co-CEO of the corporate and investment bank; Chief
Financial Officer Douglas Braunstein; and Ina Drew, who was the
bank''s chief investment officer. </p>
<p>JPMorgan senior management made a conscious, strategic
decision to use the CIO for proprietary trading in pursuit of
short-term profits, the plaintiffs said. </p>
<p>The case is In re JPMorgan Chase  Co. Securities
Litigation, 12-cv-3852, U.S. District Court, Southern District
of New York (Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jef Feeley and Bob Van Voris" date="Nov 21, 2012  2:29 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-21/pfizer-destroyed-arthritis-drugs-files-investors-claim.html"><headline>Pfizer Destroyed Arthritis Drugs'' Files, Investors Claim</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE) destroyed documents
about the development of its Celebrex and Bextra arthritis drugs
while denying the existence of electronic databases containing
millions of files about the medicines, lawyers for some of the
company''s investors said in court filings. </p>
<p>Pfizer officials should be sanctioned for denying they had
a centralized filing system for Celebrex and Bextra files and
discarding records after investors filed suit accusing the
company of misleading them about the drugs'' prospects,
shareholders'' attorneys said in a court filing that was unsealed
Nov. 16 in federal court in Manhattan. Pfizer executives later
acknowledged the company maintained more than 2,000 so-called e-
Rooms that stored documents about the drugmaker''s products, the
lawyers said. </p>
<p>Defendants destroyed documents in bad faith and
compounded their initial misconduct by making false statements
about the existence of centralized databases, Jay Eisenhofer,
a New York-based attorney serving as lead counsel in the
investors'' securities-fraud suit, said in the filing. </p>
<p>Last month, Pfizer officials agreed to pay $164 million to
settle claims by a separate group of investors that the
drugmaker distorted the results of a study about Celebrex''s
safety profile. </p>
<p>Pfizer officials said today they are asking the judge in
New York to throw out investors'' claims over statements about
the drugs and called the sanctions request over the company''s
document handling baseless. </p>
<h2>Sanctions Sought </h2>
<p>Pfizer officials also are seeking sanctions against
investors who have sued over the company''s statements about
Celebrex and Bextra for their failure to preserve electronic
documents relevant to this litigation, Chris Loder, a company
spokesman, said in an e-mailed statement. </p>
<p>Pfizer has complied with its document production
obligations in this case, Loder said. The drugmaker is looking
forward to an adjudication of this case on the merits. </p>
<p>U.S. District Judge Laura Taylor Swain in New York, who is
presiding over a series of investor suits filed in 2004, ruled
in March that shareholders could band together to sue Pfizer
over its statements about Celebrex and Bextra. </p>
<p>No trial date has been set in the case against New York-
based Pfizer, the world''s largest drugmaker. The company opposed
shareholders'' requests to have their cases granted class-action
status. </p>
<h2>2009 Settlement </h2>
<p>Celebrex is Pfizer''s fifth best-selling medicine, with
almost $2.5 billion in annual sales. Pfizer officials pulled
Bextra off the market in 2005 after it was linked to an
increased risk of heart attacks and a rare skin condition. </p>
<p>In 2009, Pfizer agreed to pay $2.3 billion to settle a U.S.
investigation into illegal marketing of 10 of its drugs,
including Bextra. Pharmacia  Upjohn Co., a Pfizer unit, pleaded
guilty to a criminal charge related to misbranding drugs,
according to the U.S. Justice Department. The fine was one of
the largest in U.S. legal history. </p>
<p>Investors sued the drugmaker accusing executives of making
misleading statements about the safety and marketability of
Pfizer''s Celebrex and Bextra products over a four-year period
starting in 2000, according to a 2004 court filing. </p>
<h2>Health Risks'' </h2>
<p>Defendants knew or recklessly disregarded that the
undisclosed health risks posed by these drugs would limit their
marketability and further knew that the potential financial
liability Pfizer faced from the harms these drugs caused posed a
serious threat to the company''s finances, according to the
investors'' suit. </p>
<p>Eisenhofer and other lawyers for investors contend in the
unsealed court filings that Pfizer failed to properly hand over
documents in pretrial exchanges and destroyed records related to
Celebrex and Bextra. </p>
<p>At one point, the company argued the existence of the e-
Rooms were a figment of plaintiffs'' imagination, the lawyer
said. Pfizer officials later acknowledged the rooms existed and
turned over documents stored there electronically, investors''
lawyers said. </p>
<p>The lawyers also complained that Pfizer''s technical staff
undertook two large-scale e-Room dismantling projects while
this case was pending and still are failing to provide vital
piece of information, including database memberships,
according to the filing. </p>
<h2>60 Million Documents </h2>
<p>Pfizer''s lawyers counter in their filings that they have
turned over more than 60 million documents related to Bextra and
Celebrex and the company never misled their opponents about
electronically stored material. </p>
<p>At no time did Pfizer ever mislead plaintiffs concerning
the existence of databases, the company''s lawyers said in the
filing unsealed Nov. 16. Stating that certain categories of
documents were not maintained in a centralized location is not
the same as representing that no databases exist. </p>
<p>Pfizer turned over the equivalent of 220 boxes of files
from the e-Rooms once plaintiffs sought the information and
spent many hours locating systems that had long been
integrated or retired to produce the requested material, the
lawyers said. </p>
<p>The data Pfizer is accused of failing to turn over about
the drugs'' safety profiles was in the possession of federal
regulators and had been publicly disclosed, the lawyers added. </p>
<p>Nothing the company has done in finding and handing over
relevant material about Celebrex and Bextra warrants
sanctions, Pfizer''s attorneys said. </p>
<p>The case is In re Pfizer Inc. Securities Litigation, 04-
cv-9866, U.S. District Court, Southern District of New York
(Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chris Dolmetsch" date="Nov 21, 2012  1:23 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-21/morgan-stanley-sued-by-german-lender-over-mortgage-bonds-1-.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Sued by German Lender Over Mortgage Bonds</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) was sued by DZ Bank
AG, a clearinghouse for cooperative banks in Germany, over
claims the investment bank misrepresented and omitted
information about $694 million in mortgage-backed securities. </p>
<p>DZ Bank, based in Frankfurt, filed the suit today in New
York State Supreme Court in Manhattan. It has taken similar
actions in the same court against other banks this year,
including JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), HSBC Holdings Plc, UBS AG and
Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) </p>
<p>Pools of home loans securitized into bonds were a central
part of the housing bubble that helped send the U.S. into the
biggest recession since the 1930s. The housing market collapsed,
and the crisis swept up lenders and investment banks as the
market for the securities evaporated. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s media office didn''t immediately return an
e-mail seeking comment on the lawsuit. </p>
<p>DZ Bank is one of two clearing organizations for Germany''s
cooperative banks, allowing it to provide structured products
directly to more than 900 local lenders. </p>
<p>The case is Deutsche Zentral Genossenschaftsbank AG v.
Morgan Stanley, 654035/2012, New York State Supreme Court, New
York County (Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sherry Su" date="Nov 21, 2012 12:38 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-21/morgan-stanley-cuts-forties-offer-force-majeure-on-qua-iboe-oil.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Cuts Forties Offer; Force Majeure on Qua Iboe Oil</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley failed to sell a
cargo of North Sea Forties crude even after lowering its offer.
No bids or offers were made for Russian Urals blend in Europe
for a third day. </p>
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. declared force majeure on Nigerian Qua
Iboe loadings because of repair works on a pipeline following an
oil leak on Nov. 9, the company said today in an e-mailed
statement. CPC Corp. bought four cargoes of Angolan Cabinda and
two of Nemba for loading in January, according to three traders
with knowledge of the matter. </p>
<h2>North Sea </h2>
<p>Morgan Stanley failed to sell the Forties for loading Dec.
8 to Dec. 10 at 10 cents a barrel less than Dated Brent, down
from its offer yesterday at a premium of 10 cents for the same
shipment dates, according to a Bloomberg survey of traders and
brokers monitoring the Platts window. A lot for Dec. 4 to Dec. 6
traded in the previous session at a discount of 25 cents. </p>
<p>Mercuria Energy Trading SA was unable to sell a cargo for
loading on Dec. 6 to Dec. 8 at 15 cents less than Dated Brent,
while Vitol Group didn''t find buyers for a consignment for Dec.
3 to Dec. 5 at a discount of 30 cents, the survey showed. </p>
<p>Reported crude trading typically occurs during the Platts
window, which ends at 4:30 p.m. London time. Before the session,
Forties loading in 10 to 25 days was 8 cents less than Dated
Brent, compared with a premium of 4 cents yesterday, data
compiled by Bloomberg show. </p>
<p>Brent for January settlement traded at $110.42 a barrel on
the ICE Futures Europe exchange in London at the close of the
window, compared with $110.05 yesterday. The February contract
was at $109.59, a discount of 83 cents to January. </p>
<p>Statoil ASA booked a supertanker to haul North Sea crude to
South Korea, boosting the tally this year to 48 million barrels,
according to shipbroker reports. </p>
<p>Statoil chartered the very large crude carrier Samco
Scandinavia to load on Dec. 15 from Mongstad, Norway, at a cost
of $5.75 million, according to four fixture lists including from
Athens-based Optima Shipbrokers Ltd. Mongstad is the loading
terminal for Norwegian Troll and Heidrun blends. This is the
first tanker booked for December and compares with two scheduled
for this month. </p>
<h2>Mediterranean/Urals </h2>
<p>Urals was unchanged at 90 cents a barrel less than Dated
Brent in the Mediterranean, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Russia will reduce Urals shipments from three ports in
early December, according to a partial loading schedule obtained
by Bloomberg News. </p>
<p>Exports from the Baltic port of Primorsk will be cut to 15
cargoes of 100,000 metric tons each from Nov. 30 to Dec. 11, six
less than a month earlier, the program showed. </p>
<p>Russia will ship four lots of 140,000 tons and five of
80,000 tons from Novorossiysk on the Black Sea in the same
period, the plan showed. This totals 960,000 tons, compared with
1.32 million tons a month earlier. Siberian Light loadings from
this port will be unchanged at one cargo of 80,000 tons,
according to the program. </p>
<p>Exports of Urals from the Baltic port of Ust-Luga will be
seven cargoes of 100,000 tons each from Dec. 1 to Dec. 11, one
less than a month earlier, according to the schedule. </p>
<h2>West Africa </h2>
<p>Qua Iboe fell 2 cents to $1.77 a barrel more than Dated
Brent, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Royal Dutch Shell Plc lifted its force majeure on Bonny
Light exports from Nigeria at 9 a.m. local time today, while
maintaining its halt on shipments of Forcados grade, a company
official said. </p>
<p>Nigeria raised its December official selling price for
benchmark Bonny Light and Qua Iboe crudes to the highest level
in six months, the Nigerian National Petroleum Corp. said in an
e-mailed statement. </p>
<p>The two grades were set at $1.90 a barrel more than to
Dated Brent, the most since June and compares with a premium of
$1.80 for this month, according to the list. </p>
<p>Sonangol Holdings, Chevron Corp., China International
United Petroleum  Chemical Corp., known as Unipec, and
PetroChina Co. were awarded the Cabinda lots from CPC, the
traders said, declining to be identified as the information is
confidential. Sonangol also sold the two Nemba shipments. </p>
<p>PT Pertamina bought 950,000 barrels of Nemba crude for
January delivery via a tender, according to a company official
who asked not to be identified because of internal policy. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Pablo Gonzalez" date="Nov 21, 2012 10:11 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-21/chevron-says-spain-courts-can-t-rule-on-deal-with-argentine-ypf.html"><headline>Chevron Says Spain Courts Can''t Rule on Deal With Argentine YPF</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX) said the Spanish court
where Repsol SA filed a lawsuit against it for entering into an
agreement with YPF SA (YPF) to develop shale gas reserves in Argentina
doesn''t have authority to rule on the deal. </p>
<p>There is no basis for this lawsuit and any such suit, if
brought forward, would be unproductive, James Craig, a
spokesman for Chevron''s African and Latin American operations,
said in an e-mailed statement sent to Bloomberg. Courts in
Spain do not have jurisdiction in this matter and Chevron stands
by the legitimacy of its memorandum of understanding with YPF. </p>
<p>Two months after San Ramon, California-based Chevron signed
a memorandum of understanding with Buenos Aires-based YPF to
study tapping aging wells in the Vaca Muerta shale formation,
Repsol sued Chevron in Mercantile Court in Madrid for allegedly
commercial unloyalty, a spokesman from the Madrid-based
company said on Nov. 19. The filing of the suit couldn''t be
verified because phonecalls to the court weren''t answered. </p>
<p>Chevron hasn''t been served with any legal action, Craig
said. Chevron remains hopeful that a needless judicial
proceeding can be averted, Craig said. Alejandro Di Lazzaro, a
YPF spokesman, declined to comment on the suit. </p>
<p>Vaca Muerta, a Connecticut-sized area located in the
western Argentine province of Neuqeun, contains the equivalent
of more than 23 billion barrels of oil. </p>
<p>YPF is seeking a partner to invest $4.5 billion as part of
a $37.2 billion five-year expansion, according to the document. </p>
<p>Repsol is also seeking $10.5 billion in compensation from
the Argentine government for the expropriation of a majority
stake of YPF, which the Spanish company says was illegal. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Aaron Kirchfeld, Elisa Martinuzzi and Giles Broom" date="Nov 22, 2012 11:02 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-22/generali-said-to-pitch-sale-of-private-bank-bsi-to-apax-rbc.html"><headline>Generali Said to Pitch Sale of Private Bank BSI to Apax, RBC</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Assicurazioni Generali SpA (G) is
seeking offers for its Swiss private bank BSI Group from buyout
firms including Apax Partners LLP and companies such as Royal
Bank of Canada (RY), according to three people with knowledge of the
situation. </p>
<p>Generali''s advisers, JPMorgan Chase  Co. and Mediobanca
SpA (MB), are sending sales documents to potential buyers this month
for the 139-year-old wealth manager, said the people, asking not
to be identified because the discussions are private. The so-
called information memorandums will be sent to at least 20
potential buyers, one of the people said. Indicative offers are
due in January, two people said. </p>
<p>Generali Chief Executive Officer Mario Greco, who took the
helm in August, is reviewing the strategy of Italy''s biggest
insurer to bolster profit and strengthen capital weakened by the
sovereign-debt crisis. Generali may battle to find a buyer as
the erosion of Swiss banking secrecy and higher regulatory costs
crimp margins, complicating the task of assessing the financial
health and business model of a private bank. </p>
<p>BSI''s book value is about 2.3 billion euros ($2.96
billion), according to Trieste, Italy-based Generali. The
insurer may struggle to sell the private bank for that amount,
two of the people said. </p>
<p>Officials at Generali, Apax, RBC, JPMorgan and Mediobanca
declined to comment. </p>
<h2>Overseas Expansion </h2>
<p>BSI, the largest private bank in Switzerland''s Italian-
speaking region, has been expanding operations abroad, winning
clients in Singapore and Hong Kong. The firm boosted client
assets under management by 4.9 percent to 81.5 billion Swiss
francs ($87 billion) in the first half from the end of 2011,
according to Lugano, Switzerland-based BSI. Net income rose 33
percent to 42.6 million francs in the period. </p>
<p>RBC CEO Gordon Nixon has said his firm would explore
strategic acquisitions amid a slowdown in Canadian consumer
lending. Toronto-based RBC, the nation''s largest lender, has
named wealth and asset management as one of the areas it plans
to grow. </p>
<p>Generali and other European insurers are selling non-core
assets before the planned implementation in 2016 of Solvency II
regulations, which requires capital reserves to be aligned with
risks to boost protection for policyholders. </p>
<p>The Italian insurer has hired Citigroup Inc. to advise on
the sale of Generali USA Life Reassurance Co., a unit that may
be valued at $800 million to $1 billion, people with knowledge
of the matter have said. </p>
<h2>Solvency Ratio </h2>
<p>Generali said Nov. 9 that its solvency ratio, a measure of
its capacity to absorb losses, rose to 140 percent at the end of
September from 130 percent at the end of June. Third-quarter
profit jumped to 291 million euros from 20 million euros after
year-earlier writedowns of Greek bonds and stakes in Italian
companies weren''t repeated. </p>
<p>Apax, which is based in London, owns financial firms
including Israeli fund manager Psagot Investment House Ltd. and
personal-finance information provider Bankrate Inc. </p>
<p>Potential buyers such as RBC and Apax haven''t decided
whether they''ll make a bid for BSI, the people said. </p>
<p>Swiss banks are seeing withdrawals by American and European
clients who are repatriating assets following a crackdown on tax
evasion that has widened since the U.S. sued UBS AG three years
ago. Higher compliance and regulatory costs as wealth managers
pursue a new white-money strategy are also crimping profit
margins. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Emma Ross-Thomas" date="Nov 22, 2012 10:17 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-22/chevron-has-five-days-to-answer-repsol-suit-on-argentine-assets.html"><headline>Chevron Has Five Days to Answer Repsol Suit on Argentine Assets</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX) has five days to
respond to a lawsuit from Repsol SA (REP) for entering into an
agreement with YPF SA (YPF) to develop reserves in Argentina,
documents from the Spanish court where the case is filed show. </p>
<p>The mercantile court in Madrid gave the U.S. company 20
working days from Oct. 26 to answer the suit or risk being
excluded from the process, court documents obtained by Bloomberg
News show. </p>
<p>The court agreed to consider the case in the same decision,
saying it has the jurisdiction to do so. A court official, who
declined to be named in line with policy, confirmed the details
of the document, which isn''t public. </p>
<p>Repsol is suing Chevron after it signed a memorandum of
understanding with Buenos Aires-based YPF to study tapping wells
in Vaca Muerta shale formation. The deal was made after
Argentina expropriated Repsol''s majority stake in YPF, a
decision the Spanish company says is illegal and for which it is
seeking $10.5 billion in compensation from the Argentine
government. </p>
<p>Chevron, based in San Ramon, California, hasn''t been served
with any legal action, and any case would be unproductive as
Spanish courts don''t have the authority to rule on the issue,
James Craig, a spokesman for Chevron''s African and Latin
American operations, said yesterday. He didn''t reply to calls
and e-mails seeking comment today. </p>
<p>Kristian Rix, a spokesman for Repsol, confirmed on Nov. 19
that the court had agreed to consider the suit against Chevron. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alessandro Vitelli" date="Nov 22, 2012  6:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-22/jpmorgan-considers-selling-ecosecurities-carbon-finance-says.html"><headline>JPMorgan Considers Selling EcoSecurities, Carbon Finance Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) may sell its
EcoSecurities carbon offset business in the U.K., according to a
report on the Carbon Finance website that sites unidentified
people. </p>
<p>The bank is keen to make an exit from the investment and
EcoSecurities executives are open to discussions with potential
buyers, the online news analysis service said. </p>
<p>Patrick Burton, vice-president of media relations at
JPMorgan in London, declined to comment on the report when
contacted by e-mail today. </p>
<p>JPMorgan acquired EcoSecurities in 2009 for 124 million
pounds ($198 million). The Oxford-based company is the largest
developer of carbon-offset projects under the United Nations''
Clean Development Mechanism, according to the UN Environment
Program''s Risoe Center in Roskilde, Denmark. The projects
generate Certified Emission Reductions that may be used by
companies in the European Union''s emissions-trading system. </p>
<p>CERs for December gained 2.6 percent to 80 cents yesterday.
They''ve fallen 97 percent since reaching their highest level in
2008. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Thomas Penny" date="Nov 23, 2012 10:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-23/general-dynamics-wins-73-million-u-k-foxhound-contract.html"><headline>General Dynamics Wins $73 Million U.K. Foxhound Contract</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The U.K. will spend 46 million
pounds ($73 million) on 51 Foxhound patrol vehicles from General
Dynamics Corp.''s (GD) Force Protection unit, Defense Minister Philip Dunne said. </p>
<p>The contract, to supply front-line units in Afghanistan,
marks the latest phase of a 340 million-pound government
investment in the British-built Foxhound since 2010 to provide a
total of 376 vehicles, the Ministry of Defense said in an e-
mailed statement today. </p>
<p>Foxhound is a real procurement success story, taking only
40 months to develop it from the initial design to deployment in
Afghanistan, Dunne said. Balancing the MoD''s budget means we
can now confidently invest in equipment like Foxhound, which has
the flexibility and adaptability to operate in a wide variety of
environments, providing capability for the Army well into the
future. </p>
<p>-Editors: Eddie Buckle, Andrew Atkinson </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Don Jeffrey" date="Nov 24, 2012  4:22 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-24/disney-s-abc-asks-judge-to-block-dish-s-autohop.html"><headline>Disney''s ABC Asks Judge to Block Dish''s Autohop</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS)''s ABC television
network is trying to shut down Dish Network Corp. (DISH)''s ad-skipping
TV recording feature two weeks after a federal judge denied a
similar bid by a different broadcaster. </p>
<p>ABC said it will seek a preliminary injunction from U.S.
District Judge Laura Taylor Swain, according to a filing late
yesterday in Manhattan federal court. On Nov. 7, U.S. District
Judge Dolly Gee in Los Angeles rejected a motion for an
injunction by News Corp. (NWSA)''s Fox Broadcasting. Fox appealed the
ruling. </p>
<p>The dispute over Dish''s ad-skipping technology, which
broadcasters warn threatens their very survival, is being played
out in federal courts on both coasts. Dish sued ABC, CBS Corp. (CBS)
and Comcast Corp. (CMCSA)''s NBC in New York in May seeking a judgment
that its AutoHop feature, which allows viewers to skip ads,
doesn''t violate network copyrights or contracts. Fox, CBS and
NBC sued Dish in Los Angeles for copyright infringement and
breach of contract on the same day. </p>
<p>Dish, based in Englewood, Colorado, introduced its new
digital video recorder, the Hopper, in March. Its PrimeTime
Anytime feature can record all the major networks'' primetime
shows and store them for eight days after their initial
broadcast. AutoHop, introduced in May, allows viewers, with the
touch of a button, to skip all the ads automatically, without
having to manually fast-forward through them. </p>




Photographer: Matthew Staver/Bloomberg News

<p>
Walt Disney Co.''s ABC television network is trying to shut down Dish Network Corp.''s ad-skipping
TV recording feature two weeks after a federal judge denied a similar bid by a different broadcaster. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bloomberg News" date="Nov 26, 2012  5:26 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-26/jpmorgan-says-ipos-smaller-part-of-china-investment-bank-revenue.html"><headline>JPMorgan Says IPOs Smaller Part of China Revenue in 2012</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) said initial
share sales may account for less than half its China investment
banking revenue in 2012 as more companies opt to raise funds
from the bond market to take advantage of lower interest rates. </p>
<p>Initial share sales had been more than half of investment
banking revenue in recent years, Fang Fang, chief executive
officer of China investment banking for JPMorgan, told reporters
in Beijing yesterday. This is the year that we did not have
many elephant IPOs.  By contrast, greater numbers of companies
are selling debt, he said. </p>
<p>Chinese companies have sold fewer shares and more bonds as
policy makers cut rates to bolster economic growth. Yields on
dollar-denominated debt sold by Chinese companies fell to a
record low of 5 percent on Nov. 7, according to JPMorgan Chase
indexes. Chinese companies have raised $15.2 billion from
overseas equity sales so far this year, 38 percent less than a
year ago, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>JPMorgan helped Haitong Securities Co. (600837), a Chinese brokerage
already listed in Shanghai, raise HK$13 billion in a Hong Kong
stock sale in April, near the bottom of a range marketed to
investors. The New York-based bank this month also helped Baidu
Inc. (BIDU), operator of China''s most popular search engine, sell $1.5
billion of bonds. </p>




Photographer: Nelson Ching/Bloomberg

<p>
The New York-based bank also helped Baidu Inc., operator of China''s most popular search engine, sell $1.5 billion of bonds. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Juan Pablo Spinetto" date="Nov 26, 2012  2:59 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-26/goldman-recommending-usiminas-on-rocca-cuts.html"><headline>Goldman Recommending Usiminas on Rocca Cuts</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Usinas Siderurgicas de Minas Gerais
SA is beating major steelmaker stocks on speculation cost cuts
will make it profitable after four quarters of losses. The rally
will continue, say Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and Deutsche Bank AG
analysts. </p>
<p>Usiminas, as the Belo Horizonte, Brazil-based company is
known, returned 40 percent in the past three months including
dividends, the most of any steel company with a market value of
$5 billion or more. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs''s Marcelo Aguiar, the most accurate
forecaster for Usiminas in a Bloomberg Absolute Return ranking,
this month joined a minority of analysts with a buy
recommendation on the stock. Aguiar and Deutsche Bank AG''s
Rodrigo Barros, the second-most accurate, expect cost-cutting
efforts since Italian billionaire Paolo Rocca''s family joined
the controlling group will result in a profit in 2013. </p>
<p>There''s a revolution going on at Usiminas, said Paolo Di Sora, a Sao Paulo-based fund manager at M. Safra  Co., which
increased its stake in Usiminas almost sevenfold in the third
quarter to 1.38 percent through its Everest Participacoes Ltda.
unit. It''s difficult to find another story like this in the
stock exchange today. </p>
<p>Surging returns for Usiminas, Brazil''s largest steelmaker
after Gerdau SA (GGBR4), compare with a 5 percent loss in the past three
months for Luxembourg-based ArcelorMittal, the world''s No. 1
producer. </p>
<p>Of 24 analysts covering Usiminas, five rate it a buy, six
have a neutral recommendation and nine say sell, according to
data compiled by Bloomberg. The remainder have it under review. </p>
<h2>Best Performer </h2>
<p>The best performer of 57 stocks in the MSCI Emerging
Markets Metals  Mining Index (MXEF0MM) since June 30, Usiminas fell 0.4
percent to 11.75 reais in Sao Paulo today, reducing a year-to-
date gain to 16 percent. Porto Alegre, Brazil-based Gerdau rose
27 percent this year and Sao Paulo-based Cia. Siderurgica
Nacional SA, the country''s third-biggest steelmaker, dropped 32
percent. ArcelorMittal fell 18 percent in Amsterdam. </p>
<p>Usiminas is trading at 38 times earnings estimates for the
next four quarters, more than triple the 11 ratio for the
benchmark Bovespa index, data compiled by Bloomberg show. </p>
<p>Ternium SA and Tenaris SA, both controlled by the Rocca
family''s Techint Group, last year agreed to pay about 5 billion
reais ($2.4 billion) for a 27.7 percent voting stake in
Usiminas, joining Tokyo-based Nippon Steel  Sumitomo Metal
Corp. (5401) in the controlling group. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs'' Aguiar estimates that Usiminas will post net
income of 592 million reais in 2013, the best in three years,
according to a Nov. 12 report. This year''s net loss will
probably amount to 440.5 million reais, he said, which would be
the biggest in at least two decades. </p>
<h2>Improvements </h2>
<p>Usiminas has boosted productivity, cut inventories and
signed accords to reduce costs and improve operations, Chief
Executive Officer Julian Eguren, who took office in January
after running the Rocca family''s Ternium unit in Mexico, said on
a Nov. 1 conference call. </p>
<p>The measures to improve efficiency, cut costs and improve
volumes will be a strong catalyst for Usiminas, Deutsche
Bank''s Barros said in an e-mailed response to questions.
Usiminas''s stock price already reflects the expected
improvements for the next 12 months, but not that such
improvements are a continuous process that may last for several
years. </p>
<p>Officials at Usiminas''s press office in Belo Horizonte
declined to comment further or make executives available. </p>
<h2>Stimulus </h2>
<p>President Dilma Rousseff''s measures to stoke growth in the
largest emerging economy after China helped Usiminas raise
prices as much as 7 percent in July. Rousseff boosted tariffs to
curb steel imports and cut taxes on carmakers, Usiminas''s main
buyers, after slashing Brazil''s benchmark interest rate by 5.25
percentage points since last August to 7.25 percent. </p>
<p>Projects for the 2014 soccer World Cup and 2016 Olympic
Games will help domestic demand rise as much as 6 percent next
year, compared with growth of about 1 percent to 2 percent this
year, Benjamin Baptista, ArcelorMittal''s Brazil head, said in an
Oct. 30 interview in Santiago. </p>
<p>A potential recovery is already incorporated in Usiminas''s
valuation and profit forecasts could be trimmed next year, HSBC
Holdings Plc equity analyst Jonathan Brandt said. </p>
<p>Most of the good news, if not all, is in the price, he
said in a Nov. 13 telephone interview from New York. All of a
sudden something happens and demand doesn''t materialize. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs'' Aguiar estimates that earnings before
interest, taxes, depreciation and amortization will triple in
2013 to 2.31 billion reais. The average of 15 analysts''
estimates compiled by Bloomberg is for 2013 adjusted net income
of 467.6 million reais on Ebitda of 1.96 billion reais. </p>
<p>Industrial efficiency continues being our main focus,
Usiminas''s Eguren said. The measures taken by the government
will help improve the situation in the short-term, but the most
effective changes will be those we do internally. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David Beasley and Christie Smythe" date="Nov 26, 2012  1:30 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-26/morgan-keegan-trial-judge-to-decide-sec-case-he-dismissed.html"><headline>Morgan Keegan Trial Judge to Decide SEC Case He Dismissed</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Keegan  Co. is going to
trial before a judge whose decision to throw out regulators''
claims the retail brokerage misled thousands of investors about
the risks of auction-rate securities was reversed on appeal. </p>
<p>Lawyers for the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission and
the Memphis, Tennessee-based financial firm delivered opening
statements today in federal court in Atlanta in a nonjury trial
scheduled to take two weeks. </p>
<p>The case, alleging that Morgan Keegan told clients that the
more than $2 billion in securities it sold had zero risk as
the market was collapsing in late 2007 and 2008, was dismissed
by U.S. District Judge William Duffey Jr. in June 2011. In May,
the U.S. Court of Appeals in Atlanta overruled Duffey, finding
he incorrectly concluded brokers'' verbal comments to four
customers were immaterial in light of disclosures posted on the
firm''s website. </p>
<p>Morgan Keegan brokers told customers auction-rate
securities were liquid, short-term investments, M. Graham
Loomis, a lawyer for the SEC, said during openings today. None
of the brokers told them their money could be tied up
indefinitely. </p>
<p>The first witness who testified today, Lakeland, Florida,
orange grower John Tillis, said he invested $400,000 in auction-
rate securities in December 2007 in order to park the funds
in a safe investment until his taxes were due in April. A Morgan
Keegan broker told him I would have no problem getting my
money back when I needed it for taxes, Tillis said. I did
not realize there was any risk. </p>
<h2>Couldn''t Sell'' </h2>
<p>When the farmer later tried to withdraw the funds, the
broker never could tell me anything except they couldn''t sell
them, Tillis testified. The company later refunded his
principal, he said. </p>
<p>The SEC, in a court filing, listed at least 10 other
witnesses it expects to call to the stand, including Calvin Sullivan,  Morgan Keegan''s chief strategy officer for fixed
income, and General Manager Thomas Galvin. Along with current
and former customers and brokers, the list also includes Kevin Giddis, fixed income head at St. Petersburg, Florida-based
Raymond James Financial Inc. (RJF) </p>
<h2>Defense Witnesses </h2>
<p>Morgan Keegan, which was acquired by Raymond James in
April, listed 71 potential witnesses in a court filing. They
include Giddis and Galvin as well as customers and brokers. </p>
<p>Morgan Keegan sold as much as $2.2 billion in auction-rate
securities that customers were unable to liquidate after the
market''s collapse in 2008, according to the SEC. The commission
sued Morgan Keegan for securities fraud in 2009, even after the
firm had begun buying back the investments. </p>
<p>Typically, auction-rate securities were municipal and
student-loan-backed bonds with interest rates that were
determined through periodic auctions, the SEC said. The company
frequently told customers the investments were the same as
cash or cash equivalents, the agency said in court papers. </p>
<p>The market for auction-rate securities began to
disintegrate in August 2007 after the companies insuring the
investments began suffering heavy losses in subprime mortgage-
related bonds, the SEC said. </p>
<h2>Failed Auctions </h2>
<p>In November 2007, Morgan Keegan learned of a small number
of failed auctions for the securities, in which some of the
investments were left unsold, according to the SEC suit. </p>
<p>By February 2008, auctions began to fail on a widespread
basis, the SEC said. </p>
<p>In March 2008, Morgan Keegan began requiring customers who
wished to buy auction-rate securities to sign statements
acknowledging it may be a considerable period of time before
liquidity returns to this investment, the SEC said. </p>
<p>Morgan Keegan said in court filings that auction-rate
securities were historically extremely safe and liquid. The
company denied the SEC allegations that it failed to tell
customers about the risks of investing in them. </p>
<p>Morgan Keegan''s failure to predict the future is not
securities fraud, a lawyer for Morgan Keegan, Amelia Rudolph,
said in openings today. This was a market that went up in
smoke overnight. Morgan Keegan did not misrepresent this product
to anyone. </p>
<h2>Not a Penny'' </h2>
<p>After the market collapsed and before the SEC filed its
lawsuit, Morgan Keegan voluntarily bought back $2 billion in
auction-rate securities from customers, it said in court
documents. </p>
<p>Participants in the repurchase program have not lost a
penny on their auction-rate investments, the company said. </p>
<p>In dismissing the case last year, Duffey said in his ruling
that failure to predict the market does not constitute
securities fraud. </p>
<p>The SEC seeks unspecified monetary penalties against Morgan
Keegan. Raymond James paid about $1.2 billion to buy the company
from Regions Financial Corp. (RF) </p>
<p>The suit is Securities and Exchange Commission v. Morgan
Keegan  Company Inc., 1:09-cv-01965, U.S. District Court,
Northern District of Georgia (Atlanta). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elisa Martinuzzi and Charles Penty" date="Nov 26, 2012  5:34 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-26/goldman-sachs-turns-down-southern-europe-banks-as-crisis-lingers.html"><headline>Goldman Turns Down Southern Europe Banks as Crisis Lingers</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), the No. 1 stock underwriter in Europe, turned down roles in offerings by banks in Spain and Italy this year, the only top U.S. securities firm not to take part in the fundraisings by southern European lenders as the region''s debt crisis stretches to a fourth year. </p> <p>The firm declined a role in Banco Popular Espanol SA (POP)''s 2.5 billion-euro ($3.2 billion) rights offering this month because it wanted greater protection to avoid potential losses on the sale, two people familiar with the talks said. JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) and Morgan Stanley are helping to guarantee the deal. Goldman also didn''t underwrite this year''s share sales by Italy''s UniCredit SpA and Portugal''s Banco Espirito Santo SA (BES), which drew Bank of America Corp. and Citigroup Inc. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs, which got 55 percent of its revenue this year from sales and trading, is passing on underwriting fees that could be at risk should the stock drop, as happened with insurer Fondiaria-SAI SpA (FSA) this year. Goldman Sachs President and Chief Operating Officer Gary D. Cohn said a month ago that he sees only a small probability that the euro area will stick together, while the firm''s equity strategists are warning investors to be wary of companies that rely on southern Europe. </p>




Photographer: Angel Navarrete/Bloomberg

<p>
Signage for Banco Popular Espanol SA hangs outside the bank''s headquarters in Madrid, Spain. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Nov 27, 2012  5:16 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-27/microsoft-says-it-has-sold-40-million-windows-8-licenses-1-.html"><headline>Microsoft Says It Has Sold 40 Million Windows 8 Licenses</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), the world''s largest
software maker, has sold 40 million licenses for Windows 8, an
updated version of its flagship operating system that can work
with touch-screen technology. </p>
<p>The newest Windows software has outpaced the previous
version in terms of upgrades, Microsoft said today on a blog
post and a speech by Windows Chief Financial Officer Tami Reller. The executive, who oversees the marketing and financial
part of the Windows unit, didn''t comment on sales of the Surface
tablet, Microsoft''s first-ever computer. </p>
<p>Microsoft hasn''t disclosed Windows 8 sales since Oct. 30,
when Chief Executive Officer Steve Ballmer said the company had
sold 4 million upgrades in the first four days. License sales
include upgrades, copies shipped on new computers and those
given to corporations with multiyear licenses. While it''s
difficult to gauge demand with the number by itself, the pace of
growth should please shareholders, said Bob O''Donnell, an
analyst at market research firm IDC. </p>
<p>It sounds pretty high, especially since Ballmer initially
said 4 million for first few days, O''Donnell said. Four
million to 40 million sounds pretty good. </p>
<p>Microsoft is overhauling its product line to remain
relevant in the post-PC era. The Redmond, Washington-based
company dominated the technology landscape during the heyday of
the personal computer in the 1990s and much of the last decade,
yet has been eclipsed in influence by a resurgent Apple Inc. (AAPL) and
the rise of mobile devices taking the place of PCs that run
Microsoft''s flagship Windows operating system. </p>
<p>Windows 8 represents Microsoft''s biggest change to its
flagship product in nearly two decades -- designed around a
revamped home screen featuring colorful tiles that launch
programs and update users with current information from the
Internet. On Oct. 26, the same day Windows 8 went on sale,
Microsoft started selling Surface, a tablet computer designed
and built by the company. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarika Gangar" date="Nov 27, 2012  4:39 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-27/walt-disney-said-to-plan-benchmark-bonds-in-four-part-sale-1-.html"><headline>Disney Raises $3 Billion in Three-Part Bond Offering</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS), the world''s largest
entertainment company, raised $3 billion in its first bond
offering in more than nine months. </p>
<p>The owner of the ABC and ESPN networks sold $500 million of
0.45 percent, three-year securities to yield 35 basis points
more than similar-maturity Treasuries, $1 billion of 1.1
percent, five-year notes at a relative yield of 60 basis points,
$1 billion of 2.35 percent, 10-year securities with a spread of
80 and $500 million of 3.7 percent, 30-year debt at 95,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>The company last sold bonds in February, issuing $1 billion
of 1.125 percent, five-year debentures and $400 million of 2.55
percent, 10-year notes, Bloomberg data show. The securities due
in February 2022 traded at 102.1 cents on the dollar to yield
2.3 percent yesterday, according to Trace, the bond-price
reporting system of the Financial Industry Regulatory Authority. </p>
<p>The new bonds are rated A by Standard  Poor''s and proceeds
will be used for general corporate purposes, which could include
debt repayment or to finance the company''s purchase of Lucasfilm
Ltd., the ratings company said today in a release. Citigroup
Inc. and JPMorgan Chase  Co. managed the sale for the Burbank,
California-based company, Bloomberg data show. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri" date="Nov 27, 2012  4:26 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-27/disney-s-mcstuffins-overtakes-dora-on-preschool-tv.html"><headline>Disney''s McStuffins'' Overtakes Dora'' on Preschool TV</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS)''s Doc McStuffins has emerged as the top-rated cable TV show for preschoolers, taking viewers from Viacom Inc. (VIA)''s children''s networks and its long-running hit Dora the Explorer. </p> <p>Doc McStuffins, introduced in March, is averaging 774,000 viewers ages 2 to 5 at 10 a.m. weekdays on the Disney Channel, according to Nielsen data. The program drew 1.7 million viewers of all ages, including those who recorded and watched within a week. Dora averaged 667,000 on Viacom''s Nickelodeon in that age group and 1.4 million in total. </p> <p>Disney, the world''s largest entertainment company, introduced Doc McStuffins this year along with Disney Junior, a new cable network aimed at 2-to-7-year-olds. The company is taking on Viacom''s flagship Nickelodeon kids'' channel and its Nick Jr., which is aimed at preschoolers. Viacom, based in New York, has long been the leader in that demographic with shows such as Dora and Blues Clues. </p> <p>Disney has executed well and is gaining share overall against Viacom in the preschool and up to 10-year-old kids market, said Martin Pyykkonen, an analyst at Wedge Partners in Greenwood Village, Colorado, who follows both companies. </p> <p>Disney''s gains translated into toy sales at the outset of the holiday shopping season. Doc McStuffins items were in short supply last weekend, according to Gerrick Johnson, an analyst at BMO Capital Markets in New York. Johnson said his team visited Toys R Us Inc. (TOYS), Target Corp. (TGT) and other stores in New York and North Carolina. </p> <p>You won''t find Doc McStuffins in any store you check, Johnson said in an e-mail. </p> <h2>Toy Doctor </h2> <p>The cartoon character, a 6-year-old who cares for sick toys, runs on both Disney Channel and Disney Junior. Ratings for Disney Junior aren''t yet available, according to the Burbank, California-based company. </p> <p>Ratings for Dora and Nickelodeon''s other shows for younger viewers are improving, said Dan Martinsen, a spokesman for Viacom''s Nickelodeon networks. The network''s preschool programming has registered higher ratings than Disney this quarter, as it did in the first half, he said. The company offered fewer preschool shows over the summer when older kids were out of school, according to Martinsen. </p> <p>This quarter, Doc McStuffins is averaging 669,000 2- to-5 year-old viewers on the Disney Channel, according to Nielsen. Dora averaged 659,000 in the same time period on Nickelodeon. </p> <p>Children''s TV is lucrative for entertainment companies because it helps sell toys and other merchandise they license, and generates cable subscriber fees. </p> <h2>Merchandise Profit </h2> <p>The Disney Channel accounts for about 25 percent of the parent company''s income from cable networks, its largest business, Pyykkonen said. In the fiscal year ended Sept. 29, Disney''s cable networks reported operating income of $5.7 billion, a 9 percent increase from a year earlier. </p> <p>Sales at Disney''s consumer products division rose 6.7 percent to $3.25 billion for the fiscal year. Ancillary revenue from Viacom''s cable networks fell 13 percent to $549 million over the same period. </p> <p>If it''s a battle of consumer products, Disney wins, said Todd Juenger, an analyst who follows both companies at Sanford C. Bernstein  Co. in New York. They have an almost insurmountable, supply, distribution, shelf-space advantage. </p> <p>Hot-selling Doc McStuffins products include the $34.99 Time for Your Check Up doll and the $14.99 Doctor''s Bag Play Set, according Nidia Tatalovich, a spokeswoman for the company. New merchandise planned for next year includes bedding, apparel and party supplies, she said. </p> <p>Dora has produced more than $11 billion in revenue at retail since her 2000 debut, Martinsen said. </p> <p>Disney fell 0.9 percent to $48.60 at the close in New York. The shares have gained 30 percent this year. Viacom rose 0.5 percent to $50.38 and has gained 11 percent in 2012. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christie Smythe" date="Nov 27, 2012  3:53 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-27/visa-mastercard-settlement-order-appealed-by-plaintiffs.html"><headline>Visa, MasterCard Settlement Order Appealed by Plaintiffs</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The tentative approval of Visa Inc. (V)
and MasterCard Inc. (MA)''s proposed $7.25 billion settlement of a
merchant fee price-fixing case will be challenged in a federal
appeals court, according to a notice filed by objecting
plaintiffs in Brooklyn, New York. </p>
<p>Four retailers and six trade groups today filed the notice
that they are appealing a component of U.S. District Judge John Gleeson''s approval order barring merchants from suing the
payment firms over the fees. </p>
<p>About 1,200 retailers and trade organizations opposed the
accord, which would end seven years of litigation over
interchange, or swipe, fees that retailers are charged when
customers pay with credit cards. Lawyers for the objectors
argued at a Nov. 10 hearing that the agreement is unfair because
it strips merchants of the right to sue over the fees in the
future. </p>
<p>This settlement has fatal legal defects and should not
get preliminary approval, Jeffrey Shinder, a lawyer for
objectors, said today in a statement. We look forward to
presenting the problems we see in this proposal to the Second
Circuit Court of Appeals. </p>
<p>Covering more than 7 million merchants, the accord would be
the largest-ever antitrust settlement, according to lawyers for
plaintiffs. Gleeson granted preliminary approval Nov. 10, saying
some issues still require significant scrutiny. The
settlement is subject to final approval later. </p>
<h2>No Concern </h2>
<p>This obscure appeal is just a badly underthrown legal
Hail Mary that shouldn''t give anyone any concern, Trish Wexler, a spokeswoman for the Electronic Payments Coalition, a
credit-and-debit-card industry trade group advising defendants
in the case, said today in a statement. </p>
<p>The retailer objectors are focusing on an extremely
limited and technical issue, she said. The move does nothing
to slow or change the settlement process, she said. </p>
<p>The case is In re Payment Card Interchange Fee and Merchant
Discount Antitrust Litigation, 05-md-01720, U.S. District Court,
Eastern District of New York (Brooklyn). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hans Nichols" date="Nov 27, 2012  3:33 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-27/goldman-ceo-blankfein-said-to-meet-with-obama-tomorrow.html"><headline>Goldman CEO Blankfein Said to Meet With Obama Tomorrow</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) Chief Executive Officer Lloyd Blankfein is among the business leaders invited to the White House tomorrow as President Barack Obama seeks their support for his approach to addressing the fiscal cliff, according to two people familiar with the matter. </p> <p>Obama''s meeting with the executives, his second such session this month, is part of an administration campaign to pressure Congress to extend tax cuts for middle-income Americans while letting them rise for top earners, according to the people, who requested anonymity because the list of those at the meeting hasn''t been officially released. </p> <p>U.S. House Speaker John Boehner of Ohio and other House Republican leaders are also scheduled to meet with Blankfein tomorrow and other CEOs pressing for an agreement to avoid the $607 billion in automatic tax increases and spending cuts scheduled to take effect in January, according to a House aide. </p> <p>With the Christmas holiday approaching, the Obama administration is mounting a campaign-style push for public support as the newly re-elected president faces off against congressional Republicans over proposals to avert the so-called fiscal cliff. He met with owners of small businesses today and is planning to visit a toy factory in Pennsylvania this week to help build public support for his plan. </p> <h2>Tax Rates </h2> <p>Obama is urging Congress to act immediately on his plan to keep existing tax rates for middle-income Americans while letting those for the top earners rise, even as talks continue on spending cuts and changes to entitlement programs such as Medicare. Many Republicans say they are willing to consider higher revenue as along as it''s accompanied by cuts in entitlement programs. </p> <p>The president is arguing that, without a deal, consumer confidence may suffer, hurting holiday shopping and the economic recovery. </p> <p>It is something that everyone in Washington agrees must be done and it is something that the House of Representatives could do today or tomorrow if they so chose, because the Senate has already passed a bill that extends those tax cuts White House press secretary Jay Carney said today. </p> <p>Negotiations have made such little headway that Obama is delaying inviting congressional leaders back to the White House this week as he had originally planned, according to a Democratic congressional aide. </p> <h2>Negotiations </h2> <p>Senate Majority Leader Harry Reid, a Nevada Democrat, told reporters today he''s disappointed by the lack of progress in the talks since he and other congressional leaders met with Obama at the White House on Nov. 16. </p> <p>There''s been little progress with Republicans, Reid said. Lawmakers need to get away from the happy talk and start discussing specifics, he said. </p> <p>Still, Reid said he was extremely hopeful and didn''t think Republicans will hold out and allow the tax increases and spending cuts to be triggered. </p> <p>U.S. stocks extended losses as Reid spoke. The Standard  Poor''s 500 Index (SPX) slipped 0.3 percent to 1,402.03 as of 3:17 p.m. in New York. The Dow Jones Industrial Average fell 0.5 percent to 12,908.08. </p> <p>Among the executives who will be meeting with members of Congress tomorrow are Thomas Wilson, the president and CEO of Allstate Corp. (ALL), Doug Oberhelman, the CEO of Caterpillar Inc., David Cote, the chairman and CEO of Honeywell International (HON) Inc. and Mark Bertolini, the chairman and CEO of Aetna Inc. (AET), according to the congressional aide. </p> <h2>Obama Meetings </h2> <p>Before tomorrow''s meeting with Blankfein and the other executives, Obama will have an event with middle-income Americans who would be affected if the tax rates rise. </p> <p>Blankfein was at the White House in July to meet with Jack Lew, Obama''s chief of staff. He also is on the CEO fiscal leadership council of the Campaign to Fix the Debt, which was founded by the co-chairman of Obama''s fiscal commission. </p> <p>The group is backing the framework laid out by 2010 fiscal commission leaders Erskine Bowles and Alan Simpson for reducing the nation''s deficit, which has exceeded $1 trillion throughout Obama''s first term. Bowles, a Democrat and former White House chief of staff for President Bill Clinton, and Simpson, a Republican and former senator from Wyoming, proposed tax increases and spending cuts. </p> <h2>CEO Council </h2> <p>The CEO councils'' principles call for Congress to overhaul Medicare and Medicaid, strengthen Social Security and enact comprehensive and pro-growth tax reform that lowers rates, broadens the tax base, raises revenue and cuts the deficit. </p> <p>Blankfein has urged policymakers to reach a compromise to avoid the fiscal cliff, including cutbacks to programs like Social Security and more revenue from the wealthiest Americans. </p> <p>Social Security wasn''t devised to be a system that supported you for a 30-year retirement after a 25-year career, he said in an interview with CBS news on Nov. 19.  The retirement age has to be changed. </p> <p>In the long run, there has to be more revenue, he said. The burden of that revenue will be disproportionately taken up by wealthier people. That''s just logical. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Nov 27, 2012  2:44 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-27/microsoft-says-it-sold-more-than-750-000-xbox-consoles-last-week.html"><headline>Microsoft Says It Sold More Than 750,000 Xbox Consoles Last Week</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) said it sold more
than 750,000 Xbox consoles in the U.S. during the week of Black
Friday, exceeding the company''s internal projections. </p>
<p>Xbox Live Gold Subscription card sales increased more than
50 percent compared with the same week of 2011, the company said
in an e-mailed statement. The sales figure includes purchases
made from Nov. 18 to Nov. 23. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David McLaughlin" date="Nov 27, 2012 12:34 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-27/jpmorgan-sued-for-fraud-by-cifg-assurance-over-cdos.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sued for Fraud by CIFG Assurance Over CDOs</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) was sued by
CIFG Assurance North America Inc., which says it lost more than
$100 million on collateralized debt obligations created by Bear
Stearns, the investment bank JPMorgan acquired in 2008. </p>
<p>Bear Stearns stocked the CDOs with toxic mortgage
securities and profited by betting against the portfolios, the
insurer said in a complaint filed yesterday in New York State
Supreme Court. Bear Stearns told CIFG that independent firms had
selected the collateral, New York-based CIFG said. </p>
<p>As a result of its fraud, Bear Stearns was able to pass
off huge losses onto CIFG, according to the complaint. </p>
<p>CIFG said it was induced to provide financial-guaranty
insurance on credit default swaps guaranteeing payment on notes
issued by ACA ABS CDO 2006-2 Ltd. and Libertas Preferred Funding
II Ltd., according to the complaint. CIFG last week sued Bank of
America Corp. for fraud over guaranty policies tied to mortgage
securities. </p>
<p>Jennifer Zuccarelli, a spokeswoman for New York-based
JPMorgan, didn''t immediately respond to an e-mail seeking
comment on CIFG''s complaint. </p>
<p>The case is CIFG Assurance North America Inc. v. J.P.
Morgan Securities LLC, 654074-2012, New York State Supreme Court
(Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Irina Savu" date="Nov 27, 2012 10:29 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-27/exxon-seeks-to-award-black-sea-drilling-contract-in-romania.html"><headline>Exxon Seeks to Award Black Sea Drilling Contract in Romania</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM)''s Romanian unit
called for bids from companies interested in providing offshore
drilling services in the Black Sea under a contract estimated to
be worth $250 million to $750 million. </p>
<p>The contract is for the duration of 48 months and includes
drilling one to seven wells in the Black Sea, where Exxon is
looking for natural gas together with Romania''s biggest oil
company OMV Petrom SA (SNP), according to a European Union procurement
document published today. </p>
<p>Bidders can submit offers until Jan. 7, 2013 for the
contract, which will be financed by Exxon from its own funds,
according to the document submitted by ExxonMobil Exploration
and Production Romania Limited Nassau. </p>
<p>Austria''s OMV AG (OMV), the majority-owner of Petrom, said on
Feb. 22 that it discovered what may be its biggest gas find in
the Black Sea well it is exploring together with a unit of
Exxon. </p>
<p>The Domino-1 well, which is operated by the Exxon unit,
encountered 70.7 meters of net gas pay, resulting in a
preliminary estimate for the accumulation ranging from 1.5 to 3
trillion cubic feet (42 to 84 billion cubic meters), OMV said.
Drilling operations started at the end of 2011 and the total
depth of the well is estimated to be more than 3,000 meters
below sea level. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Nov 28, 2012 12:42 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-28/microsoft-sees-surge-in-windows-phones-on-faster-software.html"><headline>Microsoft Sees Surge in Windows Phones on Faster Software</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) is selling four
times as many Windows phones as this time last year, helped by a
new version of its phone software for more powerful handsets
with faster screens, Chief Executive Officer Steve Ballmer said. </p>
<p>Windows Phone 8 has been on sale for a few weeks and is
off to a great start, Ballmer said at a shareholders'' meeting
today. Handsets made by HTC Corp. (2498) and Nokia Oyj (NOK1V) are getting
rave reviews and have initially sold out in many countries. </p>
<p>Microsoft is overhauling its product line to remain
relevant in the post-PC era. The Redmond, Washington-based
company dominated the technology landscape during the heyday of
the personal computer in the 1990s and much of the last decade,
yet has been eclipsed in influence by a resurgent Apple Inc. and
the rise of mobile devices taking the place of PCs that run
Microsoft''s flagship Windows operating system. </p>
<p>Windows 8 represents Microsoft''s biggest change to its
flagship product in nearly two decades -- designed around a
revamped home screen featuring colorful tiles that launch
programs and update users with current information from the
Internet. On Oct. 26, the same day Windows 8 went on sale,
Microsoft started selling Surface, a tablet computer designed
and built by the company. </p>
<p>Ballmer said Microsoft is seeing fantastic demand for
tablets and touch-screen PCs featuring Windows 8. There are now
1,500 different machines running the software, up from 1,000
when the operating system debuted, he said. </p>
<p>There are now 120,000 applications available for the
Windows phone, Ballmer said. He didn''t specify how many phones
running the new software have been sold. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chris V. Nicholson" date="Nov 28, 2012 12:21 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-28/goldman-s-altuzarra-said-to-return-to-london-from-paris-1-.html"><headline>Goldman''s Altuzarra Said to Return to London From Paris</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Philippe Altuzarra is returning to
London after running Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)''s Paris office for
three years to serve as advisory director, a person with
knowledge of the move said. </p>
<p>Altuzarra will be succeeded in Paris by Pierre Hudry and
Christian De Haaij, investment banking co-heads of France,
Belgium and Luxembourg for Goldman, the person said, asking not
to be identified as an announcement has not been made public. </p>
<p>As advisory director, Altuzarra will give strategic
guidance to international advisers in Europe and help cover
clients in the region. </p>
<p>The 62-year-old banker joined Goldman in 1993 from Havas,
after earlier posts at France''s finance ministry and its Japan
embassy. He is a graduate of the Ecole nationale
d''administration, which produces many of France''s senior
officials and executives. </p>
<p>Altuzarra, who is a partner at the bank, was first tapped
to co-run Goldman''s Paris office in 2000, a role he held until
2006, when he was succeeded by Jean Raby and appointed to the
international advisory group in London. He returned to Paris in
2009 to co-run the office there with Laurent Lellouche, who
remains head of Goldman''s operations in France. </p>
<p>A spokeswoman for Goldman declined to comment on
Altuzarra''s move, which was reported earlier by WanSquare, a
French news service. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Nov 29, 2012  1:42 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-29/microsoft-surface-with-windows-pro-to-go-on-sale-in-january-1-.html"><headline>Microsoft Surface With Windows Pro to Go on Sale in January</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) said its Surface
tablet computer running the new Windows 8 Pro software will go
on sale in January, the first versions of the machine that run
on Intel (INTC) Corp. chips. </p>
<p>Surface tablets with Windows 8 Pro will cost $899 for a
version with 64 gigabytes of memory, and $999 for a 128-gigabyte
model. They run on Intel''s Core i5 processor, giving the
machines a graphics boost, Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft
said today in a blog post. </p>
<p>Microsoft hasn''t disclosed how many units it has sold of
the Surface that runs on a chip with ARM Holdings Plc (ARM)
technology, which went on sale last month for $499 to $699. The
price for the Intel-based iteration, which doesn''t include the
tablet cover with a built-in keyboard that is one of Surface''s
key features, may be too high for many users. </p>
<p>At that price, by the time you add the keyboard you''re at
the price of an 11-inch MacBook, said Wes Miller, an analyst
at Kirkland, Washington-based Directions on Microsoft, referring
to Apple Inc.''s laptop computer. Everyone always says, well,
Apple is so expensive,'' but here we are in that same
neighborhood looking at houses. </p>
<p>Still, Miller said the price for the Surface with Windows 8
Pro is more reasonable if a user is planning to have the machine
double as a tablet and a full personal computer. For example,
customers could put the machine in a dock and use it alongside a
larger screen to replace desktop computers, he said. </p>
<p>But if you''re looking at it as just a tablet, it is
pricey, he said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chris Dolmetsch" date="Nov 29, 2012  1:34 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-29/morgan-stanley-sued-by-dutch-pension-fund-over-securities-1-.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Sued by Dutch Pension Fund Over Securities</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley was sued in New York
by Stichting Pensioenfonds ABP, the Netherlands'' biggest pension
fund, which claimed fraud over residential mortgage-backed
securities. </p>
<p>Stichting, based in Heerlen, Netherlands, sued yesterday in
New York State Supreme Court in Manhattan, saying it relied on
false and misleading statements made by Morgan Stanley when
it bought the securities. The pension fund said it suffered
unspecified substantial damages. </p>
<p>Based on these material misrepresentations and omissions,
ABP purchased securities that were far riskier than had been
represented, backed by mortgage loans worth significantly less
than had been represented, and that had been made to borrowers
who were much less creditworthy than had been represented, and
at prices far in excess of the true value of the certificates,
Stichting said in its 125-page complaint. </p>
<p>Mark Lake, a Morgan Stanley (MS) spokesman, declined to comment
on the lawsuit. </p>
<p>The pension fund has sued other banks in the same court
over similar allegations, including Deutsche Bank AG, Credit
Suisse Group AG, JPMorgan Chase  Co. and Goldman Sachs Group
Inc. </p>
<p>Pools of home loans securitized into bonds were a central
part of the housing bubble that helped send the U.S. into the
biggest recession since the 1930s. The housing market collapsed,
and the crisis swept up lenders and investment banks as the
market for the securities evaporated. </p>
<p>The Netherlands has the euro area''s biggest pension
industry, with 950 billion euros ($1.25 trillion) in assets at
the end of the second quarter, data from the Dutch and European
central banks show. </p>
<p>The assets are held in collective plans run by industry,
company and occupational pension funds. APG Groep manages
314 billion euros for pension funds including Stichting
Pensioenfonds ABP, which said in today''s complaint that it has
about 250 billion euros in assets under management. </p>
<p>The case is Stichting Pensioenfonds ABP v. Morgan Stanley,
654130/2012, New York State Supreme Court, New York County
(Manhattan.) </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Carroll, Rebecca Penty and Katia Dmitrieva" date="Nov 29, 2012  1:26 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-29/chevron-s-19-billion-disaster-gets-hearing-corporate-canada.html"><headline>Chevron''s $19 Billion Disaster'' Gets Hearing</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A judge hearing Chevron Corp.''s (CVX)
first test of whether Amazon rainforest-dwellers will collect
$19 billion in environmental damages from the world''s fourth-
largest oil company said the case should be tried in the U.S. </p>
<p>You should all be in New York, Ontario Superior Court
Justice David Brown said several times during the first day of
hearings today in Toronto. On the issue of jurisdiction, the
law is not clear on this at all. Why should the Ontario court
stick their nose into the matter. </p>
<p>A group of 47 Ecuadoreans have asked the Ontario court to
seize Chevron assets in Canada, ranging from an oil sands
project to offshore wells, to satisfy a 2011 court ruling in the
Latin American nation that ordered the company to pay for oil
pollution dating to the 1960s. </p>
<p>Today''s hearing in Toronto marks the Ecuadoreans'' inaugural
step in a global collection effort that includes seizure
attempts in Argentina and Brazil. The Ecuadoreans estimated
Chevron has $12 billion in Canadian assets, a figure that
equates to almost half of the company''s 2011 profit. An adverse
Ontario ruling for Chevron would put at risk fuel-manufacturing
and oil-production operations across Canada. </p>
<h2>Long Time'' </h2>
<p>It''s a cause for concern and it probably means this isn''t
going to go away, Robert Sweet, who helps manage $150 million
at Horizon Investment Services in Hammond, Indiana, said in a
telephone interview. As with all ecological disasters, this is
going to take a long, long time to resolve. </p>
<p>The company''s presence in Canada dates back to the 1930s
and includes an oil-refining complex in British Columbia, an
Alberta oil-sands venture, offshore wells in the Atlantic Ocean,
and cash held in Canadian bank accounts. </p>
<p>San Ramon, California-based Chevron was on the losing side
of last year''s ruling by a provincial Ecuadorean court that
blamed decades of toxic soil and water contamination on Texaco
Inc., which Chevron acquired in 2001. Texaco was found to have
discharged into the environment saltwater and other byproducts
of oil drilling. Texaco quit the country and its equipment was
taken over by the Ecuadorean state oil company in 1992. </p>
<p>The $19 billion ruling handed down last year by a court in
Lago Agrio, a town near Ecuador''s border with Colombia, held
Chevron accountable for health and environmental damages
resulting from chemical-laden wastewater dumped from 1964 to
1992. </p>
<h2>Corporate Veil </h2>
<p>The Ecuadorean plaintiffs, from the remote northern Amazon
River basin, are seeking enforcement of the judgment outside
their home country because Chevron has no refineries, oil wells,
storage terminals or other properties in the nation. Pablo
Fajardo, their lead lawyer in Ecuador, said during a February
2011 conference call with reporters he would use every
strategy and manner at our disposal to collect the award. </p>
<p>During today''s hearing, Brown leaned in favor of Chevron''s
argument that the Ontario court has no jurisdiction to grant the
Ecuadorean judgment because the company''s Canadian units are
indirect subsidiaries with independent boards separated from the
U.S. parent by several levels of ownership. </p>
<p>Attorneys for the Ecuadoreans are scheduled to present
their arguments to Brown tomorrow. </p>
<p>The Ecuadoreans face an uphill battle because they must
convince the court that Chevron and its Canadian operations
should be treated as one entity rather than separate companies,
Barry Leon, a partner and head of the international arbitration
group at Perley-Robertson, Hill  McDougall LLP in Ottawa, said
during an interview before the hearing. </p>
<p>The expression that gets used legally is lifting the
corporate veil'' and disregarding the separate personalities,
Leon said. The courts generally, in Canada and elsewhere, have
been reluctant to do that. </p>
<h2>Pending Arbitration </h2>
<p>Chevron rose 16 cents to $105.74 at 1:08 p.m. in New York
today. The shares have increased 8.6 percent in the past year. </p>
<p>Chevron has refused to pay the $19 billion judgment or
entertain the notion of settlement talks because it maintains
the ruling resulted from bribery and fraud. </p>
<p>The Ecuadoreans'' lawyers have blackmailed judges, bribed
judges, falsified evidence, falsified expert witnesses,
ghostwritten expert opinions and ghostwritten court judgments,
Chevron Chairman and Chief Executive Officer John Watson said in
comments at the Council on Foreign Relations in New York today.
If the plaintiffs were confident in the integrity of the
ruling, they would seek enforcement in U.S. courts with
jurisdiction over the parent company, Kent Robertson, a company
spokesman, said in an e-mailed statement. </p>
<h2>Hard-Fought </h2>
<p>Now that the Ecuador courts have ruled against the
company, it is manufacturing fraud charges in a desperate effort
to escape justice, Karen Hinton, a spokeswoman for the
Ecuadorean plaintiffs, said in an e-mailed statement today.
Chevron is engaging in legal theater, Hinton wrote. </p>
<p>Alan Lenczner, the Toronto attorney from the firm Lenczner
Slaght Royce Smith Griffin LP representing the Ecuadoreans,
declined to comment on the case when reached by phone before the
hearings began. </p>
<p>Whatever the outcome, it''s likely that the initial
decisions will be appealed, Leon said. It''s been extremely
hard-fought by both sides having many lawyers and having spent
what''s been a phenomenal amount of money because there''s so much
at stake. </p>
<p>Chevron doesn''t disclose how much it spends on legal fees,
Robertson said in a telephone interview. </p>
<p>Chevron is awaiting a ruling in a related case before the
Permanent Court of Arbitration, the 113-year-old panel based in
The Hague that handles trade disputes between corporations and
nations. Chevron filed the arbitration claim in 2009, accusing
the government of Ecuador of reneging on a 1998 contract that
absolved Texaco of Amazonian pollution claims. Three days of
hearings in the case concluded yesterday, Robertson said. </p>
<h2>Unfair Influence </h2>
<p>Chevron''s campaign to avoid payment suffered a setback last
month when the U.S. Supreme Court upheld a lower-court decision
that rejected the company''s request for a pre-emptive block on
collection efforts in Chevron''s home country. The lower court
had ruled that it didn''t have authority to thwart payment when
the Ecuadoreans hadn''t yet filed such a claim in the U.S. </p>
<p>Following the filing of their Canadian seizure request in
May, the Ecuadoreans sought similar forfeitures in a Brazilian
tribunal in June and in Argentina earlier this month. A judge in
Buenos Aires ordered some Chevron bank deposits held in escrow
while the case is pending, Enrique Bruchou, a lawyer for the
Ecuadoreans, said in an interview on Nov. 7. </p>
<p>Today, in paid statements published in two Argentine
newspapers, Chevron urged the local court to release its money
from escrow and indicated the company intends to pursue a legal
defense identical to that employed in Canada. Chevron
Argentina has never had operations in Ecuador and has no
relation with the fraudulent trial in Ecuador, the company
said in the newspapers Clarin and La Nacion. </p>
<p>I''m more concerned now than I was a couple of months ago
now that the Ecuadoreans have found other governments that
appear to be at least moderately friendly to their case, Sweet
said. </p>
<h2>Transparency International </h2>
<p>Chevron has accused the Ecuadorean government of unfairly
influencing court proceedings that led to the $19 billion ruling
and alleged that a damage assessment provided by a court-
appointed expert was ghostwritten by consultants and lawyers
hired by the plaintiffs. </p>
<p>Lawyers for the Ecuadoreans including Stephen Donzinger
have accused Chevron of engaging in a campaign to discredit
them, entrap an Ecuadorean judge that presided over the case and
set up dummy corporations in Ecuador to hide Chevron''s alleged
role in testing soil samples from the pollution sites. </p>
<p>Ecuador ranked 120th out of 183 nations in Transparency
International''s 2011 corruption-perception index, where No. 1
New Zealand is perceived to be the most honest. Albania, Liberia
and Lesotho were perceived as less corrupt than Ecuador,
according to the index. </p>
<p>In February 2011, Chevron filed a racketeering lawsuit
that''s ongoing against the Ecuadoreans and their lawyers in New
York for leading a fraudulent litigation and PR campaign
against the company. </p>
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) is the world''s biggest oil company by
market value, followed by PetroChina Company Ltd. and Royal
Dutch Shell Plc (RDSA), according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chris Dolmetsch" date="Nov 29, 2012 12:26 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-29/jpmorgan-suit-dismissal-upheld-by-new-york-appeals-court.html"><headline>JPMorgan Suit Dismissal Upheld by New York Appeals Court</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the biggest
U.S. bank by assets, won a New York appeals court ruling
upholding the dismissal of a lawsuit by the defunct commodities
fund Amaranth Advisors LLC. </p>
<p>Amaranth collapsed in 2006 after losing $6.6 billion on
natural gas trades. The fund sued New York-based JPMorgan in
2007 in state court in Manhattan, alleging bank executives
helped cause its demise by sabotaging a bailout by Citadel
Investment Group LLC. </p>
<p>Justice O. Peter Sherwood of New York''s trial-level Supreme
court threw out the suit in August 2011, saying Amaranth
officials can''t prove the executives'' statements were the reason
Citadel officials decided to cancel the bailout. </p>
<p>An appeals panel in Manhattan upheld the dismissal today,
saying Amaranth''s case relies on a statement indicating that
JPMorgan had concerns about the impact of any potential bridge
loan to the fund, instead of the defamatory statement alleged in
its complaint. </p>
<p>The statement Amaranth now relies on is not defamatory,
as it simply expresses an opinion based on information available
to all potential parties to the potential fund transaction,
the appeals court said in its ruling. Furthermore, the
statement is substantially true. </p>
<p>The appeals court said it found uncontroverted evidence
that JPMorgan did consider, if only briefly, making a bridge
loan to the fund and concluded that it was less than
creditworthy'' and a potential preference risk.'' </p>
<p>The case is Amaranth LLC v. JPMorgan Chase  Co.,
603756/2007, New York state Supreme Court, New York County
(Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Eliana Raszewski" date="Nov 29, 2012  7:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-29/chevron-argentina-says-victim-of-fraud-seeks-lifting-of-embargo.html"><headline>Chevron Argentina Says Victim of Fraud, Seeks Lifting of Embargo</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The Argentine unit of Chevron Corp. (CVX)
asked local courts to revoke an embargo of its assets in the
country related to a $19 billion award over pollution in
Ecuador, saying the ruling affects local operations. </p>
<p>Chevron Argentina is victim of a fraud, the company
said in a paid statement published in newspapers Clarin and La
Nacion today. Chevron Argentina has never had operations in
Ecuador and has no relation with the fraudulent trial in
Ecuador. </p>
<p>Judge Adrian Elcuj Miranda ordered 40 percent of Chevron''s
Argentine bank accounts to be held in escrow, Enrique Bruchou,
an Argentine attorney representing Ecuadorean plaintiffs, said
on Nov. 7. </p>
<p>The plaintiffs are seeking to enforce a $19 billion award
against Chevron, which they say is responsible for destroying
the environment in the Lago Agrio region, damaging living
conditions of 30,000 inhabitants. Chevron, which on Sept. 14
signed a memorandum of understanding to help develop Argentina''s
Vaca Muerta shale formation, says the Ecuador judgment is
illegitimate and the embargo is improper. </p>
<p>The embargo endangers Chevron Argentina''s capacity to
operate and reinvest as the order affects more than 90 percent
of the income from crude sales, according to today''s
statement. Those funds are used to pay salaries, royalties,
taxes and capital investments, Chevron said. </p>
<p>The company, which employs 1,500 people in Argentina, said
the funds should be applied to invest in Argentina to recover
the country''s capacity to supply itself with energy. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Heather Perlberg and Jody Shenn" date="Nov 30, 2012  5:28 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-30/goldman-pushes-subprime-abx-index-as-housing-rebounds-mortgages.html"><headline>Goldman Pushes Subprime ABX Index as Housing Rebounds: Mortgages</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs (GS) Group Inc., which
survived the U.S. real estate collapse five years ago with the
help of derivative bets against subprime mortgages, is promoting
the opposite trade to clients as housing recovers. </p>
<p>The firm, which teamed with four other dealers to create
the ABX indexes, benchmark contracts that offered investors a
way to protect against the risks of a crash, said in a Nov. 28
report on its top 10 market themes for 2013 that clients should
buy some of the derivatives. </p>
<p>Home prices are recovering from a six-year slump, helped by
Federal Reserve efforts to push mortgage rates to record lows
and buyers competing for a shrinking supply of properties. The
bank''s analysts said after the positive surprise from
housing this year, versions of the ABX that have already rallied
are still attractive compared with real estate investments such
as homebuilder shares, which have almost doubled over the past
12 months. </p>
<p>You''re going to get a further lift because of the steady
improvement in the indexes'' underlying assets and the housing
market, said Adrian Miller, a fixed-income strategist at GMP
Securities LLC in New York. Yes, there''s room to go, but how
much juice is left in the trade is another question. </p>
<p>Michael DuVally, a Goldman Sachs spokesman in New York,
declined to comment on the recommendation beyond the report. </p>
<p>New ABX indexes were created every six months by securities
firms from early 2006 through early 2008. The contracts offer
protection if the securities aren''t repaid as expected, in
return for upfront and regular insurance-like premiums. </p>
<h2>More Bullish </h2>
<p>The credit-default swaps enabled speculators to bet against
housing, and helped meet demand from investors for the high
yields of loans to homeowners with poor credit. As the credit
crisis grew, investors followed the price of the contracts as a
gauge of losses at banks and hedge funds. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs has taken a more bullish view on housing
since at least March, when it was raising money for a new fund
to buy home-loan bonds to benefit from an improving real-estate
market. </p>
<p>Investments such as homebuilders have already priced in the
recovery, the bank said in the report. PulteGroup Inc. (PHM) leads the
11-member homebuilding index with a gain of 166 percent this
year followed by M/I Homes Inc. (MHO), which rose 129 percent, and KB
Home (KBH) with a 114 percent increase. The index, which had gained 83
percent for the first 10 months of the year, fell 0.8 percent
today in New York, extending the decline in November to 3.1
percent. </p>
<h2>Ripple Effects'' </h2>
<p>Investors need to look beyond these stocks for the ripple
effects of housing stabilization, the analysts said in the
report. Potential beneficiaries include certain versions of the
ABX and U.S. domestic banks, which may be helped by more
homeowner refinancing as credit conditions improve, they wrote. </p>
<p>An ABX index tied to bonds created in the second half of
2006 that were issued with AAA ratings rose 39 percent to 47.05
cents on the dollar this year, according to London-based
administrator Markit Group Ltd. </p>
<p>The higher-rated tranches have already repriced
significantly, but still price in severe future mortgage default
assumptions that are more likely than not to surprise on the low
side, the Goldman Sachs analysts wrote. They are clearly
sensitive to further home price strength. </p>
<p>The index has tumbled from about 100 when it was created in
early 2007, just after the bank''s mortgage holdings started
dropping in value. </p>
<p>In December 2006, David Viniar, Goldman Sachs''s chief
financial officer at the time, told the firm''s traders to shift
to a neutral risk position and get closer to home, according
to a report from the Senate Permanent Subcommittee on
Investigations led by Michigan Democrat Carl Levin. </p>
<h2>Big Short'' </h2>
<p>The group sold their stockpile of subprime bonds and
collateralized debt obligations, and bought credit-default swaps
protecting against losses, according to the panel. </p>
<p>They quickly shot past home,'' leading to their first
large net short position in February 2007, the report said. By
June, the net short position reached a peak of about $13.9
billion, including $9 billion in ABX bets against top-rated
bonds that Goldman Sachs had earlier acquired as disaster
protection, in case the subprime market as a whole lost value,
the subcommittee calculated. </p>
<p>The resulting position was referred to by Viniar as the
big short, a term later used as the title of a Michael Lewis
book about the financial crisis. </p>
<p>As the worst housing slump since the 1930s deepened and
millions of Americans failed to meet mortgage payments, the ABX
index linked to the 2006 mortgages fell to as low as 23.3. While
banks, including Bear Stearns Cos., struggled, Goldman Sachs
posted record earnings in 2007. </p>
<h2>Levin Questioned </h2>
<p>In April 2010, Levin questioned Goldman Sachs executives
including former trader Josh Birnbaum and Chief Executive
Officer Lloyd C. Blankfein about whether the bank had bet
against clients even as it sold mortgage-linked securities to
customers. The firm has denied wrongdoing. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs paid a record $550 million fine that year to
settle a fraud lawsuit filed by the Securities and Exchange
Commission, which accused it of misleading investors who bought
debt tied to mortgages. </p>
<p>Investors that reaped some of the biggest profits from the
2007 bust such as hedge fund manager John Paulson, who made $15
billion, have since reversed their bets. Birnbaum and Greg Lippmann, who helped pioneer the ABX contracts at Deutsche Bank
AG (DBK), are profiting this year from a rally in subprime and other
bonds not backed by the U.S. government. </p>
<h2>Birnbaum Gains </h2>
<p>Lippmann''s $2.3 billion LibreMax Capital LLC was up 19
percent this year through October. Birnbaum, who now manages
$1.2 billion at Tilden Park Capital Management LP, has gained 34
percent in the firm''s main hedge fund through October this year. </p>
<p>Returns on senior-ranked subprime securities from 2005
through 2007, the years that produced the most defaults, average
almost 33 percent this year, according to Barclays Plc index
data. The debt lost 5.5 percent last year. </p>
<p>Kyle Bass, who made $500 million shorting subprime, said
this month that the securities offer a very safe place to
make double-digit returns and that he''s betting more than half
the money from his firm -- Hayman Capital Management LP -- on
the bonds. </p>
<p>The debt is virtually bulletproof, because even if the
housing market declines by 10 percent, investors won''t take a
principal hit on their bonds, Bass said in an interview with
Bloomberg Television. </p>
<h2>Home Prices </h2>
<p>Home prices rose 3 percent in the 12 months through
September, according to an SP/Case-Shiller (SPCS20) index, paring the
decline to 29 percent from the 2006 peak. The median existing-home price may rise 5 percent in 2013, with comparable gains in
2014, according to the National Association of Realtors. </p>
<p>While Axonic Capital LLC sees value in some subprime debt,
there''s significant risks in the market. These include loan
servicers forgiving principal for delinquent homeowners, said
Clayton DeGiacinto, a former Goldman Sachs mortgage trader and
its chief investment officer. The servicers--which collect
payments from borrowers on behalf of bond investors--can also
decide to disrupt cash flowing to investors by invoking their
right to stop advancing missed payments until foreclosure
proceeds are collected, he said. </p>
<h2>Price Views </h2>
<p>It''s a heavy analytical process to weigh the benefits of
home appreciation versus the cons, said DeGiacinto of New
York-based Axonic. The firm, which manages $1.4 billion, has
gained more than 22 percent in its credit-opportunities hedge
fund this year. The decision to buy or sell isn''t completely
predicated on home price views. </p>
<p>ABX investments also carry different risks than owning the
actual bonds. Trading in the market has fallen since before the
housing crash, making the swaps less liquid than others used to
bet on debt. Reduced liquidity can make it more expensive to
enter and exit positions at quoted prices. </p>
<p>The most active ABX index, tied to securities created in the
second half of 2005, had $2.5 billion of net outstanding
contacts as of Nov. 23, according to the Depository Trust 
Clearing Corp. data. That compares with almost $110 billion for
the largest swaps index tied to corporate bonds and $8.1 billion
for commercial-mortgage securities. </p>
<p>Outstanding ABX contracts total a net $16.7 billion,
compared with more than $310 billion of subprime securities,
according to DTCC and Amherst Securities Group LP data. As much
as $200 billion of ABX contracts tied to bonds with just the
lowest investment grades were outstanding in mid-2007, according
to an estimate from a Paulson  Co. presentation that year. </p>
<p>ABX values also often don''t track the returns on actual
securities. </p>
<h2>By Yourself'' </h2>
<p>The indexes can reflect individual funds making macro
economic wagers or dealers and investors adjusting their hedges,
said Marina Tukhin, a managing director of subprime and home
equity bond trading at Brean Capital LLC in New York. </p>
<p>They don''t really reflect much of anything at this
point, she said. Their illiquidity means you can end up
driving up the market all by yourself, she said. </p>
<p>During the 10 three-month periods over the past two years
in which subprime values gained more than 10 percent, the
correlation between the debt and an ABX index tied to the same
20 securities was negative 0.08, according to a Nov. 21 report
from JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) </p>
<p>We see better value in subprime cash bonds, New York-based analysts at the bank led by John Sim wrote. </p>
<h2>Broader Unemployment </h2>
<p>The housing recovery may also be hitting speed bumps,
according to a Nov. 29 report from Raymond James  Associates,
which cited new-home sales falling in October. Headwinds include
new financial regulation that is likely to emerge next year,
said analysts including Buck Horne. </p>
<p>It''s hard to see where the sustained demand for
residential real estate lending is going to occur absent a
sustained tick up in the employment situation in this country,
Bonnie Baha, head of global developed credit at Los Angeles
based DoubleLine Capital LP, which oversees more than $50
billion, said in a telephone interview. There''s still a lot of
inventory and while the headline unemployment number has
declined, a broader labor market metric, the U-6 jobless rate
is still elevated, she said. </p>
<p>Investors looking to bet on a housing recovery should
make sure they''re clear about what they mean and be careful
about their approach, said John Dolan, an independent market
maker for futures on the SP/Case-Shiller indexes that trade on
the CME Group Inc. New-home construction and property values may
not move at the same pace or in the same direction, and
mortgage-bond prices can be linked to unrelated issues such as
benchmark rates and how individual loan servicers deal with bad
debt, he said. </p>
<p>Still, ABX contracts are probably a good viable way of
expressing a view on home prices, said Dolan, who traded
mortgage bonds as chief investment officer at Hyperion
Brookfield Asset Management and Bankers Trust. Not the purest
theoretical way, but a good pragmatic way. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Nov 30, 2012  4:32 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-11-30/microsoft-said-to-speed-windows-upgrades-to-once-a-year.html"><headline>Microsoft Said to Speed Windows Upgrades to Once a Year</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) plans to overhaul how it develops the flagship Windows operating system in a strategic shift aimed at keeping pace with nimbler rivals Apple (AAPL) Inc. and Google Inc. (GOOG), people familiar with the matter said. </p> <p>Microsoft aims to upgrade the software more frequently, about once a year, rather than every two or three years as it''s done in the past, said the people, who asked not to be identified because the product plans are private. The company plans to unveil the first of these updates in 2013, one of the people said. </p> <p>The world''s largest software maker has floundered as personal computers, where it has long dominated, have lost ground to the smartphones and tablets championed by Apple and Google. The new approach could help Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft respond to industry changes and integrate new technologies more quickly. </p> <p>U.S. retail sales of PCs running Windows have declined 21 percent since the company released the latest version of the operating system, Windows 8, according to a report by NPD Group Inc. </p> <p>The decrease has been fueled by a 24 percent drop in sales of notebook computers as many customers opt for Apple''s iPad or tablets powered by Google''s software instead of Windows, NPD said. The report compared sales from Oct. 21 to Nov. 17 of this year to the same period of 2011. It was based on a sampling of retailers and excluded Microsoft''s own stores, where the company''s Surface tablet is sold. </p>




Photographer: Stuart Isett/Bloomberg

<p>
Microsoft aims to upgrade the software more frequently, about once a year, rather than every two or three years as it''s done in the past. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ney Hayashi" date="Dec 01, 2012 10:07 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-01/general-atlantic-buying-brazil-s-xp-brokerage-stake-veja-says.html"><headline>General Atlantic Buying Brazil''s XP Brokerage Stake, Veja Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Private equity firm General Atlantic
LLC agreed to pay 1.2 billion reais ($561.8 million) for a 30
percent stake in Brazilian brokerage XP Investimentos CCTVM SA,
Veja reported, without saying where it got the information. </p>
<p>Guilherme Benchimol and Marcelo Maisonnave remain as
controlling shareholders, Veja said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Julie Johnsson" date="Dec 02, 2012 12:46 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-02/exxon-mobil-baton-rouge-refinery-pipeline-leak-releases-benzene.html"><headline>Exxon Mobil Baton Rouge Refinery Pipeline Leak Releases Benzene</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>About 10 pounds of benzene was
released by a pipeline leak at Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM)''s Baton Rouge
Refinery in Baton Rouge, Louisiana, according to a report made
to the National Response Center. </p>
<p>Atmospheric monitoring is being conducted at the site and
absorbent pads have been placed under the leak, according to the
report, which was taken at 2:08 p.m. yesterday. </p>
<p>U.S. refineries must notify the National Response Center if
they release hazardous substance in excess of reportable
quantities, according to the Comprehensive Environmental
Response, Compensation, and Liability Act, commonly known as
Superfund. </p>
<p>Bloomberg News couldn''t immediately verify the information
in the filing was accurate. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry></news>