
<news><entry author="By Mario Parker" date="Oct 08, 2009  1:14 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-10-08/walter-u-s-coal-producers-gain-after-alcoa-tops-estimates.html"><headline>Walter, U.S. Coal Producers Gain After Alcoa Tops Estimates</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;U.S. coal producers led by Walter (WLT)
Energy Inc. surged after Alcoa Inc. reported better-than-estimated earnings, sparking optimism that coal demand will rise
as the economy recovers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walter, a southern Appalachian coal producer, jumped $4.04,
or 7.2 percent, to $59.99 at 12:31 p.m. in New York Stock
Exchange composite trading. Peabody Energy Corp. (BTU), the largest
U.S. coal company, gained $1.26, or 3.2 percent, to $40.29. Arch
Coal Inc. (ACI), the second largest, rose 57 cents, or 2.5 percent, to
$23.40. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;The group has had a lot of strength in the past week,&#8221;
said Pearce Hammond, an analyst at Simmons  Co. in Houston.
&#8220;The raw economic data is a large contributor. Of course Alcoa
is a material company and that is contributing to the
strength.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patriot Coal Corp., the fourth-largest eastern U.S. coal
producer, added 46 cents, or 3.7 percent, to $12.78. Consol
Energy Corp. (CNX), the fourth-largest U.S. coal company, climbed
$2.34, or 4.9 percent, to $49.84. Alpha Natural Resources Inc. (ANR),
the third-biggest coal company, soared $1.60, or 4.3 percent, to
$39.26. Massey Energy Corp., the fifth-biggest, gained $1.14, or
3.7 percent, to $31.71. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By David Pauly" date="Oct 15, 2009  9:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-10-15/how-else-goldman-sachs-might-divvy-up-20-billion-david-pauly.html"><headline>How Else Goldman Sachs Might Divvy Up $20 Billion: David Pauly</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Lloyd Blankfein, chief executive
officer of Goldman Sachs Group Inc., is in a pickle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His investment bank yesterday said it had earmarked $16.7
billion for employee bonuses, equal to $527,192 per worker, from
its profit for the nine months ended Sept. 25. That put Goldman
Sachs on a pace to match the $20.1 billion in bonuses it chalked
up in 2007. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blankfein has acknowledged that his firm&#8217;s massive payouts
put it in a bad light with both U.S. taxpayers -- who have
tossed billions in bailout money at Goldman Sachs and the rest
of the banking industry -- and critics of Wall Street&#8217;s bonus-
heavy pay system. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#8217;s help Blankfein find a way out of this embarrassment,
showing him what else he might do with that $20 billion: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Use the money to increase next year&#8217;s pay for all
Goldman Sachs employees -- putting the bonus system to rest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Share the money with Americans who rescued Wall Street
from the worst financial mess since the Great Depression. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Increase the firm&#8217;s paltry dividend payout. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. Buy commercial banks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5. All of the above. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Far-fetched, I know, but stick with me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bonus system -- typically amounting to 60 percent of
Wall Street&#8217;s pay -- is what led banks to take outsized risks in
disastrous subprime mortgages that fueled the credit debacle.
Why not raise 2010 salaries of Goldman Sachs employees by $20
billion and junk the bonuses? Or pay $5 billion in one-last-time
bonuses, raising salaries by the remainder? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tax Return Bliss &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blankfein instead might go with my second option and send
the cash to the Internal Revenue Service. The IRS could pass it
on to citizens when they file their next income tax returns. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Divide $20 billion by 308 million, the U.S. population, and
you get about $65 apiece. Not a fortune though enough for people
to replenish their supplies of socks and underwear. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Goldman keeps insisting that it didn&#8217;t need a
bailout, it must have found use for the $10 billion the
government invested in the company under the Troubled Asset
Relief Program. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The firm repaid the money as the financial crisis started
to ease -- but it also raised $10 billion by selling $5 billion
in preferred shares to Warren Buffett&#8217;s Berkshire Hathaway Inc.
and a like amount of common stock in a public offering. The
Federal Reserve is also backing Goldman debt. Blankfein does owe
us. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Owners&#8217; Delight &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#8217;s high time Goldman Sachs did something for its
shareholders, which brings us to option No. 3. The firm now only
pays out about $700 million a year in dividends, a yield of less
than 1 percent &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Goldman&#8217;s shareholders have done fine on a total
return basis -- 15.6 percent annually in the five years ended
Sept. 30 -- the stock has declined from about $235 two years ago
to Thursday&#8217;s close of $188.63. How about resurrecting an
ancient corporate custom, the year-end dividend, and give more
back to the owners? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Option No. 4 comes to mind because at the depth of the
crisis, Goldman Sachs became a commercial bank, hoping that
would make the firm look less risky to investors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman could reduce its risk by acquiring a bigger
commercial bank base, getting billions in deposits to back up
its investment banking business. (While I&#8217;m opposed to big banks
getting bigger, that&#8217;s probably a lost cause.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Status Quo &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;None of the above will happen, of course. Blankfein will
justify the huge bonuses by citing huge profits and Goldman&#8217;s
long-standing bonus system. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman earned $3.19 billion, or $5.25 a share, in the
third quarter, as it continued to make big bets on the financial
markets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By repaying the $10 billion to the Treasury, Blankfein has
wiggled out of government pay strictures that competitors like
Citigroup Inc. and Bank of America Corp. still face. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pay culture may change on the rest of Wall Street. Not
at Goldman Sachs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(David Pauly is a Bloomberg News columnist. The opinions
expressed are his own.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click on &#8220;Send Comment&#8221; in the sidebar display to send a
letter to the editor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Crayton Harrison" date="Oct 23, 2009  4:21 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-10-23/televisa-considers-cable-purchases-wireless-partner-update3-.html"><headline>Televisa Considers Cable Purchases, Wireless Partner</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Grupo Televisa SA (TLEVICPO), the world&#8217;s
largest Spanish-language broadcaster, wants to increase its
cable TV holdings and may seek a partner to buy wireless
airwaves for mobile high-speed Internet service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Televisa, which controls three cable operators and the Sky
satellite-TV service in Mexico, also may apply for licenses to
become a second cable carrier in Mexican markets that already
have a provider, Executive Vice President Alfonso de Angoitia
said today on a conference call. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#8217;s using pay-TV acquisitions to boost growth as the
recession in Mexico hurts broadcast-advertising sales. The
company&#8217;s cable carriers are winning customers from Telefonos de
Mexico SAB, the country&#8217;s largest phone company, with packages
of TV, voice and Internet service. Angoitia said Televisa may
bid in Mexico&#8217;s auctions of wireless airwaves to begin offering
a mobile-Internet service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;We&#8217;re talking to a lot of people,&#8221; Angoitia said. &#8220;Large
companies that have experience internationally where they&#8217;ve
gone into situations where they&#8217;re competing with incumbents and
been very aggressive in offerings of wireless types of services
-- that&#8217;s one possibility.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Telefonica SA (TEF), based in Spain, and Reston, Virginia-based
NII Holdings Inc. offer mobile-phone service in Mexico and other
parts of Latin America. Mexico City- based America Movil (AMXL) SAB,
which also has wireless networks throughout the region, is
considered the &#8220;incumbent&#8221; in Mexico with about 72 percent of
the nation&#8217;s wireless customers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Megacable &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Televisa gained 46 centavos to 52.90 pesos at 4 p.m. New
York time in Mexico City trading. The shares had climbed 30
percent this year before today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Megacable Holdings (MEGACPO) SAB, Mexico&#8217;s biggest cable operator,
fell 1.05 pesos, or 3.2 percent, to 31.60 pesos today after de
Angoitia said Televisa has no interest &#8220;in the short term&#8221; in
buying the company. The decline was the most in a month. The
shares climbed earlier this month on speculation it would be
acquired. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Televisa may want to enter Megacable&#8217;s territory, which
includes Guadalajara, Mexico&#8217;s second-largest city, Martin Lara,
an analyst at Vector Casa de Bolsa SA in Mexico City, said in a
research note. That could hurt Megacable, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry></news>