<?xml version='1.0' encoding='us-ascii'?>
<news><entry author="By Jonathan Weil" date="Mar 03, 2010  9:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-03-03/goldman-s-reputation-is-blankfein-s-job-no-1-jonathan-weil.html"><headline>Goldman&#8217;s Reputation Is Blankfein&#8217;s Job No. 1: Jonathan Weil</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Bashing Goldman Sachs Group Inc. has
been elevated from a national pastime to something far more
serious: a bona fide threat to the company&#8217;s operations. Don&#8217;t
just take my word for it, though. We have it from Wall Street&#8217;s
highest authority. That would be Goldman Sachs itself. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the new items in the investment bank&#8217;s latest annual
report is a 219-word risk-factor disclosure, cautioning that the
constant drumbeat of criticism is taking its toll. This isn&#8217;t to
say Goldman is acknowledging there might be something wrong with
the way it does business. That would be a wholly unnatural act. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather, the problem as identified by Goldman is the way
other people have chosen to respond to its existence. So many
critics are popping off in the press. So many government
investigations are being launched in response. And there&#8217;s so
little precious time for Goldman&#8217;s leaders to deal with it all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;The financial crisis and the current political and public
sentiment regarding financial institutions has resulted in a
significant amount of adverse press coverage, as well as adverse
statements or charges by regulators or elected officials,&#8221;
Goldman said in the annual report it filed March 1. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Press coverage and other public statements that assert
some form of wrongdoing, regardless of the factual basis for the
assertions being made, often results in some type of
investigation by regulators, legislators and law enforcement
officials or in lawsuits.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Responding to such matters &#8220;is time consuming and
expensive and can divert the time and effort of our senior
management from our business,&#8221; Goldman said. It concluded by
saying: &#8220;Adverse publicity, governmental scrutiny and legal and
enforcement proceedings can also have a negative impact on our
reputation and on the morale and performance of our employees,
which could adversely affect our businesses and results of
operations.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks, Guys &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that disclosure, wittingly or not, Goldman&#8217;s
management team paid the news media the highest possible
compliment, while simultaneously admitting a major failure of
its own. The message for the press is: &#8220;How flattering! Goldman
says we matter!&#8221; For Goldman Chief Executive Officer Lloyd Blankfein, it&#8217;s this: &#8220;My bank, on my watch, has let its good
name be put in danger.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Goldman spokesman, Ed Canaday, declined to comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While commercial brilliance and a rising stock price have
their place, the paramount job of the people who run Goldman is
to protect the firm&#8217;s reputational value. Take away the public&#8217;s
trust, and there would be no Goldman: Counterparties wouldn&#8217;t
trade with it, governments and corporations wouldn&#8217;t hire it,
and talented people wouldn&#8217;t work for it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gray Matter &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman, which earned $13.4 billion last year and paid its
employees $16.2 billion, used to receive the benefit of a doubt
from the public when its conduct came into question. Nowadays,
it&#8217;s the gray areas that often generate the most outrage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is Goldman to blame for helping Greece mask some of its
debt? Nowhere near as much as the Greek government is, but the
work Goldman performed looks dodgy anyway. Did Goldman force the
U.S. government to bail out American International Group Inc.?
No, but Goldman benefited just the same when AIG used taxpayer
money to pay the obligations it owed Goldman at 100 cents on the
dollar. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Was Goldman running the Treasury Department when its former
CEO, Hank Paulson, was in charge there? Officially, no; however,
it sure did seem that way at times. Does Goldman manipulate
markets or front-run its customers&#8217; trades? While there hasn&#8217;t
been any proof it does, it certainly could were it so inclined. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Too Much, Too Soon &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, what bothers the general public most is how much
money the bank and its employees have made, so soon after the
government invested trillions of dollars to rescue the financial
system -- including Goldman Sachs. Yet even today, the company&#8217;s
executives remain arrogant enough to claim that Goldman doesn&#8217;t
have a too-big-to-fail guarantee from the government, not even
an implicit one. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are precedents for the sort of risk-factor disclosure
Goldman made. One company that jumps to mind is Halliburton Co.,
the oilfield-services giant that morphed into a national pariah
soon after its former CEO, Dick Cheney, became U.S. vice
president. Halliburton cited its former relationship with Cheney
as a risk factor during the run-up to the 2004 presidential
election. It, too, said the problem was that the company had
become a target for reasons beyond its own behavior. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;To the extent we or our subcontractors make mistakes in
our government contracts operations, even if unintentional,
insignificant or subsequently self-reported to the applicable
government agency, we will likely be subject to intense
scrutiny,&#8221; the company said in a 2004 SEC filing. &#8220;Some of
this scrutiny is as a result of the vice president of the United
States being a former chief executive officer of Halliburton.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something Drastic &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By 2007, Halliburton had spun off its Kellogg Brown  Root
division, whose Defense Department contracts in Iraq triggered
Justice Department investigations. Since then, both Halliburton
and KBR largely have faded from the national spotlight. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While breaking up Goldman wouldn&#8217;t be as simple, at some
point the bank may have to try something just as drastic if it
can&#8217;t find a way to detoxify its reputation. Restoring Goldman&#8217;s
public standing should be Blankfein&#8217;s top priority. Yet there&#8217;s
no indication he has any idea how to accomplish this. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Truth is, it might no longer be possible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Jonathan Weil is a Bloomberg News columnist. The opinions
expressed are his own.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click on &#8220;Send Comment&#8221; in the sidebar display to send a
letter to the editor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the writer of this column:
Jonathan Weil in New York at 
jweil6@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Francesca Cinelli" date="Mar 08, 2010  1:52 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-03-08/fiat-shares-added-to-conviction-buy-list-at-goldman-sachs.html"><headline>Fiat Shares Added to &#8216;Conviction Buy&#8217; List at Goldman Sachs</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Goldman Sachs Group Inc. added Fiat
SpA (F) to its &#8220;conviction buy&#8221; list, saying that the company&#8217;s
industrial &#8220;plan will likely again be ambitious, but if
achieved could offer investors average annual returns of 35-50
percent per annum over five years.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The brokerage kept a price estimate of 16 euros on the
stock, according to a note today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Francesca Cinelli in Milan at 
fcinelli@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
David Merritt at 
dmerritt1@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Wendy Leung" date="Mar 17, 2010  1:10 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-03-17/alibaba-declines-after-jpmorgan-brokerages-cut-price-target.html"><headline>Alibaba Declines After JPMorgan, Brokerages Cut Price Target</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Alibaba.com Ltd., operator of
China&#8217;s biggest online commerce site, fell the most in six
months in Hong Kong trading after brokerages including JPMorgan
Securities Ltd. lowered their price estimate on the stock. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alibaba lost as much as 7.6 percent to HK$16.90, the
steepest intraday decline since Sept. 15, and traded at HK$17.20
at the midday break on the city&#8217;s stock exchange. That compared
with a 1.6 percent gain on the benchmark Hang Seng Index. The
company yesterday posted its first quarterly profit gain in a
year as a rebound in Chinese exports helped boost revenue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hangzhou, China-based Alibaba can expect to post higher
operating expenses this year as it makes further investments in
China marketing and promotion, JPMorgan Hong Kong-based analyst
Dick Wei said in a report today. The brokerage cut its price
estimate 4.5 percent to HK$21 while maintaining a &#8220;neutral&#8221;
rating on the stock. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alibaba&#8217;s operating margin may be under pressure in the
near term, as the company will soon cut subscriber fees for its
TrustPass membership service, which accounts for about 30
percent of total revenue, according to a report by Morgan
Stanley Asia Ltd. The brokerage kept its &#8220;overweight&#8221; rating
on the stock. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Victor Yip, an analyst at UOB-Kay Hian Ltd., lowered his
target 9.7 percent to HK$18.60, while maintaining his &#8220;hold&#8221;
rating. &#8220;Investors are still waiting for more solid guidance
from the company,&#8221; he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Wendy Leung in Hong Kong at 
wleung12@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Dirk Beveridge at 
dbeveridge1@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Peter Laca and Krystof Chamonikolas" date="Mar 18, 2010 12:42 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-03-18/czechs-may-sell-eurobond-soon-jpmorgan-citibank-say-update2-.html"><headline>Czechs May Sell Eurobond Soon, JPMorgan, Citibank Say</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;The Czech government may sell
Eurobonds this month to benefit from record-low yields as
investor appetite for emerging Europe returns after Greece&#8217;s
crisis hurt confidence in the euro area, according to JPMorgan
Chase  Co. and Citibank. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Finance Ministry hired Barclays Capital, Deutsche Bank
AG and Ceska Sporitelna AS to manage the first euro-denominated
bond sale in a year, signaling &#8220;preparations are in high gear
and the issue will probably happen soon,&#8221; JPMorgan economist
Miroslav Plojhar said by phone. The sale may take place &#8220;around
the end of March&#8221; as market conditions &#8220;are now quite good,&#8221;
Plojhar said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The record 280 billion koruna ($15.2 billion) of debt the
government wants to sell this year is luring investors attracted
by low debt levels and growth prospects. The Czech Republic,
whose government debt as a percentage of economic output will be
half the euro area average this year, last sold euro-denominated
debt in April, when it raised 1.5 billion euros ($2.06 billion). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the euro undergoing the harshest test in its 11-year
history, German bonds, Europe&#8217;s benchmark, have declined on
concern the bloc&#8217;s biggest economy will have to anchor a rescue
package for Greece. The euro weakened for a second day today
against the dollar on concern Greece will fail to secure
financial assistance from the European Union. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Converging Yields &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Czech 2014 euro-denominated bond rose to the highest
level since it was sold last April, pushing its yield down to
2.931 percent as of 5:15 p.m. in Prague today. The yield on the
German 5-year bund was at 2.137 percent. The premium investors
demand for holding the Czech bond over the German equivalent
fell to 79.3 basis points, the lowest level in three months. The
spread was at a high of 119.7 points on Feb. 8, according to
Bloomberg data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Investor sentiment has improved after the Greek crisis
highlighted the differences against the non-euro countries with
lower debt,&#8221; Jaromir Sindel, an economist at Citibank in
Prague, said in a phone interview. &#8220;The elections are an
important indicator here as they may bring nervousness to the
market.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Czech Finance Minister Eduard Janota said a sale is
possible in the first half if it&#8217;s cheaper than selling domestic
bonds. Deputy Finance Minister Bohdan Hejduk said yesterday he
&#8220;couldn&#8217;t comment&#8221; on preparations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Budget Woes &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The money is needed to plug a budget deficit that widened
to an estimated 6.6 percent of gross domestic product last year
in the worst recession since communism fell in 1989. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Czech credit-default swaps rose today to 58.5, from 57
basis points yesterday, which was the lowest level since
September 2008 when Lehman Brothers collapsed, according to CMA
DataVision data. Polish default swaps increased to 89, from
85.7, while Slovakia, a euro-area member since 2009, was at 49,
compared with 48 yesterday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Czech default swap prices have fallen from their 2010
high of 107.4 reached on Feb. 8, signaling improved investor
perceptions of the country&#8217;s credit quality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Czech government may want to push a Eurobond sale
through before a May 28-29 general election, analysts said.
Opinion polls show no party is placed to win a majority, making
it likely coalition talks will follow the vote. It took more
than seven months for a government to emerge after elections in
2006, when an evenly divided parliament couldn&#8217;t agree on an
administration. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Improved Outlook &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Czech Republic, Bulgaria, Estonia, Hungary, Lithuania
and Slovakia raised their 2010 economic forecasts in the past
month. The European Bank for Reconstruction and Development
lifted its growth estimate for the 30 emerging European nations
it invests in to 3.3 percent from 2.5 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Czech debt is rated A1 at Moody&#8217;s and A at Standard and
Poor&#8217;s, equal to euro members Slovakia and Malta. The European
Commission, the EU&#8217;s executive arm, in November forecast the
Czech general government debt at 41 percent of GDP in 2010. That
compares with a euro area average of 84 percent, according to
the commission. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Romania said on March 11 it sold 1 billion euros of five-year debt, its biggest offering of bonds to international
investors, setting yields above similarly rated Croatian notes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bond, maturing in March 2015 and carrying a 5 percent
coupon, was priced to yield 268 basis points above the benchmark
mid-swap rate, according to Bloomberg data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bigger Issue &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poland&#8217;s government, which may sell $1 billion to $1.5
billion of dollar-denominated bonds in April, will have debt of
about 55 percent of GDP this year and will exceed the bloc&#8217;s 60
percent limit in 2011, according to commission forecasts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;I would expect the Czech Eurobond to be bigger than what
we saw in past issues because the borrowing needs have never
been this big and the state needs to roll-over a large amount of
maturing debt this year,&#8221; said Vojtech Benda, an ING Bank
analyst in Prague. &#8220;The amount may be 3 billion euros or
more.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greece and Italy will have the largest debts in the EU, at
125 percent of GDP and 117 percent, respectively, the commission
estimates. Germany&#8217;s debt will rise to 76.7 percent this year
and 79.7 in 2011, commission forecasts show. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporters on this story:
Peter Laca in Prague at  placa@bloomberg.net.
Krystof Chamonikolas in Prague at 
kchamonikola@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Chris Kirkham at 
ckirkham@bloomberg.net.
Gavin Serkin at  gserkin@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Katia Cortes and Carla Simoes" date="Mar 24, 2010  5:57 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-03-24/brazil-s-high-court-postpones-ruling-on-pfizer-s-viagra-patent.html"><headline>Brazil&#8217;s High Court Postpones Ruling on Pfizer&#8217;s Viagra Patent</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Brazil&#8217;s high court delayed a
decision for two weeks on whether to end Pfizer Inc. (PFE)&#8217;s patent
for Viagra in Brazil, the world&#8217;s third-biggest market for the
impotence drug, after a judge asked to review the case before
voting in a key ruling for the $2.5 billion generic drug market. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three of the seven judges on the court had voted to end the
patent before voting was suspended. Massami Uyeda, who presided
over the case, announced the postponement in Brasilia today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Brazilian government says the 20-year patent expires in
June. New York-based Pfizer, the world&#8217;s biggest drugmaker,
disagrees on when the patent went into effect, saying it doesn&#8217;t
expire until June 2011. Pfizer won two lower court rulings on
the issue and the government has appealed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Should the court reject Pfizer&#8217;s claim, Hypermarcas SA (HYPE3),
Medley SA, EMS, Eurofarma Laboratorios Ltda. and other generic
drug producers would benefit, said Iago Whately, an analyst
covering the health industry at Sao Paulo-based brokerage Fator
Corretora. Drogasil SA and other pharmacy chains would also gain
as cheaper versions of drugs would help boost sales, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;The faster patents expire, the more promising it is for
the generic market,&#8221; Odnir Finotti, the head of the Brazilian
Association for the Generic Drugs Industry, said in a telephone
interview from Sao Paulo today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The court&#8217;s ruling in a fortnight may set a precedent for
37 similar cases covering drugs such as Pfizer&#8217;s Lipitor and
Novartis AG (NOVN)&#8217;s Everolimus, said Mauro Maia, chief prosecutor at
the National Institute for Industrial Property, an agency known
as INPI, which is leading the fight against extending the Viagra
patent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;$95 Million Drug &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer is seeking to ensure the patent for Viagra in Brazil
lasts as long as in Europe, Pfizer&#8217;s lawyer Gustavo Morais, who
works for Dannemann Siemsen Advogados, said in phone interview
from Sao Paulo. Pfizer and the National Institute for Industrial
Property can appeal from the court&#8217;s decision to the Supreme
Court, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer gets 170 million reais ($95 million) annually from
Viagra sales in Brazil, it said in a March 16 e-mail. The U.S.
is the largest market for Viagra, with the U.K. the second
biggest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Novartis, based in Basel, won&#8217;t comment, according to an e-mail from Impress, its external public relations firm based in
Sao Paulo. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generic drugs will account for 30 percent of total
Brazilian sales of medicines within three years, up from a
current 20 percent, Finotti said. Generic drugs started being
produced in Brazil in 2000, he said. Sales rose 25 percent in
2009 to 4.5 billion reais, said Claudio Sa, a spokesman for the
industry group. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generic copies of Viagra would cost half the price of the
original and increase consumer demand about 10 times, Finotti
said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;With cheaper drugs via generic copies, more people will
have access to them, which is good for pharmacies,&#8221; said
Whately, who has buy or hold recommendations on shares of all
nine health companies he covers in Brazil. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Katia Cortes in Brasilia at 
kcortes@bloomberg.net;
Carla Simoes in Brasilia at 
csimoes1@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Brendan Walsh at 
bwalsh8@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Tasneem Brogger" date="Mar 26, 2010  5:30 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-03-26/jpmorgan-says-east-europe-currencies-keep-rates-low-update1-.html"><headline>JPMorgan Says East Europe Currencies Keep Rates Low</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Currency gains in central and
eastern Europe, led by a 18 percent rise in the zloty against
the euro since March 30 last year, may delay monetary tightening
and extend easing cycles as policy makers try to cap exchange
rate strengthening, JPMorgan Chase  Co. said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;We expect further appreciation,&#8221; London-based JPMorgan
economist Miroslav Plojhar said in an interview. This is
&#8220;slowing inflation and making central bankers more dovish. The
risk to the outlook is that rate cutting cycles in Romania and
Hungary will be rather deeper and that rate hiking cycles in
Poland and the Czech Republic will start rather later.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The zloty, the forint, the leu and the koruna are poised to
rise further this year as the countries&#8217; current accounts
improve and because exchange rates don&#8217;t yet reflect the
region&#8217;s growth potential, Plojhar said. Currencies in the four
European Union states also benefit from fiscal health relative
to Greece, Portugal, Ireland and Spain, he said. That leaves
central banks little choice but to base decisions on exchange
rate moves. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;For the chicken-and-egg question of whether central
bankers are driving currencies or currencies are driving central
bankers&#8221; in the region, &#8220;the answer is more that central
bankers are responding more to the currencies,&#8221; Plojhar said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Czechs may delay tightening from 1 percent until the
first quarter and Poland may not raise from 3.5 percent until
the fourth quarter, he said. Hungary may keep cutting to 5
percent &#8220;or below&#8221; and Romania may go as low as 5 percent.
JPMorgans&#8217;s official forecast is for the Poles and the Czechs to
start tightening in the third and fourth quarters and for the
Hungarians and Romanians to stop at 5.5 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Regional Reward &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The region is also being rewarded for its austere fiscal
policies, including International Monetary Fund-led programs in
Hungary and Romania, reducing pressure on central bankers to
resort to monetary tightening or rein in the scope of easing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standard  Poor&#8217;s Analyst Frank Gill says responsible
programs probably will continue even as elections loom that may
oust governments. Hungarians go to the polls on April 11 and 25,
while the Czechs vote on May 28-29. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hungary&#8217;s Fidesz Party, which has promised tax cuts and
said the budget deficit may be twice as wide as the government
now estimates, won&#8217;t dare deploy policies that are hostile to
investors, according to Tim Ash, head of emerging market
research at Royal Bank of Scotland Plc. Fidesz is more than 30
points ahead of the ruling Socialists in the polls. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Anyone who steps out of line is going to get smacked by
the market,&#8221; Ash said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&#8216;Safe Haven&#8217; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Euro area debt as a percentage of gross domestic product
will average 84 percent this year and may be 125 percent in
Greece, the European Commission estimates. In emerging EU, only
Hungary will exceed the 60 percent limit, at 79.8 percent. On
average, euro area deficits will be 6.9 percent, more than twice
the EU&#8217;s threshold. Hungary, Romania and the Czech Republic will
all have smaller deficits than the currency bloc&#8217;s average. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Czech bonds and the koruna are a &#8220;safe haven&#8221; as the
country&#8217;s borrowing level makes it less likely to face a Greek-style crisis, Danske Bank A/S said in a report yesterday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standard  Poor&#8217;s is &#8220;fairly confident&#8221; the next
Hungarian government will &#8220;continue to pursue policies to
reduce public sector borrowing needs,&#8221; Gill said in an
interview. The country&#8217;s growth prospects also underline its
fiscal recovery, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fiscal Math &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Hungary will converge back to growth rates of 3 percent
between 2011 and 2012,&#8221; Gill said. &#8220;The fiscal mathematics
will begin to become far more benign than it has been over the
last several years.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Hungary, where exports make up almost 80 percent of GDP,
the forint has gained 15 percent per euro since March 30 even as
the benchmark was lowered 3.75 points to 5.75 percent. The bank
last month said &#8220;gradual&#8221; rate cuts may end in the &#8220;next few
meetings.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Romania, where the benchmark matches a 2007 record low
of 7 percent, a strong leu helped slow inflation to 4.5 percent
last month from 5.2 percent in January. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Poland, the only EU member to have avoided a recession
during the credit crisis, is &#8220;likely to continue to outperform
the rest of the region,&#8221; Plojhar said. &#8220;Looking further ahead,
it&#8217;s likely the Czechs and the Hungarians will see a much
stronger relative acceleration in GDP growth than Poland because
they&#8217;re recovering from a slower growth pace.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SP&#8217;s Gill said the Czech Republic &#8220;is potentially very
well positioned to leverage off a euro-zone recovery if there is
one.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not everyone is convinced about the growth outlook as the
export-reliant east awaits a sustainable rebound in demand from
western Europe. In Germany, investor confidence dropped for a
sixth month in March, suggesting the EU&#8217;s biggest economy is
struggling to expand, the ZEW Center for European Economic
Research said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Funding doesn&#8217;t seem to be the problem, but everyone&#8217;s
assuming there&#8217;s going to be a rebound and that growth comes
back,&#8221; RBS&#8217;s Ash said. &#8220;But that&#8217;s a big question mark, given
a very weak western European story.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter responsible for this story:
Tasneem Brogger at 
tbrogger@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story
Chris Kirkham at 
ckirkham@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Rick Warner" date="Mar 27, 2010  1:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-03-27/how-disney-awoke-sleeping-beauty-cambodian-ballet-movies.html"><headline>How Disney Awoke 'Sleeping Beauty'; Cambodian Ballet: Movies</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;When Jeffrey Katzenberg took over
Walt Disney's film division in 1984, the glory days of Disney
animation were a distant memory. The studio that had made such
classics as "Fantasia" and "Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs"
was in a major creative and commercial slump. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We've got to wake up 'Sleeping Beauty,'" Katzenberg
declared. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Katzenberg -- along with fellow Disney executives Michael
Eisner, Roy Disney (Walt's nephew) and Frank Wells -- did wake
up the slumbering giant. They revived the studio's animation
unit and ushered in a decade-long golden era that included the
blockbusters "Beauty and the Beast," "The Little Mermaid,"
"Aladdin" and "The Lion King." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story behind the comeback -- and the clash of egos that
eventually broke up the company's leadership -- is told in
"Waking Sleeping Beauty," a lively documentary directed by
former Disney producer Don Hahn. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using old home movies, film and TV clips, and fresh
interviews with the major players -- including Eisner, Disney
and Katzenberg -- Hahn reconstructs a Shakespearean tale of
jealousy, genius, passion and hubris. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From 1984-94, according to the film, the Disney animation
division was a pressure-cooker where people worked grueling
hours to produce some of the best animated films in history. It
also was a time when animators were treated like rock stars,
getting rewarded with big salaries and public recognition. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Porsches, Agents &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Suddenly there were bonuses and the parking lot was just
full of BMWs and Porsches," Hahn says in the film's narration.
"We were getting a new building and people were getting lawyers
and agents and appearing on talk shows." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But tensions grew in the executive suites. Eisner and
Disney resented Katzenberg for hogging the spotlight and taking
too much credit for the company's success. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Wells died in a helicopter crash in 1994, Katzenberg
lobbied for the vacant job of Disney president. Eisner, the
chief executive officer, turned him down and Katzenberg
resigned. (Katzenberg then co-founded Disney competitor
DreamWorks with Steven Spielberg and David Geffen. Eisner later
clashed with Roy Disney and was forced out in 2005.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many stories have been written about the Eisner-Katzenberg
saga, but "Waking Sleeping Beauty" offers a unique perspective
from those who lived through what seemed like a Hollywood fairy
tale. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Waking Sleeping Beauty," from Walt Disney Studios, is
playing in New York, Los Angeles, Chicago and San Francisco.
Rating: *** &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Dancing Across Borders' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While visiting Cambodia in 2000 with the World Monuments
Fund, arts patron Anne Bass saw a 16-year-old boy perform a
native dance at an ancient temple. She was entranced. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That encounter led her to make "Dancing Across Borders,"
a documentary about how that teenager -- Sokvannara Sar, known
as Sy -- came to the U.S., overcame enormous odds and became an
acclaimed ballet dancer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bass, the former wife of billionaire Sid Bass, follows Sy
from the rice paddies of Cambodia to the dance studios and
stages of New York, Florida, Colorado, Bulgaria and Seattle,
where he joins the Pacific Northwest Ballet. We watch his
transformation from a skinny, raw dancer to a refined, muscular
ballet artist. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a no-frills movie. Aside from some family scenes in
Cambodia, it mostly consists of Sy dancing and a bunch of
talking heads, including his teacher Olga Kostritsky, former
ballet star Jock Soto and Peter Boal, artistic director of the
Pacific Northwest Ballet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is Bass's first film, and her inexperience shows with
too much repetition. Yet Sy is such a compelling personality and
his story is so fascinating that you don't have to love ballet
to appreciate it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Dancing Across Borders," from First Run Features, is
playing in New York. Rating: **1/2 &lt;/p&gt;



What the Stars Mean:

****          Excellent
***           Good
**            Average
*             Poor
(No stars)    Worthless

&lt;p&gt;(Rick Warner is the movie critic for Bloomberg News. The
opinions expressed are his own.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the writer on the story:
Rick Warner in New York at 
rwarner1@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By John Dorfman" date="Mar 28, 2010  9:01 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-03-28/lilly-pfizer-merck-win-in-health-care-smackdown-john-dorfman.html"><headline>Lilly, Pfizer, Merck Win in Health-Care Smackdown: John Dorfman</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Which stocks will emerge as
winners, and which ones as losers, from the massive new health-
care package? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The complex new law -- which will be phased in over several
years and faces court challenges -- will increase the pool of
insured Americans. An estimated 32 million people who now aren&#8217;t
insured will be covered, giving them increased buying power to
purchase everything from drugs to surgical procedures. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big beneficiaries, in my view, will be hospitals, which
will be paid for more patient visits; pharmaceutical companies,
which will sell more drugs; and medical-device makers, which
will sell more hearing aids, pacemakers and other products. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their gains will be partly offset by higher taxes and more
regulation, but on balance I still think that the legislation is
good for these groups. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Insurers and managed-care companies will be hurt, in my
view. At first glance, you might think that health insurers
would find the new law a boon. After all, here is Uncle Sam
telling people that they must buy the industry&#8217;s product. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, insurers&#8217; costs will rise substantially as they
comply with the new requirement that pre-existing conditions be
covered. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, insurers deny coverage to some people due to
pre-existing conditions, and surcharge others. On occasion, they
also rescind previously issued coverage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Policies Terminated &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A June 2009 memo issued by the House Committee on Energy
and Commerce estimated that insurance companies save about $60
million a year by terminating health-insurance policies on the
grounds that pre-existing conditions weren&#8217;t disclosed by
customers. The memo said that about 4,000 policies a year are
rescinded. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#8217;ve been unable to obtain good estimates on what it will
cost insurers and managed-care organizations to cover pre-
existing conditions. But it will clearly involve a huge cost
increase. As I see it, this won&#8217;t bankrupt the companies but it
will make it very hard for them to show earnings progress. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Profit margins for health insurers and managed-care
companies aren&#8217;t great to begin with. Aetna Inc., for example,
had a pretax margin of less than 6 percent in 2009. Cigna
Corp.&#8217;s pretax margin was about 10 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These companies will try to protect their profits by
raising premiums, but they will run into fierce opposition from
employers, consumers, and politicians eager to make insurance
companies into whipping boys. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trouble for HMOs &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Property and casualty insurance companies don&#8217;t have to
provide coverage for a burning house, but health insurers will
have to cover someone who already has cancer or AIDS. That may
be good public policy, but it&#8217;s bad for insurers&#8217; profits. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pharmaceutical companies aren&#8217;t harmed by the pre-existing-
conditions rule. Indeed, they are helped. People who need
medication but can&#8217;t afford it under the status quo will be
insured and receiving prescriptions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some of my picks in the health-care sector. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My favorite pharmaceutical stock is Merck  Co. of
Whitehouse Station, New Jersey. It has 20 drugs in Phase III
trials, the most advanced stage of drug development, and another
20 in Phase II. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merck&#8217;s pretax margin, 56 percent last year, could fall a
lot and still dwarf insurers&#8217; profit margins. Its stock sells
for 12 times earnings and yields 4 percent in dividends. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High Yield &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other drug stocks I favor are Indianapolis-based Eli Lilly
 Co. and New York-based Pfizer Inc. Both look cheap to me,
selling for eight times earnings. Lilly yields more than 5
percent in dividends, Pfizer about 4 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the hospital arena, Tenet Healthcare Corp. of Dallas
rose 9 percent the day after the health-care bill passed the
House of Representatives. I wouldn&#8217;t chase it. I dislike Tenet
because it has debt of more than 13 times shareholders&#8217; equity,
and sells for 39 times earnings and nine times book value. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More appealing to me is LifePoint Hospitals Inc., based in
Brentwood, Tennessee. LifePoint operates about four dozen
hospitals in 17 states, mostly in rural areas with no
competition. It has been profitable each year since 2000 with
rising earnings in eight of the past 10 years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LifePoint&#8217;s stock, at 14 times earnings and 1.1 times book
value, seems to me appealingly cheap. Of 21 analysts who cover
it, only five rate it a &#8220;buy,&#8221; but I am happy to side with the
minority here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would avoid Aetna and Cigna, though their stocks have
performed well in the past two weeks. I fear their already
limited profit margins will be compressed further. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beware of Alliance HealthCare Services Inc., a Newport
Beach, California, company that performs diagnostic-imaging
services for hospitals. It has a debt-laden capital structure,
with debt equivalent to 24 times stockholders&#8217; equity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclosure note: I own Merck shares personally and for
clients, and Pfizer for a few clients. I have no positions, long
or short, in the other stocks discussed in this week&#8217;s column. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(John Dorfman, chairman of Thunderstorm Capital in Boston,
is a columnist for Bloomberg News. The opinions expressed are
his own. His firm or clients may own or trade securities
discussed in this column.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click on &#8220;Send Comment&#8221; in the sidebar display to send a
letter to the editor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the writer of this column:
John Dorfman at 
jdorfman@thunderstormcapital.com. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Zinta Lundborg" date="Mar 29, 2010 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-03-29/help-for-medical-glitches-investor-cocaine-brain-interview.html"><headline>Help for Medical Glitches, Investor Cocaine Brain: Interview</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;As the global rates of surgery
grew, so did the damage: A million patients a year died during
medical procedures and more than 7 million were left disabled.
The World Health Organization turned to Dr. Atul Gawande to come
up with a low-cost solution. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He developed a pre-operation checklist, which the WHO tried
out in eight hospitals with remarkable results. Deaths fell 47
percent, while complications dropped by more than a third. It
didn&#8217;t matter how high-tech or how poor the hospital was -- the
results were significant across the board. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In his latest book, &#8220;The Checklist Manifesto: How to Get
Things Right,&#8221; surgeon and MacArthur Award winner Gawande
argues that the complexity that now characterizes many fields,
ranging from architecture to venture capitalism, can be tamed
with a humble tool. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We spoke in a French cafe in New York&#8217;s Chelsea district. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lundborg: How does a simple checklist help manage
complexity? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gawande: In medicine, we&#8217;re overwhelmed by the volume of
knowledge and information we have to handle. A checklist fills
in for weaknesses in our brains, like memory, and helps us work
more successfully as teams. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lundborg: Why does the checklist have such a bad rap? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gawande: One is sheer embarrassment -- if you&#8217;re an expert,
you&#8217;re better than that. It&#8217;s thought to dumb things down rather
than being about the nuance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus a lot of us hate following instructions. We&#8217;ve had
experiences where it can get in the way, where the rigidity of
rules makes for bad results. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good Checklist &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lundborg: What&#8217;s a good checklist? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gawande: This is where science comes in to it. A good
checklist actually improves the ability of an expert to do a job
well. It has to be tested in the real world with feedback from
the people on the front lines. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When it works, it helps performance without any improvement
in skill. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lundborg: In the financial world, how does the checklist
counter &#8220;greed mode&#8221; and &#8220;cocaine brain?&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gawande: A group of investors studied mistakes, saw the
recurrent patterns and devised a series of checks at certain
pause points along the way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making an accurate assessment of the margin of safety is
crucial. You are so sure you&#8217;ve got a winner -- you&#8217;re working
against everything your brain is screaming at you about how
fantastic this will be -- that you start to disregard risk or
cut corners. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lundborg: Clearly, not many in the financial industry were
using checklists. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gawande: The kinds of mistakes you will never prevent with
a checklist are of values: if you know it and still do it, a
checklist can&#8217;t stop that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emergencies &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lundborg: Does the checklist function differently in an
emergency, such as when Sully Sullenberger successfully landed
his plane in the Hudson? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gawande: We wanted to say it was the heroism of the
individual. He responded by saying it was about adherence to
protocol and teamwork, so we said he was just being modest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the engines went out, he could count on the co-pilot
to run through the checks, so he could focus on the one key
thing that couldn&#8217;t be reduced to a checklist, &#8220;Where am I
going to land this plane?&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lundborg: In your New Yorker article on expensive health
care in McAllen, Texas, you showed what happens when the patient
is regarded as a profit center. What response did you get? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gawande: I&#8217;ve never had an article so widely read. There is
a battle in the culture of medicine between a desire to run a
successful business and the recognition that the patient&#8217;s needs
have to come first over any kind of business requirement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cost Factor &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a health system where doing great at the medical
business is not necessarily what is great for patients. The most
damning thing about the costs of our system is that the doctors
who get the best results are not the ones who are the most
expensive. Often they are the least expensive. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lundborg: So what can we do? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gawande: We know that the existing way of paying doctors is
both inflationary and unsuccessful for the best health of
patients. We&#8217;re in a period of needing to undergo a series of
experiments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you pay doctors a salary? Do you pay a hospital a
bundled rate for all the patients they take care of in a year?
Do you pay a single price for asthma patients? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lundborg: Doctors used to be gods. How are they faring
during all this turmoil? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demoralized &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gawande: Physicians are demoralized in many ways. We point
to bureaucracy, battles with insurance and government, as well
as changing expectations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what doctors are really responding to is the complexity
of medicine. Starting a process involves multiple people,
systems of care, and you are one part of that machine. We are
not used to learning how to be leaders or teammates in the
context of larger organizations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We find it hard to grapple in this world where the enormous
volume of information and knowledge exceeds our own abilities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;The Checklist Manifesto&#8221; is published by Metropolitan
Books (209 pages, $24.50). To buy the book in North America,
click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Zinta Lundborg is a writer for Bloomberg News. The
opinions expressed are her own. This interview was adapted from
a longer conversation.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Zinta Lundborg in New York 
zlundborg@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Ye Xie" date="Mar 31, 2010  7:01 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-03-31/goldman-sachs-recommends-chinese-hong-kong-listed-shares-as-top-trade-.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Recommends Chinese Hong Kong-Listed Shares as `Top Trade'</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;China's Hong Kong-listed companies
are a "new top trade" at Goldman Sachs Group Inc., which said
the Hang Seng China Enterprises Index will climb at least 20
percent on valuation and the outlook for economic growth. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We are recommending a new top trade," Dominic Wilson, an
economist at Goldman Sachs in New York, wrote in a report e-
mailed yesterday. "We sense that Chinese equities have fallen
off investors' radars somewhat, positioning is light, and
sentiment is, at best, skeptical, making us all the more keen to
get involved." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recommendation is Goldman Sachs's ninth top trade for
the year. The other top trades include owning Russian stocks,
favoring the British pound against the New Zealand dollar, and
the Polish zloty against the Japanese yen, according to a
separate note e-mailed yesterday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The H-share index has dropped 10 percent from a 17-month
high in November, compared with a 2.8 percent gain for the MSCI
Emerging Markets Index, on concern policy makers will curb bank
lending and raise interest rates to slow growth. The H-share
index's 3.1 percent loss this year compares to a 4.9 percent
gain in the Standard  Poor's 500 Index of U.S. stocks and 2.1
percent advance in the MSCI Emerging Markets Index of 22
developing-nation stocks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Long Position' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The "underperformance" of China's H shares left their
valuation at "undemanding" levels, Goldman Sachs said. The H-
share index is priced at 17.8 times the reported earnings of its
companies, an 11 percent discount to the MSCI Emerging Markets
Index, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman Sachs recommended a "long position" in H shares as
the index that tracks their performance rises to 15,000 from
12,397.59 yesterday. China's economy, the third largest in the
world, will expand more than 11 percent this year, Goldman Sachs
predicts, more than the 9.6 percent median forecast of 22
analysts surveyed by Bloomberg. Goldman Sachs's portfolio
strategists predict the H shares index will climb to 17,000 by
year-end, a 37 percent jump from yesterday's close. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Economic growth has stayed robust and broad based,"
Goldman Sachs wrote. "While interest rates will likely rise
soon," the risk from policy tightening "is much better flagged
than before." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporters on this story:
Ye Xie in New York at 
yxie6@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Bob Ivry and Jody Shenn" date="Mar 31, 2010  1:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-03-31/how-lou-lucido-helped-aig-lose-35-billion-with-cdos-made-by-goldman-sachs.html"><headline>How Lou Lucido Helped AIG Lose $35 Billion With CDOs Made by Goldman Sachs</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Joseph Cassano insisted American
International Group Inc. would be fine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The insurer had quit guaranteeing securities tied to U.S.
subprime loans in 2005, before lenders got reckless, the head of
AIG's derivatives unit told investors on Dec. 5, 2007, as home
prices plummeted and mortgage losses mounted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cassano didn't mention Lou Lucido, 61, a guitar-playing
bond buyer at TCW Group Inc. in Los Angeles with a taste for the
Rolling Stones. Throughout 2006 and 2007, Lucido had been buying
bundles of subprime loans for an investment pool that AIG was
bound by contract to insure against failure. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In one such purchase, 11 months before Cassano, 55, 
reassured shareholders, Lucido's team bought $7 million of a 
mostly subprime bond. They put it in a $1.5 billion fund managed 
by TCW called Davis Square Funding III Ltd., which was created
by Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and registered in the Cayman
Islands. A few months later, Lucido bought $3 million more. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By May 2008, the bond was worthless. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without having to ask AIG's permission, firms such as TCW,
hired to oversee funds called collateralized debt obligations,
replaced maturing assets with junk that quickly went bad.
Managers including Lucido said they didn't realize how severe
the mortgage crash would be and were called upon by CDO
contracts to reinvest. At the same time, buying riskier assets
could mean bigger paydays. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Perverse' Incentives &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The incentive was perverse," said Michael Lea, a finance
professor at San Diego State University and former chief
economist at mortgage giant Freddie Mac. "The fee structure
encouraged TCW to put lower-rated bonds into CDOs over time." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A look at the month-by-month transactions in one CDO --
Davis Square III, named for a difficult-to-navigate section of
Somerville, Massachusetts, near Harvard University -- shows how
collateral replacements helped drive New York-based AIG to the
brink of disaster. The insurer ended up paying $616 million to
make up for Davis Square III's loss in value and more than $35
billion overall, liabilities that helped push it into insolvency
in September 2008. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lucido's team, following criteria set by Goldman Sachs,
changed almost one-third of the collateral in Davis Square III
after the CDO's creation in 2004, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg from Moody's Investors Service reports. The securities
were mostly backed by the types of newer loans that are going
bad at more than twice the rate of older ones. By November 2008,
after U.S. taxpayers rescued AIG with a bailout that later
swelled to $182.3 billion, even the highest-rated parts of Davis
Square III had lost almost half their value. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Standards Fell' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Mortgage underwriting standards fell so much that
replacing a bunch of 2004 bonds with 2006 and 2007 bonds
definitely screwed AIG," said Thomas Adams, a former managing
director at bond insurer Ambac Financial Group Inc. and now a
partner at New York law firm Paykin Krieg  Adams LLP. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CDOs were at the heart of the financial crisis that sparked
the highest U.S. jobless rate in a generation. They were among
the largest contributors to the $1.8 trillion of losses at the
world's largest financial firms since the start of 2007,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission is
investigating how Wall Street banks bet against mortgage-linked
securities to profit as their clients took losses, according to
people familiar with the matter. As part of its examination of
the market, the agency is looking at collateral replacement,
said an SEC official with knowledge of the probe who asked not
to be identified because he wasn't authorized to comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collateral Triggers &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Replacing good collateral with bad helped erode Davis
Square III's value. Declines in quality added to the cash AIG
had to pay to holders of its insurance because its Financial
Products division, headed by Cassano, made agreements with 
banks that included what are called collateral triggers. That
was a feature other bond insurers didn't offer, Adams said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The triggers kicked in when the value of the CDOs declined
or if a rating company downgraded AIG's creditworthiness. By
December 2008, the insurer had paid out more than $35 billion,
according to a list of collateral provided by AIG to Congress. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the Financial Products unit agreed to guarantee
certain top-rated CDO pieces, it didn't envision that assets
added later could cause losses, according to a person with
knowledge of AIG's thinking who spoke on condition of anonymity
because he wasn't authorized to comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As long as managers adhered to investment criteria outlined
in the prospectus, there was little AIG could do, according to
Mark Herr, a spokesman for the insurer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph Warin, Cassano's lawyer, declined to comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Informed Decisions' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Davis Square III's 209-page prospectus spelled out the
risks for potential investors. "Characteristics" of
replacement collateral wouldn't necessarily be the same as those
of existing assets, it said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also spelled out Goldman Sachs's investment guidelines,
which allowed as much as half of Davis Square III to be bonds
backed by subprime mortgages, given to people with bad or
limited credit histories. Among other constraints, TCW needed to
meet collateral ratings requirements and maintain a mix of
lenders and types of debt. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lucido and his team followed the guidelines and avoided
certain types of mortgages and particular issuers as the home-
loan market got dicier, he said in an interview. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We made informed decisions based on the underwriting
criteria at the time and felt we were working toward our
investors' best interests," he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lucido left TCW in December to become executive vice
president of DoubleLine Capital LP, a Los Angeles investment
firm founded by his former boss, Jeffrey Gundlach. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maiden Lane III &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erin Freeman, a spokeswoman for TCW, said her firm bought
only collateral for Davis Square III that met the guidelines and
didn't allow Goldman Sachs to dictate what to buy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"TCW has managed these assets prudently and in the best
interests of investors," Freeman said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By December 2008, more than 170 AIG-insured pieces of CDOs,
including parts of Davis Square III, had been taken over by a
U.S. taxpayer-funded asset pool called Maiden Lane III after the
street where the Federal Reserve Bank of New York is located. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman Sachs and TCW's parent, Paris-based Societe
Generale SA, were paid the most before and after the New York
Fed reimbursed AIG's customers in full. Societe Generale got
$16.5 billion, more than any other firm. Goldman Sachs was
second with $14 billion. Together they accounted for almost half
of the payouts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New York-based Goldman Sachs was the biggest underwriter of
CDOs taken over by Maiden Lane III. TCW managed about twice as
many CDO assets that ended up in Maiden Lane III as anyone else,
according to the AIG list and data compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teen Bodybuilder &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among other overseers of AIG-guaranteed CDOs were Ellington
Management Group LLC's Michael Vranos, a former teen Mr.
Connecticut bodybuilder who ran the top-ranked mortgage-bond
underwriter in the early 1990s, and Michael Barnes, whose
Tricadia Capital Management LLC is so secretive that, when asked
to discuss CDO reinvestment, said, "We as a policy do not
comment on anything." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was the thing about CDOs, too. They were secretive.
Prospectuses ran hundreds of pages yet often failed to detail a
single purchase. What assets they held couldn't be seen
publicly. And they gave banks the chance to repackage risky
securities and market them as safe investments, at the same time
allowing firms to bet that mortgages would fail. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CDO Tranches &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CDOs are investment pools made up of anything that provides
a flow of cash. They can contain loans to companies used in
leveraged buyouts or securities backed by commercial and
residential mortgages, auto loans, credit-card receivables, even
pieces of other CDOs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Underwriters such as Goldman Sachs split CDOs into classes,
or tranches, categorizing them by how likely they were to
continue paying. The biggest group, called the senior classes,
accounted for 93 percent of Davis Square III and got top ratings
from Moody's, according to a September 2004 Fitch Ratings
analysis. In exchange for being first under the waterfall of
payments, senior-class investors received less interest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calyon, a unit of Paris-based Credit Agricole SA, bought
most of the senior portion of the CDO, which was insured by AIG. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investors in a smaller tier, known as the mezzanine, were
paid a higher rate because they got money only after the senior
investors did. The "mezz" pieces made up a little more than 6
percent of Davis Square III and received lower credit ratings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Equity Stakes &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tiniest slice, less than 1 percent in the case of Davis
Square III, was made up of what's called equity, which wasn't
rated by credit companies. Equity investors were paid only after
everyone else. They received a higher return while the going was
good because they took the most risk and were the first ones
wiped out if borrowers quit paying their mortgages. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Lucido said he didn't own a stake in Davis Square
III, he said he did have his own money riding on the equity
pieces of some CDOs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman Sachs did own an equity stake in Davis Square III,
according to Michael DuVally, a spokesman for the firm, who
declined to say how much it was. Even so, the bank didn't try to
influence TCW's investment decisions, DuVally said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn't have to. TCW was promised 20 percent of what was
left over after equity investors got 10 percent returns,
according to a Goldman Sachs sales pitch to potential equity
investors dated September 2004. That was on top of its fee of
0.10 percent of the CDO's assets, according to the prospectus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trickle Down &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such fees gave managers incentive to move riskier assets
into CDOs because the higher returns they produced were likelier
to trickle down to equity investors. That was especially true in
2006 and early 2007 when projected earnings on safer securities
were dwindling, said Andrey Krakovsky, chief investment officer
at New York-based asset manager Tacticus Capital LLC. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As existing collateral shrank because of mortgage
prepayments, bond maturities and pay-downs, buying safer
securities meant "equity investors would have gotten hammered
because there wouldn't have been enough cash flow for them,"
Krakovsky said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He said managers often owned equity pieces of CDOs and
earned fees linked to their returns. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Howard Hill, a former Babson Capital Management LLC
executive who helped start securitization-related departments at
four banks, said CDO managers had little choice but to reinvest
in what he called "crappier '06, '07 production'' because
older, better-quality securities weren't available. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abacus Slice &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Underwriting standards deteriorated in those years.
Cumulative loan losses as a percentage of original balances are
expected to be 18.7 percent for subprime mortgages underlying
2005 bonds, 38.4 percent for 2006 bonds and 48.1 percent for
2007 securitizations, according to Moody's. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''The managers tried their best to be able to keep the
thing alive and make money," Hill said. "The rules were
written by the underwriters, weren't they?" &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of Lucido's earliest purchases for Davis Square III was
a $12 million slice of Abacus 2004-1, a CDO created by Goldman
Sachs in July 2004 and filled with credit-default swaps,
according to the prospectus. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The swaps were side bets that paid off if an investment
failed. Goldman Sachs or its customers were essentially using
Abacus as a way to short, or bet against, certain mortgage
bonds. They would sell the swaps as an investment to customers
who took the other side of the bet, believing the mortgage bonds
would keep paying. CDOs made up of these side bets and not the
actual mortgages were called synthetic CDOs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman Sachs &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By 2007, Goldman Sachs had moved so many securities into
Abacus 2004-1 that much of the collateral didn't exist when the
CDO was created, according to data compiled by Moody's. While
AIG insured parts of Abacus deals, Goldman Sachs didn't change
the collateral in the pieces AIG insured, DuVally said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other swaps that Goldman Sachs used to bet against subprime
mortgages were contained in the $7 million bond that Lucido
bought in January 2007, according to the prospectus. The
purchase was made a month after Gundlach, TCW's chief investment
officer, told Barron's it was "silly optimism" to think
housing prices had bottomed out. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bond was known as GSCSF 2006-3GA C after its manager,
New York-based GSC Group, whose chief executive officer, Alfred
C. Eckert III, was a former Goldman Sachs executive. It paid
0.90 percentage point more than another subprime-backed bond
issued the same month with the same rating, according to data
compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Toxic' Resecuritizations &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It offered a higher return because it was a
resecuritization, a repackaging of securities that bankers used
to "shuffle the deck to hide the bad ace," according to Ann
Rutledge, founding principal of RR Consulting, a structured-
finance adviser in New York. The bond was rated A2 by Moody's,
the firm's sixth-highest rating. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asset managers typically bought resecuritizations because
of their credit ratings and didn't bother to examine the
thousands of mortgages that made up each of the hundreds of
bonds in the CDO, according to Rutledge, co-author of "The
Analysis of Structured Securities," published in 2003 by Oxford
University Press. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Resecuritization has always been toxic," Rutledge said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between May 2005 and May 2007, Davis Square III's ownership
of pieces of other CDOs rose to 11 percent of its total assets
from 8.5 percent, according to data compiled by Moody's. Over
the same period its credit ratings on investments drifted about
a quarter of a grade lower, the data show. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Deals Go Bad' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"A lot of managers and equity investors were looking for
ways to make sure these deals cash-flowed," said James
Frischling, president of NewOak Capital LLC, a New York
investment and advisory firm, and former head of CDO groups at
two European banks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"That really does explain why seasoned deals go bad," he
said, referring to CDOs that have been around a while. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time TCW bought the GSC bond for Davis Square
III, it purchased a $5 million bundle of Alt-A home loans
underwritten by Goldman Sachs. Alt-A mortgages were available to
borrowers who didn't show proof of income. That security, GSAA
2007-1 M2, also quit paying, according to Moody's. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In February and March 2007, after London-based HSBC
Holdings Plc, Europe's biggest bank, announced it was setting
aside more money to cover losses on U.S. subprime mortgages,
Lucido's team bought $29.7 million of subprime bonds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"It's not that we're arrogant, or that we've got a lot of
hubris," Lucido told the Los Angeles Times in March 2007, "but
we think we've got the position and the talent in place to be
able to analyze and manage through this period." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonded Blues Band &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of TCW's March 2007 purchases, consisting of loans
originated by Option One Mortgage Corp., then a unit of HR
Block Inc., quit paying by the end of October 2008. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between April and May 2007, TCW bought another $48 million
of securities for Davis Square III, including three bundles of
Alt-A mortgages underwritten by New York-based Morgan Stanley.
Two of those bonds have stopped paying. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The asset manager also bought a subprime-mortgage-backed
bond called HASC 2007-HE2 2A4, underwritten by HSBC. It was
rated Aaa by Moody's, its top ranking. As of the end of January,
67 percent of the borrowers of mortgages backing the bond were
at least two months late with payments, according to data
compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Unfortunately, things deteriorated in an industry way
that went beyond even our worst range of forecasts," said
Lucido, who's on the dean's executive board at New York
University's Stern School of Business and who performed with
other mortgage-securities executives in the Bonded Blues Band in
the 1990s. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stockton CDO &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In June and July 2007, while two Bear Stearns Cos. hedge
funds unraveled as a result of subprime-linked investments,
Lucido's team bought a $10 million piece of another mostly
subprime-mortgage CDO, Stockton CDO Ltd., underwritten by
Brussels-based Fortis Securities LLC. Moody's gave it a top
rating. It failed within a year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As central banks around the world made emergency loans to
financial firms in August 2007 to thaw a freeze in lending
triggered by the failure of subprime mortgages, TCW continued to
buy bonds backed by risky loans. From July 30 to Oct. 24, it
purchased about $50 million of such bonds, according to Moody's. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Between May 2005 and November 2008, when the New York Fed
agreed to buy pieces of Davis Square III, TCW put in about $400
million of assets originated after 2004 that weren't guaranteed
by government-backed companies such as Freddie Mac. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Apples to Oranges' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While TCW was adding bonds made up of risky loans, its
biggest mutual fund took a more ambivalent approach. TCW Total
Return Bond Fund shrank its mortgage holdings not guaranteed by
government-sponsored firms to 15.9 percent in July 2007 from
18.8 percent three months earlier, according to company filings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As early as August 2006, Gundlach was preparing to act on
his prediction that U.S. home prices would continue their slide.
He announced that TCW was putting together a $1.5 billion fund
to invest in bad mortgages. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gundlach wouldn't comment on Davis Square III and referred
questions to Lucido, who said he was hindered from talking
because he no longer had access to TCW's files. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freeman, the TCW spokeswoman, said the bond fund, which
beat 99 percent of competitors over the past five years, catered
to individual investors and had different investment objectives
than Davis Square III. Any comparison is "apples to oranges,"
she said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She praised TCW's performance in managing Davis Square III. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Through the worst credit environment in our lifetimes,
this CDO is still performing," she said. "It's still paying
interest to investors, and it hasn't had any event of default,
which is a credit to TCW's skill in security selection." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'High Default Risk' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CDO's maturity date is 2039, so any declaration of
success is premature, said Rutledge of RR Consulting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"A man who jumps off a 100-story building can pass the
98th floor and say, 'So far, so good,'" she said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Davis Square III continues to deteriorate as more U.S.
mortgage borrowers quit paying their monthly bills. Fitch
Ratings in February 2009 downgraded the safest class of Davis
Square III to CCC, meaning it's a "high default risk." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than $16 billion of CDOs managed by TCW have
defaulted, been liquidated or stopped paying some investors,
according to RBS Securities Inc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TCW now finds itself defending Gundlach's team at the same
time it's suing him for having "no understanding or respect for
the obligations of a fiduciary," according to a complaint filed
Jan. 7 in Los Angeles Superior Court. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sex Toys &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the suit, TCW accuses Gundlach and three other employees
of stealing data on 24,000 clients and prospects, as well as
proprietary trading information, to start their own firm. Lucido
wasn't named in the TCW complaint. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TCW also said in its complaint that Gundlach, a former
company director, kept marijuana and "12 sexual devices, 34
hardcore pornographic magazines, 17 hardcore sexually explicit
DVDs and 19 hardcore sexually explicit videocassettes" in his
two offices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gundlach, now CEO of DoubleLine, denied the allegations
that he stole client data or used proprietary information. He
countersued in February, claiming TCW owed him as much as $1.25
billion in compensation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the drugs, porn and sex toys, Gundlach said in an
interview with Bloomberg Markets in January that they were
relics from a closed chapter in his life being used by TCW to
damage his reputation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"It's ancient stuff, like a box in an attic," he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ellington, Duke &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A dispute over replacement collateral landed in New York
Supreme Court in 2008. Hamburg-based HSH Nordbank AG, the
world's biggest shipping financier, said in a complaint that UBS
AG had been "deliberately selecting inferior quality" assets
for a synthetic CDO called North Street 2002-4. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doug Morris, a spokesman for Zurich-based UBS, declined to
comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ellington Management, the asset-management firm founded by
Vranos in Old Greenwich, Connecticut, was another manager that
replaced collateral in CDOs insured by AIG. The firm bought
$11.5 million of bonds backed by mortgages originated by Irvine,
California-based New Century Financial Corp. at least two months
after the subprime lender declared bankruptcy in April 2007,
placing them in a CDO called Duke Funding VII. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About $3.4 billion of the CDOs that ended up in Maiden Lane
III were managed by Ellington. Their value had fallen by $1.9
billion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve Bruce, a spokesman for the firm, declined to comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tricadia Capital &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tricadia Capital, the asset-management affiliate of New
York-based Mariner Investment Group, also managed CDOs 
containing collateral that didn't exist when they were created.
One was TABS 2005-4, which bundled mostly subprime mortgages and
was underwritten by Morgan Stanley in January 2006. AIG
guaranteed $248.8 million of the CDO, which lost almost three-
quarters of its value by the time it was bought by the New York
Fed for Maiden Lane III. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tricadia told investors it might bet against bonds it put
into CDOs -- even ones in which it owned equity stakes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In AIG's Dec. 5, 2007, presentation, Cassano said the
Financial Products unit had conducted "a highly selective
review" of investment managers and their incentives and didn't
expect to make any payments on the insurance it wrote on the
senior classes of subprime CDOs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We are highly confident that we will have no realized
losses on these portfolios during the life of these
portfolios," Cassano said. "Vintages within the subprime
sector are key, and we do not have a lot of exposure in our
portfolio to the '06 and '07 subprime issuance.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AIG underestimated the repercussions caused by asset
managers trading collateral after CDOs were issued, said Gene
Phillips, director of PF2 Securities Evaluations, an advisory
firm in New York. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''As it turns out, the ramifications were quite drastic,''
Phillips said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporters on this story:
Bob Ivry in New York at 
bivry@bloomberg.net;
Jody Shenn in New York at 
jshenn@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Susan Decker" date="Apr 01, 2010  8:17 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-04-01/microsoft-sues-datel-for-infringing-patents-on-xbox-360-video-controllers.html"><headline>Microsoft Sues Datel for Infringing Patents on Xbox 360 Video Controllers</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Corp., the world's biggest
software maker, sued Datel Design  Development Ltd., claiming
the U.K. company is infringing design patents for controllers
used with the Xbox 360 video-game system. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a lawsuit filed in federal court in Seattle today,
Microsoft is seeking damages and a court order that would halt
sales of Datel's TurboFire and WildFire controllers. Microsoft
also sued Datel in the U.K. and filed a complaint with the U.S.
International Trade Commission in Washington, seeking to block
U.S. imports of the controllers made in China. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game controllers provide "a firepower advantage that
can make all the difference," Datel, based in Staffordshire,
England, said on its Web site. They can turn a single-shot
pistol in the "Call of Duty" into "lethal, fully automatic
weapons that can empty a clip on an enemy in a second." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The patent complaints "appear retaliatory," Datel lawyer
Martin Glick said in a telephone interview. "They said the
controller would interfere with the fair play of games and then
they licensed a controller that did exactly that." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glick, of Howard Rice in San Francisco, said he hadn't
reviewed the complaints so couldn't comment on the specific
allegations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfair Advantage &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has said in court filings that the accessories
give their users an unfair advantage in multiplayer gaming. The
TurboFire and WildFire controllers copy unique designs protected
by six U.S. patents, Microsoft said in the complaint. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 74 million Xbox 360 game controllers have been
sold worldwide since 2005, including about 40 million in the
U.S., according to the ITC complaint. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The designs of the WildFire Controller are the same or
substantially the same to the eye of the ordinary observer as
the ornamental designs claimed in the Microsoft patents,"
Microsoft said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Datel also sells a memory card that it says is four times
as powerful as the one that Microsoft offers. In October,
Microsoft deployed what it called a "dashboard update" that
disabled Datel's memory cards. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Datel filed an antitrust lawsuit in November against
Microsoft, claiming the Redmond, Washington-based company seeks
to monopolize the markets for multiplayer online gaming systems
and for accessories not sold directly with the Xbox. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Memory Cards &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glick, who called the update a "downgrade," said it was
designed to shut down Datel because the memory cards were
driving down the price of Microsoft's. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has asked that the antitrust suit be dismissed,
saying Datel isn't legally entitled to sell "accessories that
open the door for cheating that harms the Xbox 360 ecosystem." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft said in the ITC complaint it has sold or licensed
more than $7 billion worth of products that use the patents at
issue in the case. "U.S. sales and licensing revenue for Xbox
360 gamepads alone account for more than $100 million," the
company said in the complaint. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The success of Microsoft's Xbox 360 has not gone
unnoticed by others who seek to gain from Microsoft's
investment, creativity and goodwill," the company said in the
filing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new case is Microsoft Corp. v. Datel Design and
Development Ltd., 10cv562, U.S. District Court for the Western
District of Washington (Seattle). The antitrust case is Datel
Holdings Ltd. v. Microsoft Corp., 09cv5535, U.S. District Court
for the Northern District of California (San Francisco). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ITC case is In the Matter of Game Controllers,
Complaint No. 2722, U.S. International Trade Commission
(Washington). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Susan Decker in Washington at 
sdecker1@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Peter Burrows" date="Apr 01, 2010  7:10 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-04-01/microsoft-won-t-make-office-for-ipad-says-google-is-no-software-threat.html"><headline>Microsoft Won't Make Office for IPad, Says Google Is No Software Threat</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Corp., the world's largest
software maker, has no plans to make a version of its Office
suite of programs to run on Apple Inc.'s iPad, said Stephen
Elop, president of Microsoft's business division. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elop said the company would take a "wait and see"
approach to tailoring software for the iPad, which goes on sale
on April 3. He also said Google Inc. hasn't made any headway
against Microsoft in the business software market. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We haven't heard anything about Google making inroads
against Office, because they're not," Elop said today in an
interview. Office includes word-processing, spreadsheet and
other business-productivity programs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft will begin selling the next version of the
product, dubbed Office 2010, on May 12. The debut comes as
Google and other Web companies are pushing alternatives that
cost less or are even free. Office brings in about 90 percent of
the revenue of Elop's division, which is the company's largest
and one of its most profitable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The version of Office 2010 that goes on sale on May 12 is
designed for businesses. A version for consumers will be
available by late June. By then, the company also will introduce
stripped-down versions of Word and the spreadsheet program Excel
that are accessible free over the Web. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demand looks promising, particularly from companies, and 6
million people have downloaded a prerelease "beta" version of
the product, Elop said. That's twice as many as downloaded the
beta version of Office 2007, the last upgrade. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of those beta users polled by Microsoft, 80 percent said
they would recommend Office 2010 to friends, and 90 percent said
the software made them more productive, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cloud Computing &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Elop said corporate buyers are less interested in
discussing Google and other competitors and more concerned about
whether to move to new "cloud"-based versions of Microsoft
software. Customers who choose this route don't run the software
on their own computers, instead paying a monthly fee to
Microsoft to deliver it over the Internet from the company's
massive data centers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We never say never, but we have no current plans" to
develop a version of Office for the Apple iPad, Elop said. Last
year Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft said it would create a
version to work on Nokia Oyj's smartphones, since millions of
Office users already own those devices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An iPad edition of Office would likely be built by a unit
within Microsoft's consumer business that creates versions of
Office that work with Apple's Macintosh personal computers.
Kristen Woody, a spokesman for that unit, says it "doesn't have
anything to share at this time." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft fell 13 cents to $29.16 at 4 p.m. New York time
on the Nasdaq Stock Market. After gaining 57 percent last year,
the shares have slipped 4.3 percent in 2010. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporters on this story:
Peter Burrows in San Francisco at 
pburrows@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Susan Decker" date="Apr 01, 2010  1:15 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-04-01/microsoft-loss-in-i4i-patent-case-will-stand-appeals-court-in-u-s-says.html"><headline>Microsoft Loss in I4i Patent Case Will Stand, Appeals Court in U.S. Says</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Corp. failed in its bid to
have a U.S. appeals court take a second look at a patent-
infringement case that forced it to change its popular Word
software and resulted in a damage award that's grown to more
than $290 million. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit today
rejected a request that the Dec. 22 ruling won by closely held
I4i LP of Toronto be heard by the full 12-member court. The
decision was announced in a notice on the court's Web site. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has called the case the largest patent-
infringement verdict ever upheld on appeal. The request for a
rehearing centered on testimony related to damages, whether
Microsoft's infringement was intentional, and whether Microsoft
should have been forced to remove what the company called an
"obscure functionality" or stop selling Word. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I4i's invention is related to customizing extensible markup
language, or XML, a way of encoding data to exchange information
among programs. Microsoft issued an update to Word to comply
with the court order. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Word is part of Microsoft's Office software, used by more
than 500 million people. Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft is
testing Office 2010 with customers. The completed version is
scheduled to be released by June. The unit that sells Office is
Microsoft's biggest, with $18.9 billion in sales in the year
ended June 30. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;XML is a common way of encoding data, and nothing in the
order prevented Microsoft from continuing to offer that feature
in Word, or for allowing customized XML when it's used in plain
text. The disputed feature is one used by large companies to add
special data to Word files, such as information in forms
submitted by customers. I4i's patent was issued in 1998. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is I4i LP v. Microsoft Corp., 2009-1504, U.S.
Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit (Washington). The
lower-court case is I4i LP v. Microsoft Corp., 07-cv-113, U.S.
District Court, Eastern District of Texas (Tyler). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Susan Decker in Washington at 
sdecker1@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Pat Wechsler and Jeff Kearns" date="Apr 01, 2010  1:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-04-01/mylan-stock-options-surge-on-market-speculation-of-pfizer-buyout-offer.html"><headline>Mylan Stock Options Surge on Market Speculation of Pfizer Buyout Offer</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Mylan Inc. climbed to the highest
intraday level in four years and trading of bullish options
surged the most since July on speculation that the biggest U.S.
maker of generic drugs may be acquired by Pfizer Inc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stock rose 1.7 percent to $23.10 at 11:56 a.m. in Nasdaq
Stock Market composite trading, and earlier reached $23.33. More
than 20,000 calls to buy the stock changed hands, nine times the
four-week average. The most-active contracts were April $24
calls, which jumped fivefold to 25 cents for the biggest gain
among all Mylan options. This month's options expire April 16.
Mylan hasn't closed above $24 for more than three years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"What we've heard is there's chatter about a potential
takeover, but that's every day with some of these health-care
companies," said Les Funtleyder, a health-care analyst with
Miller Tabak  Co. in New York, in a telephone interview today.
"Because a couple companies have made a play for Ratiopharm and
Teva won, the thinking is that Pfizer may be interested in
another generic company because they were one of the bidders." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael Laffin, a spokesman for Canonsburg, Pennsylvania-
based Mylan, didn't immediately return a call for comment. Pfizer
spokeswoman Joan Campion said "As a matter of practice, we don't
comment on market rumors or speculation." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer, the world's largest drugmaker, has announced 25
acquisitions in the last five years with an average value of
$4.89 billion including debt, according to Bloomberg data. Pfizer
typically paid a premium of 79 percent above the average closing
price of the target companies in the 20 days before the deals
were announced, according to Bloomberg data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teva Pharmaceutical Industries Ltd. agreed on March 18 to
buy Ratiopharm GmbH for 3.63 billion euros ($5 billion), ending a
nine-month battle for Germany's second-biggest maker of generic
medicines. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Petah Tikva, Israel-based Teva beat Pfizer and Actavis Group
hf, which also competed in the auction, according to people with
knowledge of the situation who declined to be named before a deal
was announced. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporters on this story:
Pat Wechsler in New York at 
pwechsler@bloomberg.net;
Jeff Kearns in New York at 
jkearns3@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Apr 01, 2010 10:06 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-04-01/jpmorgan-s-dimon-regrets-using-government-guarantee-program-to-issue-debt.html"><headline>JPMorgan's Dimon Regrets Using Government Guarantee Program to Issue Debt</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;JPMorgan Chase  Co. Chief Executive
Officer Jamie Dimon said he regrets using the Federal Deposit
Insurance Corp.'s guarantee program to issue $40 billion in
unsecured debt during the height of the financial crisis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We didn't need it," Dimon, 54, said in his annual letter
to shareholders, which was released yesterday. "And it just
added to the argument that all banks had been bailed out and
fueled the anger directed toward banks." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dimon said the New York-based company was "highly
criticized" for issuing debt backed by the FDIC and for
accepting $25 billion from the Troubled Asset Relief Program.
The company repaid all TARP funds in June, stopped using the
FDIC's program last April and shunned participation in other
federal programs "to avoid the stigma," he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JPMorgan, which ranks second behind Bank of America Corp.
in deposits and assets among U.S. lenders, remained profitable
through the crisis with combined net income of $17.3 billion in
the last two years. The company issued $20.8 billion in FDIC-
guaranteed long-term debt in 2008, and $19.7 billion in 2009. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"It was not a question of access or need," Dimon said of
the FDIC program, whose government backing helped keep interest
rates low. "The markets always were open to us, but the program
did save us money." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FDIC Program &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FDIC spokesman Andrew Gray declined to comment. About 6,500
eligible institutions opted out of the Temporary Liquidity
Guarantee Program. More than 80 banks and thrifts used the
program to issue debt, about $305.4 billion of which was still
outstanding as of Feb. 28, according to FDIC data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dimon apologized for what he said were the bank's mistakes.
He said the two biggest were lowering mortgage underwriting
standards and making too many leveraged loans that "may have
contributed to the financial crisis." At the same time, he
claimed some credit for helping to stabilize markets through
JPMorgan's purchases of Bear Stearns Cos. and Washington Mutual. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also sought to deflect some of the public anger toward
financial companies and to correct the perception that all banks
would have failed if the federal government hadn't intervened. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We should acknowledge that the worst offenders among
financial companies no longer are in existence," Dimon said.
"And while it is true that some of the surviving banks would
not, or might not, have survived, not all banks would have
failed." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dimon, who took over as CEO in 2005, said his "No. 1
priority" this year is to find his successor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internal Candidates &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Poor CEO succession has destroyed many a company," Dimon
said, adding that the board believes there are several strong
internal candidates that could "do my job today." He said
JPMorgan will continue rotating senior staff across the business
to ensure they could smoothly take over the company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company also intends to expand retail banking, which
accounted for $97 million of JPMorgan's $11.7 billion in net
income last year. Dimon said the bank will add 2,700 personal
bankers, 400 investment sales representatives and 120 more
branches this year, even though consumer lending lost $3.8
billion in 2009. The bank plans to ramp up its branch expansion
in California and Florida over the next two years, building on
its acquisition of Washington Mutual, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporters on this story:
Dawn Kopecki in Washington at 
dkopecki@bloomberg.com. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Elizabeth Amon" date="Apr 01, 2010  9:03 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-04-01/bear-stearns-ubs-ryanair-honda-pfizer-schwab-lehman-in-court-news.html"><headline>Bear Stearns, UBS, Ryanair, Honda, Pfizer, Schwab, Lehman in Court News</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;After months of litigation and
political scrutiny, the Federal Reserve yesterday ended a policy
of secrecy over its Bear Stearns Cos. bailout. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a 4:30 p.m. announcement in a week of congressional
recess and religious holidays, the central bank released details
of securities bought to aid Bear Stearns's takeover by JPMorgan
Chase  Co. Bloomberg News sued the Fed for that information. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fed's vehicle known as Maiden Lane LLC has securities
backed by mortgages from lenders including Washington Mutual
Inc. and Countrywide Financial Corp., loans that were made with
limited borrower documentation. More than $1 billion of them are
backed by "jumbo" mortgages written by Thornburg Mortgage
Inc., which now carry the lowest investment-grade rating. Jumbo
loans were larger than government-sponsored mortgage buyers such
as Fannie Mae could finance -- $417,000 at the time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The Fed absorbed that risk on its balance sheet and is
now seen to be holding problematic, legacy assets," said
Vincent Reinhart, a resident scholar at the American Enterprise
Institute in Washington who was the central bank's monetary-
affairs director from 2001 to 2007. "There is both an
impairment to its balance sheet and its reputation." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bear Stearns deal marked a turning point in the
financial crisis for the Fed. By putting taxpayers at risk in
financing the rescue, the central bank was engaging in fiscal
policy, normally the domain of Congress and the U.S. Treasury,
said Marvin Goodfriend, a former Richmond Fed policy adviser who
is now an economist at Carnegie Mellon University in Pittsburgh. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bear Stearns assets include bets against the credit of
bond insurers such as MBIA Inc., Financial Security Assurance
Holdings Ltd. and a unit of Ambac Financial Group, putting the
Fed in the position of wagering companies will stop paying their
debts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chairman Ben S. Bernanke defended the Bear Stearns deal as
a rescue of the financial system. He said in a speech at the
Kansas City Fed's annual Jackson Hole, Wyoming conference in
August 2008 that a sudden Bear Stearns failure would have caused
a "vicious circle of forced selling" and increased volatility. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The Federal Reserve recognizes the importance of
transparency to its financial stability efforts and will
continue to review disclosure practices with the goal of making
additional information publicly available when possible," the
New York Fed said in yesterday's statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Suits &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FSA Charges Seven in Insider-Trading Ring at Banks' Print Shop &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seven people were charged in relation to an insider-trading
ring that U.K. prosecutors said made about 2.5 million pounds
($3.8 million) in illegal profits with data leaked from London
printers used by UBS AG and JPMorgan Chase  Co.'s Cazenove
unit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paresh Shah, Truptesh Patel, Pardip Saini, Neten Shah,
Bijal Shah, Mitesh Shah and Ali Mustafa were charged with
insider trading, Britain's Financial Services Authority said in
a statement yesterday. The 13 counts of insider trading relate
to dealing in shares of 12 companies, including Misys Plc and
Enodis Plc, from 2006 to 2008, the FSA said. A warrant for the
arrest of an eighth suspect was issued, it said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saini "fully disputes the allegations made by the FSA and
welcomes the chance to demonstrate his innocence in the clearest
possible terms," his lawyer, Giles Bark-Jones, said yesterday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patel's lawyer, John Williams at London-based Bankside Law,
said his client "vigorously denies all the charges." Neten
Shah also denied the charges in a statement issued by his
lawyer, Gerallt Owen of Crowell  Moring LLP. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paresh Shah's lawyer, Michael Potts at London-based Byrne 
Partners, declined to comment beyond confirming his client was
charged in the case. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mitesh Shah has also been charged in relation to money
laundering through spread bets. Stephen Smith, Mitesh Shah's
attorney at Roiter Zucker, didn't return a call. Steven Bird, a
lawyer for Bijal Shah, also didn't return a call. Hickman Rose,
the law firm representing Mustafa, didn't answer a call after
office hours. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The defendants have all been released on bail and are to
appear in court on April 14, according to the FSA's statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The regulator brought the charges after a 21-month
investigation. Around 35 FSA lawyers and investigators probed
130 individual trading accounts and took more than 250 witness
statements, the agency said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eight people were originally arrested as part of the Saturn
investigation in July 2008. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UBS said at the time of the arrests that a junior member of
its support staff had been detained, and JPMorgan Cazenove said
a former sub-contractor was involved in the investigation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard Morton, a spokesman for Zurich-based UBS, and David
Wells, a spokesman for New York-based JPMorgan, both declined to
comment. Neither of the banks is accused of any wrongdoing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HVB Is Sued by Ex-Client Saperstein Over Tax Shelters &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bayerische Hypo-und Vereinsbank AG was sued by a former
client of the German bank, David Saperstein, who claims he was
defrauded into investing in an illegal tax shelter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saperstein filed his lawsuit yesterday in Manhattan federal
court against units of HVB, the German banking division of
UniCredit SpA, Italy's biggest bank. Saperstein and Cregg
Ventures LLC, of which Saperstein is sole member, say they lost
more than $37 million by investing in 2000 in a shelter known as
BLIPS, which was sold by accounting firm KPMG LLP, HVB, and
adviser Presidio Advisory Services. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal "was to defraud people like Saperstein into
participating in BLIPS and other strategies in order to generate
fees and other income," Saperstein says in his complaint,
adding that he was never told the underlying transactions were
fraudulent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ralf Horak, a spokesman for HVB, didn't have an immediate
comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Cregg Ventures v. HVB, 10-cv-2818, U.S.
District Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ryanair Sues France for 110 Million Euros Over Air France Aid &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ryanair Holdings Plc, Europe's largest discount airline,
sued the French government for about 110 million euros ($148
million), saying it improperly aided Air France-KLM Group. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ryanair filed the complaint with Paris's administrative
tribunal on March 11 and expects hearings next year, the Dublin-
based carrier said in an e-mailed statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;France provided "unlawful state aid to Air France in the
form of reductions in airport charges on domestic routes,"
according to Ryanair. "Air France benefited from these
deductions for decades before the European Commission"
prohibited the discounts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process for granting slots at French airports "is
transparent and public, any company can bid," Air France
spokesman Nicolas Petteau said in a phone interview. "Ryanair
is never a candidate as there is no money to be made." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ryanair and Air France, Europe's largest airline, have been
in a dispute about state support each airline claims the other
received. Paris-based Air France filed a complaint with the
European Commission in November over aid to the Irish airline,
Petteau said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"There is no basis for Air France's false claims that
Ryanair receives subsidies or state aid," Ryanair Chief
Executive Officer Michael O'Leary said March 30 in a statement.
A prior European Court decision in favor of Ryanair "dooms Air
France's claims to failure." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A spokeswoman for French Transportation Minister Dominique
Bussereau didn't return a call requesting comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more new suits news from yesterday, click here. For copies
of recent civil complaints, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lawsuits/Pretrial &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KPMG, Ernst  Young Win Dismissal of Madoff Lawsuit &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Auditors KPMG LLP and Ernst  Young LLP won dismissal of a
fraud lawsuit brought against them by investors in Tremont Group
Holdings Inc., which invested with convicted money manager
Bernard Madoff. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;U.S. District Judge Thomas Griesa in Manhattan March 30
tossed out a complaint against the auditors of Tremont funds
brought by Tremont investors. He said the investors failed to
allege enough facts in their complaint to show that the auditors
had the intent to "deceive, manipulate or defraud." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The investors sought to hold the auditors liable for
failing to detect Madoff's massive fraud, not notifying them of
risks associated with Madoff's funds, and not complying with
professional auditing standards that would have uncovered
Madoff's Ponzi scheme. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The auditors were never engaged to audit Madoff's
businesses or to issue an opinion of the financial statements"
of Madoff's firm, Griesa wrote in a 19-page opinion. The
investors "do not allege that the auditors were aware of any
facts indicative of Madoff's fraud that they consciously
disregarded." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is In Re Tremont Securities Law, 09-md-2052, U.S.
District Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rajaratnam Seeks to Keep Wiretap Papers Confidential &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Galleon Group LLC founder Raj Rajaratnam, who faces
criminal insider-trading charges, asked a judge to keep
confidential wiretap applications that prosecutors say may be
disclosed to the public. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rajaratnam yesterday filed court papers opposing the
government's earlier request for a court procedure that will
address "the public's right to access wiretap applications,"
which investigators probing him had confidentially submitted to
a judge. Rajaratnam says "no such right exists" and that the
applications should remain secret until a judge decides whether
the wiretaps may be used at his trial. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Defense attorney John Dowd says Rajaratnam's right to try
to exclude the wiretaps from his trial "would be irreversibly
compromised if the government were permitted to publicize the
same evidence in public filings" before a judge rules. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The government's insider-trading case is based on testimony
from cooperating witnesses and wiretaps of Rajaratnam and
others. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standard  Poor's, Moody's Win Dismissal of Bond Suit &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McGraw-Hill Cos.'s Standard  Poor's and Moody's Corp. won
dismissal of a lawsuit claiming they defrauded investors who
relied on their ratings before buying $63 billion of investment-
grade mortgage-backed securities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;U.S. District Judge Jed Rakoff in New York also dismissed
some claims yesterday against JPMorgan Chase  Co., Bank of
America Corp.'s Merrill Lynch and ABN Amro Bank NV, a unit of
Royal Bank of Scotland Plc, in a lawsuit filed by institutional
investors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The complaint claimed banks and rating companies made
untrue statements and omissions in registration statements and
prospectuses for 84 offerings sold as safe. In a two-page order,
Rakoff tossed claims against McGraw-Hill, Moody's, Merrill Lynch
Mortgage Lending Inc., First Franklin Financial Corp. and
Credit-Based Asset Servicing  Securitization LLC, or C-Bass.
Rakoff said he will explain his reasons in a written opinion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The likely reason to come from Judge Rakoff's opinion
will be important to many defendants in financial crisis
litigation," said C-Bass attorney Jamie Wareham of Paul
Hastings Janofsky  Walker LLP. "The disclosures were adequate
and the market knew of the risks associated with subprime
products." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Samuel Rudman, a lawyer for Iron Workers Local No. 25
Pension Fund, one of the investors who sued; Floyd Abrams, a
lawyer for New York-based McGraw-Hill; Steve Weiss, a spokesman
for McGraw-Hill; and Michael Adler, a spokesman for New York-
based Moody's, didn't return calls. William Halldin, a Merrill
spokesman, didn't have an immediate comment. Brian Marchiony, a
spokesman for New York-based JPMorgan, declined to comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Iron Workers Local No. 25 Pension Fund v.
Credit-Based Asset Servicing  Securitization LLC, 08-cv-10841,
U.S. District Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abramovich Loses Bid to Dismiss Berezovsky U.K. Suit &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roman Abramovich, the Russian billionaire who owns Chelsea
Football Club in London, lost a bid to dismiss a U.K. lawsuit
filed by former business partner Boris Berezovsky over shares of
OAO Sibneft. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Justice Anthony Colman yesterday refused an application
from Abramovich's lawyers to throw out the $3.5 billion lawsuit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Berezovsky claims in the suit that Abramovich used
"threats and intimidation" to force him to sell Sibneft shares
at a fraction of their value. Berezovsky sold the stake to
Abramovich for $1.3 billion between 2001 and 2003. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Mann, a spokesman in Moscow for Millhouse LLC, the
company that manages Abramovich's assets, said that the ruling
is preliminary and came after a "substantial re-working of the
original claim by" Berezovsky. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The judge expressed serious doubts about the claim's
ultimate chances of success," Mann said in the e-mailed
statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Berezovsky claims in the lawsuit he lost as much as $4
billion on the deal. In 2005, Abramovich sold Sibneft to state-
run OAO Gazprom for $13.1 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"As the judge recognized, the overall effect of Mr.
Abramovich's applications has been to delay matters
considerably," Berezovsky said in an e-mailed statement. "The
proceedings will now move forward without further delay and I am
looking forward to the opportunity of proving my case." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Berezovsky v. Abramovich, 07-942, High Court of
Justice, Queen's Bench Division, Commercial Court. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honda Must Defend Suit Over Air Conditioner Defects &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honda Motor Co.'s U.S. unit must defend a lawsuit claiming
it knowingly sold cars with defective air conditioners and
refused to pay for repair costs, a judge ruled. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;U.S. District Judge Katharine Hayden said yesterday in
Newark, New Jersey, that motorist Jon Alin may proceed with
claims that American Honda Motor Co. engaged in fraud and
breached warranties over Hondas and Acuras sold or leased
between 2000 and 2009. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hayden granted Honda's request to dismiss two of the eight
counts in the complaint, filed under the Class Action Fairness
Act. Alin claims that after he leased a 2006 Odyssey, the air
conditioner stopped working and a Honda technician told him he
was "experiencing a common problem," according to the opinion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris Martin, a spokesman for Tokyo-based Honda, declined
to comment on the litigation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Jon Alin v. American Honda Motor Co., 08-cv-
4825, U.S. District Court, District of New Jersey (Newark). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more lawsuits news from yesterday, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trials/Appeals &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer's Neurontin Prompted Man's Suicide, Jury Told &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer Inc.'s Neurontin epilepsy drug prompted a
Massachusetts man who took the medicine as a painkiller to
commit suicide, a lawyer told a Boston jury at the opening of a
trial. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Officials of Pfizer's Warner-Lambert unit knew Neurontin
posed a suicide risk in some users and failed to disclose it to
patients and doctors, an attorney for Hartley Shearer's family
told the federal court jury yesterday. The case is the first to
come to trial since another Boston jury last week ordered Pfizer
to pay more than $140 million in damages over the drug. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shearer, who battled depression after suffering a stroke,
killed himself after being prescribed Neurontin to manage his
pain, Ron Rosenkranz, a lawyer for Shearer's wife and son, said
in opening statements in the trial of their lawsuit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The one thing that finally cast him over the edge was
Neurontin," Rosenkranz told jurors in the trial before U.S.
District Judge William G. Young. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer faces more than 1,000 lawsuits accusing the New
York-based drugmaker of illegally promoted Neurontin for
unapproved uses and helping to cause some users' suicides. The
company's Warner-Lambert subsidiary pleaded guilty to criminal
charges brought by the U.S. Justice Department in connection
with the marketing claims and paid $430 million. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer lawyers noted in their opening statements that
Shearer argued with his wife just before he shot himself to
death with a .357 Magnum handgun. They said he fought depression
for most of his life and was distraught over the lasting effects
of his 1999 stroke. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Shearer case is Shearer v. Pfizer Inc., 07-cv-11428-
PBS, U.S. District Court, District of Massachusetts (Boston). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more trial and appeals news from yesterday, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verdicts/Settlements &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merrill, Deutsche Bank End Suit Over Heaton Hire Raid &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merrill Lynch  Co., a unit of Bank of America Corp., has
discontinued a lawsuit filed against Deutsche Bank AG that
alleged Germany's biggest bank hired Eric Heaton in a raid of
bankers from its financial-institutions group. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merrill, in a complaint filed in New York State Supreme
Court in Manhattan last year, claimed Heaton, the company's
former treasurer who resigned in February of 2009, failed to
give the required six months' notice. Merrill also claimed
Deutsche Bank violated non-compete agreements prohibiting him
from working for another bank until after Jan. 31, 2010. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both sides filed a "stipulation of discontinuance" with
New York State Supreme Court Justice Eileen Bransten, court
records show. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The matter is resolved between the parties," Peter
Altieri, a lawyer for Deutsch Bank and Heaton said in a
telephone interview. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jack Gordon, a lawyer for Merrill, confirmed the case had
been discontinued and declined further comment. John Gallagher,
a spokesman for Deutsche Bank, declined comment on the case. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"A confidential agreement has been reached between the
parties," Shirley Norton, a spokeswoman for Bank of America,
said in a telephone interview. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deutsche Bank "raided" the Merrill unit's senior bankers,
including Heaton and 11 others, "many months in advance" and
all 12 quit on the same day, Merrill said in the complaint. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Eric Heaton was named as a defendant in the suit, the
11 other former Merrill bankers hired by Deutsche Bank weren't
named as defendants in the lawsuit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is: Merrill Lynch v. Deutsche Bank, 600661/2009,
filed in New York State Supreme Court (Manhattan). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schwab Broke Adviser Law in Handling Fund, Judge Says &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charles Schwab Corp. violated an investment adviser law
when it failed to get shareholder approval before investing more
than 25 percent of the assets in its YieldPlus mutual fund in
mortgage-backed securities, a federal judge ruled. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;U.S. District Judge William H. Alsup in San Francisco said
March 30 that Schwab's fund managers in 2006 "reversed field
and repudiated" the fund's policy of limiting investments in
any one industry to 25 percent. Doing so required a shareholder
vote under the Investment Company Act of 1940, Alsup wrote. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Steve W. Berman, an attorney for Schwab investors suing the
company, said the ruling affects California YieldPlus
shareholders who bought into the fund before 2006. Their damages
are estimated at as much as $157 million, he said. Alsup didn't
rule on claims by a nationwide group of investors with damages
estimated at $802 million, Berman said in a telephone interview. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"While we strongly disagree with the judge's ruling on
this issue, he has only ruled on one of several claims, and
there are many more issues to be decided," a Schwab spokesman,
David Weiskopf, said in an e-mail. "We look forward to putting
all the facts, evidence and expert testimony to the jury and
presenting a strong case at trial." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is In Re Charles Schwab Corp. Securities
Litigation, 08-cv-01510, U.S. District Court, Northern District
of California (San Francisco). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lyondell to Pay $162 Million to End U.S. Claims &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lyondell Chemical Co. will pay $162 million to U.S.
agencies to settle about $5.5 billion in environmental claims
against the bankrupt chemical maker. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The settlement of a dispute in Lyondell's bankruptcy case
was filed March 30 in Manhattan. About $108 million will be
placed in a trust funding the cleanup of properties in seven
states. The remaining $54 million will be paid to the U.S. to
settle debts relating to toxic-waste sites in five states. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lyondell's total contribution will be $250 million,
including money spent on winding down and its own cleanup
projects, company spokesman David Harpole said. The money will
be put into two trusts as outlined in the company's plan to
reorganize, which already has court approval. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is In re Lyondell Chemical Co., 09-10023, U.S.
Bankruptcy Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more verdict and settlement news from yesterday, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Litigation Departments &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weil Gotshal Bills Lehman $1,000 an Hour for Lawyers &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc.'s lead bankruptcy law firm,
Weil Gotshal  Manges LLP, bills the defunct investment bank as
much as $1,000 an hour for its top lawyers' time overseas, and
$990 an hour for U.S. lawyers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rates were set Jan. 1, Weil Gotshal said in court
papers filed March 30 in U.S. Bankruptcy Court in Manhattan. The
New York-based law firm collected $157.5 million from Lehman
during a 17-month period ending last month, according to a
regulatory filing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lehman filed the biggest U.S. bankruptcy in September 2008
with assets of $639 billion. Creditors include UBS AG, the New
York Giants and Abu Dhabi Investment Authority as well as
individuals who hold Lehman bonds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weil Gotshal partner Harvey Miller, Lehman's main lawyer,
didn't respond to an e-mail seeking comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is In re Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc., 08- 13555,
U.S. Bankruptcy Court, Southern District of New York
(Manhattan). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more litigation department news from yesterday, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the Docket &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barrick Gold Suit May Cut Nevada Mine Output by Half &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barrick Gold Corp.'s plan to double production at a Nevada
gold mine complex this year by digging out an additional $625
million in deposits may turn on a judge's decision in an
environmental suit by American Indian tribes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Canadian company forecast a production increase of
562,000 ounces with the addition this year of the Cortez Hills
mine, located 2.5 miles (4 kilometers) from an older Nevada
installation which produced 518,000 ounces last year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The state's Shoshone tribes claim the U.S. Bureau of Land
Management didn't fully evaluate the environmental impact of the
mine expansion before approving it. They sued in 2008 to stop
the new operation, about 200 miles east of Reno, and are seeking
a court order forbidding production until a trial is held. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such an injunction "would hit their share price," said
Patrick Chidley, a gold-mining analyst at Barnard Jacobs Mellet
USA LLC in Stamford, Connecticut. The judge overseeing the case
hasn't said when he will rule. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cortez deposits, near Mount Tenabo, a Western Shoshone
sacred site, contain about 14.1 million ounces of gold, Barrick
said in its annual report. The projected 2010 increase in
deposits would be worth about $625 million. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two sides are preparing for a trial whose date probably
will be set near the end of May, Flynn said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is South Fork Band Council of Western Shoshone of
Nevada v. U.S. Department of the Interior, 08-cv-00616, U.S.
District Court, District of Nevada (Reno); the appeals court
case is South Fork Band Council of Western Shoshone of Nevada v.
U.S. Department of the Interior, 09-15230, U.S. Court of Appeals
for the Ninth Circuit (San Francisco). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Elizabeth Amon in Brooklyn, New York, at 
eamon2@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Craig Torres, Bob Ivry and Scott Lanman" date="Apr 01, 2010  2:34 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-04-01/fed-reveals-bear-stearns-assets-swallowed-to-get-jpmorgan-to-rescue-firm.html"><headline>Fed Reveals Bear Stearns Assets Swallowed to Get JPMorgan to Rescue Firm</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;After months of litigation and
political scrutiny, the Federal Reserve yesterday ended a policy
of secrecy over its Bear Stearns Cos. bailout. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a 4:30 p.m. announcement in a week of congressional
recess and religious holidays, the central bank released details
of securities bought to aid Bear Stearns's takeover by JPMorgan
Chase  Co. Bloomberg News sued the Fed for that information. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fed's vehicle known as Maiden Lane LLC has securities
backed by mortgages from lenders including Washington Mutual Inc.
and Countrywide Financial Corp., loans that were made with
limited borrower documentation. More than $1 billion of them are
backed by "jumbo" mortgages written by Thornburg Mortgage Inc.,
which now carry the lowest investment-grade rating. Jumbo loans
were larger than government-sponsored mortgage buyers such as
Fannie Mae could finance -- $417,000 at the time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The Fed absorbed that risk on its balance sheet and is
now seen to be holding problematic, legacy assets," said
Vincent Reinhart, a resident scholar at the American Enterprise
Institute in Washington who was the central bank's monetary-
affairs director from 2001 to 2007. "There is both an
impairment to its balance sheet and its reputation." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bear Stearns deal marked a turning point in the
financial crisis for the Fed. By putting taxpayers at risk in
financing the rescue, the central bank was engaging in fiscal
policy, normally the domain of Congress and the U.S. Treasury,
said Marvin Goodfriend, a former Richmond Fed policy adviser who
is now an economist at Carnegie Mellon University in Pittsburgh. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Panic' Cause &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Lack of clarity on the boundary between responsibilities
of the Fed and of the Congress as much as anything else created
panic in the fall of 2008," Goodfriend said. "That created a
situation in which what had been a serious recession became
something near a Great Depression." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Central bankers also created moral hazard, or a perception
for investors that any financial firm bigger than Bear Stearns
wouldn't be allowed to fail, said David Kotok, chief investment
officer at Cumberland Advisors Inc. in Vineland, New Jersey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Policy makers' resolve was tested months later by runs
against the largest financial companies. Lehman Brothers
Holdings Inc. collapsed into bankruptcy in September 2008. The
ensuing panic caused the Fed to take even more emergency
measures to push liquidity into markets and institutions. It
rescued American International Group Inc. from collapse and
allowed Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and Morgan Stanley to convert
into bank holding companies, putting them under greater
oversight by the central bank. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early Failure &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Letting somebody fail early would have been a better
choice," Kotok said. "You would have ratcheted moral hazard
lower and Lehman wouldn't have been so severe." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bear Stearns assets include bets against the credit of
bond insurers such as MBIA Inc., Financial Security Assurance
Holdings Ltd. and a unit of Ambac Financial Group, putting the
Fed in the position of wagering companies will stop paying their
debts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fed disclosed that some of Maiden Lane's assets were
portions of commercial loans for hotels, including Short Hills
Hilton LLC in New Jersey, Hilton Hawaiian Village LLC in Hawaii,
and Hilton of Malaysia LLC, in addition to securities backed by
residential mortgages. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than a year after Washington Mutual, the largest U.S.
savings and loan, was purchased by JPMorgan Chase in a
distressed sale arranged by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corp.,
the home loans that helped bring down the Seattle-based thrift
live on in the Maiden Lane portfolio. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lending Standards &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, 94 percent of the mortgages in one security,
called WAMU 06-A13 2XPPP, required limited documentation from
borrowers, meaning the lender often didn't ask customers for
proof of their incomes. Almost 10 percent of the borrowers whose
mortgages make up the security have been foreclosed on, and
almost a quarter are more than two months late with payments,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The portfolio also includes $618.9 million of securities
backed by Countrywide, mortgages now rated CCC, eight levels
below investment grade. All the underlying loans are adjustable-
rate mortgages, with about 88 percent requiring only limited
borrower documentation, according to Bloomberg data. About 33.6
percent of the borrowers are at least 60 days late. Countrywide
is now part of Charlotte, North Carolina-based Bank of America
Corp. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CDO Holdings &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maiden Lane has $19.5 million of securities from a series
of collateralized debt obligations called Tropic CDO that are
backed by trust preferred securities of community banks and
thrifts. CDOs are investment pools made up of a variety of
assets that provide a flow of cash. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trust preferred securities, or TruPS, have characteristics
of debt and equity and their interest payments are tax-
deductible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The securities created by Bear Stearns are rated C, one
level above default, by Moody's Investors Service and Fitch
Ratings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CDO securities have tumbled in value as banks are failing
at the fastest rate in 17 years, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. The average price of TruPS CDO debt of this rating is
pennies on the dollar, according to Citigroup Inc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The trust of the taxpayer was abused," said Janet
Tavakoli, president of Chicago-based financial consulting firm
Tavakoli Structured Finance Inc. CDOs rated CCC and lower "have
a high likelihood of default," she said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bernanke Defense &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chairman Ben S. Bernanke defended the Bear Stearns deal as
a rescue of the financial system. He said in a speech at the
Kansas City Fed's annual Jackson Hole, Wyoming conference in
August 2008 that a sudden Bear Stearns failure would have caused
a "vicious circle of forced selling" and increased volatility. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The broader economy could hardly have remained immune from
such severe financial disruptions," Bernanke said in the speech.
The Fed chief, who took office in 2006 and began his second term
as chairman this year, also has repeatedly called for an
overhaul of financial regulations that would allow authorities
to take over a failing financial institution and oversee an
orderly unwinding of its positions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bernanke said last year that nothing made him "more angry"
than the AIG case, blaming the insurer for making "irresponsible
bets" and a lack of regulatory oversight for the debacle.
Officials "had no choice but to try and stabilize the system" by
aiding the firm in September 2008, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday's release by the Fed, through its New York
regional bank, also identified securities acquired in the
bailout of AIG held in vehicles known as Maiden Lane II and III. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Market Value &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assets in Maiden Lane II totaled $34.8 billion, according
to the Fed, which set their current market value in its weekly
balance sheet at $15.3 billion. That means Maiden Lane II assets
are worth 44 cents on the dollar, or 44 percent of their face
value, according to the Fed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maiden Lane III, which has $56 billion of assets at face
value, is worth $22.1 billion, or 39 cents on the dollar,
according to the Fed's weekly balance sheet. A similar
calculation for the Bear Stearns portfolio couldn't be made
because of outstanding derivatives trades. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The Federal Reserve recognizes the importance of
transparency to its financial stability efforts and will
continue to review disclosure practices with the goal of making
additional information publicly available when possible," the
New York Fed said in yesterday's statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deal With Chase &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The central bank said it reached agreement on "issues of
confidentiality" for the assets with JPMorgan Chase, which
bought Bear Stearns in 2008, and AIG. New York-based JPMorgan
and AIG would incur the first losses on the portfolios. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joe Evangelisti, a spokesman for JPMorgan, and Mark Herr, a
spokesman for AIG, declined to comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In April 2008, Bloomberg News requested records under the
federal Freedom of Information Act from the Fed's Board of
Governors related to JPMorgan's acquisition of Bear Stearns. The
central bank responded that records retained by the New York Fed
"were proprietary records of the Reserve Bank, and not Board
records subject" to the request, court records show. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bloomberg filed suit in November 2008 in U.S. District
Court in New York, challenging the Fed's denial, as well as the
denial of a separate request made in May 2008, seeking records
of four other emergency lending programs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The district court held that the Fed should release
documents related to those four programs, and should search
documents held by the New York regional bank to determine
whether any of them should be considered records of the board of
governors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Court of Appeals on March 19 upheld the district
court's ruling on the lending programs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Representative Darrell Issa of California said in a
statement that yesterday's disclosure may "signal a new
willingness to cooperate with Congress as we investigate how
these bailout deals were structured and what the decision making
process entailed." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Craig Torres in Washington at 
ctorres3@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Oliver Biggadike and Cordell Eddings" date="Apr 01, 2010  1:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-04-01/u-s-swap-spreads-to-turn-positive-as-borrowing-slows-goldman-sachs-says.html"><headline>U.S. Swap Spreads to Turn Positive as Borrowing Slows, Goldman Sachs Says</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Spreads between 10-year interest-
rate swaps and Treasury yields will turn positive by June as
U.S. borrowing slows, ending a period of "unusually high"
government and corporate issuance, according to Goldman Sachs
Group Inc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The difference fell below zero on March 23 for the first
time, reducing demand for U.S. debt as the government sold a
record-tying $118 billion in notes that week. The spread will
probably be about five basis points, or 0.05 percentage point,
over the next three months, Goldman Sachs said, citing its model
that takes into account government and corporate borrowing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Government issuance and corporate swap activity have been
unusually high," Michael Vaknin, a fixed-income analyst at the
firm in London, wrote in a report yesterday. "The latter is
almost entirely responsible for the most recent leg down in swap
spreads." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corporate sales of investment-grade bonds almost doubled to
$94 billion last month through March 30 from $53.4 billion the
previous month, increasing demand from companies to convert
their fixed-interest payments to floating rates via the swap
market. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Government issuance is scheduled to fall to $268 billion in
net marketable debt in the second quarter from $392 billion
offered during the first three months of the year, the U.S.
Treasury said in a Feb. 1 statement on its Web site. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman's model predicts 10-year swap spreads rising to 20
basis points by the middle of 2011, Vaknin wrote, from minus 1
basis point yesterday. The New York-based investment bank
forecasts the spread staying close to zero for "several
months" and increasing to 10 basis points by the end of the
year, the report said without explaining the difference between
the model's result and the forecasts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporters on this story:
Oliver Biggadike in New York at 
obiggadike@bloomberg.net;
Cordell Eddings in New York at 
ceddings@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Condon" date="Apr 01, 2010  1:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-04-01/blackrock-s-fink-snubs-socialized-money-fund-proposal-backed-by-goldman.html"><headline>BlackRock's Fink Opposes `Socialized' Money-Fund Plan Backed by Goldman</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Laurence Fink, chief executive
officer of BlackRock Inc., stands alone among the biggest U.S.
money-market fund providers in publicly opposing a proposed
safety net for the industry that manages $3 trillion for
investors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fink, who has said companies should set aside their own
capital cushions, won't back an industry plan to spread risk
among money-market mutual fund firms in its current form,
according to Brian Beades, a spokesman for BlackRock, the
world's biggest asset manager. JPMorgan Chase  Co., Federated
Investors Inc., Vanguard Group Inc., Goldman Sachs Group Inc.
and four other firms have backed the plan, which was proposed by
the industry's trade group last month. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Larry Fink has invested a lot of time and energy on an
alternative idea, talking about capital reserves," Peter Crane,
president of research firm Crane Data LLC in Westborough,
Massachusetts, said in a telephone interview. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BlackRock's dissent may make it harder for money funds to
head off regulatory changes that could include an end to the
stable $1 net asset value that made the funds a popular
alternative to bank accounts. Regulators and firms are seeking
ways to prevent a repeat of the run on money funds that followed
the 2008 collapse of the Reserve Primary Fund. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emergency Facility &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The industry has planned since last year for an emergency-
liquidity facility that would protect money-market mutual funds
that invest in corporate debt, stepping in to buy securities at
face value in the event of a financial crisis. Funds that can
purchase corporate debt, known as prime funds, held $1.67
trillion as of March 30. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paul Schott Stevens, president of the Investment Company
Institute, outlined the Washington-based trade group's plan in a
March 15 speech, two months after Fink voiced qualms about the
concept of an industry fund in a conference call with analysts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fink, in the Jan. 27 conference call, said companies should
establish their own reserves. He said BlackRock was open to an
industry liquidity bank in "some form," as long as credit risk
falls to individual fund managers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The last thing we are looking for is an industry fund,"
he said, according to a transcript of the call. "The last thing
we need to do is socialize money-market risk." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Socialized' Risk &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The New York-based company, which managed $202.6 billion in
money-fund assets as of Feb. 28, is the fifth-largest U.S.
provider, according to Crane Data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We favor those solutions that allow fund managers access
to incremental liquidity but that do not have the effect of
spreading risk among industry participants," Beades said. He
declined to comment on what changes might make the ICI's plan
acceptable to BlackRock. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the ICI plan, fees collected from money-market funds
would be used to capitalize a state-chartered bank or trust. The
facility would purchase holdings at face value from funds during
a crisis. That could prevent a fund fielding heavy redemption
requests from taking losses because it is forced to sell healthy
holdings at a discount. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a bank, it would also have access to the U.S. Federal
Reserve's discount lending window, according to the ICI, making
taxpayers the ultimate backer of money-market funds' liquidity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We absolutely support this," Christopher Donahue, chief
executive officer of Pittsburgh-based Federated, said in a
telephone interview. "We've spent a lot of work and time on
coming up with this position and the industry would be well
served by having everyone in it." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JPMorgan, Goldman &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donahue said he endorses making participation in the plan
mandatory for all money-market mutual funds eligible to purchase
corporate debt. Federated is the third-largest provider, with a
total of $247.8 billion in money funds, Crane data show. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We are strong supporters," Kristen Chambers, a JPMorgan
spokeswoman, said in an e-mail. JPMorgan in New York manages
$313.6 billion, behind only Boston-based Fidelity Investment's
$496.7 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spokesmen for Bank of New York Mellon Corp.'s Dreyfus unit,
the fourth-biggest provider; Vanguard in Valley Forge,
Pennsylvania; New York's Goldman Sachs; Baltimore-based Legg
Mason Inc.; and Charles Schwab Corp. and Wells Fargo  Co. in
San Francisco said their companies supported the basic proposal
as outlined by Stevens. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David D. Sylvester, head of money-market funds at Wells
Fargo, said the company would want to see more details before
deciding whether it would participate in the plan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geithner's Review &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vincent Loporchio, a spokesman for Fidelity, declined to
comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Money-market funds have come under scrutiny since the
September 2008 failure of the $62.5 billion Reserve Primary
Fund, when its value fell below the standard $1 a share. The
mass investor redemptions that ensued helped freeze global
credit markets by shutting down the biggest collective buyer of
short-term corporate debt. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission in January
imposed liquidity restrictions on money funds, tightened
maturity limits, raised credit standards and gave fund boards
more flexibility in dealing with depositor runs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Treasury Secretary Timothy Geithner, as head of the
President's Working Group on Financial Markets, a government
advisory group, is considering more significant changes opposed
by the funds industry and business groups, including the U.S.
Chamber of Commerce. The advisory panel is preparing a report
that examines, among other proposals, requiring funds to abandon
the $1 share price for a floating value. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;'Good Stuff' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proposed money fund safety net, which aims to fend off
such a change, wouldn't offer insurance against losses on
securities that default, like the bonds issued by Lehman
Brothers Holdings Inc. when the bank went bankrupt, causing
Reserve Primary to collapse. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donahue said the bank could minimize its credit risk by
carefully limiting what it would purchase from funds in an
emergency. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I want to stress this is a liquidity facility and not a
credit facility," Donahue said. The bank should "only take the
good stuff." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bank would still take on credit risk whenever it bought
holdings out of a fund, he said. Any default after such a sale
could cause losses for the bank. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Donahue compared the idea to the government's Commercial
Paper Funding Facility, started in 2008 to buy short-term
unsecured and asset-backed bonds during the credit crisis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How much the liquidity facility would charge participants,
how it would select assets eligible for purchase and other
details haven't been determined, according to several of the
companies contacted. The plan, once completed, would need
approval from banking regulators including the U.S. Federal
Reserve. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Christopher Condon in Boston at 
ccondon4@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Jef Feeley and Janelle Lawrence" date="Apr 02, 2010  2:06 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-04-02/pfizer-agrees-to-first-settlement-of-a-neurontin-related-suicide-lawsuit.html"><headline>Pfizer Agrees to First Settlement of a Neurontin-Related Suicide Lawsuit</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer Inc. agreed to pay about
$400,000 to settle a lawsuit mid-trial that blamed its Neurontin
epilepsy medicine for helping cause a Massachusetts man&#8217;s
suicide, two people familiar with the accord said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#8217;s the first settlement over a Neurontin-related suicide
claim. Pfizer, the world&#8217;s largest drugmaker, agreed yesterday
to resolve allegations by Hartley Shearer&#8217;s family in Boston
federal court that its Warner-Lambert unit knew the drug posed a
suicide risk and failed to disclose it to patients and doctors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Pfizer agreed to settle the case for less than its
defense costs remaining in this case,&#8221; said Rob Haralson, a
spokesman for New York-based Pfizer. &#8220;Pfizer maintains that it
has strong defenses to each of plaintiff&#8217;s claims.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer faces more than 1,000 lawsuits accusing it of
illegally promoting Neurontin for unapproved uses and helping to
cause some users&#8217; suicides. The settlement comes a week after
another Boston jury ordered Pfizer to pay more than $140 million
in damages to an insurer over the drug. Pfizer has denied any
wrongdoing in connection with its handling of Neurontin. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its Warner-Lambert subsidiary pleaded guilty in 2004 to
criminal charges filed by the Justice Department in connection
with allegations it illegally marketed Neurontin and paid a
$430 million fine. Pfizer acquired Warner-Lambert in 2000. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For 16 Months &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 57-year-old Shearer, a part-time lecturer at Williams
College in Williamstown, Massachusetts, took Neurontin for 16
months before killing himself, according to court filings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shearer&#8217;s family contends his doctor wasn&#8217;t aware of
Neurontin&#8217;s suicide risk when he prescribed the drug to help
deal with pain generated by a 1999 stroke. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer argued Shearer battled depression for most of his
life and was taking a dozen prescription drugs, including an
anti-depressant, when he shot himself to death with a .357
Magnum handgun in 2002. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The drugmaker&#8217;s lawyers also noted Shearer argued with his
wife the day he killed himself and left a suicide note saying it
was the last time she would &#8220;leave me powerless.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ron Rosenkranz, a lawyer for the Shearers, declined to
comment when contacted yesterday evening. Today, he told U.S.
District Judge William G. Young at a hearing in Boston that the
&#8220;amount of the settlement, while confidential, is substantially
less than the amount reported.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8216;An Iffy Case&#8217; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;This is an iffy case,&#8221; Young told jurors after
announcing the accord. &#8220;This is why they settled. Iffy on both
sides.&#8221; The people who said the settlement was about $400,000
declined to be identified because the terms are confidential. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By prescribing Neurontin as a painkiller, Shearer&#8217;s doctor
was recommending a so-called off-label use of the drug. While
doctors may prescribe a medicine for uses not approved by the
U.S. Food and Drug Administration, companies are barred from
promoting products for off-label uses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Charles King, a former Harvard University business
professor, told jurors in the Shearer case yesterday that
Warner-Lambert officials used illegal off-label marketing
tactics to turn Neurontin into a &#8220;blockbuster drug.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;They took a drug that was expected to generate
$500 million over its lifetime and turned it into a drug that
sold roughly $10 billion,&#8221; said King, an economist who
testified for the Shearers as an expert on pharmaceutical-
industry marketing practices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Shearer suit was the second product-liability case over
Neurontin to go to trial. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In July 2009, a Peabody, Massachusetts, family dropped its
suit over the suicide of a woman who was taking the drug. The
family was in the second day of trial in federal court in Boston
when it decided to dismiss the case. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Misleading Doctors &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another jury in Boston&#8217;s federal court March 25 said Pfizer
must pay Kaiser Foundation Health Plan Inc. $47.4 million for
misleading doctors on whether Neurontin was effective for
illnesses such as migraines and bipolar disorder. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The jury found the drugmaker violated the federal Racketeer
Influenced and Corrupt Organizations Act, or RICO, and
California&#8217;s Unfair Competition Law. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Oakland, California-based insurer is a unit of Kaiser
Permanente, the largest U.S. nonprofit health maintenance
organization. Under RICO, the amount of actual damages will be
tripled to $142.1 million. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer bought Warner-Lambert for $120 billion in 2000 and
Pharmacia for $54 billion three years later. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$430 Million Settlement &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with the $430 million settlement of allegations over
Neurontin, Pfizer also paid $2.3 billion in October 2009 to
resolve U.S. Justice Department allegations it illegally
marketed the painkiller Bextra and three other drugs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;When you acquire Warner-Lambert you get Neurontin, and
when you acquire Pharmacia you get Bextra, and some of these
problems came with the acquisitions,&#8221; Jeffrey Kindler, Pfizer&#8217;s
chief executive officer told the New York Times March 31. &#8220;It
doesn&#8217;t change the facts or our responsibility for them.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Shearer case is Shearer v. Pfizer Inc., 07-cv-11428-
PBS, U.S. District Court, District of Massachusetts (Boston). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporters on this story:
Jef Feeley in Wilmington, Delaware at  jfeeley@bloomberg.net and;
Janelle Lawrence in Boston at jmlawrence@mac.com. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Denis Maternovsky" date="Apr 02, 2010  7:54 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-04-02/russia-s-mispriced-stocks-to-bonds-may-outperform-peers-jpmorgan-says.html"><headline>Russia's `Mispriced' Stocks to Bonds May Outperform Peers, JPMorgan Says</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Equities in Russia are "mispriced"
relative to the country's bonds more than in any emerging
market, and the nation's stocks are set to outperform debt and
other share indexes as earnings grow, said JPMorgan Chase  Co. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Russian stocks have underperformed bonds in the first
quarter, with the Micex Index of stocks gaining 5.9 percent in
the first three months of 2010, compared with a return of 19
percent on sovereign bonds, according to JPMorgan's EMBI+ Index. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The implied yield risk premium, or ERP, for Russian stocks
compared with bonds has increased to an "abnormally high" 594
basis points, Alex Kantarovich, a JPMorgan Moscow-based analyst,
wrote in a research note today. The ERP for Turkey is 498 basis
points, versus 140 for Brazil, according to the report. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rally in debt has been boosted by the diminishing
likelihood of government default, whereas stocks have lagged
behind as the economic cycle takes longer for recovery to show
up in earnings, according to the bank. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Approaching the start of the tightening cycle, bonds may
hit the wall, while the strengthening earnings trend should
start supporting stocks more and more," Kantarovich wrote. The
re-allocation from bonds to stocks may help Russian shares
outperform peers, according to the note. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dollar-denominated RTS Index added 0.2 percent to
1,611.64 by 2:11 p.m. in Moscow, heading for its highest close
since Sept. 2, 2008. The ruble-denominated Micex Index fell 0.3
percent to 1,475.17, trimming its weekly gain to 4.2 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The yield on Russia's benchmark dollar bonds due in 2030
fell 5 basis points to 4.971 percent, a weekly low. Bond prices
move inversely to yields. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Denis Maternovsky in Moscow at 
dmaternovsky@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Katherine Burton" date="Apr 02, 2010  1:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-04-02/goldman-fund-buys-into-ganek-s-4-billion-hedge-fund.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Buyout Firm Acquires Stake in Ganek's $4 Billion Hedge Fund</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;A Goldman Sachs Group Inc. buyout
firm bought a minority stake in David Ganek&#8217;s $4 billion Level
Global Investors LP, adding a hedge fund that can bet on rising
as well as falling stock prices globally. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman Sachs&#8217;s Petershill Fund Offshore LP, a $1 billion
fund set up to buy minority stakes in hedge funds, won&#8217;t get any
management or investment decision-making role with the
acquisition, according to a letter Ganek sent to clients
yesterday. New York-based Level Global said it will use the
proceeds from the sale to help attract and retain top talent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;We believe this investment by Petershill is an important
milestone in the continued development of Level Global&#8217;s
investment management platform as an institutional quality
business,&#8221; Ganek and managing partner Anthony Chiasson said in
the letter, a copy of which was obtained by Bloomberg News. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ganek, an alumnus of Steven A. Cohen&#8217;s Stamford,
Connecticut-based SAC Capital Advisors LLC, founded Level Global
in 2003. The firm has 64 employees, of which 25 are investment
professionals. Petershill has interests in three London-based
funds, Capula Investment Management LLP, Winton Capital
Management Ltd. and Trafalgar Asset Managers Ltd., as well as in
Greenwich, Connecticut-based Shumway Capital Partners LLC. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andy Merrill, a spokesman for Level Global, and Melissa
Daly, a spokeswoman for New York-based Goldman Sachs, declined
to comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hedge funds are loosely regulated private partnerships that
can bet on rising or falling prices of any securities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Related News and Information:
Today&#8217;s top fund stories: TOP FUND GO
Hedge-fund rankings: WHF GO
Hedge-fund flows: TNI HEDGE FLOWS GO
Most-read hedge fund news: MNI HEDGE GO
Hedge Fund Home Page: HFND GO
Hedge Fund Holdings: FLNG GO &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki and Ian Katz" date="Apr 02, 2010  1:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-04-02/jpmorgan-goldman-sachs-resist-nuns-proposal-for-greater-swaps-disclosure.html"><headline>JPMorgan, Goldman Sachs Resist Nuns' Proposal for Greater Swaps Disclosure</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and
JPMorgan Chase  Co. aren't doing "God's work" when it comes
to derivatives, according to investor groups of nuns and
priests. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shareholders will vote starting this month on proposals
sponsored by the Sisters of Charity of Saint Elizabeth and 14
other religious organizations, asking Goldman Sachs, JPMorgan,
Citigroup Inc. and Bank of America Corp. to give more
information on the collateral used in their derivatives trading. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's the first time the four banks, among the largest U.S.
swaps dealers, will put to a nonbinding vote a call to explain
how collateral of derivatives customers is used and to keep it
from other accounts. Congress is considering bills that would
require more derivatives deals be processed through
clearinghouses, privately owned third parties that guarantee
transactions and keep track of collateral and margin. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The use of these instruments, if they're not disclosed by
the dealers and the information made available, by their very
nature can contribute to systemic risk," said Father Seamus
Finn, a director with the Missionary Oblates of Mary Immaculate
in Washington, D.C., one of the co-sponsors of the resolutions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission, in February
and March decisions, backed the religious groups' bid to put the
proposal up for a vote by shareholders of JPMorgan, Bank of
America and Citigroup. New York-based Goldman Sachs, the most
profitable firm in Wall Street history, agreed separately to add
the resolution to its proxy statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman Sachs Chief Executive Officer Lloyd Blankfein's
remark in November that he's a banker doing "God's work" was
an "inscrutable comment," Finn said. "He was part of a group
of very senior people from the banking sector who appeared to
have been advised by their PR people to acknowledge their
mistakes but more pointedly assert the uprightness of their
intentions." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ICCR &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blankfein, 55, didn't mean for the remark to be taken
seriously, Goldman Sachs spokesman Lucas van Praag said that
month. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The religious groups, members of the Interfaith Center on
Corporate Responsibility, hold shares in the four banks ranging
from 100 at Goldman Sachs to 63,977 at Citigroup. The New York-
based ICCR's 300 members include money managers for various
religious organizations, including Jewish and Buddhist, and
pension and mutual funds that oversee $100 billion in assets,
according to the organization's Web site. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"The immorality of the financial crisis is rooted in the
fact that these derivatives contracts weren't based on creating
value and didn't create incentives for people to keep their
promises," said Laura Berry, a former large-cap portfolio
manager for Citigroup who is executive director of the ICCR,
which is coordinating the proxy votes for the religious groups. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;200 Proposals &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ICCR's members have placed 200 social and environmental
measures on proxy ballots this year, including the use of
antibiotics in animal feed at Tyson Foods Inc. and carbon
emissions at Wal-Mart Stores Inc., Berry said. The organization
filed its first shareholder resolution in 1971, pressuring
General Motors Corp. to divest from South Africa because of what
was then the country's apartheid policy of racial segregation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"They do very good work," said Charles Elson, director of
the John L. Weinberg Center for Corporate Governance at the
University of Delaware. "I don't always agree with them, but
some of the stuff they've done is quite good." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JPMorgan, Bank of America, Goldman Sachs, Citigroup and
Morgan Stanley were parties to 96 percent of the $293 trillion
in over-the-counter derivatives trades made by the top 25 U.S.
bank-holding companies as of Dec. 31, according to the Office of
the Comptroller of the Currency. The religious groups didn't
seek to place a resolution on Morgan Stanley's proxy because
none have held the bank's shares long enough, said Finn. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banks Say Reject &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The religious organizations want the four broker-dealers to
disclose internal policies on how the collateral posted by
derivatives customers is used. They're also asking the lenders
to segregate the collateral from other accounts, which would
prohibit it from being used for anything else. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We were very much concerned about where's the collateral,
is this all recorded, do we know who the second or third party
is to this, the counterparties and so on," said Sister Barbara
Aires, coordinator of corporate responsibility at the Sisters of
Charity of Saint Elizabeth, in Convent Station, New Jersey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The banks have urged shareholders in their proxy
statements to reject the proposal. JPMorgan said that
segregating assets could expose it to price volatility and
potential losses "when the firm needs to liquidate collateral
quickly upon a default." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JPMorgan spokeswoman Jennifer Zuccarelli, Goldman Sachs
spokesman Michael DuVally, Bank of America spokesman Scott
Silvestri and Citigroup spokesman Stephen Cohen declined to
comment beyond the companies' proxy statements. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Proposals focusing on specific business issues like
derivatives trading "tend not to do well" in shareholder
votes, said Elson. "They're really issues of the board. But in
this climate, you can't say anything is for sure." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporters on this story:
Dawn Kopecki in Washington at 
dkopecki@bloomberg.net;
Ian Katz in Washington at 
ikatz2@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry></news>