
<news><entry author="By Cristiane Lucchesi" date="Aug 05, 2013 11:18 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-05/goldman-loses-top-brazil-executives-as-growth-plan-halted.html"><headline>Goldman Loses Top Brazil Executives as Growth Plan Halted</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), the U.S.
bank that announced plans in April to hire 50 people in Brazil,
has reversed course after the economy expanded less than
analysts estimated and top executives left the company. </p>
<p>The outlook for the economy and equity and merger-and-acquisition deal volumes are worse than we expected, Michael DuVally, a spokesman for the New York-based bank, said in an
interview on Aug. 2. </p>
<p>Brazil''s benchmark Ibovespa index has lost 13 percent since
the start of April and more than 20 percent this year. Foreign
banks from Zurich-based UBS AG to London-based Barclays Plc have
been reducing staff in Brazil as the investment-banking business
shrinks and competition from local lenders intensifies. Merger
volume fell to a six-year low this year through July. </p>
<p>About a quarter of Goldman Sachs''s roughly 45-person Brazil
investment-banking division have left, people familiar with the
matter said, asking not to be identified because the bank hasn''t
announced the departures. Five managing directors, four from the
eight-person executive committee, are no longer at the firm, the
people said. All of the executive-committee members have been
replaced, one of the people said. </p>




Photographer: Dado Galdieri/Bloomberg

<p>
The Christ the Redeemer statue stands on top of Corcovado Mountain of Rio de Janeiro, Brazil, on July 4, 2013. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Maria Kolesnikova" date="Aug 05, 2013 11:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-05/jpmorgan-buys-ubs-s-otc-commodity-derivatives-portfolio.html"><headline>JPMorgan Buys UBS''s OTC Commodity Derivatives Portfolio</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), which said last
month it plans to get out of the business of owning and trading
physical commodities from metals to oil, bought the over-the-counter commodity derivatives portfolio of UBS AG (UBSN), which is
exiting most of its raw-materials trading. </p>
<p>The transaction includes on-exchange hedge positions and
excludes precious metals and index-based products, UBS said in
an e-mailed statement today. JPMorgan assumed market risk on the
portfolio and the two banks will work together in the coming
months with their clients to fully assign contracts for
individual trades to JPMorgan, according to the statement.
JPMorgan spokesman Patrick Burton declined to comment. </p>
<p>Banks are scaling back or exiting their commodities
operations amid regulatory scrutiny and lower profits from raw
materials. Revenue in commodities at the 10 largest investment
banks fell 25 percent in the first half of the year, analytics
company Coalition said today. </p>
<p>JPMorgan said last month that it''s considering an exit from
the business of trading physical commodities, marking a reversal
of its push into raw materials with its 2010 purchase of parts
of RBS Sempra, a joint venture between Royal Bank of Scotland
Group Plc and Sempra Energy. (SRE) UBS and JPMorgan didn''t report the
price of the transaction reported today. </p>
<p>Zurich-based UBS, Switzerland''s biggest lender, last year
decided to close its oil, base metals and agriculture trading
desks, a person with direct knowledge of the decision said Oct.
31. The bank is keeping its index-investor products and precious
metals trading. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Rachel Savage" date="Aug 05, 2013  9:16 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-05/morgan-sindall-seeks-more-lucrative-building-after-earnings-drop.html"><headline>Morgan Sindall Seeks More Lucrative Work After Earnings Drop</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Sindall Group Plc (MGNS), a U.K.
construction company that specializes in affordable housing and
urban regeneration, said it intends to gain more lucrative work
after first-half earnings declined. </p>
<p>There is more work around, so we can be more choosey,
Chief Executive Officer John Morgan said in an interview. The
reality is it''s not going to change overnight, but the work we
are winning is better-quality work. </p>
<p>Pretax profit fell 95 percent to 1 million pounds ($1.54
million) in the first six months as Morgan Sindall took a 13
million-pound charge for payments it hasn''t received on a
small number of contracts. Adjusted for the provision and
intangible amortization, the measure declined 24 percent, while
revenue rose 2 percent to 1.02 billion pounds, the London-based
company said today in a statement. </p>
<p>Morgan Sindall has struggled as it tries to reduce reliance
on government spending and increase business in urban
regeneration. European construction companies face declining
profit margins amid a lack of work, although Balfour Beatty Plc (BBY)
said in July it expects first-half U.K. losses to be recouped in
the second half. Balfour gets more than one-third of its revenue
from the U.S., while Morgan Sindall is almost entirely reliant
on the U.K. </p>
<h2>Improving Outlook </h2>
<p>The outlook for British building contracts is improving,
with the U.K. Purchasing Managers Index for construction jumping
to 57 in July from 51 in June, the highest since June 2010 and
ahead of the median estimate of 13 economists surveyed by
Bloomberg. A reading above 50 indicates expansion. </p>
<p>Morgan Sindall is doing a good job of riding the waves
of the construction market, Anthony Codling, an analyst at
Jefferies, said today in a note to clients. He reiterated a buy
recommendation on the stock. </p>
<p>The shares fell 0.6 percent to 655 pence as of 2:13 p.m. in
London, after declining as much as 7.4 percent earlier in the
day. Morgan Sindall has gained 27 percent this year, valuing the
company at 282 million pounds. </p>
<p>Market conditions remain difficult and competitive
pressures have negatively impacted operating margins and
profitability, but net debt has reduced, Codling said. The
company''s focus on cash management and contract selectivity
means that its self-help is working, he said. </p>
<p>Morgan Sindall said it had 40 million pounds in cash at the
end of the period, and average daily net debt of 32 million
pounds, compared to net debt of 12 million pounds and average
debt of 36 million pounds a year earlier. </p>
<p>It''s an absolute focus on cash, said Stephen Crummett,
Morgan Sindall''s finance director Such that it gives us the
flexibility to invest in some of the regeneration schemes. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri" date="Aug 06, 2013  6:34 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-06/disney-profit-rises-on-cable-parks-to-beat-analysts-estimates.html"><headline>Disney Net Little Changed as Lone Ranger'' Charge Looms</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS), the world''s largest
entertainment company, said third-quarter profit was little
changed amid costs to market the box-office disappointment The
Lone Ranger and shrinking revenue at ABC television. </p>
<p>Net income rose to $1.85 billion, or $1.01 a share, from
$1.83 billion, or $1.01, a year earlier, Burbank, California-based Disney said today in a statement. Profit came to $1.03 a
share excluding items, compared with the $1.01 average of 30
analysts'' estimates compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Given the number of headwinds we faced, we are very
pleased with the financial results we delivered, Chief
Financial Officer Jay Rasulo said on a call with investors. </p>
<p>Disney expects to record a loss this quarter of as much as
$190 million on The Lone Ranger, which cost $225 million to
make and has produced less in worldwide sales. The company''s
ESPN, AE and domestic children''s cable channels, along with the
popular theme parks, continue to spur growth for Disney as film
profits slide and the ABC broadcast division struggles. </p>
<p>Disney fell 1.7 percent to $65.88 in extended trading after
results came out. The stock rose 1.6 percent to $67.05 at the
close in New York and has gained 35 percent this year. </p>




Photographer: Patrick T. Fallon/Bloomberg

<p>
Guests ride "Splash Mountain" at the Walt Disney Co. Disneyland Park in Anaheim, California. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Aaron Kirchfeld" date="Aug 06, 2013  1:08 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-06/goldman-names-dibelius-and-scherrer-to-new-industrials-roles-1-.html"><headline>Goldman Names Dibelius and Scherrer to New Industrials Roles</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) named Alex Dibelius and Clare Scherrer to new leadership positions at a
unit that provides strategic and financial advice to industrial
clients. </p>
<p>Dibelius was appointed chairman of the global industrials
group and Scherrer co-head, alongside Dusty Philip, according to
an internal memo obtained by Bloomberg News, whose contents were
confirmed by the bank. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs, based in New York, is No. 3 in global
industrials deals this year, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. The bank advised on transactions including
Charterhouse Capital Partners LLP''s sale of German energy-metering business Ista International GmbH to CVC Capital
Partners Ltd. in April. </p>
<p>Scherrer, currently chief operating officer of the global
industrials group, is the third female executive to be promoted
to a management role at the investment bank this year. The
others include Kate Richdale, who was named the head of
investment-banking services in Asia, and Christina Minnis, who
last month was appointed co-head of healthcare Americas. </p>
<p>Dibelius is currently co-head of the global industrials
group and has overall responsibility for the firm''s business in
Germany, Austria, and Central and Eastern Europe, the memo says. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christine Harper" date="Aug 07, 2013  4:53 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-07/jpmorgan-s-physical-commodities-value-drops-to-11-9-billion.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Physical Commodities Value Drops to $11.9 Billion</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co.''s physical
commodity assets had a total fair value of $11.9 billion at the
end of June, according to a quarterly regulatory filing today. </p>
<p>The assets were valued at $14.3 billion in March, according
to a previous filing. New York-based JPMorgan said last month
that it plans to get out of the business of owning and trading
physical commodities ranging from metals to oil. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Harris and Margaret Cronin Fisk" date="Aug 07, 2013  4:43 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-07/jpmorgan-sued-with-goldman-in-aluminum-antitrust-case.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sued With Goldman in Aluminum Antitrust Case</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the biggest
U.S. bank, was sued with Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) and Glencore
Xstrata Plc (GLEN) over claims they restrained aluminum supplies and
drove up prices. </p>
<p>The complaint was filed by a Jacksonville, Florida, direct
purchaser, Master Screens Inc., and by individual plaintiff
Daniel Price Bart of Tallahassee, who is described in the filing
as a purchaser of beverages sold in aluminum cans. </p>
<p>The banks and Glencore are accused in the complaint filed
yesterday in federal court in Tallahassee of racketeering and
conspiring with the London Metal Exchange, hoarding aluminum in
Detroit-area warehouses and violating federal antitrust laws.
Goldman Sachs was first sued over similar claims by a Michigan
company on Aug. 1. </p>
<p>By inserting itself into a healthy industry producing
widely needed commodities, severely degrading functionality and
widely distributing costs while itself benefiting, Goldman Sachs
and JPMorgan couldn''t fit a more archetypal description of a
parasite on the markets, according to the Florida complaint. </p>
<p>There are no queues at our warehouses and we believe this
suit has no merit, Brian Marchiony, a spokesman for New York-based JPMorgan Chase, said in an e-mail. </p>
<p>We believe this suit is without merit and we intend to
vigorously contest it, Michael DuVally, a spokesman for New
York-based Goldman Sachs, said in an e-mail. We also note that
aluminum prices are down 40 percent from their peak in 2006. </p>
<h2>Warehousing Giant'' </h2>
<p>More than 1 million tons of aluminum are stored in the
Detroit warehouses, many of which are owned by Goldman Sachs,
which charges rent for the storage, according to the complaint,
while London Metal Exchange load-out rules curtail how much of
the metal leaves. </p>
<p>JPMorgan-owned Henry Bath  Son Ltd., acquired in 2010, is
described in the complaint as a metal warehousing giant. </p>
<p>The Florida plaintiffs are seeking class action, or group,
status, to represent other aluminum buyers and consumers, as
well as compensatory damages. </p>
<p>Charles Watenphul, a spokesman for Baar, Switzerland-based
commodities group Glencore, declined to comment. </p>
<p>DuVally last week said the complaint filed against Goldman
Sachs in Detroit was without merit. </p>
<p>A third lawsuit, naming as defendants Goldman Sachs and its
warehouse unit, Metro International Trade Services LLC, as
defendants, was filed yesterday in federal court in New Orleans. </p>
<p>Plaintiff River Parish Contractors Inc. of Reserve,
Louisiana, also alleges the Goldman Sachs entities inflated
aluminum prices and restrained supplies in violation of U.S.
antitrust laws. Neither London Metal Exchange nor JPMorgan are
named as defendants. </p>
<p>The Florida case is Master Screens Inc. v. Goldman Sachs
Group Inc., 13-cv-00431, U.S. District Court, Northern District
of Florida (Tallahassee). The Michigan case is Superior
Extrusion Inc. v. Goldman Sachs Group Inc., 13-cv-13315, U.S.
District Court, Eastern District of Michigan (Detroit). The
Louisiana case is River Parish Contractors Inc. v. Goldman Sachs
Group Inc., 13-cv-05267, U.S. District Court, Eastern District
of Louisiana (New Orleans). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri" date="Aug 07, 2013  4:13 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-07/disney-s-profit-stalls-as-lone-ranger-expenses-hurt-film-unit.html"><headline>Disney''s Profit Stalls as Lone Ranger'' Costs Hurt Film Unit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS), the world''s largest
entertainment company, said costs to market the box-office
disappointment The Lone Ranger and shrinking revenue at ABC
television network held back third-quarter profit. </p>
<p>Net income was little changed at $1.85 billion, or $1.01 a
share, compared with $1.83 billion, or $1.01, a year earlier,
Burbank, California-based Disney said yesterday in a statement.
Profit came to $1.03 a share excluding items, compared with the
$1.01 average of 30 analysts'' estimates compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Disney expects to record a loss of as much as $190 million
this quarter on The Lone Ranger, which cost $225 million to
make and has produced less in box-office sales. The company''s
ESPN, AE and domestic children''s cable channels, along with the
popular theme parks, continue to spur growth for Disney as film
profits slide and the ABC broadcast division struggles. </p>
<p>There has been a lot said I know about the risk of
basically high-cost, tentpole films, and we certainly can attest
to that given what happened with Lone Ranger,'' Chairman and
Chief Executive Officer Robert Iger said on a call with
investors. We still believe that a tentpole strategy is a good
strategy. One way to rise above the din and the competition is
with a big film, not just a big budget, but a big story, big
cast, big marketing behind it. </p>
<p>Disney fell 1.7 percent to $65.91 at the close in New York.
The stock has gained 32 percent this year. </p>
<p>If you strip everything aside, it was maybe a tad light
compared to what people were expecting, Matthew Harrigan, an
analyst at Wunderlich Securities in Denver, said of the
earnings. He has a hold rating on the stock. </p>
<h2>Quarterly Sales </h2>
<p>Sales increased 4.4 percent to $11.6 billion in the period
ended June 29, compared with the $11.7 billion average of 27
analysts'' estimates. </p>
<p>Disney''s film studio posted a 36 percent drop in profit to
to $201 million due to pre-release marketing costs of the The
Lone Ranger and lower revenue from Iron Man 3 compared to
last year''s megahit The Avengers. </p>
<p>The Lone Ranger, featuring Armie Hammer in the title
role and Johnny Depp as his sidekick Tonto, has collected $176
million in worldwide ticket revenue since its July 3 release,
according to Box Office Mojo, an industry website. Studios split
those receipts with theater owners and incur additional costs
marketing their pictures. </p>
<h2>Cable, TV </h2>
<p>Operating income at Disney''s media networks, the company''s
largest group, rose 8.2 percent to $2.3 billion. Growth in fees
from pay-TV services and advertising at networks, including
ESPN, countered higher programing costs and lower revenue from
the ABC broadcast business. Sales increased 5.3 percent to $5.35
billion, Disney said. </p>
<p>Costs at the ABC network rose as the broadcast division
aired fewer shows made internally and acquired more programming
from outside producers, according to the statement. The ABC
network lost about 6 percent of its audience in the TV season
that ended in May and saw a 10 percent drop in the younger
viewers that advertisers target, according to Nielsen data. </p>
<p>Investments and an improving economy lifted profit at
Disney resorts and theme parks, where earnings increased 9.4
percent to $689 million on 7 percent higher attendance and more
spending by tourists. </p>
<p>The company said projects such as MyMagic+, a wristband for
guests that serves as an admission ticket, room key and credit
card, led to higher costs. The Florida parks are benefiting from
the new Disney''s Art of Animation resort and the expansion of
the Magic Kingdom. </p>
<p>Consumer products profit rose 4.8 percent to $219 million,
while losses at the company''s interactive division increased to
$58 million from $42 million a year earlier. </p>
<p>Given the number of headwinds we faced, we are very
pleased with the financial results we delivered, Chief
Financial Officer Jay Rasulo said on the call. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By John Detrixhe and Morgane Lapeyre" date="Aug 07, 2013  5:43 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-07/morgan-stanley-seeks-repeat-of-winning-dollar-call-currencies.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Seeks Repeat of Winning Dollar Call: Currencies</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley, which advised clients
to sell the dollar just before it tumbled to a four-month low in
June, has rejoined U.S. currency bulls on optimism that the
world''s largest economy will recover faster than peers. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley forecasts that the greenback will strengthen
5 percent to $1.26 per euro and 10 percent to 107 yen by year-end, making it more optimistic than the $1.27 and 105-yen median
estimates of more than 70 analysts surveyed by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>The trend in the dollar is clearly to the upside, Hans Redeker, the London-based head of global foreign-exchange
strategy at Morgan Stanley, said in an Aug. 5 phone interview.
The U.S. dollar is trading according to long-term return
expectations of underlying assets, and that''s highly dependent
on how you view the growth differential between the U.S. and the
rest of the world. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley is returning to its bullish stance just as
Commodity Futures Trading Commission data show traders are
paring bets that America''s currency will continue to strengthen
after the Bloomberg U.S. Dollar Index rose 4 percent this year,
heading for its biggest annual gain since 2008. </p>
<h2>Greenback Whipsawed </h2>
<p>The dollar climbed 0.2 percent to $1.3276 per euro at 10:36
a.m. in London, and dropped 0.7 percent to 97.05 yen. </p>
<p>The greenback has been whipsawed by mixed messages from the
Federal Reserve over when it will slow the pace of the bond
purchases it uses to bolster the economy. The central bank has
been printing enough dollars to buy $85 billion of Treasuries
and mortgage bonds a month. </p>
<p>Fed Chairman Ben S. Bernanke said July 10 that the U.S.
central bank would maintain a highly accommodative monetary
policy for the foreseeable future. That was after he said on
June 19 that officials may start dialing down their
unprecedented bond-buying program this year and end it entirely
in mid-2014 if the labor market showed sustained improvement. </p>
<p>The Bloomberg U.S. Dollar Index, which tracks the greenback
against 10 major currencies, climbed to an almost three-year
high of 1,045 in May, before falling to 1,008.6 on June 14. The
gauge was at 1,026.32 today. </p>
<p>The turmoil spread beyond the foreign-exchange market. The
Standard  Poor''s 500 Index (SPX) tumbled 1.5 percent in June, the
biggest monthly decline since October. The SP GSCI Index (SPGSCI) of
commodities fell to a two-month low on June 24, and bond yields
soared, raising the cost of borrowing. The JPMorgan Emerging
Markets Bond Index fell 5 percent in June, the most since
October 2008. </p>
<h2>Worked Out'' </h2>
<p>In June, we thought about the developments in asset
markets and about the impact it was going to have on the way the
Fed would think about its tapering policy, Redeker said. We
thought here would be a pause in this dollar bullishness. So,
basically, we implemented that pause and that worked out. </p>
<p>For all the hand-wringing over Fed policy, the economy is
showing signs of strength. U.S. gross domestic product will
expand 2.7 percent next year, according to the median forecast
of 79 economists surveyed by Bloomberg. That compares with an
average estimate of 1.9 percent for the Group of 10 nations. </p>
<p>Equities have since bounced back, with the SP 500 reaching
a record high 1,709.67 last week, and bond market losses have
slowed. A measure of U.S. fixed-income securities is little
changed since the start of July, after tumbling 3.5 percent in
May and June as measured by the Bank of America Merrill Lynch
U.S. Broad Market Index. </p>
<h2>Futures Traders </h2>
<p>The strength in the stock market is a reflection of the
U.S. recovery, Alvin Tan, a director of foreign-exchange
strategies at Societe Generale SA in London, said in an Aug. 6
phone interview. The market is pricing in better economic
conditions in the U.S. </p>
<p>Futures traders decreased bets that the dollar will rally
for a second week, figures from the CFTC show. </p>
<p>Wagers that the U.S. currency will gain versus eight peers
including the euro, yen and pound -- known as net longs -- fell
$4.5 billion to $23.5 billion in the week ended July 30, the
least since the period ending July 2, according to CFTC data
compiled by SocGen. </p>
<p>That compares with a high for this year of $38 billion in
May, and $13.4 billion of bets that the dollar would weaken at
the end of last year. </p>
<p>The currency positioning of the dollar is on the net-long
side, but not particularly heavy relative to recent history,
Tan said. Monetary policy divergence will drive the euro-dollar to the low 1.20s by the first quarter of next year. </p>
<h2>Predicting Gains </h2>
<p>Of 24 economists surveyed by Bloomberg, 20 predict that the
dollar will rally by the end of 2013 amid signs that the U.S. is
leading the developed world''s recovery from the financial crisis
and that it will reduce currency-sapping stimulus more quickly. </p>
<p>Intercontinental Exchange Inc.''s Dollar Index, which
measures the currency versus those of six U.S. trading partners,
will rise to 85.6 by Dec. 31, from 81.784, according to the
median estimate of 13 analysts surveyed by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>European Central Bank President Mario Draghi said Aug. 1
that interest rates in the euro region will remain low for an
extended period. The Frankfurt-based central bank will cut its
main rate by a quarter-percentage point to a record 0.25 percent
early next year, SocGen''s Tan forecast. </p>
<h2>Higher Yields </h2>
<p>Yields on 10-year U.S. Treasury (USGG10YR) notes, the benchmark for
everything from mortgages to corporate bonds, are climbing on
expectations that the Fed will pare stimulus. </p>
<p>While that makes U.S. investments more attractive, higher
borrowing costs may stifle the economy''s recovery, weighing on
the dollar. The yield touched 2.75 percent on July 8, the
highest level since August 2011, and was at 2.63 percent today. </p>
<p>The U.S. economy is in a more advanced position in the
business cycle than Asia or Europe at the moment, Paul Robson,
a senior currency strategist at Royal Bank of Scotland Group Plc
in London, said in an Aug. 6 phone interview. The main risk is
how the economy navigates higher U.S. yields, though as more
data point to a recovery, the dollar should do reasonably
well. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Edward Klump" date="Aug 08, 2013  4:18 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-08/exxon-and-imperial-to-buy-conoco-oil-sands-land-for-720-million.html"><headline>Exxon, Imperial to Buy Conoco Oil-Sands for $723 Million</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) and Imperial Oil
Ltd. (IMO) agreed to buy ConocoPhillips'' Clyden lease for about C$751
million ($723 million), expanding their holdings in the booming
Alberta oil-sands region. </p>
<p>The sale includes 226,000 net acres of undeveloped land
near the southern edge of the Athabasca oil sands, Houston-based
ConocoPhillips said in a statement today. Under the agreement,
Exxon will hold 72.5 percent of the leasehold and Calgary-based
Imperial, which Exxon controls, will have 27.5 percent, the
companies said. </p>
<p>It''s the second Canadian purchase in 10 months for Irving,
Texas-based Exxon, which agreed to pay C$2.86 billion for Celtic
Exploration Ltd. in October, gaining access to shale regions in
Alberta and British Columbia. Canada has the world''s third-largest oil reserves, after Venezuela and Saudi Arabia, and its
output is expected to more than double by 2030, according to the
Canadian Association of Petroleum Producers. </p>
<p>Oil-sands projects offer the same predictable
production for years, as companies like Exxon face declining
output from conventional oil fields, said Fadel Gheit, an
analyst with Oppenheimer  Co. in New York who has the
equivalent of a hold rating on Exxon and a buy on
ConocoPhillips. (COP) Exxon said in March its combined oil and gas
production will fall for a second straight year as it builds
platforms and pipelines to bring recent discoveries online. </p>
<h2>Exxon Partner </h2>
<p>The sale is expected to close in the third quarter and
requires approval from Canada''s Competition Bureau,
ConocoPhillips said. Exxon is the largest shareholder in
Imperial Oil, with a 70 percent stake as of Feb. 13, according
to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>ConocoPhillips gained 0.9 percent to $67.09 at the close in
New York, while Exxon climbed 0.5 percent to $91.78. Imperial
increased 3 cents to C$42.03 in Toronto. </p>
<p>Exxon plans to bring in a partner, reducing its stake to
27.5 percent while it keeps majority control of the project with
Imperial, the companies said. </p>
<p>Imperial has been expanding output from its oil-sands
holding, including the C$12.9 billion Kearl project in Alberta
which began production in April. Kearl is on schedule to produce
110,000 barrels a day by the end of the year, the company said
Aug. 1. </p>
<p>For Imperial Oil this seems like a logical bolt-on
acquisition that''s easy to integrate, Pavel Molchanov, an
analyst with Raymond James  Associates Inc. in Houston, said in
a phone interview today. He has the equivalent of a buy on Exxon
and a sell on ConocoPhillips and doesn''t own either shares. </p>
<p>ConocoPhillips has been selling assets for more than three
years to focus on more profitable areas. Chief Financial Officer
Jeff Sheets said earlier this month ConocoPhillips might reduce
its oil-sands holdings. The company expects about $13.5 billion
from its 2012-2013 asset sales program, including $3.8 billion
received through the end of June. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Mulholland" date="Aug 08, 2013 11:33 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-08/goldman-sachs-deutsche-bank-said-to-fund-debt-on-650-madison.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs, Deutsche Bank Said to Fund Debt on 650 Madison</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and Deutsche
Bank AG (DBK) are funding the acquisition of New York''s 650 Madison
building with an $800 million loan, according to two people with
knowledge of the transaction. </p>
<p>The lenders plan to package the debt on the Manhattan tower
into bonds to sell to investors, said the people, who asked not
to be identified because the negotiations are private. A $150
million portion may be carved into riskier mezzanine loans that
pay higher yields, one of the people said. </p>
<p>The deal signals Wall Street''s conviction that bond buyers
will snap up the commercial-mortgage backed securities even as
concern that the Federal Reserve may begin to reduce stimulus
efforts next month roils markets. Goldman Sachs and Deutsche
Bank beat out Citigroup Inc., Bank of America Corp., JPMorgan
Chase  Co. and Wells Fargo  Co. to land the assignment,
according to four people with knowledge of the talks. </p>
<p>Michael DuVally, a spokesman for Goldman Sachs, and Amanda Williams of Deutsche Bank, both in New York, declined to
comment. </p>
<p>A partnership between Crown Acquisitions and Highgate
Holdings Inc. agreed to pay a record $1.3 billion, or $2,100 a
square foot, for the tower at Madison Avenue and East 59th
Street in June. Vornado Realty Trust (VNO) and Oxford Properties Group
have joined the consortium of buyers, Vornado Chairman Steven Roth said on an Aug. 6 conference call with analysts. </p>
<p>The purchase, from Carlyle Group LP, is the largest for an
entire building in the U.S. since Google Inc.''s $1.8 billion
acquisition in 2010 of 111 Eighth Ave., a former warehouse in
Manhattan''s Chelsea section. It exceeds the record $1,583 a
square foot paid for 450 Park Ave. in 2007. </p>
<p>Wall Street banks have arranged $49.1 billion of bonds
linked to everything from strip malls to skyscrapers this year,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. Issuance is forecast to
climb to $70 billion in 2013, more than double last year''s
total, according to Credit Suisse Group AG. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Aug 08, 2013 11:28 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-08/goldman-sachs-s-european-insurance-business-up-for-sale.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs''s European Insurance Business Up for Sale</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) said it probably will sell a majority stake in its European insurance business in the next 12 months as banks face more stringent capital rules. </p> <p>Rothesay Life Ltd., a London-based insurer run by Goldman Sachs partner Addy Loudiadis, had $9.66 billion in assets as of June 30, Goldman Sachs said today in a regulatory filing. The New York-based bank sold about 80 percent of Global Atlantic Financial Group, a reinsurance business in Bermuda, to institutions and high-net worth clients in April. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs is planning the sale of Rothesay, which it set up in 2007, in part because new rules require banks to hold more equity to absorb potential losses on their assets, according to a person briefed on the discussions. The sale of Global Atlantic boosted Goldman Sachs''s Basel III Tier 1 common ratio by 0.5 percentage point, Chief Financial Officer Harvey Schwartz said last month. </p> <p>Our reinsurance business -- good business, we like the business -- but with the new Basel rules it was clear that business was better held outside of Goldman Sachs, Schwartz, 49, said at an investor conference in May. If something''s better outside of Goldman Sachs, we''ll make an adjustment. </p> <h2>Pension Hedging </h2> <p>Goldman Sachs''s Tier 1 common equity was equal to 9.3 percent of the bank''s risk-weighted assets at the end of June under new Basel III rules, according to the filing. The bank has said it wants to maintain a ratio of about 9.5 percent, or 1 percentage point higher than regulators will require. </p> <p>The firm''s Tier 1 common equity was reduced by $9.87 billion because of investments in nonconsolidated financial institutions, according to the filing. That brought its Basel III figure to $55.8 billion, compared with $61.9 billion under current rules. </p> <p>Rothesay insures more than 10 billion pounds ($15.5 billion) of pension liabilities for companies including IAG SA''s British Airways and General Motors Co.''s U.K. division. Firms such as Rothesay promise to pay pensions if retirees live beyond a certain age and then use derivatives to try to hedge the risk. The insurer typically receives a portion of the pension plan''s assets. </p> <p>Rothesay had pretax operating profit of 266 million pounds in 2012, according to the unit''s website. </p> <h2>Greek Derivative </h2> <p>The unit''s assets included corporate bonds, non-U.S. government debt and $1 billion of over-the-counter derivatives, according to the filing. The business had $10.6 billion of liabilities as of June 30. The total asset and liability figures exclude inter-company assets and liabilities, which are expected to be included in the sale, according to Goldman Sachs. </p> <p>Loudiadis, 50, who joined Goldman''s European derivatives marketing group in 1994 from JPMorgan Chase  Co. and was named partner in 2000, rose to be one of the bank''s top European sales executives. </p> <p>In 2001 she helped sell Greece a derivative that masked the country''s growing debt so the country could improve its finances to meet European Union fiscal targets. The derivative later cost Greece billions of euros. Goldman Sachs wasn''t accused of wrongdoing related to the transaction. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Aug 08, 2013  7:02 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-08/goldman-sachs-lost-on-six-trading-days-in-second-quarter.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Traders Lost on Six Days in Second Quarter</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), which
generated about half its revenue from trading last quarter,
posted losses from that business on six days in the second
quarter, unchanged from a year earlier. </p>
<p>The bank''s traders made more than $100 million on 10 days
in the quarter ended June 30, compared with four days in the
year-earlier period, the New York-based company said in a
regulatory filing today. While the largest one-day loss was
between $75 million and $100 million, none of the firm''s losses
topped its value-at-risk estimate. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs generated $4.31 billion from its trading
division in the second quarter of 2013, an increase of 11
percent from the year-earlier period. The total was down from
the first quarter amid a drop in bond prices sparked by
indications that the Federal Reserve may ease economic-stimulus
measures. </p>
<p>Macro concerns emerged again toward the end of the
quarter and were reflected in lower activity levels and risk
appetite in certain businesses, Chief Financial Officer Harvey Schwartz said on a conference call last month. In addition,
the market volatility created more challenging periods within
the capital markets for managing client flows. </p>
<p>Bank of America Corp. lost money on seven days during the
quarter, including a $54 million misstep on one of them. Morgan
Stanley posted losses on 12 days, including one that topped $50
million, while Wells Fargo  Co. reported five negative days.
Citigroup Inc. doesn''t disclose money-losing days. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
Goldman Sachs generated $4.31 billion from its trading division in the second quarter of 2013, an increase of 11 percent from the year-earlier period. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Aug 08, 2013  6:35 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-08/goldman-sachs-cooperating-with-u-s-credit-swaps-inquiry.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Cooperating With U.S. Credit-Swaps Inquiry</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs (GS) Group Inc., the fifth-largest U.S. bank by assets, said it''s cooperating with the U.S.
Department of Justice''s four-year-old antitrust probe into the
credit-default swaps market. </p>
<p>The firm has received civil investigative demands related
to the investigation, New York-based Goldman Sachs said in a
regulatory filing today. The bank was among more than a dozen
financial institutions accused by the European Union last month
of colluding to curb competition in credit derivatives. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) and Citigroup Inc. also said in filings last
week that they were cooperating with the probe. The Justice
Department sent civil investigative notices in July 2009 to the
banks that own London-based Markit Group Ltd., a provider of
data on derivatives and bonds, to find out if they had unfair
access to price information, three people familiar with the
matter said at the time. </p>
<p>Markit''s shareholders included Goldman Sachs, JPMorgan
Chase  Co. (JPM), Bank of America Corp., and Royal Bank of Scotland
Group Plc, according to filings with the U.K.''s Companies House
at the time. Bloomberg LP, the owner of Bloomberg News, competes
with Markit in selling information to the financial-services
industry. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Shannon" date="Aug 08, 2013  2:53 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-08/coca-cola-hbc-sales-decline-as-established-european-markets-slip.html"><headline>Coca-Cola HBC Sales Decline as Established European Markets Slip</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Coca-Cola HBC AG (CCH), the bottler that
switched its listing from Athens to London, said second-quarter
sales fell 2 percent as a volume gain in emerging markets failed
to offset declines in countries including Greece and Austria. </p>
<p>Revenue fell to 1.95 billion euros ($2.6 billion) in the
three months ended June 28, the company said today in a
statement. That missed the prediction of Mike Gibbs, an analyst
at JPMorgan Cazenove who estimated sales of 1.989 billion euros. </p>
<p>Volume gained 2 percent in emerging markets, Coca-Cola HBC
said, while levels dropped 6 percent in so-called established
economies and 3 percent in developing markets. The company buys
concentrate from Atlanta-based Coca-Cola Co. and sells the
products in Europe. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola HBC said it will start a progressive dividend
policy in 2014 that targets an annual payout with a ratio to
profit after tax of 35 percent to 45 percent. The company, which
switched its primary stock listing in April, paid a dividend of
34 euros cents a share in July worth 124.7 million euros, or
about 43 percent. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola HBC maintained volume share in sparkling drinks
in the majority of our markets in the first half, the
company said. </p>
<p>The bottler operates in countries with lower per-capita
consumption of sparkling drinks than the rest of the eurozone,
which will help it boost volume growth, Chief Executive Officer
Dimitris Lois said in April. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri" date="Aug 09, 2013 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-09/disney-s-planes-rescued-from-dvd-pile-in-bet-for-summer.html"><headline>Disney''s Planes'' Rescued From DVD Pile in Bet for Summer</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS)''s Planes, a low-cost animated feature that began life as a direct-to-DVD
project, is shaping up as a potential moneymaker for theaters in
a summer marked by slow sales for big-budget films. </p>
<p>The movie, inspired by Pixar''s Cars, opens today. The
picture went from DVD-only to cinemas when Disney, the world''s
largest entertainment company, saw how test audiences responded
to a rough cut, Dave Hollis, the studio''s executive vice
president for sales and distribution, said in an interview. </p>
<p>It was off the charts, he said. </p>
<p>Produced for about a fourth of what big budget movies cost,
Planes could generate $21 million this weekend and $81
million in its domestic run, according to Boxoffice.com.
Animated films typically do more outside the U.S., and Disney
already has Planes toys and apparel in stores. The film was
made for about $50 million, according to a company official who
asked not to be named because the figure isn''t public. </p>
<p>Planes could be a surprise success because of its lower
price tag, according to David Weitzner, a movie marketing
consultant who teaches at the University of Southern
California''s School of Cinematic Arts. The Lone Ranger, a
July release from Burbank, California-based Disney, may lose as
much as $190 million, the company said on Aug. 6. </p>
<p>Disney executives see where the market is going, what
families are looking for, and are bringing it in at a price that
makes sense, Weitzner said in an interview. </p>
<h2>DisneyToon Studios </h2>
<p>Planes is about a cropdusting aircraft named Dusty with
a fear of heights and dreams of racing. It has a similar look
and feel as the two Cars movies, from Disney''s Pixar, which
have collected a combined $1 billion worldwide in ticket sales,
according to researcher Box Office Mojo. Comedian Dane Cook
supplies the voice for Dusty. </p>
<p>Planes was produced by DisneyToon Studios, a division
specializing in low-budget animated features mostly for home
video. The Jungle Book 2, a $20 million theatrical release
from the division in 2003, had $135.7 million in worldwide
sales, according to Box Office Mojo. </p>
<p>John Lasseter, who joined Disney as chief creative officer
of the animation studios following the company''s acquisition of
Pixar in 2006, scaled back the unit''s production after voicing
dissatisfaction with the quality of direct-to-home features.
DisneyToon Studios has been releasing about one movie a year,
down from six a decade ago, according to researcher IMDB.com. </p>
<h2>Action Films </h2>
<p>The timing of Planes may help, according to Paul Dergarabedian, president of the box-office division at market
researcher Hollywood.com. It comes on a weekend when other new
pictures are aimed at older theatergoers. </p>
<p>August can be the land of opportunity for movies that
aren''t hardcore action films, Dergarabedian said. It''s sort
of like counter programming. </p>
<p>Elysium, a science-fiction film from Sony Corp.
starring Matt Damon and Jodie Foster, also opens today. Percy
Jackson: Sea of Monsters, based on a series of young-adult
novels, opened Aug. 7 and targets older kids than Planes
because of its PG rating. </p>
<p>Planes will compete with three animated films still in
theaters: The Smurfs 2, in its second week, the hit film
Despicable Me 2 in its sixth week, and Turbo, in its
fourth week. The picture is opening in 3,700 theaters, according
to Hollywood.com. </p>
<h2>Planes'' Toys </h2>
<p>Cars is among Disney''s largest toy franchises,
generating more than $10 billion in retail sales since the first
picture''s release in 2006, the company has said. Last year''s
Cars Land addition to the company''s California Adventure park in
Anaheim, California, led to a 23 percent jump in attendance,
according to the Themed Entertainment Association. </p>
<p>Disney has already released Planes related merchandise,
including $6 diecast airplanes, $13 story books and $18
children''s jackets. A sequel, Planes: Fire  Rescue, is
scheduled for theaters in July 2014. </p>
<p>Advertising and word-of-mouth from the theatrical release
could lead to higher sales of the DVD and merchandise tied to
the film, according to David Paiko, vice president of business
development at Rentrak Corp. (RENT), a media measurement firm. </p>
<p>All those marketing dollars to promote it theatrically
puts an awareness into people''s minds, he said in an
interview. It''s Cars'' in the sky. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elizabeth Amon" date="Aug 09, 2013 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-09/morgan-lewis-sidley-ashurst-thompson-hine-business-of-law.html"><headline>Morgan Lewis, Sidley, Ashurst, Thompson Hine: Business of Law</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Bank regulatory lawyer Charles Horn
joined Morgan Lewis  Bockius LLP as a partner in Washington. He
was previously at Morrison  Foerster LLP. </p>
<p>Horncounsels domestic and global banks and other financial
services firms on federal and state financial regulation matters
as well as corporate, institutional and retail business
activities. He provides counsel on transactional matters
including mergers and acquisitions, strategic alliances and
business integrations, the firm said. He also advises banks on
asset management, fiduciary and asset administration. </p>
<p>Charles''s intimate familiarity with the bank regulatory
framework is invaluable to financial institutions as they seek
to better understand and navigate the ever-changing supervision
and enforcement measures and policies of traditional regulators
including the Federal Reserve, the OCC and the Federal Deposit
Insurance Corporation, Steven Stone, leader of Morgan Lewis''s
investment management practice said in a statement. </p>
<p>He can also provide critical counsel to financial
services companies encountering scrutiny from the new financial
industry regulator, the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau,
which has launched dozens of investigations and issued more than
100 subpoenas over the last 18 months, he added. </p>
<p>Morgan Lewis has more than 100 attorneys who work with
financial services clients in the U.S. and abroad. The firm has
more than 1,600 lawyers and professionals in 25 offices in the
U.S., Europe, Asia and the Middle East. </p>
<h2>SEC''s Corporation Finance Chief Counsel Joins Sidley Austin </h2>
<p>Sidley Austin LLP announced that Thomas J. Kim, the chief
counsel and associate director of the Securities and Exchange
Commission''s Division of Corporation Finance since 2007, is
joining the firm as a partner in Washington.He will be a member
of the securities and derivatives enforcement and regulatory,
securities and corporate governance and executive compensation
practice teams. </p>
<p>At the SEC, Kim managed a staff of more than a dozen senior
lawyers, providing legal advice on the federal securities laws
administered by the division, the firm said. </p>
<p>It has been challenging and rewarding to work on cutting
edge issues with the commission and the commission''s talented
staff, Kim said in a statement. Sidley provides an
exceptional and global platform for building a practice and
providing high-quality legal advice to clients. </p>
<p>Sidley has approximately 1,700 lawyers in 19 offices in the
Americas, Europe and Asia. </p>
<h2>Ashurst Strengthens Asian MA Practice With Partner Hire </h2>
<p>Ashurst LLP appointed John K.J. Kim as a partner in the
Hong Kong office. He was previously with Korean law firm Yulchon
LLC, where he was head of the Outbound Practice Group, the firm
said. </p>
<p>Kim specializes in advising Korean clients in outbound MA
and other cross-border corporate transactions. </p>
<p>We view Korea as a key market, and we will continue to
significantly invest in our Korean outbound practice, Asia
managing partner Matthew Bubb said in a statement. </p>
<p>Ashurst has lawyers at offices in North America, Europe,
Asia, the Middle East and Australia. </p>
<h2>Corporate Partner Michael Coleman Joins Thompson Hine </h2>
<p>Thompson Hine LLP announced that Michael V. Coleman, along
with another lawyer, joined the firm as a partner in the
corporate transactions and securities practice group in Atlanta.
He was previously at Epstein Becker  Green PC. </p>
<p>Michael''s experience speaks for itself - he is well-known
throughout the city of Atlanta and nationally. His corporate
practice complements our existing practice, and his considerable
experience and skills will benefit our clients significantly,
Russell J. Rogers, office partner-in-charge said in a statement. </p>
<p>Coleman''s practice focuses on general corporate issues,
mergers and acquisitions, corporate finance, corporate internal
investigations, public/private transactions and business
litigation, the firm said. In addition to serving as outside
general counsel for a number of Atlanta-based companies, he has
represented Turner Broadcasting and the Atlanta Hawks in
connection with the development and financing of Phillips Arena,
the city of Atlanta in connection with the development and
financing of Atlantic Station and Central Atlanta Progress in
connection with the creation of the Atlanta Downtown Improvement
District, according to the firm. </p>
<p>Thompson Hine has lawyers at seven U.S. offices. </p>
<p>Lander  Rogers Hires Commercial Disputes Partner Tean Kerr. </p>
<p>Tean Kerr joined the Lander  Rogers Sydney office in the
insolvency and commercial dispute resolution practice. He was
previously at Swaab Attorneys. </p>
<p>Kerr has experience in commercial litigation and
insolvency. He advises on insolvency and corporate recovery and
restructuring. He also has experience acting and advising in
relation to director and officer liability and regulatory
matters as well as director and shareholder disputes, the firm
said in a statement. </p>
<p>Lander  Rogers is an Australian law firm with offices in
Melbourne and Sydney. </p>
<h2>Video </h2>
<p>Wells Fargo: Anemic Growth in BigLaw in 2013 </p>
<p>Jeff Grossman, Senior Director at Wells Fargo Private Bank,
talks with Bloomberg Law''s Lee Pacchia about his firm''s new
report on the state of BigLaw. The survey of 120 law firms saw
revenue growth of 1.5% for the first half of 2013 compared to
the same period last year. One positive finding for law firms is
that rates have increased. </p>
<p>For more, click here. </p>
<h2>News </h2>
<h2>U.K. Prosecutors Accidentally Lost Evidence From BAE Probe </h2>
<p>The U.K. Serious Fraud Office said it accidentally lost
evidence from an investigation into BAE Systems Plc (BA/), including
32,000 pages of documents and 81 audio tapes. </p>
<p>The information was from a six-year bribery probe into the
defense company that ended with a 500,000-pound ($776,000) fine
for accounting irregularities in 2010. The SFO, which has to
return data after finishing investigations, sent the material to
the wrong source, which it didn''t identify, the agency said in
an e-mailed statement yesterday. </p>
<p>This latest debacle will do little to restore public
confidence in the SFO, Andrew Smith, a criminal defense lawyer
in London, said in an e-mail. It underlines the fact that the
SFO needs radical internal reform in order to become a world-class prosecuting agency. </p>
<p>BAE Systems pleaded guilty in 2010 to not keeping proper
payment records from deals. The defense company had been under
investigation over alleged bribes paid in six countries,
including Tanzania and the Czech Republic. The lost data
accounted for 3 percent of the total information used in the SFO
probe, the agency said. It has recovered 98 percent of the lost
material and said none of the information related to national
security. </p>
<p>The SFO said it conducted an internal probe into the data
loss and has started an independent review of its systems led by
Alan Woods, a former government official. The evidence was
accidentally sent between May and October last year, the agency
said. </p>
<h2>Firm News </h2>
<h2>Baker  McKenzie Elects Managing Partner in Warsaw Office </h2>
<p>Marek Rosiski has been elected managing partner of Baker 
McKenzie''s Warsaw office for a two-year term. He takes over from
Marcin Gmaj, who held the position for two terms. </p>
<p>Rosiski, who heads the office''s intellectual property and
technology practice, has been a partner in the Warsaw office
since 2003. He was managing partner of the office between 2007
and 2009. </p>
<p>Baker  McKenzie''s Warsaw office opened in 1992. The office
currently has more than 90 lawyers and tax advisers. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Veronica Navarro Espinosa" date="Aug 12, 2013  1:36 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-12/jpmorgan-said-to-hire-deutsche-bank-s-corfield-as-analyst.html"><headline>JPMorgan Said to Hire Deutsche Bank''s Corfield as Analyst</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) hired Natalia Corfield from Deutsche Bank AG to join its emerging-market
corporate credit research group, according to two people with
direct knowledge of the matter. </p>
<p>Corfield, who was with Deutsche Bank since May 2012, will
be based in New York and report to Jacob Steinfeld, JPMorgan''s
head of Latin American corporate research, said the people, who
asked not to be identified because she hasn''t started working
yet at JPMorgan. </p>
<p>Amanda Williams, a spokeswoman for Deutsche Bank, Adrian Garcia-Aranyos, a spokesman for JPMorgan, and Corfield all
declined to comment on the matter. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jason Clenfield and Toshiro Hasegawa" date="Aug 12, 2013 12:07 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-12/morgan-stanley-strategist-kitano-leaves-after-3-months.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Strategist Kitano Leaves After 3 Months</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Hajime Kitano, the only Japan-based
equity strategist at Morgan Stanley (MS) MUFG Securities Co., left
last week after just over three months on the job. </p>
<p>Tokyo-based Morgan Stanley spokesman Natsuo Nishio
confirmed the departure and that Kitano was the bank''s sole
stocks strategist in Japan. Kitano started at the investment
firm on May 1. Before that, he worked for JPMorgan Chase  Co.
from 2006 until 2013, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>The departure leaves Morgan Stanley with nobody in the
equity-strategy role in Tokyo as Japanese stocks post the
biggest rally this year among developed markets. Kitano was
ranked Japan''s top equity strategist in 2013 by Institutional
Investor, claiming the No. 1 position for the third time since
2007, according to the magazine''s website. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley will provide coverage of Japan strategy
through its regional team in Hong Kong led by Jonathan Garner,
the firm''s chief Asian and global emerging market equity
strategist, Nishio said in an e-mail. </p>
<p>Garner wrote the bank''s reports on Japan from Hong Kong
between the July 2011 departure of Tokyo-based Alexander Kinmont
and Kitano''s arrival in May. </p>
<p>An email to Kitano''s personal address was not immediately
answered. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Louise Downing" date="Aug 13, 2013 11:15 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-13/general-electric-starts-its-first-wind-energy-plant-in-estonia.html"><headline>General Electric Starts Its First Wind Energy Plant in Estonia</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>General Electric Co. (GE) today started
its first wind farm in Estonia. </p>
<p>The company installed 18 turbines totaling 45 megawatts in
northwestern Estonia for Eesti Energia AS and Nelja Energia AS,
it said today in a statement on its website. Eesti Energia
currently operates four wind farms with a combined capacity of
111 megawatts. </p>
<p>Estonia in 2011 became the first European Union member to
exceed its 2020 renewable energy target. The nation''s share of
renewable energy in final energy consumption reached 25.9
percent in 2011, surpassing its 25 percent target. </p>
<p>Wind energy at the end of last year produced about 5.5
percent of Estonia''s total electricity consumption, according to
the Estonian Wind Power Association. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jordan Robertson" date="Aug 13, 2013  6:11 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-13/microsoft-ibm-top-list-of-u-s-tech-firms-with-biggest-overseas-profit-hauls.html"><headline>Microsoft, IBM Top List of U.S. Tech Firms with Biggest Overseas Profit Hauls</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>When it comes to the politically inflammatory issue of U.S. companies holding trillions of dollars in profits overseas, two tech firms get the lion''s share of attention and blame for the practice: Apple and Cisco Systems. </p><p>That''s because their chief executive officers, Tim Cook and John Chambers, have been among the most vocal lobbyists for a tax holiday to bring the cash home at a rate lower than the 35 percent currently required by the U.S. government.</p><p>Yet Apple and Cisco aren''t the biggest hoarders of overseas cash. According to Bloomberg Rankings, which looked at the regulatory filings of the 70 companies in the SP 500 Information Technology Index and the five in the SP 500 Internet  Catalog Retail Index, the distinction belongs to Microsoft and IBM. </p><p>Microsoft had $76.4 billion and IBM had $44.4 billion in foreign profits on their books in 2012 that were untaxed by the U.S., according to the documents. The companies were followed by Cisco, with $41.3 billion, and Apple, with $40.4 billion.</p><p>Microsoft responded to a request for comment by pointing to congressional testimony from September, when Bill Sample, corporate vice president for worldwide tax at Microsoft, said that U.S. taxes on foreign earnings create a "disincentive for U.S. investment" and need changing to be competitive with many U.S. trading partners. IBM did not respond.</p><p>It''s estimated that U.S. corporations have more than $2 trillion in offshore earnings that are not being taxed by the U.S. As my colleague Jesse Drucker has reported, companies funnel cash overseas to lower their tax rates and in some cases have figured out ways to bring the money home tax-free through acquisitions and other means.</p><p>President Obama has waded into the issue. In February 2012 he proposed reducing the top corporate rate for most companies to 28 percent from 35 percent while eliminating tax breaks and changing other core features of the tax code. </p><p>One of the central concerns about a tax holiday is that it was tried before - in 2004 - and it did little to encourage the companies that took advantage of the break to create jobs or spur domestic investment, several independent economic studies have shown. However, the holiday did encourage companies to do one thing: to hoard overseas profits in expectation of another tax break.</p><p>Chambers may address the overseas topic when Cisco reports earnings on Wednesday. He''s said in the past that the issue has "well over a 60 percent probability of being resolved in a positive way." </p><p>Whatever the eventual outcome, one thing is certain: The following companies have a deeply vested interest in it. Here are the top 25 U.S. technology companies with the most untaxed overseas profits:</p><p>1. Microsoft, $76.4 billion</p><p>2. IBM, $44.4 billion</p><p>3. Cisco Systems, $41.3 billion</p><p>4. Apple, $40.4 billion</p><p>5. Hewlett-Packard, $33.4 billion</p><p>6. Google, $33.3 billion</p><p>7. Oracle, $26.2 billion</p><p>8. Dell, $19.0 billion</p><p>9. Intel, $17.5 billion</p><p>10. Qualcomm, $16.4 billion</p><p>11. Corning, $11.9 billion</p><p>11. EBay, $11.9 billion </p><p>13. Xerox, $8.3 billion</p><p>14. EMC, $8.1 billion</p><p>15. Western Digital, $6.3 billion</p><p>16. Texas Instruments, $5.5 billion</p><p>17. Western Union, $4.4 billion</p><p>18. Broadcom, $4.2 billion</p><p>19. Analog Devices, $3.2 billion</p><p>19. Priceline.com, $3.2 billion</p><p>21. Computer Sciences, $3.0 billion</p><p>22. Adobe Systems, $2.9 billion</p><p>23. Symantec, $2.8 billion</p><p>24. Altera, $2.7 billion</p><p>25. MasterCard, $2.6 billion</p><p>(TE Connectivity, with $18 billion in overseas cash, and Seagate Technology with $2.8 billion, were excluded from the list because both are based outside the U.S.)</p><p>Methodology: Bloomberg ranked the 70 companies in the SP 500 Information Technology Index, along with the five companies in the SP 500 Internet  Catalog Retail Index, based on the amount of undistributed earnings held outside the U.S. The top 25 companies are displayed. Data were from the latest available annual report or form 10-K filed by the company. Five companies (Fidelity National Information Services, Fiserv, Paychex, SAIC and Salesforce.com) did not have information available.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Inyoung Hwang" date="Aug 14, 2013  7:01 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-14/jpmorgan-top-stock-picker-with-equities-out-of-lockstep.html"><headline>JPMorgan Top Stock Picker with Equities Out of Lockstep</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Investors had declared the stock of AllianceBernstein Holding LP (AB) a loser. From Jan. 1, 2010, to Aug. 23, 2012, it had declined 43 percent compared with a 33 percent gain for the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index. Nevertheless, on that day, Credit Suisse Group AG analyst Craig Siegenthaler lifted his rating on the New York-based money manager''s shares to a buy. </p> <p>Many investors had left it for dead, Siegenthaler says. It was a tough stock to even bring up in front of investors. Underneath the low valuation, the company was really in a transformational period. </p> <p>Since his call, AllianceBernstein''s shares have outperformed the SP 500 by almost threefold, with the stock returning 73 percent for the year ended on Aug. 14. In recommending the shares to Credit Suisse customers, Siegenthaler said that the company was cutting expenses and that fixed-income sales were improving, Bloomberg Markets magazine will report in its September issue. </p> <p>More from the September issue of Bloomberg Markets:</p>

SPECIAL REPORT: Terrorism and Tungsten | Slideshow


FAMILY OFFICES: World''s Richest | Graphic


QATAR: Money, Gas and Clout


PHILANTHROPY: One Woman''s Mission


BILLIONAIRES: Charity, Russian Style | Slideshow


MALAYSIA: Najib''s Grand Plan

<p>Siegenthaler''s calls on stocks such as AllianceBernstein helped make him and his Credit Suisse partner, Howard Chen, the top U.S. analysts of brokerage and asset management firms in 2012, according to a ranking of stock analysts by consulting firm Greenwich Associates and Bloomberg Markets. </p> <p>He currently has buy recommendations on private-equity firm Fortress Investment Group LLC (FIG) and Zions Bancorporation. (ZION) </p> <h2>Analysts Surveyed </h2> <p>To compile the ranking, Stamford, Connecticut-based Greenwich Associates surveyed 945 buy-side analysts at 190 investment management firms, mutual funds, hedge funds, pension funds and insurers from December to March. The analysts were asked to name the Wall Street research teams they considered their most important sources of advice on investments. </p> <p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s research unit, under Noelle Grainger, the bank''s head of equity research in the Americas, scored the largest number of highly ranked analysts, making it the No. 1 firm in U.S. equities research for the fourth consecutive year, according to Greenwich Associates. Bank of America Corp.''s BofA Merrill Lynch Global Research unit was No. 2, followed by Morgan Stanley. (MS) </p> <p>Research directors and analysts say the big news in their field is that the era of correlation -- when stocks move up or down in unison in reaction to macroeconomic events -- is finally ending. Weakening correlation signals that investors are less obsessed with big issues like Europe''s debt crisis, the U.S. fiscal deficit and China''s growth trajectory. They''re looking instead at more stock-specific investment drivers such as earnings, technology innovations and market share, Grainger says. </p> <h2>Adding Value </h2> <p>In 2012, people started to be willing to put a little more risk on the table, Grainger says. It was a year where analysts could add more value based on their industry and company expertise. </p> <p>It was also a year in which the tide lifted a lot of boats. More than 300 of the stocks in the SP 500 index saw returns in excess of 10 percent in 2012, including reinvested dividends. As the index surged, driven by four straight years of profit growth and three rounds of Federal Reserve stimulus, companies'' stocks began to break away from the pack and move up or down on their merits. </p> <p>From the stock pickers'' side, two things stuck out in the past year, says Brett Hodess, the head of Americas equity research at BofA Merrill Lynch. It was still very important to look at macro events in order to see which sectors would be most favored. Then you had to figure out who the winners and losers would be. That was the way to outperform. </p> <h2>Calculating Correlation </h2> <p>The correlation among SP 500 companies fell to an average of 0.59 last year, according to data compiled by Westport, Connecticut-based research firm Birinyi Associates Inc. A reading of 1.0 indicates they''re all moving in the same direction by the same amount. In 2011, stocks had moved in unison by the most since at least 1980, reaching a record correlation of 0.86 in October as prices tumbled, according to Birinyi. </p> <p>Heather Bellini, a software analyst at Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) who ranked second in her industry, started coverage of Salesforce.com (CRM) Inc. in July 2011, putting the largest maker of customer-management software on Goldman''s buy list. She saw cash flow rising on the continued success of Salesforce''s Sales Cloud -- its core product -- as well as newer offerings such as the Service Cloud customer-support software. The shares fell after her July 12, 2011, buy recommendation and then gained 66 percent in 2012. The stock is up 6.3 perpercent this year as Aug. 14. </p> <p>Bellini now has buy recommendations on Facebook Inc. (FB) and Oracle Corp. (ORCL) </p> <h2>Reassessing Private Equity </h2> <p>Credit Suisse (CSGN)''s Chen took a new look at publicly listed private-equity firms, including Apollo Global Management LLC, Blackstone Group LP (BX) and Carlyle Group LP. (CG) Investors are still struggling to properly value them, he says. </p> <p>Private-equity firms lock up investor money for as long as a decade while they buy companies, overhaul them and, if all goes well, sell them for a profit. The firms, which use debt to finance the deals, typically charge an annual management fee of 1.5 percent to 2 percent and keep 20 percent of profits from investments. </p> <p>Valuing the firms had traditionally consisted of a sum-of-the-parts analysis -- marking the value of investments every quarter, according to Chen. He argued in a February 2012 report to change that metric and judge the firms based on their longer-term cash earnings generated from management fees and profits from investments. </p> <h2>False Precision'' </h2> <p>To me, sum of the parts has a false sense of precision, Chen says. It doesn''t get to the heart of how these companies create value and why they''ve been so successful. </p> <p>Apollo and Blackstone were the best positioned in 2012 to deliver the biggest growth in cash earnings, Chen says. He maintained his buy calls on both firms throughout the year. From Chen''s Feb. 7, 2012, note calling for a new valuation methodology, Apollo returned 129 percent as of yesterday''s close and Blackstone, 46.6 percent. </p> <p>Chen today has buy recommendations on IntercontinentalExchange Inc. (ICE) and asset manager State Street Corp. (STT) </p> <p>The top analyst of large-cap banks in the Greenwich Associates/Bloomberg Markets ranking is Betsy Graseck of Morgan Stanley. In one of her best calls, she saw bad news for JPMorgan as good news for investors. </p> <h2>Double Down'' </h2> <p>On May 18, 2012, eight days after the biggest U.S. bank by assets announced a $2 billion trading loss in the firm''s London chief investment office, Graseck published a note telling investors to double down on the shares, which had plunged 27 percent from their March 2012 peak. The trading losses were attributed to Bruno Iksil, known in the market as the London Whale, and ultimately totaled at least $6.2 billion. </p> <p>We pounded the table post-Whale, Graseck says. The view was that management had the skills to be able to work with the Street and get the portfolio risks reduced. JPMorgan stock returned 67.6 percent from her May report to yesterday''s close. </p> <p>Another Graseck winner was Atlanta-based SunTrust Banks (STI) Inc., which she upgraded to a buy on July 2, 2012, after digging into data that showed a recovery in the housing market in the Southeastern U.S. SunTrust is the biggest lender in Georgia and has branches in Florida, Maryland and North Carolina. She also saw that SunTrust would benefit from a new wave of refinancing following the extension of the federal Home Affordable Refinance Program, which allows Americans with little home equity to refinance. Shares of SunTrust rallied 42.9 percent from her call to Aug. 14. </p> <h2>Trade Routes </h2> <p>Graseck''s Morgan Stanley colleague Bill Greene ranks No. 1 in transportation. One of his best calls was a sell in March 2010 on Expeditors International (EXPD) of Washington Inc., which assists companies in shipping goods across international borders. Most of Expeditors'' business is on trade routes across the Pacific Ocean, especially between China and the U.S. Greene predicted that the company''s growth would stumble as freight flows shifted to emerging markets -- between China and Vietnam, for example. In addition, companies were increasingly near-shoring, or relocating factories and offices closer to headquarters, resulting in fewer international shipments. </p> <p>All of these factors were head winds to growth, Greene says. </p> <p>Starting in the fourth quarter of 2011, Expeditors'' profits missed analysts'' estimates for six straight quarters, sending shares down 2 percent in 2012. They''ve returned 3.2 percent this year as of yesterday. </p> <h2>One-by-One </h2> <p>While judging stocks one by one has become easier, what hasn''t changed since the financial crisis is investors'' demand for research on global investment themes. Analysts now collaborate across industries and regions in order to produce comprehensive reports that identify worldwide trends. </p> <p>Companies are competing across traditional lines, Goldman software analyst Bellini says. One thing that''s important for us is to make sure we break down the silos that are set up due to the way the industries are covered. This lets us present portfolio managers with research that''s more unified and consistent. </p> <p>Bellini teamed up with William Shope Jr., Goldman''s technology hardware analyst, who''s tied for third in his group in the Greenwich Associates/Bloomberg Markets survey, and Michael Bang, a Seoul-based analyst at the firm, on a December report that noted how Apple Inc. (AAPL), Samsung Electronics Co. (005930) and Facebook would all benefit from changing trends in how consumers use smartphones and tablets. </p> <h2>Defying the Crisis </h2> <p>Stephen Penwell, Morgan Stanley''s director of North American equity research, says his firm did a report that featured companies whose profit margins had risen even as global economic events such as the European debt crisis had intensified. They included discount chain Dollar General Corp. (DG), Dunkin'' Brands Group Inc. (DNKN) and Web services firm Rackspace Hosting Inc. (RAX) </p> <p>Good old-fashioned stock picking is coming back in vogue, Penwell says. Clients are beginning to make more bets and bigger bets. </p> <p>If investors are looking to make a big bet on AllianceBernstein, Craig Siegenthaler says they''re late to the party. On July 3, he concluded the shares would no longer outperform relative to other asset managers and downgraded them to a hold. </p> <h2>How We Crunched the Numbers </h2> <p>To create rankings of the top U.S. analysts by industry, Bloomberg Rankings worked with Greenwich Associates, a consultant to financial services firms. From December through March, Greenwich Associates interviewed buy-side analysts who use Wall Street research, asking each respondent to list the 10 firms they regarded as the most important sources of information on the industries they cover. </p> <p>About 60 percent of these discussions were in person; the balance were conducted online. Greenwich Associates interviewed a total of 945 analysts at 190 institutions, including banks, insurance companies, investment management firms, mutual funds, pension funds and hedge funds. </p> <p>These accounts represent an estimated total of $4.7 billion in commissions, or an average of almost $30 million in commissions per buy-side institution. Participating institutions were placed in seven tiers based on the commissions they generated. The responses of top-tier accounts received the greatest weight. </p> <p>Greenwich Associates received responses for 58 industries, and we included in the ranking the 34 industries that had at least 45 responses. For the final ranking, Bloomberg Markets researched and added the names of the sell-side analyst or analysts with prime responsibility for tracking each industry. </p> <h2>Commission Weighted </h2> <p>Greenwich Associates listed as many as five winning firms for some industries and as few as two for others. The number of firms selected was a function of their commission-weighted share of the institutional vote. Statistical ties occurred when the difference between weighted shares was small. When the difference between the second- and third-ranked firms was substantial, no No. 3 firm was named. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kathleen Miller and Chris Strohm" date="Aug 14, 2013  5:28 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-14/ibm-wins-biggest-u-s-cloud-computing-contract-after-cia-loss.html"><headline>IBM Wins Biggest U.S. Cloud-Computing Contract After CIA Loss</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM) said today it won its biggest cloud-computing contract
from the U.S. government, a 10-year agreement valued at as much
as $1 billion. </p>
<p>The Interior Department awarded similar pacts to nine other
suppliers, including Lockheed Martin Corp. (LMT), which also said the
agreement was its largest federal cloud contract. </p>
<p>The deals might reach a total of $10 billion, allowing the
agency to speed its efforts to move information to the cloud,
the Web-based pool of shared resources such as data storage and
software. Other U.S. departments may eventually tap the program. </p>
<p>The agreement shows that IBM''s ability to help
governments transform with new technologies, like cloud,
continue to grow, Michael Rowinski, a spokesman for the
Armonk, New York-based company, said in an e-mail. </p>
<p>The award is a coup following IBM''s loss to Amazon.com Inc.
in the competition for a four-year, $600 million cloud contract
with the Central Intelligence Agency. IBM may get another chance
at that business following a successful protest to a federal
office that arbitrates contract disputes. </p>
<p>While the Interior Department awards were issued in May,
the work and many of the companies'' announcements were delayed
by CenturyLink Inc. (CTL)''s protest. </p>
<h2>CenturyLink Protest </h2>
<p>CenturyLink, based in Monroe, Louisiana, in March sued the
government in the U.S. Court of Federal Claims, partly because
it said the Interior Department''s price and technical evaluation
criteria were unreasonable. It lost last month, and it didn''t
make the Interior Department''s list of 10 winners. </p>
<p>The agency''s cloud effort may end up being the biggest
across the federal government, Afzal Bari, a senior technology
analyst for Bloomberg Government, said in an interview. </p>
<p>The 10 companies selected to provide services under the
contract will have a competitive advantage in the expanding
cloud-computing industry, Bari said. </p>
<p>Other winners include CGI Group Inc. (GIB) of Montreal; Verizon
Communications Inc. (VZ), based in New York; Unisys Corp. (UIS), based in
Blue Bell, Pennsylvania; and ATT Inc. (T), based in Dallas. </p>
<p>Four closely held vendors made the list. They are Aquilent
Inc., based in Laurel, Maryland; Smartronix Inc., based in
Hollywood, Maryland; Autonomic Resources LLC, based in Cary,
North Carolina; and Global Technology Resources Inc., based in
Denver. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Scott Harrison" date="Aug 14, 2013  3:25 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-14/jpmorgan-said-to-plan-first-30-year-bond-sale-in-20-months-1-.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sells First 30-Year Benchmark Bonds Since December 2011</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the largest
U.S. bank, sold $750 million of 30-year bonds in its first
dollar-denominated benchmark issue of the maturity in 20 months. </p>
<p>The 5.625 percent, subordinated notes yielded 190 basis
points more than similar-maturity Treasuries, according to data
compiled by Bloomberg. Proceeds will be used for general
corporate purposes, the data show. Benchmark sales are typically
at least $500 million. </p>
<p>JPMorgan issued $1.25 billion of 5.4 percent, 30-year
debentures in December 2011 to yield 250 basis points more than
benchmarks, Bloomberg data show. The notes traded at 108 cents
on the dollar to yield 4.88 percent on Aug. 12, according to
Trace, the bond-price reporting system of the Financial Industry
Regulatory Authority. </p>
<p>Two former JPMorgan employees were charged today by U.S.
prosecutors with attempting to conceal trading losses last year
as part of a probe of the bank''s $6.2 billion loss on
derivatives trades. </p>
<p>Bruno Iksil, the Frenchman at the center of the case who
became known as the London whale because his portfolio was
so large, signed a non-prosecution agreement with the U.S. in
June, the government said today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Aug 14, 2013  2:02 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-14/microsoft-delays-xbox-release-in-eight-countries.html"><headline>Microsoft Delays Xbox Release in Eight Countries</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) said it is delaying the release of its Xbox One console in eight countries, including Russia and the Netherlands, until 2014 in order to make sure it has enough supply for larger markets. </p> <p>The company, which had planned to begin sales of the console in November in 21 countries, will now cut that to 13. It will push back the date for the Xbox One''s rollout in Belgium, Denmark, Finland, Norway, Sweden, Switzerland, Russia and the Netherlands. </p> <p>We understand this will be disappointing news for our fans in the impacted countries, and we are doing everything we can to bring Xbox One to you as soon as possible next year, Microsoft said in a blog post on its website. </p> <p>The delayed rollout is another issue for the Xbox One, which will sell for $499 and which has already seen Microsoft reversing itself on limits for reselling and trading games, as well as a requirement to connect the console to the Internet once a day. It will compete against Sony Corp.''s (6758) PlayStation 4, which will cost $399. Both consoles are crucial to the companies'' efforts to reach consumers in their living rooms. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Randall Hackley" date="Aug 14, 2013 10:20 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-14/ibm-in-smart-water-management-pact-with-vietnam-city-of-da-nang.html"><headline>IBM in Smart-Water Management Pact With Vietnam City of Da Nang</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The Vietnamese seaport of Da Nang
has reached agreement on smart-water and transit technology
improvements with International Business Machines Corp. (IBM), the
world''s biggest computer-services company said today. </p>
<p>Terms weren''t disclosed of the pact with Vietnam''s fourth-largest city. Da Nang Water Co. is expanding and modernizing its
water-treatment capacity using IBM''s real-time analysis and
monitoring of the water supply, IBM said. </p>
<p>Da Nang is upgrading its water and transportation system
infrastructure using sensors to cope with urban growth and a
shortage of water in the dry season, IBM said. </p>
<p>Water and transportation are the first two areas where we
are applying some of the most advanced technologies available,
Pham Kim Son, director of Da Nang''s Department of Information
and Communications, said in an e-mailed statement. </p>
<p>IBM is also helping the city manage water salinity
problems. The hydropower plant on the upper part of the Vu Gia
River that provides water to Da Nang has reduced supplies to the
city, Armonk, New York-based IBM said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elisa Martinuzzi, Sonia Sirletti and Sergio Di Pasquale" date="Aug 14, 2013  8:11 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-14/jpmorgan-broke-disclosure-rules-over-paschi-central-bank.html"><headline>JPMorgan Broke Disclosure Rules Over Paschi: Central Bank</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) broke
disclosure rules when it arranged a 1 billion-euro ($1.3
billion) exchangeable bond for Banca Monte dei Paschi di Siena
SpA in 2008, the Bank of Italy told Siena prosecutors. </p>
<p>JPMorgan should have informed the central bank the Italian
lender had guaranteed it against losing money on the bond sale,
the Bank of Italy said in an April 19 letter to prosecutors
filed at a Siena court. The Bank of Italy said it may have
withheld approval for the deal had it known about the indemnity. </p>
<p>No claim was ever made under this indemnity -- which only
existed for a matter of days -- including either for the benefit
of JPMorgan or any of its employees, JPMorgan said in a
statement. We believe that JPMorgan and its employees acted
correctly at all times. We will defend this action vigorously. </p>
<p>Monte Paschi (BMPS), the world''s oldest bank, received a 4.1
billion-euro government bailout earlier this year. The
investigation into the fundraising is part of a wider probe by
prosecutors into allegations the Siena-based lender hid losses
using derivatives, manipulated markets and obstructed regulators
probing its takeover of Banca Antonveneta SpA in 2008. </p>
<p>Monte Paschi issued notes that converted into its own
shares to boost capital following the Antonveneta purchase. As
part of the deal, the bank issued new shares to JPMorgan to
cover the potential conversion of the bonds and the central bank
authorized JPMorgan to hold about 10 percent of Monte Paschi''s
stock, the documents show. If investors failed to pay for the
notes after ordering them, Monte Paschi would have compensated
the New York-based bank, according to the filing. </p>




Photographer: Peter Foley/Bloomberg

<p>
JPMorgan Chase  Co. should have disclosed the indemnity because it could have reduced the total amount raised for Banca Monte dei Paschi di Siena SpA and the relationship could have affected its financial dealings with the Italian lender, according to the central bank. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Patricia Hurtado, Dawn Kopecki and Keri Geiger" date="Aug 14, 2013 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-14/jpmorgan-trading-charges-said-to-be-announced-tomorrow.html"><headline>JPMorgan Trading Charges Said to Be Announced Today</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The U.S. may announce charges as
early as today related to JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s trading losses
last year, a person familiar with the matter said. </p>
<p>Former bank employees in London have been investigated by
the U.S. Justice Department for more than a year over whether
they tried to conceal the losses at the largest U.S. bank, a
person familiar with the matter previously said. </p>
<p>JPMorgan lost more than $6.2 billion last year on
derivatives bets. The loss, first disclosed in May 2012, led to
an earnings restatement, a Senate subcommittee hearing and
probes by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission and
U.K. Financial Conduct Authority. </p>
<p>The episode prompted JPMorgan''s board to cut Chief
Executive Officer Jamie Dimon''s pay in half. </p>
<p>The penalties in the U.S. are significantly higher than
in the U.K., said Jeremy Summers, a lawyer at Slater  Gordon in
London. People faced with the possibility of being charged
here or the U.S. have sought to be dealt with here because they
are less draconian, Summers said. </p>
<p>Bruno Iksil, the former JPMorgan trader who became known as
the London Whale because of the size of his trading book and
losses, has been cooperating with the Federal Bureau of
Investigation and the Manhattan U.S. Attorney''s Office for
months in their probe of the New York-based bank''s biggest
trading debacle ever, said three people with direct knowledge
with the matter. </p>




Photographer: Simon Dawson/Bloomberg

<p>
The offices of JPMorgan Chase  Co., left, stand in the Canary Wharf business and shopping district in London. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Frier and David Wainer" date="Aug 15, 2013  4:20 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-15/ibm-said-to-be-paying-more-than-800-million-to-acquire-trusteer.html"><headline>IBM Said to Be Paying More Than $800 Million to Buy Trusteer</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM), the world''s largest seller of computer services, agreed
to buy Israeli security-software maker Trusteer Inc., giving it
fresh tools to fight the ever-escalating tactics of hackers. </p>
<p>IBM is paying more than $800 million for the company, said
a person familiar with the deal, who asked not to be identified
because financial terms weren''t disclosed. As part of the
transaction, IBM will form a cybersecurity software lab in
Israel with more than 200 researchers from both companies,
according to a statement today. </p>
<p>Trusteer sells software to protect financial institutions''
employees and customers from hackers. The startup, backed by
Israeli security entrepreneur Shlomo Kramer, aims to spot
threats conventional desktop programs miss, such as malicious
software on smartphones. IBM said Trusteer, which has offices in
Tel Aviv and Boston, serves seven of the 10 largest U.S. banks. </p>
<p>If we think of the most pressing problems which are
facing our clients today in security, a lot of it is related to
malware, fraud and sophisticated attacks, Brendan Hannigan,
general manager of IBM''s security systems division, said in an
interview. Trusteer had this strong technology that we didn''t
have within our division. </p>
<p>He declined to discuss the purchase price. </p>
<p>Trusteer Chief Executive Officer Mickey Boodaei said his
company will be able to use IBM''s sales network to distribute
its products more widely. </p>
<p>IBM has been buying up smaller software companies, which
generally are more profitable than hardware and services
companies, as it seeks to reach $20 in adjusted earnings per
share by 2015, from $15.25 last year. </p>
<h2>Cloud Expansion </h2>
<p>The Trusteer acquisition is also part of Armonk, New York-based IBM''s efforts to expand cloud-computing offerings --
services delivered to customers from remote data centers. </p>
<p>In June, IBM agreed to buy Dallas-based SoftLayer
Technologies Inc., a cloud-computing storage provider that will
help it compete with Amazon.com Inc. IBM paid almost $2 billion
in that deal, a person familiar with the matter said at the
time. SoftLayer had $335 million in revenue in 2012. </p>
<p>IBM fell 0.9 percent to $185.79 at the close in New York.
The shares have dropped 3 percent this year. </p>
<p>Trusteer''s acquisition price of about $800 million was
previously reported in the Israeli press. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Aug 15, 2013  9:59 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-15/morgan-stanley-leads-in-cutting-credit-correlation-risk.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Leads in Cutting Credit Correlation Risk</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) cut risk in its
credit-correlation portfolio by 69 percent from this year''s peak
as U.S. banks seek to reduce the capital tied to derivatives
businesses built up before the financial crisis. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s comprehensive-risk measure, which seeks to
estimate potential losses in correlation positions over one year
with 99.9 percent certainty, fell to $362 million at June 30,
from a high of $1.16 billion in the first quarter, according to
a regulatory filing by the New York-based company released this
week. The risk-weighted assets tied to that business dropped
$4.85 billion to $19.3 billion. </p>
<p>The bank halted large acquisitions of credit-correlation
portfolios in an effort to boost capital ratios after buying
positions with a notional value of more than $50 billion over
the past three years, Bloomberg News reported in May. Chief
Executive Officer James Gorman, 55, has said his company is
exiting structured businesses including securitization units to
focus on trading for clients. </p>
<p>Credit-correlation positions, primarily derivatives linked
to corporate debt, indexes of companies and tranches of those
indexes, produced billions of dollars of losses in the financial
crisis. They included complex products such as collateralized
debt obligations, or CDOs, that comprised pieces of other CDOs. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
A guard stands behind the Morgan Stanley logo at the company''s headquarters in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Aug 15, 2013  6:24 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-15/microsoft-blows-another-piece-of-the-xbox-one-s-launch-with-a-delay-in-europe.html"><headline>Microsoft Blows Another Piece of the Xbox One''s Launch With a Delay in Europe</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Two months ago, Microsoft announced its most aggressive Xbox launch ever, the simultaneous release of the new Xbox One in 21 countries on four continents. Too good to be true? Yes, as it turns out.</p><p>Microsoft overestimated both its ability to produce enough machines, and the time needed to translate and add local content to the Xbox dashboard, television apps and voice controls. The company said yesterday in a blog post that it''s delaying the rollout in eight European countries, including Russia, Belgium and Denmark. The change allows Microsoft to prioritize bigger gaming centers like the U.S., U.K., Australia, Brazil and Germany.</p><p>Even without those eight markets, the remaining 13 countries will still make the new console''s November release the biggest Xbox launch. The original Xbox''s November 2001 debut was a North America-only affair. The 360 was released in November 2005, initially in the U.S. and Canada, with Europe and Japan following the next month.</p><p>Microsoft is promising Xbox One consoles to the eight countries it''s leaving out "as soon as possible in 2014." Customers who pre-ordered special first-day models of the Xbox One will get a free game as a consolation prize. </p><p>The snafu is the latest in a summer of reversals and public-relations cleanup attempts by Microsoft''s Xbox unit. Since officially unveiling the console in May, the group has been trying to undo unpopular policies, like limits on used games and Internet connectivity requirements. Maybe now Microsoft can get back to telling customers what the Xbox One can do instead of what it won''t.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Aug 15, 2013 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-15/microsoft-s-first-chip-brings-tank-finding-design-to-xbox.html"><headline>Microsoft''s First Chip Brings Tank-Finding Design to Xbox</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), seeking to fend off
competition for its Xbox game console by souping up the Kinect
motion sensor, is tapping a new semiconductor developer: itself. </p>
<p>For the first time, the company will build its own
processors based on an in-house design. The new chips will make
Kinect more accurate and responsive using an imaging technology
found in military gear, said Cyrus Bamji, who played a key role
in developing the silicon architecture. Previously, Kinect
relied on an off-the-shelf chip from Israel''s PrimeSense Ltd. </p>
<p>Microsoft joins companies such as Apple Inc. (AAPL) that are doing
more work on chips internally to add exclusive features and set
their devices apart. Microsoft will package the Kinect with the
latest version of the Xbox later this year, adding $100 to its
price. Gamers who don''t see the value may be tempted to opt for
Sony Corp. (6758)''s $399 PlayStation 4, instead of Xbox One at $499. </p>
<p>We are seeing a big trend towards more of the hardware
makers out there, whether it''s smartphones or whether it''s
tablets, starting to bring more of that semiconductor function
in-house, said Jon Erensen, an analyst at market-research firm
Gartner Inc. It allows them to differentiate. Everybody in the
market is using the same off-the-shelf processor. </p>
<h2>Time of Flight </h2>
<p>Kinect is a camera-based device that connects to the Xbox
to let users translate body motions and voice commands into game
moves -- say, in a virtual tennis or car-racing game. The newest
version of the sensor will include TV controls. </p>
<p>The Kinect chips, designed by a team mostly based in
Microsoft''s Silicon Valley office, use a technology called Time
of Flight that will let the sensor track minute changes in a
user''s body, like finger movements and facial expressions, a
much more precise system than the earlier version. That lets
Microsoft eliminate some of the failings of the first Kinect,
Bamji said. </p>
<p>Time of Flight works by bouncing photons off a person or
object, and has been used by military agencies for tasks like
detecting a tank hiding behind tree cover, Bamji said. Texas
Instruments Inc. and Infineon Technologies AG are also
developing chips using Time of Flight. </p>
<p>When it goes on sale, Xbox One will face tough competition
from Sony''s new PlayStation 4, as well as Nintendo Co. (7974)''s Wii U.
Kinect in the past has largely appealed to kids and casual
gamers and hasn''t had much content targeted at serious gamers,
said Rob Sanfilippo, an analyst at Kirkland, Washington-based
Directions on Microsoft. The new version may still not lure
those customers from rivals. </p>
<h2>Design Challenge </h2>
<p>There''s also the challenge and cost of creating a new chip
from scratch, which can run into the tens of millions of dollars
and take months of testing. One mistake in design or
manufacturing slip-up can cause months of delay to a final
product. For a company like Microsoft, with less experience in
developing chips, there''s a risk that performance may not be as
expected, Gartner''s Erensen said. </p>
<p>Microsoft, which announced the shift in May, follows some
of the largest consumer-electronics makers in taking over more
of its own chip design. Apple''s iPhone and iPad run on
processors that the Cupertino, California-based company designs
itself and has manufactured by Samsung Electronics Co. While the
chips are based on ARM Holdings Plc technology, Apple customized
the layout and makeup of the chip''s components. </p>
<p>Samsung also is using more of its own chips in its mobile
phones, and LG Electronics Inc., HTC Corp. and Lenovo Group Ltd.
have all talked about it, Gartner''s Erensen said. </p>
<h2>Taking Note </h2>
<p>While Microsoft''s Xbox and WebTV units have previously done
some work designing chips, the company has never handled this
much of a chip''s design, development and assembly, said
Microsoft Distinguished Engineer Nick Baker, who leads the
silicon architecture and verification teams. The company has
about 200 people working on microprocessors. Only the mass
manufacturing for the Kinect chips has been handed off to a chip
foundry, Taiwan Semiconductor Manufacturing Co. </p>
<p>Other groups at Microsoft are taking notice, asking the
Xbox team about their work on chips, and may even pursue a
greater role in customizing their own microprocessors, said Todd
Holmdahl, the vice president who has overseen Xbox hardware
since the development of the first version in 1999. </p>
<h2>Custom Features </h2>
<p>The world''s largest software maker first moved into making
its own computer hardware last year with a line of tablets
called Surface. The company could choose to customize existing
chips in order to gain attention and new features for Microsoft-powered smartphones and tablets, which have a tiny share of both
those markets, Directions on Microsoft''s Sanfilippo said. </p>
<p>It''s pretty likely that Microsoft will be getting more
into the hardware business, he said. So it makes sense for
them to invest more right down to the silicon so they can have
proprietary features. </p>
<p>That investment may be crucial to the continued success of
Xbox, the bright spot among Microsoft''s consumer businesses,
especially as sales of the company''s Windows personal-computer
software stagnate and as Surface demand disappoints. Xbox
accounted for the bulk of revenue in Microsoft''s $10.2 billion
Entertainment and Devices division. </p>
<p>The appeal of Xbox One will rest partially on whether the
new chips improve on the previous Kinect. After Nintendo Co.''s
Wii introduced a handheld controller than let gamers play by
swinging and moving the device, Kinect pushed the envelope
further by integrating full-body motion and voice into games.
For some customers, it hasn''t delivered on its initial promise. </p>
<p>I''m unhappy with the way it works, Sanfilippo said of
the current Kinect. And I''m not sure if I would want the
device if I upgrade to an Xbox One. The selling point from
Microsoft is that this one is more accurate and faster. </p>
<h2>Precision Needed </h2>
<p>The PrimeSense chip in the previous Kinect, which sold 24
million units, or about one for every three Xbox 360 machines,
didn''t provide the precision and responsiveness that Microsoft
needed for the device. That version has trouble reading the
motions of small children, seated players and low-light
situations, Holmdahl said. </p>
<p>The new iteration handles those situations better and can
pick up even small changes, such as a finger movement, facial
expressions and heart rate, he said, and has a field of view
that''s 60 percent bigger than the previous Kinect. </p>
<p>As the new Xbox is rolled out for the holiday shopping
season, Microsoft will see whether the new chips can make Kinect
a bigger draw for both families and hard-core gamers -- and help
justify Xbox One''s premium price. </p>
<p>It''s super-important, Holmdahl said. We have an
opportunity to change the living room. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Mary Childs and Scott Harrison" date="Aug 15, 2013 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-15/jpmorgan-shows-charged-former-traders-no-bar-corporate-finance.html"><headline>JPMorgan Shows Charged Former Traders No Bar: Corporate Finance</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>On the same day prosecutors charged
two former JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) employees with concealing $6.2
billion of losses on derivatives trades, the bank persuaded bond
investors to lend it money for 30 years at an interest rate less
than similar securities. </p>
<p>The largest U.S. bank sold $750 million of bonds yesterday
that are due in 2043 and yield 5.68 percent, below the 6.38
percent average for similarly-rated, dollar-denominated
subordinated debt maturing in 20 to 40 years, according to data
compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Terms of the deal show that at least in the bond market,
JPMorgan is suffering little to no negative repercussions 16
months after Bloomberg News first reported that bets from its
chief investment office in London were distorting the
derivatives market. Bruno Iksil, the trader at the center of the
case who became known as the London Whale because his bets
were so big, pledged to cooperate with investigators. </p>
<p>Managers have moved past the Whale story, said Adrian Miller, director of fixed-income strategies at GMP Securities
LLC in New York. As it relates to JPM''s future business,
investors care little at this point. </p>
<p>The 5.625 percent, subordinated notes yielded 190 basis
points more than similar-maturity Treasuries, Bloomberg data
show. </p>
<p>Kristin Lemkau, a spokeswoman at JPMorgan in New York,
didn''t return telephone and e-mail messages seeking comment
about the new issue left after regular business hours. </p>
<h2>$6 Billion Ding'' </h2>
<p>Timing is 90 percent of life, Craig Pirrong, a former
futures trader and now a professor of finance at the University
of Houston, said of the subordinated debt issue and allegations.
Maybe investors will figure if they can survive a $6 billion
ding no problem, the bonds are safe as can be, he said. </p>
<p>Prosecutors said in court filings that Javier Martin-Artajo
and Julien Grout falsified the value of positions in JPMorgan''s
Synthetic Credit Portfolio, which the government said had been
profitable for the unit, raking in more than $1 billion in 2009. </p>
<p>Disclosed by Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon in May
2012, the bad derivative bets led to an earnings restatement, a
U.S. Senate subcommittee hearing and probes by the Securities
and Exchange Commission and U.K. Financial Conduct Authority. </p>
<h2>Next Crisis'' </h2>
<p>The divergent performances by the CIO unit in 2009 and 2012
demonstrate the yin and yang of that operation, Pirrong said
in an e-mail. In the next crisis, their trade could exacerbate
the problems rather than save them. </p>
<p>Credit-default swaps tied to the company''s debt, which
typically rise as investor confidence deteriorates, rose 0.8
basis point to a mid-price of 81.7 basis points yesterday, up
from a 2013 low of 72.3 basis points in March, according to
Bloomberg prices. A basis point equals $1,000 annually on a
contract protecting $10 million of debt. </p>
<p>The contracts, which pay the buyer face value if a borrower
fails to meet its obligations, less the value of the defaulted
debt, reached as high as 174 basis points in June 2012 as
investors sought to estimate the size of the loss. </p>
<p>JPMorgan never lost its investment-grade status in the eyes
of swaps traders, according to Moody''s Corp.''s capital markets
research group. At worst, the contract''s prices climbed to
levels in September and October that implied the debt should be
rated Baa2, the second-lowest step of investment grade. Moody''s
Investors Service grades the company A2, and Standard  Poor''s
an equivalent A. </p>
<h2>Earnings Increase </h2>
<p>Investment-grade debt is rated Baa3 or more by Moody''s and
BBB- at SP. </p>
<p>JPMorgan reported a 31 percent increase in second-quarter
profit of $6.5 billion on July 12 that beat analysts'' estimates
as revenue from trading stocks and bonds climbed. It was
profitable every year during the financial crisis. </p>
<p>In the context of the investment-grade corporate market,
a 30-year single-A rated subordinated note yielding 190 over
is attractive, said Bonnie Baha, the head of global developed
credit at Los Angeles-based DoubleLine Capital LP. </p>
<p>While JPMorgan is still big, still generating tremendous
profitability, and well-capitalized, buying bank debt and
benefiting as yields fell relative to Treasuries, a strategy
that''s been profitable since 2009, is getting toward the end
of the road, she said in a telephone interview. </p>
<p>Investors have made a lot of money on that play, but going
forward, where''s the revenue generation going to come from that
drives profitability? </p>
<h2>Narrowing Spread </h2>
<p>The average spread investors demand to hold U.S. bank bonds
has dropped to 153 basis points through yesterday, from as high
as 834 during the financial crisis, according to the Bank of
America Merrill Lynch U.S. Banking Corporate Index. That
compares with a spread of 150 basis points for industrial debt,
from 602 basis points in December 2008, according to a Bank of
America Merrill Lynch index of U.S. industrial issuers. </p>
<p>JPMorgan''s new subordinated notes were priced at a spread
closer to the average industrial bond rated at the lowest level
of investment grade, which fell to 198 basis points yesterday,
according to the Bank of America Merrill Lynch BBB U.S.
Industrial Excluding Financial, Telecom, Transportation and
Utility Index. </p>
<p>That enabled investors to get BBB-like spreads while
still getting a single-A rating, which is important for some
money managers, according to Joel Levington, managing director
of corporate credit for Brookfield Investment Management Inc. in
New York. </p>
<p>Most people don''t have a perfect view of an
organization''s risk policies and how they are implemented on a
daily basis, Levington said in an e-mail. JPMorgan was able
to take a big hit and bounce back quickly. That says something
about the earnings power and balance sheet quality here. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kathleen Miller and Chris Strohm" date="Aug 15, 2013 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-15/ibm-wins-its-largest-u-s-cloud-computing-contract.html"><headline>IBM Wins Its Largest U.S. Cloud-Computing Contract</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines Corp. (IBM) won a federal cloud-computing contract with a maximum value of $1 billion, its largest such agreement with the U.S. government. </p> <p>The Interior Department awarded similar, 10-year pacts to nine other suppliers, including Lockheed Martin Corp. (LMT), which also described the agreement as its largest federal cloud contract. </p> <p>The deals might reach a combined $10 billion, allowing the agency to speed its efforts to move information to the cloud, a Web-based pool of shared resources such as data storage and software. Other U.S. departments may eventually tap the program. </p> <p>The agreement shows that IBM''s ability to help governments transform with new technologies, like cloud, continue to grow, Michael Rowinski, a spokesman for the Armonk, New York-based company, said in an e-mail yesterday. </p> <p>The award is a coup following IBM''s loss to Amazon.com Inc. in the competition for a four-year, $600 million cloud contract with the Central Intelligence Agency. IBM may get another chance at that business following a successful protest to a federal office that arbitrates contract disputes. </p> <p>The Interior Department''s awards are central to transforming our overall IT capabilities, which we expect to result in benefits of $100 million each year from 2016 to 2020, said Andrew Jackson, the agency''s deputy assistant secretary for technology, information and business services. </p>




Photographer: Simon Dawson/Bloomberg

<p>
The agreement shows that IBM''s ability to help governments transform with new technologies, like cloud, continue to grow, Michael Rowinski, a spokesman for the Armonk, New York-based company, said in an e-mail yesterday. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Patricia Hurtado" date="Aug 16, 2013  5:21 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-16/jpmorgan-suit-with-bear-stearns-liquidators-is-ended.html"><headline>JPMorgan Suit With Bear Stearns Liquidators Is Ended</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A lawsuit against JPMorgan Chase 
Co. (JPM) by liquidators of two Bear Stearns Cos. hedge funds seeking
$1.5 billion over their collapse formally ended today after the
parties reached a settlement in June, according to court
records. </p>
<p>Bear Stearns Cos., two of its former managers, and auditor
Deloitte  Touche were accused of misleading investors in two
hedge funds with holdings in subprime mortgages that imploded
and filed for bankruptcy in July 2007. </p>
<p>Two former Bear Stearns fund managers who were named as
defendants, Ralph Cioffi and Matthew Tannin, were acquitted
after a federal trial in Brooklyn New York in 2009 of charges
they misled investors in the funds'' losses of $1.6 billion. </p>
<p>The complaint was filed by Stillwater Capital Partners LP
of New York, Essex Fund Ltd. of the Cayman Islands and Geoffrey
Varga and William Cleghorn, two liquidators appointed in the
Caymans to recover losses for investors in feeder funds. </p>
<p>The parties filed a stipulation with U.S. District Court
Judge Alvin Hellerstein today asking him to dismiss all claims
and counterclaims, citing an accord that was originally reached
last year. The judge issued a June 13 order that he would close
the case within 90 days if a settlement hadn''t been consummated. </p>
<p>JPMorgan bought Bear Stearns in 2008. </p>
<p>The case is Varga v. The Bear Stearns Cos., 08-03397, U.S.
District Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Naureen S. Malik" date="Aug 16, 2013  4:38 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-16/electricity-gains-from-maine-to-connecticut-amid-higher-demand.html"><headline>Electricity Gains From Maine to Virginia Amid Higher Demand</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Spot wholesale electricity rose from
Maine to Virginia as demand increased. </p>
<p>Consumers were using more power in New York City than the
state grid operator had predicted. Demand was also higher in New
England and on the 13-state PJM Interconnection LLC network
stretching from New Jersey into North Carolina and Illinois. </p>
<p>Temperatures were more seasonal today in those regions
following cooler readings the previous three days, according to
AccuWeather Inc. in State College, Pennsylvania. Boston was
expected to have a seasonal high of 80 degrees Fahrenheit (27
Celsius) while Chicago''s reading was forecast to be 4 lower than
the average at 78. </p>
<p>Spot on-peak power for Boston gained $4.56, or 17 percent,
to $31.89 a megawatt-hour as of 4:14 p.m. from yesterday''s full-day average of $27.32, which was the least since Aug. 5, grid
data compiled by Bloomberg showed.  On-peak hours are Monday
through Friday from 7 a.m. until 11 p.m. </p>
<p>ISO New England Inc. said power consumption on the six-state grid it manages was 17,265 megawatts at 3:40 p.m., topping
yesterday''s average of 17,091 megawatts in that hour. </p>
<p>The discount for Boston prices versus New York City
narrowed to $3.64 from $4.51 yesterday. New York City''s on-peak
average rose $3.70, or 12 percent, to $35.53. </p>
<p>Electricity for the PJM grid, which serves more than 60
million people from Washington to Chicago, reversed earlier
losses and gained for the first time in five days. </p>
<p>Spot on-peak prices at the benchmark Western hub advanced
$3.40, or 12 percent, to $31.76 a megawatt hour as of 4:14 p.m. </p>
<p>Increased demand also bolstered prices across California
while power prices dropped in Texas amid below-normal
temperatures. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sherry Su and Laura Hurst" date="Aug 16, 2013 12:19 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-16/chevron-offers-to-sell-forties-angola-crude-exports-to-increase.html"><headline>Chevron Offers to Sell Forties; Angola Crude Exports to Increase</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX) failed to sell North
Sea Forties crude even after lowering its offer. There were no
bids of offers for Russian Urals blend. </p>
<p>Angola, Africa''s second-largest oil producer, will export
55 crude cargoes in October, two more than in September, a
preliminary loading program obtained by Bloomberg News showed. </p>
<h2>North Sea </h2>
<p>Chevron was unable to sell Forties for Sept. 6 to Sept. 8
loading at a premium of $1.15 a barrel, 30 cents less than its
offer yesterday, according to a Bloomberg survey of traders and
brokers monitoring the Platts pricing window. </p>
<p>No bids or offers were made for Brent, Oseberg or Ekofisk
crudes. Reported crude trading typically occurs during the
Platts window, which ends at 4:30 p.m. London time. </p>
<p>Brent for October settlement traded at $110.19 a barrel on
the ICE Futures Europe exchange at the close of the window,
compared with $109.79 in the previous session. The November
contract was at $109.32, a discount of 87 cents to October. </p>
<p>North Sea Alvheim and connected oil fields were shut for
nine days of maintenance, according to Marathon Oil Corp. (MRO), which
operates the field. </p>
<p>Production from the Greater Alvheim Area is now shut
according to plan, Ingvar Solberg, a Stavanger, Norway-based
spokesman said in an e-mailed response to questions. Output
halted last night at Alvheim, Volund and Vilje fields, which
feed into Alvheim''s floating production, storage and offloading,
or FPSO, vessel. The Alvheim area produces about 120,000 barrels
a day before closure. </p>
<h2>Mediterranean/Urals </h2>
<p>PKN Orlen SA closed an import tender earlier today for
100,000 metric tons of Urals for Sept. 1 to Sept. 5 loading,
according to two people with knowledge of matter who asked not
to be identified because the information is confidential. The
result wasn''t known yet. </p>
<p>OAO Surgutneftegas issued a tender to sell Urals loading on
Sept. 5 to Sept. 6 from the Baltic Sea port of Primorsk,
according to two traders who participate in the market. The
tender closes on Aug. 19. </p>
<h2>West Africa </h2>
<p>Shipments from Angola will total 52.76 million barrels, or
1.7 million barrels a day, the plan showed. That compares with a
revised plan of 50.91 million, or 1.7 million barrels a day,
next month. Most consignments are 950,000 to 1 million barrels.
The final program will be released on Aug. 26. </p>
<p>Exports for September increased to 53 lots from 52 after
one Saturno cargo was added, a revised shipping schedule showed. </p>
<p>Nigeria''s loading programs for October and official selling
prices for September are expected to be released next week. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bloomberg News" date="Aug 16, 2013 12:26 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-16/goldman-in-lead-to-take-biggest-share-of-huarong-stake-ft-says.html"><headline>Goldman in Lead to Take Biggest Share of Huarong Stake, FT Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. is leading
the race to take the biggest share of a stake in China Huarong
Asset Management Co. before a stock sale by the so-called bad
bank, the Financial Times reported, citing two people close to
the transaction. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs, Morgan Stanley (MS) and Deutsche Bank AG (DBK) have
held talks about investing in Huarong Asset''s $1.5 billion share
sale ahead of a planned listing in Hong Kong next year, the FT
said. The newspaper cited another unnamed banker as saying only
a few meetings had been held and a deal is not expected until
December. </p>
<p>Eddie Naylor, a spokesman for Goldman Sachs, declined to
comment. Jeremy Hughes, a Deutsche Bank spokesman, declined to
immediately comment. A Morgan Stanley spokeswoman couldn''t
immediately be reached for comment. Phone calls to Beijing-based
China Huarong''s press office went unanswered. </p>
<p>Huarong Asset said in October it would seek Chinese and
foreign strategic investors and sell shares in local and
overseas markets. The nation''s Ministry of Finance owns 98.06
percent of the company, while China Life Insurance (Group) Co.
holds the rest, the ministry said in September. China Life is
the parent of publicly traded China Life Insurance Co. (2628) </p>
<p>Huarong Asset had first-half profit after provisions of 7.5
billion yuan ($1.2 billion), the most among the four asset
management companies the government set up in the 1990s to
dispose of non-performing loans at the nation''s biggest banks,
according to a July 24 statement on the firm''s website. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri and Cliff Edwards" date="Aug 16, 2013 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-16/disney-pits-jack-sparrow-against-activision-s-skylanders.html"><headline>Disney Enlists Buzz Lightyear to Lure Activision''s Gamers</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>An ad for Walt Disney Co. (DIS)''s new Infinity video-game system features the Pixar characters Buzz Lightyear and Sulley squaring off against a phalanx of movie villains. </p> <p>Real-world combat moves to toy stores Aug. 18 when Disney, the world''s largest entertainment company, introduces Infinity. The system, using technology that combines collectible figures with onscreen play, goes head-to-head with the top-selling Skylanders game from Activision Blizzard Inc. (ATVI), the largest independent U.S. video-game publisher. </p> <p>For Disney Chief Executive Officer Robert Iger, Infinity represents the best shot at reviving his only unprofitable division, an interactive unit that lost $216 million last year. The product will compete with Skylanders SWAP Force, the next installment in a $1.5 billion franchise that Activision CEO Robert Kotick is counting on as he engineers an $8.17 billion buyout of his largest investor. </p> <p>Disney is going to put a lot of marketing dollars into this platform, said Michael Hickey, a Denver-based analyst at Benchmark Co. They have a treasure chest of intellectual property. They''re going to market the hell out of it. </p> <p>Infinity links collectible figures with game consoles. When players set plastic characters from Disney''s Pirates of the Caribbean or Monsters movies on top of the unit, they appear on screen as game characters and can interact, the first time the company has put characters from different films together in a game. Additional toys and discs, introducing other characters and features, cost $5 to $13. </p>




Photographer: Patrick T. Fallon/Bloomberg

<p>
Members of the media receive a demonstration of the Walt Disney Co. Infinity video-game system during a Disney Interactive event in Los Angeles, on June 9, 2013. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David Fickling" date="Aug 19, 2013  7:03 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-19/coca-cola-amatil-profit-forecast-miss-estimates-on-supermarkets.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Amatil Profit, Forecast Miss Estimates on Supermarkets</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Coca-Cola Amatil Ltd. (CCL), Australia''s
largest listed drinks company, posted first-half profit that
missed analyst estimates and said a measure of full-year
earnings would be as much as 22 percent below expectations. </p>
<p>Net income fell 12 percent to A$216 million from A$246
million a year earlier, the Sydney-based company said in a
regulatory statement. That compared with the A$220 million
average estimate of three analysts surveyed by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Competition in Australian supermarkets, where Woolworths
Ltd. and Wesfarmers Ltd. (WES) units have an 80 percent market share,
weighed on profits, the company said. Full-year group earnings
before interest and tax may fall as much as four percent below
last year''s result, missing the A$890 million average of 11
analyst estimates by about 22 percent. </p>
<p>While the Australian non-grocery business continues to
perform well, the trading conditions in the grocery channel
continue to be challenging, Terry Davis, group managing
director, said in a statement. </p>
<p>Ebit fell 6.9 percent during the first half excluding one
time items. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Laura Hurst and Sherry Su" date="Aug 19, 2013 12:30 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-19/chevron-sells-forties-crude-libya-s-noc-issues-force-majeure.html"><headline>Chevron Sells Forties Crude; Libya''s NOC Issues Force Majeure</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX) sold North Sea Forties
crude at less than half the last traded differential in the
window, after offering the cargo for a fourth time. Total SA and
Eni SpA bought Russian Urals blend at lower prices. </p>
<p>National Oil Corp. declared a force majeure on crude and
product loadings from Es Sider, Ras Lanuf, Zueitina and El Brega
ports, according to document obtained by Bloomberg News. </p>
<h2>North Sea </h2>
<p>Chevron sold Forties F0902 for Sept. 7 to Sept. 9 loading
at a premium of 60 cents a barrel, 55 cents less than its offer
on Aug. 16, according to a Bloomberg survey of traders and
brokers monitoring the Platts pricing window. It traded at
premium of $1.25 on Aug. 14. </p>
<p>Royal Dutch Shell Plc withdrew an offer for Forties loading
Sept. 3 to Sept. 5 at 35 cents more than the cash cost of North
Sea crudes for October, the survey showed. </p>
<p>No bids or offers were made for Brent, Oseberg or Ekofisk
crudes. Reported crude trading typically occurs during the
Platts window, which ends at 4:30 p.m. London time. </p>
<p>Brent for October settlement traded at $110.41 a barrel on
the ICE Futures Europe exchange at the close of the window,
compared with $110.19 in the previous session. The November
contract was at $109.39, a discount of $1.02 cents to October. </p>
<p>Forties lot F0902 was delayed a second time by one day to
Sept. 7 to Sept. 9, said two people with knowledge of the
loading program, asking not to be identified because the
information is confidential. </p>
<h2>Mediterranean/Urals </h2>
<p>Total bought 100,000 metric tons of Urals crude for loading
at the Baltic Sea port of Primorsk on Aug. 30 to Sept. 3 from
Glencore Xstrata Plc at a 25 cents a barrel above Dated Brent,
the survey showed. That''s 40 cents less than the last trade
reported in the window on Aug. 12. </p>
<p>Vitol Group sold 80,000 tons of the Russian blend to Eni
for loading at the Mediterranean port of Novorossiysk on Aug. 30
to Sept. 3 at a premium of 15 cents to Dated Brent. </p>
<p>The four Libyan terminals are closed due to Oil Security
Guards who are on strike at these locations since the end of
July 2013, which resulted total shutdown for these facilities
and cease of all exports, NOC said in the document which is
dated Aug. 18 and signed by Chairman Nuri Berruien. </p>
<p>An NOC official said oil exports were currently at a rate
of about 500,000 barrels a day, using the port of Zawiya and
offshore loading platforms at the Mellitah, Al Jurf and Bouri
fields, while another port, Hariga, will probably resume
exports, at about 180,000 barrels a day, either tomorrow or the
day after. </p>
<p>OAO Surgutneftegas sold to Shell 100,000 tons of Urals
loading on Sept. 5 to Sept. 6 from the Baltic Sea port of
Primorsk via a tender, according to two traders who participate
in the market. </p>
<p>PT Pertamina, the Indonesian state-owned oil company,
bought 950,000 barrels of Azerbaijan''s Azeri Light crude for
October delivery, said a company official. The cargo is for its
Balikpapan refinery in East Kalimantan, said the official, who
asked not to be identified because he isn''t authorized to speak
to the media. </p>
<p>PTT Pcl, Thailand''s state-owned oil company, bought 600,000
barrels of Algeria''s Saharan Blend for October delivery to IRPC
Pcl''s Rayong refinery, said two people who participate in the
market. The company bought the grade from Concord Energy Pte.,
said the people who asked not to be identified because they
aren''t authorized to speak to the media. </p>
<h2>West Africa </h2>
<p>Indian Oil Corp. bought 1 million barrels each of Nigerian
Qua Iboe and Equatorial Guinea''s Zafiro crude grades through a
second tender for October loading, two traders with knowledge of
the matter said, asking not to be identified because the
information is confidential. </p>
<p>Mangalore Refinery  Petrochemicals Ltd. is seeking to buy
600,000 or 1 million barrels low-sulfur crude for loading Oct.
16 to Oct. 31 via a tender, according to a document obtained by
Bloomberg News. The tender closes Aug. 23 at 9:30 am local time
and offers are valid until 8pm Aug. 27. </p>
<p>Nigeria''s loading programs for October and official selling
prices for September are expected to be released this week. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Olga Kharif" date="Aug 19, 2013 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-19/mobile-payment-startups-no-match-for-paypal-tech.html"><headline>Mobile-Payment Startups No Match for PayPal: Tech</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The market for tools that help consumers buy goods using mobile phones is getting crowded, inundating small businesses, putting off venture capitalists and making it hard for many payment startups to make a buck. </p> <p>Just ask Kristy Fassio, owner of a Fit4Mom exercise franchise near Seattle. She''s getting bombarded with pitches from mobile and web-payment companies pledging to provide low-cost, easy ways for her to accept payments for the mom-focused workout classes she teaches. Some don''t even charge fees. </p> <p>Generally they are like, We can beat any price you are paying,'' Fassio said. They try to sell me on zero percent, but then they don''t make any money. </p> <p>Not making money -- while fine for merchants -- is rampant in a mobile-payments market that Crone Consulting LLC estimates has more than 100 competitors. Companies like Front Desk Inc., which Fassio uses, and Flint Mobile Inc. are going head-to-head with EBay Inc.''s (EBAY) PayPal and Square Inc. as well as traditional card-terminal providers, such as First Data Corp. </p> <p>They''re all vying for a piece of a market projected to reach $235.4 billion in global transaction value this year, up 44 percent from 2012, according to researcher Gartner Inc. That includes money transfers, bill payments and merchandise purchases. </p>




Photographer: Michael Nagle/Bloomberg

<p>
PayPal Inc. digital wallet payment options on a screen at the company''s shopping showroom in New York, in this Nov. 1, 2011 file photo. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Nikolaj Gammeltoft and Donal Griffin" date="Aug 20, 2013 11:29 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-20/goldman-says-exchanges-working-to-resolve-options-order-mishap.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Said to Send Stock-Option Orders by Mistake</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A programming error at Goldman Sachs Group Inc. caused unintended stock-option orders to flood American exchanges this morning, roiling markets and shaking confidence in electronic trading infrastructure. </p> <p>An internal system that Goldman Sachs uses to help prepare to meet market demand for equity options inadvertently produced orders with inaccurate price limits and sent them to exchanges, said a person familiar with the situation, who asked not to be named because the information is private. The size of the losses depends on which trades are canceled, the person said. Some have already been voided, data compiled by Bloomberg show. </p> <p>The mishap comes about a year after computers run by Knight Capital Group Inc. flooded U.S. equity markets with erroneous orders, a mistake that almost put the market-making firm out of business. Goldman''s error is fuel for critics of America''s electronic market structure, coming four months after the Chicago Board Options Exchange was shut down for 3 1/2 hours by a computer malfunction. </p> <p>This unfortunately was an error, and in the financial world an error can be a million-dollar error, Chip Hendon, the Cincinnati-based senior fund manager at Huntington Asset Management, said in a telephone interview. His firm oversees $16 billion. You can use the computer, but there has to be that human touch as well to try and catch errors. </p>




Photographer: Jin Lee/Bloomberg

<p>
A trader is reflected in a monitor as he works on the floor of the New York Stock Exchange. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Aug 20, 2013  5:10 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-20/jpmorgan-said-to-face-justice-department-probe-of-energy-trading.html"><headline>JPMorgan Said to Face Justice Department Probe of Energy Trading</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) faces a Justice
Department probe of its energy-trading practices after the bank
settled a regulator''s market-manipulation complaint last month,
a person with direct knowledge of the matter said. </p>
<p>U.S. Attorney Preet Bharara in Manhattan is scrutinizing
the conduct at issue in JPMorgan''s settlement with the Federal
Energy Regulatory Commission, said the person, who asked not to
be named because the investigation isn''t public. The inquiry is
in an early stage, the Wall Street Journal reported late
yesterday. Jerika Richardson, a spokeswoman for Bharara, and
Mark Kornblau at JPMorgan declined to comment on the probe. </p>
<p>J.P. Morgan Ventures Energy Corp. agreed last month to pay
$410 million in penalties and forfeited gains, and gave up its
claims to $262 million of disputed payments, to settle the
FERC''s allegations that the bank manipulated power markets to
enrich itself at the expense of consumers in California and the
Midwest from 2010 to 2012. While the deal released the New York-based company and its employees from future enforcement actions
by the regulator, it didn''t preclude other U.S. authorities from
pursuing their own investigations. </p>
<p>The FERC said JPMorgan''s energy-trading unit, which is
overseen by commodities chief Blythe Masters, engaged in 12
bidding strategies in wholesale energy markets from September
2010 to November 2012, resulting in tens of millions of dollars
in overpayments from grid operators. The agency announced the
violations July 29 after investigating for more than a year. </p>
<h2>FERC''s Discussions </h2>
<p>JPMorgan used strategies such as offering below-market
rates for some hours of energy production, then charging
exorbitantly high rates for hours that state bidders agreed to
pay for the plants to ramp production, the FERC said. </p>
<p>Masters, 44, was told in an October 2010 document that the
firm''s bidding strategies would enable it to produce $1.5
billion to $2 billion in gains through 2018, according to the
FERC. The FERC didn''t take action against any individuals. </p>
<p>JPMorgan accepted the facts in the settlement agreement
without admitting or denying wrongdoing, the FERC said at the
time. The firm announced last month that it''s looking for ways
to exit the physical commodities business, which includes energy
trading. </p>
<p>FERC Chairman Jon Wellinghoff has stepped up scrutiny of
corporations as the agency wields policing powers that were
expanded in the wake of Enron Corp.''s 2001 collapse. Since 2011,
the regulator has revealed at least 13 probes of energy-market
gaming. </p>
<p>Wellinghoff said in an interview last month that other
government entities are free to pursue penalties against
JPMorgan''s employees and that the FERC would cooperate with
them. He said he wasn''t aware of any separate investigations. </p>
<p>We have had some discussions with some agencies that I
can''t disclose at this time, he said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jesse Hamilton" date="Aug 20, 2013  4:31 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-20/morgan-drexen-sued-by-u-s-consumer-agency-over-debt-relief-fees.html"><headline>Morgan Drexen Sued by U.S. Consumer Agency Over Debt-Relief Fees</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Drexen Inc., a provider of
debt-relief services to consumers through law firms, charged
illegal upfront fees and deceived clients, according to a
lawsuit filed by the U.S. Consumer Financial Protection Bureau. </p>
<p>The Costa Mesa, California-based firm misled thousands of
customers with claims they wouldn''t be charged upfront fees and
would be debt-free in months, the CFPB said in a statement. The
lawsuit, filed today in U.S. District Court for the Central
District of California, said Morgan Drexen advertised debt-relief services and used a network of attorneys nationwide that
turned over most of their clients'' fees to the firm. </p>
<p>This company took advantage of people who were
struggling, said CFPB Director Richard Cordray, in a statement
today. The company charged consumers illegal fees and deceived
them about the services provided. We will hold them accountable
for these actions. </p>
<p>U.S. law bans debt-relief providers from charging for their
services before a debt is settled or reduced. The company was
charging such fees and also charged for bankruptcy services
without performing any significant work, the agency said, adding
that Morgan Drexen had more than 22,000 customers since October
2010. </p>
<p>The firm filed a lawsuit last month to block the CFPB
probe, claiming the bureau is unconstitutional. The CFPB lacks
the accountability the Constitution requires for a government
agency and the law provides no definition of the unfair and
deceptive practices the bureau is supposed to police, according
to the company''s lawsuit. </p>
<p>CFPB has chosen to engage in procedural gamesmanship by
opening a new front to the lawsuit, the company said in an e-mailed statement today. This is disruptive and inefficient and
distracts from what we should be doing, which is preparing to
present arguments to the D.C. court on the constitutionality of
the CFPB structure. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kevin Dugan" date="Aug 20, 2013  4:18 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-20/jpmorgan-sells-its-largest-structured-note-tied-to-s-p-500-index.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sells Its Largest Structured Note Tied to S&amp;amp;P 500 Index</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) sold $102.7
million of notes tied to the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index, the
bank''s largest such offering since at least 2010. </p>
<p>The one-year securities, issued Aug. 16, yield twice the
gains of the benchmark, with returns capped at 15.7 percent and
all capital at risk, according to a prospectus filed with the
U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. The bank, which
distributed the notes for a 1 percent fee, estimated their
initial value at 99 cents on the dollar. </p>
<p>Issuers have sold $5.21 billion of securities linked to the
stock benchmark this year, 23 percent less than the $6.76
billion during the same period in 2012, according to data
compiled by Bloomberg. JPMorgan has issued $291.2 million of
notes tied to the index in 2013, less than half the $585.7
million during same period last year. </p>
<p>Justin Perras, a spokesman for the bank in New York,
declined to comment. </p>
<p>The benchmark of 500 U.S. companies, which is the most
popular underlying asset for U.S. structured notes, has risen
15.9 percent this year to 1,652.35 at the close of trading
today. </p>
<p>Bloomberg started to collect comprehensive data on SEC-registered structured-note offerings in 2010. </p>
<p>Banks create structured notes by packaging debt with
derivatives to offer customized bets to retail investors while
earning fees and raising money. Derivatives are contracts that
have a value derived from stocks, bonds, commodities and
currencies, or events such as changes in interest rates or the
weather. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Donal Griffin" date="Aug 20, 2013  3:31 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-20/goldman-sachs-working-with-exchanges-to-resolve-options-trades.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Working With Exchanges to Resolve Options Trades</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. is working
with exchanges to resolve faulty options trades that roiled
markets this morning and any losses would not be material to
the financial condition of the firm, according to an e-mail
from spokesman David Wells. </p>
<p>At least three operators of U.S. options exchanges are
reviewing trades that took place at the beginning of the day and
NYSE Amex Options said most of the transactions may be canceled. </p>
<p>A large number of trades in tickers beginning with
letters H through L in the first 17 minutes are being examined
by NYSE Amex Options, it said in a statement. CBOE Holdings, the
largest venue, said it is examining trades between 9:30 and 9:41
a.m. Nasdaq OMX Group Inc. is reviewing options transactions
from 9:30 to 9:47 a.m., according to its website. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri and Andy Fixmer" date="Aug 21, 2013  6:20 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-21/disney-s-espn-holds-preliminary-talks-for-web-based-pay-tv.html"><headline>Disney''s ESPN Holds Preliminary Talks for Web-Based TV</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS)''s ESPN sports
network has held preliminary talks to offer programming on a
Web-based TV service like those proposed by Google Inc. (GOOG), Sony
Corp. and Intel Corp. (INTC) </p>
<p>An Internet TV provider would have to pay as much or more
than cable and satellite services, President John Skipper said
today at ESPN''s campus in Bristol, Connecticut. He declined to
specify the companies ESPN has spoken with. </p>
<p>A Web-based service would have to buy the whole suite of
products, Skipper said. We''re not going to offer one-offs.
The network includes the flagship channel, plus others such as
ESPN2, ESPN News and mobile applications offered to existing
pay-TV subscribers. </p>
<p>Access to ESPN would give new online TV providers instant
credibility and a foothold to compete with established players
like Comcast Corp. and DirecTV. The network is the most valuable
channel on pay TV, garnering the highest subscriber fees on
basic cable, according to researcher SNL Kagan. </p>
<p>Talks with alternative TV providers are exploratory and any
new platform would have to offer a package of channels
comparable to what other operators provide, according to Chris LaPlaca, a spokesman for ESPN. </p>
<p>To get deals done with ESPN and other networks, the new
providers will have to guarantee minimum subscriber numbers and
pay the associated fees even if fewer viewers sign up, David Bank, an analyst at RBC Capital in New York, wrote in an e-mail. </p>




Photographer: Jonathan Alcorn/Bloomberg

<p>
Walt Disney Co.''s ESPN is the most valuable channel on pay TV, garnering the highest subscriber fees of any basic cable network, according to researcher SNL Kagan. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Katia Porzecanski" date="Aug 21, 2013  5:05 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-21/goldman-sachs-hires-deutsche-bank-s-roca-for-latin-america-1-.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Hires Deutsche Bank''s Roca for Latin America</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. hired Mauro Roca from Deutsche Bank AG as an economist for Latin America,
according to a person familiar with the matter. </p>
<p>Roca had worked as a local markets strategist and senior
economist in Deutsche Bank''s Latin America group since 2010 and
previously held jobs at the International Monetary Fund,
Barclays Plc and Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. </p>
<p>Andrea Raphael, a spokeswoman at Goldman Sachs, and Roca
declined to comment on his employment at the firm. The company''s
Latin America economics team is led by managing director Alberto Ramos. </p>
<p>Roca''s departure from Deutsche Bank''s Latin America group
follows those of corporate credit analyst Natalia Corfield and
economist Fernando Losada. Amanda Williams, a spokeswoman for
Deutsche Bank, declined to comment on the departures. </p>
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. hired Corfield to join its emerging-market corporate credit research group, two people with direct
knowledge of the matter said Aug. 12. Losada joined
AllianceBernstein LP as senior economist for Latin America in
May, according to Jonathan Freedman, a spokesman for the New
York-based firm. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andy Fixmer" date="Aug 21, 2013  4:12 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-21/disney-abc-tv-division-said-to-cut-175-jobs-in-efficiency-drive.html"><headline>Disney Said Cutting 2.3% of Positions at ABC TV Division</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS)''s ABC television
division is cutting about 175 jobs as part of a restructuring of
the broadcast business, according to a person with knowledge of
the situation. </p>
<p>The cuts amount to about 2.3 percent of the unit''s
approximately 7,600 employees, said the person, who asked not to
be identified because the numbers aren''t being announced. ABC
lost about 10 percent of its prime-time viewers in a key
audience demographic last season. </p>
<p>The move follows several hundred job cuts at Disney''s ESPN
and the film and interactive divisions. ABC is eliminating
positions as the network rolls out new technology, including a
Watch ABC application for mobile devices that provides a live-stream of its broadcast. The primary areas affected will be ABC
operations and owned stations in eight markets, including New
York and Los Angeles, the person said. </p>
<p>As technological advances continue to alter the
competitive landscape and viewer habits, it''s incumbent upon us
to stay ahead of the curve, Burbank, California-based ABC said
today in an e-mailed statement. To that end, we''ve undergone a
review of our organizational structures and processes. </p>
<p>The restructuring will begin tomorrow and take about a week
to complete, the person said. Changes will occur across the
Disney/ABC Television Group, which includes the Disney Channel
and ABC Family cable networks, the person said. Some new
positions may also be created, the person said. </p>
<h2>TV Ratings </h2>
<p>Disney, owner of theme parks in California and Florida, had
about 166,000 employees at the end of September 2012, according
to a company filing. </p>
<p>ABC finished the prime-time TV season in May last among the
major broadcast networks in viewers ages 18 to 49, the group
most targeted by advertisers, according to Nielsen data. The
network averaged 7.84 million total viewers a night for second
place among the four major U.S. broadcast networks. </p>
<p>Disney, the world''s largest entertainment company, fell 1.2
percent to $61.14 at the close in New York. The stock has gained
23 percent this year, beating the 15 percent gain of the
Standard  Poor''s 500 Index. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Anthony Palazzo" date="Aug 21, 2013  4:07 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-21/disney-to-shutter-10-year-old-toontown-multiplayer-game.html"><headline>Disney to Shutter 10-Year-Old Toontown Multiplayer Game</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS) will close its 10-year-old Toontown Online video game and two other virtual worlds
for kids, as the company''s interactive unit shifts resources
toward the larger Club Penguin and to mobile games. </p>
<p>Toontown, in which members form teams to fight evil robots,
will close on Sept. 19, according to a website announcement. The
$9.95-a-month game, which Disney called the first massively
multiplayer online title for kids and families, made its debut
in June 2003. Pirates of the Caribbean Online and Disney Fairies
Pixie Hollow will also close. </p>
<p>We are shifting our development focus toward other online
and mobile play experiences, such as Club Penguin and a growing
selection of Disney Mobile apps, the Burbank, California-based
company said in an e-mailed statement. </p>
<p>The changes leave the $7.95-a-month Club Penguin as the
only so-called virtual world operated by Disney. The site,
acquired in 2007, is the largest of its kind, according to the
company, which is asking players to move there. Club Penguin has
added content tied to characters from Star Wars and Pixar
films such as Monsters University. More than 200 million
penguin characters have been created, Variety reported in July. </p>
<p>Chairman and Chief Executive Officer Robert Iger has been
working to shore up Disney''s interactive unit, which lost $216
million last year. This week, the company introduced its
Infinity video-game system, which features collectibles
including Pixar''s Buzz Lightyear and Captain Jack Sparrow from
Pirates of the Caribbean. </p>
<p>Disney, the world''s largest entertainment company, fell 1.2
percent to $61.14 at the close in New York. The stock has
climbed 23 percent this year, beating the 15 percent gain of the
benchmark Standard  Poor''s 500 Index. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Monks" date="Aug 21, 2013 11:20 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-21/jpmorgan-securities-industry-banker-william-cruger-said-to-leave.html"><headline>JPMorgan Securities Industry Banker William Cruger Said to Leave</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>William Cruger, an investment banker
focused on securities industry deals for JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM),
has left the firm, a person with knowledge of the matter said. </p>
<p>Cruger left in June, the person said, asking not to
identified because his plans are not public. The Financial
Industry Regulatory Authority Inc.''s website shows he is no
longer with the New York-based firm. Cruger was registered as an
employee of JPMorgan since 1997, the website shows. </p>
<p>Cruger, who advised Raymond James Financial Inc. on its
$930 million purchase of Morgan Keegan  Co. from Regions
Financial Corp. last year, is the second senior adviser to
exchanges and other securities businesses to leave JPMorgan
recently. His colleague Joseph Molluso has left to join
electronic trading firm Virtu Financial LLC, the person said. </p>
<p>Justin Perras, a spokesman at JPMorgan, declined to comment
on the departures. Cruger, Molluso and officials at closely held
Virtu couldn''t immediately be reached. </p>
<p>The departure of Molluso, who had been with JPMorgan since
2006, was reported by the Wall Street Journal this month. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Nikolaj Gammeltoft and Alex Barinka" date="Aug 21, 2013  9:57 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-21/goldman-options-error-shows-peril-persists-one-year-after-knight.html"><headline>Goldman''s Options Error Shows Peril Persists After Knight</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>For all the efforts to shore up
electronic markets in the aftermath of one of America''s biggest
trading catastrophes, yesterday''s options malfunction by Goldman
Sachs (GS) Group Inc. shows the dangers haven''t gone away. </p>
<p>A programming error caused the firm to send unintentional
stock options orders in the first minutes of trading, pushing
prices on dozens of contracts to a dollar each, according to a
person briefed on the matter yesterday and data compiled by
Bloomberg. Any losses for Goldman Sachs, the fifth-largest U.S.
bank by assets, won''t be known until exchanges determine which
contracts should be canceled, said the person, who requested
anonymity because the information is private. </p>
<p>Investors who fret about the increasing dominance of
electronic exchanges say the error at Goldman Sachs, which
generated about half its revenue from trading last quarter,
shows that worse breakdowns are inevitable. A year ago, Knight
Capital Group Inc. was pushed to the brink of bankruptcy by a
trading breakdown, and Chinese regulators are investigating
broker Everbright (601788) Securities Co. after $3.8 billion of incorrect
buy orders sent the Shanghai Composite Index up about 6 percent
in two minutes last week. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
Lloyd Blankfein, chief executive officer of Goldman Sachs Group Inc., in Washington, D.C., on June 13, 2013. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Peter Burrows" date="Aug 21, 2013  7:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-21/goldman-invests-40-million-in-salesforce-rival-sugarcrm.html"><headline>Goldman Invests $40 Million in Salesforce Rival SugarCRM</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>SugarCRM Inc., a maker of sales-tracking software, raised $40 million from Goldman Sachs Group
Inc. to speed global expansion as it takes on larger rivals
Oracle Corp. (ORCL) and Salesforce.com Inc. (CRM) </p>
<p>The Cupertino, California-based company will use the cash
to invest in research and development as well as sales and
marketing, Chief Executive Officer Larry Augustin said in an
interview. Sugar 7, the latest version of SugarCRM''s customer-relationship management software, will debut in October. </p>
<p>We think the opportunity for CRM is vastly
underpenetrated, Augustin said. We figure there are 450
million to 500 million people in customer-facing roles. Today,
commercial CRM companies serve maybe 20 million of them. </p>
<p>Investors on the public and private markets are circling
emerging business software providers as companies move away from
traditional packaged and desktop software. Cloud-based providers
like Workday Inc. (WDAY) and ServiceNow Inc. (NOW) have soared since their
initial public offerings last year, while startups such as Box
Inc., Zendesk Inc. and New Relic Inc. have raised growth-equity
rounds from large institutional investors. </p>
<p>Before this investment, SugarCRM had raised $79 million.
Augustin wouldn''t comment on the valuation, saying only that
it''s up and to the right since the last investment round
early last year. </p>
<p>SugarCRM, founded in 2004, added 600 new customers in the
second quarter, bringing the total to 6500 commercial clients.
Most individual users run a free version of the program, and
paying customers are charged $35 to $100 per user per month.
Sales rose 30 percent in the second quarter from the same period
a year earlier, about half the growth rate for all of 2012. </p>
<h2>Nearing Profit </h2>
<p>Augustin, who said late last year that the company may go
public as soon as 2013, declined to comment further on its
plans. The company has 400 employees and is close to
profitability, he said. </p>
<p>Antoine Munfa, a vice president at New York-based Goldman,
will join SugarCRM''s board. The investment was made by Goldman''s
Private Capital Investing group, which backs growth and mid-sized companies in North America. </p>
<p>The CRM market is ripe for technologies and products that
change the face of how enterprises conduct business with their
customers, Munfa said in today''s statement. SugarCRM, with
its user-centric vision and product design, has stepped up to
meet a real market need. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri" date="Aug 21, 2013 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-21/disney-opening-sabotaged-by-fake-tickets-balky-plumbers.html"><headline>Disney Opening Sabotaged by Fake Tickets, Balky Plumbers</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt''s dream is a nightmare. Crowds gripe over long waiting lines. Opening day was a confused mess. </p> <p>These were the first newspaper reviews of Disneyland, the California theme park that debuted one scorching day in July 1955. </p> <p>As a junior publicist hired a month earlier, Marty Sklar had an inside view of the event which included women''s heels stuck in the hot asphalt, not enough water fountains due to a plumber''s strike and attendance double what was planned because of ticket counterfeiting. </p> <p>He remembers Davy Crockett star Fess Parker, mounted on his steed, pleading: Marty, help me get out of here before this horse kills somebody. Sklar escorted them both backstage. </p> <p>Disney''s PR staff turned things around by inviting the press to come back at night, when the park wasn''t so crowded. </p> <p>Sklar went on to become president of the Walt Disney Co. (DIS)''s Imagineering unit, which designs the company''s parks and hotels, and has now written a memoir called Dream It! Do It! (Disney Editions, $24.99). In an interview, he described the company''s early days and why the world''s largest licensor may never lend its name to a car. </p> <p>Palmeri: What was it like to work with Walt? </p> <p>Sklar: He was not the kind of person who would pat you on the back and say Great idea. He just expected it. Dick Irvine (a design executive) was a master at getting something in position, something Walt could build on. Walt loved plus-ing other people''s ideas. That was exciting to be around. </p>




Source: Disney via Bloomberg

<p>
"Dream It! Do It!: My Half-Century Creating Disney''s Magic Kingdoms," by Marty Sklar. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki, Keri Geiger and Lindsay Fortado" date="Aug 22, 2013  7:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-22/jpmorgan-said-to-face-whale-fines-as-soon-as-next-month.html"><headline>JPMorgan Said to Face Whale'' Fines as Soon as Next Month</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>U.K. and U.S. regulators are
preparing to impose fines as soon as mid-September on JPMorgan
Chase  Co. (JPM) after an investigation into the bank''s London
trading losses last year, a person with direct knowledge of the
matter said. </p>
<p>The U.K.''s Financial Conduct Authority and the U.S.
Securities and Exchange Commission are in negotiations with the
New York-based company to settle their probes, according to the
person, who asked not to be identified because the talks aren''t
public. In the U.S., the Commodity Futures Trading Commission
and the Justice Department are also investigating events
surrounding the losses. </p>
<p>JPMorgan, the biggest U.S. bank by assets, lost more than
$6.2 billion last year on derivatives bets made by Bruno Iksil,
a trader who was dubbed the London Whale because of the size of
his positions. The U.S. last week charged Javier Martin-Artajo
and Julien Grout, two of Iksil''s former colleagues, with wire
fraud and conspiracy charges for allegedly seeking to hide
losses. Iksil is cooperating with the U.S. in the case. </p>
<p>Spokesmen for JPMorgan, the SEC and the FCA declined to
comment. </p>
<p>The SEC, which also sued Martin-Artajo and Grout last week,
wrote in its complaint that JPMorgan failed to furnish to the
commission, in accordance with the rules and regulations
prescribed by the commission, such financial reports as the
commission has prescribed. JPMorgan, which restated last
year''s first-quarter earnings because of the losses, is
expecting multiple fines from regulators investigating the
losses, a person familiar with the matter said last week. </p>




Photographer: Simon Dawson/Bloomberg

<p>
Pedestrians walk along the dockside near the offices of JPMorgan Chase  Co. in the Canary Wharf business and shopping district in London. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ari Levy" date="Aug 22, 2013 12:32 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-22/microsoft-former-president-sinofsky-joins-andreessen-horowitz.html"><headline>Microsoft Former President Sinofsky Joins Andreessen Horowitz</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Steven Sinofsky, the former
Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) executive who was pushed out in November, said
on his blog that he''s joined venture-firm Andreessen Horowitz as
a board partner. </p>
<p>In this position I will represent the firm on the boards
of portfolio companies when the opportunities present
themselves, but will not be a full-time member of the firm,
Sinofsky wrote. Sinofsky added that he will keep his current
position as executive in residence at Harvard Business School. </p>
<p>Andreessen Horowitz has been staffing up with experienced
technology executives since opening in 2009. In addition to
founders Marc Andreessen and Ben Horowitz, who have worked
together since the 1990s, the firm''s partners also include
former OpenTable Inc. (OPEN) Chief Executive Officer Jeff Jordan,
IronPort Systems Inc. co-founder Scott Weiss and SuccessFactors
Inc. founder Lars Dalgaard. </p>
<p>Andreessen Horowitz, based in Menlo Park, California,
confirmed the hiring of Sinofsky in an e-mail and said he will
not be an investing partner. </p>
<p>Sinofsky, a 23-year Microsoft veteran, left the Redmond,
Washington-based company last year after clashes with
executives, including CEO Steve Ballmer, people with knowledge
of the matter said in November. Sinofsky was president of the
Windows operating system division. </p>
<p>Bloomberg LP, the parent of Bloomberg News, is an investor
in Andreessen Horowitz. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass and Ian King" date="Aug 22, 2013 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-22/microsoft-says-bribery-investigation-includes-russia.html"><headline>Microsoft Says Bribery Investigation Includes Russia</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), the world''s largest
software maker, said it''s cooperating with federal authorities
investigating possible illegal activity by employees and
business partners in Russia and Pakistan. </p>
<p>The company takes every allegation seriously and will
cooperate fully with any government inquiries, John Frank,
Microsoft''s deputy general counsel, wrote in a blog posting
yesterday. Mark Murray, a spokesman for Microsoft, confirmed
that the software maker''s activities in Russia and Pakistan are
now part of an investigation. </p>
<p>The statement followed a Wall Street Journal report that
federal regulators are extending their examination of the
company''s relations with business partners that allegedly bribed
foreign officials for contracts. The investigation had earlier
looked into allegations made by a former Microsoft
representative in China, and the company''s relationships with
resellers and consultants in Romania and Italy, the newspaper
said. </p>
<p>John Nester, a spokesman for the U.S. Securities and
Exchange Commission, and Michael Passman, a Justice Department
spokesman, didn''t immediately return e-mails seeking comment on
the probe. </p>
<p>Microsoft, based in Redmond, Washington, said it employs
more than 50 people to investigate potential breaches of company
policy, as well as 120 more people to make sure the software
maker complies with local laws and regulations. </p>
<p>Microsoft said in March that that lawyers from the Justice
Department and the SEC were examining allegations that Microsoft
partners bribed foreign government representatives in exchange
for software contracts, following a Wall Street Journal report. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kevin Dugan" date="Aug 23, 2013  5:06 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-23/jpmorgan-sells-largest-worst-of-structured-note-this-year.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sells Largest ''Worst-of'' Structured Note This Year</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) sold $50.4
million of four-year notes tied to the least performing of two
stock indexes and an exchange-traded fund, the largest worst
of offering this year. </p>
<p>The securities, issued on Aug. 21, yield 8 percent a year
as long as the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index, the Russell 2000
Index and the iShares MSCI EAFE ETF are all at least 60 percent
of their initial value with all capital at risk, according to a
prospectus filed with the U.S. Securities and Exchange
Commission. The bank distributed the notes, which can be called
in as soon as three months, for a 1.75 percent fee and estimated
their value at 97 cents on the dollar at the time of sale. </p>
<p>Justin Perras, a spokesman for JPMorgan in New York,
declined to comment. </p>
<p>Sales of worst-of notes have soared to $1.27 billion this
year, 23 percent more than the $1.03 billion issued in all of
2012, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. The securities
have become more popular as issuers look for ways to construct
bonds with higher yields. </p>
<p>Correlation between changes in the Russell 2000 and iShares
MSCI EAFE dropped to .75 this year from .83 for all of 2012,
Bloomberg data show. The closer the correlation is to one, the
more the prices of assets tend to move together. Notes tied to
less correlated assets can give investors better terms. </p>
<p>Banks create structured notes by packaging debt with
derivatives to offer customized bets to retail investors while
earning fees and raising money. Derivatives are contracts whose
value is derived from stocks, bonds, commodities and currencies,
or events such as changes in interest rates or the weather. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Scott Moritz, Sarah Frier and Dina Bass" date="Aug 23, 2013  5:01 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-23/microsoft-says-ceo-ballmer-to-retire-within-next-twelve-months.html"><headline>Microsoft CEO Ballmer to Retire Within Next 12 Months</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) Chief Executive Officer Steve Ballmer, who has struggled to adapt the world''s largest software maker to the shift away from personal computers and toward mobile devices, will retire after more than a decade at the helm. </p> <p>Ballmer, 57, plans to step down within 12 months, Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft said today in a statement. The company''s lead independent director, John Thompson, will oversee the search for his successor, heading a committee that will also include Microsoft co-founder Bill Gates. Investors applauded the move, sending the shares up the most since 2009. </p> <p>Ballmer''s move reflects the changes roiling the computing industry his company helped pioneer. Microsoft, which supplies the software running most PCs, lost almost half its value on Ballmer''s watch. The stock hasn''t closed above $50 since his first year on the job amid competition from Google Inc. (GOOG), Apple Inc. (AAPL) and Facebook Inc. (FB) in everything from tablets to the Web. </p> <p>Related Features:</p>
Ballmer Fortune Up $625 Million as Microsoft CEO Retires
Ballmer Exit Leaves Microsoft Searching for Hero in Slump
Ballmer''s Four Craziest Moments
Lenovo Turns to Startup to Bring Start Menu Back to Windows
Sony Milks Xbox One Delay With Big PlayStation 4 Showing in Europe
<p>There is never a perfect time for this type of transition, but now is the right time, Ballmer wrote in a memo to employees today that was posted on Microsoft''s website. We need a CEO who will be here longer term for this new direction. </p>




Photographer: SeongJoon Cho/Bloomberg

<p>
Steve Ballmer, chief executive officer of Microsoft Corp., in Seoul, South Korea. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Graham Morrison" date="Aug 23, 2013  3:01 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-23/microsoft-ceo-ballmer-to-retire-within-next-12-months-photos.html"><headline>Microsoft CEO Ballmer to Retire Within Next 12 Months: Photos</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. Chief Executive
Officer Steve Ballmer, who has struggled to adapt the world''s
largest software maker to the shift away from personal computers
and toward mobile devices, will retire after more than a decade
at the helm. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Frier and Ian King" date="Aug 23, 2013 12:18 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-23/microsoft-said-not-to-consider-gates-for-ceo-role-after-ballmer.html"><headline>Microsoft Said Not to Consider Gates for CEO Role After Ballmer</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), seeking a successor to Chief Executive Officer Steve Ballmer, doesn''t plan to consider co-founder Bill Gates for the role, according to two people with knowledge of the matter. </p> <p>Gates, who is on the committee in charge of finding a new CEO, plans to stay on in his role at the Bill  Melinda Gates Foundation, a philanthropic organization, said one of the people, who asked not to be identified because the search is private. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Laura Marcinek" date="Aug 23, 2013 11:37 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-23/jpmorgan-worth-30-more-if-broken-up-kbw-says.html"><headline>JPMorgan Worth 30% More If Broken Up, KBW Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the biggest
U.S. bank by assets, would be worth 30 percent more if broken
into its four business segments, an unlikely scenario, an
analyst at Stifel Financial Corp. (SF)''s KBW unit said. </p>
<p>JPMorgan''s businesses -- traditional banking, investment
banking, asset management and private equity -- are separately
worth $255.7 billion, KBW''s Christopher Mutascio said today in a
note. That compares with the New York-based lender''s $197
billion market capitalization as of yesterday''s closing price. </p>
<p>While the possibility of breaking up JPMorgan is quite
low, it could potentially result in substantial upside for
current shareholders if the segments were valued like similar
companies, Mutascio wrote in the note. </p>
<p>JPMorgan said it estimates that losses from lawsuits and
investigations could exceed its legal reserves by as much as
$6.8 billion, according to an Aug. 7 regulatory filing. While
litigation costs are high and uncertain, JPMorgan can
easily earn through them, Mutascio wrote. </p>
<p>New regulatory probes and potential litigation costs have
damped JPMorgan''s stock price compared to other large banks,
Mutascio said. JPMorgan has slid 7.8 percent since Aug. 1 to
$52.11 at 11:35 a.m. in New York, compared with the 3.4 percent
drop in the 24-company KBW Bank Index. </p>




Photographer: Peter Foley/Bloomberg

<p>
People stand inside of JPMorgan Chase  Co. headquarters in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Rich Miller and Aki Ito" date="Aug 23, 2013 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-23/jpmorgan-sub-new-normal-growth-seen-confronting-next-fed-chief.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sub-New Normal Growth Seen Vexing Next Fed Chief</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The next chairman of the Federal Reserve faces an alarming possibility: the new normal for the economy is even worse than advertised. </p> <p>The long-run potential growth rate for gross domestic product has slid to around 1 3/4 percent per year, from an average rise in GDP of 2 1/2 percent since 1990, according to economists at JPMorgan Chase  Co., the largest U.S. bank by assets. That would be the lowest level since World War II and below the 2 percent mark that Pacific Investment Management Co. pegged as the new normal for the economy. </p> <p>The U.S. future isn''t what it used to be, said Michael Feroli, chief U.S. economist at JPMorgan in New York. Declining productivity gains and a slower expansion of the labor force should limit the U.S. average growth pace in the long run. </p> <p>As they gather for the Fed''s annual conference at Jackson Hole, Wyoming, economists and central bankers are aware of the implications. A slower potential growth rate -- the top speed at which the economy can expand without heating up inflation -- means the Fed would have to tighten credit quicker if growth does gain momentum. Slower growth would limit the ability of businesses to boost profits and workers to win pay increases and make it tougher to reduce the federal budget deficit. </p>




Photographer: Pete Marovich/Bloomberg

<p>
Fed Chairman Ben S. Bernanke said in November that the financial crisis and its aftermath had probably "reduced the potential growth rate" of the economy, as discouraged workers dropped out of the labor force and businesses held back on investment. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass, Scott Moritz and Sarah Frier" date="Aug 24, 2013 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-24/microsoft-ceo-ballmer-said-to-discuss-exit-in-2010.html"><headline>Microsoft CEO Ballmer Said to Discuss Exit in 2010</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) Chief Executive Officer Steve Ballmer has been contemplating his departure from the world''s largest software maker for at least three years. </p> <p>Ballmer and the company''s board started discussing succession planning as early as 2010, said a person with knowledge of the matter, who asked not to be identified because the deliberations were private. The conversations centered on what attributes Ballmer and other board members wanted in a new CEO. That led to Ballmer exposing internal CEO candidates to the board and also meeting with external candidates, said the person. </p> <p>The exit plans gathered steam about three to four months ago, when Ballmer approached the board and said he was considering stepping down and asked directors to examine what an official succession process would look like, said the person. Ballmer finalized his decision with the board on Wednesday. </p> <p>The CEO, 57, will now retire within 12 months, Microsoft said yesterday in a statement. The Redmond, Washington-based company''s lead independent director, John Thompson, will oversee the search for his successor, heading a committee that will also include Microsoft co-founder Bill Gates. Investors applauded the move, sending the shares up the most since 2009. </p> <h2>Industry Decline </h2> <p>Ballmer''s announcement reflects the changes roiling the computing industry his company helped pioneer. Microsoft, which supplies the software running most personal computers, lost almost half its value on Ballmer''s watch. The stock hasn''t closed above $50 since his first year on the job amid competition from Google Inc. (GOOG), Apple Inc. (AAPL) and Facebook Inc. (FB) in everything from tablets to the Web. </p> <p>The world has figured out that you don''t need a PC to connect to the Internet, said Dan Niles, portfolio manager with Alphaone Capital Partners LLC, in Tiburon, California. A tablet or a smartphone is just fine. Microsoft is going from having 90 percent of the market in PCs to 5 percent in smartphones. </p> <p>Ballmer, in a memo to employees yesterday that was posted on Microsoft''s website, wrote, There is never a perfect time for this type of transition, but now is the right time. He added, We need a CEO who will be here longer term for this new direction. </p> <h2>Management Shakeup </h2> <p>The announcement comes six weeks after Ballmer streamlined the company''s management, spurring speculation that he was grooming successors. He cut the number of business units to four and said Windows chief Julie Larson-Green, 51, would oversee all hardware, including the Surface tablet and Xbox console and related games. Windows Phone software head Terry Myerson gained responsibility for the Windows and Xbox operating systems. Skype president Tony Bates, 46, was put in charge of a new group for business development and acquisitions. </p> <p>Other PC-related companies are also been struggling with an industry decline. Intel Corp. (INTC), which supplies the chips used in PCs, announced a CEO change last year. Dell Inc. (DELL), the No. 3 PC maker, is embroiled in a months-long battle to go private. And this week, Hewlett-Packard Co. (HPQ), the No. 2 PC company, shook up its executive ranks as it attempts a turnaround. </p> <p>The mantle of technology leadership has instead been taken up by Google, Apple and Facebook, which have over the past decade moved the landscape toward mobile, search and social networking -- all areas where Microsoft is weak. </p> <h2>Lightning Rod'' </h2> <p>Amid these shifts, Microsoft last month reported quarterly profits and sales that missed analysts'' estimates. The company''s latest computing operating system, Windows 8, also hasn''t spurred the comeback that Ballmer was aiming for. In April, activist investor ValueAct Holdings LP disclosed a stake of about $1.9 billion in Microsoft, pushing the software maker to consider giving the shareholder a board seat. </p> <p>He''s become a lightning rod for frustration over Microsoft''s lack of progress in mobile and Windows 8, said Richard Williams, an analyst at Cross Research in Millburn, New Jersey. </p> <p>The company''s stock rose 7.3 percent to $34.75 at the close in New York yesterday. Since Ballmer became CEO in 2000, Microsoft''s total return including shares and dividends was down 13 percent, according to data compiled by Bloomberg, meaning investors who invested $1,000 in the company''s shares at the time would only have $867.24 left now. </p> <h2>Internal Shock </h2> <p>Ballmer said in an interview with ZDNet yesterday that he officially communicated that he would exit during a board call two days ago. Gates, who is chairman and on the board, didn''t ask Ballmer to stay, said the CEO. </p> <p>Bill respects my decision, Ballmer said to ZDNet. Ultimately, these kinds of things have to be one''s own personal decision. </p> <p>Members of Microsoft''s senior leadership team only learned about Ballmer''s decision to retire at a meeting on Aug. 22, said a person with knowledge of the matter. Many senior executives were surprised, said another person, who asked not to be identified because the discussions were private. </p> <p>The announcement of Ballmer''s departure coincides with the time when Microsoft conducts the CEO''s annual performance review. In each of the past two years, Ballmer has received less than his maximum bonus because of deficiencies in areas like online services, mobile and tablets. </p> <h2>Possible Successors </h2> <p>Microsoft said it would consider both external and internal candidates for CEO. Among the internal candidates are Bates, Myerson, Satya Nadella, head of the server business who was appointed to direct cloud and enterprise products last month, and Qi Lu, responsible for the Bing search engine and other Internet projects and who was named to oversee Office and the Skype videoconference business and to run a new applications group, according to people with knowledge of the matter who asked not to identified because the discussions are private. </p> <p>Someone who isn''t in the running is Gates, 57, who has been working on projects at the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation, among other things, said two people with knowledge of the matter. </p> <p>Ballmer took over the CEO role in 2000 from Gates, his schoolmate at Harvard University. While Ballmer had a boisterous style that made him legendary at company presentations, he largely remained in Gates''s shadow. Ballmer wasn''t seen as possessing the same vision for technology or the ability to anticipate changes in the industry, said Williams. </p> <h2>Different Styles </h2> <p>Ballmer was more the executive than the visionary and he missed a few turning points that visionaries wouldn''t have, Williams said. </p> <p>Unlike Gates, who dropped out of Harvard to start Microsoft, Ballmer stayed in school and received a degree in applied math and economics. He then joined Microsoft in 1980. </p> <p>Gates and Ballmer had very different management styles. While Gates was Microsoft''s geeky visionary, Ballmer was its excitable salesman. One video of the CEO on YouTube, entitled The Best of Steve Ballmer, features clips of him yelping and jumping on stage, wide-eyed and sweating, singing Microsoft''s virtues. </p> <p>In the 1980s and 90s, Microsoft''s swift rise to PC software dominance made Ballmer a billionaire many times over. He was the world''s 44th richest person as of yesterday, according to the Bloomberg Billionaires Index, with a fortune of $16.8 billion. Gates, the richest person in the world, has a net worth of $72.4 billion. </p> <h2>Enriched Departure </h2> <p>This is a time of important transformation for Microsoft, Ballmer wrote in the memo. This is an emotional and difficult thing for me to do. I take this step in the best interests of the company I love. </p> <p>He said he plans to continue as one of the company''s largest owners. Ballmer is the company''s fifth-largest shareholder, with a 4 percent stake, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p> <p>With Microsoft shares soaring yesterday on the announcement of his coming retirement, Ballmer''s net worth jumped about $786 million, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p> <p>Last month''s reorganization, Microsoft''s largest shakeup in a decade, is designed to speed development of hardware and services as the company''s Windows business suffers from the shrinking PC market and poor demand for Windows-based mobile devices. The shuffle reversed some changes Ballmer made in 2002, when he divided Microsoft into what was then seven individual product units, each led by an executive with operational and financial responsibilities. </p> <h2>Changing Executives </h2> <p>In the decade since then, he mainly tinkered with individual businesses. In 2011, Bob Muglia was pushed out as server chief, and in 2006 Ballmer revamped leadership of the Windows and Internet units after development delays for the Windows Vista operating system. </p> <p>The latest reorganization was seen by analysts as a signal of which executives may be poised to succeed Ballmer. As demand wanes for PCs, the shakeup also sought to turn away from Microsoft''s original focus on putting a PC on every desk in every home, Ballmer wrote in a memo at the time. PC shipments fell about 11 percent in the second quarter, for a record fifth straight quarter of declines, according to market research firms IDC and Gartner Inc. </p> <p>Comprehensive Vision? </p> <p>Ballmer did a very good job turning Microsoft from a bloated monstrosity into a much leaner and meaner machine over the last few years, said Microsoft investor Michael Obuchowski, a portfolio manager at North Shore Asset Management LLC in Cold Spring Harbor, New York. However, despite the improved operations and much better quality of programming, Microsoft was severely lacking a comprehensive vision that would have allowed the company to stay ahead of the trends. </p> <p>Microsoft also is trying to challenge Amazon.com Inc. (AMZN) and Google in cloud services as more customers opt for software that''s run over the Web instead of installed on corporate machines. Cloud efforts that were scattered across several divisions were concentrated under two units in the reorganization. </p> <p>Even with all the recent executive changes, there''s no heir apparent, Obuchowski said. </p> <p>This is not going to be an easy search, he said. The expectations are very high and I don''t think Microsoft can afford to make a mistake here. I can''t think of any obvious candidates off the top of my head. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Aug 26, 2013  5:42 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-26/microsoft-said-to-reassure-workers-that-plan-is-on-track.html"><headline>Microsoft Said to Reassure Workers That Plan Is On Track</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) is moving to reassure employees that a reorganization plan by departing Chief Executive Officer Steve Ballmer will go ahead. </p> <p>Some members of Microsoft''s senior leadership team e-mailed their staff Friday to say they remain committed to Ballmer''s vision and the reorganization, said two people with knowledge of the matter, who asked not to be identified because the e-mails were private. </p> <p>The communications follow concern at the software maker that any new CEO -- especially an external one -- won''t keep the company as Ballmer laid out last month in the biggest restructuring in more than a decade. Ballmer is refocusing Microsoft on hardware and Internet-based services, in a bid to move the company away from software for the declining personal-computer industry and onto better footing with Google Inc. (GOOG), Facebook Inc. (FB) and Apple Inc. (AAPL) </p> <p>There''s going to be more confusion near-term, said Sid Parakh, an analyst at McAdams Wright Ragen in Seattle. It just seems like now there''s the question of how''s the new person going to look at these changes. From an employee perspective, they are at a point of OK, now what do we do here?'' </p> <p>Tony Imperati, a spokesman for Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft, declined to comment. </p> <h2>As Planned </h2> <p>Microsoft''s leadership team also held a previously planned meeting on Friday, said the people with knowledge of the matter. Microsoft''s board stressed in statements Friday that a new CEO will execute Ballmer''s strategy. </p> <p>Already behind in mobile and tablets and with new products scrounging up minuscule market share while its core revenue from the Windows operating system shrinks, Microsoft can ill afford to wait and see if a new CEO alters the Ballmer plan. The company''s stock is down about 37 percent under Ballmer''s tenure as CEO, which started in January 2000. Last month, Microsoft also reported sales and profit that missed analysts'' estimates. </p> <p>Now as Microsoft embarks on a new CEO search, it will also have to contend with retaining employees and tamping down unease that for some began with the July reorganization. </p> <p>Microsoft executives and workers in the process of moving into new divisions and roles don''t know if they will be asked to shift again under new management, said one of the people. Some executives unhappy with their new roles may leave after stock grants and bonuses are given at the end of August, said another person. </p> <p>Microsoft executives have also received an increase in outside job offers since the reorganization and expect that to accelerate as the next CEO remains to be chosen, said another person with knowledge of the matter. </p> <p>Ballmer''s reorganization, which put all of Microsoft''s hardware into one unit and shifted the Windows and Windows Phone operating systems under the same executive, was undertaken with the knowledge that a new CEO might end up at the company''s helm, said another person with knowledge of the matter. It didn''t make sense to put the changes on hold for as much as a year until a new CEO was in place, the person said. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Peter Burrows and Carol Hymowitz" date="Aug 26, 2013 12:13 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-26/microsoft-board-in-needle-in-haystack-hunt-for-new-ceo.html"><headline>Microsoft Board in Needle-in-Haystack Hunt for New CEO</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT)''s next chief executive officer will need the expertise and strategic vision that can help the biggest software maker confront a broad range of threats that Steve Ballmer, for all his expertise as a salesman, was never able to repel. </p> <p>Microsoft requires a product person like Marissa Mayer, who oversaw some of Google Inc. (GOOG)''s most-popular services including its home page, and was brought in to turn around Yahoo! Inc. (YHOO), according to analysts and executive recruiters. </p> <p>The new CEO will also need to help Microsoft hone its strategy, comparable to Lou Gerstner''s overhaul of International Business Machines Corp. (IBM) The challenge: making up for a lost decade when Microsoft fell behind Google and Apple Inc. (AAPL) in smartphones, tablets and Web search -- and pushing it deeper into areas such as cloud computing, wearable technology and online advertising. </p> <p>It''s a challenge akin to searching for a needle in a haystack, knowing the needle isn''t likely there, said Robert Sutton, a professor at Stanford University and author of several books on corporate management. This is a massive effort in strategy, leadership and culture. </p> <p>Within Microsoft, Tony Bates, Satya Nadella, Qi Lu and Terry Myerson are the leading choices, people with knowledge of the matter said. Microsoft should look carefully within Google for possible successors, executive recruiters said. The operator of the world''s most-popular search engine is known for a fast-moving culture that has enabled it to find and succeed in new markets, such as cloud computing and mobile, where its Android software now runs 75 percent of the world''s smartphones. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
Ballmer''s move reflects the changes roiling the computing industry his company helped pioneer. Microsoft, which supplies the software running most PCs, lost almost half its value on Ballmer''s watch. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Aug 27, 2013  4:48 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-27/microsoft-seeks-to-reassure-workers-spooked-by-ceo-search.html"><headline>Microsoft Seeks to Reassure Workers Spooked by CEO Search</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) is telling employees that a reorganization plan by departing Chief Executive Officer Steve Ballmer will go ahead, seeking to reassure senior managers who are concerned that the search for a successor will throw turnaround efforts into disarray. </p> <p>Some members of Microsoft''s senior leadership team e-mailed their staff on Aug. 23 to say they remain committed to Ballmer''s vision and the reorganization, said three people with knowledge of the matter. Some Microsoft executives have seen an increase in outside job offers since the July restructuring plan and others may be tempted to leave after stock grants and bonuses are awarded in late August, said the people, who asked not to be identified because the communications were private. </p> <p>Even as it hunts for a CEO who may change tack, Microsoft''s board needs managers to stay focused on the reorganization plan, the biggest shift in more than a decade. Ballmer is emphasizing hardware and Internet-based services, shifting away from software for the declining personal-computer industry and putting Microsoft on better footing to compete with Google Inc. (GOOG), Facebook Inc. (FB) and Apple Inc. (AAPL) in mobile devices and online advertising. </p>




Photographer: David Paul Morris/Bloomberg

<p>
Steve Ballmer, outgoing chief executive officer of Microsoft Corp., watches a demonstration at the 2012 International Consumer Electronics Show (CES) in Las Vegas. Ballmer said on Aug. 23 that he intends to retire within 12 months after leading Microsoft since January 2000. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Sherman and Scott Moritz" date="Aug 28, 2013  8:38 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-28/microsoft-ceo-hunt-a-tough-bet-as-web-gamblers-favor-elop.html"><headline>Microsoft CEO Hunt a Tough Bet as Web Gamblers Favor Elop</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A gambling website picked Nokia Oyj (NOK1V) Chief Executive Officer Stephen Elop, who has presided over a 62 percent decline in market value, as the favorite to become Microsoft Corp. (MSFT)''s new CEO. </p> <p>Elop, a former Microsoft executive, has 5-to-1 odds to be hired as Steve Ballmer''s replacement, according to Ladbrokes Plc (LAD), the U.K.-based gambling operator. He leads a pool including internal candidates Kevin Turner and Julie Larson-Green and outsiders like Apple Inc. (AAPL) CEO Tim Cook -- a 100-to-1 dark horse. </p> <p>Microsoft is searching for a CEO who can help the biggest software maker fight back against competition in mobile, search, video, gaming and personal-computing development. Microsoft said last week Ballmer, its leader since 2000, would step down within the next 12 months. </p> <p>Elop was the president of Microsoft''s business division, where he was in charge of Microsoft Office, before taking the top job at Nokia. The mobile-phone maker announced a strategic partnership with Microsoft just months after Elop became CEO. Elop likened his company''s mobile position at the time to a burning oil platform on the verge of being engulfed in flames. </p> <p>On Sept. 10, 2010, when the Espoo, Finland-based company hired Elop, it was trading at 7.79 euros a share. Nokia fell 1 percent to 2.96 euros yesterday in Helsinki. </p>




Photographer: Ramin Talaie/Bloomberg

<p>
Customers wait in line outside the Microsoft Corp. store during its grand opening in New York, on Oct. 25, 2012. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chris Dolmetsch" date="Aug 28, 2013  6:07 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-28/goldman-sachs-jason-lee-indicted-on-rape-charge-in.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs'' Jason Lee Indicted on Rape Charge</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) managing
director Jason Lee was indicted by a grand jury on a rape charge
stemming from the alleged assault on a 20-year-old woman at a
Long Island, New York, home, court records show. </p>
<p>Lee, 37, was arrested and charged with first-degree rape on
Aug. 21 in the town of East Hampton after police went to his
Clover Leaf Lane vacation home and learned that a woman had been
sexually assaulted inside the residence, where several people
had gathered, according to a police statement. </p>
<p>A grand jury indicted Lee on three charges: one count of
first-degree rape, which carries a maximum sentence of 25 years
in prison, and two misdemeanor counts of assault and sexual
misconduct, according to online state court records. Lee, who is
free on $20,000 cash bail, is scheduled to be arraigned before
Judge Barbara R. Kahn in Suffolk County Court in Riverhead on
Sept. 20, court records show. </p>
<p>The police statement didn''t identify Lee''s employer. Lee,
who lives in New York, is head of convertibles at Goldman Sachs
and has been placed on leave, according to a person familiar
with the matter who wasn''t authorized to speak publicly about a
private personnel matter and asked not to be named. </p>




Source: East Hampton Police via Bloomberg

<p>
Goldman Sachs Group Inc. Managing Director Jason Lee was arrested and charged with first-degree rape, arraigned in East Hampton Justice Court Aug. 21 and released after posting bail. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ellen Rosen" date="Aug 28, 2013  8:49 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-28/morgan-lewis-outten-golden-cooley-business-of-law.html"><headline>Morgan Lewis, Outten &amp;amp; Golden, Cooley: Business of Law</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) violated the
National Labor Relations Act by requiring five former employees
to use binding arbitration after they joined a class-action suit
involving overtime pay, an administrative law judge of the
National Labor Relations Board said. </p>
<p>In an Aug. 21 ruling, Steven Fish, the administrative law
judge, relied on a 2012 labor board decision that says requiring
an employee to relinquish his or her right to sue is counter to
the NLRA. </p>
<p>By maintaining a binding arbitration agreement that
waives the right to maintain class or collective actions in all
forums, whether arbitral or judicial, the bank engaged in
unfair labor practices, Fish wrote. </p>
<p>Fish said that while some courts have questioned the
rationale of the 2012 ruling, he was bound by it unless it''s
overturned by the courts. </p>
<p>JPMorgan can file objections to the ruling with the full
labor board. If the board upholds the ruling, the bank can
appeal in federal court. </p>
<p>Morgan Lewis  Bockius LLP represented JPMorgan. Jonathan
Fritts, a partner at Morgan Lewis, declined to comment on the
ruling. Trish Wexler, a spokeswoman for JPMorgan, declined to
comment. </p>
<p>The plaintiffs were represented by Outten  Golden LLP, a
firm specializing in employment law. </p>
<p>The arbitration agreements frustrated the right to engage
in concerted activity, which includes bringing a lawsuit over
how you''re paid, said Michael Scimone, a lawyer with Outten. </p>
<p>The case is JPMorgan Chase  Co. and Chase Investment
Services Corp. 02-CA-098118. The federal court case is Lloyd v
JPMorgan Chase, 1:11-cv-09305, U.S. District Court for the
Southern District of New York (Manhattan). </p>
<h2>Courts </h2>
<h2>Facebook''s Settlement Over Sponsored Stories'' Approved </h2>
<p>A federal judge on Aug. 26 approved a $20 million
settlement of a lawsuit against Facebook Inc. (FB) which claimed the
social networking site used subscribers'' names without their
permission to advertise products in its Sponsored Stories. </p>
<p>Under the settlement users can claim a $15 payment, and
funds left over will go to advocacy groups. While the deal
initially approved by the judge in December included a $10 per
claimant settlement, U.S. District Judge Richard Seeborg wrote
in the order that so few persons have filed claims that the
parties increased the amount. </p>
<p>Seeborg held that the court is satisfied that the
revisions to the terms of the settlement are sufficient to
warrant preliminary approval under the applicable standards. </p>
<p>Cooley LLP represented Facebook in the litigation. </p>
<p>The case is Fraley v. Facebook Inc., 11-cv-01726, U.S.
District Court, Northern District of California (San Jose). </p>
<h2>Law Firm News </h2>
<h2>Squire Sanders Adds Health-Care Partner in Cincinnati Office </h2>
<p>Adam Colvin joined Squire Sanders LLP as a partner in the
health-care practice group in Cincinnati. </p>
<p>Colvin focuses his practice on regulatory and transactional
matters, including fraud and abuse issues, joint ventures,
purchase and sale of physician practices, employment and
recruitment agreements and the establishment of ambulatory
surgery centers. </p>
<p>We are veryexcited for Adam to join our health-care
practice group, David Grauer, head of the practice group, said
in a statement. His talent and extensive health-care
experience will create new opportunities and will add to the
level of service we can provide our clients. </p>
<h2>Holland  Knight Opens Office in Mexico City </h2>
<p>Holland  Knight LLP is opening a new office in Mexico City
after previously operating in Mexico through a joint venture
established in 1998. </p>
<p>The office, which continues the firm''s expansion in Latin
America, will be led by Boris Otto, the former managing partner
of the Mexico City office of Chadbourne  Parke LLP.Alejandro Landa Thierry and Jos Antonio Prado, formerly with Chadbourne 
Parke, will join Holland  Knight. Two counsel, Miriam Grunstein
and Leslie Palma, and five associates expand the firm''s Latin
American practices. </p>
<p>The Mexico City office will focus on corporate finance,
energy, project finance, capital markets, mergers and
acquisitions, securitizations and private equity. </p>
<p>We see enormous potential in Mexico for the firm and its
clients, Steven Sonberg, the managing partner of Holland 
Knight, said in a statement. Mexico is a dynamic market and
many of our clients have operations or interests there. </p>
<h2>Ballard Spahr Expands Its New York Office </h2>
<p>Justin Angelo joined the consumer financial services group
of Ballard Spahr LLP in New York. </p>
<p>Angelo, who joins the firm from the Fort Lauderdale office
of Greenberg Traurig LLP, has experience defending banks and
non-banks against claims under various residential mortgage and
other consumer laws, including the Truth in Lending Act, Real
Estate Settlement Procedures Act, Fair Debt Collection Practices
Act, Fair Credit Reporting Act and Equal Credit Opportunity Act. </p>
<p>The firm opened its New York office on July 1 when it
joined with Stillman  Friedman, a boutique litigation firm. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Aug 28, 2013 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-28/microsoft-seen-raising-dividend-payouts.html"><headline>Microsoft Seen Raising Dividend Payouts</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), within weeks of announcing plans by Chief Executive Officer Steve Ballmer to retire, will probably boost its dividend amid calls by an activist shareholder to return more cash to investors. </p> <p>ValueAct Holdings LP, which in April disclosed a stake of about $1.9 billion in the world''s largest software maker, has been seeking a return of more money, according to a person with knowledge of the matter. Microsoft is poised to increase the quarterly dividend by 13 percent to 26 cents a share, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p> <p>Microsoft''s policy for the last several years has been to boost the quarterly dividend in September in line with increases in operating income, which rose 23 percent in the latest fiscal year. While too big a payout might require Microsoft to incur a tax on cash held overseas, an overly modest increase would put the company at odds with investors clamoring for more. ValueAct has until Aug. 30 to decide whether to mount a proxy battle for representation on Microsoft''s board. </p> <p>Microsoft has a target on its back, said Kim Caughey Forrest, an analyst at Pittsburgh-based Fort Pitt Capital Group Inc., which manages $1.4 billion in assets, including Microsoft shares. It wouldn''t surprise me if technology companies that generate a lot of cash, regardless of where it''s domiciled, would consider bigger dividend increases, because the activist investor has really come into play in the last 18 months, and not just at Microsoft. </p>




Photographer: Justin Sullivan/Getty Images

<p>
Microsoft''s policy for the last several years has been to boost the quarterly dividend in September in line with increases in operating income, which rose 23 percent in the latest fiscal year. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christie Smythe" date="Aug 29, 2013  1:06 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-29/visa-mastercard-merchants-better-with-pact-expert-says.html"><headline>Visa, MasterCard Merchants Better With Pact, Expert Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Merchants will be better off with a
multibillion-dollar price-fixing settlement with Visa Inc. (V) and
MasterCard Inc. (MA) over swipe fees than they would be if they went
to trial, a court appointed expert said. </p>
<p>Alan O. Sykes, a New York University law professor, found
that U.S. merchants face a substantial probability of
failure if they proceed with the case, according to a
memorandum filed yesterday in Brooklyn, New York federal court.
Sykes, who was asked by U.S. District Judge John Gleeson to
weigh in on the pact, also found some concerns with legal
releases and the possible impact of certain rule changes
promised in the deal. </p>
<p>The expected returns to continued litigation are highly
uncertain, Sykes said in the memorandum. Plaintiffs face a
substantial probability of securing little or no relief at the
conclusion of trial. </p>
<p>Announced last July, the settlement was estimated at one
time to be worth as much as $7.25 billion and was described by
lawyers for the plaintiffs as the largest-ever U.S. antitrust
accord. </p>
<p>Dozens of major retailers, including the world''s biggest,
Wal-Mart Stores Inc., (WMT) opposed the deal, claiming merchants
should receive more money. They contend promised rule changes
wouldn''t be helpful and that the card companies would have too
much freedom to raise fee rates in the future. </p>
<p>The size of the settlement will be reduced based on the
number of retailers that decided to opt out, according to court
documents. </p>
<p>A hearing on final approval of the accord is scheduled for
Sept. 12. </p>
<p>The case is In re Payment Card Interchange Fee and Merchant
Discount Antitrust Litigation, 05-md-01720, U.S. District Court,
Eastern District of New York (Brooklyn). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elisha Bala-Gbogbo" date="Aug 29, 2013 10:46 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-29/chevron-withdraws-from-nigeria-lng-plant-citing-lack-of-progress.html"><headline>Chevron Withdraws From Nigeria LNG Plant Citing Lack of Progress</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX) pulled out of
Nigeria''s Olokola liquefied natural gas plant venture, becoming
at least the second partner to withdraw from the project. </p>
<p>The decision to divest the 23 percent holding is based on
a review of our investment decision, the lack of progress on
the project, and a reprioritization of resources to focus on
growing domestic gas supply, Andrew Fawthrop, chief executive
officer of the U.S. oil company''s Nigeria unit, said today in an
e-mailed statement from Lagos, the commercial capital. </p>
<p>Tumini Green, a spokeswoman in the capital Abuja for state-owned partner Nigeria National Petroleum Corp., didn''t
immediately respond to two phone calls seeking comments. </p>
<p>Last year BG Group Plc (BG/) withdrew from the OK LNG project,
formed by NNPC in 2007. The remaining partner, Royal Dutch Shell
Plc (RDSA), pulled out in July, according to the Chevron statement.
Shell''s spokesman in Lagos, Precious Okolobo, declined to
comment when reached today by Bloomberg News. </p>
<p>NNPC has been informed of Chevron''s decision, and the
divestment process is being managed in line with the terms of
the shareholder agreement, according to the statement. </p>
<p>Chevron, Nigeria''s third-biggest energy producer, said it
remains committed to Nigeria and continues to pursue other
investments in the West African nation''s oil and gas industry. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Harris" date="Aug 30, 2013  1:24 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-30/morgan-stanley-sued-by-federal-credit-union-regulator.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Sued by Federal Credit Union Regulator</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS), owner of the world''s
largest brokerage, was sued by the federal credit union
regulator over the sale of $566 million in residential mortgage-backed securities to two credit unions that failed. </p>
<p>The bank and three units made misleading statements about
the securities in offering documents, National Credit Union
Administration said in the complaint filed Aug. 16 in federal
court in Kansas City, Kansas. The agency announced the lawsuit
today, saying it waited until all defendants were served. </p>
<p>Originators of the securities systematically abandoned
the stated underwriting guidelines in the offering documents,
the agency said in a statement today. The securities were
significantly riskier than represented. </p>
<p>NCUA, based in Alexandria, Virginia, previously sued
securities firms run by banks including Goldman Sachs Group
Inc., JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), Royal Bank of Scotland Plc and UBS
AG over the MBS sales. </p>
<p>Mary Claire Delaney, a spokeswoman for Morgan Stanley,
declined to comment on the allegations. </p>
<p>NCUA, which is responsible for covering losses to minimize
costs to its industry-funded stabilization fund, said it has
recovered $335 million in settlements with Bank of America
Corp., Citigroup Inc., Deutsche Bank AG and HSBC Holdings Plc. </p>
<h2>Failed Unions </h2>
<p>The agency is seeking to recoup from Morgan Stanley losses
it claimed contributed to the 2010 liquidation of U.S. Central
Federal Credit Union, based in Lenexa, Kansas, and Western
Corporate Federal Credit Union, based in San Dimas, California,
according to the complaint. </p>
<p>Firms like Morgan Stanley sold securities that turned out
to be faulty, triggering a crisis in the credit union industry
that has been extremely expensive to contain and repair, and
credit unions are still paying the tab, NCUA Chairman Debbie Matz said in the agency''s statement. </p>
<p>The case is National Credit Union Administration Board v.
Morgan Stanley  Co., 13-cv-2418, U.S. District Court, District
of Kansas (Kansas City). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Rebecca Penty" date="Sep 01, 2013  3:55 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-09-01/chevron-natural-gas-pipeline-leaks-in-gulf-of-mexico-nrc-report.html"><headline>Chevron Natural Gas Pipeline Leaks in Gulf of Mexico: NRC Report</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX) leaked an unknown
quantity of natural gas from a pipeline in the Gulf of Mexico
near Pascagoula, Mississippi, according to a report filed Aug.
30 with the U.S. National Response Center. </p>
<p>An investigation was under way by a dive team according to
the report, filed at 5:24 p.m. local time on Aug. 30. </p>
<p>Bloomberg News couldn''t immediately verify the information
in the filing was accurate. </p>
<p>Kurt Glaubitz, a Chevron spokesman, didn''t immediately
respond to an e-mail inquiry today, outside of normal business
hours. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry></news>