
<news><entry author="By Warwick Thompson" date="Jun 03, 2013  7:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-03/disney-misses-mickey-in-philip-glass-s-perfect-american-.html"><headline>Disney Misses Mickey in Philip Glass''s Perfect American''</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney fighting with a malfunctioning robot of Abraham Lincoln -- what great fodder for a juicy operatic scene. </p> <p>You wouldn''t guess that from watching Philip Glass''s The Perfect American, having its U.K. premiere at English National Opera. At the end of Act 1, robo-Lincoln and Walt tussle. The music chugs without excitement. The curtain comes down quietly. </p> <p>It''s a robotic American president going crazy, for heaven''s sake. Shouldn''t there be a chorus screaming? Some brass playing comical raspberries? Some tension? </p> <p>There should, and there isn''t. </p> <p>It''s symptomatic of the problems in Glass''s 25th opera, which presents the imaginary memories of Disney as he lies dying in 1966. Even though Rudy Wurlitzer''s libretto (based on a novel by Peter Stephan Jungk) is bitty, it does offer a few moments which cry out for big musical brush-strokes. </p> <p>The malfunctioning Lincoln-bot provides one such scene. There''s another when megalomaniacal Walt insists he will never die, and forces his family and friends to salute the American flag and repeat the words Never say die. </p> <p>It could be a chilling set piece. Glass simply repeats the same few familiar chord progressions, and studiously avoids emotional peaks and troughs. You''d find more variety in the monitor of a coma patient going beep-beep-beep. </p>




Photographer: Richard Hubert Smith/English National Opera via Bloomberg

<p>
Christopher Purves, Donald Kaasch, and David Soar in "The Perfect American." Walt Disney meets a disgruntled former employee called Dantine who had been fired for wishing to join a union. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Nikolaj Gammeltoft" date="Jun 03, 2013  5:52 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-03/general-motors-rejoins-s-p-500-after-four-years-replacing-heinz.html"><headline>General Motors Rejoins S&amp;amp;P 500 After Four Years, Replacing Heinz</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>General Motors Co. (GM) will replace H.J.
Heinz Co. in the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index after the close of
trading on June 6, SP said in a statement today. </p>
<p>The automaker is rejoining the SP 500 after it was dropped
following the company''s bankruptcy in June 2009. Heinz is being
taken private by Warren Buffett''s Berkshire Hathaway Inc. (BRK/A) and
Jorge Paulo Lemann''s 3G Capital in a $23 billion buyout. </p>
<p>The GM team has been working very hard to earn the
business of customers around the world and to win the confidence
of investors, and rejoining the SP 500 shows we''re very much on
track, Chief Executive Officer Dan Akerson said in an e-mail. </p>
<p>The revisions in the SP 500 may prompt money managers to
shift holdings to match the index. About $5.58 trillion is
benchmarked to the gauge, according to SP''s website. </p>
<p>American International Group Inc. will take the spot of
Baker Hughes Inc. (BHI) in the SP 100, the index provider said in a
statement. Detroit-based GM will also become part of the SP
100, the statement said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Rick Green" date="Jun 03, 2013  8:36 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-03/morgan-stanley-s-murphy-departs-to-join-phillips-edison-as-cfo.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley''s Murphy Departs to Join Phillips Edison as CFO</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Devin I. Murphy has left Morgan
Stanley (MS) where he was vice chairman of investment banking to
become chief financial officer at Phillips Edison  Co., a
privately owned owner and operator of shopping centers. </p>
<p>Phillips Edison plans to open a corporate office in New
York, the Cincinnati-based company said today in a statement. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Justin Doom" date="Jun 03, 2013  8:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-03/electric-vehicle-charging-network-collaboratev-names-wolf-as-ceo.html"><headline>Electric-Vehicle Charging Network Collaboratev Names Wolf as CEO</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Collaboratev LLC, the electric-vehicle charging-station venture formed in March by Ecotality
Inc. (ECTY) and ChargePoint Inc., named Jason Wolf as its first chief
executive officer. </p>
<p>Wolf''s top priority is expanding the network and
eliminating range anxiety among drivers of electric cars. He was
formerly North American vice president for the failed Israeli
charging-station venture Better Place LLC, Collaboratev said in
a statement today. </p>
<p>Wider use of electric cars will depend on the development
of a broad network of charging stations that are easy to access,
said Wolf, who was also a founder of Collaboratev. </p>
<p>With the growth of e-fueling, we''re going to need to have
a solution that''s easy for drivers, Wolf said in an interview.
I''ve got a pound of cards and stuff on my keychain. I have to
look at three or four different apps to find at all the charging
stations out there, and then I have to hope that station is
activated by any of my cards. That''s the reality every driver
faces. </p>
<p>Collaboratev connects the monitoring and billing systems of
San Francisco-based Ecotality and Campbell, California-based
ChargePoint, and the combined network includes about 90 percent
of the public charging stations in the U.S. The two networks
will be fully integrated by early 2014, said Ecotality CEO Ravi Brar. </p>
<p>Other car-charging providers may join the venture, said
Wolf, who drives a Nissan Motor Co. Leaf electric car. </p>
<p>Better Place developed a system that switched drained
batteries from electric cars with full ones, and filed a motion
for liquidation in Israel last month. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass, Ian King and Tim Culpan" date="Jun 03, 2013  6:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-03/microsoft-said-to-cut-windows-for-tablet-prices.html"><headline>Microsoft Said to Cut Windows for Tablet Prices</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) is cutting the price of its Windows software for small tablets, seeking to shore up foundering efforts to combat Apple Inc. (AAPL) in the mobile-computing market, people with knowledge of the matter said. </p> <p>Microsoft is using the changes to try and get more manufacturers to adopt Windows RT, a version of its flagship software for tablets, said the people, who asked not to be identified because pricing is confidential. The price cuts affect Windows RT for small-sized tablets. </p> <p>A year after unveiling the first Windows RT machines aimed at eroding Apple and Google Inc. (GOOG)''s lead in the $64 billion tablet market, Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft is struggling. Global device makers such as Hewlett-Packard Co. (HPQ) and HTC Corp. (2498) are shunning the system, leaving a dearth of RT machines in stores and giving Windows RT less than a percentage point of market share in the first quarter, compared with 40 percent for Apple, according to IDC. </p> <p>You need more breadth of equipment manufacturers making the devices, you need lower prices, you need a better selection of devices, said Wes Miller, an analyst at Kirkland, Washington-based Directions on Microsoft. That''s calling into question the long-term viability of Microsoft''s Windows RT strategy, he said. </p>




Photographer: Kiyoshi Ota/Bloomberg

<p>
Asustek Computer Inc.''s ASUS Vivo Tab RT TF600T tablet computer, running Microsoft Corp.''s Windows RT operating system, is displayed during a launch event for the company''s Windows 8 operating system in Tokyo. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Duane D. Stanford and Haslinda Amin" date="Jun 04, 2013  9:39 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-04/coca-cola-ceo-opens-myanmar-bottling-plant-to-stave-off-pepsico.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Says Myanmar''s Opening Is Like Fall of Berlin Wall</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Coca-Cola Co (KO). Chief Executive Officer Muhtar Kent marked the return of the world''s largest soda maker to Myanmar after 60 years by opening a bottling plant and pledging more investment in the newly opened economy. </p> <p>The company will invest $200 million in the next five years and a second plant will open in a month''s time, Kent said in an interview with Haslinda Amin on Bloomberg Television. </p> <p>It''s a great moment in history, just like it used to be when we opened up our business in east and central Europe in the former Soviet Union right after the fall of the Berlin wall, Kent said. We can retain and grow our leadership that we already have in this market today. </p> <p>Coca-Cola''s new plant begins in earnest a race with PepsiCo Inc. (PEP) to control beverage markets in the Southeast Asia nation, which reopened its borders last year to foreign investment. Myanmar President Thein Sein has allowed more political freedom and loosened economic controls since coming to power two years ago, attracting companies such as Ford Motor Co., MasterCard Inc. (MA) and Unilever NV. (UNA) </p> <p>The country is boosting economic, military and political ties with Western nations after years of isolation that left its 64 million people among Asia''s poorest. Its transition to democracy last year after about five decades of military rule prompted the U.S. to ease sanctions last May. </p> <h2>Boosting Ties </h2> <p>Coca-Cola will need to focus on distribution to win over the nation''s consumers, Kent said. PepsiCo has been building drinks distribution in the country, will soon distribute snacks there and is pursuing plans for a factory. </p> <p>As important as price, it is availability, it is serving the product in the right conditions, making it available, making it at an arms reach of desire, Kent said. We have plans to ensure that we have the best, most modern 21st century consumer distribution system in the country. </p> <p>While Coca-Cola left Myanmar about 60 years ago, PepsiCo has more recent experience in the nation. The world''s largest snack maker pulled out of Myanmar in 1997 after activists urged the company to sever ties with the military dictatorship because of human-rights violations. </p> <p>Unilever has said it will focus on opportunities in new markets in Southeast Asia, such as Myanmar, which could be another Vietnam in 20 years, according to Peter Ter-Kulve, the London- and Rotterdam-based company''s chief executive officer for Southeast Asia. The company is already selling its products through 100,000 outlets in the country, he said in an interview last month. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Nadja Brandt and Brian Louis" date="Jun 04, 2013  4:47 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-04/morgans-hotel-to-explore-sale-if-board-nominees-elected.html"><headline>Morgans Jumps to Highest Since 2011 on Sale Consideration</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgans Hotel Group Co. (MHGC), a hotelier
embroiled in a proxy battle with its largest stockholder,
climbed to the highest in almost two years after saying it has
received interest in a takeover and would consider a sale. </p>
<p>The company''s board nominees plan to explore strategic
alternatives, including a sale, if they are re-elected, New
York-based Morgans said today in a statement. The company, which
operates hotels including the Mondrian in Los Angeles and the
Delano in Miami''s South Beach, said it has received unsolicited
expressions of interest in a takeover from five investors. </p>
<p>Morgans shares rose 13 percent to $7.53, the highest
closing price since July 2011. The stock has gained 36 percent
this year. </p>
<p>Morgans''s Delano, Mondrian and Hudson brands would be
desirable brands for better-capitalized, larger hotel
franchisors seeking to grow their room pipeline in the boutique
segment, Stephen Altebrando, an analyst at Sidoti  Co. in New
York, said in a research note. A combination would also
eliminate the company''s high debt costs and provide capital to
expand the management pipeline. </p>
<p>Altebrando has a buy rating on Morgans stock. </p>
<p>OTK Associates LLC, which owns about 14 percent of
Morgans''s shares, is seeking to overhaul the board to try to
return the company to profitability. Morgans, which includes 13
boutique hotels, has lost money in every quarter since 2007,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>OTK said Morgans''s announcement is an attempt to undermine
the proxy battle and that the company is highly unlikely to
pursue a sale, according to a statement. </p>
<h2>Burkle Deal </h2>
<p>OTK in April sued board members over a recapitalization
deal with billionaire Ron Burkle''s Yucaipa Cos. Jason Taubman Kalisman, a founding member of OTK, is currently a director. He
has a slate of seven nominees to the board, which will be
decided at the company''s annual meeting June 14. </p>
<p>Morgans''s hotels would be attractive to operators seeking
to add boutique brands, said Chris Agnew, a Stamford,
Connecticut-based analyst at MKM Partners LLC. The company said
last month it had received a $7.50-a-share takeover offer from a
large international hotel company late last year that it
rejected as too low. </p>
<p>Everyone is interested in the younger generation today
and is looking at how to make their brands relevant and
attractive to this type of consumer, said Agnew, who has a
neutral rating on the stock. Morgans has these brands that
quite neatly fit into this category. </p>
<p>Morgans last week said its board voted to end a poison-pill
plan and instated a new policy requiring shareholder approval of
any future rights provision. Poison pills are used to discourage
takeover bids by making companies less attractive to potential
buyers. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Frier" date="Jun 04, 2013  4:41 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-04/ibm-to-acquire-cloud-computing-provider-softlayer-technologies.html"><headline>IBM to Buy Cloud-Computing Firm SoftLayer for $2 Billion</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM), the world''s largest seller of computer services, agreed
to buy SoftLayer Technologies Inc., a cloud-computing storage
provider that will help it compete with Amazon.com Inc. (AMZN) </p>
<p>IBM is paying almost $2 billion for Dallas-based SoftLayer,
according to a person familiar with the deal, who declined to be
named because the financial terms aren''t being released.
SoftLayer had $335 million in revenue in 2012, Chief Executive
Officer Lance Crosby said in an interview. </p>
<p>IBM plans to add SoftLayer to its SmartCloud unit to create
a new Cloud Services division to capitalize on a market that
researcher IDC estimates may more than double to $105 billion by
2016 from last year. SoftLayer specializes in public clouds --
data-center networks that manage computing and software for
businesses remotely -- where Amazon dominates. IBM is pairing
those capabilities with private-cloud operations, building
dedicated systems for individual customers. </p>
<p>Starting a new division through acquisition allows us to
get focused, said Ric Telford, IBM''s vice president of cloud
services. It''s all about acceleration. We had been building
out but we saw SoftLayer and the acquisition was too compelling
to pass up, he said. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
International Business Machines Corp. plans to combine Dallas-based SoftLayer Technologies Inc. with its SmartCloud unit to create a new Cloud Services division, helping capitalize on the market''s growth, IBM said in a statement. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri" date="Jun 04, 2013  4:31 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-04/disney-s-upgraded-california-theme-park-draws-23-more-visitors.html"><headline>Disney''s Upgraded California Park Draws 23% More Visitors</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS)''s California
Adventure, bolstered by a $1.1 billion expansion, led the
world''s largest theme parks with a 23 percent surge in visitors
to 7.78 million last year. </p>
<p>Attendance at the top 25 parks worldwide increased 5.2
percent to 205.9 million visitors in 2012, according to a report
today by the Themed Entertainment Association and the consulting
firm Aecom. </p>
<p>The market in North America was, this year as last year,
driven by major reinvestment at the major operators'' parks,
according to the report. </p>
<p>Disney, the world''s largest theme park operator, tripled
its investment in its resorts division between 2008 and 2012,
spending $9.2billion on two new cruise ships and improvements
to its properties. The company''s net income jumped 32 percent to
$1.51 billion in the second quarter, in part due to higher
attendance and a surge in profits at its parks business. </p>
<p>Disney''s California Adventure park in Anaheim opened its
Cars Land attraction in June 2012, drawing tourists to a new
area based on the Pixar Cars films. Neighboring Disneyland
was the only park among the world''s largest to register fewer
visitors last year, with attendance shrinking 1.1 percent to 16
million, according to the report. </p>




Photographer: Patrick T. Fallon/Bloomberg

<p>
Walt Disney Co., the world''s largest theme park operator, tripled its investment in its resorts division between 2008 and 2012, spending $9.2billion on two new cruise ships and improvements to its properties. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jun 04, 2013 12:32 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-04/goldman-sachs-public-finance-executive-kathleen-brown-to-retire.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Public Finance Executive Kathleen Brown to Retire</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Kathleen Brown, who helped lead
Goldman Sachs Group Inc.''s municipal finance business after
serving as California''s state treasurer, is retiring after 12
years with the firm. </p>
<p>Brown, 67, was chairman of investment banking for the
Midwest, according to a memo from Richard J. Gnodde, David Solomon and John S. Weinberg, the firm''s co-heads of investment
banking. Michael DuVally, a spokesman for the New York-based
bank, confirmed the memo. </p>
<p>Kathleen has played an integral role in building the
firm''s public sector and infrastructure franchise, the memo
reads. She has developed trusted relationships with many of
the firm''s clients and has led many important transactions. </p>
<p>Brown ran the firm''s West Coast municipal finance team
until 2010, when she moved to a newly created post in Chicago
and helped lead the public finance unit in the Midwest. The move
came in part to avoid any conflict of interest after her brother
Jerry Brown was elected California''s governor. </p>
<p>Brown''s father, Edmund Pat Brown Sr., also served as
governor and Brown herself was the 1994 Democratic nominee,
losing to Pete Wilson. She served as treasurer of the state from
1991 to 1995. </p>
<p>Brown worked at Bank of America Corp. before joining
Goldman Sachs in 2001 with its private wealth management group,
according to the memo. </p>
<p>Dow Jones Newswires reported Brown''s retirement earlier
today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Max Julius" date="Jun 04, 2013 12:12 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-04/jpmorgan-asset-management-boosts-treasury-holdings-on-fed-bet.html"><headline>JPMorgan Asset Management Boosts Treasury Holdings on Fed Bet</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Asset Management boosted its
Treasury holdings in recent weeks to take advantage of higher
yields and on the expectation the Federal Reserve will maintain
an accommodative monetary policy to spur growth. </p>
<p>The benchmark 10-year yield climbed to the highest level in
14 months last week amid speculation improving U.S. economic
data will prompt the Fed to scale down its asset-purchase
program. Chairman Ben S. Bernanke said last month the Fed could
reduce stimulus if there are indications of economic growth will
be sustained. </p>
<p>You''ve got an ambiguous growth picture, said Nick Gartside, international chief investment officer for fixed
income in London at JPMorgan Asset Management, which oversees
about $1.5 trillion. That''s Treasury supportive because it
means the risk is that central banks keep monetary policy looser
as opposed to tightening it. </p>
<p>The Treasury 10-year yield rose one basis point, or 0.01
percentage point, to 2.13 percent at 12:07 p.m. in New York
after climbing to 2.23 percent on May 29, the highest level
since April 2012. </p>
<p>JPMorgan Asset Management increased its holdings of
Treasuries to neutral-ish from underweight a week or so
ago, Gartside said. An underweight position means it owns
fewer securities than recommended in the benchmark index it uses
to track performance. </p>
<p>The Fed, which is buying $85 billion of government and
mortgage-backed securities each month, will probably taper its
purchases at some point, Gartside said. </p>
<p>To us it''s just part of the natural evolution of central
bank policy but I think the message is that it will still look
loose as opposed to tight, irrespective of the degree of
tapering, he said. </p>
<p>The company prefers German and Japanese government bonds to
Treasuries due to the differences in central-bank policy that
will probably develop in light of the weaker underlying
economies of Japan and the euro area, Gartside said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Simon Kennedy" date="Jun 04, 2013  4:48 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-04/goldman-sachs-s-hatzius-says-fed-could-taper-buying-in-september.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs''s Hatzius Says Fed Could Taper Buying in September</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The Federal Reserve could announce a
reduction of its monthly bond purchases as early as September if
employment and inflation strengthen enough, said Jan Hatzius,
chief economist at Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) </p>
<p>While Goldman Sachs''s forecast remains for Fed officials to
wait until December before slowing their $85 billion of monthly
asset purchases, Hatzius said yesterday that so-called tapering
could occur sooner. </p>
<p>A September tapering is certainly possible, I think that
is going to depend on the data, Hatzius said in a Bloomberg
Television interview at Goldman Sachs''s Global Macro Conference
in London. </p>
<p>Speculation that a strengthening U.S. economy will allow
the Fed to reduce its monetary stimulus has helped propel the
yield on the 10-year Treasury bond to its highest since April
2012 even as Chairman Ben S. Bernanke expresses caution over
trimming the program too soon. </p>
<p>The likelihood that the economy will continue to grow about
2 percent over the next couple of quarters with inflation well
below target will probably stay the Fed''s hand until December,
Hatzius said. </p>
<p>By contrast, an earlier pullback could occur if payrolls
regularly increase by more than 200,000 a month or inflation
outside of food and energy costs speeds up. </p>
<p>It''s definitely a mosaic of different indicators,
Hatzius said. It''s the broad picture. </p>
<h2>Consider Tapering </h2>
<p>Bernanke said May 22 during a response to questions
following Congressional testimony that the central bank could
consider reducing the amount of assets it buys within the next
few meetings if officials see signs of sustained improvement
in the labor market. Still, he has warned that premature
tightening could reduce inflation and jeopardize the economic
expansion. </p>
<p>With unemployment lingering at 7.5 percent, higher than
before the last recession, the policy-setting Federal Open
Market Committee announced May 1 it will increase or decrease
the pace of its monthly purchases in response to changes in
inflation and the labor market. Policy makers agreed to maintain
monthly buying of $40 billion in mortgage securities and $45
billion of U.S. Treasuries in a bid to boost employment. The
purchases have expanded Fed assets to about $3.4 trillion. </p>
<h2>Very Resistant'' </h2>
<p>Even with global bond markets posting their biggest monthly
losses in nine years in May, led by a 2 percent drop in
Treasuries, Hatzius said the Fed is going to be very resistant
to a large tightening of financial conditions precipitated by a
bond-market sell off. </p>
<p>He predicted the 10-year Treasury bond yield will end 2013
at 2.5 percent and 2014 at 3 percent, up from 2.12 percent
yesterday. Goldman Sachs anticipates U.S. economic growth of 1.9
percent this year and 2.9 percent in 2014. </p>
<p>Not in his outlook is a repeat of 1994 when a sudden and
sharp increase in interest rates from the Fed surprised many
investors. Goldman Sachs Chief Executive Officer Lloyd Blankfein
said May 2 that the current rate environment has parallels to
then. </p>
<p>The Fed increased its benchmark rate 3 percentage points
from February 1994 to February 1995, from a then record-low 3
percent to 6 percent. The yield on the 30-year U.S. Treasury
bond surged above 8 percent in late 1994 from below 6 percent 12
months earlier. </p>
<p>Still, employment and inflation are weaker than two decades
ago, while the Fed has become more transparent and better at
communicating its plans to financial markets, Hatzius said. </p>
<p>We''re not expecting a 1994, he said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Brian Louis and Nadja Brandt" date="Jun 05, 2013  5:29 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-05/morgans-says-iss-recommends-holders-deny-full-otk-slate.html"><headline>Proxy Firms Recommend Three OTK Nominees to Morgans Board</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgans Hotel Group Co. (MHGC) investors
should vote for three of the seven board nominees put forth by
the company''s largest stockholder, OTK Associates LLC, according
to two shareholder-advisory firms. </p>
<p>Institutional Shareholder Services Inc. recommended votes
for Jason Taubman Kalisman, Mahmood Khimji and Jonathan Langer,
according to separate statements today from Morgans and OTK.
Glass Lewis  Co. advised voting for Kalisman, Khimji and John
Dougherty at the annual meeting, scheduled for June 14. </p>
<p>OTK, owner of about 14 percent of Morgans''s shares, is
seeking to overhaul the board after the company reported losses
for every quarter since 2007. New York-based Morgans has said it
would nominate six candidates for its seven-person board,
keeping an OTK representative as a director. </p>
<p>We are very pleased that both ISS and Glass Lewis
recognize that change is urgently needed on the Morgans board,
Michael Olshan, a founding member of OTK, said in a statement. </p>
<p>Morgans climbed 13 percent yesterday after saying it had
received five expressions of interest in a takeover. The
company''s board nominees would consider a sale if they are re-elected, the hotelier said yesterday in a statement. </p>
<p>ISS correctly identified significant deficiencies in
OTK''s full slate of nominees that make them unfit to act as an
effective board and incapable of representing the interests of
all shareholders.Morgans Chief Executive Officer Michael Gross said in a statement today. </p>
<p>The stock climbed 4.9 percent today to $7.90, a two-year
high. Morgans operates boutique hotels including the Delano in
Miami''s South Beach and Royalton in New York. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By William Selway" date="Jun 05, 2013  4:53 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-05/jpmorgan-s-alabama-debacle-set-to-cost-bank-1-5-billion.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Alabama Debacle Set to Cost Bank $1.6 Billion</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) may see as much as $1.6 billion go down an Alabama (BEESAL) sewer. </p> <p>The biggest U.S. bank by assets agreed to forgive $842 million of debt owed to it by Jefferson County, Alabama, where it took the lead in arranging risky securities deals that pushed the county into the largest U.S. municipal bankruptcy, in November 2011. </p> <p>That agreement follows a $722 million settlement in 2009 with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission related to the Jefferson County financing. JPMorgan''s total costs amount to a quarter of the $6.2 billion trading loss in 2012 from corporate-credit bets by a trader known as the London Whale. </p> <p>Elizabeth C. Seymour, a bank spokeswoman, had no comment on the accord announced yesterday. If accepted by the court, it would cap almost a decade-long fiscal disaster in Alabama''s largest county, where JPMorgan initially reaped substantial fees arranging interest-rate swaps that subsequently proved tainted by municipal corruption and devastating to taxpayers during the 2008 credit crisis. </p> <p>Everybody thought there was a free lunch and they could all take advantage of it at the same time, said Christopher Taylor, the former executive director of the Municipal Securities Rulemaking Board. It burned them all. </p>




Photographer: Victor J. Blue/Bloomberg

<p>
Pedestrians walk by the offices of JPMorgan Chase  Co. in New York. Under the agreement, JPMorgan would forgive about 70 percent of the $1.2 billion in sewer debt Jefferson County holds, according to a statement from the county. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Pablo Gonzalez" date="Jun 05, 2013  4:36 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-05/chevron-argentina-asset-freeze-revoked-easing-shale-development.html"><headline>Chevron Argentina Asset Freeze Revoked Easing Shale Venture</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Argentina''s Supreme Court revoked the seizure of Chevron Corp.''s (CVX) assets in the country six months after an embargo that threatened to derail plans to develop shale deposits with state-run YPF SA. (YPF) </p> <p>The embargo was rejected in a five-page ruling, overturning a November decision by Judge Adrian Elcuj Miranda ordering 40 percent of Chevron''s Argentine bank accounts to be held in escrow at the request of Ecuadorean plaintiffs to enforce a $19 billion award against the second-biggest U.S. oil company, according to the ruling posted late yesterday on the Supreme Court''s website. </p> <p>The decision from Argentina''s Supreme Court confirms that the Ecuadorian embargo should not have been issued in the first place, James Craig, a spokesman for San Ramon, California-based Chevron, said yesterday in an e-mailed response to questions. This is a significant development further demonstrating the illegitimacy of the Lago Agrio Plaintiffs'' attempt to enforce their fraudulent judgment. </p> <p>Ecuador has blamed Texaco Inc. (677004Q), which Chevron acquired in 2001, for destroying the environment in the Lago Agrio region through its oil exploration activities and damaging the living conditions of 30,000 inhabitants. The Ecuadorean plaintiffs filed the attachment order in Argentina under an international treaty signed by Ecuador, Argentina and Colombia. </p> <h2>Shale Deposits </h2> <p>We respectfully disagree with the ruling, Enrique Bruchou, the Argentine lawyer for the Ecuadorean plaintiffs, said in an e-mailed statement. The trial court, a unanimous Court of Appeals, and especially senior Judge Carlos Fayt in his dissent, all appreciated, Chevron''s Argentine subsidiaries do have the right to be heard in Ecuador. We will continue pursuing the defense of the rights of the Ecuadorean plaintiffs against the Argentine subsidiaries of Chevron. </p> <p>The Ecuadorean plaintiffs rights to sue Chevron''s Argentine units haven''t been affected by this ruling, which refers exclusively to a precautionary ruling for the seizure of assets, Bruchou said. The Ecuadorean plaintiffs filed the attachment order under an international treaty signed by Ecuador, Argentina and Colombia. </p> <p>The ruling unfreezing Chevron''s accounts paves the way for a $1.5 billion venture between Chevron and YPF (YPFD) to develop shale oil and gas at what may be the the world''s second-largest shale oil reservoir, according to Ali Moshiri, Chevron''s head of Latin America and Africa. </p> <h2>Vaca Muerta </h2> <p>YPF rose 2.2 percent to 123.15 pesos at the close in Buenos Aires, the biggest gain since May 29. Chevron slid 1.1 percent to $121.57 in New York trading. </p> <p>Chevron, the fourth-largest producer of oil in Argentina, signed an accord on May 15 establishing terms for a definitive agreement with YPF (YPF), Argentina''s biggest energy company, to develop an area at the shale formation of Vaca Muerta. The total investment in the venture could reach $15 billion. </p> <p>Any deal to work with YPF in exploring the nation''s shale formations must be preceded by a lifting of the embargo on Chevron''s assets, Chairman and CEO John Watson said on March 12. </p> <p>Alejandro Di Lazzaro, a spokesman for YPF in Buenos Aires, declined to comment in a telephone call. </p> <p>YPF has struggled to proceed with plans to tap non-conventional oil and gas deposits in Argentina to boost output a year after President Cristina Fernandez de Kirchner seized a 51 percent stake in the company from Spain''s Repsol SA. </p> <p>YPF increased energy imports this year after a fire in April at its largest refinery in La Plata lowered output levels. The company has been shut out of international capital markets because of double-digit borrowing costs for Argentine issuers. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Campbell and Joe Carroll" date="Jun 05, 2013  8:13 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-05/chevron-hires-ex-citigroup-energy-banker-lovegrove-as-adviser.html"><headline>Chevron Hires Ex-Citigroup Energy Banker Lovegrove as Adviser</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX) hired former Citigroup
Inc. (C) oil and gas banker Martin Lovegrove in an advisory role as
the energy group looks to expand production. </p>
<p>Chevron has contracted Martin Lovegrove to an advisory
position within the company, Gareth Johnstone, a Chevron
spokesman, said in an e-mail. He will assist with business
development activities. </p>
<p>Lovegrove was Citigroup''s chairman for global energy until
departing the New York-based bank earlier this year. He advised
on transactions including Cnooc Ltd.''s $15.1 billion acquisition
of Canada''s Nexen Inc., the largest-ever foreign takeover by a
Chinese company. </p>
<p>San Ramon, California-based Chevron is spending $36.7
billion this year on exploration, export terminals and refinery
upgrades after oil and gas output hit a four-year low in 2012. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Samuel Potter" date="Jun 05, 2013  6:51 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-05/goldman-breaks-drought-with-saudi-property-bond-islamic-finance.html"><headline>Goldman Breaks Drought With Saudi Property Bond: Islamic Finance</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), whose
shariah-compliant bond program was questioned by Islamic
scholars in 2011, led its first sukuk in more than three years
after helping a Saudi property developer raise $450 million. </p>
<p>The bank was a lead arranger on Dar Al Arkan Real Estate
Development Co. (ALARKAN)''s sukuk on May 21, reforging links with the
Riyadh-based real estate company after helping arrange the sale
of its $450 million five-year bonds in February 2010. </p>
<p>The New York-based bank is seeking to catch up with U.S.
competitors as demand accelerates for securities that conform to
Islamic principles. Global sales reached a record $46.5 billion
last year, according to data compiled by Bloomberg, while
issuance has increased 4 percent to $18.3 billion in 2013.
Citigroup Inc. (C) and Morgan Stanley (MS) are U.S. banks that have
appeared among the global top 10 underwriters for Islamic bonds
in the last five years, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>This is an area of growing importance as a source of
funding for borrowers, Martin Weber, head of debt capital
markets for Europe Middle East  Africa growth markets at
Goldman Sachs, said by phone yesterday. Our presence in the
region and connectivity with local issuers has gone up. You have
seen us on Dar Al Arkan, and there is going to be more. </p>
<h2>Demand </h2>
<p>Islamic financial assets could more than double by 2015 to
as much as $3 trillion, Standard and Poor''s said in September.
Emerging market sukuk have returned 0.3 percent this year,
according to the HSBC/NASDAQ Dubai Sukuk Total Return Index.
That compares with a loss of 1.9 percent for debt in Bloomberg
USD Emerging Market Composite Bond Index. (BEM) </p>
<p>Dubai Electricity  Water Authority secured more than $5
billion of bids for the $1 billion of Islamic bonds it sold in
February. Islamic Development Bank, the Saudi Arabia-based
multinational lender, last week received $1.5 billion in bids
for $1 billion of securities as it paid the lowest yield of the
year. </p>
<p>The Islamic industry is growing faster than conventional,
so every financial institution is looking at it, Afaq Khan,
chief executive officer of Standard Chartered Saadiq, said by
phone this week. If clients are demanding Shariah-compliant
solutions, you must develop accordingly. </p>
<h2>GE Sukuk </h2>
<p>Goldman in 2009 helped arrange the sale of GE Capital''s
$500 million Islamic bond, ranking it 24th on the list of global
sukuk underwriters. The bank was 17th in 2010. </p>
<p>International sukuk issues, which is where houses such as
ours would historically add value, had better times three years
ago, said Weber. </p>
<p>Goldman has yet to issue from its own $2 billion sukuk
program. The sukuk, blessed at the time by eight of the world''s
top scholars, was criticized by some Islamic advisers for not
ensuring the debt would be traded at par value as mandated by
Islamic law. Advisers including Riyadh-based Mohammed Khnifer of
Edcomm Group Banker''s Academy in New York also said it''s unclear
how Goldman will use the funds it raises. </p>
<p>A lack of product and industry knowledge could up-end the
essence of Shariah-compliance, Hatim El-Tahir, director of
Deloitte''s Islamic Finance Knowledge Centre, said by e-mail this
week. It could threaten the risk-return profile of both
industry and product. </p>
<h2>Growth Strategy </h2>
<p>Banks need to see a buoyant product, and right now that
is sukuk, Rizwan Kanji, Dubai-based partner at King 
Spalding, said by phone this week. That is what is driving
these players. </p>
<p>JPMorgan has hired a big name in Hussein Hassan, former
global head of Islamic structuring at UBS AG (UBSN), which proves the
bank''s commitment to the industry, Kanji said. </p>
<p>BofA Merrill Lynch was a lead manager as Asya Katilim
Bankasi AS (ASYAB) raised $250 million in Tier 2, 10-year bonds on March
28. The issue was the first of its kind from Europe, Turkey or
the Middle East, King  Spalding said. Kanji worked on the deal. </p>
<p>BofA Merrill Lynch has done a lot of conventional
issuance in Turkey, said Kanji. The bank has played to its
strengths to build an Islamic platform. </p>
<p>Spokesmen for JPMorgan and BofA Merrill Lynch weren''t
available for comment. </p>
<p>Increased competition in the industry could work in banks''
favor, said Standard Chartered (STAN)''s Khan, as lower fees increase
the chances borrowers will come to market and more banks means a
greater profile for the Islamic industry. </p>
<p>Forty-three banks have underwritten global sukuk sales this
year, compared with 30 in the year-earlier period, according to
data compiled by Bloomberg. Forty-four companies and governments
have sold Islamic bonds, up from 36 in the year-earlier period. </p>
<p>The more people we have talking about a product and
Islamic solutions to their clients, the deeper the market
becomes, said Khan. So while a few fees may go down, the
absolute size of the market will increase. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Jun 05, 2013  3:30 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-05/microsoft-to-add-outlook-to-windows-rt-update-after-complaints.html"><headline>Microsoft to Add Outlook to Windows RT After Complaints</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), facing lackluster
sales of tablets running its software, said it will include the
popular Outlook e-mail program in a new version of Windows RT,
after a previous application met with customer complaints. </p>
<p>Outlook 2013 RT will be part of the free Windows 8.1 update
that will be publicly tested starting June 26 and officially
released later this year, the company said in a blog posting.
Users of Windows RT -- Microsoft''s software for devices running
chips with ARM Holdings Plc (ARM) technology -- said the previous e-mail program was more basic and lacked many Outlook features. </p>
<p>Microsoft, whose executives are speaking today at the
Computex computer show in Taipei, are trying to jump-start sales
of Windows RT-based tablets after just 200,000 units were
shipped in the first quarter, according to IDC. In an effort to
woo device makers that have avoided using the operating system,
the company is rolling out price cuts for partners who opt to
use RT in smaller tablets, people familiar with the matter said. </p>
<p>We''re always listening to our customers, the company
said in the blog. One piece of feedback was that people want
the power of Outlook on all their Windows PCs and tablets. </p>
<p>Windows Chief Financial Officer Tami Reller will unveil the
addition of Outlook as part of a speech at the conference, and
Antoine Leblond, a Windows vice president, will give the first
public demonstration of Windows 8.1. The company announced some
features of the updated software last week. </p>
<h2>ARM Tablets </h2>
<p>Windows RT is a version of Windows 8 for machines running
chips based on ARM designs. Of five such devices that have gone
on sale since the program was released in October, only
Microsoft''s own Surface tablet remains widely available, Reller
said last month. Computer makers such as Acer Inc. (2353) and Hewlett-Packard Co. (HPQ) have steered clear of the operating system. </p>
<p>Windows RT already comes with several Office programs,
including Word and Excel for spreadsheets. Instead of including
Outlook, which also lets users manage contacts and calendars,
the company built a new mail app for this version of Windows,
prompting complaints from customers. </p>
<p>At least one Microsoft partner also asked the company to
reconsider. Nvidia Corp. (NVDA) Chief Executive Officer Jen-Hsun Huang
has said he wants Microsoft to include a version of Outlook that
works on RT. </p>
<p>Give me Outlook and I''ll use it every day, Huang, whose
company makes chips used in Microsoft''s Surface RT and other
devices based on the software, said in May. The executive said
in March that he was disappointed with sales of RT-based
tablets. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Foster Wong and Lulu Yilun Chen" date="Jun 05, 2013  1:02 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-05/goldman-said-to-pledge-500-million-to-alibaba-loan-as-ipo-looms.html"><headline>Goldman Said to Pledge $500 Million to Alibaba as IPO Looms</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. will lend
$500 million to Alibaba Group Holding Ltd. as the company seeks
$8 billion of loans, two people familiar with the matter said. </p>
<p>The pledge by the New York-based bank forms part of a
facility that will cut debt costs for China''s biggest e-commerce
company, the people said yesterday, asking not to be identified
because the details are private. Edward Naylor, a spokesman for
Goldman Sachs in Hong Kong, declined to comment. </p>
<p>Alibaba is locking in three- and five-year loan financing,
introducing a smartphone operating system and buying a stake in
China''s biggest Twitter-like service -- steps considered a
prelude to an initial public offering that may value the company
at as much as $100 billion. Investment banks are keen to form
relationships with Alibaba to increase their chances of being
selected to help with the share sale. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs wants to use this as an opportunity for
further chances of cooperation, including the IPO, said Alex Wang, a Beijing-based analyst at Internet consulting group
iResearch. These banks might not come across a chance like
this in years. </p>
<p>John Spelich, a Hong Kong-based spokesman for Alibaba, said
he had no comment on speculation regarding who may have joined
the syndication when asked about the company''s financing
plans. </p>




Photographer: Nelson Ching/Bloomberg

<p>
Employees work at Alibaba.com Ltd.''s headquarters in Hangzhou, Zhejiang Province, China. Alibaba was formed in 1999 as an online marketplace for Chinese companies. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Richter, Elizabeth Campbell and Debarati Roy" date="Jun 06, 2013  5:21 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-06/goldman-sees-bull-run-over-as-returns-trail-stocks-commodities.html"><headline>Goldman Sees Bull Run Over as Returns Trail Stocks: Commodities</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Commodities are trailing equities for
the longest stretch in almost 15 years as Goldman Sachs Group
Inc. and Citigroup Inc. predict the end of the decade-long bull
market even as the global economy expands. </p>
<p>The Standard  Poor''s GSCI Spot Index of 24 commodities
lagged behind the MSCI All-Country World Index for six months,
the longest stretch since 1998. Hedge funds cut combined bullish
bets across 18 U.S. raw-material futures by 51 percent from a
16-month high in September and are bearish on six of them.
Commodities will return 1.6 percent in a year as losses in
agriculture and precious metals diminish gains from energy and
industrial metals, Goldman said last month. </p>
<p>Investors pulled a record $23.3 billion from commodity
funds this year as global equities attracted $182 billion,
according to EPFR Global, which tracks money flows. Prices that
more than doubled in 10 years spurred expansions at mines, farms
and oil fields. Gluts are emerging as the International Monetary
Fund predicts global growth of 3.3 percent this year, from 3.2
percent in 2012. The group cut last week its estimates for
China, the top consumer of metals, grains and energy. </p>
<p>There are times when you probably should be avoiding
commodities, and I think this is one of them, said John Stephenson, who helps oversee about C$2.7 billion ($2.61
billion) at First Asset Investment Management Inc. in Toronto.
Anytime you have a whole lot of inventory and visible supply,
prices are going to be under pressure. The real issue for
commodities is the source of demand, China, is weak. </p>
<h2>Natural Gas </h2>
<p>The SP GSCI dropped 2.8 percent this year, as 17 members
of the gauge retreated. Silver led the decline, falling 25
percent. Corn and gold also entered bear markets in April,
joining copper, sugar, wheat, soybeans and coffee. Natural gas
is leading the gainers with a 14 percent advance, while cotton
rose 13 percent. The commodity index is 29 percent below its
record close in July 2008. </p>
<p>The MSCI equity gauge gained 6.7 percent since the end of
December, with the Dow Jones Industrial Average and the SP 500
Index reaching records last month. The dollar strengthened 2.2
percent against six major trading partners. Global bonds
measured by the Bank of America Merrill Lynch Global Broad
Market Index lost 1.5 percent in May, the most since April 2004. </p>
<p>Commodities are diverging from equities as the supercycle,
or longer-than-average period of rising prices, is eclipsed by
the supply surge, Jeffrey Currie, Goldman''s head of commodities
research in New York, wrote in a report May 14. The agricultural
segment of the SP GSCI will drop 13 percent in 12 months as
livestock and precious metals lose 4 percent, he said. Energy
and industrial metals will advance 5 percent. </p>
<h2>Domestic Consumption </h2>
<p>Most commodities will drop this year as China''s economy
moves from a focus on infrastructure to domestic consumption and
services, Citigroup''s Ed Morse said in a May 20 report. That
means investors should pay more attention to supply and demand
rather than just broad economic trends, he said. The bank
predicted the end of the supercycle in November. UBS AG and
Credit Suisse Group AG made similar forecasts this year. </p>
<p>The SP GSCI more than tripled since the end of 1999,
including 11 gains over the past 13 years, setting records in
everything from oil to gold to copper. Producers struggled to
keep up as China''s economy expanded more than fivefold. That
attracted a surge of investment and assets under management
totaled $409 billion in March, from $154 billion at the end of
2008, Barclays Plc estimates. </p>
<h2>Corn Supply </h2>
<p>Pessimism about commodities is focusing on the price of raw
materials as the pace of growth in consumption slows. China will
use 5.2 percent more copper this year, from a gain of 6.8
percent in 2012, Barclays estimates. The nation is still using
enough copper in cables each month to circle the globe almost 90
times, government data show. It will consume more than one in
every five tons of global corn supply this year as its hog herd
reaches 447 million animals, six times the U.S. figure. </p>
<p>In the U.S., where builders use about 400 pounds of copper
in a single-family home, sales of new properties in April
reached the second-fastest pace since July 2008. Central banks
in the U.S., Europe and Asia are still printing unprecedented
amounts of money to boost growth, adding to the almost doubling
of global sovereign debt to $23 trillion since the end of 2008,
a Bank of America index shows. </p>
<h2>Biggest Exporter </h2>
<p>Supply expansions may fall short of forecasts as bad
weather curbs crops in the U.S., the biggest exporter, and
mining is disrupted. Farmers in Iowa, the largest U.S. corn and
soybean grower, had their wettest April and May in records going
back to 1873. Freeport-McMoRan Copper  Gold Inc.''s Grasberg
operation may be shut for as long as three months after a tunnel
collapsed last month. The Indonesian mine is the biggest source
of copper after Escondida in Chile, where port strikes have
disrupted metal shipments. </p>
<p>The outlook for commodities is likely to be brighter,
said Alan Gayle, a senior strategist at RidgeWorth Capital
Management in Richmond, Virginia, which oversees about $48
billion of assets. The outlook will turn bullish when demand
starts moving higher. I''m not jumping in yet with both feet and
am going to let the story develop first, which I expect to
happen over the next few months. </p>
<p>The International Monetary Fund cut its forecast for
Chinese growth this year and next on May 29. It''s now predicting
7.75 percent, from an earlier projection of 8 percent for 2013
and 8.2 percent for 2014. The U.S. economy grew at a 2.4 percent
annualized rate in the first quarter, the Commerce Department
said May 30, cutting its previous estimate of 2.5 percent. </p>
<h2>Largest Retailer </h2>
<p>Cheaper raw materials may boost margins for companies from
McDonald''s Corp. to General Mills Inc. to Boeing Co., while
keeping inflation in check and allowing the Federal Reserve to
continue stimulus. Kraft Foods Group Inc. cut the cost of its
Gevalia coffee by 6 percent last month and Wal-Mart Stores Inc.,
the world''s largest retailer, is reducing grocery prices. U.S.
retail gasoline fell 4.5 percent from this year''s peak in
February, American Automobile Association data show. </p>
<p>Hedge funds and other large speculators are holding a net-long position of 652,708 futures and options across 18 U.S.
commodities, from 1.3 million in September, government data
show. Supply will exceed demand for 12 of 18 of the metals and
agricultural products, according to estimates from Barclays and
Rabobank International. </p>
<p>West Texas Intermediate crude oil will average $90 a barrel
this year, from $94.15 in 2012, Citigroup estimates. U.S.
inventories reached the highest since 1931 on May 24, government
data show. New drilling technology is unlocking supplies trapped
in shale formations, helping the U.S. meet the highest
proportion of its own energy needs since 1986. Crude rose 2.7
percent in New York trading this year. </p>
<h2>Exchange Traded </h2>
<p>Gold dropped 17 percent, the worst start to a year since
1982. Holdings through exchange-traded products tumbled 19
percent to the lowest since May 2011. Bullion will drop this
year for the first time since 2000, according to a Bloomberg
survey of 38 analysts. </p>
<p>The LMEX index of six industrial metals fell 6.3 percent.
Copper stockpiles tracked by exchanges in London, Shanghai and
New York more than doubled in the past year. Production will
outpace demand for the first time in four years in 2013, Morgan
Stanley predicts. Prices will decline about 6 percent in 12
months, Goldman estimates. </p>
<p>Farmers around the world will harvest the biggest grain and
soybean crops ever, the U.S. Department of Agriculture
estimates. Corn will extend this year''s 22 percent decline by
another 3.2 percent in six months, as wheat drops 11 percent,
Goldman says. </p>
<p>You have the combination of higher production together
with slower growth in China, said Adrian Day, who manages
about $135 million of assets as the president of Adrian Day
Asset Management in Annapolis, Maryland. For rest of the year,
you have a potential surplus of production over demand, which
obviously means lower prices. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Mary Childs" date="Jun 06, 2013  4:59 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-06/morgan-stanley-s-o-connor-leaving-to-be-full-time-isda-chair-1-.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley''s O''Connor Leaving to Be Full-Time ISDA Chair</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Stephen O''Connor is leaving Morgan
Stanley (MS) to become full-time chairman of the International Swaps
and Derivatives Association as the $633 trillion privately
negotiated swaps market faces regulation for the first time. </p>
<p>O''Connor, who joined Morgan Stanley in 1988 and held
several positions in regulatory-reform strategy, clearing and
counterparty risk management, is starting in the broadened role
effective today, New York-based ISDA said in a statement.
O''Connor has been on the group''s board since 2008 and was
elected chairman by its members in April 2011 while he stayed on
at Morgan Stanley. </p>
<p>The industry group is navigating rules under the 2010 Dodd-Frank Act that include increased collateral requirements for
swaps-market participants and a mandate that most trades be
backed by a clearinghouse. </p>
<p>ISDA''s mission, leadership and activities have never been
more important in building safe, efficient markets for all users
of derivatives, O''Connor said in the statement. </p>
<p>O''Connor, who set up Morgan Stanley''s counterparty
portfolio management group, was most recently focused on over-the-counter derivatives regulations, according to an internal
Morgan Stanley memo announcing the departure. Mark Lake, a
spokesman for the bank in New York, confirmed the contents of
the memo. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Danielle Ivory" date="Jun 06, 2013  4:49 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-06/ibm-wins-part-of-protest-over-600-million-cia-amazon-contract.html"><headline>IBM Wins Part of Protest Over $600 Million CIA Contract</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines Corp. (IBM)
won a key part of a protest over the Central Intelligence
Agency''s cloud-computing contract with Amazon.com Inc. (AMZN) </p>
<p>The U.S. Government Accountability Office, which arbitrates
federal contract disputes, today sustained Armonk, New York-based IBM''s challenge of the four-year award, which has a
maximum value of $600 million. </p>
<p>The GAO recommended that the CIA reopen negotiations with
the companies and amend the solicitation if necessary, said
Ralph White, the office''s managing associate general counsel for
procurement law. </p>
<p>The intelligence agency failed to properly evaluate prices
and waived one contract requirement only for Amazon, according
to the GAO. </p>
<p>The GAO denied IBM''s assertion that the CIA failed to
properly evaluate Amazon''s past performance, including service
outages that occurred in 2012. </p>
<p>IBM filed the protest Feb. 26. The full decision wasn''t
publicly released. </p>
<p>We now anticipate the reopening of the contract proposal
process, said Clint Roswell, an IBM spokesman. </p>
<p>Officials with the CIA and Amazon didn''t immediately
respond to calls and e-mails seeking comment about today''s
decision. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sridhar Natarajan" date="Jun 06, 2013  3:37 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-06/jpmorgan-vouches-for-leveraged-loans-as-junk-bonds-face-losses.html"><headline>JPMorgan Vouches for Leveraged-Loans as Junk Bonds Face Losses</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Investors should turn to leveraged-loans to preserve income as volatility in the high-yield bonds
sparks outflows, according to JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the second-largest underwriter of the debt in the U.S. </p>
<p>Record money flowing into funds that purchase floating-rated debt and issuance of collateralized loan obligations has
supported senior ranking debt in the face of a bond sell-off in
the last two weeks, the New York-based lender said in a report
yesterday as it it''s overweight loans this month versus bonds.
Returns of 0.12 percent on the Standard  Poor''s/LSTA 100 index
outpaced U.S. junk bonds for the first time in six months, which
lost 0.5 percent in May. </p>
<p>Bonds sold by companies in the U.S. suffered losses on
concern that Federal Reserve policy makers may consider reducing
stimulus measures that had fueled demand for higher yielding
debt. Loans funds have received record deposit on expectations
the debt will deliver positive returns during a period of rising
rates. </p>
<p>Loan prices are being supported by demand for floating
rate instruments amid concerns about QE tapering, JPMorgan
strategists led by Jan Loeys wrote in the report. This is
helping to keep the loan market particularly steady in the face
of higher volatility in high-yield bond markets. A strong
payroll report on Friday will likely further hurt HY bonds and
support their floating rate counterparts. </p>
<p>On May 22, Federal Reserve Chairman Ben Bernanke said the
Fed could slow the pace of its $85 billion of bond purchases in
its next few meetings, in testimony to the Joint Economic
Committee of Congress in Washington. </p>
<h2>Bonds Lose </h2>
<p>Since then, U.S. junk bonds have lost 2.3 percent, to trim
gains this year to 3 percent, Bank of America Merrill Lynch
index data show. That compares with a 2.6 percent advance for
the SP/LSTA 100 index this year. </p>
<p>Investors added $930 million last week to funds that
purchase loans, pushing year-to-date deposits to more than $28
billion, according to a May 30 report from Bank of America Corp.
That represents an increase of about 36 percent in net assets
for the year, outperforming funds that purchase credit assets
such as U.S. and emerging market corporate debt. CLO issuance
climbed to $35 billion for the year at the end of last month,
according to SP Capital IQ Leveraged Commentary  Data. </p>
<p>BlackRock Inc. (BLK)''s iShares iBoxx High Yield Corporate Bond
exchange-traded fund reported investor redemptions of 3.3
million shares, or about $305 million, from the fund June 4, its
biggest one-day outflow on record. </p>
<p>Leveraged loans are a form of high-risk debt that carry
ratings of less than Baa3 by Moody''s Investors Service and below
BBB- at SP. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Yusuke Miyazawa" date="Jun 06, 2013  3:07 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-06/jpmorgan-joins-samurai-bond-boom-with-biggest-sale-since-october.html"><headline>JPMorgan Joins Samurai Boom With Biggest Sale Since October</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the biggest
U.S. lender, raised 105.6 billion yen ($1.1 billion) in the
largest sale of Samurai bonds since October as overseas
borrowers flock to a market flush with stimulus cash. </p>
<p>The four-part offering includes 51.5 billion yen of 0.462
percent three-year bonds priced to yield 10 basis points more
than the yen swap rate, and 27 billion yen of 2018 notes at a
spread of 14 basis points, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. The New York-based lender also sold 10-year fixed-rate and three-year floating-rate debt, the data show. </p>
<p>JPMorgan follows Rabobank Nederland and Nordea Bank AB in
offering Samurai notes as Bank of Japan Governor Haruhiko
Kuroda''s plan to double the monetary base helps bolster demand
for higher-yielding debt. HSBC Holdings Plc''s banking unit,
Credit Agricole SA and the Slovak Republic are planning
offerings this month, according to regulatory filings. </p>
<p>Investors are looking to shift their portfolios from
government bonds, but they can''t really go into the more
volatile securities like stocks, Mana Nakazora, Tokyo-based
chief credit analyst at BNP Paribas SA, said in a telephone
interview. The issuers are taking advantage of the strong
investor appetite for foreign bonds. </p>




Photographer: Victor J. Blue/Bloomberg

<p>
Pedestrians walk by the offices of JPMorgan Chase  Co. in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joseph Ciolli" date="Jun 07, 2013 12:37 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-07/morgan-stanley-increases-forecast-for-dollar-gains-versus-yen.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Increases Forecast for Dollar Gains Versus Yen</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley boosted its forecast
for a stronger dollar against the yen, even after the U.S.
currency tumbled yesterday by the most in two years. </p>
<p>The U.S. currency will appreciate to 107 yen by the end of
2013, up from a previous forecast of 105, said Ian Stannard,
head of European foreign-exchange strategy at Morgan Stanley in
London. The greenback fell as much as 3.2 percent yesterday, the
most since Marcy 17, 2011, to 96.97. </p>
<p>Rising U.S. yields will lead to more investment in the
U.S., resulting in a stronger dollar, Stannard said. Yields will
increase as the U.S. economy strengthens and the Federal Reserve
scales back its bond-buying monetary stimulus, he said. </p>
<p>We see the U.S. becoming an investment destination, which
will lead not just to portfolio inflows, but also increased
internal investment, which will lead to increased capital
demand, Stannard said in a telephone interview. It''s going to
be a very supportive factor in the longer term. </p>
<p>The dollar increased 0.5 percent to 97.47 yen in New York.
The currency rose beyond 100 yen on May 9 for the first time
since 2009 and has since weakened back below the 100-level. The
greenback is the third worst-performing major currency during
the past week. </p>
<p>Investors yesterday unwound the most bearish futures market
position on the yen since July 2007, triggering dollar-yen stops
and strengthening the Japanese currency. The yen has declined 11
percent this year against the dollar as The Bank of Japan has
increased monetary stimulus to support Prime Minister Shinzo
Abe''s goal of a 2 percent rate of inflation. </p>
<p>While the dollar may see some more weakness in coming days
as this retracement completes its course, it will resume its
upward trend, according to Stannard. </p>
<p>Once this correction is complete and the market is
reassured that the underlying themes are still in place, we''re
likely to see the dollar trend resume, Stannard said.
Investors will return and use this correction as an
opportunity to re-establish some dollar bullish positions. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ilya Khrennikov" date="Jun 07, 2013  7:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-07/mobile-telesystems-profit-drops-after-uzbekistan-exit.html"><headline>Mobile TeleSystems Profit Drops After Uzbekistan Exit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>OAO Mobile TeleSystems (MBT), Russia''s
largest wireless operator, reported a 17 percent drop in first-quarter profit as a closing of Uzbekistan operations hurt
revenue and the ruble declined. </p>
<p>Net income fell to 13 billion rubles ($402 million) from
15.6 billion rubles a year earlier, Moscow-based MTS said today
in a statement. Sales rose 2 percent to 92.9 billion rubles.
Adjusted operating income before depreciation and amortization
advanced to 39.1 billion rubles from 38.1 billion rubles. </p>
<p>Data revenue in Russia rose by 37 percent as subscribers
browsed the Web and sent e-mail, helping MTS offset slowing
voice revenue in a market where mobile penetration exceeds 160
percent. MTS, controlled by billionaire Vladimir Evtushenkov,
shut operations in Uzbekistan, where it had been the largest
operator with 9.5 million users, in July over a legal dispute
with the government. </p>
<p>The growth in mobile browsing and e-mailing helped MTS
almost catch up with rival OAO MegaFon in data revenue, Chief
Executive Officer Andrei Dubovskov told reporters in Moscow. </p>
<p>MTS advanced 0.2 percent to 255.54 rubles at 2:50 p.m. in
Moscow, valuing the company at about $16 billion. The stock had
gained 3.7 percent this year through yesterday. </p>
<h2>Acquisitions Planned </h2>
<p>MTS changed its dividend policy in April, boosting the
payout and linking it to cash flows. The company plans to pay a
minimum of 75 percent of free cash flow, or no less than 40
billion rubles, in dividends each calendar year through 2015.
First-quarter free cash flow was 23.9 billion rubles, down from
24.4 billion rubles a year earlier. </p>
<p>The company said it had foreign-exchange losses of 1.5
billion rubles in the quarter. The ruble declined 5.8 percent
against the dollar in the year through March 31 as Russia''s
economy slowed. MTS had total debt 222.4 billion rubles as of
March 31, with 16 percent of its loans in dollars. </p>
<p>To expand its broadband business, MTS is studying an
acquisition of Moscow pay-TV and Internet provider Akado,
Dubovskov said. MTS company asked Akado for documents to be able
to perform due diligence and decide on a potential purchase, he
said. </p>
<p>MTS is constantly monitoring the market and weighing
various acquisition opportunities, Dubovskov said. It''s too
early to speak about Akado. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri and Cliff Edwards" date="Jun 10, 2013  6:22 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-10/disney-showcases-lone-ranger-characters-for-game-system.html"><headline>Disney Showcases Lone Ranger'' Characters for Game System</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS) showcased Lone
Ranger and Monsters University characters tied to its
Infinity video-game platform, which goes on sale in August and
is designed to boost the company''s money-losing interactive
unit. </p>
<p>The play sets, drawing on characters from the forthcoming
Disney movies, feature plastic figurines that are set on top of
a base unit and appear on screen. The characters were shown
yesterday with the Infinity system at E3, the video-game
industry''s annual conference in Los Angeles that runs through
this week. </p>
<p>Disney, the world''s largest entertainment company, unveiled
Infinity in January, saying it would reduce costs and improve
earnings at its interactive division by incorporating characters
from multiple Disney movies in the same game. The company also
has been promoting other characters for the platform, including
from its Cars and Pirates of the Caribbean films. </p>
<p>You play your way and it is as fun for you as anyone
else, said John Blackburn, chief executive officer of
Avalanche Software, a Disney Interactive unit. We want this to
be deep enough for a father to play with his sons but we wanted
it to be easy enough where kids can play as well. </p>
<p>Burbank, California-based Disney will sell the figures,
which will come with power discs that add special powers,
weapons and vehicles from Disney movies. A starter kit with the
base and figures from the Pirates and Monsters
franchises and The Incredibles is priced at $75, and the
game can be played by four people over an Internet connection. </p>
<p>Players can use characters from the starter pack across
other games. An area called Toy Box allows users to create
their own game in genres including racing, sports, fighting and
world-building. </p>
<h2>Strong Buzz'' </h2>
<p>Infinity''s combination of video-game play with collectible
figures is similar to Skylanders, a game from Activision
Blizzard Inc. (ATVI) that generated more than $500 million in sales in
the U.S. last year. Infinity comes out Aug. 18. </p>
<p>I think the buzz around Infinity is very strong, Sean McGowan, an analyst at Needham  Co., said in an e-mail. It
comes at a time when parents are being asked to shell out a lot
of money for gadgets -- tablets and new consoles that already
have a solid claim on some of that discretionary budget, but if
it''s a quarter the success of Skylanders,'' it''s a big hit. </p>
<p>Disney earlier this year pushed back the release date for
Infinity from June and said in a May 7 conference call that the
interactive division would report a loss in the current fiscal-third quarter similar to the $54 million shortfall it
experienced in the prior three-month period. </p>
<p>We believe in Infinity, Bob Iger, chairman and chief
executive officer, said on the call. We think it will be a
great product and it''s going to help drive profitability for
fiscal year 2014. </p>
<p>Disney fell 1.6 percent to $63.83 at the close today in New
York. The stock has gained 28 percent this year, compared with a
15 percent advance for the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kevin Dugan" date="Jun 10, 2013  6:07 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-10/goldman-sachs-sells-biggest-topix-tied-note-since-december-2010.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Sells Biggest Topix-Tied Note Since December 2010</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) sold $85
million of notes tied to the Topix index of Japanese stocks, the
largest such offering since December 2010, after increasing the
size twice. </p>
<p>The six-month securities, $15 million of which were most
recently issued on June 4, yield the gains and losses of the
benchmark with all capital at risk, according to a prospectus
filed with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. The New
York-based bank sold the first $50 million offering on March 21
and $20 million more on May 31. </p>
<p>Japan''s stocks have gained the most among developed markets
this year after Prime Minister Shinzo Abe pledged to beat
deflation and the Bank of Japan embarked on unprecedented
stimulus measures. The central bank plans to buy more than 7
trillion yen ($71 billion) of bonds a month to increase
inflation to 2 percent within two years. </p>
<p>As Japan continues to pursue these policies, it is
helping to bolster domestic and foreign interest in their stock
market, said Michael Woolfolk, global markets strategist in
New York at Bank of New York Mellon Corp. </p>
<p>The Topix, as the Tokyo Price Index is known, climbed 29
percent to 1,111.97 this year as of the close of trading on June
10. The Standard  Poor''s 500 Index, the most common equity
benchmark tied to U.S. structured notes, rose 15 percent to
1,642.81 during the same period. </p>
<p>The bank estimated the value of the original offering as
98.9 cents on the dollar, a prospectus filed with the SEC shows. </p>
<h2>Bigger Offerings </h2>
<p>There have been two larger offerings tied to the Topix
index since 2010, when Bloomberg started collecting
comprehensive data on structured notes. The biggest, $174.2
million of 16-month notes, was issued by the Scandinavian lender
Eksportfinans ASA on Dec. 8, 2010. </p>
<p>Tiffany Galvin, a spokeswoman for Goldman Sachs in New
York, declined to comment. </p>
<p>Banks create structured notes by packaging debt with
derivatives to offer customized bets to retail investors while
earning fees and raising money. Derivatives are contracts whose
value is derived from stocks, bonds, commodities and currencies,
or events such as changes in interest rates or the weather. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Margaret Cronin Fisk and Steve Raphael" date="Jun 10, 2013  6:04 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-10/general-motors-wins-dismissal-of-suit-brought-by-spyker.html"><headline>General Motors Wins Dismissal of Suit Brought by Spyker</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>General Motors Co. (GM) won dismissal of
a lawsuit in which Spyker NV (SPYKR) alleged the U.S. automaker sought
to drive the Dutch company''s Saab cars into bankruptcy by
interfering with a transaction that would have saved it. </p>
<p>GM thwarted a transaction with Chinese investors that
would have permitted Saab to restructure and remain a solvent,
going concern, Spyker claimed in the lawsuit. Spyker was
seeking $3 billion in compensatory damages and unspecified
punitive damages, according to court filings. </p>
<p>GM sold Saab to Zeewolde, Netherlands-based Spyker in
February 2010. GM lawyers said that the purchase agreement
required Saab to get the U.S. company''s prior consent for
financing and restructuring. The judge agreed with GM''s
interpretation of the contract. </p>
<p>The language is clear, unambiguous and absolute, U.S.
District Judge Gershwin A. Drain in Detroit said today at a
hearing. </p>
<p>Drain rejected Spyker''s contention that General Motors
disparaged Saab or intended to harm the company. GM''s statements
were not wrongful or made with malice, Drain said. They
were not designed to intentionally inflict harm upon Saab. </p>
<p>Drain will issue a written order in two weeks, Spyker said
today in a statement. The company will assess whether it shall
exercise its right to appeal upon review of the written order,
according to the statement. </p>
<p>Dave Roman, a General Motors spokesman, said the company
was pleased with the decision. </p>
<p>The case is Saab Automobile v. General Motors Co., 12-cv-13432, U.S. District Court, Eastern District of Michigan
(Detroit). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Cliff Edwards and Dina Bass" date="Jun 10, 2013  5:02 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-10/microsoft-seeks-gamer-acceptance-with-xbox-one-e3-event.html"><headline>Microsoft Seeks Gamer Acceptance With Xbox One E3 Event</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), seeking to position its Xbox One entertainment console as the premium living-room choice for gamers as well as families, showed exclusive titles such as Halo and set a price that surprised analysts. </p> <p>The Xbox One will hit stores in November for $499 in the U.S., Microsoft executives said today at the annual Electronic Entertainment Expo in Los Angeles. The console will have 13 exclusive next-generation games, said Don Mattrick, president of the company''s interactive entertainment unit. </p> <p>Microsoft is using E3 to blunt the perception that the console de-emphasizes games in favor of movies, sports and functions like Skype video-calling. The company today showed major titles like Electronic Arts Inc. (EA)''s Battlefield 4 with some exclusive content, and highlighted features that make games more interactive, social and hyper-realistic. </p> <p>As we''ve been promising, it''s all about the games, Mattrick said from the stage at E3. </p> <p>The machine, first announced on May 21, uses improved Kinect voice commands and motion sensing to recognize users and switch between games, TV shows and Skype calls. The emphasis on other content led to grumbling among serious gamers, concerns Microsoft set out to answer today showing the new Xbox''s advanced features can lift traditional game play as well. </p> <p>The next version of Halo, Microsoft''s top-selling science-fiction game that has anchored the Xbox, will arrive in 2014, the company said. It will run at 60 frames per second, more than double the speed of most movies today. Plants vs. Zombies, another Electronic Arts game, will be exclusive to Xbox. </p> <h2>Price Tag </h2> <p>Exclusive Xbox One titles with advanced graphics also include Sunset Overdrive, from Insomniac Games Inc., and Crytek''s Ryse: Son of Rome. </p> <p>Analysts said they were surprised at the $499 price tag for the console, an upfront cost that could potentially be lowered by contracts for content such as for Microsoft''s Xbox Live service. The machine will cost 499 euros ($662) in most of Europe and 429 pounds ($668) in the U.K., Microsoft said. </p> <p>It seems expensive, said Brian Blau, an analyst with researcher Gartner Inc. It really seems like they are trying to create a different type of premium product, like Apple creates a premium product with high-end design, and comes in at a high price. It certainly seems Microsoft is putting enough resources behind it to put a lot of games into the ecosystem. </p> <h2>Price Debate </h2> <p>Xbox One will compete against Sony Corp. (6758)''s coming PlayStation 4, which also will be selling by the holidays, in addition to consoles, tablets and other devices that have eaten away at the traditional video-game market. Nintendo Co. (7974)''s Wii U, released in November, sells for about $300 in the U.S. and has missed sales targets. </p> <p>The Xbox Live service, content partnerships with the NFL, access to Skype video calls and unique features such as the SmartGlass app that allows users to switch between screens set Microsoft apart, Mattrick said in an interview. </p> <p>We''re overdelivering value against other choices, Mattrick said. Any modern product these days, when you look at it, $499 isn''t a ridiculous price point. </p> <p>While Microsoft showed a lot of games, the high price could work against it, Blau said. In the last generation of consoles, Sony''s PlayStation 3 lost its lead pursuing a similar premium pricing strategy. The Wii sold the most units in that generation and the Xbox has sold the most in the past two years or so. </p> <p>It''s a huge price increase, Blau said. Creating that premium product hasn''t really worked in the games industry. I''m skeptical. </p> <h2>Loyal Users </h2> <p>The Xbox one will probably be subsidized, said Michael Pachter, an analyst with Wedbush Securities in Los Angeles. He said Microsoft is probably calculating it can fetch the higher price for the first 10 million units, pulling in an extra $1 billion, and it can cut the price if it has to. </p> <p>It will come out of the pockets of their most faithful, Pachter said. </p> <p>The Xbox 360 ranges from about $199 to $299, depending on accessories bundled with it, such as Kinect. Microsoft unveiled a new, slimmer version of the current-generation machine today at E3. </p> <h2>Special Features'' </h2> <p>Xbox One titles include Forza Motorsport 5, which takes advantage of the console''s social capabilities to create an avatar that learns the player''s driving habits and stands in for them to keep playing while they''re away, for example at work. </p> <p>Another title called Project Spark allows users to create their own games. The company also played up integration with the SmartGlass app. </p> <p>Developers are looking for the first new consoles in almost seven years to pull the video-game industry out of a two-year slump in retail sales. </p> <p>Our goal is to make sure that we really do take advantage of whatever special features the machines are going to bring, said Tony Key, vice president of sales and marketing at Ubisoft SA. </p> <p>After some gamers criticized Microsoft for its lack of clarity on used games and how new ones will be played, the company said last week consumers may sell their games back to retailers or give them to friends, provided they have approval from the publisher. All games must be authenticated at least once every 24 hours to continue playing, the company said. </p> <h2>Stock Rise </h2> <p>John Reseburg, a spokesman for Electronic Arts (EA), and Alan Lewis, a spokesman for Take-Two Interactive Software Inc (TTWO)., declined to comment on whether their companies would place limits on used games sales, trade-ins or swaps among friends. A spokeswoman for Activision Blizzard Inc. (ATVI), the largest publisher, didn''t return a e-mail seeking comment. </p> <p>Microsoft, based in Redmond, Washington, fell 0.6 percent to $35.47 at the close in New York. The stock has gained 33 percent this year, compared with an advance of 15 percent for the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore and Krista Giovacco" date="Jun 10, 2013 11:36 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-10/morgan-stanley-said-to-name-bonetti-for-leveraged-finance-post.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Said to Name Bonetti for Leveraged Finance Post</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS), owner of the world''s
largest brokerage, promoted Jim Bonetti to head its U.S.
leveraged finance syndicate team, two people briefed on the
decision said. </p>
<p>Bonetti will report to Dan Toscano, the New York-based
firm''s head of acquisition and leveraged finance, said the
people, who asked to remain anonymous because the promotion
hadn''t been made public. </p>
<p>Leveraged lending helps borrowers and buyout firms use
high-yield debt to support acquisitions, dividend deals and
refinancings. The technique has gained favor as investors search
for yield amid low interest rates, with new-issue leveraged
loans jumping 59 percent this year through May 22. Morgan
Stanley ranks ninth in the field among underwriters, according
to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Syndicate desks sell off pieces of the loans to
institutional investors, or non-bank lenders, and help structure
collateralized loan obligations to spread risk. </p>
<p>Bonetti joined Morgan Stanley in 2005 after attending
Harvard Business School and previously working at Goldman Sachs
Group Inc., according to employment records with the Financial
Industry Regulatory Authority. He was named a managing director
at the firm this year. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Katie Linsell" date="Jun 10, 2013  8:15 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-10/coca-cola-hbc-joins-poste-italiane-selling-bonds-as-yields-rise.html"><headline>Coca-Cola HBC Joins Poste Italiane Selling Bonds as Yields Rise</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Coca-Cola HBC AG (CCH) is issuing its
first bonds since the world''s second-biggest bottler of the soft
drink switched its stock listing to London from Athens as
European borrowing costs climb to a three-month high. </p>
<p>Air Liquide SA (AI), the French maker of industrial gases, and
Poste Italiane SpA, the state-owned postal service, are also
raising debt as the average yield investors demand to hold
investment-grade company bonds in euros rose to 1.90 percent
from a record low of 1.64 percent reached May 17, according to
Bank of America Merrill Lynch index data. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola HBC moved its listing to London to access a wider
pool of investors, Chief Financial Officer Michalis Imellos said
in April. Borrowing costs are climbing after Federal Reserve
Chairman Ben S. Bernanke said the central bank could taper asset
purchases if the employment outlook shows sustainable
improvement. </p>
<p>There''s an element of some of these companies looking to
get into the market before nervousness spreads further, said
Duncan Warwick-Champion, the London-based head of corporate
research at ECM Asset Management Ltd. which oversees $9.5
billion. There''s a lot of discussion about the potential for
yields rising further so some of the companies that haven''t
locked in their refinancing for 2013 and 2014 are looking to do
so now. </p>
<h2>Coca-Cola </h2>
<p>Coca-Cola HBC wants to sell 800 million euros ($1.1
billion) of seven-year notes that will be priced to yield 105
basis points more than the benchmark midswap rate, according to
a person familiar with the deal. </p>
<p>The bottler is also offering to buy back any or all of the
500 million euros of 7.875 percent notes due 2014 to lower its
interest costs and improve its debt profile, the company said
today in a statement. Philip Walters, an external spokesman for
Coca-Cola HBC, declined to comment on the new bond sale, which
needs to be completed before the buyback can begin. </p>
<p>Air Liquide is raising 700 million euros from notes in
three tranches, according to a person familiar with the
transaction. The Paris-based company is selling 250 million
euros of six-year fixed-rate bonds, 250 million euros of two-year floating-rate notes and 200 million euros of three-year
floating-rate notes. </p>
<p>Poste Italiane is raising 750 million euros of bonds from
its first sale since 2002. The company is offering five-year
securities to yield 225 basis points, according to a person
familiar with the transaction. </p>
<p>Anna Maria Morsucci, a spokeswoman for the Rome-based
company, didn''t immediately respond to an e-mail seeking comment
on the transaction. </p>
<h2>Rolls-Royce </h2>
<p>SSE Plc (SSE), the U.K.''s second-biggest energy supplier, is
selling its first bonds this year. The Perth, Scotland-based
company is raising 600 million euros from seven-year bonds that
will be priced to yield 70 basis points more than swaps,
according to a person familiar with the offer. </p>
<p>Rolls-Royce Holdings Plc (RR/), Europe''s largest maker of
aircraft engines, has mandated banks to organize a call with
investors today before a possible sale of securities in euros
and pounds. It would be the London-based company''s first bond
issue since 2009, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>In the high-yield market, Groupe SMCP, a French distributor
of women''s apparel, is selling 290 million euros of seven-year
securities through its subsidiary, SMCP SAS, to yield about 8.75
percent, according to a person familiar with the deal. The
proceeds will be used to repay existing debt and finance part of
its acquisition by KKR  Co., Moody''s Investors Service reported
on June 4 when it provisionally rated the notes B3, six levels
below investment grade. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael Bathon" date="Jun 11, 2013  7:30 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-11/electric-car-maker-coda-wins-approval-of-fortress-sale.html"><headline>Electric-Car Maker Coda Wins Approval of Fortress Sale</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Coda Holdings Inc., parent of the
electric-car maker that sold fewer than 100 vehicles, won court
approval of a $25 million sale to a group led by a Fortress
Investment Group LLC (FIG) unit. </p>
<p>U.S. Bankruptcy Judge Christopher Sontchi at a hearing
today in Wilmington, Delaware, approved the sale after
overruling objections from a lawyer for terminated workers and
the U.S. Trustee, an arm of the Justice Department that monitors
bankruptcy cases. </p>
<p>The Fortress group will pay $1.7 million in cash and the
rest of the purchase price will come from forgiving debt from a
$5 million bankruptcy loan and debt from notes owned by Fortress
affiliates. Coda will focus on its energy-storage business and
its automotive assets will be liquidated. </p>
<p>The sale was negotiated as part of a broader deal brokered
with the official committee of unsecured creditors that will lay
the groundwork for a potential reorganization plan. In addition
to the $1.7 million in cash, $1.9 million of the bankruptcy loan
will remain with the estate to help pay administrative claims. </p>
<p>This has been a lengthy and complicated process,
Sontchi told the attorneys. It was a close call, the judge
said. The opposing arguments were tempered by the fact the
creditors'' committee is onboard with the sale, after
negotiating for better terms under the deal, he said. </p>
<h2>Forgiven Loans </h2>
<p>The U.S. Trustee argued that what he called potential
claims for fraudulent transfers, against two officers for the
forgiveness of loans before the bankruptcy, were being
inappropriately sold as part of the deal. </p>
<p>The purpose of a sale is not to protect insiders in this
ring, but to maximize value, David L. Buchbinder, a lawyer for
the U.S. Trustee, told Sontchi. </p>
<p>The alleged claims are not particularly strong, Roberto
J. Kampfner, a lawyer for Coda, told the judge. </p>
<p>The Los Angeles-based company, whose Coda Automotive unit
also sought court protection, listed assets of as much as $50
million and debt of as much as $100 million in court documents
filed in May. </p>
<p>Coda was forced to seek bankruptcy protection because of
production delays, insufficient capital to market and sell its
sedan, and slow growth for the electric-vehicle market, which it
blames on the scarcity of charging stations, according to a
declaration by Chief Restructuring Officer John P. Madden. </p>
<h2>Production Delays </h2>
<p>Sales of the Coda sedan, built off China-based Hafei Motor
Co.''s Saibao platform, fell short of expectations, with fewer
than 100 units sold since entering the market in March 2012,
according to court papers. Complications adapting the sedan to
an electric platform and meeting U.S. regulatory standards
delayed production. </p>
<p>The compact, which cost $37,250 before a $7,500 U.S. tax
credit, averages 88 miles (142 kilometers) per charge and can
travel as far as 125 miles, according to U.S. Environmental
Protection Agency estimates. </p>
<p>Coda had raised about $344 million in equity investments
since its founding, according to court documents. Investors
included New World Strategic Investment Ltd., Indus Capital and
Och-Ziff Capital Management Group LLC (OZM), Aeris Capital, Angeleno
Group LLC, billionaire Philip Falcone''s Harbinger Capital
Partners LLC and Riverstone Holdings LLC, Coda said in 2011. </p>
<p>The case is In re Coda Holdings Inc., 13-11153, U.S.
Bankruptcy Court, District of Delaware (Wilmington). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Jun 11, 2013  5:46 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-11/jpmorgan-s-dimon-says-there-was-no-lying-hiding-on-whale-loss.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Dimon Says There Was No Lying, Hiding on Whale</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co (JPM). will fight till the end anyone who sues claiming they were misled over more than $6.2 billion in losses at the chief investment office last year, Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon said. </p> <p>There was no hiding, there was no lying, there was no bulls----ing, period, Dimon said today at a conference sponsored by Morgan Stanley in New York. </p> <p>While he conceded the company made some mistakes, no one at JPMorgan Chase (JPM), not one single solitary person, from CIO, to risk, to finance, to myself -- and a lot of people looked at it -- thought we had a big problem when the bank reported earnings on April 13, 2012, the day Dimon dismissed news reports about the trade as a complete tempest in a teapot, he said. Executives thought they had losses that might cost about $200 million, Dimon said, not a $6 billion problem. </p> <p>The trading book had already lost more than $1 billion by that time, according to documents turned over to the U.S. Senate Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations, which released a 301-page report in March that accused the largest and most profitable U.S. bank of hiding losses, deceiving regulators and misinforming investors. </p> <p>Dimon, 57, said the New York-based company would vigorously defend against lawsuits tied to the losses. Anyone who sues, we''re going to fight that one till the end, too, by the way, he said. So keep that in mind. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
Jamie Dimon, chief executive officer of JPMorgan Chase  Co., speaks during a Senate Banking Committee hearing in Washington, D.C., on June 13, 2012. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jim Snyder" date="Jun 11, 2013  3:29 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-11/chevron-ceo-says-industry-must-deal-with-fracking-concern.html"><headline>Chevron CEO Says Industry Must Deal With Fracking Concern</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Energy producers must deal with the
legitimate concerns that gas development associated with
hydraulic fracturing is unsafe by adopting tougher standards,
Chevron Corp. (CVX) Chief Executive Officer John Watson said. </p>
<p>BP Plc''s 2010 oil spill at its deepwater well in the Gulf
of Mexico -- the worst in U.S. waters -- fueled public
skepticism of the industry, Watson said today in Washington.
Fracking, a drilling technique that has increased production by
extracting oil and gas trapped in shale rock, has drawn oil and
gas companies to rural communities that aren''t familiar with the
development. </p>
<p>Recent developments add to public awareness of the risks of
drilling, and the industry needs to do a better job in resolving
the concerns, Watson said at a Center for Strategic and
International Studies event. </p>
<p>Public expectations are very high, and there''s no reason
they shouldn''t be high, Watson said. There are some risks
out there. Some risks are overstated. But we have to engage them
either way. </p>
<p>Kurt Glaubitz, a Chevron spokesman, said Watson was
referring to concerns with truck traffic and the disposal of
hazardous wastewater from the fracking process as areas of
concern the industry needs to confront. </p>
<h2>Air, Water </h2>
<p>In hydraulic fracturing, or fracking, producers shoot a
mixture of water, sand and chemicals underground to break apart
shale rock formations to free trapped oil and gas. The technique
has led to record production of natural gas and sent domestic
oil output to its highest level in two decades. </p>
<p>Opponents say fracking creates air and water pollution. </p>
<p>Chevron has joined environmental groups including the
Environmental Defense Fund to establish the Center for
Sustainable Shale Development that has crafted 15 performance
standards to be followed by oil and gas producers. </p>
<p>I don''t believe any company would be certified today, but
we''re moving towards those standards, Watson said. </p>
<p>The U.S. Energy Information Administration said yesterday
that oil and gas from shale formations are greater than
previously estimated. Tight oil resources could be 345 billion
barrels worldwide, and shale gas estimates were increased by 10
percent from 2011, to 7,299 trillion cubic feet, according to
the EIA, which tracks and analyzes energy data. </p>
<p>Watson said it may take a lot of time to develop some
of the resources because infrastructure is in short supply. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sonia Sirletti" date="Jun 11, 2013  1:05 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-11/generali-sells-minority-stakes-to-banorte-for-857-5-million.html"><headline>Generali Sells Minority Stakes to Banorte for $857.5 Million</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Assicurazioni Generali SpA (G) agreed to
sell minority stakes in Mexican businesses to Grupo Financiero
Banorte SAB for $857.5 million as Italy''s biggest insurer seeks
to boost capital. </p>
<p>Generali is selling its 49 percent stakes in Seguros
Banorte Generali and Pensiones Banorte Generali to Banorte,
Mexico''s third-largest lender, which holds the remainder, the
Trieste, Italy-based company said in a statement today. Generali
will book a 500 million-euro ($664 million) capital gain,
boosting its Solvency I ratio by four percentage points. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Mario Greco wants to boost profit
and increase capital by disposing of certain assets, cutting
costs and focusing on faster-growing emerging markets. The
company, which set a goal of 4 billion euros of revenue from
asset sales by 2015, exceeded 50 percent of the target with this
sale, Greco said in the statement. </p>
<p>We seized Banorte''s offer at the best conditions for us
and withdrew from a minority position which was no longer
consistent with Generali''s current strategy, Greco said.
Latin America remains a very attractive market for Generali;
we therefore are interested in developing our business in the
region, in particular in the Brazilian market. </p>
<h2>Asset Sales </h2>
<p>The Italian insurer is also selling its Swiss asset-management unit BSI Group as part of a plan approved in January,
after completing the disposal of its U.S. reinsurance unit last
week. Generali is in an advanced stage of selling BSI, Greco
said last month. </p>
<p>Bankinter SA (BKT) of Spain may buy BSI, CEO Maria Dolores
Dancausa said in April. The firm offered 1.5 billion euros in
partnership with U.S.-based Apollo Global Management, Swiss
newspaper L''Agefi reported in March. Generali has said the unit
has a book value of 2.3 billion euros. </p>
<p>Generali said June 4 it expects proceeds from the sale of
its U.S. unit to Scor SE (SCR), France''s largest reinsurer, of $920
million, including the $750 million purchase price, $30 million
of estimated profit and $140 million of released collateral. The
company will book a $150 million capital gain from the sale,
boosting its Solvency I ratio by about one percentage point. </p>
<p>The insurer, which expects higher total operating profit
this year, reported first-quarter net income rising 6.3 percent
to 603 million euros as non-life insurance earnings surged. </p>
<p>Generali, which has gained 55 percent in the past 12
months, fell 1.4 percent to 13.93 euros in Milan trading today
giving the company a market value of 21.7 billion euros. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki and Michael J. Moore" date="Jun 11, 2013 12:12 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-11/jpmorgan-chase-credit-rating-outlook-changed-to-negative-by-s-p.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Credit Outlook Cut by S&amp;amp;P as U.S. Support Wanes</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s credit-rating
outlook was revised to negative by Standard  Poor''s, which said
the likelihood of extraordinary government support for the
largest U.S. banks is waning. </p>
<p>The outlook on JPMorgan''s long-term rating of A was lowered
from stable, SP said today in a statement. That brings JPMorgan
in line with the seven other systemically important banks
including Bank of America Corp. and Goldman Sachs Group Inc.,
whose outlooks were held at negative. New York-based JPMorgan is
the biggest U.S. bank, with $2.4 trillion in assets. </p>
<p>SP may stop giving weight to the implied taxpayer support
that has bolstered credit ratings at eight of the largest U.S.
bank-holding companies. In the wake of the 2008 credit crunch,
investors have assumed the federal government would bail out
lenders in a renewed crisis because their failure would be
catastrophic for the financial system. </p>
<p>It is becoming increasingly clear that holding company
creditors may not receive extraordinary government support,
SP analysts led by Matthew Albrecht wrote in the statement. He
cited the framework regulators are developing that could be used
to dismantle and liquidate distressed banks. </p>
<p>SP analysts believe that the U.S. government would still
stand by the operating subsidiaries of the largest banks,
Albrecht said on a conference call. </p>
<h2>Absorbing Losses </h2>
<p>Regulators are intent on asking holding-company creditors
to absorb losses ahead of operating-company creditors, and
they''re putting mechanisms in place that could make that more
likely, he said. We don''t believe the U.S. government is
becoming less supportive, simply less supportive to a certain
class of creditors. </p>
<p>If SP entirely removed U.S. support from the credit rating
of the bank-holding companies, it could result in a one- to two-level cut in their grades, he said. </p>
<p>JPMorgan''s shares dropped 0.9 percent to $53.90 at 11:52
a.m. in New York, compared with a 0.7 percent decline in the KBW
Bank Index. Kristin Lemkau, a spokeswoman for the bank, didn''t
respond to a request for comment. </p>
<p>SP said it will review progress that regulators make on
their new orderly liquidation authority as it determines
whether to stop including government support in its bank
ratings. </p>
<h2>Lehman Bankruptcy </h2>
<p>U.S. and U.K. regulators have been working on plans to
allow large international banks to fail without damaging the
rest of the financial system. The bankruptcy of Lehman Brothers
Holdings Inc. in 2008 helped trigger a worldwide economic
meltdown that threatened to destroy other global lenders. </p>
<p>We may remove the ratings uplift we currently incorporate
if we believe that regulators and lawmakers are increasingly
likely to ask holding-company bondholders to bear losses in the
event of a liquidation of a systemically important bank, SP
said. We currently believe those creditors will be supported
to prevent the contagion of a crisis. </p>
<p>Both the Bank of England and the Federal Deposit Insurance
Corp. foresee that a wide range of unsecured creditors could
face losses during a bank''s failure, according to a paper
released in December. Unsecured senior bondholders and uninsured
depositors are among those who could take a financial hit, the
paper said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Miles Weiss" date="Jun 11, 2013 11:51 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-11/goldman-loan-to-ex-trader-cader-is-backed-by-15-000-wines.html"><headline>Goldman Loan to Ex-Trader Cader Is Backed by 15,000 Wines</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Talk about liquid assets. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) accepted almost 15,000 bottles of fine wine as loan collateral from a former high-ranking executive, according to a regulatory filing last month. Andrew Cader, a former senior director at Goldman Sachs''s specialist-trading unit, pledged a secured interest in the wines, which are primarily from the Burgundy and Bordeaux regions of France, the filing showed. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs''s move stands out because private banks that lend money to wealthy clients against assets such as artwork and real estate have been less willing to extend loans backed by fine wines, said four specialty lenders and attorneys. While investment-grade wines have outperformed the stock market over the past decade, the asset class has been prone to fraud, prompting billionaire William Koch to file a series of lawsuits to deter counterfeiting. </p> <p>There are a lot of very highly valued wines here, said David Parker, the head of Benchmark Wine Group in Napa, California, adding that the collection cited in the filing had an estimated market value in the low-seven-digit dollar range. The Bordeaux are all first growth and other classified-growth and the Burgundies are all grand cru and top premier cru. </p>




Photographer: Haruyoshi Yamaguchi/Bloomberg

<p>
Andrew Cader was sued in April by hedge-fund manager Warren Lichtenstein, pictured, the chairman of New York-based Steel Partners LLC, who claimed Cader helped wrongly inflate child support payments for the mother of Lichtenstein''s 5-year-old daughter. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elisha Bala-Gbogbo" date="Jun 11, 2013  8:13 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-11/chevron-to-sell-interest-in-two-nigeria-shallow-water-oil-leases.html"><headline>Chevron to Sell Interest in Two Nigeria Shallow-Water Oil Leases</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX), the second-largest
U.S. oil company, said it plans to sell its interest in two
Nigerian shallow-water leases in the oil-rich delta of Africa''s
top producer. </p>
<p>The sale of interest in oil-mining leases 83 and 85 is
part of a continuous process of portfolio evaluation and
business prioritization, James Craig, a Houston-based company
spokesman, said today in an e-mailed response to questions. </p>
<p>Chevron, the third-largest producer in the West African
country, operates a joint venture in which it holds a 40 percent
stake and state-owned Nigerian National Petroleum Corp. owns 60
percent. The company holds interests in 10 deepwater oil blocks
in Nigeria, including its 250,000 barrel-a-day Agbami field
located 70 miles (113 kilometers) off the coast. </p>
<p>Chevron joins Royal Dutch Shell Plc (RDSA) and ConocoPhillips (COP) in
selling Nigerian oil interests. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Frier" date="Jun 12, 2013  4:52 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-12/ibm-said-to-start-u-s-jobs-cuts-amid-1-billion-restructuring.html"><headline>IBM Said to Start U.S. Job Cuts Today Amid Global Reduction</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM), the world''s largest computer-services provider, began
cutting U.S. jobs today as part of a global restructuring plan
announced in April, a person familiar with the move said. </p>
<p>The reduction targets employees with a range of seniority,
from rank-and-file staff to executives, said the person, who
asked not to be named because the information is private. Some
U.S. workers began to receive notifications of the cuts last
night, according to Lee Conrad, a coordinator for Alliance@IBM,
an employee group. The restructuring will cost $1 billion
worldwide, including severance expenses. </p>
<p>IBM announced the job-cutting effort after releasing
disappointing first-quarter results in April. The Armonk, New
York-based company posted profit of $3 a share in the period,
missing the $3.05 predicted by analysts -- the first earnings
shortfall since 2005, according to data compiled by Bloomberg.
IBM said at the time that the job reduction would be
concentrated overseas and mostly complete by the end of June. </p>
<p>The company is probably cutting 6,000 to 8,000 jobs
globally, based on the $1 billion cost figure, said Laurence Balter, an analyst at Oracle Investment Research in Fox Island,
Washington. That would represent less than 2 percent of IBM''s
total workforce of 434,246 as of Dec. 31. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
International Business Machines Corp., the world''s largest provider of computer services, announced the job-cutting effort after releasing disappointing first-quarter results in April. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jun 12, 2013  4:08 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-12/morgan-stanley-s-gorman-seeks-higher-fixed-income-trade-returns.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley''s Gorman Seeks Higher Fixed-Income Trade Returns</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley has a plan to boost
return on equity in fixed-income trading above its cost of
equity after four of the five units failed to meet that metric
last year, Chief Executive Officer James Gorman said. </p>
<p>The credit-trading unit can earn a 15 percent return and
interest rates and foreign-exchange trading can each top 10
percent, Gorman, 54, said today at a conference sponsored by the
New York-based bank. All had returns on equity of more than 5
percent last year, said Gorman, who cited 10 percent as the
firm''s cost of equity. </p>
<p>We''re not where we want to be with fixed-income and
commodities, Gorman said. On the other hand, we think we''ve
made more progress than perhaps has been understood, but this is
a multiyear transformation of a very complex business. </p>
<p>Commodities, which had a return on equity of less than 5
percent last year, was the one unit for which he didn''t state a
target. Morgan Stanley (MS) held talks with Qatar''s sovereign-wealth
fund last year about selling a stake in the business, and Gorman
said the firm is carefully re-evaluating the proper
structure for the business. </p>
<p>The U.S. Dodd-Frank Act limits the firm''s ability to
acquire physical commodities, Gorman said. The past two quarters
have been among the worst for commodities since 1995, he said. </p>
<p>The overall performance of the business can and will be
improved, Gorman said. But that said, we continue to explore
strategic structures that may make sense for us. </p>
<p>The securitized-products unit had a return on equity of
more than 15 percent last year, and that remains the firm''s
target, Gorman said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sophia Pearson, Susan Decker and David Voreacos" date="Jun 12, 2013 12:36 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-12/pfizer-gets-2-15-billion-settlement-from-teva-sun-on-protonix.html"><headline>Pfizer Reaches $2.15 Billion Protonix Accord With Teva</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Teva Pharmaceutical Industries Ltd. (TEVA)
and Sun Pharmaceutical Industries Ltd. will pay $2.15 billion to
Pfizer Inc. (PFE) and a partner to settle litigation over unauthorized
sales of the heartburn drug Protonix. </p>
<p>Pfizer, the world''s largest drugmaker, will receive
64 percent of the settlement while partner Takeda Pharmaceutical
Co. will get the rest, New York-based Pfizer said in a statement
today. Teva will pay $1.6 billion, including $800 million this
year and the rest in 2014, according to a company statement. Sun
said it will pay $550 million. </p>
<p>We are pleased with today''s settlement, which recognizes
the validity and value of the innovation that led to Protonix,
Amy Schulman, Pfizer''s general counsel, said in the statement. </p>
<p>Teva and Sun (SUNP) began selling generic versions in 2008 only to
lose a challenge to a patent on the medicine two years later.
Pfizer''s Wyeth unit was seeking $2.7 billion from Teva and Sun,
saying it was entitled to a share of the revenue from those
generic versions, as well as compensation for sales it lost to
the copycat. </p>
<p>A trial over Pfizer''s claims began June 3 in federal court
in Newark, New Jersey. </p>
<p>We are pleased to put this matter behind us as we
continue to focus on delivering safe and affordable medicines to
patients around the world, Richard Egosi, Teva''s chief legal
officer, said in the statement. </p>




Photographer: JB Reed/Bloomberg.

<p>
Pfizer Inc. said a $2.15 billion settlement has been reached with Teva Pharmaceutical Industries Ltd and Sun Pharmaceutical Industries Ltd. after an almost 10-year dispute over the sale of generic Protonix in the U.S. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Noah Buhayar" date="Jun 12, 2013 12:21 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-12/jpmorgan-hires-goldman-s-sharma-for-insurance-bond-post.html"><headline>JPMorgan Hires Goldman''s Sharma for Insurance Bond Post</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s asset-management unit hired Prashant Sharma as head of international
fixed-income investments for insurance clients. </p>
<p>Sharma will be based in London and report to Nick Gartside,
international chief investment officer of fixed-income, New
York-based JPMorgan said today in an e-mailed statement. Sharma
previously worked at Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)''s asset-management
business and has a decade of experience working as a fixed-income portfolio manager. </p>
<p>Asset managers including Goldman Sachs and BlackRock Inc.
have been expanding their offerings and adding staff to win
mandates from insurance companies as low interest rates pressure
income from bond portfolios. JPMorgan, which oversees about $50
billion for the industry, recently made additions in Hong Kong
and Tokyo for the insurance solutions business and last year
named Douglas Niemann, who previously worked at American
International Group Inc., to lead strategy and analytics. </p>
<p>Fixed-income investing is extremely important to insurance
clients, particularly in the current low interest-rate
environment,Gartside said in the statement.However, their
investment needs as a client group are unique, and as our
insurance solutions business grows, Prashant''s dedicated
expertise will be integral to this. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
JPMorgan Chase  Co., which oversees about $50 billion for the industry, recently made additions in Hong Kong and Tokyo for the insurance solutions business. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sheenagh Matthews" date="Jun 12, 2013 10:20 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-12/chevron-phillips-looks-at-new-middle-east-chemical-plant.html"><headline>Chevron Phillips Looks at New Middle East Chemical Plant</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Phillips Chemical Co., the
petrochemical venture of U.S. oil producer Chevron Corp. (CVX) and
refiner Phillips 66 (PSX), is exploring ways to expand in the Middle
East, including building a new plant. </p>
<p>The U.S. partnership would consider setting up a site on
its own or in a joint venture, and the entire region is
under consideration, Benny Mermans, head of Europe and Africa at
Chevron Phillips Chemical''s international operations, said in an
interview at a petrochemical conference in Frankfurt. </p>
<p>The chemical company''s owners are very supportive of
growth plans, Mermans said. Woodlands, Texas-based Chevron
Phillips, also known as CPChem, is already spending about $5
billion on a new ethylene plant, or cracker, and two factories
making polyethylene in Baytown, Texas, to take advantage of
cheap natural gas, which is used as a raw material as well as an
energy source. </p>
<p>Look at our ownership structure, Mermans said. We
represent a fair share of their net income. By having that
support, by creating margins, that provides us with a lot of
legroom for gaining resources for growth. </p>
<p>Chevron Phillips has three joint ventures in the Saudi
Arabian industrial city of Jubail as well as partnerships in
Qatar in Messaieed and Ras Laffan, Melanie Samuelson, a
spokeswoman at the U.S. company, said in an e-mail. </p>
<h2>Funding Sources </h2>
<p>Expansion would be financed by the chemical business
itself, and Chevron Phillips would tap capital markets for
further cash should the need arise, Mermans said. </p>
<p>Availability of cheaper shale gas in the U.S., extracted by
the hydraulic fracturing process known as fracking, means that
Europe is being squeezed on all sides, Mermans said. The
company will focus on more specialty chemicals in the region and
is expanding a plant in Tessenderlo, Belgium, to add sulfur-based organic products. </p>
<p>In the U.S., Chevron Phillips is the first company in more
than a decade to build an ethylene plant, Mermans said. The
cracker, which will produce 1.5 million metric tons of the
gaseous chemical a year, is on schedule to start operations in
2017, with the company''s board expected to give final approval
in the third quarter, he said. </p>
<p>Dow Chemical Co. (DOW), the largest U.S. chemical maker by sales,
and Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM), the biggest U.S. oil company, have said
they plan similar-sized ethylene plants in Texas. </p>
<p>It''s a race, Mermans said. CPChem is well placed to
be first. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Janelle Lawrence" date="Jun 12, 2013 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-12/goldman-sachs-s-trial-win-in-dragon-systems-deal-upheld.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Wins Ruling After Dragon Systems Deal Trial</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)''s missteps
advising speech-recognition pioneer Dragon Systems Inc. in a
merger weren''t egregious enough for the bank to be found in
violation of a Massachusetts law, a federal judge ruled. </p>
<p>U.S. District Judge Patti B. Saris in Boston, citing a jury
verdict in January that rejected a $580 million negligence suit
filed by Dragon founders Jim and Janet Baker and two other
shareholders, denied the plaintiffs'' request for claims against
Goldman Sachs under the state''s Unfair Trade Practices statute. </p>
<p>The judge called the investment banking team assigned to
the all-stock sale of Dragon to a Belgium competitor in 2000
professionally negligent because it didn''t fully vet buyer
Lernout  Hauspie Speech Products NV, which collapsed in an
accounting fraud rendering the deal worthless. </p>
<p>The reasons why small startup companies like Dragon go to
a place like Goldman to assist with hatching their golden eggs
is because they don''t have their own expertise to analyze
revenue projects by asking tough questions to potential merger
partners, the judge said. </p>
<p>Still, I give weight to the fact that the jury found for
the defendant on this claim and there was sufficient evidence to
support that finding even if I conclude otherwise, Saris said
in yesterday''s ruling. </p>
<p>The Bakers'' attorney, Alan Cotler of Reed Smith LLP, said
yesterday in an e-mail that his firm was still studying the
ruling. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs said yesterday in a statement it was pleased
the judge respected the jury''s unanimous verdict. </p>
<h2>Jury''s Conclusion </h2>
<p>The evidence showed, and the jury concluded, that the
banking team satisfactorily performed its role for Dragon
Systems in all respects, the New York-based bank said. </p>
<p>The Bakers, who started Dragon in 1982 in their Newton,
Massachusetts, home, along with shareholders Robert Roth and
Paul Bamberg, lost about $300 million along with the
intellectual property, the judge found. </p>
<p>Plaintiffs may have been brilliant mathematicians and
scientists, but they had no financial experience with mergers
and acquisitions, Saris said. </p>
<p>The Goldman team was lead by Richard Wayner, then 31, and
included two bankers in their 20s, and a technology strategist. </p>
<p>The judge found Wayner should have spoken up at a key
Dragon board meeting and told members that Goldman Sachs wanted
further review of LH''s revenue figures in Asia, which were
later revealed as a fraud. Instead, Wayner deferred to Janet
Baker, who was eager to complete the sale and made positive
comments about the pending deal, the judge said. </p>
<h2>Due Diligence </h2>
<p>At the very least, in my view, the Goldman team should
have disclosed their continuing due diligence concerns, Saris
said. However, there is no evidence that their failure to do
so was egregious. </p>
<p>Plaintiffs argued Goldman Sachs should have told Dragon
that the bank''s own Principal Investment Area considered an
investment in LH in the late 1990s and decided against risking
the bank''s money. </p>
<p>The judge found none of the bankers on the Dragon deal knew
about the work known as Project Sermon, and no one at
Goldman withheld information about why the bank never invested. </p>
<p>LH created bogus customers, booked circular transactions
with shell companies and recorded loans as sales from 1996 to
2000, according to a U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission
probe. Four executives were sentenced to prison for fraud in a
criminal investigation. </p>
<p>The case is Baker v. Goldman Sachs  Co., 09-cv-10053, U.S.
District Court, District of Massachusetts (Boston). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Frier" date="Jun 13, 2013  4:47 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-13/ibm-s-u-s-job-cuts-reach-at-least-1-300-employee-group-says.html"><headline>IBM U.S. Job Cuts Reach at Least 1,300, Employee Group Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM), the world''s largest computer-services provider, has fired
at least 1,300 workers in a round of U.S. job cuts that began
yesterday, according to the employee group Alliance@IBM. </p>
<p>The job reduction includes at least 222 people in marketing
for the software business and 165 in semiconductor research and
development, according to Lee Conrad, a coordinator for
Alliance@IBM, which is affiliated with the Communications
Workers of America union. </p>
<p>The move is part of a global restructuring plan that IBM
announced in April after releasing disappointing first-quarter
results. The cuts target employees with a range of seniority,
from executives to rank-and-file workers, said a person familiar
with the effort, who asked not to be identified because the
information is private. The restructuring will cost $1 billion
worldwide, including severance expenses. </p>
<p>Just about every division at every location is being
impacted, Conrad said, including IBM hubs near Raleigh, North
Carolina; Burlington, Vermont; Austin, Texas; and New York''s
Hudson Valley. Everything''s getting hit. </p>
<p>The Armonk, New York-based company posted profit of $3 a
share last quarter, missing the $3.05 predicted by analysts --
the first earnings shortfall since 2005, according to data
compiled by Bloomberg. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
Pedestrians walk past International Business Machines Corp. (IBM) offices in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ruth David" date="Jun 13, 2013  2:44 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-13/jpmorgan-chase-names-esteve-head-of-emea-equity-syndicate.html"><headline>JPMorgan Chase Names Esteve Head of EMEA Equity Syndicate</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. named Manuel Esteve head of equity syndicate for Europe, the Middle East and
Africa, according to a memo obtained by Bloomberg News. </p>
<p>Esteve succeeds Greg Chamberlain, who will become head of
the U.K. equity capital markets team, according to the memo,
which was confirmed by a spokeswoman for the New York-based
bank. Jonathan Wilcox, who has run U.K. equity capital markets,
will move to U.K. investment banking to focus on corporate
clients as a coverage banker. </p>
<p>Esteve previously ran the Iberia and Greece ECM team.
Francesco Cardinali will add Iberia and Greece to his current
responsibilities as head of Italy and Turkey equity capital
markets, the memo shows. </p>
<p>JPMorgan ranked No. 6 in managing share sales in Europe,
the Middle East and Africa this year, according to data compiled
by Bloomberg. The U.S. bank was the sole manager of Volkswagen
AG (VOW)''s 1.2 billion-euro ($1.6 billion) convertible sale earlier
this week. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Drew Armstrong" date="Jun 13, 2013  1:52 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-13/pfizer-s-two-new-top-pills-selling-slower-than-expected.html"><headline>Pfizer''s Two New Top Pills Selling Slower Than Expected</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE)''s touted two new drugs
aren''t selling as fast as the company anticipated, a top
executive said today, though the drugmaker expects the pills
should still become blockbusters. </p>
<p>Eliquis, a blood thinner, and Xeljanz, a rheumatoid
arthritis medicine, were approved late last year and projected
to be the backbone of new sales growth at the world''s biggest
drugmaker. The pills are competing against well-entrenched
products, though, and Pfizer hasn''t been able to gain as much of
the market in the first months of sales as it had hoped. </p>
<p>The trajectory isn''t what we would have liked it to have
been, Geno Germano, who heads New York-based Pfizer''s
specialty drugs and oncology businesses, said of Xeljanz. With
Eliquis, he said, two competing pills have made early sales
harder. I think some of the low-hanging fruit has been taken
by the entries that came before Eliquis, he said. </p>
<p>Pfizer is counting on the new drugs and cancer treatments
and vaccines in development, to return the company to sales
growth after losing top product Lipitor to generic competition
in November 2011. Chief Executive Officer Ian Read has shed non-drug units to focus on developing new brand-name therapies. </p>
<p>Eliquis may generate $613 million in annual sales for
Pfizer by 2016, according to the average of three analysts''
estimates compiled by Bloomberg. Xeljanz may have $1.6 billion
in sales by then, according to the analysts'' estimates. </p>
<p>Pfizer rose 1.5 percent to $28.85 at 1:07 p.m. New York
time. The stock gained 28 percent in the 12 months through
yesterday. </p>
<h2>Blood Thinner </h2>
<p>Eliquis is competing to replace warfarin, a generic pill
used to prevent strokes, and with Boehringer Ingelheim GmbH''s
Pradaxa, and Bayer AG (BAYN) and Johnson  Johnson''s Xarelto. While
Eliquis is considered to have superior clinical data, its rivals
were approved earlier and have had time to establish themselves
with doctors and patients. </p>
<p>I think some of us are a little bit surprised, given the
strength of the label, the strength of the field force, said
Jami Rubin, an analyst with Goldman Sachs Group Inc. Germano''s
comments came today at an investor conference hosted by Goldman.
The trajectory of the launch is a little bit below what some
of us had expected, Rubin said. </p>
<p>Pfizer is splitting promotion and sales of Eliquis with New
York-based Bristol-Myers Squibb Co. (BMY) A direct-to-consumer ad
campaign should begin soon, Germano said, without giving a
timeline. </p>
<p>We think that ultimately, the profile will prevail,
Germano said of Eliquis. </p>
<h2>Sluggish Start </h2>
<p>Rubin said Xeljanz''s first months of sales also were below
expectations. From our perspective, it does look a little bit
lower than I would have thought, she said. </p>
<p>Xeljanz is approved for use in rheumatoid arthritis. It
competes directly with AbbVie Inc. (ABBV)''s Humira, an injection, and
is approved for use after patients fail a first-line therapy,
typically methotrexate. Germano said that about half of the
patients now taking Xeljanz had failed treatment on
methotrexate, and the other half were those who no longer
responded to Humira or related medications. </p>
<p>Everything I see and hear is positive, Germano said.
Changing practice just takes a lot of work. </p>
<p>Some health insurers and drug benefit managers were
limiting access to Xeljanz and forcing patients to try multiple
other therapies before getting access to the new drug, he said. </p>
<p>These are issues for all of us. I''m not going to say we
don''t have those issues. But we don''t seem to have a pattern of
reimbursement that''s different. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Jun 13, 2013 12:35 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-13/jpmorgan-s-hogan-might-leave-after-returning-to-work-dimon-says.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Hogan Might Leave After Returning to Work, Dimon Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) Chief Risk
Officer John Hogan is returning to the bank in a new role after
taking almost five months off and may decide to leave the firm
altogether later this year or next, Chief Executive Officer
Jamie Dimon told employees in a memo today. </p>
<p>Hogan will return to Dimon''s operating committee and assume
a newly created job as chairman of risk while interim CRO Ashley Bacon takes over in a permanent capacity starting next week,
Dimon said in the memo. Bacon will also join the operating
committee, he said. </p>
<p>John plans to carry out this important transition for
several months, Dimon said. We then hope he will stay at the
firm in another senior role, but he may choose to do something
different outside of our company. </p>
<p>A copy of the memo was obtained by Bloomberg News, and its 
contents were confirmed by Joe Evangelisti, a spokesman for the 
New York-based company. </p>
<p>Dimon said Hogan did a superb job as head of risk when we
needed him most and that he respects Hogan''s decision to
return to the bank in a different role. Hogan took leave in
January for personal reasons. </p>
<p>We''re very glad to have John back -- his judgment and
candor make all of us better, Dimon said. </p>




Photographer: Jason Alden/Bloomberg

<p>
JPMorgan Chase  Co. Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lisa Abramowicz" date="Jun 13, 2013 10:48 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-13/jpmorgan-to-barclays-usher-bond-shift-to-stocks-credit-markets.html"><headline>JPMorgan to Barclays Ushering Bond Buyers Into Equities</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Wall Street''s biggest bond dealers
are telling clients to shift from most fixed-income markets into
U.S. stocks as deepening concern the Federal Reserve will pare
unprecedented stimulus fuels the worst debt losses since 2011. </p>
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the most-active underwriter of
corporate bonds since 2007, last week joined Barclays Plc (BARC), Bank
of America Corp. (BAC), Morgan Stanley (MS) and Goldman Sachs (GS) Group Inc. in
recommending stocks over most bonds as equity returns outpace
company notes by the most since at least 1997. The Bank of
America Merrill Lynch U.S. Corporate  High Yield Index''s 0.73
percent loss this year through June 11 compares with a 15.1
percent gain for the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index. (SPX) </p>
<p>Securities from Treasuries to junk bonds are showing their
vulnerability to a potential pullback from Fed actions that have
pumped more than $2.5 trillion into the financial system since
2008. Debt remains most tied up with the search for yield
and faces more volatility than equities as interest rates rise,
JPMorgan strategists led by Jan Loeys said in a June 7 report. </p>
<p>We''ve now seen a little bit of a rotation out of bond
funds, said Hans Mikkelsen, head of U.S. investment-grade
credit strategy at Bank of America in New York. You could see
a very quick change in asset allocation on the retail side that
the institutional side can''t keep up with it. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
The global economy is in the early stages of the recovery of the equity culture and perhaps the end of a 30-year growing love affair with bonds, said Jim O''Neill, former chairman of Goldman Sachs Asset Management in a June 11 interview on Bloomberg Television. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jim Brunsden" date="Jun 13, 2013  5:45 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-13/visa-europe-s-offer-to-end-card-fee-probe-is-market-tested-by-eu.html"><headline>Visa Europe''s Offer to End Card-Fee Probe Is Market Tested by EU</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>European Union antitrust regulators
invited comments on Visa Europe Ltd.''s offer to cut
significantly the fees it sets for processing cross-border
credit-card payments in a bid to end an EU antitrust probe. </p>
<p>Visa Europe''s offer from last month would bring its fees
into line with those of its main competitor MasterCard Inc. (MA), the
European Commission said in an e-mailed statement today. The
operator of the EU''s largest payment-card network has also
offered to overhaul its rules so that banks will be able to
apply a reduced interbank fee when they compete for clients
across borders. </p>
<p>If the proposals address the commission''s competition
concerns, the commission may decide to make them legally binding
on Visa Europe in exchange for ending the probe, the regulator
said. </p>
<p>The commission sent a formal complaint to Visa about the
interchange fees last year, as part of a broader campaign it has
waged against such charges. MasterCard has started a legal
challenge against a settlement it reached with the commission in
2009 to avoid a daily penalty of as much as 3.5 percent of
sales. The EU is also probing MasterCard''s bank fees on foreign
card payments such as when tourists go shopping in the 27-nation
bloc. </p>
<p>The EU regulator also announced today that it has closed a
probe into the European Payments Council, an association of
banks that seeks to standardize payments practices, after the
body stopped its work on e-payment rules at the center of the
probe. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bloomberg News" date="Jun 13, 2013  5:11 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-13/morgan-stanley-to-ubs-cut-china-growth-forecasts-after-may-data.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley to UBS Cut China Growth Forecasts After May Data</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley joined banks from UBS
AG and Barclays Plc in cutting estimates for China''s economic
growth after weaker expansion in exports, industrial output and
new lending last month. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley lowered its estimate for an increase in 2013
gross domestic product to 7.6 percent from 8.2 percent,
economists led by Hong Kong-based Helen Qiao wrote in a note
today. UBS and Royal Bank of Scotland Group Plc this week pared
their forecasts to 7.5 percent while Barclays now sees 7.4
percent, which would be the slowest pace since 1990. </p>
<p>President Xi Jinping and Premier Li Keqiang have signaled a
tolerance for slower expansion since taking office in March as
they reduce the state''s role in the economy, give market forces
more power and curb pollution. Their room to loosen policies is
limited by rising financial risks, with Moody''s Investors
Service warning today that some local authorities who have taken
on too much debt may need to be bailed out. </p>
<p>Policy makers see such short-term pain as the necessary
price to pay for reforms and growth sustainability in the long
term, Morgan Stanley economists wrote in today''s report. The
lower growth forecasts reflect the new government''s less pro-growth policy stance, they said. </p>
<p>The bank also cut its estimate for 2014 expansion to 7.6
percent from a previous 7.9 percent and pared its inflation
forecast for this year to 2.6 percent from 3.5 percent. </p>
<h2>Bearish Outlook </h2>
<p>The World Bank lowered its projection for global growth
this year to 2.2 percent from 2.4 percent after a larger-than-forecast slowdown in emerging markets including China, according
to a report released yesterday in Washington. </p>
<p>While we remain cautious about growth, we are not getting
bearish, Chang Jian, a Hong Kong-based economist at Barclays
wrote in a June 9 note that cut the 2013 growth estimate from
7.9 percent. Fundamentally China is going through a transition
period and pain is unavoidable as the economy experiences a
deflating of the global demand and domestic investment bubble,
while searching for new growth drivers. </p>
<p>Australia  New Zealand Banking Group Ltd. (ANZ) lowered its 2013
China estimate to 7.6 percent from 7.8 percent on June 9, the
same day the National Bureau of Statistics reported May economic
data that showed industrial production growth slowed to 9.2
percent from a year earlier, inflation eased to 2.1 percent and
factory-gate prices fell for a 15th month. </p>
<p>Also on June 9, People''s Bank of China data showed new
local-currency lending in May was 667.4 billion yuan ($109
billion), down from 793.2 billion yuan a year earlier. The
previous day, figures from the customs administration showed
export growth slumped to a 10-month low of 1 percent and imports
unexpectedly fell after a crackdown on fake trade invoices used
to circumvent capital controls. </p>
<h2>Structural Challenges </h2>
<p>ANZ said a quarter percentage-point cut in interest rates
may be imminent while Haitong International Securities Co. sees
two or three cuts in banks'' reserve requirements, one rate cut
and approval of more infrastructure projects in the next several
months. </p>
<p>Daiwa Capital Markets, which lowered its 2013 growth
estimate to 7.8 percent from 8.1 percent and its 2014 forecast
to 7.5 percent from 7.7 percent on June 10, said the government
will not start any stimulus measures as it is satisfied with
the pace of economic growth and willing to pursue economic
reforms to solve structural challenges. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chisaki Watanabe" date="Jun 13, 2013  3:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-13/goldman-sachs-eyes-japan-offshore-wind-in-clean-energy-expansion.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Eyes Japan Offshore Wind in Clean Energy Expansion</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), the New
York-based bank planning as much as 300 billion yen ($3.19
billion) in renewable energy investments in Japan, is eyeing
offshore wind power after building up holdings in more
established clean energy sources such as solar. </p>
<p>Japan Renewable Energy Co. was set up by Goldman in August
after Japan began offering above-market rates to producers of
clean energy. The incentives, or feed-in tariffs, have spurred
investments in renewables, setting Japan on course this year to
become one of the world''s largest solar markets by annual
installations. </p>
<p>The company sees offshore wind as promising, Shigeru Yasu,
a representative director at Japan Renewable Energy, said in an
interview in Tokyo yesterday. Geothermal and biomass power also
hold potential, he said. </p>
<p>It takes three to four years to do an environmental
impact study for an onshore wind project with more than 10
megawatts of capacity, Yasu said. Projects with larger
capacity are more attractive because an environmental study
requires the same amount of time even for a 500-megawatt
offshore farm. </p>
<h2>Five-Year Investment </h2>
<p>Japan Renewable Energy plans in the next five years to
invest as much as 50 billion yen directly into clean energy
projects with capital provided by GS Infrastructure Partners. It
will take as much as 250 billion yen of loans for project
financing, Takahisa Nakagawa, also a representative director at
Japan Renewable Energy, said in the interview. The investments
and loans will amount to about 1,000 megawatts of clean energy,
he said. </p>
<p>Wind power is more challenging than solar for a developer
because it requires prior investment such as an environmental
impact study, Nakagawa said, adding that his company has the
advantage of having people with expertise in wind power. </p>
<p>Japan''s offshore wind market -- 31 megawatts in cumulative
capacity -- lags behind countries like the U.K. and Denmark with
3,093 megawatts and 923 megawatts of capacity, respectively,
according to 2012 data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Offshore wind typically requires approval from local
fishermen before projects can move ahead and costs more for
installation and maintenance than onshore wind. </p>
<p>Japan Renewable Energy is considering more than 300
megawatts worth of solar projects, Nakagawa said. The company
will use panels by LS Industrial Systems Co. (010120), a South Korean
electric and industrial equipment maker, at least for its first
four plants. </p>
<h2>Panel Supplier </h2>
<p>LSIS was picked because it offers quality products for less
compared with Japanese makers and because panels aren''t the only
product the company produces, the officials said. </p>
<p>There are big pureplay solar panel companies that went
bankrupt and that''s worrisome, Yasu said. Even though a
company offers 20 years of warranty, it''s no good if the company
won''t be around 20 years later. </p>
<p>Japan is set to overtake Germany as the world''s largest
solar market, Bloomberg New Energy Finance said last month. </p>
<p>Developers may install 6.9 gigawatts to 9.4 gigawatts of
solar in Japan in 2013, the London-based research agency said.
Germany led solar installations in 2012 with 7.6 gigawatts of
capacity. Cumulative global solar energy installations reached
102 gigawatts for the first time in 2012, according to
preliminary BNEF data. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Nadja Brandt" date="Jun 14, 2013  6:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-14/morgans-investors-back-all-7-otk-nominees-results-show.html"><headline>Morgans Investors Back All 7 OTK Nominees, Results Show</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgans Hotel Group Co. (MHGC) investors
voted to elect all seven board members proposed by OTK
Associates LLC, the company''s largest shareholder, according to
preliminary results. </p>
<p>Stockholders chose the OTK-proposed nominees at Morgans''s
annual meeting today in New York, according to Dan Gagnier, an
OTK spokesman with Sard Verbinnen  Co., citing initial results
after the meeting had ended. </p>
<p>OTK, owner of about 14 percent of New York-based Morgans''s
shares, sought to overhaul the board to try to return the
company to profitability. Morgans, which operates hotels
including the Mondrian in Los Angeles and the Delano in Miami''s
South Beach, has lost money each quarter since 2007, according
to data compiled by Bloomberg. Billionaire Ron Burkle''s Yucaipa
Cos. is a major investor in the company through holdings of
preferred stock, notes and warrants. </p>
<p>Morgans shareholders elected John Dougherty, Jason Kalisman, Mahmood Khimji, Jonathan Langer, Andrea Olshan,
Michael Olshan and Parag Vora, OTK said in a statement today.
Final results are expected to be completed shortly, the
company said. Kalisman was already a director. </p>
<p>The new board is eager to begin working constructively to
address the company''s balance sheet and expense structure, and
to run the company in a manner that is in the best interest of
all stockholders, Michael Olshan, a founding member of OTK,
said in the statement. </p>
<p>Morgans fell 1.2 percent to $7.47 at the close of New York
trading. The stock climbed to the highest in almost two years on
June 4 after the company said it received interest in a takeover
and would consider a sale if its current board were re-elected. </p>
<h2>Actual Intentions'' </h2>
<p>The stock is reacting to the uncertainty over what OTK''s
actual intentions are, Chris Agnew, a Stamford, Connecticut-based analyst at MKM Partners LLC, said in a telephone
interview. The original Morgans board was very clear on that
they wanted to expedite the strategic process, including a
possible sale. While I think OTK will end up doing the same,
nobody is sure as to how and when they may do that. </p>
<p>Lex Suvanto, a spokesman for Morgans with Abernathy
MacGregor Group, declined to comment on the vote. </p>
<p>OTK in April sued Morgans board members over a
recapitalization deal with Yucaipa. OTK called a proposed swap
for the Delano South Beach and a $100 million rights offering
insider dealings that would benefit Yucaipa while Burkle was
on the board. </p>
<p>Burkle has the right to one board seat. Yucaipa owns all of
Morgans''s preferred stock, more than half its convertible notes
and warrants for 12.5 million shares, according to the
investment company. </p>
<h2>Yucaipa Disappointed'' </h2>
<p>We are disappointed, Yucaipa said in a statement late
today. We do not believe that OTK will begin a sales process
for Morgans. </p>
<p>Yucaipa''s stake in Morgans would be best protected by
exploring strategic alternatives including a sale of the
company, the Los Angeles-based investment firm said. Morgans
has received over nine expressions of interest in the company
and to not follow up on these is clearly not in the best
interest of all stakeholders. </p>
<p>Institutional Shareholder Services Inc. and Glass Lewis 
Co. on June 5 recommended that investors vote for three of the
seven board nominees proposed by OTK. Institutional Shareholder
Services had recommended votes for Kalisman, Khimji and Langer.
Glass Lewis advised voting for Kalisman, Khimji and Dougherty. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sonja Elmquist" date="Jun 14, 2013  4:37 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-14/walter-declines-after-forbes-says-1-55-billion-loan-canceled.html"><headline>Walter Cancels Plan to Refinance $1.55 Billion of Debt</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walter Energy Corp. (WLT), a U.S. miner of
coal used in steelmaking, canceled a plan to refinance $1.55
billion of loans as yields on bonds from the riskiest to the
most creditworthy borrowers in the U.S. reached a 10-month high. </p>
<p>Walter had explored options including a new secured term
loan facility, a new revolving credit facility and unsecured
debt financing, the Birmingham, Alabama-based company said in a
statement today. </p>
<p>The company said it has no material debt principal payments
due until 2015 and doesn''t need incremental funding right now.
The shares earlier dropped as much as 20 percent to $11.76 in
New York, the biggest intraday decline since August 2011, before
being halted after Forbes reported the decision. </p>
<p>Walter joins Odebrecht SA, the Brazilian construction and
engineering firm, and U.S. candle producer Yankee Candle Co. in
terminating or delaying bond sales this week because of market
conditions. </p>
<p>Yields on bonds from the riskiest to the most creditworthy
borrowers in the U.S. reached 3.91 percent yesterday, the
highest since August, and up from a record-low 3.35 percent on
May 2, according to the Bank of America Merrill Lynch U.S.
Corporate  High Yield index. </p>
<p>Metallurgical coal prices have dropped as miners haven''t
cut output quickly enough to match falling demand. Prices no
longer cover cash production costs, even for mining companies
considered to be low-cost producers, Mitesh Thakkar, an analyst
at FBR  Co. (FBRC) In Arlington, Virginia, wrote in a note yesterday. </p>
<h2>Challenging'' Markets </h2>
<p>While met markets have been challenging for marginal
assets, we now believe that spot met prices have fallen to a
level where they no longer cover full cash costs (including
attributable corporate expenses) even for some of the low-cost
producers, Thakkar said. </p>
<p>Walter investors rejected five nominees to its board
proposed by activist shareholder Audley Capital Advisors LLP on
April 25. Audley had called on the mining company to reduce debt
and corporate expenses to boost profit. It was the second
attempt by London-based Audley''s co-founder and Managing Partner
Julian Treger to compel change at Walter, which has posted two
consecutive quarterly losses and seen its shares drop 65 percent
this year. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Jun 14, 2013 11:30 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-14/jpmorgan-private-equity-unit-to-become-independent-from-bank.html"><headline>JPMorgan Private-Equity Unit to Become Independent</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the largest
U.S. bank, plans to break off its private-equity unit as an
independent firm as the business raises a new fund backed by
outside investors. </p>
<p>One Equity Partners will still make direct investments on
behalf of JPMorgan for an interim period and continue to
manage the bank''s existing group of portfolio companies, the New
York-based company said today in a statement. </p>
<p>The business eventually will be split off as those
investments mature, according to a person with direct knowledge
of the plan. One Equity manages about $4.5 billion for the bank,
according to the statement. </p>
<p>The One Equity team has produced strong returns over the
years, Matt Zames, JPMorgan''s chief operating officer, said in
the statement. The time is right for them to seek new capital
to strengthen their global strategy, as they continue to manage
our existing portfolio to maximize value to the firm. </p>
<p>Banks are expanding businesses overseeing client money as
they seek more stable forms of revenue, such as management fees.
JPMorgan''s private-equity results have been uneven in recent
quarters, swinging from a $50 million profit in the fourth
quarter to a $182 million loss in the first three months of this
year, according to the filings. </p>
<h2>Volatile Earnings </h2>
<p>Earnings within the unit will likely be volatile and
influenced by capital-markets activity, market levels, the
performance of the broader economy and investment-specific
issues, the company said in a May 8 filing with the Securities
and Exchange Commission. </p>
<p>One Equity typically invests from $50 million to $250
million per transaction, the firm said, concentrating in North
America, Europe, Asia and South America. </p>
<p>Federally backed banks face restrictions in how much they
can invest in private-equity and hedge funds under the so-called
Volcker rule, a provision of the 2010 Dodd-Frank law. The rule
limits investments to no more than 3 percent of the fund or 3
percent of the lender''s Tier 1 capital. JPMorgan had about $7.7
billion in total private-equity holdings and $163.8 billion in
Tier 1 capital as of March 31, according to regulatory filings. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Colin McClelland and Joe Carroll" date="Jun 16, 2013 12:40 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-16/chevron-led-angola-lng-ships-first-cargo-after-18-month-delay.html"><headline>Chevron''s $10 Billion Angola LNG Ships First Gas Cargo</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX)''s $10 billion Angola
LNG plant shipped its first cargo today after an 18-month delay
prompted by fires, labor shortages and U.S. shale drilling that
erased demand for African fuel in the world''s largest gas
market. </p>
<p>The shipment of gas that was cooled to -256 degrees
Fahrenheit (-160 degrees Celsius) to shrink its volume was sold
to state-owned Sonangol EP for transport to Brazil aboard the
ship Sonangol Sambizanga, Artur Pereira, chief executive officer
of Angola LNG Marketing, said in an e-mailed statement today. A
large number of LNG sales from the plant have been signed or
are in negotiation, the London-based company said. </p>
<p>Chevron, the world''s third-largest energy company by market
value, has made LNG a linchpin of its goal to raise its
worldwide output by 20 percent through the end of 2017 to the
equivalent of 3.3 million barrels of crude a day. The company is
spending more than $77 billion on two LNG projects in Australia,
and in December acquired a 50 percent stake in the proposed
Kitimat LNG terminal on Canada''s Pacific Coast. </p>
<p>First gas at Angola LNG is an important milestone in
support of our strategic plan to grow our production, George Kirkland, vice chairman of San Ramon, California-based Chevron,
said in a statement distributed by Business Wire today. This
project will commercialize natural gas resources in western
Africa to meet growing demand in the region and
internationally. </p>
<h2>Shipments Planned </h2>
<p>Production at the liquefaction plant, with a capacity of
5.2 million metric tons a year, was postponed because of fires,
pipeline collapses and a lack of skilled workers, three people
with knowledge of the situation said last month. </p>
<p>The facility in Soyo in northern Angola plans one or two
shipments in June and July before performing checks on its
systems and resuming output in the fourth quarter, said the
people, who asked not to be identified because the information
isn''t public. </p>
<p>Global LNG demand is expected to exceed production around
the end of this decade with the deficit growing to 100 million
metric tons a year by 2025, Chevron Chairman and Chief Executive
Officer John Watson said in a presentation to analysts in New
York on March 12. Demand for the fuel will increase at an
estimated average rate of 15 million tons a year through 2025,
led by growth in Asian nations such as Japan, South Korea and
Taiwan, Watson said. </p>
<h2>Reduced Flaring </h2>
<p>Angola LNG is entering the market at an exciting time,
Pereira said. The world LNG market is expected to remain tight
over the coming years, with very limited new LNG capacity. </p>
<p>Chevron is Angola LNG''s largest shareholder with a 36.4 
percent stake. BP Plc (BP/), Eni SpA (ENI) and Total SA (FP) each hold 13.6
percent, while Sonangol has 22.8 percent. </p>
<p>Angola LNG''s vision is to be a reliable and competitive
supplier, a strong community partner, and a role model for the
economic development of Angola, Sonangol Chairman Antonio
rfao said in the same e-mail. The project provides a solution
to minimize flaring and environmental pollution by gathering
associated gas from Angola''s offshore oil fields. </p>
<p>Angola produced 1.87 million barrels of oil a day in May,
equal to Nigeria, according to data compiled by Bloomberg.
Chevron and its partners built Angola LNG in part to market gas
that otherwise would have been burned off because of the lack of
a local demand for the fuel. </p>
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) is the world''s largest energy company by
market value, followed by PetroChina Co. (857), according to data
compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Cliff Edwards" date="Jun 17, 2013  6:30 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-17/microsoft-s-xbox-tops-u-s-retail-console-sales-in-may.html"><headline>Microsoft''s Xbox Tops U.S. Retail Console Sales in May</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) said U.S. retailers
sold 114,000 Xbox 360 game consoles in May, helping it retain
the top-selling spot for the 29th straight month. </p>
<p>Spending in May on all Xbox products, including the
console, Kinect motion-sensing peripheral and software totaled
$149.8 million, Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft said today
in an e-mail, citing NPD Group Inc. data. </p>
<p>Sales of the console fell 29 percent compared with a year
earlier, when it sold 160,000 units. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarika Gangar" date="Jun 17, 2013  6:07 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-17/chevron-said-to-plan-four-part-bonds-in-first-sale-this-year-1-.html"><headline>Chevron Issues $6 Billion of Bonds in First Offering This Year</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX), the second-largest
U.S. oil company, issued $6 billion of bonds in four parts for
its first sale of 2013. </p>
<p>The company''s $750 million of 0.889 percent, three-year
notes yield 40 basis points more than similar-maturity
Treasuries; $2 billion of 1.718 percent, five-year securities
pay a relative yield of 65 basis points; $1 billion of 2.427
percent, seven-year debt pay an 85 basis-point spread; and $2.25
billion of 3.191 percent, 10-year bonds yield 100 more,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>The company canceled plans to offer floating-rate notes due
in 2016 and 2018, according to a person familiar with the
transaction, who asked not to be identified citing lack of
authorization to speak publicly. </p>
<p>Proceeds from the bonds, expected to be rated Aa1 by
Moody''s Investors Service, will be used to refinance commercial
paper, the person said. </p>
<p>Chevron is finding it increasingly difficult to expand
production and add reserves as many of the remaining pools of
cheap, easily accessible resources are owned by governments
and national oil companies, David Schivell, an analyst at
Chicago-based research firm Morningstar Inc., wrote in a note
today. Still, the company maintains a rock solid balance
sheet, he said. </p>
<h2>November Deal </h2>
<p>Morningstar estimated a fair-value spread of 45 basis
points on the new three-year bonds, 55 basis points on the five-year, 70 for the seven-year and 90 on the 10-year, according to
the report. </p>
<p>Chevron last sold debt in November, issuing $2 billion each
of 1.104 percent, five-year debentures at a spread of 47 basis
points and 2.355 percent, 10-year securities at 72 basis points,
Bloomberg data show. The bonds due December 2022 traded at 95
cents on the dollar to yield 2.96 percent on June 11, or a
relative yield of 75 basis points, according to Trace, the bond-price reporting system of the Financial Industry Regulatory
Authority. </p>
<p>The average new issue concession on investment-grade bonds
in the U.S. reached 11 basis points last week, the highest since
the five days ended June 28, 2012, according to data from
Barclays Plc. </p>
<p>Barclays, JPMorgan Chase  Co., Morgan Stanley and Wells
Fargo  Co. managed the offering for San Ramon, California-based
Chevron, Bloomberg data show. </p>
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. is the largest U.S. oil company. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Catarina Saraiva" date="Jun 17, 2013 10:08 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-17/goldman-sachs-cuts-brazil-2013-2014-gdp-forecasts-table-.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Cuts Brazil 2013, 2014 GDP Forecasts</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The following table shows Goldman Sach''s
Latin America economic forecasts as of June 14, compared to their forecasts
as of May 17.        </p>

==============================================================================
                        -Forecast-    --Change--     -Forecast-    --Change--
                       2013   2014    2013   2014    2013   2014   2013   2014
==============================================================================
                        ---Annual Average GDP---     ---Annual Average CPI---
Argentina              3.4%   2.7%   -0.1%     --   10.9%  13.0%  -0.2%     --
Brazil                 2.5%   3.1%   -0.8%  -1.3%    5.8%   5.5%   0.1%   0.1%
Chile                  4.6%   4.6%   -0.3%  -0.2%    2.5%   2.9%  -0.3%     --
Colombia               4.2%   4.8%      --     --    3.0%   3.0%     --     --
Mexico                 3.1%   3.8%      --     --    3.5%   3.2%     --     --
Peru                   5.9%   6.3%   -0.2%     --    2.5%   2.5%     --     --
Venezuela              1.6%   2.5%   -0.6%   0.1%   37.6%  22.0%   9.0%     --
==============================================================================
SOURCE: Goldman Sachs Latin America Economic Analyst''

]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ruth David" date="Jun 18, 2013 10:42 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-18/jpmorgan-names-de-hillery-to-head-u-k-investment-bank.html"><headline>JPMorgan Names De, Hillery to Head U.K. Investment Bank</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) named Ina De
and Conor Hillery co-heads of its U.K. investment banking
business, according to a memo obtained by Bloomberg News. </p>
<p>De, currently co-head of equity capital markets for Europe,
the Middle East and Africa, and Hillery, head of the U.K.
financial institutions group, will report to Chairman Tim Wise,
the memo shows. Its contents were confirmed by a spokeswoman. </p>
<p>U.S. banks including JPMorgan and Goldman Sachs Group Inc.
have been increasing their share of European investment-banking
fees, the New York-based research firm Freeman  Co. reported
today. </p>
<p>JPMorgan''s broking clients include the U.K.''s largest
fixed-line telecommunications company, BT Group Plc (BT/A), as well as
car-repair business Halfords Group Plc. (HFD) </p>
<p>Laurence Hollingworth, previously head of investment
banking in the U.K., will take over from Jake Donavan as the
head of industry coverage in the EMEA region. Donavan will
become senior country officer of Benelux and the Nordics, the
bank said in the memo. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Frier" date="Jun 18, 2013 10:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-18/ibm-to-sell-cloud-software-directly-to-top-executives.html"><headline>IBM to Sell Cloud Software Directly to Top Executives</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM), the largest computer-services provider, said it will sell
software over the Internet direct to corporate executives, going
beyond the traditional model of doing business with chief
information officers. </p>
<p>IBM will market more than 100 cloud applications to heads
of marketing, supply chain, human resources and others, changing
the way it sells software as competition from Silicon Valley
startups mounts. </p>
<p>It''s the company''s second big move into cloud delivery this
month, following the purchase of SoftLayer Technologies Inc., a
cloud-computing storage provider that will help it compete with
Amazon.com Inc. Many of IBM''s customers are just starting to
become interested in software delivered via the Internet, known
as software-as-a-service or SaaS, said Marc Dietz, the director
of SmartCloud solutions for IBM. </p>
<p>We''re serving a growing demand with a new way that we''re
going to market, Dietz said. It''s really an expansion and a
comprehensive cloud strategy for our clients. </p>
<p>With SaaS, customers buy software as they use it and can
access it through the Internet, as opposed to signing multiyear
contracts for installation and support. </p>
<p>IBM, based in Armonk, New York, is also adding new software
to the portfolio, including a social-media analytics product
that will allow businesses to monitor customer sentiment on
Facebook and Twitter. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kristen Schweizer" date="Jun 20, 2013  6:01 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-20/ibm-atom-boy-joins-police-sketch-artist-to-give-ads-novel-twist.html"><headline>IBM Atom Boy Joins Police Sketch Artist to Give Ads Novel Twist</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A police sketch artist and the
world''s smallest film are helping to sell soap and technology
for Dove and IBM as advertisers unleash a wave of more subtle,
intelligent and entertaining campaigns to lure a jaded public. </p>
<p>Unilever NV (UNA)''s six-minute Dove Sketches film, in which a
former San Jose Police Department sketch artist helps women
realize You are more beautiful than you think, became the
most viewed online ad of all time in May with more than 114
million views. International Business Machines Corp. (IBM)''s
researchers manipulated individual atoms to depict a youngster
playing with a ball. The result is A Boy and His Atom, which
holds the record as the world''s smallest stop-motion movie. </p>
<p>These spots from WPP Plc (WPP)''s Ogilvy  Mather agency weren''t
part of a traditional TV and newspaper campaign, yet racked up
millions of views online at YouTube. As the divide between
content and marketing narrows, a new category called native
advertising is advancing. In addition to expensive films and
mini-documentaries, it includes sponsored newsfeeds on Facebook
and LinkedIn (LNKD), and branded content for magazines and newspapers. </p>
<p>The ad industry is getting smarter about putting the
right ads in front of the right people, said Jonathan Nelson,
chief executive officer for digital at Omnicom Group Inc. (OMC), the
second-largest advertising company. We''re not trying to dupe
the customer into not knowing it''s an ad, but in a world with so
much fragmentation it''s hard to get attention. </p>




Photographer: Dario Pignatelli/Bloomberg

<p>
WPP Chief Executive Officer Martin Sorrell said in an interview, I''ve always been of the view that the dividing line between editorial and advertising would blur, and that was fine as long as you made it quite clear to the consumer. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jun 20, 2013  5:51 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-20/morgan-stanley-said-to-cut-commodities-jobs-as-revenue-declines.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Said to Cut 10% of Commodities Jobs Amid Rut</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley is cutting jobs in
its commodities business, one of the Wall Street''s three
biggest, after Chief Executive Officer James Gorman said revenue
the past two quarters was among the unit''s worst in 18 years. </p>
<p>The bank is shutting businesses including agricultural
products and dry freight, according to an internal memo today
from Colin Bryce and Simon Greenshields, co-heads of the unit.
Morgan Stanley will cut about 30 to 35 jobs in commodities, or
10 percent of its workforce, according to a person briefed on
the matter who asked not to be identified because the
information isn''t public. </p>
<p>Gorman said last week that he''s carefully re-evaluating''''
the proper structure for the commodities unit after holding
talks with Qatar''s sovereign-wealth fund last year about selling
a stake in the business. The past two quarters have been among
the worst for commodities since 1995, he said. The company
doesn''t disclose the unit''s revenue in financial reports. </p>
<p>The overall performance of the business can and will be
improved, Gorman, 54, said on June 12. We continue to
explore strategic structures that may make sense for us. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) is also closing its Australian power
business and exiting some Eastern European markets for power and
gas, according to the memo, a copy of which was obtained by
Bloomberg News. Mark Lake, a spokesman for the New York-based
bank, confirmed the memo''s contents and declined to comment
further. The job cuts were reported earlier today by the
Financial Times. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
Morgan Stanley Chief Executive Officer James Gorman. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Jun 20, 2013  4:30 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-20/microsoft-says-looked-at-connecting-search-shopping.html"><headline>Microsoft Says Looked at Connecting Search, Shopping</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) recently canceled an
early stage project looking at ways to combine its Bing Web
search with shopping, the company said without explaining why
the effort was abandoned. </p>
<p>The project was a small scale incubation effort to enable
a more direct commerce model between customers and brands and
merchants, the largest software maker said in a statement.
The project was recently canceled, but we remain committed to
finding new and differentiated ways to enable a richer, more
task-oriented approach to e-commerce and online advertising. </p>
<p>Microsoft''s Bing search engine, which lags market-dominating rival Google Inc. (GOOG), has experimented for several years
with shopping programs, including an effort that ended in 2010
which gave customers cash back on purchases. Besides increasing
search traffic, Microsoft has looked at options for bolstering
an ailing display advertising business. </p>
<p>The project, called Brazil, and its cancellation were
reported earlier by the Wall Street Journal, which described it
as effort to compete with online retailer Amazon.com Inc. (AMZN) and
Web marketplace EBay Inc. (EBAY) </p>
<p>Microsoft, based in Redmond, Washington, said in its
statement that it''s inaccurate to characterize Project Brazil
as conceived to compete with Amazon or EBay. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andy Fixmer" date="Jun 20, 2013  4:29 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-20/disney-drops-most-since-2012-after-goldman-downgrade-l-a-mover.html"><headline>Disney Drops Most Since 2012 After Goldman Downgrade: L.A. Mover</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS), the world''s biggest
entertainment company, dropped the most since November 2012
after Goldman Sachs  Co. downgraded the stock. </p>
<p>Disney slid 3.7 percent to $61.98 at the New York close.
The stock fell the most among the 30 companies in the Dow Jones
Industrial Average (INDU), which declined 2.3 percent after the Federal
Reserve said it may cut back its bond purchases. The shares
have gained 24 percent this year. </p>
<p>Disney''s ESPN faces rising costs for sports broadcast
rights and new competition from News Corp. (NWSA)''s Fox Sports 1, which
begins airing in August, Drew Borst, an analyst at Goldman
Sachs (GS), wrote in a report published today. He lowered Disney''s
rating to neutral and removed the Burbank, California-based
company from the firm''s conviction buy list. Borst didn''t
change his 12-month price target of $70. </p>
<p>ESPN, which provides about 45 percent of Disney''s operating
income, will be less profitable next year due to the higher cost
of airing NFL football, Major League Baseball and college
sports, Borst wrote. Fox Sports 1 will drive up prices by
competing for  TV rights. ESPN''s NBA basketball contract expires
after the 2015-2016 season and its Nascar rights expire next
year, he wrote. </p>
<p>Disney''s cable channels, including ESPN and ABC Family,
produced $5.7 billion in operating income on revenue of $13.6
billion in the fiscal year that ended Sept. 29. In that same
period, Disney reported total operating profit of $9.96 billion
on $42.3 billion in revenue. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Mathew Carr" date="Jun 20, 2013  2:27 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-20/morgan-stanley-said-to-exit-energy-in-three-east-europe-nations.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Said to Exit Energy in Three East Europe Nations</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) will exit power and
natural gas trading in Bulgaria, the Czech Republic and Poland
as it scales back in commodities, a person with direct knowledge
of the matter said. </p>
<p>The bank, based in New York, will leave markets in eastern
Europe where it doesn''t have a competitive advantage, said the
person, who asked not to be identified because the plans are not
public. It will continue to trade western European power and
carbon permits, according to the person. Charles Rankin, the
bank''s London-based head of European commodities, declined to
comment on job cuts today when reached by phone. </p>
<p>We will reduce our footprint in EU power and gas by
exiting some Eastern European markets, the bank said today in
a memo to employees from Colin Bryce and Simon Greenshields, co-heads of the unit, obtained by Bloomberg News. The commodities
revenue pool available to firms in our sector has fallen by
almost 50 percent from the peak years of 2007 to 2009. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley is cutting jobs in its commodities business,
one of the three biggest on Wall Street, after Chief Executive
Officer James Gorman said last week the unit''s revenue in the
past two quarters was among its worst in 18 years. The latest
round of commodity redundancies will eliminate 30 to 35 jobs, or
about 10 percent of its workforce, the person said. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
Morgan Stanley Chief Executive Officer James Gorman. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lynn Doan" date="Jun 20, 2013 12:52 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-20/exxon-torrance-said-to-shut-crude-unit-up-to-2-weeks-for-repairs.html"><headline>Exxon Torrance Said to Shut Crude Unit Up to 2 Weeks for Repairs</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM)  is shutting the
crude distillation unit at the Torrance, California, refinery
for a week or two of repairs related to a metallurgical issue, a
person familiar with the operations said. </p>
<p>The rest of the units at the 150,000-barrel-a-day plant
near Los Angeles will operate at about half of normal rates
while the crude unit is out of commission, said the person, who
asked not to be identified because the information isn''t public. </p>
<p>Gesuina Paras, an Exxon spokeswoman at the refinery, didn''t
immediately respond to an e-mail requesting comment. </p>
<p>The crude unit returned to full rates earlier this month
after parts were shut for a planned turnaround that also
included work on a coker and alkylation unit, two people
familiar with the schedule said at the time. </p>
<p>The Torrance refinery, which processes mostly heavy crude
from California''s San Joaquin Valley, makes almost 10 percent of
the state''s gasoline and provides jet fuel to Los Angeles
International Airport by pipeline, Exxon''s website shows. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Brendan Case" date="Jun 20, 2013 10:33 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-20/goldman-to-buy-rco-tollway-stake-as-ica-seeks-cash.html"><headline>Goldman to Buy RCO Tollway Stake as ICA Seeks Cash</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Empresas ICA SAB (ICA*), Mexico''s largest
construction company, will sell its minority stake in a Mexican
tollway operator to partner Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) and use the
proceeds to pay short-term debt. </p>
<p>The Mexico City-based builder said it expected to receive
5.07 billion pesos ($380 million) from the sale of its 18.7
percent stake in Red de Carreteras de Occidente, which is
majority-owned by Goldman Sachs. The deal needs approval by
Mexico''s antitrust regulator and the Ministry of Communications
and Transportation, ICA said in an e-mailed statement today. </p>
<p>ICA shares have tumbled more than 30 percent since May 16,
the day before Moody''s Investors Service downgraded the
company''s credit rating citing its high leverage and delays in
public-works spending by President Enrique Pena Nieto. The
company''s sales dropped 27 percent in the first quarter while
debt climbed 14 percent to 54.2 billion pesos from its Dec. 31
level. </p>
<p>We are significantly strengthening our financial
position, ICA Chief Executive Officer Alonso Quintana said in
the statement. The sale of ICA''s investment in RCO is a clear
example of our strategy of selective recycling of capital in our
asset portfolio and creating value for ICA''s shareholders. </p>
<p>ICA fell 2.8 percent to 21.28 pesos at 9:18 a.m. in Mexico
City as Mexico''s benchmark IPC index dropped 2.5 percent. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Jun 20, 2013  8:34 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-20/jpmorgan-boston-race-emotional-return-for-bombing-victims.html"><headline>JPMorgan Boston Race Emotional Return for Bombing Victims</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The last time Roseann Sdoia attended
a road race, terror shattered the course and left her with a leg
amputated above the knee. Tonight, she''ll be back to sound the
starting horn as racing returns to downtown Boston. </p>
<p>I have mixed emotions because I should be there running,
but I''m not, said Sdoia, 45, who has undergone three surgeries
since the April 15 Boston Marathon bombing that killed three and
injured more than 260 people. </p>
<p>Tonight''s 3.5-mile J.P. Morgan Corporate Challenge race,
which starts at 7:20 p.m., is one of the first organized
competitions in downtown Boston since the terrorist attack. It
begins at the Boston Common and runs parallel to the last mile
or so of the marathon course. For many participants, the event
is an emotional return to a neighborhood devastated by the twin
bomb blasts. </p>
<p>The race itself symbolizes a lot of the running community
and the Boston community coming together and really slowly
taking back the city and taking back running, said Cara
Bednar, 28, who finished the marathon in under four hours, about
10 to 15 minutes before the first blast. </p>
<p>About 12,000 people from 569 companies are registered for
tonight''s race, said Erich Timmerman, a spokesman for New York-based JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), which is organizing the event.
JPMorgan, the largest U.S. bank, is donating all registration
fees, about $500,000, to One Fund Boston, which was created to
assist victims of the bombings and their families, he said. </p>




Photographer: Pat Greenhouse/The Boston Globe via Getty Images

<p>
Boston Marathon bombing victim Roseann Sdoia received her prosthetic leg this week and said she wants to eventually get a running blade so she can resume her workouts. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ye Xie" date="Jun 21, 2013 12:07 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-21/goldman-says-real-lira-rand-must-weaken-to-close-trade-deficit.html"><headline>Goldman Says Real, Lira, Rand Must Weaken to Close Trade Deficit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Brazil''s real, Chile''s peso and
Turkey''s lira may fall significantly to curtail widening
current account deficits, according to Goldman Sachs Group Inc. </p>
<p>The lira, South African rand and India''s rupee would need
to depreciate about 30 percent on a trade-weighted basis, while
the real and peso need to fall about 20 percent, London-based
analyst Themistoklis Fiotakis wrote in a note today. While the
assessments aren''t forecasts, they signal where the currencies
might ultimately belong, the analyst said. </p>
<p>The currencies are among the worst performers in emerging
markets over the past month, with the real falling 10 percent
since May 21, as the Federal Reserve signaled plans to taper off
monetary stimulus. Rising bond yields in U.S., Germany and Japan
are attracting funds away from emerging markets, making it more
difficult for the countries to finance the deficits in their
current accounts, the broadest measure of international trade
and service. </p>
<p>A larger exchange rate depreciation might be necessary,
which will bring external accounts back into full balance,
Fiotakis wrote. Although some of the recent shifts may prove
to be overshoots in the short term, the EM bond and FX selloff
of the last month is likely to constitute only a small part of a
longer trend for EM assets. </p>
<p>Brazil''s current account deficit widened to a record $73
billion in the year through May, equivalent to 3.2 percent of
gross domestic product, according to a central bank report
today. Chile''s deficit reached 4 percent of the GDP in the first
quarter, the widest since 1998, while Turkey''s amounted to 5.9
percent at the end of March, Bloomberg data show. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jun 21, 2013 11:10 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-21/morgan-stanley-receives-fed-approval-for-smith-barney-purchase.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Receives Approval to Purchase Smith Barney</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley will buy the rest of
its wealth-management joint venture with Citigroup Inc. (C) as soon
as next week, capping a four-year effort to reshape the
investment bank into a more stable firm reliant on the retail-brokerage business. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley will pay $4.7 billion in cash for the 35
percent of the business it doesn''t already own after receiving
regulatory approval, the New York-based company said today in a
statement, adding that it will take a $200 million charge in the
second quarter related to the purchase. The brokerage will also
redeem $2.03 billion of preferred interests owned by Citigroup,
according to the statement. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer James Gorman, 54, set a price in
September with Citigroup to purchase the rest of the brokerage
venture, which was created in 2009. Morgan Stanley said in
January that the purchase will place demands on an additional
$400 million of capital. </p>
<p>This is a historic day for Morgan Stanley, Gorman said
in the statement. It is the culmination of a multiyear effort
to transform our business model into one that offers stronger
shareholder returns and greater stability in volatile markets. </p>
<p>The Federal Reserve was reviewing the transaction after
determining during its annual stress test in March that Morgan
Stanley had sufficient capital to move forward. The bank didn''t
ask to return additional capital to shareholders through
buybacks and dividends this year because of a desire to purchase
Citigroup''s stake and own the entire business. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
Morgan Stanley Chief Executive Officer James Gorman, 54, set a price in September with Citigroup to purchase the rest of the brokerage venture, which was created in 2009. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Heather Perlberg and John Gittelsohn" date="Jun 24, 2013  2:38 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-24/morgan-stanley-analyst-swaps-research-for-home-rebabs.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Analyst Swaps Research for Home Rehabs</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Oliver Chang quit his job as head of housing strategy at Morgan Stanley last year to follow his own advice and invest in distressed homes to rent. He''s since become one of the largest landlords in Atlanta. </p> <p>Chang, 37, has more than $500 million for his company Sylvan Road Capital LLC to acquire and rehabilitate homes and expand into other cities across the U.S., according to a letter sent this weekend to investors obtained by Bloomberg. </p> <p>The former analyst has gained investors including Carlyle Group LP after writing a six-page report in July 2011 detailing how the worst real estate crash since the Great Depression was moving America toward a rentership society. While he foresaw that leasing single-family homes could become a large-scale business similar to apartments, he didn''t predict how fast private equity firms backed by cheap borrowing from Wall Street would flood regions hardest hit by the foreclosure crisis to help fuel the fastest home-price gains in seven years. </p> <p>I''ve certainly been surprised by the pace of acquisitions, Chang said in a telephone interview from Atlanta. There has been a rush of capital into the space. </p> <p>Blackstone Group LP (BX) has spent $5 billion on almost 30,000 properties across 13 metropolitan areas since last April to become the largest rental buyer in the U.S. It''s obtained $3.6 billion in loans from banks including Deutsche Bank AG. (DBK) </p> <h2>Largest Landlords </h2> <p>Other large-scale landlords include Public Storage founder Wayne Hughes, who''s bought more than 14,000 properties though his American Homes 4 Rent, using $600 million from the Alaska Permanent Fund Corp. and a $500 million credit facility with Wells Fargo  Co. (WFC) They''re joined by hedge funds and former bankers, including Donald R. Mullen Jr., an ex-Goldman Sachs Group Inc. executive, whose Progress Residential LP, formerly known as Fundamental REO LLC, plans to spend as much as $2 billion by 2016. </p> <p>Institutional investors are trying to turn what has traditionally been a mom and pop business into a new asset class after more than 5 million Americans lost their homes to repossession since the real estate crash of 2008. While they''ve dominated some foreclosure auctions and complete the biggest bulk purchases, the pool of institutional ownership is still less than 1 percent of the $2.8 trillion rental market, according to Goldman Sachs estimates. </p> <p>Chang recognized the opportunity while touring neighborhoods in Phoenix (SPCSPHXS) in 2011, where prices were down 50 percent from the peak in 2006, compared to the national average of a 35 percent fall. Broad housing market data wasn''t telling the story of what was happening on the ground, he said. </p> <h2>Something New'' </h2> <p>That''s when the light went off, Chang said. I thought this was the beginning of something new, and that if I was right, I would prefer to be a part of it rather than just write about it. </p> <p>He resigned from Morgan Stanley last May and made his foray into property ownership by co-founding Sylvan Road, named after a street in Atlanta, with Robert Lee, Sarah Lee and Gavin Kleinknecht, principals of Delmar Realty Advisors, a homebuilder that already owned an assortment of rentals in Atlanta. </p> <p>Chang was a central node in this business early on because he sought out the local real estate operators that were the first people executing the strategy, said Carl Bell, a mortgage bond manager at Smith Breeden Associates. Obviously he knew the data and through networking with local operators and flippers he built a large web for sourcing ground level information that combined with the data put him in a unique position when he jumped to the buy side of this industry. </p> <h2>Attracting Investors </h2> <p>Sylvan Road hasn''t been on a buying spree like many of its competitors, said Chang, who declined to disclose exactly how many homes the firm owns or their cost. The firm has instead focused on building operations and software platforms, putting major renovations into the several hundred homes it has purchased. </p> <p>His firm avoids foreclosure auctions -- where buyers can''t inspect inside the houses before the sale -- and doesn''t compete for the same properties as the majority of investors, who target three-bedroom homes built since 1990 that need few repairs. </p> <p>Chang has attracted investors such as Ron Mass, who considered giving money to at least 10 other rental businesses before investing in Sylvan Road. </p> <p>Some of the companies I was looking at wanted to just buy as quickly as possible, said Mass, who oversaw as much as $90 billion of fixed-income investments at Western Asset Management Co. which he left last year. I liked the fact that Sylvan Road was going at a slower pace and building out while some folks in the market were five or more times their size, had less developed infrastructure and were taking months longer to lease out their properties. </p> <h2>Declining Yields </h2> <p>Even as demand for rentals rises amid a falling homeownership rate, yields are declining and companies formed to buy the homes that have gone public have yet to show a profit because they acquired houses faster than they can fill them. </p> <p>Colony American Homes Inc., a division of Thomas Barrack Jr.''s Colony Capital LLC with 13,000 homes, has found tenants for only about half of its properties, according to a regulatory filing last month. </p> <p>Jonathan Gray, Blackstone''s global head of real estate, said last month during a conference call with investors that while about 85 percent of the firm''s renovated homes were leased they have an awful lot of homes to continue renovating. </p> <p>Purchases by investors, including individuals, declined to 20 percent of sales in May, from 22 percent in April, as home prices rose and competition increased, according to the Campbell/Inside Mortgage Finance HousingPulse Tracking survey released today. </p> <h2>Rising Prices </h2> <p>Sylvan Road spends on average $30,000 to $40,000 to repair homes. American Homes 4 Rent spent about 5 percent or $8,762 per house on renovation and acquisition fees, while American Residential Properties Inc. (ARPI), a Scottsdale, Arizona-based single-family real estate investment trust, invested an average $4,222 per house on capital improvements, regulatory filings show. </p> <p>Because we are trying to add value through renovations, a lot of the times we are buying houses that nobody else will buy, Chang said. When we put an offer on it we''re the only ones, and it''s a house that is typically in the condition that nobody wants to live in it either. In some cases it''s falling apart and basically uninhabitable. We''ll take that and fix it up and if we do this for several houses within a neighborhood, it''s helping improve that community. </p> <p>Even though Chang''s expertise is in analyzing data, starting as a summer associate with Morgan Stanley while he was still at Columbia Business School in 2004, his first experience into being a landlord came as a youth in Toronto. His parents owned a few investment homes that they rented out and often recruited him to help tidy up between tenants. </p> <h2>Giant Weed </h2> <p>One resident didn''t take care of the lawn, Chang said. I was around 10 years old, and I remember there was a weed that was as big as I was tall, and it took me about two hours to get it out of the ground. And what stuck with me, even when I first started writing about this at Morgan Stanley, is just how difficult it is to manage these properties. </p> <p>Sylvan Road houses come with an electric lawnmower, because many renters want their children to cut the grass as a chore, Chang said. </p> <p>Landlord profits depend on finding efficient ways to change locks, turn on utilities and reduce tenant turnover, according to Aaron Edelheit, a former hedge fund manager whose American Home Inc., owns 2,500 rental houses in the U.S. Southeast. </p> <p>The difference between earning 8 percent and 2 percent is all in the details, Edelheit said in a telephone interview. It''s death by 1 million paper cuts. </p> <h2>Big Test </h2> <p>The big test for rental companies is showing they can manage scattered-site properties that have their own lawns and roofs, unlike multifamily apartment buildings, many of which have been under institutional management for years. </p> <p>The multifamily industry has had several decades of a head start to refine processes and this industry has not even had two years, Chang said. So some of the challenges still lay ahead. </p> <p>Companies building rental businesses are facing the biggest increase in home prices since 2006. The SP/Case-Shiller index of home values for 20 cities probably rose 10.6 percent for the year ended April after a 10.9 percent increase in March that was the biggest year-over-year advance since 2006, according to the median forecast in a Bloomberg survey of economists before a June 25 report. </p> <p>Investor buying is pushing up prices that are also recovering as the economy improves and the Fed for now keeps mortgage rates near record lows. </p> <h2>Later Stages </h2> <p>It''s unclear how long the buy-to-rent acquisition boom will last, as rising home prices make it a less-profitable pursuit. Blackstone''s Gray said June 10 in an interview with Bloomberg television, for our type of capital and the returns we hope to generate, my guess is we''re in the later stages of this. </p> <p>For Chang, it''s less important for Sylvan Road to grow big than to prove his analysis of the housing economy is the basis to create a sustainable company. </p> <p>Chang is one of the best known people in this industry and certainly has a reputation as one of the best analysts, Bell said. Whether or not he is one of the best at executing this strategy remains to be seen. It''s still early for everyone. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Rubin" date="Jun 24, 2013 12:01 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-24/microsoft-joins-merck-in-pitch-for-tech-friendly-tax-code.html"><headline>Microsoft Joins Merck in Pitch for Tech-Friendly Tax Code</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), Merck  Co. (MRK) Inc.,
Amgen Inc. and other technology-focused companies are joining
forces to seek U.S. tax code changes that wouldn''t put at a
disadvantage income earned from patents and intangible assets. </p>
<p>The companies are part of the newly formed Tax Innovation
Equality Coalition, whose other members include Xilinx Inc. (XLNX),
Adobe Systems Inc. (ADBE) and Netflix Inc. (NFLX) </p>
<p>The Washington-based group, which announced its formation
today, is responding to proposals -- including one from House
Ways and Means Chairman Dave Camp -- that would apply different
tax rules to income earned from intangible assets. Changes to
those laws could raise these companies'' taxes to pay for lighter
burdens on the foreign income of all U.S.-based multinational
corporations. </p>
<p>It only makes sense that any tax reform proposal would
try to cut the benefits of the members of this coalition,
because they have the lowest effective tax rates, said Martin
Sullivan, chief economist at Tax Analysts in Falls Church,
Virginia. This coalition is playing defense. </p>
<p>Camp, a Michigan Republican, this month endorsed a carrot-and-stick approach that would apply a 15 percent immediate tax
to such income regardless of where it''s earned. That would give
the companies a tax increase abroad and a tax cut at home. </p>
<h2>25% Rate </h2>
<p>Other corporate income would be subject to a 25 percent
rate on domestic profits and almost no U.S. tax on foreign
income. </p>
<p>Companies would feel less pressure to shift income to
low-tax jurisdictions because that income would be taxed at the
same rate -- whether it is earned in the United States or
Bermuda, Camp said at a June 13 hearing. </p>
<p>Under the current U.S. tax system, companies can move
intangible assets derived from intellectual property across
borders and can structure their businesses in ways that minimize
foreign taxes. They can then avoid U.S. taxes by keeping the
money overseas. </p>
<p>The TIE Coalition is the latest in a series of groups that
have formed as Congress considers a rewrite of the U.S. tax
code. Other groups are focusing on the corporate tax rate and
changing international tax rules. </p>
<p>The coalition isn''t advocating or opposing a particular
plan, said Mark Nebergall, president of the Washington-based
Software Finance  Tax Executives Council. </p>
<p>All these proposals, with a few exceptions, seem to pick
on intangible property, he said. Proposals that do not
discriminate against intangibles are the ones that deserve the
most scrutiny. </p>
<h2>Tax Credits </h2>
<p>Congress should be careful not to impose tax changes that
could cost jobs in industries reliant on intellectual property,
said Matthew Slaughter, a Dartmouth College professor who
conducted a study for the coalition. </p>
<p>In many ways, tax policy being one, there are literally
dozens of other countries in the world that are moving
aggressively to try to build their capacity in these
industries, he said in a phone interview today. </p>
<p>The current U.S. system already gives these companies
breaks, Sullivan said. They are eligible for the research tax
credit and can take advantage of the mobility of intangible
assets, which can be transferred more easily than factories. </p>
<p>It''s hard to value and it''s hard to locate, Sullivan
said, and so that makes it easy to put a lot of profit into a
tax haven. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Drew Armstrong and Samuel Adams" date="Jun 24, 2013 11:15 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-24/pfizer-s-animal-health-stock-exchange-offer-has-too-many-takers.html"><headline>Pfizer''s Animal Health Stock Exchange Offer Has Too Many Takers</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Investors in Pfizer Inc. (PFE), the
world''s biggest drugmaker, oversubscribed to a program to
exchange some or all of their shares for those of its former
animal-health unit, Zoetis Inc. (ZTS) </p>
<p>Pfizer will retire about 405 million shares, or about $11.4
billion worth, at today''s price, as investors tried to exchange
more Pfizer shares than there was Zoetis stock. Shareholders
will get 24 percent of the 1.68 billion shares tendered. </p>
<p>The share exchange completes the New York-based company''s
restructuring plan, in which it dropped two non-drug units, the
animal health business and an infant nutrition line. Zoetis
began trading as a separate company on February 1, surging 19
percent in its debut after raising $2.24 billion in an initial
public offering. As a result of the spinoff completion, the
company expects adjusted earnings of $2.10 to $2.20 a share,
from a previous projected range of $2.14 to $2.24, according to
its statement today. </p>
<p>Pfizer offered investors the Zoetis stock at a 5.4 percent
discount. For every $100 of Pfizer stock traded in, they''ll get
$105 of Zoetis shares in return, which Pfizer gave as an
incentive to participate in the exchange. </p>
<p>Zoetis is based in Florham Park, New Jersey, and makes and
sells drugs and treatments for animals. Livestock products make
up 65 percent of its sales, while medicines for pets account for
the rest. Much of the company''s growth depends on rising wealth
levels around the world, as people eat more meat and care for
companion animals. </p>
<h2>Board Appointment </h2>
<p>The company today also said it appointed Michael McCallister, a former chief executive officer at the Louisville,
Kentucky-based health insurer Humana Inc. as Zoetis''s non-executive chairman. He replaces Chief Financial Officer Frank D''Amelio, who will remain on the Zoetis board. </p>
<p>Zoetis shares fell 1.8 percent to $30.05 at 10:25 a.m. in
New York. Pfizer declined by less than 1 percent to $28.20 </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Ian Read is now deciding whether to
split the company in two to separate its generic drug''s
business. The split could happen in the next three years. </p>
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co., Bank of America Corp., Goldman Sachs
Group Inc. and Morgan Stanley managed the deal. Skadden, Arps,
Slate, Meagher  Flom LLP acted as legal adviser. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Greg Stohr" date="Jun 24, 2013  9:33 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-24/pfizer-loses-top-court-bid-for-shield-from-asbestos-suits.html"><headline>Pfizer Loses Top Court Bid for Shield From Asbestos Suits</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The U.S. Supreme Court refused to
shield Pfizer Inc. (PFE) from some asbestos lawsuits connected to its
Quigley Co. subsidiary, a bankrupt unit that stopped most
operations in 1992. </p>
<p>The justices today rejected Pfizer''s appeal of a ruling
that opened the New York-based drugmaker to some claims related
to Quigley, which made asbestos-containing products for the
steel industry from the 1940s to the 1970s. Pfizer acquired
Quigley in 1968. Asbestos, once widely used an insulator, was
later shown to cause cancer. </p>
<p>Pfizer, the world''s largest drugmaker, contended that
Quigley''s bankruptcy proceedings insulated the parent company
from suits filed under Pennsylvania state law by the Baltimore
law firm of Peter Angelos. </p>
<p>The firm began suing Pfizer in Pennsylvania state courts in
1999, saying the company was legally responsible for some claims
because its logo appeared on Quigley products. </p>
<p>Pfizer says it played no role in making or selling the
Quigley products. A federal appeals court in New York said the
claims against Pfizer could go forward. </p>
<p>The Obama administration urged the high court to reject
Pfizer''s appeal. </p>
<p>The bankruptcy case is In re Quigley Co., 04-15739, U.S.
Bankruptcy Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). The
Supreme Court case is Pfizer v. Law Offices of Peter Angelos,
12-300. </p>




Photographer: Peter Foley/Bloomberg

<p>
Pfizer Inc. says it played no role in making or selling the Quigley Co. products. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Laura Marcinek" date="Jun 24, 2013  7:43 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-24/morgan-stanley-could-fall-short-of-capital-rules-goldman-says.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Could Fall Short of Capital Rules, Goldman Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) and Bank of New York
Mellon Corp. are the two U.S. banks likely to have the largest
capital shortfall if regulators double the so-called leverage
ratio without exempting cash and government bonds, Goldman Sachs
Group Inc. analysts wrote in a note today. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s Tier 1 leverage ratio is about 4.5 percent
and Bank of New York''s 3.9 percent, the farthest behind the 6
percent requirement said to be under consideration, Goldman
Sachs analysts led by Richard Ramsden said today in a note. The
average Tier 1 leverage ratio for large banks is 5.5 percent,
the analysts said. </p>
<p>U.S. regulators are considering doubling the amount of
capital the largest banks must hold to 6 percent of total
assets, four people with knowledge of the talks said last week.
Last year, rulemakers proposed implementing a 3 percent
international requirement for what''s known as the simple
leverage ratio. </p>
<p>Bank of New York and Morgan Stanley screen as outliers as
outsized cash/repo books meaningfully inflate their asset
bases, the analysts wrote. Both companies are based in New
York. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Glenys Sim" date="Jun 24, 2013  1:45 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-24/goldman-lowers-gold-forecast-through-2014-as-selloff-accelerates.html"><headline>Goldman Lowers Gold Forecast Through 2014 as Selloff Accelerates</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. cut its
forecasts for gold through 2014 after selling quickened as
investors priced in expectations of reduced asset purchases by
the U.S. Federal Reserve. </p>
<p>The bank cut its target for the end of this year to $1,300
an ounce from $1,435 and lowered its prediction to $1,050 from
$1,270 for the end of 2014. Investors are assuming an earlier
tapering of quantitative easing and a Fed fund rate increase
sooner than the bank''s economists expect, analysts Damien Courvalin and Jeffrey Currie wrote in a report dated yesterday. </p>
<p>Gold has fallen 23 percent this year, heading for the
biggest annual drop since 1981, as speculation increased that
the Fed would pare monetary stimulus that helped the metal cap a
12-year bull run last year. Prices slumped to the lowest since
September 2010 last week after Fed Chairman Ben S. Bernanke said
the central bank may slow its bond-buying program if the U.S.
economy continues to improve. </p>
<p>The momentum in gold prices leaves risk to current prices
as skewed to the downside, the analysts wrote. Medium term,
we expect that gold prices will decline further given our U.S.
economists'' forecast for improving economic activity and a less
accommodative monetary policy stance. </p>
<p>Gold for August delivery on the Comex in New York slid 0.7
percent to $1,282.60 an ounce as of 1:41 p.m. in Singapore after
tumbling to $1,268.70 on June 21, the least expensive since
Sept. 16, 2010. Investors sold 533.3 metric tons from bullion-backed exchange-traded products this year, wiping out more than
$54 billion from the value of the funds. </p>
<h2>ETP Slump </h2>
<p>Holdings in ETPs declined to 2,098.605 tons on June 21, the
least since February 2011, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. Assets are down 20 percent in 2013 after climbing
every year since the first product was listed in 2003. Goldman
expects ETPs to decline at a steady pace of 1 million ounces a
month, slightly below their recent pace but twice as fast as
we had previously expected, the analysts wrote. </p>
<p>Goldman joins Credit Suisse Group AG and Societe Generale
SA in predicting further declines. Prices will drop to an
average of $1,200 in the fourth quarter, Societe Generale
forecasts. Credit Suisse sees the metal at $1,100 in 12 months,
according to Ric Deverell, head of commodities research. </p>
<p>In April, when gold entered a bear market, a buying frenzy
from China to India and the U.S. followed the biggest price drop
in 30 years, driving prices up more than $150 an ounce. Russia
and South Korea were among nations that added gold to reserves
this year, after central banks around the world bought 534.6
tons last year, the most since 1964, according to World Gold
Council estimates. </p>
<p>We continue to expect that continued central bank gold
buying will not be sufficient to offset this decline in
prices, the analysts wrote. Further, we would expect this
decline in prices to coincide with rising jewelry demand, which
we view as price responsive and not price setting. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Jun 25, 2013 12:17 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-25/microsoft-starts-venture-program-providing-funding-to-incubation.html"><headline>Microsoft Starts Venture Program Providing Funding to Incubation</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) is introducing a
venture capital division that will provide funding, advice and
computing and software services to startups. </p>
<p>Through the newly formed Microsoft Ventures, fledgling
business will have access to funding, services such as cloud
computing and an accelerator program lasting three to six
months, Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft said in a blog. The
company already provides several of these services. The new
program will help bring cohesion to the effort, Microsoft said. </p>
<p>By unifying our various efforts, we will give
entrepreneurs a single point of entry to engage with
Microsoft, the company said. Startups have enough to worry
about. We want to make access to us as intuitive and friction-free as possible. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Glenys Sim" date="Jun 25, 2013 11:54 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-25/morgan-stanley-to-goldman-cut-gold-forecasts-as-easing-may-end.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley to Goldman Cut Gold Forecasts on Fed Outlook</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley lowered its forecasts
for gold, joining Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and UBS AG in paring
estimates on prospects that the U.S. Federal Reserve will scale
back monetary stimulus as the economy recovers. </p>
<p>The bank cut its 2013 target to $1,409 an ounce from
$1,487, reduced its prediction for 2014 to $1,313 from $1,563,
and trimmed its 2015 estimate to $1,300 from $1,450. Morgan
Stanley also lowered its gold and silver forecasts through 2018,
analysts Peter Richardson and Joel Crane wrote in a report. </p>
<p>Analysts from BNP Paribas SA to Standard Bank Plc are
cutting their outlook for gold as the precious metal heads for
its biggest annual drop in more than three decades. Bullion has
fallen 24 percent in 2013 after rallying for 12 years, slumping
to the lowest level since September 2010 last week after Fed
Chairman Ben S. Bernanke said the central bank may slow its
bond-buying program if the U.S. economy continues to improve. </p>
<p>With investor demand for safe-haven assets waning against
the backdrop of a strengthening U.S. dollar and rising U.S. bond
yields, market conditions for gold and silver have become
markedly less favorable, Morgan Stanley analysts wrote. </p>
<p>Gold for immediate delivery fell 0.5 percent to $1,276.09
today after tumbling to $1,269.46 on June 21, the cheapest since
Sept. 16, 2010. Investors sold 541.5 metric tons from bullion-backed exchange-traded products this year, erasing $56 billion
from the value of the funds. </p>
<h2>ETP Slump </h2>
<p>Holdings in ETPs declined to 2,090.4 tons yesterday, the
least since June 2010, according to data compiled by Bloomberg.
Assets are down 21 percent in 2013 after climbing every year
since the first product was listed in 2003, as waning investor
faith turned more serious, said Morgan Stanley. </p>
<p>This historic and fundamental change in one of the key
drivers of the gold bull market is highlighting a sharp decline
in the desirability of this form of investment, Richardson and
Crane wrote. </p>
<p>Goldman, which expects ETPs to decline at a steady pace of
1 million ounces a month, cut its 2013 year-end price target to
$1,300 from $1,435 and lowered the 2014 prediction to $1,050
from $1,270. Investors are assuming an earlier tapering of
quantitative easing and a Fed fund rate increase sooner than the
bank''s economists expect, analysts Damien Courvalin and Jeffrey Currie wrote in a June 23 report. </p>
<p>Bernanke said on June 19 that the central bank, which buys
$85 billion of Treasury and mortgage debt each month, may begin
reducing purchases this year and end the program in 2014. This
will keep gold prices under pressure, according to James Steel
and Howard Wen at HSBC Securities (USA) Inc., who yesterday
reduced their 2013 forecast to $1,396 from $1,542 and trimmed
their 2014 estimate to $1,435 from $1,600. Credit Suisse Group
Inc. lowered its estimates today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Martijn van der Starre" date="Jun 25, 2013  9:12 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-25/ibm-dutch-team-up-on-water-data-real-time-intelligence.html"><headline>IBM, Dutch Team Up on Water Data, Real-Time Intelligence</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM) started a program with Dutch authorities to investigate
how to analyze water and flood data in the Netherlands, almost a
fifth of which is covered by lakes, rivers and dikes. </p>
<p>The initiative will provide water experts with a real-time intelligent dashboard to harness information so it can be
shared immediately across organizations and agencies, IBM said
today in a statement. Collaboration partners include an
Environment Ministry office and the University of Delft, said
IBM, based in Armonk, New York. </p>
<p>The new management system in the Netherlands, where a
quarter of the land is below sea level, will address concerns
ranging from drinking water quality to the increasing frequency
and impact of extreme weather, IBM said. The data sources
include water level monitors, levee sensors and current and
historic maintenance information from sluices, pumping stations
and dams. </p>
<p>By modeling weather events, the Netherlands will be able
to determine the best course of action including storing water,
diverting it from low-lying areas, avoiding saltwater intrusion
into drinking water, sewage overflows and water contamination,
the largest computer-services provider said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kevin Dugan" date="Jun 26, 2013  6:07 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-26/morgan-stanley-sells-largest-note-tied-to-lululemon-stock.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Sells Largest Note Tied to Lululemon Stock</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley sold $10.7 million of
one-year securities tied to Lululemon Athletica Inc. (LULU), the
largest such offering in at least three and a half years. </p>
<p>The securities, issued June 21, yield as much as 12 percent
so long as the stock doesn''t end up below 70 percent of its
starting value, with all principal at risk, according to a
prospectus filed with the Securities and Exchange Commission.
The bank distributed the securities for a 1.5 percent
commission. </p>
<p>Lululemon, the Vancouver-based athletic clothing maker that
recalled some of its women''s pants in March for being too sheer,
tumbled 18 percent on June 11. The day before, Christine Day,
the company''s chief executive officer, said she would leave the
company. </p>
<p>I think what Lulu has done well is create an immensely
strong consumer following that is pretty sticky, said Camilo Lyon, a New York-based analyst for Canaccord Genuity Corp.
Whoever succeeds Day doesn''t really have a lot to change, he
said. </p>
<p>Canaccord lowered its 12-month target price for the stock
to $87 on June 11 from $92. </p>
<p>Shares fell 16 percent this year to close at $63.88 today.
Morgan Stanley (MS) will automatically redeem the notes quarterly if
the stock rises above its initial level of $61.90. </p>
<p>Lauren Bellmare, a spokeswoman for Morgan Stanley in New
York, didn''t return an e-mail seeking comment on the note. The
bank is the largest U.S. structured note issuer by volume. </p>
<p>Banks create structured notes by packaging debt with
derivatives to offer customized bets to retail investors while
earning fees and raising money. Derivatives are contracts whose
value is derived from stocks, bonds, commodities and currencies,
or events such as changes in interest rates or the weather. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Jun 26, 2013  4:32 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-26/microsoft-getting-facebook-application-for-windows-8.html"><headline>Microsoft Gets Facebook App for Windows 8</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Facebook Inc. (FB) is building an application for Microsoft Corp. (MSFT)''s Windows 8, adding one of the most popular programs missing from the operating system designed to help the software maker gain tablet customers. </p> <p>Flipboard Inc., which lets users combine articles into a digital magazine, and the National Football League will also create apps for Windows 8, Microsoft Chief Executive Officer Steve Ballmer said at a conference today in San Francisco. There are now more than 100,000 apps for Windows 8. </p> <p>Microsoft commanded just 3.7 percent of the tablet market in the first quarter as a lack of some high-profile features, including a Facebook app, limited the appeal of Windows 8 and the software maker''s Surface tablet. Twitter''s app for Windows 8 was released in March. Microsoft is courting developers and adding features to Windows 8 to gain share in a tablet market dominated by Apple Inc. and Samsung Electronics Co. </p> <p>Microsoft today released a test version of its Windows 8.1 software, which restores some old Windows features, like a start button and rolls out new ones in a bid to reignite interest in its flagship operating system. Some customers had complained about the software''s usability without the familiar start button. </p> <p>The finished version of Windows 8.1 will be available later this year. </p> <p>Flipboard plans to release its app, and a version for Windows Phone, later this year, Eric Feng, chief technology officer for the developer, said in an interview. The NFL program is a fantasy football app. </p> <p>Microsoft''s shares rose 2 percent to $34.35 at the close in New York, leaving them up 29 percent this year. </p> <p>-- Editors: Lisa Rapaport, Niamh Ring </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tiffany Kary" date="Jun 26, 2013 12:08 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-26/pfizer-s-quigley-can-end-nine-year-bankruptcy-judge-says.html"><headline>Pfizer''s Quigley Can End Nine-Year Bankruptcy, Judge Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE)''s non-operating Quigley
Co. can end almost nine years in bankruptcy under a plan that
will resolve most asbestos claims against the world''s largest
drugmaker and its former maker of insulation products. </p>
<p>U.S. Bankruptcy Judge Stuart Bernstein in Manhattan today
approved a Chapter 11 plan under which Pfizer will contribute
assets worth $964 million. He rejected a prior plan almost three
years ago, saying Pfizer was improperly using Quigley''s
bankruptcy to shield itself from asbestos claims. </p>
<p>Bernstein found in September 2010 that Pfizer''s proposed
$216.2 million contribution to a prior plan wasn''t enough
considering court testimony that Quigley may face $4.45 billion
in claims over 42 years, and that asbestos claimants could have
fared better by suing the company under civil tort law. A
company reorganizing in bankruptcy is shielded from lawsuits,
including tort, or wrongful-injury claims. Once it emerges, it
is a new legal entity, and often can no longer be sued. </p>
<p>Quigley, which made asbestos-containing products from the
1940s to the 1970s, including Insulag, a powdered insulation,
was bought by Pfizer in 1968. It stopped most operations in 1992
and filed for bankruptcy in 2004, facing 160,000 lawsuits. Many
also named Pfizer, whose name appeared on Insulag packaging. </p>
<p>Pfizer has said throughout the case that it never made or
sold Quigley''s products and it doesn''t have liability for them.
Asbestos, once widely used as an insulator, was later shown to
cause cancer. </p>
<h2>U.S. Objection </h2>
<p>The U.S. Trustee, a bankruptcy watchdog for the Justice
Department, sought to have the case thrown out in 2010, saying
that while it''s pending, creditors with alleged asbestos-related
health problems have been unable to sue New York-based Pfizer,
and many have died. </p>
<p>Wilentz, Goldman  Spitzer was the sole objector to the
current plan. The Woodbridge, New Jersey-based law firm called
it yet another flawed plan after nine years of afflicted
deals in which Pfizer has tried to buy votes. </p>
<p>The case is In re Quigley Co., 04-bk-15739, U.S. Bankruptcy
Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). The appeals
case is 11-2635, 11-2767, U.S. Court of Appeals for the Second
Circuit (Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Drew Armstrong" date="Jun 27, 2013  5:51 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-27/pfizer-announces-10-billion-share-repurchase-program.html"><headline>Pfizer Announces $10 Billion Share Repurchase Program</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE), the world''s biggest
drugmaker, said it will buy back $10 billion in stock after
earlier this week announcing it will retire about $11.4 billion
in shares through the spinoff of its animal-health unit. </p>
<p>The buyback is the fourth major share repurchase program
for New York-based Pfizer in the past 2 1/2 years. During that
time, the company has announced $39 billion in share buybacks,
including today''s. Pfizer has $3.9 billion left on its current
repurchase program, the company said today in a statement. </p>
<p>Ian Read, Pfizer''s chief executive officer, has said that
share repurchases are the best uses of Pfizer''s cash, compared
with acquisitions or increasing the dividend. Read has shed non-drug units to focus on developing and selling new, brand-name
therapies. The company, which had a market capitalization of
about $200 billion as of today''s close, is looking at whether it
will split itself and get rid of its generics drug business. </p>
<p>Pfizer earlier this week announced the completion of a deal
to exchange shares of its own stock for equity in Zoetis Inc. (ZTS),
its former animal-health unit. That exchange is expected to
retire about $11.4 billion in Pfizer shares. </p>
<p>Pfizer shares gained 1.4 percent to $28.58 in extended
trading at 5:35 p.m. New York time after the buyback was
announced. The company''s stock has increased 25 percent in the
past 12 months. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Agnieszka Troszkiewicz" date="Jun 27, 2013 12:25 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-27/jpmorgan-s-henry-bath-delists-21-lme-storage-units-worldwide.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Henry Bath Delists 21 LME Storage Units Worldwide</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Henry Bath  Son Ltd., owned by
JPMorgan Chase  Co., requested the London Metal Exchange to
delist 21 of its warehouses and storage facilities. </p>
<p>Five warehouses in Baltimore, three in Liverpool and two in
Bilbao, Spain, were delisted with immediate effect, the bourse
said in notices to members today. Henry Bath also had two
Singapore warehouses, and one warehouse in Chicago, New Orleans
and Busan, South Korea removed, according to the LME. </p>
<p>Six of Henry Bath''s Rotterdam facilities were also removed
from the network of LME warehouses with immediate effect, the
LME said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Jun 27, 2013 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-27/microsoft-seeks-end-to-dinosaur-era-software-upgrade-cycle-tech.html"><headline>Microsoft Seeks End to Dinosaur-Era Software Upgrade Cycle: Tech</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp (MSFT)., which for decades has refreshed its popular Office corporate software just once about every three years, says it will soon switch to weekly updates. </p> <p>It''s a radical shift as Microsoft overhauls its Internet-based programs, seeking to stay in sync with the fast-changing technology industry. </p> <p>For much of Microsoft''s 38-year history, infrequent upgrades made sense for businesses seeking predictable improvements. That''s changed as nimbler entrants such as Dropbox Inc., Box Inc., Jive Software Inc (JIVE) (JIVE). and Google Inc. refine features and deliver automatic updates over the Web. That tinkering has helped lure customers and put pressure on margins at Microsoft''s biggest division, which accounted for $24 billion in sales last year, or a third of the total. </p> <p>Microsoft, on this every-three-year schedule for the massive wave of new products, looks like a dinosaur, said Melissa Webster, an analyst at market-research firm IDC, based in Framingham, Massachusetts. Three years is a lifetime in tech these days. </p> <p>That message has gotten through. Within a year, users of Internet-based versions of Office productivity software, as well as e-mail, telephony and collaboration tools, will have parts of their software refreshed weekly, Jeff Teper, an Office vice president, said in an interview. Microsoft has been moving toward more frequent updates with other programs, including Windows. </p>




Photographer: Mario Tama/Getty Images

<p>
The Microsoft Windows 8 operating system is unveiled at a press conference on October 25, 2012 in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Catarina Saraiva" date="Jun 28, 2013  4:25 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-28/goldman-sachs-cuts-brazil-2013-2014-gdp-forecasts-table-.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Cuts Brazil 2013, 2014 GDP Forecasts</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The following table shows Goldman Sach''s
Latin America economic forecasts as of June 28, compared to their forecasts
as of June 14.       </p>

==============================================================================
                        -Forecast-    --Change--     -Forecast-    --Change--
                       2013   2014    2013   2014    2013   2014   2013   2014
==============================================================================
                        ---Annual Average GDP---     ---Annual Average CPI---
Argentina              2.9%   2.5%   -0.5%  -0.2%   10.8%  13.0%  -0.1%     --
Brazil                 2.3%   2.8%   -0.2%  -0.3%    5.8%   5.5%     --     --
Chile                  4.1%   4.1%   -0.5%  -0.5%    2.5%   2.9%     --     --
Colombia               4.2%   4.8%      --     --    3.0%   3.0%     --     --
Mexico                 2.8%   3.6%   -0.3%  -0.2%    3.5%   3.2%     --     --
Peru                   5.5%   6.0%   -0.4%  -0.3%    2.5%   2.5%     --     --
Venezuela              1.6%   2.5%      --     --   37.6%  22.0%     --     --
==============================================================================
SOURCE: Goldman Sachs Latin America Economic Analyst''

]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Brendan Case" date="Jun 29, 2013 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-06-29/coca-cola-femsa-targets-brazil-growth-with-fluminense-purchase.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Femsa Targets Brazil Expansion With Fluminense Deal</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Coca-Cola Femsa SAB (KOFL), the largest
bottler of the soft drink in Latin America, agreed to buy
Brazil''s Cia. Fluminense de Refrigerantes for $448 million in
cash to expand in the region''s largest country. </p>
<p>The purchase will bolster Coca-Cola (KO) Femsa''s Brazilian
business by linking two other areas it serves, clearing the way
for the reconfiguration of the supply chain of our combined
operations, Chief Executive Officer Carlos Salazar said
yesterday in a statement. </p>
<p>The Fluminense deal caps a $4 billion acquisition spree in
the past two years by Mexico City-based Coca-Cola Femsa, which
also has purchased four Mexican bottlers and control of Coca-Cola Co.''s Philippines bottling operation. Fluminense, which was
founded in 1949 in the state of Rio de Janeiro, posted sales of
about $232 million in the year ending March 31, shipping 56.6
million unit cases of beverages, including beer. </p>
<p>This acquisition highlights the long-term strategic
importance of the Brazilian market for Coca-Cola Femsa as we
believe in the attractive domestic consumption prospects and
socio-economic dynamics, Salazar said in the statement. This
transaction underscores our commitment to continue focusing on
the opportunities that the Latin American Coca-Cola bottling
system presents. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola Femsa will seek to increase sales by offering a
broader range of products, adding coolers at retailers and
serving more points of sale, according to investor relations
chief Jose Castro. </p>
<h2>Beverage Breakdown </h2>
<p>The deal is subject to approval by Brazil''s antitrust
regulator, said Coca-Cola Femsa, which is controlled by
Monterrey, Mexico-based Fomento Economico Mexicano SAB. (FEMSAUBD) The
bottler also will seek approval from Atlanta-based Coca-Cola.
The transaction is expected to close in the fourth quarter,
Castro said, and is being funded with the company''s existing
cash balances. </p>
<p>Fluminense had an estimated $40 million in consolidated
earnings before interest, taxes, depreciation and amortization
in the 12 months ended March 31, Coca-Cola Femsa said. </p>
<p>With one bottling plant and four distribution centers, it
operates in parts of Sao Paulo, Rio de Janeiro and Minas Gerais
states. Carbonated soft drinks make up 86 percent of its
business, with 8 percent coming from beer, 5 percent from non-carbonated beverages and 1 percent from water, Castro said. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola Femsa sold 494.2 million unit cases last year in
Brazil, up 1.8 percent from a year earlier, the company said
Feb. 27. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry></news>