
<news><entry author="By Alex Barinka and Jesse Drucker" date="Feb 03, 2014  6:38 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-03/ibm-uses-dutch-tax-haven-to-boost-profits-as-sales-slide.html"><headline>IBM Uses Dutch Tax Haven to Boost Profits as Sales Slide</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines Corp. has reduced its tax rate to a two-decade low with help from a tax strategy that sends profits through a Dutch subsidiary. </p> <p>The approach, which involves routing almost all sales in Europe, the Middle East, Africa, Asia and some of the Americas through the Netherlands unit, helped IBM as it gradually reduced its tax rate over 20 years at the same time pretax income quadrupled. Then last year, the rate slid to the lowest level since at least 1994, lifting earnings above analysts'' estimates. </p> <p>IBM is aiming for $20 a share in adjusted earnings by 2015, up from $11.67 in 2010 -- a goal made more difficult as the company posted seven straight quarters of declining revenue. To stay on target, IBM has bought back shares, sold assets, and fired and furloughed workers. A less prominent though vital role is played by its subsidiary in the Netherlands, one of the most important havens for multinational companies looking for ways to legally reduce their tax rates. </p> <p>They''ve got a lot of ways to beat earnings and they definitely take advantage of it, said Josh Olson, an analyst at Edward Jones  Co. It''s part of how IBM operates. </p> <p>IBM ended 2013 with a tax provision $1.84 billion lower than it initially projected, thanks to a tax rate of 15.6 percent -- compared with its forecast of 25 percent. Without the lower rate, the company''s earnings per share would have fallen from the previous year instead of rising, and net income would have missed analysts'' estimates by about 14 percent instead of 2.9 percent, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>




Photographer: Graham Carlow/IBM via Bloomberg

<p>
Chief Executive Officer Ginni Rometty has stuck with IBM''s profit goals. To stay on track for her $20-a-share earnings target, the company spent $1 billion last year to restructure its workforce -- shedding 3,300 employees in the U.S. andCanada, according to employee group Alliance@IBM. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Feb 03, 2014  4:38 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-03/goldman-sachs-names-powell-to-lead-urban-investment-group.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Names Powell to Lead Urban Investment Group</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), the fifth-largest U.S. bank by assets, named Dina H. Powell, who leads the
firm''s charitable efforts, to also head its urban investment
group that makes socially minded deals. </p>
<p>Powell will retain her role as head of the office of
corporate engagement and join the management team of the bank
subsidiary, according to an internal memo sent by Goldman Sachs
Chief of Staff John Rogers and Esta Stecher, the head of Goldman
Sachs Bank USA. </p>
<p>Powell has helped Goldman Sachs develop its 10,000 Small
Businesses initiative that provides training and loans to
entrepreneurs. The urban investment group, or UIG, has created
the Goldman Sachs Social Impact Fund, which provided financing
to a program announced last week to cut recidivism among youth
in Massachusetts. </p>
<p>UIG has evolved its mission to focus on impact investing,
deploying more than $3 billion in loans and equity investments
to revitalize neighborhoods and support underserved
communities, Rogers and Stecher wrote in the memo. More
recently, UIG has led the way in developing creative market-based solutions to help address significant economic and public
policy challenges. </p>
<p>Powell joined New York-based Goldman Sachs in 2007 and was
named a partner in 2010. She previously served as U.S. assistant
secretary of state for educational and cultural affairs in
George W. Bush''s administration. </p>
<p>Powell''s expanded duties were reported earlier today by the
New York Times. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Marie Mawad" date="Feb 03, 2014  6:41 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-03/mobile-carrier-sfr-spinoff-from-vivendi-is-only-plan-ceo-says.html"><headline>SFR Spinoff From Vivendi Is Only Plan for Carrier, CEO Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A spinoff of French phone company SFR
from owner Vivendi SA (VIV) is the only plan for the unit, its chief
executive officer said, dismissing an alternative merger
involving the country''s second-largest carrier. </p>
<p>The planned separation of SFR with 2012 revenue of 11.3
billion euros ($15.3 billion) is well advanced, and will
lead to a stock listing on July 1, SFR Chairman and CEO Jean-Yves Charlier told reporters in Paris today. </p>
<p>We have one plan, and only one -- it''s splitting SFR from
Vivendi, Charlier said. We''re not at all operating a dual-track scenario. There''s only a single track. </p>
<p>While Vivendi and cable operator Numericable SAS (NUM) have held
talks on and off in the past year about a merger without being
able to agree on valuation, Altice SA, Numericable''s biggest
investor, is making a renewed push to consolidate
telecommunications assets in Europe, people familiar with the
matter said last month. </p>
<p>Altice raised 1.3 billion euros in an initial public
offering last week, giving the company founded by entrepreneur
Patrick Drahi a vehicle for raising capital for possible deals.
While the IPO is subject a so-called share lockup for 180 days,
an exception allows Altice to issue new shares starting 45 days
after the IPO if the proceeds are used to finance a merger or
acquisition, according to regulatory filings. </p>
<h2>Listing Vehicle </h2>
<p>Altice, which debuted in Amsterdam last week, rose for a
second day, adding 1.2 percent to 28.92 euros at 12:39 p.m.
local time and valuing the company at 6 billion euros. Vivendi,
which relied on SFR for almost 40 percent of its 2012 revenue,
slipped 1.1 percent to 19.72 euros in Paris trading. Numericable
lost less than 1 percent to 27.96 euros. </p>
<p>Vivendi, which will ask shareholders in June to approve a
split of the Paris-based company into two, is aiming to file
details of SFR''s spinoff plan to market regulators by March,
people familiar with the matter have said. </p>
<p>The separation is part of Vivendi''s reorganization around
media, music and broadcasting assets. SFR is valued at 12
billion euros, according to analysts at Liberum Capital Ltd. </p>
<p>SFR and smaller rival Bouygues SA (EN) agreed last week to share
part of their mobile-phone networks, allowing each other to
cover more ground for less money. Charlier today called analyst
estimates of 200 million euros in annual savings for SFR from
the pact realistic. The savings will fully kick in from
2018, he said. </p>
<p>The network-sharing agreement is part of plans by SFR to
reduce spending to preserve cash as it fights price wars and
declining phone bills. Differentiating from rivals'' fixed-line
and wireless offers will also be key, Charlier said. </p>
<p>We have an ambitious plan to re-position SFR, focused on
cash flow and differentiating products, he said. It will be
up to investors to decide if this, as well as the French
telecoms industry eventually being reshuffled, makes for an
attractive equity story. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jason Corcoran" date="Feb 03, 2014  6:29 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-03/goldman-sachs-vtb-capital-buy-half-of-russian-gym-chain.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs, VTB Capital Buy Half of Russian Gym Chain</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (G) and VTB
Capital bought a 50 percent stake in Russian Fitness Group for
an undisclosed amount to invest in the country''s growing
enthusiasm for working out. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs, a minority investor since 2006, will
substantially increase its holding with the deal, managing
director Anton Schreider said in an an e-mailed statement today. </p>
<p>The transaction is a further demonstration of Goldman
Sachs''s long-term commitment to investing in Russia as well as
our flexible investment mandate allowing us to back strong local
businesses over extended time horizons, Schreider said. </p>
<p>Russian Fitness Group, which runs the World Class and
FizKult chains, has grown to 60 clubs in 22 cities in 21 years.
The clubs have 109,000 members with 2,700 training and
administrative staff, according to its website. Pop star Madonna
came to Moscow in 2012 to open a branch of her Hard Candy
fitness clubs near the Kremlin. </p>
<p>Olga Sloutsker, president of World Class and a former
Russian fencing champion, said the company plans to open nine
more clubs this year in Russia and the Commonwealth of
Independent States. Sloutsker, the chain''s founder, will remain
with the company, according to the statement. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs, based in New York, said in 2011 it has made
more direct investments in closely held Russian businesses than
any foreign bank, buying stakes in 15 companies totaling more
than $1 billion since 2007. </p>
<p>One of those was lender Tinkoff Credit Systems, which did
an initial public offering in London last year. Goldman helped
to organize the October IPO and raised $226 million from selling
stock, cashing out almost two-thirds of its stake. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Beth Jinks and Dina Bass" date="Feb 03, 2014 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-03/microsoft-s-new-director-plans-to-seek-windows-sales-redo.html"><headline>Microsoft''s New Director Plans to Seek Windows-Sales Redo</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>ValueAct Holdings LP President Mason Morfit, the investor set to join Microsoft Corp. (MSFT)''s board as it
prepares to make Satya Nadella chief executive officer, will
seek another break with tradition: how the company sells its
flagship products. </p>
<p>Morfit, 38, and ValueAct want the world''s largest software
maker to reduce its focus on Windows, the operating system that
underlies most of the company''s offerings, according to people
familiar with the matter who asked not to be identified because
the information is private. For two decades, Microsoft has
focused on selling applications and server software designed to
work specifically for Windows. </p>
<p>Now ValueAct wants Microsoft to accelerate efforts to
unchain products and services from Windows so that they can be
more widely adopted on smartphones and tablets. Microsoft
programs like Office, which typically run on Windows, could then
also be used on Apple Inc. (AAPL) and Samsung Electronics Co. gadgets
that have other operating systems, the people said. The moves
are intended to reinvigorate growth at a company that''s
struggled to adapt to the rise of mobile devices, away from the
shrinking personal computing arena. </p>
<p>Morfit also wants to emphasize enterprise and cloud
businesses and push Microsoft to look at jettisoning or scaling
back hardware and consumer products such as the Xbox game
console, which carry expensive marketing and manufacturing
costs, the people said. </p>




Photographer: Krisztian Bocsi/Bloomberg

<p>
ValueAct wants Microsoft to accelerate efforts to unchain products and services from Windows so that they can be more widely adopted on smartphones and tablets. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Feb 04, 2014  7:24 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-04/microsoft-names-satya-nadella-as-ceo-to-transform-pc-pioneer.html"><headline>Microsoft''s Nadella Named CEO to Transform PC Pioneer</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) named Satya Nadella chief executive officer, tapping an insider steeped in business technology to speed up a turnaround at a software maker that helped usher in the personal-computing age, only to be left behind as the world embraced the Web and mobile devices. </p> <p>Nadella, 46, is replacing Steve Ballmer effective immediately after a five-month search, Microsoft said in a statement today. Bill Gates, the company''s first CEO, will step aside as chairman, devote more time to product development as a director and continue running his philanthropic foundation. John Thompson, the director who led the CEO search, becomes chairman. </p> <p>Related:</p>
Thompson Replacing Gates as Microsoft Chairman in Revamp
Microsoft CEO Pick Leaves Losers Grappling With Fallout
Microsoft Buys $15 Million Stake in Foursquare for Mobile Data
<p>The new CEO, who was born in India and joined Microsoft in 1992, takes over at a critical juncture. Consumers and businesses are shunning PCs in favor of handheld devices made by rivals, sapping demand for Microsoft''s flagship products. Besides playing catchup to the likes of Apple Inc. (AAPL) and Google Inc. (GOOG), Nadella will be tasked with completing strategy changes, begun by Ballmer last year, that include integrating the $7.2 billion integration of Nokia Oyj (NOK1V)''s handset unit and turning Microsoft into a provider of services and hardware. </p>




Photographer: Kevin P. Casey/The New York Times via Redux

<p>
Satya Nadella, the head of corporate software and cloud computing at Microsoft, in Redmond, Wash., in this Oct. 3, 2012 file photo. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Feb 04, 2014  6:06 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-04/morgan-stanley-agrees-to-1-25-billion-settlement-over-mbs-sales.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Reaches $1.25 Billion Settlement of FHFA Suit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) agreed to pay
$1.25 billion to settle a U.S. regulator''s claims the investment
bank sold faulty mortgage-backed securities to Fannie Mae and
Freddie Mac (FMCC) that added to their losses in the financial crisis. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley took a $150 million charge, reducing fourth-quarter and full-year 2013 earnings by 5 cents a share, the New
York-based bank said today in a regulatory filing. That would
bring last year''s earnings per share to $1.36. </p>
<p>The Federal Housing Finance Agency sued 18 banks in 2011
seeking to recoup some of the losses taxpayers covered when the
government took control of the failing mortgage-finance
companies in 2008. Seven banks, including JPMorgan Chase  Co.
and Deutsche Bank AG, agreed to pay a total of almost $8 billion
last year to settle claims they sold faulty mortgage bonds to
Fannie Mae (FNMA) and Freddie Mac. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley said last month it added $1.2 billion to
legal reserves in the fourth quarter related to mortgage-backed
securities litigation and investigations. The firm disclosed in
a filing in November that the case involved the sale of $11
billion of mortgage-related securities. </p>
<p>Denise Dunckel, a spokeswoman for FHFA, confirmed the
settlement in principle. The agreement requires final approvals
by the parties, according to Morgan Stanley''s filing. </p>




Photographer: Victor J. Blue/Bloomberg

<p>
Morgan Stanley took a $150 million charge, reducing fourth-quarter and full-year 2013 earnings by 5 cents a share, according to a regulatory filing today by the New York-based firm. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Frier and Dina Bass" date="Feb 04, 2014  2:15 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-04/microsoft-buys-15-million-stake-in-foursquare-for-mobile-data.html"><headline>Microsoft Buys $15 Million Stake in Foursquare for Mobile Data</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) invested $15 million in Foursquare Labs Inc., forging a partnership that will help Windows-powered phones offer restaurant and entertainment suggestions to consumers on the move. </p> <p>The investment, confirmed in an interview by Foursquare Chief Executive Officer Dennis Crowley, is part of a funding round from late last year that valued New York-based Foursquare at more than $600 million, people with knowledge of the terms said in December. </p> <p>Microsoft is adding features to its Windows Phone software in an effort to compete with Apple Inc. (AAPL)''s iPhone and Google Inc.''s Android software, which together dominate the smartphone market. Location data from Foursquare will appear in a voice-activated assistant, code-named Cortana, that has yet to be released and will go up against Apple''s Siri technology, according to a person with knowledge of the plans. </p> <p>Related:</p>
Thompson Replacing Gates as Chairman in Revamp
Nadella Chosen to Transform PC Pioneer
CEO Pick Leaves Losers Grappling With Fallout
<p>This is huge validation for the stuff we''ve been working so hard on, Crowley said. It''s one of the leaders in the space we work in looking at us and saying we can really help power the next generation of devices. </p> <p>Foursquare, which has struggled to generate sales in almost five years on the market, will get a new stream of data licensing revenue from the partnership, Crowley said. Foursquare''s valuation has been stagnant since 2011. </p> <p>Bloomberg News reported in August that Microsoft and American Express Co. were both vying for a stake in Foursquare. Microsoft has been courting startups to add features to its phones and tablets, which lag behind Apple and Android products in the number of applications available to users. </p> <h2>Cortana Coming </h2> <p>Cortana, named for the artificially intelligent character in Microsoft''s popular Halo video game series, is scheduled to be part of the Windows Phone 8.1 release, to be shown within several months, according to a person familiar with the project and Foursquare agreement, who asked not to be identified because details haven''t been made public. </p> <p>As part of the deal, Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft will gain access to more of Foursquare''s data than the company makes available publicly and to other partners. That data would allow Microsoft, with a user''s permission, to push out tips, suggestions and discounts tied to a person''s location, said Zig Serafin, a vice president in Microsoft''s Bing search unit. </p> <p>We''re building some contextually aware experiences to power some upcoming products in Windows Phone, Serafin said. This will be for anywhere you get a Bing-powered experience. </p> <p>Crowley and Serafin, along with other employees from the two companies, began working on a deal last year to collaborate on products, which eventually led to an investment, said the person familiar with the agreement. The companies did not discuss an acquisition, the person said. </p> <h2>Uphill Struggle </h2> <p>Brendan Lewis, a spokesman for Foursquare, declined to comment on negotiations with Microsoft or plans for Cortana. Adam Sohn, a Microsoft spokesman, couldn''t immediately be reached for comment and the company hasn''t publicly commented on Cortana. </p> <p>In December, Foursquare raised $35 million led by venture fund DFJ Growth. The company spent the year adding products for businesses to advertise to its users as well as ways to send instant and relevant recommendations to people. </p> <p>Foursquare has 45 million users, compared with more than 230 million for Twitter Inc. and 1.2 billion for Facebook Inc. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Peter Burrows and Dina Bass" date="Feb 04, 2014  2:13 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-04/microsoft-ceo-pick-leaves-losers-grappling-with-fallout.html"><headline>Microsoft CEO Pick Leaves Losers Grappling With Fallout</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Now that there''s a winner for the chief executive officer position at Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), those who lost out on the job will need to decide whether to stick around. </p> <p>With Microsoft''s board disclosing today that it picked Satya Nadella as CEO, that leaves internal candidates such as Executive Vice President Tony Bates and Chief Operating Officer Kevin Turner among those who failed to get promoted, people with knowledge of the search have said. Stephen Elop, the former CEO of Nokia Oyj who was set to join the software maker after it closes a $7.2 billion deal for Nokia''s handset unit, was also on the shortlist, among others. </p> <p>While there''s no telling how long some executives might stick around were a better offer to come along, the conclusion to Microsoft''s search may not spark an immediate exodus, said people with knowledge of the matter. The CEO candidates were informed that they didn''t get the role last week, said people familiar with the matter, who asked not to be identified because the information is private, giving the executives time to work out some next steps. </p> <p>Turner plans to stay at the Redmond, Washington-based company, said a person close to the COO. And while Bates and Elop both have ambitions to be CEO, they are also set to continue at Microsoft for the time being since success in their current jobs may be the best way to attract other offers, said people close to the executives, who asked not to be identified because the information is private. </p>




Photographer: VIEW/Demotix/Corbis

<p>
Microsoft Corporation Chief Operating Officer Kevin Turner, right, speaks to customers during the opening of Microsoft''s store at Times Square in this Oct. 25, 2012 file photo in New York City. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Weiyi Lim and Inyoung Hwang" date="Feb 04, 2014  1:35 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-04/goldman-to-fidelity-call-for-calm-after-global-stock-wipeout.html"><headline>Goldman to Fidelity Call for Calm After Global Stock Wipeout</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Panic is making an enemy of telephones for Catherine Yeung, the director for equities at Fidelity Investment Management Ltd. in Hong Kong. </p> <p>My children hate that BlackBerry, said Yeung, whose clients have been calling amid two weeks of declines that erased $3 trillion from global stocks. She''s advising calm, noting that profits are rising and shares just got a lot less expensive. </p> <p>Being a contrarian and getting in when things seem bad is often a good thing, she said in an interview today. The companies we are looking into can still deliver attractive margins. Things are getting cheap. </p> <p>Strategists from Goldman Sachs Group Inc. to AMP Capital Investors and JPMorgan Chase  Co. are also telling clients to hang on after losses that began with currencies in Turkey and Argentina spread to developed markets. The Standard  Poor''s 500 Index slid 2.3 percent yesterday, capping its first 5 percent retreat in eight months, while Japan''s Topix index plunged 4.8 percent for its biggest decrease since June. </p> <p>Related: Market''s 19th Breakdown Sees Bulls Unmoved</p><p>We didn''t expect the U.S. would be this weak, Kathy Matsui, chief Japan strategist for Goldman Sachs in Tokyo, said by e-mail. Since we do not see sufficient reason to change our fundamental earnings outlook and stock prices have fallen, the market still appears attractive to us. </p>




Photographer: Diego Giudice/Bloomberg

<p>
Argentina''s peso started sliding as the central bank pared dollar sales to preserve international reserves that have fallen to a seven-year low. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Wayne" date="Feb 04, 2014 12:16 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-04/pfizer-among-10-drugmakers-in-new-government-project.html"><headline>Pfizer Among Drugmakers in U.S. Chronic Disease Project</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE), Eli Lilly  Co. (LLY) and
eight other large drugmakers will partner with the U.S.
government in a $230 million effort to identify new approaches
to treat Alzheimer''s, diabetes, lupus and arthritis. </p>
<p>Data generated from the work will be made public for other
scientists to use, a move the U.S. National Institutes of Health
called groundbreaking. The targeted diseases are some of the
most prevalent conditions among Americans, costing the nation
billions of dollars in treatment and lost productivity. </p>
<p>The venture may be particularly important in Alzheimer''s
research. Since 1998, there have been more than 100 attempts to
develop a treatment, and all have failed. The last two years
have featured setbacks by Pfizer and Johnson  Johnson. Sanofi (SAN)
Chief Executive Officer Chris Viehbacher has said his company
won''t pursue therapies there because the science isn''t advanced
enough to justify the risks and cost to develop a drug. </p>
<p>We are going to try to increase the odds of picking the
right targets to go after for the next generation of drug
development,'''' Francis Collins, the NIH director, said today at
a press conference in Washington. We want to pick them at the
very beginning of the development process and thus avoid wasting
precious time and money chasing down drugs. </p>
<p>The companies and the NIH will split the $230 million cost
about equally, Collins said. </p>
<p>More than 5 million Americans suffer with Alzheimer''s
disease, and the number is expected to triple by 2050. The only
drugs approved for the condition ease symptoms for a few months
while the debilitating brain disease rampages on. Still, the
treatments generate more than $5 billion annually. </p>
<h2>Biomarker Research </h2>
<p>Research coordinated by the NIH will include collecting
tissue samples from thousands of patients to look for common
biomarkers that might be good targets for new drugs, the
agency said in a statement. The first projects are expected to
last three to five years, and may lead to collaborations on
other diseases if the research is successful, NIH said. </p>
<p>The coordinated effort rallies scientific key players of
the innovation ecosystem in a more unified way, Mikael Dolsten, president of worldwide research and development for New
York-based Pfizer, said in a statement. </p>
<p>Rupert Vessey, senior vice president at Whitehouse Station,
New Jersey-based Merck  Co. (MRK), identified new, innovative ways to
develop drugs as the most critical health challenge facing the
industry. The collaboration will be important to unraveling
the mysteries of the diseases that cause suffering for
individuals and are a burden to our society, he said in an e-mail. </p>
<h2>AbbVie, Biogen </h2>
<p>Other companies involved are AbbVie Inc., Biogen Idec Inc. (BIIB),
Bristol-Myers Squibb Co., GlaxoSmithKline Plc (GSK), JJ (JNJ), Sanofi and
Takeda Pharmaceutical Co. The U.S. Food and Drug Administration
will also participate, as well as nonprofit advocacy groups
representing patients suffering from the diseases, the
government said. </p>
<p>We exited mental illness and largely Alzheimer''s about
four years ago, but not because we weren''t interested in it, but
because we thought it was so difficult alone, said Lon Cardon,
senior vice president of alternative discovery and development
at London-based Glaxo. Now we''re interested in the Alzheimer''s
space because we can join forces. </p>
<p>The NIH is the largest source of funding for biomedical
research in the world, with an annual budget of more than $30
billion. Much of that money is consumed by basic research into
human biology and the study of the major causes of death,
including cancer and infectious diseases. </p>
<p>The agency expects to spend about $1.1 billion on diabetes
this year; $562 million on Alzheimer''s; $260 million on
arthritis and $109 million on lupus. The agency will spend $3.1
billion researching HIV and AIDS, by comparison, the most of any
single disease. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Erik Larson" date="Feb 04, 2014 11:58 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-04/jpmorgan-s-543-million-madoff-trustee-settlement-approve.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s $543 Million Madoff Trustee Settlement Approved</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s $543 million settlement with the trustee for Bernard Madoff''s defunct firm was approved by the judge overseeing its liquidation, ending a case in which thousands of investors accused the bank of turning a blind eye to the U.S.''s biggest Ponzi scheme. </p> <p>The accord, reached Jan. 7, was approved today by U.S. Bankruptcy Judge Stuart Bernstein in New York. The deal resolves a lawsuit by the trustee, Irving Picard, and two related class-action cases filed by Madoff victims who accused the bank of negligence. </p> <p>The settlements are fair, reasonable and in the best interest of the Madoff estate, Bernstein said. The deals provide substantial benefit to victims, he said. </p> <p>Related: Madoff Ex-Aides Seen Facing Hurdle With Duped'' Defense</p><p>With the JPMorgan deal, Picard''s recoveries for victims topped $10 billion, or 59 percent of the $17 billion in principal lost by thousands of customers in Madoff''s investment advisory business. Picard alleged the bank helped perpetuate Madoff''s scam for years by ignoring signs of fraud. </p> <p>Madoff deposited money from new customers into the account instead of investing it in securities, and made withdrawals to pay back earlier investors. The Ponzi scheme collapsed after Madoff''s confession and arrest in December 2008. </p> <p>Picard said New York-based JPMorgan, the biggest U.S. bank, ignored signs of wrongdoing to benefit financially from the con man''s business. </p> <h2>Class Actions </h2> <p>JPMorgan agreed to pay Picard $325 million to settle his lawsuit on behalf of thousands of victims, and another $218 million to resolve two related class-action lawsuits that were filed with Picard''s assistance after an appeals court barred him from bringing common-law claims against the bank. </p> <p>Picard had appealed the JPMorgan decision to the U.S. Supreme Court, which hasn''t decided whether it will hear the case. </p> <p>The amount of the accord indicated there was a value to the claims and the compromise made good sense, David Sheehan, a lawyer for Picard, said at today''s hearing. There is no guarantee Picard will win at the Supreme Court, Sheehan said. </p> <p>A group of about 200 Madoff victims who are net winners -- customers who withdrew more money from the scam than they deposited -- get nothing under the deal and have said in court filings they will sue the bank. They advised Bernstein in court papers that they were declining to be part of the JPMorgan accord. </p> <h2>Opting Out </h2> <p>You''re opting out of a class you''re not a member of -- sounds like a Groucho Marx joke, Bernstein said to a lawyer for the group at today''s hearing. </p> <p>Picard is pursuing claims totaling about $3.5 billion from UBS AG (UBSN), HSBC Holdings Plc (HSBA) and UniCredit SpA (UCG), which the trustee has also accused of benefiting from Madoff''s fraud. The banks have denied the claims. </p> <p>At the same time Picard reached the deal with JPMorgan, the bank agreed to pay $1.7 billion to the U.S. to resolve related criminal allegations, and $350 million in a case by the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency. </p> <p>The parallel efforts by the trustee and federal investigators have resulted in a total recovery for victims of almost $14 billion, or 82 percent of the lost principal. Picard has distributed about $4.9 billion to victims, with billions more held in reserve until legal issues are resolved. </p> <p>Madoff, 75, pleaded guilty to fraud in 2009 and is serving a 150-year sentence at a federal prison in North Carolina. At least seven others pleaded guilty, including his brother Peter Madoff, who is serving a 10-year term. </p> <h2>Picower Estate </h2> <p>Before the JPMorgan accord, Picard''s team had recovered $9.5 billion through lawsuits and out-of-court settlements, including $5 billion from the estate of Jeffry Picower, who began investing with Madoff in the 1970s. Picower, whom Picard called the biggest beneficiary of Madoff''s scheme, had a heart attack and drowned in a pool in Florida in October 2009. </p> <p>U.S. investigators had recovered about $2.3 billion for Madoff investors before reaching their deal with JPMorgan, including $2.2 billion from Picower''s estate and $100 million from Madoff''s Midtown Manhattan penthouse apartment and other belongings. The JPMorgan deal brings total U.S. recoveries to $4 billion -- a sum it will distribute through a separate process from the one used by Picard. </p> <p>The liquidation case is Securities Investor Protection Corp. v. Bernard L. Madoff Investment Securities LLC, 08-bk-01789, U.S. Bankruptcy Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ari Altstedter" date="Feb 05, 2014  5:18 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-05/goldman-sachs-maple-bond-increased-to-c-600-mln-from-c-350-mln.html"><headline>Goldman Almost Doubles Amount of Maples Bonds to C$600 Million</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. sold C$600
million ($541.5 million) of Canadian dollar-denominated debt in
the year''s initial sale of what are known as Maple bonds. </p>
<p>The New York-based bank, which had initially come to market
with C$350 million of notes, increased the size of its seven-year offering and priced the debt to yield 173 basis points over
benchmark Canadian government bonds, according to a term sheet
seen by Bloomberg News. </p>
<p>The coupon was 3.55 percent and the securities yielded
3.568 percent with ratings of Baa1 from Moody''s Investors
Service and A- from Standard  Poor''s. </p>
<p>The notes'' yielded more than the 2.3 percent average
effective yield in the Bank of America Merrill Lynch Single-A
U.S. Banking Index, where the average maturity is 6.1 years. </p>
<p>It was Goldman''s first Canadian issue since January 2013,
when it''s C$650 million of notes were sold with a coupon of
3.375 percent. </p>
<p>The Maple bond market, nicknamed for the nation''s maple-leaf flag, regained some investor acceptance after deal-making
froze in 2008 following government bailouts of banks that were
among the biggest issuers, reaching C$6 billion in 2012 and C$5
billion last year. </p>
<p>The Canadian subsidiary of Wells Fargo  Co., sold C$1.25
billion of seven year notes Jan. 23, with a coupon of 3.04
percent. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Editors: Chapin Wright" date="Feb 05, 2014 12:59 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-05/morgan-stanley-trims-2014-clo-forecast-on-volcker-rule-questions.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Trims 2014 CLO Forecast on Volcker Rule Questions</headline><body><![CDATA[
<h2>
By Kristen Haunss </h2>
<p>Feb. 5 (Bloomberg) - Morgan Stanley (MS) cut its collateralized
loan obligation forecast by as much as 27 percent to $55 billion
as issuance slowed last month because of questions about the
Volcker Rule''s impact on the funds that finance buyouts. </p>
<p>Five new-issue U.S. CLOs for $2.55 billion were sold in
January compared with 17 transactions for $9.04 billion in the
same month last year, Morgan Stanley said today in a report.
The New York-based bank lowered its 2014 forecast to $55 billion
to $65 billion, from its initial projection of $65 billion to
$75 billion, according to the report. </p>
<p>Issuance of CLOs surged 49 percent last year to $82
billion, the most since 2007, when $92.8 billion were arranged,
according to Royal Bank of Scotland Group Plc. A lack of
enthusiasm from AAA investors, the largest portion of a CLO,
because of the Volcker Rule''s unknown effects has led to a
slowdown in the pace of new issuance, Morgan Stanley said. </p>
<p>The most notable aspect of the CLO market has been
lackluster new issuance year-to-date, driven mainly by Volcker
Rule uncertainties, analysts led by Vishwanath Tirupattur
wrote in the report. </p>
<p>CLOs pool high-yield loans and slice them into debt
securities of varying risk and return, typically from AAA
ratings down to B. The lowest portion, known as the equity
tranche, offers the highest potential returns and the greatest
risk because investors are the first to see their interest
payouts reduced when loans backing the CLO default. </p>
<h2>Tightening Spreads </h2>
<p>CLO sales of deals backed by widely syndicated loans
plunged to $1.22 billion in 2009, the year after the collapse of
Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. precipitated the biggest financial
crisis since the Great Depression, according to Morgan Stanley
data. </p>
<p>Spreads on existing AAA CLO debt fell to 110 basis points
in December from a 2013 high of 130 basis points during the
first quarter, according to Morgan Stanley data. They rose to as
high as 725 basis points in April 2009 from a nine-year low of
23 basis points in 2007. A basis point is 0.01 percentage point. </p>
<p>The CLO new-issue market may remain sluggish until there
is regulatory/legislative relief from Volcker for existing
holdings of CLO tranches for banks or until clarity emerges
about the way forward for resolving Volcker compliance, the
analysts wrote. </p>
<p>Under Volcker, banks would not be able to own debt of CLOs
that are invested in bonds or other securitized products.
Industry groups including the Loan Syndications and Trading
Association submitted a proposal with alternatives to regulators
to clarify the language around ownership, according to the
report. An Interim Final Rule for Volcker released Jan. 14
didn''t provide any clarification or a reference to CLOs, Morgan
Stanley said. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Feb 05, 2014 11:35 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-05/goldman-sachs-currency-traders-cho-lim-said-to-depart.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Currency Traders Cho, Lim Said to Depart</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Steven Cho and Leland Lim, Goldman
Sachs (GS) Group Inc. partners in its currency-trading business, have
left the firm, according to a person briefed on the matter. </p>
<p>Cho was global head of spot and forward trading of G-10
currencies in New York, while Lim was co-head of macro trading,
which includes interest-rates and currencies, for Asia ex-Japan,
said the person, who asked to remain anonymous because the
departures weren''t public. Cho and Lim were both named partners
in 2010. </p>
<p>Regulators are probing whether traders at the world''s
largest banks colluded through instant-message groups to
manipulate benchmarks such as the WM/Reuters rates. Michael DuVally, a spokesman for New York-based Goldman Sachs, declined
to comment on whether the departures were related to any probe.
Cho didn''t return a call for comment, while Lim didn''t respond
to an e-mail. </p>
<p>Currency-trading revenue at the 10 largest global
investment banks declined 6 percent in the first nine months of
2013, according to industry analytics firm Coalition Ltd.
Goldman Sachs Chief Financial Officer Harvey Schwartz said the
currency business had difficulty managing inventory in the
third quarter as the firm posted its worst fixed-income trading
revenue since the financial crisis. </p>
<p>Cho worked under Guy Saidenberg, Goldman Sachs''s global
head of foreign-exchange trading, who remains in his role, the
person familiar with the matter said. Cho joined the firm in
1996 after previously working at Citigroup Inc., according to a
biography on the website of the nonprofit organization Apex for
Youth. </p>
<p>Dow Jones Newswire reported Cho''s departure earlier today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andy Hoffman and Hugh Son" date="Feb 05, 2014 11:03 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-05/jpmorgan-said-to-pick-mercuria-for-commodities-unit-sale.html"><headline>JPMorgan Said to Pick Mercuria for Commodities Unit Sale</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) entered
exclusive talks to sell its physical commodities unit to
Mercuria Energy Group Ltd. as the bank seeks to end a five-year
foray into owning and storing materials such as metals and oil,
according to two people briefed on the matter. </p>
<p>The bid from Geneva-based Mercuria beat offers from
Macquarie Group Ltd. (MQG) and Blackstone Group LP (BX), said one person,
who asked not to be identified because the discussions are
private. Blythe Masters, JPMorgan''s commodities chief, probably
won''t join Mercuria as part of the deal, which is still being
negotiated, the person said. </p>
<p>JPMorgan is selling the unit as regulators examine whether
catastrophic losses at federally backed banks could endanger the
financial system and lawmakers question whether firms have the
power to manipulate some prices. The Federal Reserve said in
July it might force insured lenders to get out of the business,
and New York-based JPMorgan agreed later that month to pay $410
million for claims that it manipulated power markets. </p>
<p>Spokesmen for Mercuria and JPMorgan declined to comment, as
did spokesmen for New York-based Blackstone and Sydney-based
Macquarie. Reuters reported on the exclusive talks earlier
today. </p>




Photographer: Peter Foley/Bloomberg

<p>
JPMorgan Chase  Co. is selling the unit as regulators examine whether catastrophic losses at federally backed banks could endanger the financial system and lawmakers question whether firms have the power to manipulate some prices. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Peter Burrows and Dina Bass" date="Feb 05, 2014 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-05/microsoft-gets-style-shift-with-nadella-replacing-ballmer.html"><headline>Microsoft Gets Style Shift With Nadella Replacing Ballmer</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Right from the start, new Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) Chief Executive Officer Satya Nadella is showing that he will operate differently from predecessor Steve Ballmer. </p> <p>On his first day leading the world''s largest software maker, Nadella, a 22-year Microsoft veteran who was yesterday named CEO, exuded an understated calm during a less than 20-minute webcast for customers and employees. Rather than the customary press conference, the 46-year-old used the event to introduce himself and take questions from Microsoft Vice President Susan Hauser. The first line in his memo to employees started with today is a very humbling day for me. </p> <p>That contrasts with Ballmer, who for 14 years as Microsoft CEO was famous for his oversized personality. Ballmer, 57, once jumped out of a cake at Microsoft''s 25th anniversary party at Seattle''s Safeco Field and ran through the crowd giving high-fives as if he''d won the Super Bowl. In a memo to employees yesterday, Ballmer said he was pumped. </p> <p>If jarring, the change in style will be one of the advantages of choosing Nadella as Microsoft''s third CEO, said David Yoffie, a professor at Harvard Business School. Ballmer''s aggressive salesmanship during the boom days of the personal-computer industry exemplified how Microsoft became the world''s most valuable company. Now the software maker needs a new approach as it plays catch-up in areas including tablets, smartphones and cloud services. </p> <p>Nadella''s obviously a deep technologist, and he''s going to bring that back to a Microsoft that hasn''t had it in the CEO office for years, Yoffie said. </p> <h2>Changing Guard </h2> <p>Nadella''s low-key manner is also a sign of a changing of the guard in technology, as larger-than-life founders and near-founders such as Ballmer leave the scene. As part of yesterday''s changes, Microsoft co-founder Bill Gates also stepped aside as chairman and was replaced by lead independent director John Thompson. </p> <p>Microsoft isn''t the only technology company that has hired a product-focused CEO in recent years. Yahoo! Inc. recruited engineer Marissa Mayer from Google Inc. in 2012 to be CEO, while networking-equipment maker Juniper Networks Inc. recently appointed Shaygan Kheradpir, who had built networks for Verizon Communications Inc. and others, as CEO. </p> <p>Opinion: Why Microsoft and Everyone Else Loves Indian CEOs</p><p>This industry goes through cycles, and we''re in a cycle where customers are looking for new products, Kheradpir said in an interview yesterday. It''s not a sales or a marketing thing right now. </p> <p>Microsoft''s decision to forgo a press conference on Nadella''s ascension may also be an effort to show that the business isn''t about one person or personality, said Carol Blymire, a communications consultant. Maybe we''ve come to the end of the era of the rock star technology CEO. </p> <p>Frank Shaw, a spokesman for Microsoft, declined to comment. </p> <h2>Employee Rally </h2> <p>At a rally with employees yesterday at the atrium in Studio D, one of the newer buildings at Microsoft''s corporate campus in Redmond, Washington, Nadella demonstrated some continuity with the Ballmer-Gates era. Amid a standing-room-only crowd, Nadella appeared with Gates and Ballmer, who have been Microsoft''s only other two CEOs. Nadella emphasized the importance of software and talked about how the company is moving into devices and cloud services, according to a person who attended. </p> <p>Yet Nadella also delivered a message that it was time for a change. In his e-mail to employees, he wrote, Our industry does not respect tradition -- it only respects innovation. Make no mistake, we are headed for greater places. </p> <h2>Basketball, Cricket </h2> <p>The differences between Ballmer and Nadella begin with their backgrounds. Nadella is an engineer with degrees in electrical engineering and computer science, as well as an MBA that he earned by taking weekend classes after he had started at Microsoft. Ballmer is an Ivy League-educated businessman who specialized in sales and marketing. </p> <p>The dissimilarities extend into the two men''s personal lives. Ballmer is known as a ferocious defender and rebounder on the basketball court. Nadella lists poetry as an interest and one of his favorite sports is cricket, which features scheduled tea breaks. </p> <p>He''s a thoughtful, quiet leader who rallies people around him, former Microsoft Chief Financial Officer John Connors said of Nadella. He works harder than anybody. He''ll make the tough calls but he''s very urbane and civil. </p> <h2>Ballmer''s Changes </h2> <p>Ballmer has made some changes in the past year that will help Nadella, said Will Poole, a former Microsoft vice president who left in 2008 and remains in close touch with the company. Last year, Ballmer discontinued a review system he had implemented that ranked each person in every work group on a bell curve, an approach that forced some employees to behave more politically. </p> <p>Ballmer also pushed through a major reorganization in July to break down walls at Microsoft. Rather than run their own discrete businesses, top executives now oversee functional areas, such as software and hardware engineering. </p> <p>Ballmer''s strained relationship with Wall Street also leaves Nadella plenty of room for improvement, said Daniel Ives, an analyst with FBR Capital Markets. </p> <p>Ballmer wasn''t hands on with the Street, said Ives, who has the equivalent of a hold rating on the stock. I expect Nadella to be a lot more front and center, because it''s needed. He needs to prove that his vision is right. </p> <p>Nadella will still work with Ballmer in the boardroom, where both are directors. Having Ballmer there may make it complicated for Nadella to undo major initiatives from his predecessor, Yoffie said. </p> <p>Communicating with his board will be as challenging in some ways as all the other challenges he''ll face with the external world, Yoffie said of Nadella. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore, Joel Rosenblatt and Patricia Hurtado" date="Feb 05, 2014 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-05/jpmorgan-joins-morgan-stanley-in-settling-u-s-mortgage-cases.html"><headline>JPMorgan Joins Morgan Stanley in Settling U.S. Mortgage Lawsuits</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) and JPMorgan Chase 
Co. (JPM) agreed to pay $1.86 billion to end U.S. accusations of
misconduct in their handling of home loans and related
securities that left taxpayers shouldering losses after the
financial crisis. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley said yesterday it reached a $1.25 billion
deal to end Federal Housing Finance Agency claims the bank sold
faulty mortgage bonds to Fannie Mae (FNMA) and Freddie Mac (FMCC) before the
firms'' losses pushed them into U.S. conservatorship. JPMorgan
will pay $614 million after admitting it submitted ineligible
loans for Federal Housing Administration and Veterans Affairs
insurance. </p>
<p>JPMorgan put profits ahead of responsibility by
recklessly churning out thousands of defective mortgage loans,
failing to inform the government of known problems with those
loans and leaving the government to cover the losses,
Manhattan U.S. Attorney Preet Bharara said in a statement. </p>
<p>The six largest U.S. lenders have allocated more than $114
billion since the financial crisis to cover legal expenses,
government probes and mortgage-related claims. Morgan Stanley''s
deal with the FHFA prompted the New York-based bank to book an
additional $150 million charge in the fourth quarter, reducing
earnings for the period by 5 cents a share. </p>




Photographer: Victor J. Blue/Bloomberg

<p>
Morgan Stanley, which disclosed its settlement in a regulatory filing yesterday, was among 18 banks sued by the FHFA in 2011. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Toluse Olorunnipa" date="Feb 05, 2014 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-05/disney-battles-casino-operators-over-florida-expansion.html"><headline>Adelson Takes On Disney in Florida Casino Battle</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>To bring Las Vegas-style gambling to
Florida, casino operators like Sheldon Adelson are sending more
than 100 lobbyists to the state Capitol to battle their biggest
adversary: Mickey Mouse. </p>
<p>The clash pits casino operators Genting Bhd. (GENT) and Las Vegas
Sands Corp. (LVS), controlled by billionaire Adelson, against Walt
Disney Co. (DIS), which runs theme parks and resorts near Orlando, and
may face new competition for convention business. Companies on
both sides of the dispute are sending lobbyists and campaign
checks to Florida lawmakers, who say they''ll consider expanding
gambling this year. </p>
<p>A state-commissioned study found that full-service casinos
and their associated hotels could generate $1.5 billion in
spending annually in Florida, making the fourth-most populous
state an attractive target for the gambling industry as it
pushes to expand in the U.S. The outcome is critical for Disney,
as the world''s largest entertainment company seeks to protect
its Walt Disney World Resort, which includes theme parks and
five convention facilities. </p>
<p>Gambling interests in Las Vegas and Atlantic City are
looking for new territory, and opening Florida to them would be
tremendous, said Robert Jarvis, who teaches gambling law at
Nova Southeastern University in Fort Lauderdale. The fear for
Disney is that instead of people going to Disney and dropping
their disposable income there, they''ll go to the destination
casinos and drop their money there. </p>




Photographer: Jerome Favre/Bloomberg

<p>
Sheldon Adelson, chairman and chief executive officer of Las Vegas Sands Corp., center, watches a traditional lion dance during the opening of the Sands Cotai Central resort in Macau, China. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Feb 06, 2014 12:21 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-06/goldman-sachs-energy-analyst-murti-retires-after-15-years.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Energy Analyst Murti Retires After 15 Years</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Arjun Murti, a Goldman Sachs (GS) Group
Inc. equity research analyst who covers oil companies including
Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) and ConocoPhillips, will retire after 15 years
at the firm. </p>
<p>Murti, a partner at the New York-based company who served
as co-head of equity research in the Americas, will become an
advisory director, according to an internal memo from Steve Strongin, head of global investment research. Leslie Shribman, a
Goldman Sachs spokeswoman, confirmed the memo and declined to
comment further. </p>
<p>Murti in March 2005 correctly predicted a super spike
in the price of oil, which almost tripled from that point to a
record $147.27 in July 2008. Exxon shares hit an all-time high
last December as Murti raised his rating to buy. </p>
<p>Over the course of his career, Arjun has distinguished
himself as a leading expert in the energy sector, Strongin
wrote in the memo. Murti will continue covering the integrated
oil and refining sectors while the firm makes plans for his
successor, according to the memo. </p>
<p>Murti joined Goldman Sachs in 1999 and was named partner in
2006. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Susan Decker" date="Feb 06, 2014 12:12 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-06/pfizer-wins-ruling-to-block-generic-lyrica-until-2018.html"><headline>Pfizer Wins Ruling to Block Generic Lyrica Until 2018</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc., the world''s biggest
drugmaker, won a court ruling that will block generic versions
of its No. 1 product, Lyrica, in the U.S. until December 2018. </p>
<p>Teva Pharmaceutical Industries Ltd. (TEVA), Actavis Plc (ACT) and Lupin
Ltd. (LPC) are among the generic-drug makers that would infringe a
valid patent on the pain medicine, the U.S. Court of Appeals for
the Federal Circuit in Washington said in an opinion today on
its website. The other generic-drug makers in the case were Sun
Pharmaceutical Industries Ltd., Wockhardt Ltd. and Mylan Inc. </p>
<p>Lyrica has become increasingly important to Pfizer''s
earnings since the New York-based company lost patent protection
on its cholesterol pill Lipitor, which once generated almost $13
billion a year. Sales of Lyrica, used to treat shingles,
fibromyalgia, epilepsy, and hot flashes, reached $4.6 billion
last year, accounting for 9 percent of Pfizer''s total revenue. </p>
<p>The appeal centered on a single aspect of a patent covering
the active ingredient, pregabalin. The generic-drug makers
argued that the patent didn''t adequately describe a new
invention, and was an obvious variation of other compounds. They
conceded that, if the patent claim was upheld, they had no
chance at winning on that or a second patent. </p>
<p>We perceive no error in the district court''s
construction of what the patent claim covers, the three-judge
panel wrote. </p>
<p>The case is Pfizer Inc. (PFE) v. Teva Pharmaceuticals USA Inc.,
12-1576, U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit
(Washington). The lower court case is Pfizer Inc. v. Teva
Pharmaceuticals USA Inc., 09cv307, U.S. District Court for the
District of Delaware (Wilmington). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Karin Matussek" date="Feb 06, 2014  9:59 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-06/goldman-s-dibelius-bafin-s-menke-to-testify-at-oppenheim-trial.html"><headline>Goldman''s Dibelius, Bafin''s Menke to Testify at Oppenheim Trial</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The head of Goldman Sachs (GS) Group
Inc.''s operations in Germany and the country''s second-highest
ranking bank regulator will testify at the trial of former
managers of Sal. Oppenheim Jr.  Cie this month. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs''s Alexander Dibelius will give evidence on
Feb. 12 at the tribunal in Cologne where the case is being
heard, according to the court''s witness list. Frauke Menke, the
head of banking supervision at Bafin, is scheduled to testify
Feb. 20, the same day as Thomas Middelhoff, the former chief
executive officer of Bertelsmann AG. </p>
<p>The former Sal. Oppenheim managers are charged with breach
of trust over bad investments, including property deals
prosecutors say resulted in about 150 million euros ($204
million) of losses. The court is also reviewing loans to
Arcandor AG (ARO), a German retailer which went bankrupt in 2009, in
the trial, which began last year. </p>
<p>Ben Fisher, a spokesman for Bafin, said he didn''t know what
Menke''s testimony would be about. A spokesman for the Cologne
court, Achim Hengstenberg, said he couldn''t comment on the
subject of the testimony. The court is reviewing allegations
over the Arcandor investment at the moment, he said. </p>
<p>Sal. Oppenheim put itself up for sale after reporting a
2008 loss of 117 million euros, its first yearly loss since
World War II, from investments in real estate and companies.
Deutsche Bank AG bought the family-run lender, founded in 1789,
for its wealth-management operations. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Barinka" date="Feb 06, 2014 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-06/ibm-to-spend-100-million-to-bring-watson-technology-to-africa.html"><headline>IBM to Spend $100 Million to Bring Watson Technology to Africa</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines Corp. (IBM)
is raising its bet on Africa by spending $100 million to bring
its Watson technology to the continent. </p>
<p>The world''s biggest computer-services provider plans to
introduce Watson, an artificial-intelligence system best known
for beating humans on the Jeopardy! game show, to government
agencies, universities, scientists and other partners in Africa
to process socioeconomic information, the company said in a
statement. It will also establish a research center to help
advance a 10-year IBM initiative to spur development. </p>
<p>The moves are part of an effort by Chief Executive Officer
Ginni Rometty to make the continent into a growth engine for
IBM, which has reported seven consecutive quarters of falling
revenue. Last year''s 5 percent sales decline in its traditional
growth markets of Brazil, Russia, India and China helped drag
down total revenue. </p>
<p>In Africa, we''re getting more partners and we''re helping
the economic development, Solomon Assefa, an IBM researcher,
said in an interview. Africa is really moving forward. We
believe that this investment reflects that it''s also a very good
business decision. </p>
<p>IBM will be expanding its investment in Watson as the
Armonk, New York-based company looks to data analytics to boost
growth. IBM said last month that it will spend $1 billion to
create a new division around Watson, which analyzes troves of
data and can answer questions in conversational language. </p>
<h2>Research Center </h2>
<p>Last year, the company opened a research laboratory in
Nairobi, Kenya, its 12th in the world. In 2013, IBM had
operations in more than 20 African countries, up from four in
2006. </p>
<p>Watson can analyze large amounts of data after the
information is uploaded to the tool. Assefa said IBM''s new
research center, the Center of Excellence for Data-Driven
Development, will serve as a central point for universities,
government agencies and other partners to upload data. Assefa
declined to comment on partners for the project. </p>
<p>Health care and education will be two initial focus areas
for which IBM intends to deploy the Watson technology, he said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alison Vekshin" date="Feb 06, 2014 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-06/goldman-workers-back-kashkari-bid-for-california-governor.html"><headline>Goldman Workers Back Kashkari Bid for California Governor</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)''s current
and former employees, including former U.S. Treasury Secretary
Henry Paulson, have helped Republican Neel Kashkari raise almost
$1 million in his bid for California''s governorship. </p>
<p>Kashkari, a former Goldman vice president who as a Treasury
official managed the $700 billion rescue of the U.S. banking
system, reported $976,000 in contributions since announcing his
candidacy on Jan. 21. The donations included $79,400 from
Goldman employees and $54,400 from Paulson and his wife, Wendy,
according to a filing yesterday with the California Secretary of
State. </p>
<p>Our campaign''s robust fundraising in these first two
weeks underscores Neel''s strength as a candidate, and it will
help ensure that we have the resources necessary to share with
voters his vision for turning California around, Pat Melton,
Kashkari''s campaign manager, said in a statement. </p>
<p>Kashkari, 40, is running in California''s June 3 primary,
where the top two vote-getters, regardless of party, advance to
the November general election. Also running for governor is
Republican state Assemblyman Tim Donnelly, 47, who raised
$374,000 last year. </p>
<p>Governor Jerry Brown, a Democrat who hasn''t said whether
he''ll seek another term, has $17 million in campaign funds from
donors including Exxon Mobil Corp., Facebook Inc. (FB) and Microsoft
Corp., as well as porn mogul Larry Flynt. </p>
<p>Brown was elected in 2010 after having previously served as
governor from 1975 to 1983. Prior to his second stint as
California''s chief executive, he also was elected mayor of
Oakland and the state''s attorney general. </p>
<h2>Equity Work </h2>
<p>After his work in the Troubled Asset Relief Program under
Paulson, Kashkari joined Pacific Investment Management Co. in
Newport Beach, California, in 2009, where he led the world''s
largest bond fund''s expansion into equities. He left in January
2013 and has said he spent the past year meeting with almost 700
potential donors from around the U.S. </p>
<p>Paulson, a former chief executive officer at New York-based
Goldman Sachs, and his wife each gave the maximum individual
contribution of $27,200 under California law. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs employees who donated to Kashkari''s campaign
include George C. Lee, II, listed as an executive living in
Tiburon, California, who gave $27,200; Jon Woodruff, a banker
from Menlo Park, California, who donated $27,200; and Andrew Gordon, an investment banker from Los Angeles, who gave $5,000. </p>
<p>Former Goldman Sachs employee Matthew L''Heureux of
Kentfield, California, gave $9,000 and O''Malley Miller, a
partner at the law firm Munger, Tolles  Olson LLP, who has
represented Goldman Sachs, gave $10,000, according to the
campaign filing. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Katia Dmitrieva" date="Feb 07, 2014  4:41 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-07/jpmorgan-hires-levy-roach-moves-to-transcanada-vlaad-says.html"><headline>JPMorgan Hires Levy, Roach Moves to TransCanada, Vlaad Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Robert Winslow left his agriculture
analyst role at National Bank of Canada to join Bank of
Montreal''s asset management unit as vice president and director
of research, according to Vlaad  Co., a Toronto-based financial
services recruiting firm. </p>
<p>Other moves in the Bill''s Buzz weekly newsletter
include: </p>
<p>* JPMorgan Chase  Co. hired Jason Levy for its investment
banking team in Toronto from Canaccord Genuity Group Inc. where
he was an associate. </p>
<p>* Canadian Imperial Bank of Commerce added analyst Michael Liu
to its diversified and telecom, media, technology team. </p>
<p>* Mo Gulamhusein left CIBC to join the consumer retail group at
Ontario Teachers'' Pension Plan. </p>
<p>* Andre Uddin was hired as managing director of research and
healthcare at Mackie Research Capital Corp. </p>
<p>* Azza Abdallah, former chief compliance officer at Global
Maxfin Capital Inc., left to join KPMG LLP''s corporate finance
team. </p>
<p>* Sam Roach, formerly an energy services research associate at
Royal Bank of Canada moved to TransCanada Corp. as a business
development analyst. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Feb 07, 2014  4:02 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-07/morgan-stanley-said-to-add-four-managers-to-operating-committee.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Said to Expand Operating Committee to 16</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley, owner of the world''s
largest brokerage, named four executives to its operating
committee, including fixed-income trading co-heads Michael Heaney and Robert Rooney, a person briefed on the move said. </p>
<p>Shelley O''Connor, who runs the New York-based firm''s
private bank, and Andy Saperstein, head of the brokerage''s
investment products and services unit, were also added to the
committee, bringing it to 16 members, said the person, who asked
to remain anonymous because the decision wasn''t yet public. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer James Gorman, 55, has signaled his
commitment to the fixed-income trading unit as some rivals have
exited large parts of the business. Gorman has also identified
higher profit margins at the brokerage and an increase in
lending to clients through the private bank as major parts of
his strategy to boost Morgan Stanley''s return on equity. </p>
<p>These appointments reflect the importance to the firm of
the businesses these individuals run and the leadership role
each plays in driving our firm strategy and our future
success, Gorman wrote in an internal memo, according to the
person. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s operating committee is the highest group
of managers at the bank, helping Gorman set its strategy. The
firm said in its proxy letter to investors that it views the
committee''s members as highly talented executives capable of
rotating among the leadership positions of our businesses and
key functions. </p>
<h2>Salary Boost </h2>
<p>The bank last year raised the base salary to at least $1
million for all the committee members, who must must agree not
to sell 75 percent of equity awards granted during their service
on the committee. </p>
<p>Heaney and Rooney became co-heads of the fixed-income unit
last year after Ken deRegt left to join hedge-fund firm Canarsie
Capital Group. Morgan Stanley (MS) has set a goal of a 10 percent
return on equity for that business, and Chief Financial Officer
Ruth Porat said last week that the unit offers opportunities for
profit beyond that target. </p>
<p>O''Connor, 53, has run the private bank for more than three
years, helping the company boost lending to its 4 million
brokerage clients. Morgan Stanley has said it wants 10 percent
of its customers to have loans with the firm, up from the
current 5 percent. Gorman said the company can generate about 3
percent yield from lending its rising deposits, compared with
the 0.3 percent it gets from investing in short-term securities. </p>
<p>Saperstein, 47, who followed Gorman to Morgan Stanley from
Merrill Lynch  Co. in 2006, took over the investment products
and services group in 2012. He has sought to boost connections
between the brokerage and the investment bank, and Morgan
Stanley said last year it had 35 such initiatives. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hugh Son and Silla Brush" date="Feb 07, 2014  1:06 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-07/jpmorgan-s-masters-said-to-withdraw-from-cftc-advisory-panel.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Masters Said to Quit CFTC Panel After One Day</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Blythe Masters, JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s commodities head, withdrew from an advisory committee of the U.S. Commodity Futures Trading Commission a day after her appointment was disclosed, according to two people with direct knowledge of the decision. </p> <p>The regulator may include another executive from New York-based JPMorgan on the global markets committee, said one person close to the bank who requested anonymity because the move hasn''t been publicly announced. Masters, 44, stepped down because the company''s sale of its physical commodities unit will keep her occupied, the person said. </p> <p>JPMorgan is selling a division that deals in assets such as metals and oil, as government watchdogs examine whether federally backed lenders should be involved in such markets. Masters''s appointment drew criticism from Twitter users who questioned the propriety of her advising the regulator of futures and swaps. </p> <p>Masters, whose name appeared on a list of committee members on the CFTC''s website yesterday, had been scheduled to participate in a Feb. 12 meeting to discuss cross-border guidance on rules. She was invited to the panel by acting Chairman Mark Wetjen, said one of the people. Her name has since been removed from the list. </p>




Photographer: Joshua Roberts/Bloomberg

<p>
Blythe Masters, managing director and head of the global commodities group at JPMorgan Chase  Co., in Washington, D.C., in this Dec. 2, 2009 file photo. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarika Gangar" date="Feb 07, 2014 12:43 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-07/ibm-leads-25-rise-in-bond-offerings-in-rush-to-beat-jobs-report.html"><headline>IBM Leads 25% Rise in Bond Offerings in Rush to Beat Jobs Report</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines Corp. (IBM)
and BP Plc led a 25 percent jump in U.S. company bond sales this
week as borrowers rushed to lock in yields at about a seven-month low before a labor report today that showed employers
added fewer jobs than economists projected. </p>
<p>IBM, the world''s biggest computer-services provider, and
London-based BP led $23.8 billion of offerings that rose from
$19.1 billion in the five days ended Jan. 31, according to data
compiled by Bloomberg. Issuance compares with $24.3 billion in
the first week of February 2013 and follows $140.8 billion of
sales last month. </p>
<p>Offerings increased as companies sought to borrow before
the report on employment growth that MFR economist Joshua
Shapiro said might be a crapshoot. Payrolls rose 113,000 in
January, the Labor Department said, less than the 180,000 median
forecast of economists in a Bloomberg survey. Investors are
watching for signs of weakness in the world''s biggest economy
amid a rout in emerging markets from Argentina to Turkey. </p>
<p>In any given month, it''s the date on the calendar that
issuers are most mindful about assessing, Edward Marrinan, a
macro credit strategist at RBS Securities in Stamford,
Connecticut, said before the report. Weak jobs numbers give a
lot of people a lot of reasons to get anxious about the growth
story. </p>
<h2>Assessing Growth </h2>
<p>The extra yield investors demand to own corporate bonds
rather than government debentures reached 193 basis points
yesterday, unchanged from Jan. 31, according to the Bank of
America Merrill Lynch U.S. Corporate  High Yield Index. Yields
increased to 3.9 percent from 3.89 percent, and compare with a
record low 3.35 percent in May. Yields last week touched 3.84
percent, the lowest since June. </p>
<p>IBM sold $4.5 billion of bonds in four parts including $2
billion of 3.625 percent, 10-year notes to yield 95 basis points
more than similar-maturity Treasuries, Bloomberg data show. The
Armonk, New York-based company also issued $1.5 billion of five-year notes in fixed- and floating-rate portions and $1 billion
of two-year floaters. </p>
<p>BP, Europe''s second-largest oil company, issued $2.5
billion of bonds in three parts through its BP Capital Markets
unit, Bloomberg data show. The largest portion, $1.25 billion of
3.81 percent, 10-year securities, priced with a relative yield
of 115 basis points. </p>
<p>Sales of investment-grade debentures reached at least $17
billion, compared with $13.2 billion last week and a weekly
average of $21.9 billion in 2013, Bloomberg data show. Offerings
of speculative-grade bonds reached at least $6.8 billion,
compared with $6 billion last week and a weekly average of $7.2
billion last year. </p>
<p>Speculative-grade bonds are rated below Baa3 by Moody''s
Investors Service and lower than BBB- by Standard  Poor''s. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Heather Perlberg and Alexis Leondis" date="Feb 07, 2014 11:38 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-07/jpmorgan-said-to-offer-bad-debt-as-blackrock-plans-hsbc-sale-1-.html"><headline>JPMorgan Said to Offer Bad Debt as BlackRock Plans HSBC Sale</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>     Feb. 7 (Bloomberg) -- JPMorgan Chase  Co. is offering $390
million of non-performing loans as banks including HSBC Holdings
Plc and Regions Financial Corp. increasingly look to sell
troubled mortgage debt. </p>
<p>JPMorgan put the pool of debt, a portion of which is tied
to residential properties in New York, on the market this week,
said two people with knowledge of the offering, who asked not to
be named because the sale is private. HSBC hired BlackRock Inc.
to manage the potential sale of as much as $1 billion in
delinquent loans and Goldman Sachs Group Inc. is handling an
auction of about $700 million of modified loans for Regions,
according to two separate people. </p>
<p>Sales of the debt are accelerating amid financial
regulations that force banks to pledge more capital for some
assets they hold, including non-performing loans, or NPLs. The
government also is adding to the supply as it auctions the debt
to help prevent foreclosures and stem losses at the Federal
Housing Administration. </p>
<p>Banks have made a decision internally that a delinquent
borrower is not a core customer,Ashish Pandey, chief
executive officer of Altisource Residential Corp. (RESI), said at a
conference in Las Vegas last month. Pandey, whose firm had 6,300
delinquent loans as of the third quarter of 2013, said he
expects as many as 500,000 non-performing loans to sell in 2014. </p>




Photographer: Peter Foley/Bloomberg

<p>
A pedestrian passes by JPMorgan Chase  Co. offices in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Finbarr Flynn" date="Feb 09, 2014  5:14 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-09/jpmorgan-ge-sell-least-samurai-as-tight-spreads-deter-investors.html"><headline>JPMorgan, GE Sell Least Samurai as Tight Spreads Deter Investors</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) and General
Electric Co. (GE)''s finance arm had their smallest Samurai-bond sales
in more than nine years as a global stock rout damped investor
demand for debt that offered investors record-low yields. </p>
<p>General Electric Capital Corp. sold 55 billion yen ($536
million) in three-year fixed-rate, yen-denominated notes that
pay 0.313 percent on Feb. 6, while JPMorgan offered 48.5 billion
yen in a two-tranche deal, including three-year fixed-rate notes
offering 0.373 percent. Those rates are the lowest ever paid by
the companies on the yen-denominated debt, according to data
compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Japanese investors are wary of buying overseas debt
offering such low yields after concerns that the Chinese economy
is slowing and the impact from U.S. Federal Reserve stimulus
cuts triggered a selloff in emerging-market currencies and
global stocks. JPMorgan joined Morgan Stanley last week in
agreeing to pay $1.86 billion to settle U.S. accusations of
misconduct in their handling of home loans and related
securities that left taxpayers shouldering losses after the
global financial crisis. </p>
<p>Compared with notes from local issuers, Samurai bonds are
more exposed to overseas risk, said Yoshihiro Nakatani, a
Tokyo-based senior fund manager who oversees about 100 billion
yen of bonds at Asahi Life Asset Management Co. Spreads on
Samurai have fallen to unattractive levels, and it will be
difficult for Japanese investors to buy at the kind of rates
offered by JPMorgan and GE in future. </p>
<h2>Spread Unattractive'' </h2>
<p>Nakatani, who has invested in GE Capital''s debt in the
past, said he didn''t buy the Norwalk, Connecticut-based
company''s notes this time because the spread was
unattractive. He doesn''t invest in U.S. banks like JPMorgan
as they can be affected more by financial regulation, he said. </p>
<p>Tom Steiner, a London-based spokesman for GE Capital,
declined to comment on the company''s sale. Yukako Yoshino, a
spokeswoman for JPMorgan in Tokyo, also declined to comment. </p>
<p>JPMorgan last had a Samurai sale smaller than last week''s
in September 2004, when it issued 25 billion yen in notes,
following two bigger sales the same year, according to
Bloomberg-compiled data. General Electric hasn''t had a smaller
sale, according to the data going back to 1999. </p>
<p>GE Capital sold 95 billion yen of Samurai notes in
September, including 72.1 billion yen in debt also 10 basis
points over yen swaps. The spread on securities of the same
length offered last week declined to 4 basis points. A basis
point is 0.01 percentage point. </p>
<p>JPMorgan issued 105.6 billion yen of Samurai bonds in June,
including 51.5 billion yen in three-year notes at 10 basis
points over swaps, the same level as last week. </p>
<h2>Falling Spread </h2>
<p>The average spread on Samurais was at 41 basis points on
Feb. 6, the least since November 2007, according to Bank of
America Merrill Lynch index data. </p>
<p>GE is rated AA+ by Standard  Poor''s, its second-highest
ranking, and four levels above the A grade it gives JPMorgan.
SP lowered its outlook on JPMorgan to negative from stable in
June, saying that the likelihood of extraordinary government
support for the U.S. bank is waning. </p>
<p>The Topix index of Japanese shares has fallen 8.7 percent
this year after a 52 percent gain in 2013. The gauge rose on
Feb. 7 to pare a fifth straight week of losses. </p>
<p>Stock prices are falling and investors are worried, so
they aren''t going after credit investments, said Mana Nakazora, the chief credit analyst at BNP Paribas in Tokyo, in a
telephone interview. There''s very little incentive to make
investments at such low levels at a difficult time to assess
risk. </p>
<h2>Biggest Seller </h2>
<p>JPMorgan is the biggest U.S. seller of Samurai bonds since
the global financial crisis, issuing 426.7 billion yen of the
notes from 2008, according to data compiled by Bloomberg.
General Electric is the second largest, at 370.7 billion yen. </p>
<p>Issuers from Australia to Norway have raised about 370
billion yen via Samurai sales this year, up from 60 billion for
the entire first quarter of last year. National Australia Bank
Ltd. is the biggest issuer of the securities this year, having
sold 123.8 billion yen last month. Norway''s DNB Bank ASA sold
81.6 billion yen also in January. </p>
<p>Following the emerging-market shock, and possibility of
spreads widening for overseas names, there appears to have been
a feeling that there wasn''t a need to rush to buy GE Capital''s
Samurai this time, said Yusuke Ueda, a Tokyo-based credit
analyst at Bank of America Merrill Lynch. For JPMorgan, the
tone seems to have been a little different and the bank had
less of a need to sell Samurai debt, he said. </p>
<h2>Mortgage Settlement </h2>
<p>JPMorgan will pay $614 million after admitting it submitted
ineligible loans for Federal Housing Administration and Veterans
Affairs insurance, according to a statement on Feb. 4 by the
U.S. Justice Department. </p>
<p>The company said in a statement the same day that the
settlement represents another significant step in the firm''s
efforts to put historical mortgage-related issues behind it.
The bank separately agreed last year to pay $4 billion to settle
Federal Housing Finance Agency claims related to about $33
billion in mortgage bonds. </p>
<p>Under normal circumstances, JPMorgan probably would have
liked to sell a lot, lot more bonds at a premium of as little
as 10 basis points, said BNP''s Nakazora said. It''s litigation
risk has been very big. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Zajac and Cheyenne Hopkins" date="Feb 10, 2014  6:39 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-10/jpmorgan-s-13-billion-u-s-pact-seen-needing-court-review-1-.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s $13 Billion Accord Seen Needing Court Review</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s $13 billion
fraud settlement with the U.S. government should be blocked
until a court is able to review it, a Wall Street watchdog group
founded by an Atlanta hedge fund manager said. </p>
<p>Better Markets Inc. is seeking judicial scrutiny of the
accord because it''s the largest settlement with a single
entity in the 237-year history of the U.S., according to a
complaint filed today in Washington federal court. No one has
any ability to determine if the $13 billion agreement is fair
or if it is a sweetheart deal, the group said in the filing. </p>
<p>The accord, announced in November, settled allegations that
the biggest U.S. lender by assets misled investors and the
public when it sold bonds backed by faulty residential
mortgages. U.S. and state officials blamed JPMorgan''s actions
for helping to cause the credit crisis, and said the agreement
didn''t shield JPMorgan or its employees from possible charges. </p>
<p>The Justice Department acted as investigator, prosecutor,
judge, juror, sentencer and collector, Dennis Kelleher, chief
executive officer of Better Markets, said at a press conference
in Washington. The agreement was mostly designed to conceal,
not reveal. </p>
<p>Brian Marchiony, a spokesman for New York-based JPMorgan,
declined to comment on the complaint. </p>
<p>The department is confident that the settlement reached
with JPMorgan Chase complies with the law, Ellen Canale, a
Justice Department spokeswoman, said in an e-mailed statement. </p>
<h2>Financial Reform'' </h2>
<p>Better Markets describes itself as a nonprofit,
nonpartisan organization that promotes the public interest in
financial reform. It was founded by Michael Masters, founder
and managing member of Atlanta-based Masters Capital Management. </p>
<p>The group expects that its standing to bring the complaint
will be challenged, Kelleher said. </p>
<p>It will be hotly contested but I believe we have a solid
foundation to prove and demonstrate concrete and demonstrable
harm that give us ample standing to assert both the
constitutional claims and the statutory claims, Kelleher said. </p>
<p>If we do not, what that means is that no one in the
United States can ever challenge a backroom deal like this cut
by any attorney general, he said. </p>
<p>Better Markets'' standing derives from its public interest
purpose being thwarted by a lack of transparency in the
settlement process and the lack of a judicial forum in which
it could seek to participate to influence the outcome, the
group said in its complaint. </p>
<h2>Novel Claim'' </h2>
<p>The complaint doesn''t cite any precedents for challenges to
similar Justice Department settlements with banks. </p>
<p>I think it''s fair to call it a novel claim, driven by
uniquely damaging and far-reaching circumstances, Kelleher said
in a phone interview following his press conference. </p>
<p>At least one portion of the settlement, a $2 billion civil
penalty obtained under the Financial Institutions Reform,
Recovery and Enforcement Act of 1989, or FIRREA, explicitly
required a court to levy the sanction, according to the
complaint. </p>
<p>Better Markets also alleged that the Justice Department and
U.S. Attorney General Eric Holder have an apparent conflict of
interest because they have been criticized for failing to be
tough enough on large Wall Street firms and have aggressively
used the $13 billion agreement to try to restore their
reputations. </p>
<p>The settlement is a mere contract whereby JPMorgan
agreed to pay in exchange for complete civil immunity from DOJ
for years of pervasive, egregious and knowing alleged fraud and
other illegal conduct related to the worst financial crash in
the U.S. since 1929, according to the complaint. </p>
<p>The case is Better Markets Inc. v. U.S. Department of
Justice, 14-cv-00190, U.S. District Court, District of Columbia
(Washington). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Jacob" date="Feb 10, 2014  4:29 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-10/visa-ceo-says-china-delays-opening-card-payments-market.html"><headline>Visa CEO Says China Delays Opening Card-Payments Market</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Visa Inc. (V) Chief Executive Officer
Charlie Scharf said China isn''t opening as quickly as expected
to foreign payment processors and must be viewed as a five- to
15-year opportunity. </p>
<p>It''s going to take a long time for the market to actually
open up in a way that we actually do have that level playing
field, Scharf told analysts today in New York during an
industry conference sponsored by Keefe, Bruyette  Woods Inc. </p>
<p>Scharf plans to be in China next week and said the company
needs to understand why the market hasn''t become more open to
foreign firms. Visa, the world''s biggest bank-card network, has
been in talks with U.S. and local officials, Chinese banks and
China UnionPay Co., he said. UnionPay is a payment processor
founded in Shanghai by the State Council and central bank that
competes globally with Visa and MasterCard Inc. (MA) </p>
<p>Chinese law limits what Visa can do, Scharf said at his
company''s annual meeting in January. If you want to issue a
card locally in China, denominated in the local currency, it has
to be issued by a Chinese-owned company called China UnionPay,
said Scharf, 48. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Leslie Picker and Ari Levy" date="Feb 10, 2014  4:14 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-10/mobileiron-said-to-work-with-goldman-sachs-on-u-s-ipo.html"><headline>MobileIron Said to Work With Goldman Sachs on U.S. IPO</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>MobileIron Inc., whose software
helps companies protect data that employees access on
smartphones, is working with banks including Goldman Sachs Group
Inc. as it prepares for an initial public offering, people with
knowledge of the matter said. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley, Deutsche Bank AG and Barclays Plc are also
working on the IPO, said the people, asking not to be named
because the information is private. MobileIron plans to raise
about $150 million in the IPO, for a valuation of $1 billion to
$2 billion, the people said. </p>
<p>Demand for software that manages data on a variety of
mobile devices is growing as employees bring smartphones and
tablets from Apple Inc. to Google Inc. into the workplace,
instead of relying on company-issued devices made by BlackBerry
Ltd. MobileIron''s biggest competitor, AirWatch LLC, agreed to be
acquired last month by VMware Inc. (VMW) for $1.54 billion. </p>
<p>Sales of mobile-device management, or MDM, software could
reach $1.6 billion this year, compared with $784 million in
2012, according to forecasts by researcher Gartner Inc. Alvaro Monserrat, a vice president at Citrix, said at a conference in
December that the company''s primary competition in the MDM
market is coming from MobileIron and AirWatch, who are being
very aggressive on price. </p>
<p>We don''t have anything to share at this time, Clarissa
Horowitz, senior director of communications at Mountain View,
California-based MobileIron, said by e-mail about plans for an
IPO. Spokesmen for Goldman Sachs, Morgan Stanley, Deutsche Bank
and Barclays declined to comment on the MobileIron IPO. </p>
<p>MobileIron, founded in 2007, has raised about $150 million
from venture investors including Sequoia Capital, Norwest
Venture Partners, Foundation Capital and Institutional Venture
Partners. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Feb 10, 2014  4:09 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-10/goldman-partners-exercise-77-million-of-2008-options.html"><headline>Goldman Partners Exercise $77 Million of 2008 Options</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) partners
exercised options awarded at the end of 2008, benefiting from a
doubling in the firm''s stock price since the financial crisis. </p>
<p>Sixty-four partners exercised options last month that
yielded them $77 million in shares, after covering the cost of
the options and some tax withholding, according to a Feb. 7
regulatory filing. Gregory A. Agran, who runs the New York-based
firm''s commodities unit, received $7.1 million of stock, while
Steve Strongin, 55, head of global investment research, netted
$4 million. </p>
<p>In December 2008, Goldman Sachs granted 36 million options
in an effort to give top performers an incentive to stay after
the bank reduced pay costs by almost half during the financial
crisis. That grant was more than five times the number of
options the firm awarded in the three previous years. </p>
<p>The options show that Wall Street employees received
substantial awards even after the largest U.S. banks accepted
government support amid the worst credit crisis since the Great
Depression. They also echo regulators'' desire to have bonuses
tie employee incentives to the long-term performance of the
bank, as partners have had to wait more than five years to reap
the gains. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
A trader works in the Goldman Sachs Group Inc. booth on the floor of the New York Stock Exchange. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Charles Mead and Alex Barinka" date="Feb 10, 2014  3:52 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-10/ibm-pays-up-for-new-debt-as-revenue-contracts-corporate-finance.html"><headline>IBM Pays More to Borrow in Bond Market as Sales Decline</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines Corp. (IBM)''s borrowing costs are rising even as those of its peers fall, underscoring concerns that the world''s largest seller of computer services is struggling to find its place in the cloud. </p> <p>IBM sold 10-year bonds last week with a 3.625 percent coupon, exceeding the cost of similar-maturity 3.375 percent notes issued in July even as average yields for debt in the company''s AA rating tier contracted. Quarterly revenue dropped 5.5 percent in the last three months of 2013 to $27.7 billion, the biggest decline since the U.S. economy exited its last recession, as an industrywide shift to offsite data storage erodes demand for IBM''s hardware. </p> <p>Big Blue Tries to Adapt. Again.</p><p>It''s an early signal that bondholders want a slightly larger premium to hold IBM because of the disappointing results, the challenges it''s facing in the hardware business and favoring shareholder returns over improving balance-sheet fundamentals, said Nikhill Patel, an analyst at San Antonio-based Frost Investment Advisors LLC, which oversees about $10 billion and doesn''t own IBM bonds. </p> <h2>Druckenmiller Short </h2> <p>Debt investors are demanding higher interest rates about two months after money manager Stan Druckenmiller said he''s betting against the stock of IBM, the only company in the Dow Jones Industrial Average (INDU) to deliver a loss to shareholders last year. The century-old Armonk, New York-based business has attempted to support its equity by selling assets, using tax havens and repurchasing shares, which has coincided with an increase in its ratio of debt to cash flow. </p>




Photographer: Ben Torres/Bloomberg

<p>
IBM is increasing its bet on the cloud with a plan to invest $1.2 billion in its SoftLayer Technologies Inc. network-infrastructure business. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Feb 10, 2014  2:36 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-10/goldman-sachs-names-varadhan-co-head-of-trading-unit.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Names Varadhan Co-Head of Trading Unit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc., the U.S.
bank most reliant on trading, named Ashok Varadhan as the third
co-head of that division. </p>
<p>Varadhan, the 41-year-old chief of macro trading, joins
Pablo Salame and Isabelle Ealet in running the securities
division, according to an internal memo obtained today by
Bloomberg News. Michael DuVally, a spokesman for the New York-based firm, confirmed the memo''s contents. </p>
<p>Varadhan will help run the business that generates the most
revenue and profit among Goldman Sachs''s segments and that has
produced many of its top officers. He takes over as the trading
unit faces constraints from new capital rules and has seen
declines in revenue in three of the past four years. </p>
<p>He joined Goldman Sachs in swap trading in 1998, and was
named a partner at age 30 four years later. He was chosen to run
North American interest-rate products in 2001 and became head of
foreign exchange in 2007. </p>
<p>As a long-tenured leader in the securities division,
Ashok has demonstrated dedication to our clients and a deep
understanding of our business, Chief Executive Officer Lloyd C. Blankfein and President Gary D. Cohn wrote in the memo. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs generated $15.7 billion in revenue from
equity and fixed-income trading in 2013, down 13 percent from a
year earlier. While it set a Wall Street record for trading
revenue in 2009 as other firms took longer to recover from the
financial crisis, Goldman Sachs has been passed by fixed-income
giants JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) and Citigroup Inc. </p>




Photographer: Ron Antonelli/Bloomberg

<p>
Goldman Sachs Group Inc. headquarters stand in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Stefania Bianchi" date="Feb 10, 2014  6:47 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-10/morgan-stanley-predicts-billion-dollar-gulf-ipos-on-market-rally.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Predicts Billion-Dollar Gulf IPOs on Rally</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley, owner of the world''s biggest brokerage, is predicting the return of initial public offerings worth more than $1 billion in the Persian Gulf after asset values and stock markets rallied. </p> <p>We expect to see two to three billion dollar-plus IPOs in the second half of this year out of the Gulf region, Klaus Froehlich, head of investment banking for Morgan Stanley in the Middle East and North Africa, said yesterday in an interview at the bank''s Dubai offices, declining to say if it was involved in any deals. It''s a renaissance of the local IPO market. </p> <p>Dubai''s benchmark index, the world''s best-performing stock measure in 2014, surpassed 4,000 points yesterday for the first time in five years as economic growth and rising oil prices drive demand for assets in the region. Qatar Petroleum raised 3.2 billion riyals ($879 million) last month selling shares in its Mesaieed Petrochemical Holding unit, while Dubai-based Damac Real Estate Development Ltd. generated $348 million in December through the sale of global depositary receipts in London. </p> <p>Government-related entities and large family companies are returning to equity markets after a five-year hiatus, according to Froehlich. Some older deals are being revived because of better trading conditions and risk appetite, he said. </p> <p>Valuations and volatility are at a good place right now so we''re in a sweet spot, he said. We''ve actually been in this sweet spot for about a year in this region, but people are finally recognizing this and want to do something about it. </p> <h2>DFM Doubles </h2> <p>The DFM General Index more than doubled last year, outperforming all benchmark measures in the 50 largest equity markets globally on a dollar basis, pushing valuations to near a five-year high, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. Shares in Dubai rose 1 percent yesterday, taking this year''s gains to 18 percent. </p> <p>Arabtec Holding, the largest listed construction contractor in the United Arab Emirates, said yesterday it will set up Arabtec Capital in the Dubai International Financial Centre to provide financial and public offering services. </p> <p>The six-member Gulf Cooperation Council generated IPOs valued at $1.1 billion last year, compared with $15.4 billion in 2007 before the financial crisis, data compiled by Bloomberg show. </p> <h2>DP World </h2> <p>Port operator DP World Ltd., a unit of Dubai World, raised $4.96 billion in November 2007 in the Middle East''s largest IPO. That offering was 15 times oversubscribed and the last such deal valued at more than $1 billion in the United Arab Emirates. Since then, the region''s largest IPOs have been in Saudi Arabia, where foreign investors can''t invest directly. </p> <p>Saudi Arabian Mining Co., the metals and minerals producer known as Ma''aden, raised $2.47 billion after selling a 50 percent stake to the Saudi public in July 2008. Zain Saudi Arabia, a unit of Kuwait-based Mobile Telecommunications Co. completed a $1.9 billion share sale in February 2008, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p> <p>Qatar Petroleum''s Mesaieed offering was the country''s biggest share sale since Vodafone Qatar QSC raised $928 million in 2009, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. Damac''s sale was the first IPO by a Dubai-based developer since the sheikhdom''s property crash in 2008 and followed the London listings of Abu Dhabi-based health-care providers Al Noor Hospitals Group Plc in June and NMC Health Plc in 2012. </p> <p>Often companies that are looking at an IPO of a larger size initially look at going abroad to get the international recognition and potentially more flexibility on pricing, Froehlich said. But people are also very conscious of where they come from which means many are also looking at dual listings. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Schneider" date="Feb 11, 2014  6:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-11/exxon-mobil-new-zealand-unit-not-liable-for-clean-up.html"><headline>Exxon Mobil New Zealand Unit Not Liable for Clean Up</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM)''s New Zealand unit
isn''t liable for the cost of cleaning up waterfront land it
leased in Auckland partly because the country has no laws to
deal with the issue, a judge ruled. </p>
<p>The Auckland Waterfront Development Agency, which is
undertaking New Zealand''s biggest urban revitalization project,
sought NZ$10 million ($8.3 million) from Mobil Oil New Zealand
Ltd. to pay for the cost of the clean up in the area known as
Wynyard Quarter, according to the ruling. </p>
<p>Mobil Oil operated a bulk fuel storage and distribution
center at the site since the 1950s, leaving the properties
heavily contaminated when it ceased operations in 2011, the
judge said. The contamination was caused by Mobil''s own
operations as well as what was left by previous oil company
tenants and what had spread from neighbors, such as a 1.8
million liter spill of jet fuel by a Royal Dutch Shell Plc (RDSA) unit
in 1986, the judge said. </p>
<p>Unlike a number of other countries, New Zealand has no
specific legislation dealing with liability for historic
contaminated sites, High Court Justice Sarah Katz wrote in the
Feb. 7 decision, posted on the court''s website today. </p>
<p>Mobil acted reasonably, leaving the property in a condition
suitable to be taken over by another industrial tenant, Katz
said. </p>
<p>When it signed the last lease in 1985, there was no
realistic possibility of the land being used for commercial or
residential purposes, the judge wrote. It was not until a
further plan change became operative in 2010 that there were
concrete provisions to develop the Wynyard Quarter. </p>
<p>The area is now being developed to include a mix of
residential, retail and commercial uses, while retaining
existing marine and fishing industry uses, the judge said. </p>
<p>The case is between Auckland Waterfront Development Agency
Ltd. and Mobil Oil New Zealand Ltd. 2014-NZHC-84. High Court of
New Zealand (Auckland). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Barbara Powell" date="Feb 11, 2014  3:25 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-11/exxon-baton-rouge-plant-said-to-shut-hydrocracker-next-week.html"><headline>Exxon Baton Rouge Plant Said to Shut Hydrocracker Next Week</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM)''s refinery in
Baton Rouge, Louisiana, will shut a hydrocracker next week for
about two weeks of planned work, two people familiar with
operations said. </p>
<p>The refinery currently has an alkylation unit shut for
repairs, said the people, who asked not to be identified because
the information is not public. </p>
<p>Hydrocrackers convert heavy feedstocks into lighter fuels
such as high-octane gasoline and diesel. Alkylation units work
with catalytic crackers to make high-octane gasoline blending
components. </p>
<p>Todd Spitler, a spokesman for Exxon in Fairfax, Virginia,
and Jennifer Hughes and Stephanie Cargile, spokeswomen for the
refinery in Baton Rouge, didn''t immediately respond to requests
for comment. </p>
<p>The Baton Rouge refinery can process 503,500 barrels of
crude oil a day, according to data compiled Bloomberg. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tina Davis" date="Feb 11, 2014 12:34 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-11/chevron-says-one-missing-after-well-fire-in-pennsylvania.html"><headline>Chevron Says One Missing After Well Fire in Pennsylvania</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX) said one person was
hospitalized and another is missing after a fire at a well in
Greene County, Pennsylvania. </p>
<p>The fire was reported at about 6:45 a.m. local time at the
Lanco Unit 7H well, the Houston-based company said in a
statement on its website today. Emergency personnel responded
and are containing the fire, the company said. </p>
<p>Drilling began on the horizontal well south of Pittsburgh
on March 15, 2012, according to state data records. </p>
<p>Chevron owned the third-largest acreage in the Marcellus
shale as of the third quarter, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. Production of natural gas from the Marcellus, helped
by hydraulic fracturing and horizontal drilling, was expected to
exceed 13 billion cubic feet a day in December, up from less
than 2 billion cubic feet in 2010, the Energy Information
Administration said. </p>
<p>Five horizontal rigs targeting gas were in Greene County as
of Feb. 7, data compiled by oil-field services company Baker
Hughes Inc. show. All them drill development wells 5,000 feet to
10,000 feet deep, the company''s website shows. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrea Wong" date="Feb 11, 2014 12:25 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-11/goldman-currency-strategist-stolper-leaving-to-form-venture.html"><headline>Goldman Currency Strategist Stolper Leaving to Form Venture</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Thomas Stolper, chief currency
strategist at Goldman Sachs Group Inc., said he will be leaving
the firm by early March to set up a venture. </p>
<p>Stolper, 45, who joined Goldman in 1999 and became chief
foreign-exchange strategist in 2009, said in a telephone
interview that the enterprise will be foreign exchange related. </p>
<p>The London-based managing director said this week the
dollar will disappoint analysts expecting a broad rally in the
currency versus major peers as a tapering of Federal Reserve
stimulus isn''t improving the U.S.''s interest-rate advantage. The
U.S. currency was little changed at $1.3652 per euro at 12:24
p.m. in New York. </p>
<p>Stolper correctly predicted the greenback''s slide against
the euro in 2013, and forecasts the U.S. currency will drop to
$1.40 in six months. That compares with analysts'' median
estimates for a rise to $1.31 by the end of June, and $1.30 by
the end of the third quarter, according to Bloomberg surveys of
economists. </p>
<p>During his tenure at the firm, Thomas has developed many
analytical tools that have become a reference point for
institutional investing clients globally, Dominic Wilson,
chief markets economist, and Francesco Garzarelli, co-head of
macro and markets research, said in an internal memo obtained by
Bloomberg News. He has also helped to elevate the profile of
Global Markets Research and has served as a mentor to many of
his colleagues. </p>
<p>Michael DuVally, a spokesman for the New York-based bank,
confirmed the memo''s contents and declined to comment further. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jesse Riseborough and Maria Kolesnikova" date="Feb 11, 2014 11:55 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-11/morgan-stanley-s-richardson-quits-to-start-commodity-consultants.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley''s Richardson Quits to Start Commodity Consultants</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS)''s chief metals
economist Peter Richardson has left the bank after almost five
years in the role to start his own research and advisory group. </p>
<p>Metallum Commodity Consulting Ltd. will advise investors in
North America, Europe, Australia and South Africa on trends in
metals and bulk commodity markets. </p>
<p>The collective memory of the financial industry,
particularly in relation to commodity cycles, appears to me to
be shrinking if not disappearing altogether, Richardson, 66,
said today by phone. There''s a strong role to be had for
people with experience who are in a position to provide that
guidance based on a much longer timeframe than many in the
investment banking industry are aware of. </p>
<p>Commodity prices rose almost fourfold in the decade through
2011 on Chinese demand. The Standard  Poor''s GSCI Index of 24
raw materials posted the first drop since 2008 last year as bear
markets extended from corn to gold to copper. Citigroup Inc.
says the so-called super-cycle of rising demand has ended and
Goldman Sachs Group Inc. said last month a reversing cycle will
eventually drive raw materials into a structural bear market. </p>
<p>Richardson, a three-decade veteran of working with the
commodity and mining industry, has held roles at Deutsche Bank
AG, UBS AG and Macquarie Group Ltd. Based in Melbourne, he left
Morgan Stanley at the end of last month. Larissa Haida, a
spokeswoman for the bank in London, declined to comment. </p>
<p>It will essentially be a bespoke service for a very
limited number of clients who want in-depth advice on investment
activity both in equities and in underlying commodities, he
said. I will be offering similar services for corporates on a
bespoke basis for a limited number of commodities in which I
think I have a particular depth of expertise. </p>
<p>Last year Richardson was voted Research Analyst of the Year
by the Australian Stockbroking Foundation and Best Commodities
Analyst for Australia in the East Coles Equities Awards. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Feb 12, 2014  5:54 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-12/morgan-stanley-asset-management-chief-sees-profitability-rising.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley''s Fleming Sees Asset-Management Gains</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Greg Fleming, who runs Morgan
Stanley''s asset-management division, said the business will
boost profitability in the next two years while increasing
assets by about one-third. </p>
<p>Reaching about $500 billion of assets under management by
the end of 2016 from $373 billion in December is very
achievable, Fleming, 50, said today at an investor conference
hosted by Credit Suisse Group AG. Return on equity will rise to
about 20 percent by then and will be maintained consistently, he
said. That compares with 18 percent last year. </p>
<p>Fleming set new targets four years after he was brought in
to help repair the asset-management unit amid losses and
investor withdrawals. While the division is the smallest of the
New York-based investment bank''s three businesses, it was also
the most profitable in 2013. </p>
<p>We''ve come a long ways, Fleming said. We are well-positioned over the next three years to continue to grow
investment management and increase its relevance and
contribution to Morgan Stanley. </p>
<p>The division, known as Morgan Stanley Investment
Management, had $3 billion of revenue and $984 million of pretax
profit last year, the most since 2007. Assets under management
have climbed 46 percent from when Fleming took over. </p>
<p>The unit now oversees $343 billion in traditional equity
and fixed-income funds as well as money-market products and
funds that invest with hedge-fund and private-equity managers.
It has $30 billion of assets in a merchant-banking unit that
operates real-estate and private-equity funds. </p>
<h2>Expansion Plans </h2>
<p>Fleming said he''ll boost assets and revenue by increasing
the North American sales force, adding more choices within long-only fund offerings and raising new merchant-banking funds. The
firm will also seek more assets for its liquidity products and
reduce capital tied up in hedge funds, he said. </p>
<p>Risks to the plans include new regulations, an investor
shift toward passive investments and fee compression, Fleming
said. Merchant banking will take 18 months to 36 months to show
benefits from raising new funds, he said. </p>
<p>Fleming also runs the firm''s brokerage, known as Morgan
Stanley (MS) Wealth Management, that serves mostly individual
investors. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Mulholland" date="Feb 12, 2014 11:37 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-12/goldman-sachs-s-glass-half-full-cmbs-pace-rally-credit-markets.html"><headline>A Real Estate Surge Revives Goldman''s Doom-Era Bonds</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>As they marketed one of the biggest commercial-mortgage bond deals ever in June 2007, just as credit markets began to crumble, bankers at Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and Royal Bank of Scotland Group Plc (RBS) handed out T-shirts depicting a glass it declared half full. </p> <p>Six years later, after the $7.6 billion of securities plunged in the collapse of the U.S. property market that pushed loans included in the deal into default, the glass is filling up. Portions of the deal that have been cut to junk, which fell to as low as 16 cents on the dollar in 2008, have jumped about 5 cents in the past month to as high as 69 cents, according to traders and investors. </p> <p>The bonds are rising after distressed real estate, including properties in the 2007 deal, sold in an auction for more than their most recent appraisals. The sale provides a glimpse of what to expect in the $550 billion market as loan servicers work through a pipeline of $66.6 billion of defaulted mortgages funding everything from Manhattan skyscrapers to shopping malls in Tennessee. </p> <p>In many cases the buildings are in fairly decent areas -- they were just overleveraged, said Keerthi Raghavan, a debt analyst at Barclays Plc in New York, referring to properties sold in the recent auction. This is a chance to wipe the slate clean. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
Commercial and residential buildings in the financial district of Manhattan. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Brian Louis" date="Feb 13, 2014  4:30 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-13/general-growth-returns-not-enough-for-ackman-requirements.html"><headline>General Growth Returns Not Enough for Ackman Requirements</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Bill Ackman, the activist hedge-fund
manager, said he sold his firm''s General Growth Properties Inc. (GGP)
shares because the expected returns on the investment after
management fees wouldn''t be high enough for his investors. </p>
<p>There''s still meaningful upside in General Growth,
Ackman said yesterday at the Harbor Investment Conference in New
York. I do view this as a teens compounded return over the
next four or five years, so I think that''s actually a good
investment. </p>
<p>Continuing to own stock in the Chicago-based company, the
second-largest U.S. shopping-mall owner, wouldn''t work with the
expected return after Pershing Square Capital Management LP''s
fees of 1.5 percent of assets and 20 percent of profit, Ackman
said. You don''t get to a high enough number to please our
investors, so that''s why we sold General Growth, he said. </p>
<p>The real estate investment trust, one of Ackman''s most
profitable investments, bought back about 28 million shares from
New York-based Pershing Square for $556 million, General Growth
said this week. The hedge-fund firm, which in September sold 25
million shares for $500 million, no longer holds any General
Growth common stock, the mall owner said. </p>
<p>Ackman, 47, helped rescue General Growth from near-collapse
by pushing it to file for bankruptcy in 2009, and was part of an
investor group in its subsequent reorganization. The effort
turned $60 million into $1.6 billion, the hedge-fund manager
told Bloomberg News in 2011, and contributed to his flagship
fund''s net return of 29 percent in 2010. </p>
<p>General Growth Properties is a great company, Ackman
said yesterday. I''d recommend it to my sister, my mother. </p>
<h2>Largest Bankruptcy </h2>
<p>General Growth filed the largest real estate bankruptcy in
U.S. history in April 2009 after amassing $27 billion in debt
that it was unable to refinance because of the financial crisis
and collapse of the commercial mortgage-backed securities
market. The company''s restructuring plan provided a full
recovery for creditors and a rare recovery for shareholders. </p>
<p>Pershing Square was in an investor group that included
Brookfield Asset Management Inc. and Bruce Berkowitz''s Fairholme
Capital Management LLC. The partnership committed more than $8
billion to bring General Growth, the biggest U.S. mall owner
after Simon Property Group Inc., out of Chapter 11. </p>
<p>General Growth shares rose 0.1 percent to $21.62 today.
They''ve climbed 8.6 percent in the past year. </p>
<p>The company used available liquidity to fund the
purchase of Pershing Square''s shares, according to General
Growth''s Feb. 10 statement. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Morgane Lapeyre" date="Feb 13, 2014  8:13 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-13/morgan-advanced-materials-seeks-high-tech-purchases-ceo-says.html"><headline>Morgan Advanced Materials Seeks High-Tech Purchases, CEO Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Advanced Materials Plc (MGAM), whose
insulation protects airplane black-boxes, will consider making
acquisitions to gain technology, according to Chief Executive
Officer Mark Robertshaw. </p>
<p>The company is looking to expand in aerospace and
healthcare markets, Robertshaw said today. Shares of Morgan,
whose ceramics are used in everything from body armor to medical
instruments, gained as much as 2.4 percent in London trading
after reporting better-than-estimated pretax profit. </p>
<p>We have more of these types of businesses in North
America, and it''s no coincidence that margins for the region are
16 percent compared with just under 13 percent for the group,
the CEO said in an interview. </p>
<p>Robertshaw is leading the company''s transformation as it
focuses on higher-growth and more profitable areas to counter
weaker demand for ceramics used in semiconductors. Windsor,
England-based Morgan sold businesses with 20 million pounds in
sales last year, and that tally could reach 50 million pounds in
2014 through additional divestments, split between electrical
carbon and thermal-ceramic products, the CEO said. </p>
<p>The stock rose 1.1 percent to 315.8 pence as of 12:26 p.m.
in London, giving the company a market value of 901.8 million
pounds. </p>
<h2>Medical Market </h2>
<p>Healthcare and aerospace industries in emerging markets
such as China and India have good growth potential in the
future as these economies become more sophisticated, the CEO
said. Morgan makes ceramics used in medical instrumentation and
implantable devices. China contributes about 9 percent to group
revenue. </p>
<p>Boeing Co., the world''s largest planemaker, and Airbus
Group NV, the No. 2, have pushed output to record levels helping
lift sales at their suppliers. </p>
<p>The U.K. company, previously known as Morgan Crucible, is
also poised to benefit from expansion in the U.S. petrochemical
industry as manufacturers take advantage of shale gas and
cheaper raw materials, the CEO said. Morgan has about 40 percent
of the North American market for high-temperature fibers, used
for heat insulation in ethylene plants and fire-protection
products. </p>
<p>After a pretty subdued 2013, the last couple of weeks
has seen an uptick in enquiries converting into contract wins,
Robertshaw said. Morgan won a $5 million contract to supply a
petrochemical project in India at the end of last year, and
another one of a similar amount in North America. </p>
<p>We''re feeling a bit more optimistic in 2014, he said. </p>
<h2>Middle East </h2>
<p>A new insulating-fiber plant being built in the Middle East
will bring Morgan closer to the attractive petrochemical and
aluminum markets, while also giving it access to low-cost energy
supplies, Robertshaw said. </p>
<p>Bolt-on acquisitions will supplement what will be
predominantly organic growth, Robertshaw said. Morgan will
spend as much as 6 million pounds on restructuring this year,
down from 10.5 million pounds last year, he said. </p>
<p>The company was seen in 2012 as potentially a takeover
target because of its cheap valuation and after 3M Co. agreed to
buy rival Ceradyne Inc. </p>
<p>The operational performance of the business stands up
incredibly well versus all of our direct competition,
Robertshaw said, when asked whether the company had been
approached by potential buyers. That''s the best possible
defense. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Natalie Obiko Pearson" date="Feb 13, 2014  7:46 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-13/goldman-s-renew-in-solar-dash-as-u-s-moves-wto-corporate-india.html"><headline>Goldman''s ReNew in Solar Dash as U.S. Moves WTO: Corporate India</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>India will award permits this month
to build solar power plants in the first national auction since
2011 as a trade spat with the U.S. over import curbs deepens. </p>
<p>ReNew Power Ventures Pvt., a company backed by Goldman
Sachs Group Inc., the Tata group, whose businesses span software
to automobiles, and First Solar Inc. (FSLR), the biggest U.S. maker of
solar panels, are among 68 bidders vying for projects as India
seeks clean alternatives to fossil fuels. The winners for the
750 megawatts of capacity will be announced by the end of this
month. </p>
<p>India plans a sixfold increase in solar capacity that may
draw $11.7 billion of investment by 2017 as the technology sheds
perceptions that risks are high. In contrast, banks are slowing
lending to coal and gas-fired projects hamstrung by a fuel
squeeze. Rising demand for equipment is also prompting panel
makers to seek a bigger share of the trade as the U.S. lodged a
complaint with the World Trade Organization this week against
India''s barriers. </p>
<p>The advantage of renewables is that you know that the
cost is going to be forever, said Sumant Sinha, chief
executive officer of ReNew Power, which is backed by a $385
million investment from Goldman Sachs. You lock in the price
today. You''re not impacted by the rupee''s depreciation. There''s
no fuel risk. </p>
<h2>Yarn Maker </h2>
<p>Three years ago, India''s first national solar auction drew
skepticism with record-low bids from a woolen yarn maker and
animation company. Tata Power Co. shunned that tender, saying
banks wouldn''t loan to projects deemed too risky. </p>
<p>The current tender received bids for more than double the
capacity available. The offers include 100 megawatts by ReNew,
150 megawatts by a unit of India''s Infrastructure Leasing 
Financial Services Ltd. and 40 megawatts by Tata Power. </p>
<p>The growth of the industry has boosted inbound shipment of
photovoltaic gear, with the value of the purchases reaching $2.4
billion since 2010 when India started its solar program,
according to data from the Ministry of Commerce. </p>
<p>In order to help local makers of solar modules including
Moser Baer India Ltd. (MBI), India is requiring half of the capacity
being auctioned to be built with locally made equipment. That''s
375 megawatts or about 10 percent of the total capacity India
has offered in the past year. The U.S. said this rule unlawfully
restricts access to American manufacturers such as First Solar. </p>
<p>India said it will dispute the complaint lodged by the U.S.
with the WTO against the unfair barrier to U.S. exports. </p>
<h2>Offsetting Costs </h2>
<p>India is offering as much as 18.75 billion rupees ($302
million) in grants for the first time to solar developers to
offset project costs. That will enable the plants to reduce the
electricity tariff to 5.5 rupees a kilowatt-hour, equal to the
cost of grid power. </p>
<p>That eliminates one of the main investment hurdles the
industry faced: the risk that cash-strapped state utilities
buying the power would default, leaving plants unable to sell
their output elsewhere. At 5.5 rupees, the plants could find
alternate buyers, including industrial and commercial consumers
who pay the highest rates for power. </p>
<p>Renewables are attracting a different class of investors
who want stable yields, said Sunil Wadhwa, chief executive of
ILFS Energy Development Co., a developer of gas, coal and
clean-energy projects. These are stable cash flows. For the
investor, the costs are highest in the beginning, but it''s more
predictable. </p>
<h2>Stable Returns </h2>
<p>Clean energy projects in Europe are luring institutional
cash as retirement and insurance funds, including Allianz SE,
Aviva Plc (AV/) and PensionDanmark A/S seek stable returns to match
their long-term liabilities. Copenhagen-based PensionDanmark has
invested about $1.8 billion in renewable energy, while Allianz
Capital Partners, a unit of Europe''s largest insurer, invested
more than 400 million euros ($545 million) last year. </p>
<p>In India, investors from Goldman to Morgan Stanley (MS) have led
about $2 billion of private-equity buyouts, project and company
acquisitions in the renewable industry since 2010, according to
Bloomberg New Energy Finance. In the past year, the Government
of Singapore Investment Corp. invested 100 million pounds ($166
million) in Greenko Group Plc (GKO), a developer of Indian wind farms.
GE Energy Financial Services invested 2.57 billion rupees in a
hydropower plant in northern Sikkim state under development by
Gati Infrastructure Pvt. </p>
<p>Photovoltaic plants in India are likely to earn a 16
percent return, according to calculations by the central
electricity regulator to set tariffs. That compares with a yield
of 8.87 percent offered by India''s benchmark 10-year bond. </p>
<h2>Thermal Power </h2>
<p>Foreign direct investment in India''s thermal power sector
has collapsed to less than one-third its level two years ago as
fuel risks, regulatory uncertainties and environmental delays
hold up projects, according to government data. </p>
<p>More than 60 percent of power stations owned by NTPC Ltd.,
the nation''s biggest generator, are running below capacity due
to a lack of coal supply, NTPC Director A.K. Jha said this week.
India plans to raise local gas prices by as much as 90 percent
to $8 per million British thermal units, a level that will be
unviable for power plants, Oil Secretary Vivek Rae said on Jan.
12. </p>
<p>With coal and gas prices rising and an increasing share to
be imported, a clean-energy project may already be able to
supply electricity about 3 percent cheaper over the long term,
said Wadhwa of ILFS Energy, which is building a 750-megawatt
gas power plant and is India''s second-biggest owner of wind
farms. </p>
<p>Indonesia, the biggest coal supplier to India, banned
exports of raw ores last month. Tomorrow it might be coal,
said Wadhwa. In thermal, you''re never sure. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Benjamin Purvis" date="Feb 13, 2014  1:13 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-13/goldman-makes-2014-aussie-bond-debut-as-westpac-plans-new-issue.html"><headline>Goldman Makes 2014 Aussie Bond Debut as Westpac Plans Issue</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) is poised
to become the first U.S. commercial bank to sell bonds in
Australia this year, while Westpac Banking Corp. is also
planning a new line of notes. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs is marketing fixed- and floating-rate
Australian dollar bonds due August 2019 at a yield of about 135
basis points more than swap rates, according to an e-mailed
statement today from the issuer. Sydney-based Westpac,
Australia''s second-biggest lender by market value, plans to sell
five-year securities at a spread of around 95 basis points,
according to a person familiar with the matter who asked not to
be identified because the terms aren''t set. </p>
<p>Investor appetite for credit has helped cap borrowing costs
in Australia with the yield premium over the swap rate on bank
paper averaging 99 basis points yesterday and 94 on Feb. 7, a
low unseen since February 2008, according to a Bank of America
Merrill Lynch index. No U.S. commercial bank has sold bonds in
Australia since Goldman Sachs''s last transaction in July, when
it priced A$750 million ($670 million) of five-year fixed and
floating-rate notes at a 170-basis-point spread. </p>
<p>Investment banks were one of the strongest performing
sectors in 2013 and I''d expect the Goldman Sachs deal to perform
well, although recent emerging-market ructions could damp demand
a bit, said Justin Davey, a money manager at BT Investment
Management Ltd. </p>
<h2>Rabobank, ABN Amro </h2>
<p>Dutch lenders Rabobank Groep and ABN Amro NV are the only
other foreign commercial banks to have come to the Australian
market so far this year, issuing A$600 million and A$500 million
of notes respectively last month. </p>
<p>The August 2018 fixed-rate bond that Goldman Sachs sold
last year yielded 106 basis points more than the swap rate
today, Australia  New Zealand Banking Group Ltd. prices show.
The American bank carries a credit rating of A- at Standard 
Poor''s, the seventh highest, and is ranked Baa1 at Moody''s
Investors Service, one level lower. </p>
<p>National Australia Bank Ltd. was the last of the so-called
four-pillar domestic banks to sell new five-year notes in its
home market, pricing A$1.5 billion of floating-rate debentures
in November at a spread of 88 basis points, according to data
compiled by Bloomberg. Both Commonwealth Bank of Australia and
ANZ priced five-year securities in October. The last new
benchmark-sized five-year bond from Westpac (WBC) was issued in
January 2013 at a 95-basis-point premium, the data show. </p>
<p>There haven''t been many primary bank issues since the
latter part of 2013, BT''s Davey said. I''d expect there to be
solid interest for the Westpac transaction given the lack of
supply and the benign conditions for banks as evidenced by
recent results announcements from ANZ and CBA. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs is managing its own offering along with CBA,
NAB and Royal Bank of Canada. Westpac is also managing its own
sale, the person familiar with that matter said. Both
transactions are expected to price by tomorrow. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Schneider" date="Feb 13, 2014 12:17 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-13/pfizer-sued-by-australian-regulator-over-generic-lipitor-deals.html"><headline>Pfizer Sued by Australian Regulator Over Generic Lipitor</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE)''s Australian unit was
sued by the country''s competition regulator for misuse of market
power relating to sales of its generic version of the Lipitor
cholesterol drug. </p>
<p>The Australian Competition and Consumer Commission said it
filed the lawsuit today in federal court in Sydney claiming
Pfizer Australia Pty.''s deals with pharmacies in 2012 for the
sale of atorvastatin breached competition rules. A copy of the
filing wasn''t immediately available. </p>
<p>Patent protection on Lipitor, the biggest selling
prescription drug in Australia under the federal drug plan,
expired in May 2012. At the time Lipitor was prescribed to more
than 1 million Australians with annual sales exceeding A$700
million ($625 million), according to the ACCC. Prior to the
expiry Pfizer struck a deal with pharmacies, offering discounts
and rebates on the condition they bought a minimum 12 months''
supply of atorvastatin, the generic equivalent, the ACCC said. </p>
<p>Pfizer engaged in this conduct for the purpose of
deterring or preventing competitors in the market for
atorvastatin from engaging in competitive conduct, ACCC
Chairman Rod Sims said in a statement. This case also raises
an important public interest issue regarding the conduct of a
patent holder nearing the expiry of that patent. </p>
<p>Pfizer said in an e-mailed statement today it believes the
offers made to the pharmacies were competitive. Since the matter
is before the court, the company said it wouldn''t be appropriate
to comment further. </p>
<p>The ACCC said it''s seeking pecuniary penalties and
declarations, without specifying them. </p>
<p>A preliminary hearing is scheduled to be held on Mar. 18,
the regulator said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lisa Abramowicz" date="Feb 14, 2014  9:57 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-14/morgan-stanley-sees-bond-evolution-in-trade-jump-credit-markets.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Sees Bond Evolution in Trade Jump: Credit Markets</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Corporate-bond trading volumes are
surging to the highest ever to start the year as investors adapt
to a new reality of reduced dealer balance sheets by turning to
electronically exchanged debt and smaller transactions. </p>
<p>Even as issuance of the securities slowed, the amount of
investment-grade and junk bonds changing hands increased to
$20.3 billion on average each day this year, 3 percent more than
during the same period in 2013, Financial Industry Regulatory
Authority data show. Bond investors are turning to exchange-traded funds at a record pace, with BlackRock Inc.''s junk-bond
ETF posting record withdrawals and the greatest volume of
bearish wagers ever. </p>
<p>The trading surge is part of a bond-market evolution that
Morgan Stanley strategists led by Sivan Mahadevan say is
allowing debt buyers to maneuver without Wall Street''s biggest
banks using their own money to buy and sell in bigger blocks. As
the size of trades shrink, investors are transacting about 50
percent more than five years ago, the analysts said in a Feb. 13
report. </p>
<p>We''ve seen an increase in trading volumes despite the
fact that dealers are devoting less of their balance sheets,
Mahadevan said in a telephone interview. We''ve seen a more
efficient market, more velocity of trading. </p>
<h2>Issuance Declines </h2>
<p>Corporate-debt volumes have been higher this year than in
any other similar period and are up from the average $18.1
billion that changed hands daily in 2013, according to Trace (NTMBIV),
Finra''s bond-price reporting system. Transactions jumped even as
the amount of U.S. corporate-bond sales, which typically fuel
volumes, fell to $190.1 billion this year from $218 billion in
the period in 2013, Finra and Bloomberg data show. </p>
<p>Buyers exchanged $58.1 billion of debt on MarketAxess
Inc.''s electronic platform last month, 15 percent more than in
January 2013 and the most ever for the month, according to data
on the New York-based firm''s website. </p>
<p>Despite the banks'' unwillingness to commit capital to
facilitate client trading, people are still finding ways, said
Kevin McPartland, head of market structure research at
financial-research firm Greenwich Associates. There are new
ways that are not necessarily your traditional electronic
trading ways. </p>
<h2>Less Volatile </h2>
<p>Corporate bonds have benefited this year from a flight to
fixed-income assets amid signs that a pullback in U.S. monetary
stimulus threatens to weaken economies from South Africa to
Russia. Even speculative-grade corporates have gained 1.4
percent this year, as measured by the Bank of America Merrill
Lynch U.S. High-Yield Index (SPX), while the Standard  Poor''s 500
Index of stocks has lost 0.7 percent. </p>
<p>Company-bond prices have been less volatile than in the
period last year, with values swinging by 1.47 cents on the
dollar, a narrower swing than in the same period during the past
two years. Prices have been steadied by both declining benchmark
Treasury yields and increased demand from institutional money
managers as individual investors fled riskier assets. </p>
<p>Buyers from retirees to hedge funds yanked as much as $1.7
billion from the 10-biggest junk-bond ETFs in the two weeks
after Jan. 22, the day before a report showing that a gauge of
China''s manufacturing contracted and triggered the selloff,
Bloomberg data show. </p>
<h2>BlackRock ETF </h2>
<p>BlackRock''s $13.2 billion junk-bond ETF reported a $630
million outflow on Feb. 3, its biggest one-day withdrawal since
its inception in 2007, the data show. </p>
<p>Investors including Western Asset Management Co.''s Michael Buchanan saw the outflows as a buying opportunity. </p>
<p>We were buyers on days of weakness, Buchanan, who
oversees $127 billion of credit investments at Western Asset in
Pasadena, California, said in a Feb. 4 telephone interview. </p>
<p>Debt traders who wanted to bet against junk bonds borrowed
$3.87 billion of shares in BlackRock and State Street Corp.''s
high-yield ETFs (JNK) as of Jan. 31, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. The two funds are the biggest of their kind and hold
$23.6 billion of the securities. </p>
<p>Investors are managing to slip in and out of a market even
with the diminished balance sheets of dealers, which
traditionally have bought larger pools of bonds that they could
sell over a longer period of time at a profit. The strategy,
credited with cushioning price swings and facilitating larger
trade sizes, was made costlier by regulations demanding a bigger
buffer of capital to protect against losses among bank holdings. </p>
<h2>Dealers Shrink </h2>
<p>Bond dealers jettisoned assets to comply with rules issued
in 2010 by the Basel Committee on Banking Supervision and the
Dodd-Frank Act passed by Congress the same year. Primary dealers
that trade directly with the Federal Reserve cut their holdings
of corporate bonds by 76 percent from a peak of $235 billion in
2007 to $56 billion at the end of March, Fed data show. </p>
<p>Investment-grade bond holdings fell to a net $12.5 billion
in the week ended Feb. 5 from $14.4 billion the previous week,
according to Federal Reserve Bank of New York data. </p>
<p>Even as total trading volumes fell behind a 91 percent
growth in corporates outstanding since 2008, investors are
adapting, the Morgan Stanley strategists said this week. They''re
trading 53 percent more frequently than they did five years ago
and larger trades were 8 percent smaller in 2013 than three
years earlier, the analysts wrote. </p>
<p>While electronic platforms are unlikely to dominate a
business that''s often conducted over the phone and in e-mail
messages, some slices of the market are trading more like
equities and interest-rate products than they have in the past,
they said in the report. </p>
<p>Transparency and electronic platforms are driving a
credit-market evolution that is likely still in the beginning of
a multi-year process, the strategists wrote. The market
landscape has shifted in favor of investors, at the expense of
dealers. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Benjamin Purvis" date="Feb 14, 2014  2:17 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-14/goldman-joins-westpac-with-biggest-australian-bonds-in-two-years.html"><headline>Goldman Joins Westpac With Biggest Australian Bonds in Two Years</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) and Westpac (WBC)
Banking Corp. sold their largest Australian dollar-denominated
bonds in more than two years today. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs, the first U.S. commercial bank to come to
the Australian market since July, issued A$950 million ($855
million) of notes maturing in August 2019 to yield 130 basis
points more than swap rates, a person familiar with the matter
said, asking not to be identified because the terms are private.
Westpac, the third-biggest issuer of bank debt in Australia last
year, priced A$3 billion of five-year securities at a 94-basis-point spread, according to an e-mailed statement. </p>
<p>Investor appetite for credit has helped cap borrowing costs
in the South Pacific nation with the average yield premium on
bank paper over the swap rate at 98 basis points yesterday and
94 on Feb. 7, a low unseen since February 2008, according to a
Bank of America Merrill Lynch index. Today''s unsecured bond
sales, the largest in Australia this year, were also accompanied
by a A$2.5 billion securitized issue from Commonwealth Bank of
Australia. </p>
<p>More than A$6 billion of issuance on one day is massive
for the Australian market, said Ken Hanton, a director in
National Australia Bank Ltd.''s debt markets group. The level
of demand we have seen is a clear demonstration of the health of
the market at the moment. </p>
<p>The Goldman transaction was split into a A$700 million
fixed-rate portion and a A$250 million floating-rate component,
the person familiar said. No U.S. commercial bank has sold bonds
in Australia since Goldman''s last deal in July, when it priced
A$750 million of five-year fixed and floating-rate notes at a
170-basis-point spread, data compiled by Bloomberg show. </p>
<h2>Goldman Offerings </h2>
<p>The New York-based company raised A$600 million in November
2012 and A$1.25 billion in May 2011, its first Australian
offering following a five-year hiatus. The American bank carries
a credit rating of A- at Standard  Poor''s, the seventh highest,
and is ranked Baa1 at Moody''s Investors Service, one level
lower. </p>
<p>Westpac''s sale was also a two-part deal, comprising A$1.1
billion of fixed-rate notes and A$1.9 billion of floaters. The
last transaction from the Sydney-based lender larger than that
was in January 2012, when Westpac borrowed A$3.1 billion via its
debut domestic covered bond, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. It''s rated higher than Goldman Sachs, with scores of
Aa2 at Moody''s and AA- at SP. </p>
<h2>Domestic Sales </h2>
<p>NAB was the most recent of the so-called four-pillar
domestic banks to sell new five-year notes in its home market,
pricing A$1.5 billion of floating-rate debentures in November at
a spread of 88 basis points, the data show. The last new
benchmark-sized five-year bond from Westpac was issued in
January 2013 at a 95-basis-point premium, the data show. </p>
<p>CBA (CBA), the nation''s biggest lender, also priced A$2.5 billion
of residential mortgage-backed securities today. It sold A$1.4
billion of class A1 floating-rate notes at a yield 80 basis
points above the bank-bill swap rate, A$610 million A2 class
floating-rate notes at a 90-basis-point spread and A$300 million
A3 class fixed-rated securities at a 110 basis-point spread, a
person familiar with the matter said. Pricing on a further A$201
million of notes wasn''t disclosed. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elisa Martinuzzi" date="Feb 17, 2014 12:36 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-17/goldman-sachs-is-outpaced-by-rivals-as-equity-sales-jump.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Is Outpaced by Rivals as Equity Sales Jump</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), the U.S.
bank most reliant on trading, lost market share in equities
revenue relative to the world''s top firms last year, according
to Tricumen Ltd., a financial research company. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs''s share of total operating revenue from
equities in 2013 dropped 4.1 percent from the previous year,
while sales by the bank''s peer group rose a combined 15 percent,
Tricumen said in a report published today. UBS AG (UBSN), Switzerland''s
biggest bank, expanded its share by 1.4 percent, the largest
gain in the group, the data show. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs lost ground in equity derivatives due to its
limited range of services and products compared with No. 1
competitor JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), said Darko Kapor, a partner at
London-based Tricumen. Goldman Sachs fell to sixth from the
second rank by revenue in equity derivatives last year, and to
third from second in servicing hedge funds, according to
Tricumen. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs, based in New York, reported $15.7 billion in
revenue from equity and fixed-income trading in 2013, down 13
percent from a year earlier, hurt mostly by interest-rate and
currency trading. In stocks, it remained the leader for cash
equities last year and is also the No. 1 in proprietary trading
by revenue, Tricumen data show. </p>
<p>Tricumen uses corporate filings and its own industry data
to compile the rankings. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jason Corcoran" date="Feb 17, 2014 11:09 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-17/goldman-names-arsenyev-sedov-russia-investment-banking-co-heads.html"><headline>Goldman Names Arsenyev, Sedov Russia Investment Banking Co-Heads</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (G) named
Sergei Arsenyev and Dmitri Sedov as co-heads of its investment
banking division in Moscow, according to an internal memo
obtained by Bloomberg News. </p>
<p>Arsenyev, who joined the New York-based bank in 2000, is
focusing on coverage of the government and family offices, the
memo said. Sedov, who joined Goldman Sachs in 2007, is MA
captain for Russia and is focusing on telecommunications,
media, technology, infrastructure, industrials and healthcare in
the region, the memo said. </p>
<p>Sergei and Dmitri will be working closely with Paolo Zannoni and Nick Jordan in their roles of co-chief executive
officers of the Russia/Commonwealth of Independent States
business, said the memo, signed by co-heads of investment
banking Richard Gnodde, David Solomon and John Weinberg. Monika Schaller, a spokeswoman for Goldman Sachs in Frankfurt,
confirmed the memo''s contents by phone. </p>
<p>The appointments come a year after Goldman Sachs was hired
by Russia''s Economy Ministry and the Russian Direct Investment
Fund as a corporate broker to burnish the nation''s image
overseas and attract more institutional investors. Jordan was
hired from UBS AG as co-head of the Russian business to work
alongside Zannoni last March. </p>
<p>The bank also named Tim Talkington as head of its Russian
securities unit, according to another memo. Talkington joined
Goldman Sachs in 2000 in London and rejoined the firm in Moscow
in 2007. He was named head of equities for Russia in 2012.
Schaller also confirmed his appointment. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Stefania Bianchi" date="Feb 17, 2014  7:13 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-17/morgan-stanley-said-to-name-delivanis-mena-investment-bank-head.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Said to Name Delivanis MENA Investment Bank Head</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS), owner of the world''s
biggest brokerage, appointed Patrick Delivanis to take over as
investment banking head in the Middle East and North Africa,
according to a person with knowledge of the matter. </p>
<p>Delivanis takes over with immediate effect from Klaus Froehlich and has worked for the New York-based bank in Dubai
since 2007, according to the person, who asked not to be named
as the information isn''t public. Froehlich becomes head of
global capital markets for Germany and Austria, the person said. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley was the Middle East and Africa''s top MA
adviser last year, working on deals valued at $11.8 billion,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. The bank last year
advised Abu Dhabi''s Sorouh Real Estate Co. on its merger with
Aldar Properties PJSC (ALDAR), the emirate''s largest developer. It also
advised Riyadh-based utility ACWA Power International when Saudi
Arabian sovereign wealth fund Sanabil and the nation''s pension
agency acquired a 19 percent stake. </p>
<p>Froehlich, in an interview last week, said the bank was
predicting the return of initial public offerings worth more
than $1 billion in the Persian Gulf this year after asset values
and stock markets rallied. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Duane D. Stanford" date="Feb 18, 2014  4:30 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-18/coca-cola-profit-falls-8-4-as-cost-cuts-announced.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Plans $1 Billion in Cost Cuts as Profit Falls</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Coca-Cola Co. (KO), the world''s largest
beverage company, dropped the most in more than two years after
North American soft-drink demand shrank and its once-effervescent growth in emerging markets showed signs of slowing. </p>
<p>Fourth-quarter net income slid 8.4 percent to $1.71
billion, or 38 cents a share, from $1.87 billion, or 41 cents, a
year earlier, Atlanta-based Coca-Cola said today in a statement.
Sales fell 3.6 percent to $11 billion in the period, missing the
average analyst estimate compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Muhtar Kent, facing sluggish demand
worldwide, embarked on a plan to cut $1 billion in annual costs
by 2016, aiming to reduce supply and data-management expenses
and overhaul marketing programs. Still, the company has been
slow to react to health concerns about its drinks, as well as
the growing desire for beverages that aren''t carbonated colas,
said Ali Dibadj, an analyst at Sanford C. Bernstein  Co. </p>
<p>The changes that the company is making just aren''t
enough, Dibadj, who is based in New York, said in an
interview. Many investors aren''t sharing the confidence that
management does of the company''s future. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola shares fell 3.8 percent to $37.47 in New York,
marking the biggest one-day decline since August 2011. The
shares have dropped 9.3 percent this year, compared with a 0.4
percent decline for the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index. PepsiCo
Inc. (PEP), the company''s biggest competitor, has decreased 5.7
percent in that period. </p>




Photographer: Patrick Fallon/Bloomberg

<p>
Bottles of Coca-Cola Co. soda are displayed for sale at a convenience store in Redondo Beach. Global sales volume rose 2 percent for the year and 1 percent for the quarter, less than the 4 percent annual and 3 percent quarterly growth reported a year ago. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Calev Ben-David" date="Feb 18, 2014 10:21 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-18/goldman-says-export-rise-slims-rate-cut-odds-israel-markets.html"><headline>Goldman Says Export Rise Slims Rate Cut Odds: Israel Markets</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A rebound in Israeli exports is
signaling to Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) that central bank Governor
Karnit Flug will resist manufacturers'' calls to cut interest
rates to weaken the shekel. </p>
<p>We expect growth in total exports to pick up to around 4
percent in 2014, Kasper Lund-Jensen and Ahmet Akarli, London-based economists at Goldman Sachs, said in a report last week.
Imports will grow by a similar amount, making net impact on the
shekel fairly neutral and reducing the risks of a near-term rate cut, they said. </p>
<p>Manufacturers say the strength of the shekel, which
outperformed 30 other major currencies Bloomberg tracked last
year, was a major reason exports slipped 0.1 percent in 2013.
They kept their demand for a rate cut even after exports began
rebounding late last year and the shekel''s appreciation stalled. </p>
<p>Sales abroad rose to $4.2 billion in January from $4
billion in December, according to government data. The currency,
which gained 7.5 percent last year against the dollar, has
declined about 1 percent this year. </p>
<p>The Bank of Israel, which has held the rate at 1 percent
since October, is scheduled to announce its next decision on
Feb. 24. Sixteen of 19 economists surveyed by Bloomberg forecast
the bank will hold the rate again, with the rest predicting a
quarter-point cut. The shekel strengthened 0.1 percent to 3.5090
per dollar at 5:20 p.m. in Tel Aviv. </p>
<h2>Economic Upturn </h2>
<p>The bank''s monetary policy committee cited an economic
pickup and rising home prices when it kept the rate unchanged
last month. The Manufacturers Association of Israel called the
Jan. 27 decision disappointing and said borrowing costs
should be cut to 0.25 percent to weaken the shekel and make
goods sold abroad more competitive. The Israel Export 
International Cooperation Institute said on Dec. 10 that the
currency''s appreciation dealt exports a mortal blow. </p>
<p>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said in Davos
last month that Israeli exporters must adjust to the stronger
shekel because policy makers have limited options to curb it. </p>
<p>The government today announced measures to aid exporters,
including raising the ceiling on export guarantees, expediting
approvals of export risk insurance and allocating 50 million
shekels ($14.2 million) to market goods abroad. </p>
<p>While exports have rallied in recent months, imports have
climbed more, widening the trade gap to $1.5 billion in January
from $1.2 billion a month earlier. </p>
<h2>Market Benefit </h2>
<p>The rise in exports, if maintained, will benefit equity and
bond markets, said Jonathan Katz, a Jerusalem-based economist at
HSBC Holdings Plc. The export figures were pretty broad-based
and varied, not limited to one sector like pharmaceuticals or
technology, Katz said. So although so far it''s just one
robust number, if exports and domestic demand continue trending
upwards, it will be good for companies and the whole economy and
eventually the markets. </p>
<p>The central bank has tried to weaken the shekel by stepping
up its purchase of foreign currency reserves. It bought $1.7
billion in January, after buying $630 million the previous
month, bringing its reserves to a record $83.2 billion. </p>
<p>The stabilization of the dollar-shekel rate in recent weeks
makes it probable the bank will pare its currency purchases this
month and hold the key rate, said Tal Zohar Avda, chief
executive officer of the Tel Aviv branch of FXCM Inc. (FXCM) U.S.
Federal Reserve head Janet Yellen''s Feb. 11 comment that she
intends to maintain the policy of gradually reducing bond
purchases, also support this view, Avda said. </p>
<h2>Less Pressure </h2>
<p>If the dollar continues to strengthen globally, mainly
against the euro, it will get stronger in Israel, too, Avda
said. As long as the dollar continues to stabilize or
strengthen, there will be less pressure from the exporters on
the Bank of Israel to cut the rate. </p>
<p>Goldman forecasts the bank will hold the rate through the
first half of 2014, until a continued improvement in exports, a
gradual quickening of inflation and rising housing prices
trigger a hiking cycle in the third quarter. </p>
<p>The International Monetary Fund, in its annual report on
Israel''s economy released Feb. 12, urged the government to rein
in housing costs by limiting loan-to-value ratios on mortgages
and raising the property purchase tax for secondary homes. </p>
<p>If global growth prospects improve sharply or
appreciation pressures on the shekel ease, the monetary policy
stance should be gradually normalized, the IMF said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David Fickling" date="Feb 18, 2014  1:07 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-18/coca-cola-amatil-apologizes-after-a-404-million-spc-writedown.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Amatil Apologizes After $367 Million SPC Writedown</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Coca-Cola Amatil Ltd. (CCL) Managing
Director Terry Davis told investors he was sorry after a A$404
million ($367 million) writeoff at its packaged-foods unit SPC
Ardmona drove profit to its lowest level since 1992. </p>
<p>I apologize to not be able to bring you a better
result, Davis, who''s leaving the job March 3, told investors
on a call today after announcing an 83 percent drop in net
income to A$79.9 million for the year ended Dec. 31. Hopefully
we''ve turned the tide with SPC, he said. </p>
<p>Sales volumes at Coca-Cola Amatil''s main Australian soft
drinks business fell 3.2 percent to 338 million cases last year,
cutting group revenue by 1.1 percent to A$5.08 billion, the
first decline since 2006, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. Australia''s biggest beverage company fell 5.3 percent
to A$11.22 at the close in Sydney, its lowest price since August
2011. </p>
<p>Australian food companies have been hurt by currency swings
in recent years. The Australian dollar''s rise to a 29-year high
of $1.11 in July 2011 lowered the cost of competing imports, and
its subsequent decline to 90 cents has increased the price of
raw materials. </p>
<p>Asahi Group Holdings Ltd. (2502)''s Schweppes Australia unit, which
sells Pepsi in the country, raised prices for the first time in
two years this month, Citigroup Inc. analyst Gino Rossi wrote in
a Feb. 7 note to clients, driven by an estimated 3.5 percent
increase in costs of imported ingredients. </p>
<p>That will lessen pricing pressure on Coca-Cola, which sells
at a premium of more than 50 percent to Pepsi, according to
Rossi. </p>
<p>Aggressive competitor pricing was responsible for the
poor result from Coca-Cola Amatil''s Australian beverage unit,
the company said today. </p>
<h2>State Support </h2>
<p>The results were a negative for Coca-Cola Amatil''s credit,
Moody''s Investors Service senior vice president Ian Lewis wrote
in an opinion after the announcement. It wouldn''t affect the
company''s investment-grade ratings, which are stable at A3, he
wrote. </p>
<p>The high Australian dollar has enabled a flood of cheap
imported product to be sold in Australia below the cost of
production here while decimating SPCA''s export markets, Coca-Cola Amatil said in a regulatory statement today. The company
will pursue anti-dumping measures, changes to import tariffs,
and enforcement of standards on ingredients, according to the
statement. </p>
<h2>''Corporate Welfare'' </h2>
<p>Australia''s federal government, which has said it doesn''t
believe in corporate welfare, on Jan. 30 turned down Coca-Cola Amatil''s request for a A$25 million grant to fund
efficiency savings at SPC Ardmona. The government of Victoria
state will instead provide A$22 million alongside A$78 million
from the company, the parent company said Feb. 13. </p>
<p>The remaining book value of SPC Ardmona is just north of
A$300 million, Alison Watkins, who will take over from Davis
next month, told investors on the call. The state''s investment
won''t eliminate Coca-Cola Amatil''s ability to exit the business
if it continues to underperform, Davis said, without giving
further details. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Gabrielle Coppola and Elena Popina" date="Feb 19, 2014 10:51 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-19/coca-cola-scares-off-sodastream-bears-as-stock-rout-ends.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Scares Off SodaStream Bears as Stock Rout Ends</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Coca-Cola Co. is giving SodaStream
International Ltd. (SODA) a hand in scaring away short sellers. </p>
<p>Since Coca-Cola agreed Feb. 5 to buy a 10 percent stake in
Green Mountain Coffee Roasters Inc. (GMCR), a company developing a
make-your-own, single-serve product similar to SodaStream''s,
short interest on the stock has fallen. It dropped to 22 percent
of the Israeli beverage maker''s outstanding shares on Feb. 14
from an 18-month high of 30 percent at the start of the year,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg and Markit, a London-based research firm. </p>
<p>The Green Mountain deal helped validate the do-it-yourself
beverage market and fueled speculation that PepsiCo Inc. (PEP), the
world''s second-largest soft-drink maker after Coca-Cola, will
make a bid for SodaStream. The stock has started to rebound,
climbing 15 percent from a 14-month low it hit on Feb. 3 after
the company released worse-than-forecast preliminary earnings
for 2013. </p>
<p>There is a chance SodaStream can repeat Green Mountain''s
success story, Albert Saporta, the head of research at Makor
Capital Ltd. in Ramat Gan, Israel who has a buy rating on the
stock, said in a Feb. 12 telephone interview. If the at-home
carbonated beverage market proves to be a substantial market,
you win without paying anything for that. </p>




Photographer: Ariel Jerozolimski/Bloomberg

<p>
An employee uses a forklift truck to prepare pallets of SodaStream products for export at the SodaStream International Ltd. factory in Mishor Adumim, near Jerusalem. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hugh Son, Suzi Ring and Deema Almashabi" date="Feb 19, 2014 10:43 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-19/jpmorgan-said-cut-tie-to-saudi-bank-amid-focus-on-control.html"><headline>JPMorgan Said Cut Tie to Saudi Bank Amid Focus on Control</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) dropped Al-Rajhi Bank, the world''s largest Shariah-compliant lender, as a correspondent banking client amid a push to improve risk controls, said two people with direct knowledge of the move. </p> <p>The relationship with Saudi Arabia''s biggest publicly traded bank ended Dec. 31 because JPMorgan couldn''t get enough information on where payments in dollar-clearing services for Al-Rajhi had originated, said one of the people, who requested anonymity because the decision wasn''t public. </p> <p>JPMorgan said it cut off the service to about 500 foreign lenders last year as regulators press the world''s biggest banks to verify that transactions are used for legitimate business. The crackdown seeks to halt funds tied to money laundering, terrorism and countries covered by economic sanctions. Correspondent accounts allow lenders to take deposits or make payments on behalf of foreign institutions. </p> <p>JPMorgan has to be extra careful to make sure they''re adhering to standards and not even approaching anything questionable, said David Kass, a professor at the University of Maryland''s Robert H. Smith School of Business. </p> <p>The two banks haven''t been cited by U.S. regulators for involvement in illegal money transfers. Tasha Pelio, a JPMorgan spokeswoman, declined to comment on clients of the company, which is based in New York and ranks as the nation''s largest lender by assets. A spokesman for Al-Rajhi (RJHI) didn''t respond to inquiries, and there was no response to messages sent to the firm''s Riyadh headquarters. </p>




Photographer: Goh Seng Chong/Bloomberg

<p>
Al-Rajhi, founded in 1957 by billionaire Sulaiman Al Rajhi, had 9,000 employees and about 500 branches in Saudi Arabia, Jordan, Malaysia and Kuwait, according to a January 2012 media kit. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Anna Kitanaka and Satoshi Kawano" date="Feb 19, 2014  2:06 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-19/jpx-will-consider-merging-jasdaq-mothers-tse-second.html"><headline>JPX Will Consider Merging Jasdaq, Mothers, TSE Second</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Japan Exchange Group Inc. (8697) will
consider merging three smaller equity markets to simplify its
exchange structure, a bourse official said. </p>
<p>JPX, created last year from the merger of the Tokyo Stock
Exchange and Osaka Securities Exchange, will weigh combining its
Mothers, TSE Second Section and Jasdaq markets, Yasuyuki Konuma,
executive officer for the new listings department, said in an
interview in Tokyo yesterday. Serious discussion has yet to
begin and there is no schedule for the merger, he said. </p>
<p>There are some who say it''s a problem that we have so
many markets, said Konuma. We need to begin discussing
whether we need to merge them, the merit being simplicity. </p>
<p>The creation of the national bourse last year was part of a
state plan to streamline Japan''s securities industry and revive
its standing as a financial hub. Potential consolidation
contrasts with the U.S., where trading is spread across more
than 50 public and private markets as well as dozens of internal
platforms at broker-dealers. </p>
<p>That fragmentation is blamed by some for making American
capital markets too complex. Two U.S. exchange operators, Bats
Global Markets Inc. and Direct Edge Holdings LLC, have retained
their four individual markets even after the parent companies
completed their merger this month. </p>




Photographer: Kiyoshi Ota/Bloomberg

<p>
Yasuyuki Konuma, executive officer for the new listings department at Tokyo Stock Exchange Inc. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Morwenna Coniam and Jeanette Rodrigues" date="Feb 20, 2014  8:45 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-20/goldman-asset-buys-rupee-to-join-william-blair-as-deficit-slides.html"><headline>Goldman Asset Buys Rupee to Join William Blair on Deficit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Asset Management and
William Blair Investment Management are buying the rupee as
India reins in a current-account deficit that drove the currency
to a record low in August. </p>
<p>The rupee, which slid 21 percent in the past two years,
looks cheap relative to India''s improving external finances,
according to Goldman Sachs Asset, which opened a small long
position on the currency this year. William Blair has boosted
the currency to about 20 percent of its foreign-exchange
holdings for its higher yield and inexpensive valuation, said
Chicago-based fund manager Brian D. Singer. </p>
<p>The rupee has rebounded more than 10 percent from last
year''s all-time low of 68.845 per dollar as India curbed gold
imports to shore up the current account and the central bank
acted to spur dollar inflows. Only Indonesia''s rupiah has fallen
more than the rupee among Asian emerging markets. While India''s
finances have improved since last year, the nation needs a
coordinated plan to respond to volatility in global currency
markets as the U.S. reduces stimulus, the International Monetary
Fund said in a report. </p>
<p>The current-account numbers have been the key driver
because it''s a very transparent measure of whether the policy
prescriptions are having an impact, Philip Moffitt, Sydney-based head of fixed income for Asia-Pacific at Goldman Sachs
Asset, which oversaw more than $1 trillion on Dec. 31, said in 
an e-mail interview yesterday. If you can find something 
that''s relatively cheap and the fundamentals appear to be 
improving, it''s usually a good mix. </p>
<h2>Principal Risk'' </h2>
<p>The shortfall in the broadest measure of trade will shrink
to $45 billion in the year through March from an unprecedented
$88 billion the previous period, the government said Feb. 17. </p>
<p>The principal risk facing India is the inward spillover
from a tightening of global liquidity interacting with domestic
vulnerabilities, the IMF said in the report. Pressures
associated with India''s still-significant external financing
need could lead to higher borrowing costs, fund outflows and
disorderly adjustments in the exchange rate, it said. </p>
<p>Any plan should make rupee flexibility the key defense and
include measures to raise the benchmark interest rate, impose
cash curbs, open foreign-exchange swap windows and raise diesel
prices, the Washington-based lender said in an annual review of
India''s economy. </p>
<h2>Current Account </h2>
<p>Dollar-based investors will earn 9 percent including
interest by holding the rupee until the end of 2014, the second-biggest return in Asia, according to Bloomberg data based on
appreciation estimates and deposit rates. Two-year government
bonds pay 8.67 percent in India, compared with 0.31 percent in
the U.S. and 3.70 percent in China. The rupee was at 62.23 per
dollar yesterday. </p>
<p>India''s current-account shortfall decreased to $5.2 billion
in the third quarter of 2013, from $21.8 billion in the previous
three months, after Finance Minister Palaniappan Chidambaram
raised tariffs on gold in the world''s largest bullion-consuming
nation. Reserve Bank of India Governor Raghuram Rajan lured $34
billion of foreign-currency inflows by offering discounted swaps
for dollars raised by banks, one of his first steps on taking
office on Sept. 4. </p>
<p>Rajan has also raised interest rates three times so far,
helping curb consumer-price inflation to 8.79 percent last month
from as much as 11.2 percent in November. </p>
<h2>Rising Confidence </h2>
<p>Options are signaling increased confidence in the rupee as
external balances improve and price pressures cool. One-month
implied volatility, a gauge of expected moves in the exchange
rate used to price options, has eased to 8.17 percent from last
year''s peak of 22.4 percent in September, according to data
compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Carry traders, who borrow in currencies with lower yields
and buy those with higher rates, have earned 4.1 percent on
rupee investments using dollars since Sept. 30, the most among
23 emerging-market currencies tracked by Bloomberg. Favorable
policies will help the rupee and Indonesia''s rupiah perform
better than currencies of other nations with current-account
deficits such as Brazil, Turkey and South Africa, Goldman Sachs
Group Inc. economist Fiona Lake wrote in a Feb. 19 report. </p>
<p>The appointment of Rajan, an economist credited with
presaging the 2008 global financial crisis, as the RBI''s head
encouraged William Blair, which oversaw more than $72 billion as
of Dec. 31, to boost bullish positions on the rupee, according
to portfolio manager Singer. </p>
<p>The rupee is a cheap currency with significant carry,
he said in an interview in Melbourne yesterday. It has
deviated from fundamentals and should not be included in the
fragile five, he added, referring to a description used by
Morgan Stanley last year to describe currencies most vulnerable
to capital flight. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Duane D. Stanford" date="Feb 20, 2014  2:04 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-20/coca-cola-names-waller-finance-chief-as-fayard-retires.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Names Waller Finance Chief as Fayard Retires</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Coca-Cola Co. (KO) said Kathy Waller,
vice president of finance and controller, will become chief
financial officer, replacing Gary Fayard, who is retiring. </p>
<p>Waller, 55, joined Coca-Cola as a senior accountant in
1987, the Atlanta-based company said today in a statement.
Fayard, who is 62 years-old and has been CFO since 1999, will
retire in May. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Muhtar Kent is leading the world''s
largest soft-drink maker in a plan to cut $1 billion in costs by
2016 and plow the savings into marketing to help revive demand.
Earlier this week, Coca-Cola shares had their biggest one-day
decline in two months after the company posted fourth-quarter
results that showed North American soft-drink demand is
shrinking and growth in emerging markets was slowing. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola rose 0.6 percent to $37.30 at 1:52 p.m. in New
York. The shares fell 10 percent this year through yesterday,
compared with a 1.1 percent drop for the Standard  Poor''s 500
Index. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hugh Son" date="Feb 20, 2014 10:25 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-20/jpmorgan-revises-market-risk-gauge-to-show-trading-losses.html"><headline>JPMorgan Revises Market Risk Gauge to Show Trading Losses</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the biggest
U.S. bank, revised its gauge of market gains and losses to
incorporate new regulatory requirements, resulting in a jump in
the frequency of losses last year. </p>
<p>Under the new method, JPMorgan posted gains on 177 of the
260 trading days in 2013 and twice exceeded its estimated value-at-risk, according to the New York-based firm''s annual filing
with the Securities and Exchange Commission today. With the old
measurement, the bank had zero days of trading losses and never
surpassed its VaR target, the firm said. </p>
<p>Value at risk is one measure that banks use to gauge how
much traders could lose in a single day. JPMorgan disclosed in
June 2012 that a miscalculation in VaR was one reason the firm
failed to prevent a London-based trader from losing more than
$6.2 billion that year. The London Whale episode led to
criminal charges against two of the trader''s former colleagues,
management changes and more scrutiny from regulators. </p>
<p>JPMorgan''s new formula calculates gains and losses by
excluding fees, commissions, fair-value adjustments, net
interest income and intraday trading fluctuations, the firm
said. That''s consistent with what regulators use under
international standards known as Basel 2.5, the company said. </p>




Photographer: Peter Foley/Bloomberg

<p>
Pedestrians walk outside JPMorgan Chase  Co. offices in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lenka Ponikelska" date="Feb 20, 2014  6:41 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-20/general-sees-prague-s-bitcoin-atm-as-sales-springboard.html"><headline>General Sees Prague''s Bitcoin ATM as Sales Springboard</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>General Bytes s.r.o. wants to use
Prague''s first Bitcoin automated teller machine as a springboard
to expand abroad, seeking to make as many as 500 such ATMs a
month, the company''s founder said. </p>
<p>We aim to be competitive worldwide, Karel Kyovsky, the
company''s 34-year-old founder, said by phone today. Our
advantage is lower prices and the fact that the owner can
operate terminals remotely. </p>
<p>Prague-based General Bytes installed its ATM on Feb. 19 in
the Czech capital''s Holesovice district. The machine, which
Kyovsky said will cost less than $3,000, is operated by its own
computer and is based on the Android operational system.
Production should start in March and may reach its full capacity
of 500 machines a month as soon as April, he said, adding that
the plans hinge on orders. </p>
<p>General Bytes is among companies seeking to join the
Bitcoin frenzy. Bitcoins were introduced in 2008 by a programmer
or group of programmers under the name Satoshi Nakamoto.
Bitcoins exist as software and can potentially cut banking
transaction fees, making it an attractive option for trading via
the Web or in stores. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Louise Downing" date="Feb 20, 2014  3:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-20/morgan-stanley-backed-atlantis-raises-33-million-for-tidal-plan.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley-Backed Atlantis Raises $33 Million for Tidal Plan</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Atlantis Resources Corp., a Morgan
Stanley-backed maker of tidal turbines, raised 20 million pounds
($33 million) with a European grant, funds from a government
institution and an initial public offering in London. </p>
<p>The Singapore-based company raised 12 million pounds by
selling about 12.8 million new shares at 94 pence each on
London''s Alternative Investment Market, Chief Executive Officer
Tim Cornelius said. That values Atlantis at 72 million pounds. </p>
<p>Most investors were London-based institutions, with some
from continental Europe, Cornelius said. Morgan Stanley, which
had 45.7 percent before the placing, didn''t sell any shares. </p>
<p>We chose AIM because people in the U.K. market are
familiar with the renewables sector and there is good support,
Cornelius said. People understand the landscape here. </p>
<p>Atlantis also raised 8 million pounds through a cash grant
from the European Commission and from a government institution
that offered non-recourse financing repaid from future profits. </p>
<p>Funds investing in renewable energy have listed in London
in the past year as investors seek steady dividends that beat
returns on government bonds. Ingenious Media Holdings Plc last
month said it was planning to raise 160 million pounds. </p>
<p>The tidal-power industry is in its infancy, with developers
testing prototypes in the hope of bringing systems to market. As
yet there are no commercial-scale projects in operation. </p>
<p>It''s a growth story because we have a global portfolio
and it''s a new and emerging market, Cornelius said by phone.
From that perspective I think people tend to find it really
interesting. It''s not solar and it''s not wind. </p>
<h2>MeyGen Project </h2>
<p>Part of the proceeds will be spent on developing the 86-megawatt first phase of Atlantis''s MeyGen project in Scotland. </p>
<p>Construction is expected to start early in the second
quarter, generation is projected from early 2015, and capacity
may eventually reach as high as 398 megawatts. </p>
<p>The project seeks to take advantage of government subsidies
for the power it produces, with Scotland offering one of the
highest for tidal energy. Waters in the region are estimated to
account for as much as a quarter of Europe''s tidal resource. </p>
<p>Any remaining money from the funds raised will be invested
in development of turbine technology alongside Lockheed Martin
Corp. and for investments around the world, Cornelius said. The
company is pursuing projects in Canada, India and China. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Fox Hu and Zijing Wu" date="Feb 20, 2014  1:48 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-20/mobile-game-maker-chukong-said-to-plan-150-million-ipo-in-u-s-.html"><headline>Mobile Game-Maker Chukong Said to Plan $150 Million IPO in U.S.</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chukong Technologies Inc., a Chinese
mobile-gaming company, plans to seek about $150 million through
an initial public offering in the U.S., said two people with
knowledge of the matter. </p>
<p>Deutsche Bank AG and Morgan Stanley are helping prepare the
IPO, said the people, who asked not to be identified because the
information is private. Chukong, based in Beijing, aims to start
the offering in the second half, they said. </p>
<p>Founded in 2010, Chukong develops leisure games for
smartphones, according to the company''s website. Fishing Joy,
one of its most popular games, has attracted more than 200
million users in China, the website shows. </p>
<p>Chinese companies raised $907 million in U.S. initial
offerings last year, more than five times the amount for 2012,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. JD.com Inc., backed by
Russian billionaire Yuri Milner''s DST Global, filed last month
to raise $1.5 billion in what would be the largest IPO of a
Chinese Internet company in the U.S. </p>
<p>Chukong''s investors include Northern Light Venture Capital,
Steamboat Ventures, Sequoia Capital and GGV Capital, the website
shows. The phrase chukong means touch and control in Chinese.
Sequoia is the only venture investor in WhatsApp Inc., the
mobile messaging service that Facebook Inc. yesterday agreed to
buy for as much as $19 billion. </p>
<p>Officials at Chukong''s Beijing office were not immediately
available to comment on the IPO plan. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Meg Tirrell" date="Feb 20, 2014 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-20/jpmorgan-dad-starts-biotech-in-muscular-dystrophy-quest.html"><headline>JPMorgan Dad Starts Biotech in Muscular Dystrophy Quest</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Ilan Ganot, a hedge fund banker at
JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), left his life in finance to create a new
business model aimed at developing drugs more quickly. His son''s
life may depend on his success. </p>
<p>Since his 2-year-old was diagnosed a year ago with Duchenne
muscular dystrophy, a fatal genetic disease, Ganot quit his job
in London, moved his family to the Boston area, raised $17
million and founded a biotechnology company. </p>
<p>Ganot, 40, a former Israeli army captain, is one of a
generation of parents who are stepping in when medicine and
industry don''t move fast enough to save their children. Instead
of the usual approach of forming or supporting an advocacy
group, Ganot is using his roots in finance to start a business
aimed at getting treatments to market. </p>
<p>He''s a really exceptional example of a parent who says,
I''m going to take my skills and apply them to this problem,''
said Sharon Hesterlee, vice president of research at Parent
Project Muscular Dystrophy, a nonprofit focused on the disease.
You want them to solve world peace after this. </p>
<p>Ganot would settle for making a difference in the disease
afflicting his son, Eytani. There''s no cure for Duchenne
muscular dystrophy, which occurs when the body fails to produce
a protein called dystrophin that supports muscle fiber strength.
DMD puts kids in wheelchairs before their teens and is often
fatal in their 20s. </p>




Photographer: Jason Grow Photography via Bloomberg

<p>
Ilan Ganot and his son Eytani pose for a portrait on February 9, 2014. Eytani was diagnosed a year ago with Duchenne muscular dystrophy, a fatal genetic disease. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tim Culpan and Dina Bass" date="Feb 22, 2014 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-22/microsoft-said-to-cut-windows-price-70-to-counter-rivals.html"><headline>Microsoft Said to Cut Windows Price 70% to Counter Rivals</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) is cutting the price of Windows 8.1 by 70 percent for makers of low-cost computers and tablets as they try to fend off cheaper rivals like Google Inc. (GOOG)''s Chromebooks, people familiar with the program said. </p> <p>Manufacturers will be charged $15 to license Windows 8.1 and preinstall it on devices that retail for less than $250, instead of the usual fee of $50, said the people, who asked not to be named because the details aren''t public. The discount will apply to any products that meet the price limit, with no restrictions on the size or type of device, the people said. </p> <p>Stronger competition from Apple Inc. (AAPL) and Google cut revenue last quarter at Microsoft''s devices and consumer licensing division, which includes Windows software, as the computer industry posted its biggest annual decline on record. By offering incentives for PC makers to sell cheaper models, Microsoft may be able to increase its share of the growing $80 billion tablet market and stave off Chromebooks, notebooks that run Google''s operating system. </p> <p>Microsoft, which named Satya Nadella as chief executive officer earlier this month, is seeking to speed up development and introduction of new devices. It won''t require products that use the cheaper licensing to complete logo certification, a process that verifies hardware compatibility, one of the people said. Devices aren''t required to be touch-screen compatible, they said. </p> <p>Julia Kelly-Echeverio, a spokeswoman for Microsoft, declined to comment yesterday. </p> <h2>Slower Adoption </h2> <p>Microsoft said earlier this month that it has sold more than 200 million licenses of Windows 8 since the program went on sale in October 2012, a slower rate of adoption than the previous Windows 7. </p> <p>While the regular Windows list price was $50, some of the largest global computer makers paid closer to $30 after incentives such as marketing funds provided by Microsoft, the people said. Products that receive discounted license fees won''t be eligible for such marketing support and incentives, one of the people said. </p> <p>Global computer shipments fell a record 10 percent last year and are forecast to continue to decline this year as tablets and smartphones lure consumers away from traditional desktop and notebook designs, according to data from market research firm IDC. Tablet sales volume -- dominated by Apple and Google, whose operating systems account for 95 percent of that market -- will climb an average 16 percent through to 2017. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Anna Edney" date="Feb 24, 2014  4:08 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-24/pfizer-s-vaccine-meets-goals-in-post-approval-study.html"><headline>Pfizer''s Vaccine Meets Goals in Post-Approval Study</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE)''s pneumonia vaccine met
the goals of a study that was required by U.S. regulators when
the therapy was approved for patients at least 50 years old. </p>
<p>The clinical trial called Capita showed the vaccine worked
against a first episode of vaccine-type community-acquired
pneumonia in patients 65 and older, Pfizer said today in a
statement. The Food and Drug Administration approved Prevnar 13
for adults 50 and older in December 2011 on an accelerated basis
with the condition the New York company prove the shot protects
against pneumonia in post-clearance studies. </p>
<p>The vaccine is expected to generate $4.4 billion in revenue
this year, according to the average of three analysts'' estimates
compiled by Bloomberg. Prevnar 13 competes with Merck  Co.''s
Pneumovax 23, approved about 30 years ago. </p>
<p>The vaccine''s use in adults is expected to contribute $1
billion to sales, Mark Schoenebaum, an analyst with ISI Group,
said in a note today. </p>
<p>Pfizer rose 1.7 percent to $31.99 at the close in New York.
The company has gained 17 percent in the past 12 months. </p>
<p>The FDA approval was based on studies that showed patients
taking Prevnar 13 had comparable or higher antibody levels than
those taking Pneumovax 23. The results indicated the vaccine was
reasonably likely to produce clinical benefit, which is what
Pfizer sought to prove in the Capita trial. </p>
<p>Pfizer plans to share detailed results from the trial at a
conference in India on March 12, according to the statement. </p>
<p>Prevnar 13 was approved in the U.S. in 2010 for children 6
weeks to 5 years old. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Harry R. Weber" date="Feb 24, 2014  1:18 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-24/electricity-prices-jump-in-midwest-as-demand-exceeds-forecast.html"><headline>Electricity Prices Jump in Midwest as Demand Exceeds Forecast</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Spot wholesale power in the Midwest
jumped as demand exceeded expectations on the region''s grid. </p>
<p>Electricity use on the Midcontinent Independent System
Operator Inc. network, which stretches from Canada to the Gulf
Coast, averaged 83,622 megawatts at 12:15 p.m. New York time,
versus the day-ahead forecast of 83,578 megawatts. </p>
<p>The high temperature today in Indianapolis may reach 30
degrees Fahrenheit (minus 1 Celsius), 13 below the historical
average, according to AccuWeather Inc. in State College,
Pennsylvania. </p>
<p>Spot power at the benchmark Indiana hub rose $2.76, or 7.8
percent, to average $38.20 a megawatt hour for the hour ended at
11 a.m. local time from the same time Feb. 21, data compiled by
Bloomberg show. </p>
<p>At PJM Interconnection LLC''s benchmark Western hub, which
includes deliveries to Washington, spot power advanced $9.43, or
20 percent, to average $57.36 in the hour ended at noon New York
time. 21. Prices at the Eastern hub, which includes New Jersey,
jumped $9.83, or 19 percent, to average $61.26. </p>
<p>New York City spot power fell $3.34, or 2.6 percent, to
average $123.32 a megawatt hour at noon versus the same time
Feb. 21, while Boston power gained $40.20, or 27 percent, to
average $187.94. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Barinka" date="Feb 24, 2014  9:50 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-24/ibm-boosts-investment-in-new-cloud-services-to-attract-customers.html"><headline>IBM Boosts Investment in Cloud Services to Attract Customers</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM) is expanding its cloud services to lure customers to its
SoftLayer Technologies Inc. business, which it''s counting on to
help reverse seven quarters of falling sales. </p>
<p>IBM is making it easier for developers to build and adjust
applications in the cloud, where information is delivered online
instead of stored on local servers, said Danny Sabbah, chief
technology officer of IBM''s Next Generation Platform. The
Armonk, New York-based company plans to spend more than $1
billion on cloud-software development through 2015, a double-digit percentage increase from the past two years. </p>
<p>The move increases IBM''s bet on SoftLayer after acquiring
the company for $2 billion last year and committing $1.2 billion
in January to add 15 new data centers. As customers rely on the
cloud rather than buying their own servers, a slump in hardware
demand has contributed to IBM''s declining revenue. </p>
<p>This is crucial to expanding the potential audience and
helping them get benefit and value from using SoftLayer,
Sabbah said in an interview. This is not just about IBM''s
conventional enterprise customers. There will be a lot of
emerging companies in different areas. </p>
<p>The move underscores SoftLayer''s position as one of IBM''s
biggest gambles as it faces off with competitors such as
Amazon.com Inc. (AMZN) in cloud services. </p>
<h2>Big Bet </h2>
<p>The price IBM paid to acquire Dallas-based SoftLayer last
year was the biggest it has disclosed for a takeover since the
purchase of software company Lotus Development Corp. in 1995,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. SoftLayer is becoming
the backbone for IBM''s cloud business as the company wound down
its legacy SmartCloud Enterprise product this year, Lance Crosby, chief executive officer of SoftLayer, said in an
interview last month. </p>
<p>IBM is making these new capabilities available for
SoftLayer in hopes of attracting customers in different
industries than the typical bank and insurance clients that use
its cloud products at the moment, Sabbah said. One new addition
is an open-source enterprise software portfolio called BlueMix,
a platform-as-a-service that aims to help developers build
applications on its cloud infrastructure. </p>
<p>The service would rival existing platform-as-a-service
products like Amazon''s AWS Elastic Beanstalk, Heroku Inc.''s
development platform and Red Hat Inc.''s OpenShift. </p>
<p>IBM has agreed to acquire Cloudant Inc., a cloud-delivered
database company, whose services will be offered in the BlueMix
portfolio, the company said today in a statement. Financial
terms weren''t disclosed. </p>
<h2>Watson Services </h2>
<p>SoftLayer will also gain middleware offerings, including
WebSphere, to let apps be installed on hybrid clouds, which can
access data both onsite and offsite. </p>
<p>IBM also said last month that it would create a new
business division around its Watson technology, which can
analyze large volumes of data and answer questions in
conversational language. IBM will invest more than $1 billion in
the unit and give it a headquarters in New York. Watson''s big-data services, which let customers mine vast troves of
information, will be run on SoftLayer''s cloud. </p>
<p>IBM will integrate its Power Systems servers into
SoftLayer''s cloud to help support Watson and will make it
available in the second quarter of this year, said Robert Leblanc, senior vice president of software and cloud solutions
at IBM. </p>
<p>We''ve been shifting resources for a number of years into
this space, Leblanc, said in an interview. The $1 billion is
additional investment over the next two years to continue down
that path and bring even more services out to the cloud. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Samuel Potter" date="Feb 24, 2014  5:38 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-24/jpmorgan-rates-dp-world-at-buy-before-upgrade-islamic-finance.html"><headline>JPMorgan Rates DP World at Buy Before Upgrade: Islamic Finance</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. says investors
should buy record-low yielding sukuk from Dubai-based port
operator DP World Ltd. (DPW) and Jebel Ali Free Zone Authority FZE
before credit ratings improve. </p>
<p>The yield on DP World''s $1.5 billion Islamic bonds due July
2017 slid 61 basis points this year to 2.6 percent at 2:22 p.m.
in Dubai, the lowest level since they were sold in 2007. The
yield on Jafza''s sukuk maturing two years later fell 32 basis
points. Moody''s Investors Service and Fitch Ratings, which rate
DP World the lowest investment grade and business-park operator
Jafza junk, could raise both in 2014, JPMorgan said in a note
Feb. 18. </p>
<p>Dubai issuers are benefiting from an economic resurgence in
the Gulf business hub that''s boosting balance sheets, driving
funding costs lower and helping companies pay debt early. Emaar
Properties PJSC''s Islamic bond yields fell the most in more than
four months after the emirate''s biggest developer was raised by
Standard  Poor''s Feb. 5. </p>
<p>We continue seeing tangible credit momentum in Dubai
almost without exception, Zafar Nazim, a credit analyst at
JPMorgan Securities Ltd., said by phone Feb. 20. Companies are
paying off debt backed by strong cash flows, he said. </p>
<h2>Deep-Sea Port </h2>
<p>DP World lowered its net leverage by more than half since
its last upgrade three years ago, according to JPMorgan. At the
same time it invested in projects including London Gateway, a
new deep-sea port in the U.K. Jafza was raised to two steps
below investment grade by Moody''s in October after making
progress in reducing debt. </p>
<p>Jafza may not get to investment grade but they''re on
course for an upgrade with Moody''s given their deleveraging
trajectory, Nazim said. DP World was last upgraded in 2011
using 2010 numbers. Back in 2010 the world was still going
through a tight spot. </p>
<p>Moody''s said yesterday it doesn''t comment on speculation
regarding future rating actions. </p>
<p>Sukuk were among securities caught up in a developing
markets selloff last year when the U.S. said it would reduce its
$85 billion per-month bond-purchasing program. The yield on
Jafza''s debt climbed to as high as 5.84 percent June 26, while
that on DP World''s notes rose to 4.9 percent a day earlier. </p>
<h2>Another Bubble'' </h2>
<p>There are three main risks for the bonds, according to
Richard Segal, London-based head of international credit
strategy at Jeffries International Ltd. </p>
<p>Yields could rise if the U.S. Treasury (USGG10YR) market sells off
sharply again or if risk perceptions elsewhere in emerging
markets settle down and flight to quality flows reverse, he
said by e-mail Feb. 20. Segal sees a third risk if investors
begin to consider the possibility of another bubble in the
United Arab Emirates, he said. </p>
<p>Still, many feel equities are more expensive than fixed
income, so this is less of a near-term risk, Segal said. </p>
<p>Growing liquidity is another factor acting in DP World and
Jafza''s favor, Nazim said, as investors seek a place to put
their money. Sukuk sales from Dubai slowed this year, with $300
million raised compared with $750 million in the year-earlier
period. </p>
<p>Islamic bond sales in the emirate are expected to increase
as Dubai invests more than $8 billion preparing to host the
World Expo in 2020 and as $30 billion of debt comes due this
year. The sheikhdom, one of seven that make up the U.A.E., has a
stated ambition to become capital of the world''s Islamic economy
within three years. </p>
<p>Dubai expects economic growth to average 4.6 percent,
between 2012 and 2015, more than twice the pace as in the prior
four years. Amid the growth, property prices and trade are
soaring, helping Emaar, the operator of the world''s largest
mall, to regain the investment grade rating lost in 2009. </p>
<p>Upgrades will ensure that regional investors will get
more comfortable, Nazim said. You don''t need too many to
push the bonds tighter. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Feb 25, 2014  5:27 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-25/morgan-stanley-records-trading-losses-for-33-days-in-2013.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Records Trading Losses for 33 Days in 2013</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS), owner of the world''s
biggest brokerage, lost money in its trading businesses on 33
days last year, down from 37 days in 2012 and the fewest since
2006. </p>
<p>The bank''s traders lost money on six days in the fourth
quarter, compared with seven in the third, the New York-based
firm said in a regulatory filing today. Morgan Stanley made more
than $100 million on 14 days in 2013, the least since 2005. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer James Gorman, 55, has pitched
investors on a plan that relies more on wealth and asset
management and a trading business that produces less volatile
results. The number of days that featured gains of more than
$100 million or losses were both down by more than half from
their peaks. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s trading revenue, excluding accounting
charges, dropped 5 percent last year to the lowest since the
financial crisis as the firm shrank the amount of capital it
allocated to its fixed-income business. The bank generated the
second-most revenue from equity trading among the nine largest
global investment banks and the eighth-most from fixed income. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Feb 25, 2014  5:21 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-25/morgan-stanley-agrees-to-pay-275-million-to-resolve-sec-probe.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Agrees to Pay $275 Million to End SEC Probe</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) agreed to pay the
U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission $275 million to resolve
a probe into the sale of subprime mortgage-backed securities in
2007. </p>
<p>The SEC hasn''t presented the proposed settlement to the
commission and offered no assurance it will be accepted, the New
York-based bank said today in an annual regulatory filing. The
firm said it''s also responding to subpoenas and requests for
information from federal and state regulators in mortgage-related matters. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley listed nine legal matters it resolved or
settled since October, including agreements with MetLife Inc.
and Cambridge Place Investment Management Inc., as the largest
U.S. banks seek to put crisis-era lawsuits behind them. The firm
said its litigation costs more than tripled to $1.95 billion in
2013 from $513 million in 2012. </p>
<p>The company expects future litigation expenses in general
to continue to be elevated, and the changes in expenses from
period to period may fluctuate significantly, given the current
environment regarding financial crisis-related government
investigations and private litigation affecting global financial
services firms, the bank said in the filing. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley agreed this month to pay $1.25 billion to
settle a U.S. regulator''s claims the investment bank sold faulty
mortgage-backed securities to Fannie Mae (FNMA) and Freddie Mac. Morgan
Stanley took a $150 million charge to its fourth-quarter
results, after saying last month it added $1.2 billion to legal
reserves in the period related to mortgage-backed securities
litigation and investigations. </p>




Photographer: Victor J. Blue/Bloomberg

<p>
Morgan Stanley agreed this month to pay $1.25 billion to settle a U.S. regulator''s claims the investment bank sold faulty mortgage-backed securities to Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Anthony Palazzo" date="Feb 25, 2014  5:21 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-25/disney-starts-online-movie-service-in-itunes-alliance.html"><headline>Disney Starts Online Movie Service in ITunes Alliance</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS) started an online
movie service, Disney Movies Anywhere, with Apple Inc. (AAPL)''s iTunes
to increase sales of films such as Toy Story that can be
stored in Web-based accounts. </p>
<p>Movies can be played on Apple''s iPad, iPhone and iPod
Touch, as well as through the Internet, Burbank, California-based Disney said today in a statement. Users will be able to
link to iTunes and import films they''ve previously purchased
there to Disney Movies Anywhere accounts. </p>
<p>The service underscores a longstanding TV and film alliance
between Disney, the world''s largest entertainment company, and
Apple. Disney''s ABC television programs were the first to appear
on iTunes in 2005, and former Apple Chief Executive Officer
Steve Jobs sat on Disney''s board. Both companies stayed out of a
movie-industry initiative called Ultraviolet, meant to let users
buy movies from any studio or retailer and store them in a
cloud-based library. </p>
<p>Disney Movies Anywhere could stabilize Disney''s home-entertainment business, which has experienced lower results for
five consecutive years, Drew Crum, an analyst with Stifel
Nicolaus  Co., said in a report. He recommends buying Disney
stock. </p>
<p>Disney fell 0.6 percent to $80.21 at the close in New York.
The shares have advanced 5 percent in 2014, while the Standard 
Poor''s 500 Index is little changed. </p>
<p>Movie studios have been struggling with a decline in DVD
sales since the mid-2000s, when home-video revenue accounted for
more than two-thirds of film-industry sales. </p>
<h2>Changing Habits </h2>
<p>Audiences at home have turned to subscription services such
as Netflix Inc., or one-time movie rentals, available on iTunes,
Amazon.com, or through their pay-TV provider. These transactions
provide smaller profit margins to the studios. </p>
<p>Sales of DVD and Blu-ray discs fell 8.1 percent to $7.8
billion in the U.S. last year, according to the industry''s
Digital Entertainment Group, while electronic sales advanced 47
percent to $1.19 billion. Total sales declined 3.3 percent. </p>
<p>Subscription streaming advanced 32 percent to $3.16
billion. Total home-video spending increased 0.7 percent to
$18.2 billion. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hugh Son and Zeke Faux" date="Feb 25, 2014  2:33 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-25/jpmorgan-names-rauchenberger-compliance-chief-after-armine-quits.html"><headline>JPMorgan Compliance Chief Armine Leaves Post After a Year</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the lender
whose legal and regulatory battles led to more than $23 billion
in settlements in 2013, said Chief Compliance Officer Cindy Armine left to join another firm after a year on the job. </p>
<p>Lou Rauchenberger, the chief administrative officer of the
corporate and investment bank, was named as interim replacement,
according to a staff memo from Chief Operating Officer Matt Zames obtained by Bloomberg News. </p>
<p>The departure was reported earlier today by the Wall Street
Journal, which said Armine is moving to First Data Corp., the
payment processor run by former JPMorgan executive Frank Bisignano. He left JPMorgan last year when Chief Executive
Officer Jamie Dimon named Zames sole chief operating officer at
the bank. Bisignano hired JPMorgan''s former Chief Information
Officer Guy Chiarello as president last year. </p>
<p>JPMorgan has clashed with regulators and law enforcement
officials over accusations that it misled buyers of mortgage
bonds, rigged markets and overlooked suspicious activity by
clients. The company agreed last month to pay $2.6 billion to
settle allegations that it ignored signs of wrongdoing in
Bernard Madoff''s Ponzi scheme. </p>
<p>As Jamie and our leadership team have said, controls and
compliance are our most important priority, Zames wrote. We
have made great progress over the past few years on our controls
agenda, and we will continue to focus on it relentlessly. </p>
<p>Managers will seek to ensure a fortress compliance and
control environment, according to a slide show today at an
annual presentation for investors. </p>
<p>Armine joined the firm in May 2011 as chief control officer
of home lending after 31 years at Citigroup Inc., where she was
chief compliance officer. She was promoted to JPMorgan''s head of
compliance in January 2013. Attempts to reach Armine for comment
weren''t immediately successful. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore and Hugh Son" date="Feb 25, 2014  1:23 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-25/jpmorgan-boosts-profit-goal-to-27-billion-amid-job-cuts.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sees Profit Up 50% in Five Years Amid Job Cuts</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) said the bank
can increase profit 50 percent in the next four to five years as
higher rates boost interest margins and the firm cuts 5,500 more
jobs from retail units than it had forecast. </p>
<p>Profit can reach $27 billion if legal costs subside and
income from loans and investments improves, the New York-based
company said today in a slide presentation for its annual
investor day. The bank now plans to eliminate about 8,000 jobs
in consumer and mortgage banking this year as demand wanes for
refinancings. Hiring in areas such as compliance and risk
management will offset some of the cuts, the company said. </p>
<p>Managers led by Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon are
laying out strategy at the biggest U.S. bank by assets after a
year marred by clashes with regulators and $23 billion in legal
costs. Dimon, 57, is seeking to accelerate growth and trim
unwanted units while fending off allegations that the firm
misled buyers of mortgage bonds, rigged markets and ignored
suspicious activity by clients. </p>
<p>We now have clarity on most of the regulatory rules, and
we believe that we, more than others, will successfully adapt to
the new financial architecture and will emerge where we started
-- with best-in-class margins and returns, Chief Financial
Officer Marianne Lake said at the investor conference. </p>




Photographer: Matthew Lloyd/Bloomberg

<p>
JPMorgan Chase  Co. said it expects $3.5 billion of net income by 2017 from expansions in businesses including middle-market lending and private banking. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Louise Downing" date="Feb 25, 2014  7:10 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-25/morgan-stanley-backed-atlantis-carnegie-wave-to-cut-power-costs.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley-Backed Atlantis, Carnegie Wave to Cut Power Costs</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Carnegie Wave Energy Ltd. and
Atlantis Resources Corp. agreed to work together on driving down
the cost of ocean-power technologies. </p>
<p>Carnegie, a developer of wave-energy systems, and Morgan
Stanley-backed tidal device maker Atlantis will jointly work on
technology and project developments to cut costs, Perth,
Australia-based Carnegie said today in a statement on its
website. </p>
<p>Collaboration between developers in the marine energy
space is both essential for progress to be continued to be made
and inevitable as marine energy technologies and markets
mature, Michael Ottaviano, managing director of Carnegie, said
in the statement. </p>
<p>The wave and tidal energy industry is still in its infancy
with developers testing prototype and pre-commercial systems as
they aim to bring their devices to market. Energy from the waves
currently costs about $496 a megawatt-hour and tidal about $440
a megawatt-hour. That compares with coal-fired power at $82 a
megawatt-hour, according to Bloomberg estimates. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Feb 25, 2014 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-25/microsoft-ceo-moves-larson-green-to-software-and-services.html"><headline>Microsoft CEO Moves Larson-Green to Software and Services</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) hardware group chief
Julie Larson-Green will move to the software maker''s
applications and services unit in the first executive shift by
Microsoft Chief Executive Officer Satya Nadella since he took
over earlier this month. </p>
<p>As chief experience officer, she''ll be responsible for
modern digital experiences regardless of device, Larson-Green wrote in an e-mail yesterday, obtained by Bloomberg News.
Larson-Green will switch to the new role once former Nokia Oyj
CEO Stephen Elop returns to Microsoft to lead the company''s
hardware efforts. </p>
<p>Larson-Green, who started at Microsoft 21 years ago, had
been put in charge of all hardware in a sweeping reorganization
in July. That group is responsible for Xbox and the company''s
push into gadgets such as tablets, which so far is faltering as
consumers and businesses shun the company''s Surface computer in
favor of the iPad from Apple Inc. and mobile machines from
Samsung Electronics Co. </p>
<p>Dawn Beauparlant, a spokeswoman for Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft, confirmed the e-mail''s authenticity and Larson-Green''s new job title. She declined to comment further and said
Larson-Green wasn''t available for comment. </p>
<p>Microsoft said in September that Larson-Green, who led a
design overhaul of both Office and Windows, would be superseded
as leader of the unit that makes Xboxes and video games by Elop
when the $7.2 billion acquisition of the Nokia handset unit
closes and joins Microsoft''s hardware unit. </p>
<p>Nadella was appointed CEO earlier this month after a five-month search, charged with speeding up a turnaround at the
world''s biggest software maker. </p>
<p>Larson-Green''s move was reported earlier by GeekWire. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Jacob" date="Feb 26, 2014  4:51 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-26/jpmorgan-adopts-pew-disclosure-form-for-prepaid-card-fees.html"><headline>JPMorgan Adopts Pew Disclosure Form for Prepaid Card Fees</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the biggest
U.S. bank by assets, adopted a new disclosure form for its
prepaid card to provide greater clarity on fees. </p>
<p>The disclosure, based on a model released by Pew Charitable
Trusts, gives customers a description of fees and when deposits
are available in an easy-to-read format, the New York-based bank
said today in a statement. Pew is a Washington-based non-profit
research firm specializing in trends and public attitudes. </p>
<p>Government agencies including the Consumer Financial
Protection Bureau are pushing financial firms to make their
retail products easier to understand. The amount loaded onto
prepaid cards by U.S. consumers more than doubled in 2012 to $64
billion from 2009, according to Pew''s website. </p>
<p>This disclosure box should be required by the Consumer
Financial Protection Bureau for all general purpose reloadable
prepaid cards, Susan Weinstock, director of Pew''s safe
checking research, said on the trust''s website. </p>
<p>Samuel Gilford, spokesman for the Consumer Financial
Protection Bureau, didn''t immediately respond to inquiries about
the Pew standard. U.S. Senator Mark R. Warner, a Virginia
Democrat on the Banking Committee, has introduced legislation
requiring financial institutions to be more upfront with prepaid
cards. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christie Smythe" date="Feb 26, 2014  4:47 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-26/jpmorgan-goldman-sachs-reach-interim-surveys-deals.html"><headline>JPMorgan, Goldman, 16 Other Firms to End Analyst Previews</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) and Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) were among 18 financial firms that agreed to stop participating in some surveys of analyst sentiment while New York investigates early access to the information. </p> <p>The firms will stop answering analyst surveys by certain elite, technologically sophisticated clients seeking to use the information for trading, according to New York Attorney General Eric Schneiderman. The interim pacts are part of efforts to combat advantages secured by investors that get to see potentially market-moving data before other traders. </p> <p>Schneiderman requested that the firms stop participating in these surveys while he conducts an industry wide investigation into early access to analyst sentiment. The deals follow an accord last month with BlackRock Inc. (BLK), the world''s largest asset manager, to end a program in which it systematically surveyed analysts on companies they cover. </p> <p>Opinion: What Does Eric Schneiderman Know That the Rest of Us Don''t?</p><p>Our markets will only be fair and healthy if everyone plays by the same rules, which is why we will continue to take action against those who provide unfair advantages to elite traders at the expense of the rest of us, Schneiderman said yesterday in an e-mailed statement. </p>




Photographer: Brendan Bannon/Bloomberg

<p>
Eric Schneiderman, attorney general for New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sridhar Natarajan" date="Feb 26, 2014  4:37 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-26/goldman-s-gmelich-likens-loan-inflows-to-one-way-freight-train.html"><headline>Goldman''s Gmelich Likens Junk Loans to One-Way Freight Train</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Investors who have been pouring
money into funds that purchase leveraged loans need to be wary
of a reversal in demand, according to Justin Gmelich, the head
of credit trading at Goldman Sachs Group Inc. </p>
<p>It''s been a bit of a one-way freight train, Gmelich
said in a question and answer session, posted on the company''s
website yesterday. I would just caution those that are
involved in the loan space to be mindful of the fact that
they''ve been beneficiaries of inflows for 88 straight weeks and
the tide can turn. </p>
<p>The floating-rate debt, which offers a shield for investors
from rising rates, has seen unprecedented demand with the funds
that purchase the debt receiving deposits every single week
since the summer of 2012. That enabled speculative-grade
companies to raise $676 billion last year of bank debt, with
more than 80 percent of that used to escape maturing debt
deadlines, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Leveraged loans in the U.S. have returned 1.2 percent this
year, after gains of 5.3 percent in 2013, according to the
Standard  Poor''s/LSTA Leveraged Loan index. Loans, which are
ranked higher up in the capital structure than junk bonds in
case of a bankruptcy, are better protected from rising interest
rates since they are generally pegged to floating-rate
benchmarks. The value of a fixed-rate security diminishes with
an increase in rates. </p>
<h2>Rate Protection </h2>
<p>Folks have been shrewd enough to try to protect against
some of the rate shock, Gmelich said. When you see fund
flows reverse, irrespective of whether or not the credit quality
is good, you see a risk retracement. </p>
<p>Retail inflow into loan mutual funds exceeded $63 billion
last year and have already netted $4.6 billion this year,
according to a Feb. 20 report from Bank of America Corp.
Companies have been able to find willing lenders as the assets
managed by mutual funds investing in the debt swelled to more
than $150 billion from about $70 billion at the start of last
year, according to data from the bank. </p>
<p>Leveraged loans and high-yield, high-risk, or junk, bonds
are rated below Baa3 by Moody''s Investors Service and lower than
BBB- at SP. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Barinka and Cornelius Rahn" date="Feb 26, 2014  2:01 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-26/ibm-encourages-software-developers-to-make-apps-on-watson.html"><headline>IBM Encourages Software Developers to Make Apps on Watson</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM) is encouraging software developers to build applications
on its artificial-intelligence system Watson, looking to data
analytics to help reverse falling revenue. </p>
<p>IBM will host a mobile developer challenge that urges
programmers to create consumer and business apps powered by
Watson, Chief Executive Officer Ginni Rometty said in a speech
today at the Mobile World Congress in Barcelona. In three
months, the company will choose three prototypes to receive
design consulting and support to develop commercial apps. </p>
<p>IBM has been increasing its investment in Watson as the
Armonk, New York-based company works to show clients the value
of the technology, which analyzes troves of data and can answer
questions in conversational language. The company said in
January that it will spend $1 billion to create a new division
around Watson to help spur growth after seven consecutive
quarters of declining revenue. </p>
<p>You run a business today and you reinvent it for the
future at the same time, Rometty said. You go through these
transitions. If you try to compare today to the past, today the
speed is much faster. </p>
<p>As sluggish demand for computer hardware has hurt sales,
IBM has focused on more profitable, faster-growing areas such as
data analytics and cloud computing, and the company has also
sold hardware businesses. Watson and other big-data services
were the company''s primary focus in 2013, Rometty said in March.
Last year, IBM boosted its expected sales from the data-analysis
business to $20 billion in 2015, compared with an earlier
forecast of $16 billion. </p>




Photographer: Angel Navarrete/Bloomberg

<p>
IBM will host a mobile developer challenge that urges programmers to create consumer and business apps powered by Watson, Chief Executive Officer Ginni Rometty said in a speech today at the Mobile World Congress in Barcelona. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David M. Levitt and Hugh Son" date="Feb 26, 2014  1:29 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-26/jpmorgan-said-to-plan-move-of-2-000-workers-to-brooklyn.html"><headline>JPMorgan Said to Plan Move of 2,000 Workers to Brooklyn</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the biggest U.S. lender, is moving about 2,000 employees to offices in Brooklyn''s MetroTech Center after a review of its real estate holdings, said a person with direct knowledge of the plan. </p> <p>The biggest single source of employees heading to Brooklyn by year-end is 1 Chase Manhattan Plaza, the 60-story lower Manhattan skyscraper the bank sold to Shanghai-based Fosun International Ltd. (656) in 2013, said the person, who asked not to be identified because the move isn''t public. The employees are from several of the bank''s business lines, the person said. </p> <p>JPMorgan is consolidating its real estate as it pushes to trim expenses and simplify itself by exiting businesses including student lending and private equity. Offices in and near downtown Brooklyn, where MetroTech Center is located, are among the most in demand in the city, in particular drawing young technology and social-media companies. </p> <p>If JPMorgan follows through with its plans, it will show that the market also can appeal to traditional financial firms while it tries to attract and retain young talent, said Tucker Reed, president of the Downtown Brooklyn Partnership, a group representing local businesses. </p> <p>Were they to come, it would be a validation of our office market here, Reed said in a telephone interview. The only drawback, if you can call it that, would be the challenge it creates. It means there would be even less office space for us to grow into. It makes our space dilemma a little more acute, but that''s a good problem to have. </p> <h2>Tightest Market </h2> <p>Brooklyn''s 15.5 million square feet (1.4 million square meters) of offices are more than 96 percent occupied, data from CBRE Group Inc. show. By comparison, Manhattan''s tightest office market -- the area roughly from 30th to Canal streets, known as midtown south -- has a 93 percent occupancy rate, according to the real estate services firm. </p> <p>MetroTech Center is a 3.7 million-square-foot office campus close to the Brooklyn and Manhattan bridges. JPMorgan owns two buildings at the complex. </p> <p>Another group of Chase Plaza-based staff members is bound for the bank''s offices at the Newport office complex on Washington Street in Jersey City, New Jersey, the person said. The transfers started in December and will continue throughout 2014, according to the person. </p> <p>The lender intends to keep about 300,000 to 400,000 square feet of offices at Chase Plaza, the person said. JPMorgan occupied about half the space in the 2.2 million-square-foot tower, according to data from CoStar Group Inc. </p> <p>We''re continually looking at ways to ensure that our space and occupancy strategy aligns with the ever-evolving needs of our business, Melissa Shuffield, a spokeswoman for the bank, said in an e-mail. </p> <h2>MetroTech Space </h2> <p>As recently as 2012, JPMorgan considered giving up at least some of its offices at MetroTech, listing about 700,000 square feet for rent, according to the person. After floods from Hurricane Sandy damaged bank offices at 4 New York Plaza, another downtown Manhattan tower, displaced workers were moved temporarily into the Brooklyn space. </p> <p>JPMorgan owns 4 MetroTech Center, with about 1.35 million square feet, and 3 MetroTech Center, according to Mrofficespace.com, a website that tracks New York office buildings. The other six buildings at the office park are owned by Forest City Ratner Cos., which started building MetroTech in the late 1980s. </p> <p>The 16-acre (6.5-hectare) campus was Brooklyn''s first modern office development, built in partnership with the New York City government. Many of its earlier tenants have been financial firms, including Bank of New York and Bear Stearns Cos., which used the properties for back-office operations. </p> <p>In recent years, the complex has attracted technology and media companies such as MakerBot Industries LLC, a developer of three-dimensional printers; and ImpreMedia LLC, which publishes Hispanic newspapers including New York''s El Diario La Prensa. </p> <p>Downtown Brooklyn has now become a very diverse ecosystem of varied companies that are more reflective of all of Brooklyn and all of New York City, said Ali Esmaeilzadeh, vice president of commercial development and leasing at Forest City Ratner. There''s still the presence of government and back-office, there''s also a surge in technology-based firms, entrepreneurial-type companies. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Feb 26, 2014  1:25 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-26/morgan-stanley-promotes-o-connor-to-lead-brokerage-s-workforce.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Promotes O''Connor to Lead Firm''s Brokers</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) named Shelley O''Connor to lead its brokerage workforce, the world''s largest,
replacing Doug Ketterer, who was appointed head of strategy and
client management. </p>
<p>Eric Heaton was named to succeed O''Connor as head of the
private banking group, Greg Fleming, president of wealth
management for Morgan Stanley, said today in a memo to
employees. Jim Wiggins, a spokesman for the New York-based firm,
confirmed the contents of the memo. </p>
<p>Fleming is shuffling wealth management leaders after
boosting the unit''s targets for margins following its most
profitable year. Morgan Stanley doubled the size of its
brokerage through a joint venture with Citigroup Inc. (C) in 2009,
buying that bank''s remaining stake in the business last year. </p>
<p>O''Connor, 53, who was added to the bank''s operating
committee this month, will oversee 16,456 advisers and 649
branches as head of field management. She will manage the unit''s
three geographic regions and private-wealth business. </p>
<p>Given the breadth of her experience and proven ability to
execute strategies focused on clients and advisers, she is
ideally suited to lead the field, Fleming wrote in the memo. </p>
<p>Ketterer, who ran private-wealth management before taking
over field management in 2012, will take a new role developing
strategies for gaining customers among wealthy individuals,
foreign citizens and corporations, according to the memo. </p>
<h2>Strategy Focus </h2>
<p>Doug will focus on our overall client strategy,
acquisition and retention initiatives, how we engage with
clients, and our client-facing platforms, Fleming wrote.
Doug''s experience in each of our wealth-management,
investment-management and institutional businesses will serve us
well in this new function. </p>
<p>Heaton, who worked with Fleming at Merrill Lynch  Co. and
was recruited to Morgan Stanley in 2012, takes over O''Connor''s
role of helping the company boost lending to 4 million brokerage
clients. Morgan Stanley has said it wants 10 percent of its
customers to have loans with the firm, up from the current 5
percent. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Freeman Klopott" date="Feb 26, 2014 12:14 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-26/disney-is-said-set-to-film-marvel-series-for-netflix-in-new-york.html"><headline>Disney Set to Film Marvel Series for Netflix in New York</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS) will film a live-action series for Netflix Inc. (NFLX) with Marvel superheroes in New
York City, the biggest production commitment in state history,
Governor Andrew Cuomo said. </p>
<p>Cuomo, who announced the deal today in Manhattan, is
providing incentives valued at about $4 million, said an aide,
who spoke on the condition of anonymity because the details
aren''t public. In November, Disney agreed to create four
television series for Netflix using Marvel characters such as
Daredevil, adding to the online-streaming video service''s
growing lineup of orginal content. </p>
<p>New York is where the entertainment industry started, and
this unprecedented commitment from Disney and Marvel is further
evidence that we''re bringing it back bigger and better than ever
before, Cuomo said in an e-mailed statement. The competition
for these projects is fierce. </p>
<p>Disney''s Marvel TV will start bringing the shows to Netflix
in 2015, according to a November statement. They will focus on
heroes battling villains in New York''s Hell''s Kitchen. Netflix
committed to a minimum of four 13-episode series, culminating in
the miniseries The Defenders. </p>
<p>Netflix, based in Los Gatos, California, is gaining more
Disney content following an agreement in 2012 for rights to show
movies including Marvel, Pixar and Lucasfilm titles. </p>
<p>Our Marvel series for Netflix will inject millions
directly into the local economy and create hundreds of new
jobs, said Robert Iger, chief executive officer of Burbank,
California-based Disney, in an e-mailed statement. </p>
<p>The Wall Street Journal reported the deal earlier today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri" date="Feb 26, 2014 11:24 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-26/disney-s-marvel-to-film-four-netflix-series-in-new-york.html"><headline>Disney''s Marvel to Film Four Netflix Series in New York</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS)''s Marvel announced
plans to film four television programs and a miniseries in New
York as part of its plans to create shows for Netflix Inc. </p>
<p>The plans were announced today by Governor Andrew M. Cuomo
and Robert Iger, Disney''s chairman and chief executive officer.
Filming is set to start later this year and will create at least
3,000 jobs in the state, including as many as 400 full-time
positions, they said. </p>
<p>The project will include almost 60 one-hour episodes
focused on the 4 Defenders characters: Daredevil, Jessica Jones,
Luke Cage and Iron Fist. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Aoife White" date="Feb 26, 2014  6:40 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-26/visa-europe-settles-eu-antitrust-probe-with-credit-card-fees-cut.html"><headline>Visa Europe Settles EU Antitrust Probe With Credit-Card Fees Cut</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Visa Europe Ltd.''s pledge to reduce
credit-card fees was accepted by European Union regulators in a
settlement that ends an antitrust probe that dates back more
than a decade. </p>
<p>Visa Europe, operator of the EU''s largest payment-card
network, will cap so-called interbank fees for processing credit
card payments to 0.3 percent of the value of the transaction for
cross-border and domestic payments in Europe for four years,
from Jan. 1, 2015. The commitment will reduce card charges by 40
percent to 60 percent. </p>
<p>Card fees charged by Visa Europe and MasterCard Inc. have
been probed by European Union regulators since at least 2002.
MasterCard is currently challenging a similar settlement at the
EU''s highest court, saying such multilateral interchange fees
are crucial for sharing the costs of card payments among banks,
retailers and customers. </p>
<p>The agreement provides legal certainty and allows the
company focus on its payment business rather than pursuing
lengthy legal cases, Nicholas Huss, Visa Europe''s chief
executive officer, said in an e-mailed statement. Visa Europe
will also make its pricing more transparent to help retailers
compare rates. </p>
<p>A 0.3 percent cap on credit card fees for payments that
customers make in their home nation will be applied after a two-year delay to deter banks switching to cards with higher
charges, the EU said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Feb 26, 2014 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-26/morgan-stanley-deferred-awards-for-2013-hit-2-72-billion.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Deferred Awards for 2013 Hit $2.72 Billion</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS), owner of the world''s
largest brokerage, gave employees $2.72 billion in deferred
awards for 2013 performance as the firm disclosed the amount for
the first time. </p>
<p>The bank will recognize $1.74 billion of the awards this
year, assuming no forfeitures, cancellations or accelerations,
the firm said yesterday in an annual regulatory filing. Morgan
Stanley also may face $831 million of costs in 2014 from
previous awards. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley, which deferred 100 percent of 2012 bonuses
for many senior bankers, paid some portion of awards for last
year''s performance in immediate cash. The bank still deferred at
least half of bonuses for any employees who have both total pay
of at least $350,000 and incentive pay of $50,000, a person
familiar with the matter said last month. </p>
<p>The total cost of deferred awards in 2014 may be as much as
$2.57 billion, excluding costs tied to returns on investments
made with deferred cash. That''s equal to 2013''s result on the
same basis. The final number will probably be lower as employees
leave before their stock and cash vest. </p>
<p>Employees who got deferred equity awards over the last two
years have benefited as Morgan Stanley''s stock doubled,
including a 64 percent jump in 2013. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Feb 26, 2014 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-26/morgan-stanley-to-pay-275-million-to-resolve-sec-probe.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley to Pay $275 Million to Resolve SEC Probe</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) agreed to pay the
U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission $275 million to resolve
a probe into the sale of subprime mortgage-backed securities in
2007. </p>
<p>The SEC hasn''t presented the proposed settlement to the
commission and offered no assurance it will be accepted, the New
York-based bank said yesterday in an annual regulatory filing.
The firm said it''s also responding to subpoenas and requests for
information from federal and state regulators in mortgage-related matters. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley listed nine legal matters it resolved or
settled since October, including agreements with MetLife Inc. (MET)
and Cambridge Place Investment Management Inc., as the largest
U.S. banks seek to put crisis-era lawsuits behind them. The firm
said its litigation costs more than tripled to $1.95 billion in
2013 from $513 million in 2012. </p>
<p>The company expects future litigation expenses in general
to continue to be elevated, and the changes in expenses from
period to period may fluctuate significantly, given the current
environment regarding financial crisis-related government
investigations and private litigation affecting global financial
services firms, the bank said in the filing. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley agreed this month to pay $1.25 billion to
settle a U.S. regulator''s claims the investment bank sold faulty
mortgage-backed securities to Fannie Mae (FNMA) and Freddie Mac. (FMCC) Morgan
Stanley took a $150 million charge to its fourth-quarter
results, after saying last month it added $1.2 billion to legal
reserves in the period related to mortgage-backed securities
litigation and investigations. </p>
<h2>Due Diligence </h2>
<p>The bank said yesterday it is responding to subpoenas and
requests for information from members of the RMBS Working Group
of the Financial Fraud Enforcement Task Force. </p>
<p>These matters include, but are not limited to,
investigations related to the company''s due diligence on the
loans that it purchased for securitization, the company''s
communications with ratings agencies, the company''s disclosures
to investors, and the company''s handling of servicing and
foreclosure related issues, the firm said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Barinka" date="Feb 28, 2014  4:15 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-28/ibm-starts-cutting-u-s-jobs-in-1-billion-restructuring.html"><headline>IBM Starts Cutting U.S. Jobs in $1 Billion Restructuring</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM) began dismissing U.S. workers yesterday, part of a $1
billion restructuring to help the company meet profit goals as
it adapts to shifts in the technology industry. </p>
<p>Workers in New York, Vermont, Minnesota, Iowa, Missouri,
Oklahoma and North Carolina were fired yesterday, according to
Alliance@IBM, an employee group. The Armonk, New York-based
company had a headcount of 431,212 at the end of 2013, down 0.7
percent from a year earlier -- its first decline in a decade. </p>
<p>IBM is aiming for $20 a share in adjusted earnings by 2015,
up from $11.67 in 2010 -- a target made more difficult by seven
straight quarters of falling revenue. To get there, Chief
Executive Officer Ginni Rometty has fired and furloughed
workers, sold assets, cut IBM''s tax rate and bought back shares. </p>
<p>The company has already begun eliminating positions this
year in Europe, Asia and South America, according to
Alliance@IBM. Worldwide, this year''s job cuts could lead to the
elimination of at least 13,000 employees, Toni Sacconaghi, an
analyst at Sanford C. Bernstein  Co., said in a Feb. 3 report. </p>
<p>Rometty is seeking to transform IBM as clients shift to
storing their data and applications offsite, or in the cloud,
rather than buying their own servers. </p>
<p>IBM continues to rebalance its workforce to meet the
changing requirements of its clients and to pioneer new, high-value segments of the IT industry, the company said in a
statement yesterday. At any given time, IBM has more than 3,000
job openings in its growth units, including its cloud business
and nanotechnology, the company said. </p>
<h2>Hudson Valley </h2>
<p>IBM had agreed to keep high-technology jobs in New York''s
Hudson Valley through 2016, increasing the number of positions
it has pledged to retain by 750 to 3,100, New York Governor
Andrew Cuomo said this week in a statement. That would restore
the 697 workers fired last year in Dutchess County, where the
company had about 8,000 employees as of 2012, according to the
county government. </p>
<p>Firings took place yesterday in Endicott and Poughkeepsie,
New York, Alliance@IBM said. </p>
<p>The job cuts in New York raise questions about the newly
brokered deal between the company and the state, said
Assemblyman Kieran Lalor, who represents Fishkill, New York.
Fishkill is a town in Dutchess County, where IBM has a
semiconductor chip manufacturing plant. </p>
<p>Both the state and IBM have been short on details about
the agreement, Lalor said in a letter dated Feb. 27 to Cuomo,
requesting disclosure of how many people IBM employs in New York
and information on the 3,900 jobs not guaranteed under the plan. </p>
<h2>Chip Plants </h2>
<p>IBM also makes semiconductor chips at its plant in
Burlington, Vermont, and servers in Rochester, Minnesota,
according to its website. The company has a delivery center in
Dubuque, Iowa, that was to create as many as 1,300 jobs when it
opened in 2009. The facility provides services including
outsourcing-client support, server-systems operations, security
services, and maintenance of hardware and software, according to
the website. IBM dismissed workers in all three cities, in
addition to Columbia, Missouri; Tulsa, Oklahoma; and the
Raleigh, North Carolina, area, Alliance@IBM said. </p>
<p>The company has already begun eliminating positions this
year in Europe, Asia and South America, according to
Alliance@IBM. </p>
<h2>Global Restructuring </h2>
<p>As part of the shift in its focus to products like cloud
services and data analytics, the company agreed in January to
sell its low-end server division for $2.3 billion to Lenovo. IBM
said it expects to send more than 7,000 workers to the Chinese
computer maker in the transaction. </p>
<p>The company is focused on finding a joint-venture partner
for its chip-manufacturing business after failing to attract a
buyer for the division, two people with knowledge of the matter
said this month. </p>
<p>IBM was little changed at $185.17 at the close of trading
in New York. The shares are up less than 1 percent since the
start of Rometty''s tenure at the beginning of 2012, compared
with a 48 percent gain for the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bob Van Voris" date="Feb 28, 2014  2:50 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-28/jpmorgan-300-million-accord-over-kickback-claim-approved.html"><headline>JPMorgan $300 Million Accord Over Kickback Claim Approved</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A $300 million settlement by
JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) and insurers with homeowners who accused
the bank of taking kickbacks in exchange for sticking them with
overpriced insurance policies was approved by a judge. </p>
<p>U.S. District Judge Federico Moreno in Miami today approved
the accord. It requires JPMorgan, Assurant Inc. (AIZ) and other
insurers to pay refunds valued at 12.5 percent of annual premium
costs to homeowners who had certain policies placed on their
properties by the bank starting in January 2008. JPMorgan and
Assurant didn''t admit wrongdoing. </p>
<p>The homeowners sued New York-based JPMorgan last year,
claiming the bank placed required hazard and wind coverage with
Assurant and other insurers at inflated rates. Some of the
excess costs were kicked back to a JPMorgan unit, the homeowners
alleged in their class-action, or group, lawsuit. </p>
<p>JPMorgan is among several large banks facing claims by
homeowners that they overcharged mortgage borrowers for lender-placed insurance. Last year, New York-based Assurant agreed to
pay $14 million to resolve similar allegations by the New York
State Department of Financial Services. </p>
<p>In his ruling, Moreno rejected objections to the settlement
and approved $20 million in fees to lawyers for the class. </p>
<p>The case is Saccoccio v. JPMorgan Chase Bank NA, 13-cv-21107, U.S. District Court, Southern District of Florida
(Miami). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Feb 28, 2014  2:43 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-28/goldman-sachs-s-egol-retires-after-heading-team-that-made-abacus.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs''s Egol Retires After Heading Team That Made Abacus</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Jonathan Egol, a Goldman Sachs Group
Inc. trader whose desk produced the security that prompted the
Securities and Exchange Commission to sue the firm, has retired. </p>
<p>Egol, 44, left the New York-based bank earlier this year,
said Michael DuVally, a company spokesman. He joined the firm in
1998 and was named a managing director in 2007. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs paid a then-record $550 million in 2010 to
settle an SEC suit over the marketing of a synthetic
collateralized debt obligation dubbed Abacus 2007-AC1. The firm
created a committee that year to review its business standards
and practices. </p>
<p>The SEC sued Fabrice Tourre, 35, one of the employees under
Egol, after dropping a plan to file claims against Egol,
according to interviews with SEC enforcement staff conducted by
the agency''s inspector general. Tourre was found liable in a
jury trial last year in which the SEC claimed he intentionally
misled investors in the deal. </p>
<p>Egol testified in Tourre''s trial in July that he was not
aware of any disclosures to investors that Paulson  Co.,
which stood to make money from the failure of the transaction,
helped select the assets underlying it. Egol said Tourre did
tell a superior that the hedge-fund firm run by billionaire John Paulson helped pick the portfolio of 90 subprime mortgage-backed
securities. </p>
<p>The Wall Street Journal reported the departure earlier
today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Harry R. Weber" date="Feb 28, 2014 12:20 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-28/electricity-prices-in-mid-atlantic-rise-as-use-exceeds-forecast.html"><headline>Electricity Prices in Mid-Atlantic Rise as Use Exceeds Forecast</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Spot wholesale electricity prices
jumped across PJM Interconnection LLC''s territory as demand on
the largest U.S. power grid exceeded expectations. </p>
<p>Power use on the 13-state PJM network, which stretches from
Chicago to Washington, averaged 117,192 megawatts at 11:15 a.m.,
a 3.8 percent increase from the day-ahead forecast of 112,855
megawatts, according to the grid''s website. </p>
<p>The high temperature today in Washington may reach 27
degrees Fahrenheit (minus 3 Celsius), 23 below the historical
average, said AccuWeather Inc. in State College, Pennsylvania. </p>
<p>Spot power at PJM''s benchmark Western hub, which includes
deliveries to Washington, advanced $59.11, or 71 percent, to
average $142.74 a megawatt-hour for the hour ended at 11 a.m.
from the same time yesterday, grid data compiled by Bloomberg
show. Prices at the Eastern hub, which includes New Jersey,
gained $39.13, or 43 percent, to average $130.82. </p>
<p>PJM West on-peak power traded $6.85 above the Eastern hub,
compared with a discount of $14.18 yesterday and a three-month
average discount of $13.97 for PJM West. </p>
<p>New York City power fell $42.97, or 19 percent, to average
$179.60 a megawatt-hour at 11 a.m., while Boston prices slid
$47.40, or 19 percent, to average $209.38. </p>
<p>New York on-peak power traded $104.08 above Boston,
compared with a discount of $8.93 yesterday and a three-month
average discount of $22.14 for New York. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jack Kaskey" date="Feb 28, 2014 11:58 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-28/goldman-sees-tesla-consuming-up-to-17-of-lithium-output.html"><headline>Goldman Sees Tesla Consuming Up to 17% of Lithium Output</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Tesla Motor Inc. (TSLA)''s planned battery
factory may consume as much as 17 percent of current lithium
output, easing a forecast oversupply and benefiting producers
like Rockwood Holdings Inc. (ROC), Goldman Sachs Group Inc. said. </p>
<p>The battery plant that Tesla co-founder Elon Musk has
called a gigafactory could require the equivalent of 15,000
tons to 25,000 tons of lithium carbonate annually at full
capacity, Goldman analysts led by Robert Koort said in a report
today. That estimate exceeds a Feb. 26 Bank of America Corp.
prediction the facility would use 9,000 tons. </p>
<p>Tesla today sold $2 billion of convertible notes to fund
the factory intended to lower the cost of lithium-ion batteries
used in its vehicles and for power storage. The increasing
popularity of Tesla''s electric cars, which use larger battery
packs than competing models, should help narrow the coming
lithium oversupply, Koort wrote. </p>
<p>We continue to see a near-term oversupply scenario as
likely, Koort, who rates Rockwood neutral, said in the note.
An inflection in pure battery electric vehicles may help ease
oversupply of lithium around 2020. </p>
<p>Galaxy Resources Ltd. (GXY)''s decision not to resume production
in Mt. Cattlin, Australia, also contributes to the tighter
supply outlook, he said. </p>
<p>While companies like FMC Corp. don''t get a big portion of
earnings from lithium, Rockwood is positioning for an electric
vehicle inflection, Koort said. </p>
<p>Rockwood is divesting units to focus on lithium products
and surface treatments. The Princeton, New Jersey-based chemical
maker gained more access to lithium supplies with its December
agreement to form a joint venture with China''s Chengdu Tianqi
Industry Group Co. to get a stake in Talison Lithium Pty. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Feb 28, 2014 10:23 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-28/goldman-awards-employees-2-3-billion-of-restricted-stock.html"><headline>Goldman Awards Employees $2.3 Billion of Restricted Stock</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) awarded
employees restricted stock worth $2.3 billion for their 2013
performance, the smallest amount in two years as the firm cut
costs by lowering the portion of revenue it set aside for pay. </p>
<p>The firm granted 13.8 million restricted shares that vest
over several years, New York-based Goldman Sachs said today in
its annual regulatory filing. The value, down from $2.4 billion
a year earlier, is based on the closing price on Jan. 28, when
senior executives were given their awards. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Lloyd C. Blankfein, 59, cut
compensation to 37 percent of revenue last year, the second-lowest portion since the firm went public in 1999. That
contributed to a 6 percent increase in net income even as
revenue was little changed. </p>
<p>Banks have been seeking to balance regulatory pressure to
tie awards to long-term performance with shareholders'' desire
for flexibility to cut pay costs if needed. Goldman Sachs Chief
Financial Officer Harvey M. Schwartz, 49, has said the firm is
reluctant to ramp up the amount of pay it defers because it is
a bit of mortgaging the future. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs said about 70 percent of the restricted stock
awards were recognized as expenses immediately. The cost
recorded by the firm is probably lower than the current value of
the shares because the bank accounts for the fact that employees
can''t immediately sell the shares. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS), owner of the world''s largest brokerage,
gave employees $2.72 billion in deferred awards for 2013
performance, including $1.25 billion of restricted stock and
$1.47 billion of deferred cash. About $100 million of the awards
were expensed in 2013. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs didn''t disclose any deferred cash awards, and
the firm hasn''t typically given such bonuses. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Feb 28, 2014  7:53 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-28/goldman-sachs-s-reasonably-possible-legal-losses-drop.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs''s Reasonably Possible'' Legal Losses Drop</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), which more
than doubled the amount it set aside for litigation costs in
2013, said reasonably possible legal losses beyond those
reserves were $3.6 billion. </p>
<p>The figure dropped from $4 billion at the end of the third
quarter, while rising from $3.5 billion a year earlier, the New
York-based bank said today in an annual regulatory filing. The
estimate doesn''t include potential claims from investigations by
the Residential Mortgage-Backed Securities Working Group of the
U.S. Financial Fraud Enforcement Task Force, the firm said. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs added some items to its list of activities
that are subject to current regulatory investigations and
reviews, including allocations of and trading in fixed-income
securities, its financial-advisory services and interactions
between the bank''s research analysts and third parties. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs had $962 million of net provisions for
litigation and regulatory proceedings in 2013, primarily tied to
mortgage-related matters, up from $448 million in 2012. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Feb 28, 2014  6:19 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-28/goldman-sachs-says-traders-posted-losses-on-27-days-last-year.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Traders Posted Losses on 27 Days Last Year</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), which
generated 46 percent of revenue from sales and trading last
year, recorded losses from that business on 27 days in 2013, up
from 16 the previous year. </p>
<p>None of the daily losses exceeded the firm''s value-at-risk,
an estimate of potential losses with 95 percent confidence, the
New York-based company said today in a filing with the U.S.
Securities and Exchange Commission. Traders made more than $100
million on 34 days, down from 41 days a year earlier. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs''s trading revenue fell 15 percent to $16
billion in 2013, excluding accounting charges, as the firm
generated less from bond trading and sold a reinsurance unit
that reported its results in the firm''s equities segment. The
bank''s net income climbed 6 percent as Chief Executive Officer
Lloyd C. Blankfein set aside a lower portion of revenue for pay. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS), owner of the world''s biggest brokerage,
reported this week that it lost money in its trading business on
33 days last year, down from 37 in 2012 and the fewest since
2006. </p>
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the biggest U.S. bank, revised its
gauge of market gains and losses to incorporate new regulatory
requirements, resulting in a jump in the frequency of losses
last year. Under the new method, JPMorgan posted gains on 177 of
the 260 trading days in 2013, while the old measurement showed
losses on zero days. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Vladimir Kuznetsov" date="Feb 28, 2014  5:51 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-28/morgan-stanley-flips-on-rates-as-ruble-hits-bonds-russia-credit.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Flips on Rates as Ruble Hits Bonds: Russia Credit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The plunging ruble is prompting
Morgan Stanley to switch its interest-rate forecast to an
increase from a cut as inflation risks mount, punishing holders
of Russian bonds already roiled by rising tensions with Ukraine. </p>
<p>The ruble, set for the biggest drop against the dollar this
month among 31 major currencies tracked by Bloomberg, tumbled to
record lows this week as Russia conducted military exercises
near its border with Ukraine, where gunmen occupied a regional
parliament building and airport in the Crimean peninsula. The
slide is stoking inflation concern, jeopardizing the central
bank''s 5 percent target for consumer-price growth this year.
Policy makers suggested they may need to lift borrowing costs. </p>
<p>Recent ruble weakness is sparking the risk that inflation
will accelerate over the next few months, Dmitry Dorofeev, a
money manager at BCS Financial Group in Moscow, said in e-mailed
comments on Feb. 25. This may force the central bank to
temporarily raise rates. The biggest losers are the medium-dated
notes, where local players dominate. </p>
<p>The currency depreciated 0.5 percent to 42.2585 against
Bank Rossii''s target basket of dollars and euros at 2:23 p.m. in
Moscow, heading for another record-low close. It has weakened
2.6 percent against the greenback this month, while Russia''s
local-currency bonds lost 2.7 percent in dollars, the worst
performance in the Bloomberg Emerging Market Local Sovereign
EMEA index. The gauge is up 2.6 percent in February. </p>
<h2>Game Changer'' </h2>
<p>This year''s depreciation is a game changer that will
lead to higher inflation and a 50 basis point, or 0.5 percentage
point, interest-rate increase by the end of June, Morgan Stanley
analysts led by Jacob Nell and James Lord said in an e-mailed
note on Feb. 24. They revised an earlier call for a half-percentage-point rate cut in the second half of 2014. </p>
<p>Such calls are weakening Russia''s shorted-dated government
notes most, compressing the spread with longer-dated securities. </p>
<p>The extra yield investors demand to hold 15-year government
bonds over five-year debt declined to 55 basis points today, the
lowest in 13 months, data compiled by Bloomberg show. </p>
<p>A weaker ruble with pass-through effect into inflation
and more hawkish comments from the central bank have pushed up
the short end of the curve, Jetro Siekkinen, an emerging-market bond manager in Helsinki at Aktia Asset Management, which
has about $10.5 billion in assets, said by e-mail on Feb. 25. </p>
<h2>Armed Gunmen </h2>
<p>Ukraine''s acting president Oleksandr Turchynov said Russian
soldiers were directly involved in a conflict in Crimea as
armed troops wearing uniforms without insignia guarded the
region''s main airport in Simferopol. </p>
<p>This week gunmen occupied the Crimean parliament in the
same city after the ouster of Ukraine''s pro-Moscow President
Viktor Yanukovych following months of anti-government protests. </p>
<p>Russia, whose Black Sea fleet is based in Crimea, put
fighter jets on combat alert yesterday as part of its military
drills, Interfax news service said, citing the Defense Ministry. </p>
<p>The market is really afraid because it doesn''t understand
what''s going on, Vadim Bit-Avragim, who helps oversee about
$4.2 billion at Kapital Asset Management in Moscow, said by
phone yesterday. All investors are pricing in the possibility
of Russia''s military intervention in Ukraine. </p>
<h2>Credibility'' Issue </h2>
<p>Russia''s benchmark Micex (INDEXCF) stock index snapped four days of
declines, rising 0.1 percent today. The additional yield on
Russian dollar bonds over Treasuries declined three basis points
to 244, according to an index compiled by JPMorgan Chase  Co. </p>
<p>The yield on bonds due February 2027 rose two basis points
to 8.46 percent today, equal to a 19-month-high set last week.
The share of non-residents in the 3.7 trillion local ruble bond
market fell to 23.9 percent on Jan. 1 from 28.1 percent on May
1, according to central bank data. </p>
<p>Russia''s inflation rate may rise above 6.5 percent in March
and April, from 6.1 percent in January, pushing Bank Rossii to
hike to maintain its credibility, according to Morgan
Stanley''s note. Rates will stay on hold in the second half of
2014 before a gradual, 100 basis-point easing cycle once
inflation is in line with the target, the analysts wrote. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Cathy Chan" date="Feb 28, 2014  3:11 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-02-28/morgan-stanley-says-laroia-to-replace-strong-as-asia-pacific-ceo.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Appoints Gokul Laroia as Asia Pacific Co-CEO</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) appointed Gokul
Laroia as Asia-Pacific co-chief executive officer to replace
William Strong, who is retiring in May. </p>
<p>Laroia, 47, becomes head of the region excluding Japan with
Wei Sun Christianson and will retain his current
responsibilities as head of the New York-based firm''s
institutional equity and wealth-management business, Nick Footitt, a Hong Kong-based spokesman, said by telephone. </p>
<p>Strong, 61, will remain as a senior adviser at the firm,
Footitt said, confirming an internal memo. Strong, who has been
at Morgan Stanley since 1993, and Christianson were named to
lead the bank''s operations in the region in March 2011. </p>
<p>During his three-year tenure, Strong oversaw the firm''s
expansion in Indonesia and exit of businesses in India as Morgan
Stanley sought to cut costs and improve return on equity. In
2012, the firm started its local equities business in Indonesia.
Last year, it sold its domestic wealth management and mutual-fund business in India and surrendered an Indian banking
license. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley already had banking and capital markets
operations in Indonesia prior to establishing the domestic
institutional equities business, which Laroia oversees. </p>
<h2>Management Committee </h2>
<p>Laroia, who is based in Hong Kong, joined Morgan Stanley in
1995 and was earlier this month appointed to the firm''s global
management committee. He was co-head of investment banking in
the region for almost two years through April 2011, after
serving as head of global capital markets for Asia between 2006
and 2009. Prior to that, he was head of mergers and acquisition
for Asia-Pacific, excluding Japan. </p>
<p>Strong joined Morgan Stanley to run North American
investment banking offices outside New York. He was previously
head of international investment banking at Salomon Brothers,
based in London. He joined Salomon in 1979 in New York. </p>
<p>Last year, Strong was named by Hong Kong Chief Executive
C.Y. Leung as a member of the newly established Financial
Services Development Council, a 22-person committee tasked with
the development of the city''s financial services industry. </p>
<p>Strong graduated from Purdue University in 1973 with a
Bachelor of Science and has a Master of Business Administration
degree from Northwestern University''s Kellogg School of
Management. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry></news>