<news>
    <entry author="By Anil Varma and Edgar Ortega" date="Jan 10, 2007  5:08 PM ET"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-10/nyse-goldman-invest-in-india-s-national-market-update10-.html">
        <headline>NYSE, Goldman Invest in India''s National Market</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;NYSE Group Inc. and Goldman Sachs
            Group Inc. led a group of investors that agreed to buy 20 percent
            of the National Stock Exchange of India Ltd., tapping the world''s
            second-fastest-growing major economy. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The National exchange will receive $115 million from NYSE
            Group for a 5 percent stake in a transaction that values India''s
            largest equity market at $2.3 billion. Goldman, General Atlantic
            LLC and Softbank Asian Infrastructure Fund will buy 5 percent
            each, the closely held NSE said without disclosing a price. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;NYSE Group, operator of the world''s biggest stock exchange,
            is making its first investment in Asia through a market where the
            combined worth of equities rose 50 percent in the past two years
            to $820 billion. The Indian government lifted a ban on foreign
            ownership three weeks ago as markets race to make acquisitions
            and expand internationally into trading multiple securities. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;''''Goldman and NYSE are clearly investing in India''s long-term growth story,'''' said Navneet
            Munot, who helps manage the
            equivalent of $4 billion of Indian stocks and bonds at Birla
            Sunlife Asset Management Co. in Mumbai. ''''For NSE, a tie-up with
            the NYSE would mean technology, visibility and access to new
            financial products.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;India''s government on Dec. 22 allowed international
            investors to buy as much as a combined 49 percent in any of the
            nation''s 22 stock exchanges. The limit for a single investor was
            set at 5 percent by the Securities and Exchange Board of India. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Closest Competitor &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Mumbai-based National Stock Exchange, home to companies
            such as Reliance Industries Ltd. and Infosys Technologies Ltd.,
            handled a daily average of 72.3 billion rupees ($1.6 billion) in
            the past six months. That''s more than twice the value of its
            closest competitor, the Bombay Stock Exchange. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The 14-year-old National exchange also dominates trading in
            equity-based futures contracts and owns stakes in India''s
            National Commodity Derivatives Exchange and the Multi-Commodity
            Exchange. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;India''s gross domestic product grew 9.2 percent in the three
            months through September, second only to China among the world''s
            major economies. India may overtake China in growth this year,
            Credit Suisse Group economists estimated in December. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The investment may help the NYSE draw the listing of Indian
            companies, said NYSE Group Chief Financial Officer Nelson Chai.
            It currently lists 10 Indian companies. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Investing in Asia &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;''''We are going to be on the ground with them, meeting people
            both at the corporate level and also within the regulatory and
            government level,'''' Chai told reports in a conference call from
            Delhi. ''''We are neither in a control position nor in a position
            to capture cost synergies. But we do believe there are long-term
            growth prospects here, and we''re closer to participating in that
            growth.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Chief Executive Officer John Thain said on Dec. 20 NYSE
            Group was looking to invest in Japan, China or India after
            shareholders approved its $14.6 billion purchase of Euronext NV.
            Thain, who joined the NYSE in 2004 from Goldman, has extend the
            exchange''s reach overseas and beyond equities trading since
            transforming the 214-year-old market into a publicly traded
            company through the acquisition of Archipelago Holdings Inc. in
            March. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;NYSE Group shares rose $3.63, or 3.5 percent, to $108.21 at
            4:01 p.m. in composite trading in New York. The stock has gained
            68 percent since its debut March 8. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Exchange Ownership &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Rival exchanges have also pursued international
            acquisitions. Nasdaq Stock Market Inc. this week urged
            shareholders of the London Stock Exchange Plc to accept its
            takeover bid that values the company at 2.7 billion pounds ($5.2
            billion). The Bombay exchange is considering selling stakes to
            five overseas investors, India''s Business Standard reported last
            week, citing people it didn''t identify. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;India''s government said today it will set rules within six
            weeks opening up the nation''s $600 billion commodities markets to
            international investors, clearing the way for the world''s third-largest gold exchange to sell shares. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;''''We hope to announce norms related to exchange ownership
            soon,'''' Yashwant Bhave, secretary at the department of Consumer
            Affairs, said today in Mumbai. ''''Norms on foreign investors''
            participation in the market will also be announced.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The deal unveiled today will be completed this quarter,
            subject to regulatory approvals from various Indian government
            agencies, the NYSE said in a statement. The 20 percent stake will
            be sold by companies including ICICI Bank Ltd. (ICICIBC), IFCI Ltd. (IFCI), ILFS
            Trust Company Ltd., Punjab National Bank (PNB) Ltd. and General
            Insurance Corp. of India Ltd., the National exchange said in its
            statement. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Goldman and NYSE &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Goldman, the most profitable brokerage in Wall Street
            history, already owns a 7 percent stake in India''s National
            Commodity Derivatives Exchange Ltd. Goldman and the buyout firm
            General Atlantic were early investors in Archipelago and are
            currently among the top five shareholders of NYSE Group. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;General Atlantic, which overseas $12 billion in Greenwich,
            Connecticut, last year acquired a stake in the New York
            Mercantile Exchange in anticipation of an initial public
            offering. Since their debut in November, shares of the world''s
            largest energy exchange have more than doubled. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Mary Jane Credeur" date="Jan 22, 2007  4:26 PM ET"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-22/coca-cola-shifts-minnick-s-marketing-duties-to-kent-update1-.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola Shifts Minnick''s Marketing Duties to Kent</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Co. (KO), the world''s largest
            soft-drink maker, will shift some of outgoing marketing chief
            Mary Minnick''s responsibilities to recently promoted President
            Muhtar Kent. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Kent will oversee marketing for the Atlanta-based company
            beginning March 1, Chief Executive Officer Neville Isdell, said
            today in an internal memo to employees. Minnick, who was passed
            over when Kent was named president and chief operating officer
            in December, said last week she will leave in February to pursue
            other personal and professional goals in the U.K. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The move gives more responsibility to Kent, 54, who is
            Coca-Cola''s second-highest ranking executive and likely
            successor to Isdell. Coca-Cola''s strategy and innovation groups,
            formerly overseen by Minnick, will report to Isdell. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;''''As the health of our business continues to improve, the
            factors that necessitated the combining of marketing, strategy
            and innovation have evolved,'''' Isdell, 63, said in the memo. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The new structure allows Coca-Cola to ''''increase the impact
            and effectiveness of the global marketing community, while
            preserving the benefits we have captured'''' by previously
            combining the groups, wrote Isdell, who hasn''t said when he
            plans to retire. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola also said today Marc Mathieu, who previously
            oversaw marketing for brands such as Coca-Cola, Sprite and
            Fanta, will assume similar duties for noncarbonated drinks
            including Dasani and Powerade. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Shares of Coca-Cola fell 23 cents to $48.03 at 4 p.m. in
            New York Stock Exchange composite trading. They increased 20
            percent last year, the biggest annual gain since 1997. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Sarah Thompson" date="Jan 23, 2007 10:46 AM ET"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-23/goldman-sachs-is-selling-eu71-1-million-worth-of-fiat-shares.html">
        <headline>Goldman Sachs Is Selling EU71.1 Million Worth of Fiat Shares</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Goldman, Sachs Co. is selling
            shares worth 71.1 million euros ($92.7 million) in Fiat SpA (F),
            Italy''s largest manufacturer. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The brokerage is selling 4.5 million shares for 15.80 euros
            each, according to an e-mail Goldman sent to clients. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Shares of Fiat added 0.9 percent to 15.81 euros at 3:39
            p.m. in London. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;A spokesman for Goldman Sachs in London was not immediately
            available to confirm or deny the stock sale. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Mary Jane Credeur" date="Jan 24, 2007  4:42 PM ET"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-01-24/coca-cola-will-run-first-super-bowl-ads-since-1998-update3-.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola Will Run First Super Bowl Ads Since 1998</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Co. (KO) will go head-to-head
            with PepsiCo Inc. (PEP) in Super Bowl television advertising for the
            first time in almost a decade as it tries to boost sales of its
            top-selling drink. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;One new ad for Coca-Cola Classic will air during
            professional football''s championship game along with two spots
            that debuted during the television show ''''American Idol,'''' the
            Atlanta-based company said in a statement today. Coca-Cola hasn''t
            run promotions during the Super Bowl since 1998. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Advertising during television''s most-watched event pits
            Coca-Cola against PepsiCo as both companies try to reverse a drop
            in U.S. soda sales. PepsiCo has advertised during the Super Bowl
            for 21 consecutive years and will sponsor the half-time show for
            the first time. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;''''Coke wants back in the game,'''' said Z. John Zhang,
            marketing professor at the Wharton School at the University of
            Pennsylvania. ''''They''ve waited this many years to come back, so
            the pressure is on them to have the louder voice.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Both soft-drink makers are trying to stop declines in the
            U.S., where soda consumption dropped in 2005 for the first time
            in at least 15 years because of concern that sugary beverages
            contribute to obesity. Coca-Cola''s soft drink volume fell 1
            percent in North America during the third quarter, and PepsiCo''s
            dropped 2 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Cost of Ads &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola''s Super Bowl advertisements include a 60-second
            spot titled ''''Video Game,'''' showing a character who passes out
            bottles of Coca-Cola Classic to people he meets on the street.
            Coca-Cola will also run a 30-second ad called ''''Happiness
            Factory'''' that follows a bottle of Coke through an imaginary
            vending machine. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The company won''t say anything about the new commercial
            being made for the Super Bowl. The ads were created by
            independent agency Wieden + Kennedy, based in Portland, Oregon. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;''''Coca-Cola Classic has always been about having fun, and
            that''s what people get together to do when they watch the Super
            Bowl,'''' said Katie Bayne, senior vice president for Coca-Cola
            brands in North America. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Shares of Coca-Cola fell 1 cent to $48.13 at 4 p.m. in New
            York Stock Exchange composite trading. They gained 20 percent
            last year, the biggest gain since 1997. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;PepsiCo shares climbed 36 cents to $65.20. They rose 5.9
            percent last year. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola spokeswoman Susan McDermott wouldn''t say how much
            the company is spending on the game. A 30-second ad during the
            Super Bowl can cost $2.5 million, according to AdWeek. Coca-
            Cola''s advertising budget was $2.48 billion in 2005. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Bears vs. Colts &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;More than 141 million people watched last year''s Super Bowl.
            This year''s game, scheduled for Feb. 4 at Dolphin Stadium in
            Miami Gardens, Fla., is a match-up between the Chicago Bears and
            the Indianapolis Colts. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Super Bowl will be broadcast on CBS Corp.''s CBS network.
            The television show American Idol, the most popular show on
            primetime television, airs on News Corp.''s Fox network. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;In addition to the half-time show sponsorship, PepsiCo plans
            to run 90 seconds of ads during the first half of the Super Bowl,
            spokeswoman Nicole Bradley said. She wouldn''t say how much the
            company is spending, or which ads it plans to run. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;PepsiCo has a promotion featuring a sterling silver can of
            Pepsi studded with diamonds, rubies and sapphires. The company
            will give away the can, worth $100,000, and Super Bowl tickets
            for life after the half-time show, which includes a performance
            by the musician Prince. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;''''We thrive on the Super Bowl spotlight. It''s been a part of
            our game plan for more than two decades,'''' Bradley said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Last year, Coca-Cola sponsored a Super Bowl pre-game show
            with its Full Throttle energy drink. Ads showed a semi-tractor
            trailer truck mounted with an oversized can of Full Throttle
            overtaking a small pickup truck with a slender can of rival
            energy drink Red Bull. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
    <entry author="By Mary Jane Credeur" date="Feb 01, 2007  4:39 PM ET"
           url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-02-01/coca-cola-agrees-to-buy-fuze-to-add-healthier-drinks-update4-.html">
        <headline>Coca-Cola Agrees to Buy Fuze to Add Healthier Drinks</headline>
        <body>
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Co. (KO), the world''s largest
            soft-drink maker, agreed to buy Fuze Beverage LLC to add more
            juice, tea and energy drinks in an effort to catch up with
            PepsiCo Inc. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola gains a half-dozen new products including Fuze
            Tea, NOS energy drinks and Fuze Slenderize, which has chromium
            and amino acids that Fuze says help promote weight loss. Atlanta-
            based Coca-Cola didn''t disclose terms of the purchase. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Fuze beverages may help Coca-Cola win back customers who
            switched from sugary sodas to drinks such as PepsiCo''s SoBe tea.
            It''s Coca-Cola''s biggest U.S. acquisition since buying Odwalla
            Inc. in 2001 for $186 million to gain protein drinks and juices,
            said John Sicher, editor of industry journal Beverage Digest. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;''''This represents Coke aggressively getting itself into a
            better place in the noncarbonated business in the U.S.,'''' Sicher
            said. ''''Fuze is small but growing strongly.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Sicher estimated that Coca-Cola paid $225 million to $250
            million for closely held Fuze. He said the Englewood Cliffs, New
            Jersey-based company sold about 11.5 million cases last year, up
            from 8 million cases in 2005, generating $90 million to $100
            million in revenue. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Shares of Coca-Cola rose 22 cents to $48.10 at 4:22 p.m. in
            New York Stock Exchange composite trading. They increased 20
            percent last year, their biggest gain since 1997. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;h2&gt;Bottlers &lt;/h2&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;The Fuze purchase may help sate bottlers that had
            complained about Coca-Cola falling behind PepsiCo in adding
            drinks other than soda. Coca-Cola depends on soda for 80 percent
            of its volume, compared with less than 20 percent for PepsiCo. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Enterprises Inc. (CCE), the largest distributor, agreed
            to distribute Arizona bottled teas in the U.S. last year, making
            good on a promise to get new drinks from someone other than Coca-
            Cola if it needed to. The bottler is 36 percent owned by Coca-
            Cola. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;''''This should be well-received by Coke''s bottlers,'''' Bill Pecoriello, an analyst at Morgan
            Stanley, wrote today in a note. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Fuze was already distributed by 20 Coca-Cola bottlers
            including Coca-Cola Bottling Co. United of Birmingham, Alabama,
            and the Philadelphia Coca-Cola Bottling Co. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Only about 15 percent of Fuze''s volume currently goes
            through Coca-Cola bottlers, Pecoriello wrote. The Cadbury
            Schweppes Bottling Group had distributed Fuze in much of the
            U.S., Sicher said. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Bottling Co. Consolidated, the second-largest
            bottler for Coca-Cola, sells Cinnabon bottled coffee and created
            a separate unit called Beverages and Beyond Brands to create or
            buy drinks it wasn''t getting from the soda maker. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola''s soda volume in the U.S. dropped by a low single
            digit in 2005, while noncarbonated volume jumped 10 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;</body>
    </entry>
</news>