
<news><entry author="By Robert Fenner" date="May 07, 2009  2:36 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-05-07/david-jones-surges-after-goldman-upgrades-to-buy-update1-.html"><headline>David Jones Surges After Goldman Upgrades to &#8216;Buy&#8217;</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;David Jones Ltd., Australia&#8217;s second-biggest department store chain, surged the most in six months
after Goldman Sachs JBWere Pty. raised its rating to &#8220;buy.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Jones shares rose 11 percent to A$3.64 at the 4:10
p.m. market close, their largest gain since Oct. 29. The stock
has gained 14 percent this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consumer spending is likely to improve in the second half
of the year while management of the Sydney-based retailer have
been able to protect earnings amid falling sales, Phillip Kimber,
a Melbourne-based analyst at Goldman, said in a note to clients.
He also cited &#8220;solid valuation support&#8221; and a dividend yield
of about 8 percent as he raised his rating from &#8220;hold.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;We recognize that there are risks to our outlook for an
improvement in consumer spending,&#8221; Kimber said. &#8220;We believe
that David Jones&#8217; proven management team and business model
mitigate some of this risk.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Jones yesterday announced a 9.2 percent fall in third-quarter sales, a result that beat Kimber&#8217;s estimates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The retailer, anticipating lower sales amid a recession,
cut inventory holdings and renegotiated trading terms with
suppliers to limit the impact of falling demand for designer
fashions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chief Executive Officer Mark McInnes affirmed his forecast
for second-half profit growth of zero to 5 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;This is a very impressive outcome,&#8221; Kimber said. The
result &#8220;reflects David Jones&#8217; successful management of the
consumer spending cycle.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By John Duce and Shiyin Chen" date="May 19, 2009  5:44 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-05-19/cnooc-oil-stocks-raised-to-buy-at-goldman-sachs-update3-.html"><headline>Cnooc, Oil Stocks Raised to &#8216;Buy&#8217; at Goldman Sachs</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Cnooc Ltd. (883), China&#8217;s biggest offshore
oil producer, and Inpex Corp. (1605) were among oil stocks that had
their ratings raised at Goldman Sachs Group Inc., which said
crude prices are likely to rise as demand recovers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cnooc, Inpex and PTT Pcl (PTT) were raised to &#8220;buy&#8221; from
&#8220;neutral,&#8221; the brokerage said in a report today. PetroChina
Co. (857), China&#8217;s biggest oil producer, was upgraded to &#8220;neutral&#8221;
from &#8220;sell&#8221; and Citic Resources Holdings Ltd. (1205), a Hong Kong-listed oil supplier, was raised to &#8220;buy&#8221; from &#8220;sell.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crude oil has risen 74 percent since reaching an intra-day
low of $32.40 a barrel on Dec. 19 last year. Prices will average
$55 in the second half, rising to $70 a barrel next year as
demand increases, the report said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Oil prices are likely to trend higher through the second
half of 2009 and 2010,&#8221; Kelvin Koh, a Hong Kong-based analyst
at the brokerage, said in the report. There is &#8220;upside risk&#8221;
to the forecasts, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cnooc rose 5.4 percent in Hong Kong to HK$10.48, the most
since Sept. 8 last year. PetroChina gained 4.8 percent to
HK$8.45, the highest since Sept. 25 in 2008. Inpex climbed 5.4
percent to 707,000 yen on the Tokyo Stock Exchange while PTT was
up 5.2 percent in Bangkok. China Resources Holdings gained 19
percent to HK$1.92. The MSCI Asia Pacific Index rose about 2
percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Valuations &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;While most Asian energy stocks have rebounded
significantly from their lows, we believe valuations for Asian
exploration and production and integrated oil stocks are
undemanding versus their historical normalized valuations,&#8221;
Goldman Sachs said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The brokerage raised its target prices for oil explorers&#8217;
and integrated oil companies&#8217; shares by a median of 61 percent,
the report said. The long-term forecast is for crude to rise to
$85 a barrel, it said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PetroChina&#8217;s Hong Kong share target was raised by 80
percent to HK$8.35 and that of its Shanghai shares by 81 percent
to 11.5 yuan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world&#8217;s biggest company by market value after Exxon
Mobil Corp. said yesterday it will sell 26 billion yuan of
medium-term notes and buy eight gas distributors for 1.1 billion
yuan from its parent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;The money will help with cash flow, the day-to-day
running of the business and fund major projects such as West-East Gas pipeline now under construction,&#8221; PetroChina spokesman
Mao Zefeng said by phone today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bond issue was approved last year and doesn&#8217;t form part
of the 100 billion yuan of bonds planned for this year, Mao said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PetroChina got approval from shareholders to sell as much
as 100 billion yuan of bonds and will use the funds for
exploration, pipeline and overseas projects, the company said
May 12. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry></news>