
<news><entry author="By John Dorfman" date="Feb 02, 2009 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-02-02/pfizer-nikon-may-benefit-from-the-stimulus-plan-john-dorfman.html"><headline>Pfizer, Nikon May Benefit From the Stimulus Plan: John Dorfman</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Stocks of road builders and
construction companies were jolted last week when the $819
billion stimulus plan passed by the House of Representatives
proved to have only $30 billion designated for roadways, bridges
and tunnels. </p>
<p>Many investors had expected more money for such
infrastructure projects. Shares in Granite Construction Inc. (GVA), a
road construction company based in Watsonville, California, have
fallen to $36.45 from more than $44 in early January. They had
risen 23 percent in November and December in anticipation of the
stimulus package. </p>
<p>If not road builders, then which stocks will be the major
beneficiaries of the stimulus plan now working its way through
Congress? The dimensions of the plan are huge -- $819 billion in
the House version and about $900 billion in the Senate version --
and the bills are complex. Final details aren''t yet known. </p>
<p>Both plans stick closely to the blueprint provided to
Congress by President Barack Obama. He has met with Congressional
leaders to rally support; so far he has it from most Democrats
but not from Republicans. </p>
<p>Here are six stocks I believe could benefit from the
stimulus package: Pfizer Inc., Nikon Corp. (7731), Jos. A. Bank (JOSB)
Clothiers, Inc, Garmin (GRMN) Ltd., Lincoln Electric (LECO) Holdings Inc. and
Parker Hannifin (PH) Corp. </p>
<h2>Healthcare Emphasis </h2>
<p>The House bill includes $81 billion for Medicaid, a program
that pays for healthcare for poor people. There is also $30
billion to extend the Cobra health-care program for people who
lose their health insurance when they lose a job. These funds
could expand the market for pharmaceuticals. </p>
<p>While several pharma stocks are appealing, I''m especially
partial to Pfizer, the world''s largest drugmaker, based in New
York. It sells for six times earnings and currently yields 8
percent a year in dividends. In a thorny market like the current
one, that dividend yield is especially welcome. Pfizer (PFE) last week
agreed to buy Wyeth for more than $68 billion; I think the
proposed acquisition makes sense. </p>
<p>The administration''s plan includes about $275 million in tax
relief for consumers and businesses. About a third of that total
takes the form of tax cuts for families earning as much as
$150,000 or individuals making up to $75,000. Families would be
eligible for a tax credit of as much as $1,000; individuals would
get one of up to $500. </p>
<h2>Consumer Spending </h2>
<p>I can picture some people using the savings to buy a nice
camera. That would redound to the benefit of Nikon The Tokyo-based company is best known for high-quality cameras; it also
makes microscopes and other instruments. </p>
<p>Nikon (NINOY) stock, traded in the U.S. as an American depositary
receipt, sells for seven times earnings and yields 2.6 percent in
dividends. Its balance sheet is strong, with debt only 24 percent
of stockholders'' equity. </p>
<p>Consumers might take their tax credit and buy some new
clothes. And someone who was recently laid off may want to spend
money on a new suit for job interviews. This could work to the
benefit of Jos. A. Bank, a Hampstead, Maryland-based retailer
selling classic men''s clothing. </p>
<p>Jos. A. Bank pays no dividend, and its stock sells for 10
times earnings. The company has recorded a profit 11 years
running, and the streak should go to 12 when results are reported
for the fiscal year ended Jan. 31, 2009. </p>
<h2>Garmin''s Gains </h2>
<p>One more potential beneficiary in the consumer realm is
Garmin, the largest U.S. maker of car-navigation devices. Garmin
had a 59 percent market share in the U.S. as of mid-2008, and a
19 percent share in Europe as of 2007. </p>
<p>Competition and the recession have forced Garmin to cut
prices. Garmin shares fetch a mere five times earnings, and the
stock yields 4 percent in dividends. The Cayman Islands-based
company is debt-free. </p>
<p>The stimulus package also includes provisions designed to
make it easier for businesses to invest in new equipment. These
provisions might benefit Lincoln Electric of Cleveland, the
world''s largest maker of welding equipment. </p>
<p>A few years ago, it looked as if Lincoln might be imperiled
by lawsuits alleging that use of its welding equipment could
produce symptoms similar to those of Parkinson''s Disease.
However, the company prevailed in the vast majority those
lawsuits. Of some 15,000 cases filed, about 12,000 have been
dismissed. Lincoln has lost in four cases, three of which are
being appealed. Lincoln Electric shares trade for seven times
earnings, and the stock yields 2.4 percent in dividends. Debt is
admirably low at 11 percent of equity. </p>
<p>Another potential beneficiary of the proposed liberalized
tax treatment of new-equipment purchases is Parker Hannifin, also
of Cleveland. It is the world''s largest manufacturer of hydraulic
equipment. On Jan. 28 the company announced it had won a contract
worth as much as $2.5 billion to make jet engine parts for Rolls
Royce. </p>
<p>Parker Hannifin''s other products include systems for
regulating fluid flow, fluid purification and assembly line
processes. The stock sells for seven times earnings and yields
2.5 percent in dividends. </p>
<p>Disclosure note: I own shares of Pfizer and Lincoln Electric
personally and for clients. I don''t currently own the other
stocks mentioned in this column. </p>
<p>(John Dorfman, chairman of Thunderstorm Capital in Boston,
is a Bloomberg News columnist. The opinions expressed are his
own. His firm or clients may own or trade securities discussed in
this column.) </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Steve Scherer and Francesca Cinelli" date="Feb 24, 2009  2:05 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-02-24/generali-mediobanca-piaggio-saras-italian-equity-preview.html"><headline>Generali, Mediobanca, Piaggio, Saras: Italian Equity Preview</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The following companies may have
unusual price changes in Italian trading. Stock symbols are in
parentheses, and share prices are from the previous close. </p>
<p>Italy''s SP/MIB (FTSEMIB) Index fell for a sixth day, dropping 139, or
0.9 percent, to 15,391. </p>
<p>Antichi Pellettieri SpA (AP IM): The leather-goods unit of
Mariella Burani Fashion Group SpA (MBFG IM) had its price
estimate cut by 19 percent to 4.8 euros at Bank of America Corp.
The brokerage also lowered its price projection by 18 percent to
8.5 euros on Mariella Burani. Bank of America Corp. has Zignago
Vetro SpA (ZV) , a specialist bottle maker, as a top pick in
Italy among small and mid caps on a 12 month-view. </p>
<p>Antichi Pellettieri shares were unchanged at 1.94 euros.
Mariella Burani shares declined 1 cent, or 0.1 percent, to 8.56
euros. Zignago Vetro shares fell 18 cents, or 4.8 percent, to 3.6
euros. </p>
<p>Arnoldo Mondadori Editore SpA (MN) : Exane BNP Paribas cut
its price estimate on the publisher controlled by Prime Minister
Silvio Berlusconi to 2.2 euros from 2.5 euros. The shares
declined 13.5 cents, or 4.9 percent, to 2.63 euros. </p>
<p>Assicurazioni Generali SpA (G) : Italy''s biggest insurer
agreed to buy the rest of its Alleanza Assicurazioni SpA (AL IM)
unit, predicting 200 million euros in annual synergies by 2012. </p>
<p>Alleanza will be merged by incorporation into Generali
through a new share issue with an exchange ratio of 0.33 shares
of Generali common stock for every Alleanza share. </p>
<p>Given last week''s announcement the deal should be widely
anticipated and we expect a broadly neutral share price
reaction, Bank of America Corp. analysts Frank Stoffel and Thea
Yates wrote in a note. Financially, the deal appears to be
broadly neutral for Generali''s shareholders at first glance
before considering synergies or restructuring costs.
Strategically, we believe the message is that the unloved
concentration on the three most mature Continental European
markets will even increase going forward and for the foreseeable
future an expansion into faster growing markets is unlikely to be
on the agenda. </p>
<p>Deutsche Bank AG believes Generali is now likely to
outperform the sector ahead of shareholders'' meeting. </p>
<p>Shares of Generali and Alleanza were suspended from trading
yesterday. </p>
<p>Compagnie Industriali Riunite SpA (CIR) : Net income at
Sorgenia SpA, the Italian power generator owned by CIR, rose to
66.7 million euros in 2008 from 65.2 million euros a year
earlier. Deutsche Bank AG reiterated a buy rating on CIR
after Sorgenia''s results. Shares of CIR fell 3.5 cents, or 4.7
percent, to 70.4 cents. </p>
<p>Enel SpA (ENEL) : Italy''s biggest utility had its price
estimate cut to 6.6 euros at Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and to 5
euros at Citigroup Inc. The shares added 7.75 cents, or 1.8
percent, to 4.33 euros. </p>
<p>Fiat SpA (F) : Moody''s Investors Service cut the long-term
credit ratings of Italy''s biggest carmaker''s to junk, citing
significantly negative free cash flow and concern about the
economic outlook. The shares dropped 21 cents, or 5.6 percent, to
3.55 euros. </p>
<p>Mediobanca SpA (MB) : Italy''s biggest investment bank is
scheduled to hold a conference call on results for its fiscal
second-quarter. Nomura International PLC expects Mediobanca to
report a loss of 111 million euros in the quarter, mainly owing
to the writedown on the equity investment in Telco SpA.
However, the brokerage believes the market will be focused on the
underlying operating trends of the wholesale and retail
divisions. The shares declined 5 cents, or 0.8 percent, to 6.48
euros. </p>
<p>Piaggio  C. SpA (PIA) : Equita Sim SpA downgraded
Europe''s largest motor-scooter maker to reduce from hold.
The shares were unchanged at 1.05 euros. </p>
<p>Saipem SpA (SPM) : Chief Executive Officer Pietro Franco
Tali and Chief Operating Officer Hugh James O''Donnell meet
analysts in London to discuss last year''s results. The shares
fell 24 cents, or 2 percent, to 11.91 euros. </p>
<p>Saras SpA (SRS) : The Italian oil refiner posted a fourth-quarter loss of 248.3 million euros, compared with net income of
46.2 million euros in the fourth quarter of last year. The shares
declined 6.25 cents, or 2.7 percent, to 2.22 euros. </p>
<p>Telecom Italia SpA (TIT) : Italy''s biggest phone company,
juggling the need to refinance 4.5 billion euros ($5.7 billion)
in debt this year with its biggest shareholder''s desire for
dividends, may cut the payout as soon as this week. </p>
<p>The board of Italy''s largest phone company probably will
lower the payout on ordinary shares to 6 cents when it meets Feb.
27 from 8 cents a year earlier, according to the average of 20
analyst estimates compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>The shares fell 2.7 cents, or 2.8 percent, to 93.6 cents. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Steve Scherer" date="Feb 24, 2009  1:40 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-02-24/generali-fiat-mediobanca-saipem-italian-equity-preview.html"><headline>Generali, Fiat, Mediobanca, Saipem: Italian Equity Preview</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The following companies may have
unusual price changes in Italian trading. Stock symbols are in
parentheses, and share prices are from the previous close. </p>
<p>Italy''s SP/MIB (FTSEMIB) Index fell for a sixth day, dropping 139, or
0.9 percent, to 15,391. </p>
<p>Assicurazioni Generali SpA (G) : Italy''s biggest insurer
agreed to buy the rest of Alleanza Assicurazioni SpA and create a
new company comprising the Alleanza and Toro units, predicting
200 million euros in annual synergies by 2012. The shares were
suspended at 13.03 euros. </p>
<p>Fiat SpA (F) : Moody''s Investors Service cut the long-term
credit ratings of Italy''s biggest manufacturer to junk, citing
significantly negative free cash flow and concern about the
economic outlook. The shares dropped 21 cents, or 5.6 percent, to
3.55 euros. </p>
<p>Mediobanca SpA (MB) : Italy''s biggest investment bank is
scheduled to hold a conference call on results for its fiscal
first-half. The shares declined 5 cents, or 0.8 percent, to 6.48
euros. </p>
<p>Saipem SpA (SPM) : Chief Executive Officer Pietro Franco
Tali and Chief Operating Officer Hugh James O''Donnell meet
analysts in London to discuss last year''s results. The shares
fell 24 cents, or 2 percent, to 11.91 euros. </p>
<p>Saras SpA (SRS) : The owner of the Mediterranean region''s
biggest refinery said it posted a fourth-quarter loss of 248.3
million euros, compared with net income of 46.2 million euros in
the fourth quarter of last year. The shares declined 6 cents, or
2.7 percent, to 2.22 euros. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry></news>