
<news><entry author="By Chris Reiter, Brian Parkin and Andreas Cremer" date="May 20, 2009  4:46 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-05-20/general-motors-says-opel-unit-attracted-three-bids-update5-.html"><headline>General Motors Says Opel Unit Attracted Three Bids</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>General Motors Corp. (GM), which is
selling its Opel unit while preparing for a probable June 1
bankruptcy, attracted three bids for the German division,
according to Chris Preuss, a spokesman for GM Europe. </p>
<p>Fiat SpA (F), Italy''s largest carmaker, presented an offer for
GM''s Opel and Vauxhall divisions in Europe as part of a plan to
combine with them and with Chrysler LLC in the U.S., the Turin-based manufacturer said today in a statement. </p>
<p>Magna International Inc. (MG), a Canadian car-parts maker, and
RHJ International (RHJI) SA, a Brussels-based investment firm started
by Ripplewood Holdings LLC founder Timothy Collins, submitted
detailed offers for Opel to the German government, said a state
official, speaking on condition that he not be identified
because the bids are confidential. </p>
<p>GM faces bankruptcy if it doesn''t reorganize by June 1 to
meet terms for U.S. government loans. The Detroit-based carmaker
is willing to sell a majority stake in cash-strapped Opel, which
is based in the Frankfurt suburb of Ruesselsheim and has
assembly plants in countries including Spain, Belgium and
Poland. Vauxhall builds cars in the U.K. </p>
<h2>Significant Progress'' </h2>
<p>German Chancellor Angela Merkel''s government made
significant progress yesterday in talks with state-owned
banks including KfW Group toward securing bridge loans of at
least 1 billion euros ($1.38 billion) for Opel, Juergen Reinholz, economy minister of the state of Thuringia, said
yesterday in a phone interview. A decision on a winning bid may
take until June, he added. </p>
<p>Government officials are likely to meet this week to
discuss the Opel bids and will convene as often as they need to
find a solution very quickly, Labor Minister Olaf Scholz
told reporters in Berlin today. </p>
<p>GM rose 18 cents, or 14 percent, to $1.45 at the close of
New York Stock Exchange composite trading. </p>
<p>Without a bridge loan, Opel will run out of money during
the third quarter, GM Europe President Carl-Peter Forster said
on May 15. Aurora, Ontario-based Magna''s bid would focus on
Russia, while Fiat''s plan would have a Latin American emphasis,
Forster said in a May 15 interview. Fiat Chief Executive Officer
Sergio Marchionne said in early May that he''s interested in an
as-yet-undefined venture with GM in Latin America. </p>
<p>We will work with all parties over the next few days on
how to proceed in terms of getting memoranda of understanding
with the bidder or bidders, GM Europe''s Preuss said in a
telephone interview today. </p>
<h2>States Favor Magna </h2>
<p>The four German states where Opel employs 25,000 workers
predominantly favor Magna''s proposal, which shuns factory
closures in Europe''s biggest economy, Hendrik Hering, economy
minister of Rhineland-Palatinate, said today. Magna wants to
turn Opel into an integrated automaker and supply it with
components directly. </p>
<p>The supplier angle is extremely attractive. That''s
something that Fiat is lacking, Hering said in a phone
interview. At the same time, job cuts may be considerable
under Magna, he added. </p>
<p>The offer from Fiat seems to have been well received by
German regional governments, Italian Industry Minister Claudio Scajola told reporters today in Rome, without providing details.
Germany''s Economy Ministry has no favorite bidder for Opel,
Steffen Moritz, a spokesman in Berlin, said today. </p>
<p>Arnaud Denis, a spokesman for RHJ in Brussels, declined to
comment. Daniel Witzani, a Magna spokesman based in
Oberwaltersdorf, Austria, couldn''t be reached on his cell phone. </p>
<h2>Fiat''s Labor Meetings </h2>
<p>Fiat has been the most vocal suitor for Opel. Marchionne
met with labor unions and German state politicians in the past
week in an effort to defuse concerns about a plan that worker
leaders have said may lead to losses of as many as 18,000
automotive-industry jobs in Europe. </p>
<p>It''s not just an Opel issue, Marchionne, who engineered
a deal to control most of the assets of Auburn Hills, Michigan-based Chrysler, said in an interview yesterday. It''s a
question of industry saturation. We need to handle this in an
intelligent way in Europe. It doesn''t have to be as drastic and
draconian as the American solution. </p>
<p>RHJ gets more than two-thirds of revenue from sales of
automotive parts. The company is led by CEO Leonhard Fischer,
who joined in 2007 from Credit Suisse, where he was head of
European operations. </p>
<h2>European Aid Needs </h2>
<p>GM has said it needs 3.3 billion euros in aid from European
governments to secure Opel''s survival. Merkel''s coalition
government, facing elections on Sept. 27, is keen to avoid a
collapse at Opel, which is Germany''s second-largest carmaker
after Volkswagen AG and is identified by a lightning-bolt
trademark. The Economy Ministry said on May 18 that it may send
a negotiating team to the U.S. this week to seek an agreement on
plans for Opel. </p>
<p>Opel is an integral brand of German carmaking, a true
symbol of this country''s postwar recovery, Reinholz said.
Governments have every reason to ponder all possible ways to
try and rescue the company. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chris Reiter" date="May 20, 2009  4:17 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-05-20/general-motors-received-3-bids-for-opel-unit-spokesman-says.html"><headline>General Motors Received 3 Bids for Opel Unit, Spokesman Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>General Motors Corp. has received
three bids for its Opel unit in Germany, GM Europe''s spokesman
Chris Preuss said in a telephone interview today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Nadja Brandt" date="May 21, 2009 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-05-21/electricite-de-france-fiat-shell-ucb-europe-equity-preview.html"><headline>Electricite de France, Fiat, Shell, UCB: Europe Equity Preview</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The following companies may have
unusual price changes in European trading. Stock symbols are in
parentheses, and share prices are from the previous close. </p>
<p>The Dow Jones Stoxx 600 added 0.5 percent to 211.75. The
Dow Jones Stoxx 50 Index climbed 0.5 percent to 2,142.77. The
Euro Stoxx 50 Index (SX5E), a benchmark for the nations using the euro,
increased 1.1 percent to 2,487.17. </p>
<p>Electricite de France SA (EDF FP): Chief Executive Officer
Pierre Gadonneix of Europe''s biggest power producer said the
company is studying a possible sale of bonds to the public. The
shares rose 93 cents, or 2.5 percent, to 37.55 euros. </p>
<p>Fiat SpA (F) : The carmaker made an offer for General
Motors Corp.''s Opel unit. The shares climbed 14 cents, or 1
percent, to 7.98 euros. </p>
<p>Royal Dutch Shell Plc (RDSA) : Europe''s largest oil
company has started to invite shareholders to discuss the
rejection of an executive pay package after performance targets
were missed. Shell gained 27 cents, or 1.5 percent, to 18.90
euros. </p>
<p>UCB SA (UCB) : Belgium''s biggest drugmaker by sales said
Melanie Lee, executive vice president and president of UCB
NewMedicines, will leave the company at the end of August. The
drugmaker is looking for an external candidate to succeed Lee.
UCB gained 68 cents, or 3 percent, to 23.52 euros. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David Pauly" date="May 28, 2009 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-05-28/general-motors-bondholders-might-take-20-percent-david-pauly.html"><headline>General Motors Bondholders Might Take 20 Percent: David Pauly</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>It will be a shame if General Motors
Corp. (GM) goes into bankruptcy proceedings simply because the U.S.
government and the automaker''s bondholders can''t compromise. </p>
<p>General Motors -- or rather, government appointees pulling
the strings -- offered owners of GM bonds a 10 percent equity
stake in a restructured company in exchange for $27 billion in
debt securities. </p>
<p>The bondholders objected, saying GM, until last year the
world''s largest vehicle manufacturer, was discriminating against
them in favor of its workers. </p>
<p>While the bondholders were voting against the proposal
Tuesday, Detroit-based General Motors got the United Auto
Workers to reduce to 17.5 percent the equity in the new GM to be
owned by a union health-care trust. A previous agreement called
for 39 percent. The UAW trust also gets $6.5 billion of
preferred stock and a $2.5 billion note. </p>
<p>This new agreement gives GM and the government some wiggle
room. Why not offer the bondholders a 20 percent stake in the
remade General Motors? There would still be at least 60 percent
left for the taxpayers, and maybe a dribble for current GM
shareholders. </p>
<p>Wouldn''t that be preferable to the company going into
bankruptcy? Chrysler LLC, the also-ran among U.S. automakers,
sought court protection last month after its debt holders
refused an offer of $2.25 billion for $6.9 billion in face value
for their securities. </p>
<h2>Not So Easy </h2>
<p>While the Chrysler bankruptcy may be on a fast track to
completion -- with its best assets sold to Italian automaker
Fiat (F) SpA -- a court proceeding for the much bigger and far-flung
General Motors might become an ordeal that benefits only the
lawyers. </p>
<p>The U.S. already has invested $19 billion in General Motors
and intends to dump in tens of billions more. Don''t waste money
in court. </p>
<p>It''s a bit of mystery why GM bondholders have been so
recalcitrant. They say the government is trampling on their
property rights and prefer to take their chances with a
bankruptcy judge. </p>
<p>Not all of the bondholders are speculators, as President
Barack Obama said. But some of them are -- they bought GM debt
on the cheap, betting on a windfall. That may make their legal
pleading look less reasonable. </p>
<p>Longer-term holders of GM bonds may have a better case.
Still, you wonder if they''re not just seeking cover for their
own poor investments. GM bonds due in 2033, for instance, trade
at between 5 cents and 7 cents on the dollar, compared with
about 70 cents a year ago. </p>
<h2>Something or Nothing </h2>
<p>If a restructured General Motors can''t compete any better
against foreign rivals than the old one, the bondholders
wouldn''t benefit if they owned 100 percent of the company. On
the other hand, if the new GM prospers, a 10 percent stake might
wipe out bad investment memories. </p>
<p>An offer from the government now to give the investors a 20
percent stake would be subject to the same sort of reasoning. A
bigger equity share in a continuing flop would have no more
value than a smaller share. Still, if General Motors does have a
profitable future, the bondholders could double up on their
share of the earnings. </p>
<p>The deadline for GM to restructure outside of bankruptcy
court is Monday. As a taxpayer, I''m willing to reduce my share
of the government''s stake in the company if they offer the
bondholders more. Do it. Fast. </p>
<p>(David Pauly is a columnist for Bloomberg. The opinions
expressed are his own.) </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry></news>