
<news><entry author="By Daniel Taub" date="Oct 03, 2008  4:39 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-10-03/general-growth-s-slump-shows-debt-risk-for-u-s-reits-update3-.html"><headline>General Growth''s Slump Shows Debt Risk for U.S. REITs</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>General Growth Properties Inc. (GGP) lost
more than 82 percent of its market value in the past year as
investors punished the mall owner for the loans it has coming due.
There may be more around the corner for other landlords. </p>
<p>Maguire Properties Inc., down 37 percent since Sept. 12;
Glimcher Realty Trust (GRT), down 22 percent; and Education Realty Trust
Inc. (EDR), down 9.8 percent, are among the real estate investment
trusts that, like General Growth, face debt repayment deadlines
through 2009. General Growth has dropped 65 percent since Sept.
12, the last trading day before New York-based securities firm
Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. filed for bankruptcy protection. </p>
<p>''''There is a general fear of real estate,'''' said Raphael Bostic, a real estate finance professor at the University of
Southern California and former Federal Reserve senior economist.
''''The business strategy very much relies on a liquid financing
market, and that just doesn''t exist right now. So when you rely on
that kind of strategy, you''re at risk of that excess volatility.'''' </p>
<p>General Growth shares tumbled on investors'' concern that the
Chicago-based company wouldn''t be able to refinance about $1.2
billion of debt it has coming due this year, said Rich Moore, an
analyst at RBC Capital Markets in Cleveland. Then they fell
further after company executives reported they had sold 5.67
million of their own shares for $112.5 million since Aug. 1. </p>
<p>`Poster Child'' </p>
<p>General Growth shares today rose $2.08, or 27 percent, to
$9.67 in New York Stock Exchange composite trading after the
company announced it had fired Chief Financial Officer Bernard Freibaum and suspended dividends. Freibaum was replaced by Chief
Accounting Officer Edmund Hoyt until a permanent successor is
found, the company said. General Growth will stop paying dividends
because of ''''uncertainty and volatility in the capital markets.'''' </p>
<p>If credit markets stay frozen, a similar fate may await other
REITs whose cash flow hasn''t yet caught up with expensive loans
financing acquisitions made as prices peaked, Moore said. </p>
<p>General Growth, whose troubles stem from the $11.3 billion
purchase of Rouse Co. in 2004, is the ''''poster child'''' for REITs
that are highly leveraged and have loans reaching maturity soon,
said Moore and Mathew Kirschner, an investment analyst at New
York-based REIT investor Cohen  Steers (CNS) Inc. No other U.S. REIT
has close to as much debt reaching maturity as soon as General
Growth, Kirschner said. </p>
<p>General Growth Chief Executive Officer John Bucksbaum called
the company''s share drop a ''''tremendous overreaction'''' by
investors and said in an interview last month that he has ''''every
confidence'''' debt coming due this year will be refinanced. </p>
<h2>Short Selling </h2>
<p>Proxy adviser Glass, Lewis  Co. this week criticized the
company for asking the New York Stock Exchange to ban short
selling of its shares even as executives, not including Bucksbaum,
sold 2.44 million of their own shares. </p>
<p>''''You''re going to have a lot of companies that had prudent
approaches that are going to be caught in this wave,'''' Bostic
said. ''''It really affects how investors view these companies.'''' </p>
<p>Like General Growth, companies such as Maguire, the largest
landlord in downtown Los Angeles, and shopping-mall owner Glimcher
are leveraged enough to worry investors who expect the troubles
afflicting lenders to continue, Moore said. </p>
<p>''''You really have to look at it on a case-by-case basis,''''
said Scott Black, founder and president of Delphi Management Inc.
in Boston, which has about $1.4 billion under management and is
considering buying shares of apartment and medical REITs. </p>
<p>REITs are ''''definitely affected by the lack of credit
availability in the banking system,'''' Black said. ''''But you better
look at when the debts are coming due.'''' </p>
<h2>Maguire Properties </h2>
<p>Glimcher shares are down 41 percent this year and Maguire''s
are down 78 percent. The drops are greater than the 15 percent
decline in the Bloomberg REIT Index and the 25 percent drop in the
Standard  Poor''s 500 Index. </p>
<p>In addition to General Growth, Los Angeles-based Maguire is
most at risk, Moore said. The company, which owns 30 office
properties in Southern California and one in Denver, plunged as it
reported losses, replaced the chief executive officer, and was
criticized by investors who wanted Maguire to put itself up for
sale. </p>
<p>Maguire has an 89 percent implied leverage, making it the
most highly leveraged of the 15 office REITs tracked by Green
Street Advisors Inc., the Newport Beach, California-based research
company said in a report last month. </p>
<p>The debts are the result of Maguire''s $2.88 billion purchase
last year of 24 office properties and 11 development sites from
Blackstone Group LP. (BX) The purchase encompassed all of the real
estate in downtown Los Angeles and Orange County that Blackstone
acquired in its takeover of Equity Office Properties Trust, and
came shortly before the collapse of the subprime mortgage industry
boosted office vacancies in Orange County. </p>
<h2>Debt Coming Due </h2>
<p>''''That was financed all with debt, and it was a big
percentage expansion to their portfolio, so it was definitely the
thing that put them in the position they''re in today,'''' said
Michael Knott, a senior analyst at Green Street, which has a
''''sell'''' rating on Maguire''s stock. </p>
<p>Maguire, as of June 30, had 11 percent of its total debt
coming due by the end of 2009, including $244.2 million in
construction loans and other debt maturing this year and $301.8
million in floating-rate debt, construction loans and other debt
coming due next year, according to the company. </p>
<p>The company said this week it extended maturities until 2010
on two construction loans totaling $49.1 million, completed a $100
million financing secured by a hotel, office and retail complex in
Pasadena, California, and extended until Sept. 28, 2009, the
maturity on an Orange County office construction loan. </p>
<h2>Shopping Malls </h2>
<p>''''We are mindful of the near-term maturities and are working
to extend those accordingly,'''' Maguire spokeswoman Peggy Moretti
said in an interview. The company is ''''in ongoing discussions''''
with its lenders and the ''''recent meltdown does not affect those
discussions,'''' she said. </p>
<p>Green Street calculates leverage using the current market
value of a company''s assets. Columbus, Ohio-based Glimcher is 65
percent leveraged, more than any other shopping-mall REIT the
research company tracks except Chattanooga, Tennessee-based CBL 
Associates Properties Inc. (CBL), which also has debt equaling 65
percent of its net asset value. CBL shares have declined 39
percent this year. Green Street has a ''''sell'''' rating on the
shares of both CBL and Glimcher. </p>
<h2>Loan Financings </h2>
<p>Glimcher has two loans totaling $92 million maturing this
year, and is working on restructuring one loan and refinancing the
other, said Lisa Indest, the company''s vice president for finance
and accounting, in an e-mail. In 2009, Glimcher has a $30 million
loan maturing on a mall it''s selling, a $46 million loan that''s
under discussion with lenders, and a line of credit with a June 30
balance of $297 million that can be extended one year, she said. </p>
<p>''''We feel the 2008 and 2009 maturities are manageable,''''
Indest said. </p>
<p>CBL said last week it refinanced $288.1 million of debt and
secured an $85 million term loan, satisfying all of its remaining
debt maturities for 2008. </p>
<p>''''It''s a tough environment, but this year we''ve been able to
work through it, and we expect that to continue,'''' CBL President
Stephen Lebovitz said in an interview. Refinancing the $400
million in mortgages maturing in 2009 probably will give CBL
additional cash because its malls have risen in value, he said.
''''Most of these loans have been in place for seven to 10 years, so
the cash flow has increased considerably over that time.'''' </p>
<h2>Resistant to Recession </h2>
<p>Among REITs that own apartment buildings, the company with
the highest 2008 and 2009 funding requirements as a percentage of
total assets is Memphis, Tennessee-based Education Realty Trust,
which develops and manages college student housing in 21 states.
The company has loans equivalent to more than 30 percent of its
total assets coming due in 2009, and ''''stands out as the most at
risk to a continued freeze-up in the credit markets,'''' Green
Street said in an August report. </p>
<p>Education Realty executives wouldn''t comment on the company''s
debt, outside spokesman Brad Cohen of ICR Inc. said. </p>
<p>While student housing is more resistant to recession than
other parts of the real estate industry, Education Realty''s
properties tend to be farther from campus than rival American
Campus Communities Inc. (ACC)''s housing, making them less attractive to
both renters and lenders, said Green Street analyst Andy McCulloch. He has a ''''hold'''' rating on the shares of both
companies. American Campus''s shares are up 20 percent this year,
compared with the 11 percent drop in Education Realty. </p>
<h2>Freddie and Fannie </h2>
<p>Education Realty is in a better position than some REITs
seeking financing because the loans it will need are relatively
small, and Freddie Mac and Fannie Mae have given indications that
they will continue to finance the development of apartment
buildings, giving the company a potential source of funds,
McCulloch said. </p>
<p>''''The fact that Fannie and Freddie are out there puts them in
a little better situation than some of these companies, that''s for
sure,'''' he said. </p>
<p>The only U.S. REITs with debt-to-asset-value ratios that
alarm Kirschner of Cohen  Steers, which has about $27 billion
under management, are Maguire and General Growth. General Growth
not only has ''''high leverage, but they have short-term
maturities,'''' he said. </p>
<p>''''Generally speaking, REITs operate at conservative leverage
levels,'''' Kirschner said. ''''Absent the General Growths of the
world, the REITs are in pretty good shape.'''' </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry></news>