
<news><entry author="By David Reilly" date="Dec 17, 2009  9:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-12-17/goldman-s-inner-conflicts-also-need-unraveling-david-reilly.html"><headline>Goldman''s Inner Conflicts Also Need Unraveling: David Reilly</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Let''s make banking boring again. That
is the noble goal of those calling for a return to the days when
the Glass-Steagall Act separated commercial and investment
banking. </p>
<p>The idea is that banks taking deposits insured by the
Federal Deposit Insurance Corp., and so backed by taxpayers,
shouldn''t play in the capital-markets casino. </p>
<p>To really achieve this, though, legislators may have to do
more than restrict what banks can do. They may have to bring
Wall Street back to life. </p>
<p>That would be the natural consequence of forcing some too-
big-to-fail banks to go back to their commercial-banking roots,
as envisaged by legislation proposed earlier this week by
Senators John McCain and Maria Cantwell. JPMorgan Chase  Co.
would have to spin off Bear Stearns. Bank of America Corp. would
have to shed Merrill Lynch. Citigroup Inc. would have to hive
off its own investment-banking activities. </p>
<p>Given all that''s happened over the past two years this
might sound crazy. Actually, it can make lots of sense if
Congress simultaneously splits up Wall Street titans such as
Goldman Sachs Group Inc. </p>
<p>And let''s not forget that the Glass-Steagall separation
worked for more than 60 years, from its passage in 1933 until
its repeal in 1999. The prohibition even gave birth to firms
such as Morgan Stanley, which in 1935 was spun off from what is
now JPMorgan. </p>
<p>First, though, a practical question: does such legislation
have any chance at success? </p>
<p>Long Odds </p>
<p>The odds are against it. Yet the politics of Wall Street,
bailouts and the economy are fluid, especially since 2010 will
see Congressional elections. </p>
<p>Plus, McCain and Cantwell aren''t the only ones buzzing
about Glass-Steagall. Earlier this week, House Majority Leader
Steny Hoyer said a return to that system is certainly under
discussion. </p>
<p>No wonder analysts at FBR Capital Markets in a research
note yesterday hedged their bets on just how far this may go.
While a forced breakup of banks may prove too big to swallow
for Congress, they wrote, this debate is going to garner the
spotlight much more quickly than we expected. </p>
<p>Politics aside, a renewed embrace of Glass-Steagall would
give current reform legislation real teeth. </p>
<p>The bills now in Congress provide for more stringent
regulation of financial institutions and impose rules such as
stronger capital requirements and a cap on the amount of
borrowed money firms can use to juice profit. </p>
<p>Falling Short </p>
<p>Yet they don''t tackle the issue of too big to fail.
Instead, by saying only that regulators can break them up as a
last resort, the legislation in the House gives the firms a
privileged status and doesn''t remove the threat that taxpayers
may again have to rescue them. </p>
<p>If the current strictures were combined with a new Glass-
Steagall-like provision, reform would have muscle. </p>
<p>Granted, Glass-Steagall isn''t a silver bullet. Plenty of
banks got into trouble in their bread-and-butter business of
lending to homeowners and businesses; Washington Mutual was a
good example. </p>
<p>That''s why the provisions in existing legislation for
beefed up regulation and capital are important, even if they
don''t go far enough on their own. </p>
<p>Congress shouldn''t stop there, though. Simply saying that
Goldman Sachs and Morgan Stanley are no longer bank-holding
companies (a coveted status they received last fall that allows
them to borrow at the Federal Reserve''s discount window), as
would likely happen under a Glass-Steagall-like split, won''t go
far enough. A newly reconstituted Wall Street would need to be
further divided. </p>
<p>Bundles of Conflicts </p>
<p>As things now stand, Wall Street and big banks are bundles
of conflicts that too often pit firms against their customers.
That led to some of the riskier practices that helped fuel the
financial crisis. </p>
<p>Investment houses underwrote and sold investors complex
bundles of mortgages, for example, even as they bet the housing
market would crater. </p>
<p>This needs to change. Either a firm is an adviser, a
broker, an asset manager or a hedge fund. It can''t be all things
to all customers. Nor can a firm be all those things and not
create the kind of linkages that threaten the stability of the
financial system. </p>
<p>So firms should have to choose between being, say, brokers
and investment bankers versus proprietary trading shops or asset
managers. </p>
<p>Making a Choice </p>
<p>In that case, if Goldman Sachs wants to be a giant hedge
fund, that''s all it should be. After all, some smaller, focused
players such as hedge funds failed during the crisis but didn''t
require taxpayer bailouts. </p>
<p>Splitting up Wall Street would also make finance easier to
regulate. In their current agglomerated state, too many firms
are impenetrable black boxes. </p>
<p>Regulators don''t really know what''s going on inside.
Neither do investors. And it often seems management is clueless
as well. </p>
<p>To be sure, changes along these lines would be painful and
bitterly opposed by banks and Wall Street. They would also be
tough to swallow since foreign banks wouldn''t face similar
restrictions. </p>
<p>Even former Federal Reserve Chairman Paul Volcker, who for
months seemed like a lone voice in favor of Glass-Steagall, has
admitted it''s tough to draw the line between certain banking and
trading activities. </p>
<p>Still, it''s worth a try. The result, as McCain said, may be
a larger number of smaller, more aggressive companies that are
not so big that their failure would bring the entire economy
down. </p>
<p>That would be good for markets, competition, the economy,
and ultimately banks themselves. </p>
<p>Plus, if Congress isn''t willing to find a new way to end
the threat of too-big-to-fail firms, why not revisit a proven
antidote. </p>
<p>(David Reilly is a Bloomberg News columnist. The opinions
expressed are his own.) </p>
<p>Click on Send Comment in the sidebar display to send a
letter to the editor. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lu Wang" date="Dec 17, 2009  4:46 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-12-17/general-growth-ldk-solar-lincoln-valence-u-s-equity-movers.html"><headline>General Growth, LDK Solar, Lincoln, Valence: U.S. Equity Movers</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Shares of the following companies
had unusual moves in U.S. trading. Stock symbols are in
parentheses, and prices are as of 4 p.m. in New York. </p>
<p>Allegheny Technologies Inc. (ATI)  rose the most in the
Standard  Poor''s 500 Index, jumping 5.6 percent to $40.20. The
specialty-metals producer said it will earn at least 20 cents a
share in the fourth quarter. Analysts surveyed by Bloomberg had
estimated profit of 3 cents on average. </p>
<p>A123 Systems Inc. (AONEQ)  advanced 5.9 percent to $19.40,
the highest price since Nov. 2. SAIC Motor Corp. (600104 CH),
China''s biggest automaker, said it will set up a $20 million
venture with A123 to make batteries for electric vehicles. </p>
<p>     A-Power Energy Generation Systems Ltd. (APWR US) climbed
2.6 percent to $19.15, the highest price since September 2008.
The Chinese power system manufacturer said it signed an
agreement in which it will supply turbines for a 600 megawatt
wind farm in West Texas. </p>
<p>Career Education Corp. (CECO)  tumbled 19 percent, the
most since August 2006, to $22.88. The U.S. Department of
Education said it found a serious issue at the agency that
carries out the accreditation of the company''s American
InterContinental University unit. </p>
<p>Other pro-profit schools also retreated. Apollo Group Inc. (APOL)
 fell 5.1 percent to $57.38. Corinthian Colleges Inc. (COCO)
 declined 5.5 percent to $13.13. ITT Educational
Services Inc. (ESI)  lost 5.5 percent to $90.53. </p>
<p>Cedar Fair LP (FUN)  surged 23 percent, the most since
March 10, to $11.20. The operator of the Cedar Point amusement
park agreed to be purchased for $11.50 a share, or 27 percent
more than yesterday''s closing price, by Apollo Global Management
LLC. </p>
<p>Citigroup Inc. (C)  had the second-steepest decline in
the SP 500, dropping 7.3 percent to $3.20. The recipient of the
biggest U.S. bank bailout sold 5.4 billion shares at $3.15
apiece, less than the $3.25 the government paid when it acquired
a one-third stake in the company in September. </p>
<p>Delta Petroleum Corp. (DPTR US) added 6.3 percent to $1.36,
the highest price since Oct. 29. The oil and gas producer backed
by billionaire Kirk Kerkorian said it signed a settlement
agreement with the U.S. government concerning Lease 452 located
offshore of California that will result in $65 million payment
to the company. </p>
<p>Discover Financial Services (DFS)  dropped 9.1 percent to
$14.92 for the biggest loss in the SP 500. The credit-card
lender that took $1.2 billion from the U.S. bank bailout fund
said profit fell 16 percent in the fourth quarter as credit-card
defaults increased. </p>
<p>EZchip Semiconductor Ltd. (EZCH)  fell 4.4 percent to
$11.04, the lowest price since March 9. The maker of network
processors sold 3.86 million shares at $10.50 each from funds
affiliated with Goldman Sachs and JKB Capital. </p>
<p>FedEx Corp. (FDX)  lost 6.1 percent, the most since March
20, to $84.47. The second-largest U.S. package-shipping company
forecasts earnings for the quarter ending in February won''t
exceed 70 cents a share. Analysts expected 84 cents, based on
the average of 17 estimates compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>General Growth Properties Inc. (GGP)  rose 8.7 percent
to $9.58, the first gain in three days. The mall owner seeking
to emerge from bankruptcy next year said it will consider all
offers for the company and may sell shares to the public to
raise capital. </p>
<p>GeoEye Inc. (GEOY US) had the second-steepest decline in
the Russell 2000 Index, sliding 16 percent to $26.71. The
provider of satellite imagery said it detected an
irregularity in the equipment GeoEye-1 uses to point the
antenna that transmits imagery to receiving stations on the
ground. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)  fell 2.5 percent to
$160.93, the lowest price since Sept. 2. Meredith Whitney
Advisory Group projects the New York-based bank will earn $19.57
a share in 2009, $19.65 in 2010 and $20.60 in 2011. Those
estimates were reduced from $19.95, $21.73 and $24.04,
respectively. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS)  lost 4 percent to $29.12. Meredith
Whitney cut its earnings projection for 2010 to $2.60 a share
from $2.63, while the 2011 forecast was reduced to $2.75 from
$3.28. </p>
<p>Harley-Davidson Inc. (HOG)  fell 4.8 percent, the most
since Oct. 30, to $25.59. The biggest U.S. motorcycle maker was
added to Goldman Sachs Group Inc.''s conviction sell list as
the brokerage cited near-term downside on retail sales in a
report to clients. The bank has a six-month price estimate of
$23 on the shares. </p>
<p>LDK Solar Co. (LDK US) dropped 15 percent to $7.84 the
steepest slide since Nov. 30. The Chinese manufacturer of
polysilicon wafer said it will sell 18.9 million shares and use
$120 million it expects to pay down short-term debt. </p>
<p>Lincoln National Corp. (LNC)  added 1.9 percent to
$23.52, the highest price since Nov. 25. The insurer was raised
to overweight from equal weight by Morgan Stanley, which
said the company is generating very solid new business. </p>
<p>MetroPCS Communications Inc. (PCS US) fell 6.5 percent to
$7.19, the steepest drop since Nov. 5. The pay-as-you-go mobile-phone was rated sell in new coverage by analysts at Deutsche
Bank AG, who said the Dallas-based company is the most
challenged U.S. wireless carrier because of increased prepaid
competition and the weak economy. </p>
<p>Leap Wireless International Inc. (LEAP US), MetroPCS''s
smaller rival that was rated hold in new coverage by
Deutsche Bank, slid 4.2 percent to $16.71. </p>
<p>Pier 1 Imports Inc. (PIR)  added 9.4 percent to $5.45,
the highest price since July 2008. The U.S. retailer of imported
furniture reported third-quarter profit excluding some items of
2 cents a share, beating the 5 cent average loss estimate by
analysts in a Bloomberg survey. </p>
<p>Rite Aid Corp. (RAD)  rose the most in the Russell 1000
Index, climbing 13 percent to $1.50. The third-largest U.S.
drugstore chain posted a third-quarter loss excluding some items
of 6 cents a share, 65 percent narrower than the average analyst
estimate, according to Bloomberg data. </p>
<p>Valence Technology Inc. (VLNC US) rallied 8.7 percent, the
most since Oct. 23, to $1. The maker of rechargeable lithium
polymer batteries said it will ship $1.4 million of its U-Charge
systems over the next two quarters to Smith Electric Vehicles
U.S. for use in electric trucks. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry></news>