
<news><entry author="By Rodrigo Orihuela and Macarena Munoz" date="Jul 07, 2014 11:04 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-07/jpmorgan-and-danske-among-funds-exposed-to-gowex-fraud.html"><headline>JPMorgan and Danske Among Funds Exposed to Gowex Fraud</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) and Danske Bank
A/S (DANSKE) funds are among investors in Let''s Gowex SA (GOW), the Spanish
Internet startup that''s filing for insolvency after saying it
falsified accounts for at least four years. </p>
<p>JPMorgan''s Euroland Focus fund had 2.9 percent of its
holdings invested in Gowex as of May 31, while the bank''s Europe
Focus fund had 2 percent of its portfolio dedicated to the
stock, according to the most recently available data on their
website. Danske''s Europe Absolute fund had 2.7 percent of its
portfolio invested in Gowex as of June 30, data compiled by
Bloomberg show. </p>
<p>Gowex founder and Chief Executive Officer Jenaro Garcia
resigned on July 5, taking responsibility for the accounting
fraud after a 60 percent drop in share prices in the wake of a
report last week by short-seller Gotham City Research LLP saying
the company inflated revenue. </p>
<p>The responsibility isn''t with just one person, it''s also
with the auditor and market regulator, said Javier Flores at
investor group Asinver, who puts the number of individual Gowex
shareholders at some 5,000. The damage isn''t only economic;
it''s also about the reputation of the Spanish market. </p>
<p>Jens Larsson, Danske Europe Absolute''s portfolio manager,
declined to comment, as did a Danske Capital spokesman. A
JPMorgan spokeswoman in Madrid declined to comment. </p>




Photographer: Gerard Julien/AFP via Getty Images

<p>
People walk past an advertisement for wifi provider Gowex in Madrid. Excluding the insiders, JPMorgan and Danske are among the top 10 institutional investors in Gowex, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bloomberg News" date="Jul 07, 2014  5:07 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-07/ibm-to-help-china-manage-air-quality-renewable-energy-supplies.html"><headline>IBM to Help China Manage Air Quality, Renewable-Energy Supplies</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines Corp. (IBM) started a project to support China in managing air quality and energy consumption as well as forecasting renewable-energy supplies. </p> <p>Under the project, the Armonk, New York-based company is cooperating with the Beijing municipal government on a system to determine the type, source and level of emissions and predict air quality in the capital, IBM said today in a statement. </p> <p>The project will enable utilities to estimate the amount of renewable energy that will be available for grid transmission or storage, IBM said. The company is also developing a new system to manage energy consumption of industrial companies that represent more than 70 percent of China''s total energy consumption. </p> <p>The move comes as IBM seeks to counter declining sales in the world''s second-biggest economy, where revenue fell 20 percent last quarter, dragged down by decreasing hardware spending. U.S. companies have also faced tensions over cybersecurity in China after U.S. prosecutors in May charged five Chinese military officers with allegedly hacking into computers of American companies. </p> <p>China is reviewing whether domestic banks'' reliance on IBM''s high-end servers compromises the nation''s financial security, Bloomberg News reported May 27 citing people familiar with the matter. IBM said in May it wasn''t aware of any government policy recommending against use of its servers. </p> <p>The world''s biggest carbon emitter is paying closer attention on renewable energy and air quality after Premier Li Keqiang declared war on smog in a speech in March. The nation has pledged to cut carbon emissions per unit of economic output by as much as 45 percent from 2005 levels before 2020. </p> <p>IBM is helping Hengqin Island in Guangdong province to cut energy consumption, costs and carbon emissions, it said. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Laura J. Keller and Tim Loh" date="Jul 08, 2014  6:36 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-08/walter-energy-bonds-would-pay-off-revolver-limiting-debt.html"><headline>Walter Energy Sells Bonds to Pay Off Loan Limiting Debt</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walter Energy Inc. (WLT) is turning to the
bond market to raise money that will allow the coal miner to pay
off a revolving loan that restricts its borrowing capacity. </p>
<p>Walter sold $320 million of debt in an add-on to its $650
million of 9.5 percent, first-lien notes due October 2019,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. It will use the money
to repay borrowings on its revolving lines of credit, according
to a regulatory filing today. </p>
<p>The new notes, part of a deal initially offered to
investors in September 2013, were sold at 99 cents on the dollar
to yield 9.74 percent, Bloomberg data show. The securities
traded at 101.5 cents on the dollar yesterday to yield 9.12
percent, according to Trace, the bond-price reporting system of
the Financial Industry Regulatory Authority. </p>
<p>The paydown will terminate the loan, ridding the
Birmingham, Alabama-based company of a corresponding leverage
test that prevented the highly indebted coal miner from
accessing the full amount of the revolver, according to Srihari Rajagopolan, a credit analyst at UBS AG. </p>
<p>The company will be left with $77 million of revolving
credit, down from $314 million before the transactions, and $43
million will be accounted for by letters of credit, according to
a statement from Moody''s Investors Service. </p>
<h2>Unsustainable'' Debt </h2>
<p>The new notes would add to Walter''s debt load, which
included $2.92 billion of long-term borrowings on March 31,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. Standard  Poor''s
lowered its credit rating to CCC+ from B- on June 27, saying in
a ratings statement that Walter had an unsustainable amount
of debt because of the low price of the metallurgical coal it
produces. </p>
<p>Executives of the coal miner told bondholders and lenders
on a private teleconference today that after the notes were
sold, it would have no more capacity under its credit agreement
to sell first-lien debt, according to two people on the call who
asked not be named because it wasn''t public. Walter would also
give up its ability to issue new second-lien bonds if it acts on
an option to pay interest with more debt on its $350 million of
11 percent notes due April 2020, said the people. </p>
<p>The company told investors today that it would continue
considering requests to swap debt for equity, the people said.
Chief Financial Officer Bill Harvey didn''t immediately respond
to a phone message left for comment about today''s call. </p>
<h2>Debt Swap </h2>
<p>Walter swapped $35 million of its 9.875 percent of $520
million senior unsecured notes due 2020 for $3.15 million in
common stock during the first quarter this year, Harvey said
during in a public conference call on May 1. </p>
<p>Speculation that shares could be diluted helped send
Walter''s stock down 8.6 percent to $5.62 today. Shares have
dropped 66 percent this year. </p>
<p>Walter executives on today''s call laid out several cost-saving measures they expect to undertake. The company plans to
save at least $20 million in annual capital expenditures from
the $130 million it previously told debt investors it would
spend, the people said. </p>
<p>Walter began idling its Canadian mines in April after the
global benchmark price for metallurgical coal fell to a six-year
low of $120 per metric ton. The money-saving measure resulted in
a charge of about $7 million related to severance costs,
according to today''s filing. </p>
<h2>Force Majeure </h2>
<p>The coal miner said today it plans to assert a force
majeure defense against Ridley Terminals Inc. that would allow
it to skirt an otherwise obligatory payment set forth in a
logistics contract with the coal transportation company. It has
an agreement with Ridley requiring a minimum yearly throughput
in British Columbia of 4 million metric tons of coal. </p>
<p>Walter''s maximum cost for not using the terminal is C$25
million ($23.4 million). The force majeure defense is based on
certain geological conditions affecting the idled Wolverine
mine, according to the filing. </p>
<p>A spokeswoman for Ridley declined to comment. </p>
<p>Maple Leaf Loading Ltd., which transported Walter''s
metallurgical coal from the now-idled Brule Mine to its
processing plant, has been placed into receivership by its
creditors, Walter said in the filing. As a result, Walter is
looking for an alternative transporter. </p>
<p>Moody''s assigned a B3 rating to the new notes today, while
reducing Walter''s corporate family rating to Caa2 from Caa1. </p>
<p>Before lenders agreed on July 7 to grant a temporary
reprieve of the loan''s leverage test, Walter was unable to
borrow more than $94.1 million on its $313.8 million of
revolving credit lines, according to a May 6 regulatory filing. </p>
<p>The company expects to retain access to short-term capital
through a new $62.1 million portion of the revolving loan that
it expects lenders to agree to today, according to the filing. </p>
<p>The company''s $450 million 8.5 percent notes due in April
2021, which are junior to the new notes, traded today at 56.5
cents on the dollar to yield 20.7 percent, compared with 59
cents on July 3, Trace data show. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jae Hur and Phoebe Sedgman" date="Jul 08, 2014  4:03 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-08/morgan-stanley-raises-nickel-forecast-by-13-in-2014.html"><headline>Metals May Benefit by China''s Easing: Morgan Stanley</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Industrial metals will probably be
the greatest beneficiaries of China''s intensifying policy-easing
measures in the third quarter, according to Morgan Stanley. </p>
<p>Economic growth in China is set to improve, helped by
easing and stronger export markets, metals analysts including
Joel Crane wrote in a report today, citing the bank''s chief
economist for China, Helen Qiao. </p>
<p>The LMEX Index of the six main metals traded on the London
Metal Exchange has risen 3 percent this year. Beijing will step
up policy-easing measures this quarter to counter potential
property market weakness and strengthen growth momentum, Morgan
Stanley said. </p>
<p>Copper, lead, and zinc supply-demand balances are already
in deficit, the bank said, adding that nickel and aluminum are
headed in that direction. The bank maintained its positive
outlook on copper amid a global shortage and expects prices to
average $7,055 a metric ton in the second half of this year and
$7,397 in 2015. </p>
<p>Copper for delivery in three months rose 0.7 percent to
$7,171.25 a ton at 5:01 p.m. in Tokyo, paring this year''s loss
to 2.6 percent. The metal is the worst performer among six
metals on the LME this year. </p>
<h2>Qingdao Port </h2>
<p>A probe into metals warehousing in China''s Qingdao port
will not disrupt the copper market, the bank said, adding it
doesn''t believe inventory financing behavior will have any
lasting effect on supply and demand fundamentals. Bonded
warehouse stockpiles in Shanghai declined sharply to about
600,000 tons as a result of unwinding financing since Beijing''s
initial crackdown in March, the bank said. </p>
<p>An acute shortage of scrap will continue this year,
increasing demand for refined copper and driving the global
market to remain in a deficit, the bank said. Mined supply
growth is struggling, with about 3 percent, or 600,000 tons, of
mine production capability lost to disruptions and technical
difficulties, it said. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley raised its nickel price forecast by 13
percent to $17,640 a ton for this year and 6 percent to $19,346
for 2015, anticipating a supply squeeze caused by Indonesia''s
ban on ore exports. </p>
<h2>Ore Exports </h2>
<p>Nickel has jumped 40 percent in 2014, the most among six
main metals on the LME, after Indonesia barred exports of
unprocessed ores in January. China is the biggest consumer of
the metal, with Indonesia its most important supplier of ore to
make nickel pig iron, a cheaper alternative to refined metal for
making stainless steel. </p>
<p>Prices caught a second wind in the second quarter after
production at two key projects in New Caledonia, Glencore
Xstrata Plc''s Koniambo and Vale SA''s VNC, failed to meet
expectations, likely accelerating the impending supply-demand
imbalance, the analysts wrote. </p>
<p>Global supply will exceed demand by 44,200 tons in 2014
before shifting to a deficit of 97,100 tons in 2015, the first
annual shortfall since 2010, the bank said. Nickel for delivery
in three months on the LME climbed 0.6 percent to $19,437 a ton. </p>
<p>Nickel ore and concentrate imports into China have slumped
36 percent this year, the bank said. China''s nickel pig iron
output will drop to 388,000 tons in 2014 and to 212,000 tons in
2015 from 472,000 tons in 2013, it said. Indonesia''s pig iron
production will rise from 1,000 tons this year to 46,000 tons in
2015 and about 150,000 tons in 2017, the analysts wrote. </p>
<p>Stainless steel orders in the U.S. remain strong, with some
mills booking as far out as November to December, the bank said,
citing Wood Mackenzie Ltd. In Europe, consumption of stainless
products is strong because of a substantial pick-up in demand
from the construction and auto industries, it said. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley also raised its average price estimates for
aluminum by 7 percent to $1,830 a ton in 2014 and 6 percent to
$1,913 in 2015, while the bank increased its estimates for zinc
by 3 percent to $2,123 in 2014 and 1 percent to $2,348 in 2015. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Grace Huang" date="Jul 09, 2014  1:09 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-09/disney-halts-on-demand-movie-sales-on-itunes-in-japan.html"><headline>Disney Resumes On-Demand Movie Sales on ITunes in Japan</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS), the world''s largest
entertainment company, resumed sales of new movies through Apple
Inc. (AAPL)''s online store in Japan after halting them temporarily in a
dispute over terms. </p>
<p>Disney said in a statement today that the transactions had
resumed, after the Burbank, California-based company had said on
its Japanese website yesterday that sales through iTunes of
films, including Frozen and Thor: The Dark World, had
stopped while rentals of existing titles continued. </p>
<p>We deeply apologize to our customers for this enormous
inconvenience, Disney said in the statement today. </p>
<p>The two companies have had close ties in the past and
Disney Chief Executive Officer Bob Iger has been a board member
of Cupertino, California-based Apple since 2011. When video was
first added to iTunes, the entertainment company was the first
major studio to sign on with service. </p>
<p>Apple co-founder Steve Jobs was a director at Disney before
his death in 2011. He became the entertainment company''s biggest
shareholder after Disney in 2006 bought Pixar, the animation
studio he helped create. </p>
<p>Calls by Bloomberg News to the media office of Apple in
Japan seeking comment on the temporary halt weren''t immediately
returned. </p>




Photographer: Kiyoshi Ota/Bloomberg

<p>
An Apple Inc. iPhone 5S smartphone in Tokyo. Sales through iTunes of films, including Frozen and Thor: The Dark World, stopped yesterday and the company is trying to restart the service while rentals of existing titles are continuing, Disney said in a statement on its Japanese website. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jeff Black" date="Jul 09, 2014  7:31 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-09/walter-says-ecb-bank-oversight-based-on-unprecedented-analysis.html"><headline>Walter Says ECB Bank Oversight Based on Unprecedented Analysis</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The European Central Bank will be
better able to identify lenders with poor risk management than
any previous supervisor, according to the official soon to be
responsible for monitoring the region''s largest banks. </p>
<p>We are going to carry out Europe-wide, comparative
analysis of banks that have similar business models, Stefan Walter, director general for Microprudential Supervision I at
the ECB, said in a speech in Frankfurt today. That wasn''t
possible in the previous nationally oriented supervision system.
A comparative peer-group analysis like this is an effective
instrument for supervisors to identify banks which are lagging
behind the risk- and business-models of other banks. </p>
<p>The ECB will take up oversight duties on Nov. 4. and is
currently building a more detailed record of the balance sheets
of euro-area banks than has ever been available. Officials from
the 128 lenders covered by the health check, or Comprehensive
Assessment, are meeting ECB staff in Frankfurt this week for an
update. </p>
<p>I want to emphasize that we''re going to use a
multiplicity of methods to assess the risks in the banking
system, and use them to direct our approach to supervision,
Walter said. </p>
<p>Walter, a former secretary general of the Basel Committee
on Banking Supervision and senior vice president at the Federal
Reserve Bank of New York, was appointed to the ECB in January. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Macarena Munoz" date="Jul 09, 2014  6:53 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-09/jpmorgan-contacts-clients-to-clarify-funds-position-on-gowex.html"><headline>JPMorgan Contacts Clients to Clarify Funds'' Position on Gowex</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Asset Management is
contacting clients to clarify its investments in Let''s Gowex SA (GOW),
the Spanish Wi-Fi provider that said it would declare insolvency
after falsifying financial accounts. </p>
<p>Fraud is a risk that is extremely hard to insure against
in portfolios and, by its nature, hard to detect, the asset
management unit said in an e-mail to clients, which was seen by
Bloomberg News. Three funds run by the company had exposure to
Let''s Gowex, according to the e-mail. A JPMorgan press officer
wasn''t immediately available to comment. </p>
<p>Let''s Gowex announced on Sunday that it would file for
insolvency and that its chief executive officer had resigned.
The company''s shares dropped 60 percent last week following a
report by Gotham City Research LLC that said Let''s Gowex
inflated revenue. </p>
<p>At the end of June, the stock was a 2.1 percent holding in
JPMorgan Funds Europe Focus Fund, 2.9 percent in JPMorgan Funds
Euroland Focus Fund and 0.31 percent in JPMorgan Funds Europe
Strategic Growth Fund. Trading in the stock has been suspended
since Thursday. JPMorgan Asset Management said the stock for
the purposes of the portfolios involved, is now subject to
consideration by the JPMAM Non Standard Pricing Committee. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alastair Marsh" date="Jul 09, 2014  5:37 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-09/morgan-stanley-joins-bofa-cutting-abs-outlook-amid-flood-of-cash.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Joins BofA Cutting ABS Outlook Amid Flood of Cash</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Mario Draghi is undermining his own
plan to support asset-backed debt as he floods banks with cheap
money, according to Morgan Stanley and Bank of America Corp. (BAC),
prompting them to cut forecasts for sales of the securities. </p>
<p>The European Central Bank President has made a revival of
the notes a key part of plans to fuel growth in the region to
help boost lending to businesses. The $2 trillion ABS market
contracted 32 percent since 2009 as regulators cracked down on
the debt they blamed for deepening the financial crisis. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley analysts led by Srikanth Sankaran cut their
estimate of full-year issuance to 72 billion euros ($98 billion)
from 78 billion euros, according to a note yesterday. Bank of
America analysts led by Alexander Batchvarov said last week
annual sales will total 90 billion euros, down from an initial
estimate of as much as 140 billion euros. </p>
<p>Easy access to central bank financing and muted balance
sheet growth limit the need for ABS funding across all
countries, the Morgan Stanley (MS) analysts said in their report. </p>
<p>Draghi is pumping cash into the 18-nation currency bloc in
an effort to bolster credit supply and boost inflation that is
running at about a quarter of the ECB''s goal. He estimates that
banks can take up as much as 1 trillion euros under targeted
longer-term refinancing operations, known as TLTROs. </p>




Photographer: Martin Leissl/Bloomberg

<p>
European Central Bank President Mario Draghi is pumping cash into the 18-nation currency bloc in an effort to bolster credit supply and boost inflation that is running at about a quarter of the ECB''s goal. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Monks" date="Jul 10, 2014  6:20 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-10/jpmorgan-names-guyett-asia-co-head-as-esperdy-returns-to-u-s-.html"><headline>JPMorgan Names Guyett Asia Co-Head as Esperdy Returns to U.S.</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) named Greg Guyett co-head of Asia-Pacific banking as part of a management
shuffle in the region. </p>
<p>Guyett will succeed Therese Esperdy, who is returning to
the U.S. to become global chairman of the financial institutions
group, according to a memo obtained by Bloomberg News and
confirmed by the New York-based bank. </p>
<p>The changes come after a management shuffle in China in the
wake of a probe by U.S. regulators into JPMorgan''s Asian hiring
practices. Guyett last year was named chief executive of
JPMorgan''s Greater China unit, a position that is being phased
out. China will now be overseen by UBS AG''s former China
Chairman David Li, who is joining JPMorgan in October as head of
the firm''s operations in the region. </p>
<p>Guyett previously ran JPMorgan''s Japan business and oversaw
its global corporate bank. He will oversee investment banking,
equity markets, and other operations in the Asia-Pacific with
Tom DuCharme, according to the memo. </p>
<p>Esperdy and DuCharme became co-heads of banking for Asia
Pacific in 2012. Esperdy will return to the U.S., and work with
the bank''s financial services team around the world on cross-border deals, the memo states. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Carroll" date="Jul 10, 2014  5:47 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-10/chevron-says-second-quarter-profit-exceeded-first-quarter-result.html"><headline>Chevron''s Second-Quuarter Profit Boosted by Asset Sales</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX), the world''s third-largest energy producer by market value, said more than half a
billion dollars in asset sales helped lift second-quarter profit
higher than the first three months of the year. </p>
<p>Chevron sold $500 million to $600 million in assets such as
oil and natural gas wells during the April-to-May period,
according to a statement the San Ramon, California-based company
issued today. </p>
<p>Production for the first two months of the quarter averaged
the equivalent of 2.566 million barrels of crude a day,
according to the statement. If that pace held for the final
month of the period, output slid 0.6 percent from the second
quarter of 2013. </p>
<p>Chevron is scheduled to release full results for the
quarter on Aug. 1. The statement was released after the close of
regular U.S. stock trading. Chevron shares have risen 4.3
percent this year, underperforming the 6.3 percent gain of the
Standard and Poor''s 500 Index. </p>
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. is the world''s biggest energy company by
market value, followed by Royal Dutch Shell Plc, according to
data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Jul 10, 2014  3:42 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-10/microsoft-ceo-nadella-outlines-vision-with-more-overhauls.html"><headline>Microsoft CEO Nadella Outlines Vision With More Overhauls</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT)''s Satya Nadella
unveiled his first vision statement as chief executive officer,
saying that more engineering and organizational changes are
needed as he attempts to turn around the software maker. </p>
<p>We''ve got to back it up with products people love and
that''s what we''re galvanizing to do, Nadella said in an
interview. </p>
<p>The CEO didn''t address the prospect of job cuts, yet people
familiar with the company''s plans said reductions will probably
happen. Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft is shifting its
focus from the devices and services strategy that former CEO
Steve Ballmer reorganized the company around last July and is
homing in more on productivity, mobile and cloud, Nadella wrote
in the memo today that was distributed to employees and posted
on the company''s website. </p>
<p>Over the course of July, the senior leadership team and I
will share more on the engineering and organization changes we
believe are needed, Nadella wrote. Nothing is off the table
in how we think about shifting our culture. </p>
<p>The memo is Nadella''s most comprehensive statement about
Microsoft''s direction since he was appointed CEO in February.
Since then, he has made several appearances at company and
technology events to discuss the priorities of mobile and cloud
products, as he works to shift Microsoft away from its longtime
core business of software for personal computers. Nadella has
signaled a desire to produce software for rival operating
systems like Apple Inc.''s iOS and Google Inc.''s Android and has
shuffled management in areas like marketing, business
development and the Xbox game console. </p>




Photographer: David Paul Morris/Bloomberg

<p>
Microsoft Corp. Chief Executive Officer Satya Nadella. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tanya Angerer and Fion Li" date="Jul 10, 2014 12:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-10/jpmorgan-sees-boc-in-rearview-as-asian-issues-boom-china-credit.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sees BOC in Rearview as Asian Issues Boom: China Credit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Competition to arrange global bond
sales in Asia is heating up as Chinese banks take advantage of
their compatriots'' dominance of fundraising in the region. </p>
<p>Bank of China Ltd.''s 3.7 percent market share ranked 10th
in the first half as Chinese lenders comprised seven of the top
30 sale managers, the highest on record, according to data
compiled by Bloomberg. HSBC Holdings Plc, Citigroup Inc. and
JPMorgan Chase  Co. were the top three arrangers, even as
Chinese issuers accounted for more than 50 percent of the $106.4
billion-equivalent of issues denominated in either dollars, euro
or yen in Asia ex-Japan. </p>
<p>The market has definitely become more competitive and
you''ve seen the new entrance of Chinese banks, said Mark Follett, the Hong Kong-based head of high-grade debt capital
markets for Asia ex-Japan at JPMorgan, whose 8.6 percent market
share trailed HSBC''s 12.8 percent and Citigroup''s 10.8 percent.
There''s still a clear separation between the top five or six
players and the rest, he added. </p>
<p>Banks from Asia''s largest economy have raised their share
of underwriting business to 9 percent from 4.4 percent five
years ago as Chinese companies involve them in their offshore
push. Dollar, euro and yen bond sales in Asia will set another
record in 2014, beating 2013''s $137 billion, the top five ranked
arrangers say. Sales of bonds in yuan outside China are also
heading for an all-time high. </p>
<h2>Leading Role </h2>
<p>We aim to maintain the leading role in the offshore
renminbi market and all the Chinese issues, leveraging our
relationships in the Dim Sum market into the G3 currencies,
Tony Wang, deputy general manager for global markets at Bank of
China (Hong Kong) Ltd., said in a July 10 interview. There are
more Chinese companies expanding in overseas markets and picking
Hong Kong as a funding platform. As a Chinese bank with
international experience, we''re able to understand their needs
and the global dynamics. </p>
<p>China''s influence in the region''s international bond market
has grown, with the country''s borrowers making up 60 percent of
sales last quarter versus 47 percent the first three months of
2014, data compiled by Bloomberg show. China''s 10 biggest
issuers make up 13 percent of JPMorgan''s Asia Credit Index,
which covers 324 companies around the region, Moody''s Investors
Service said in a June 23 report. </p>
<h2>Global Footprint </h2>
<p>This is further amplified when taking into account the
level of state ownership that exists behind many of the
country''s bond issuers, said Laura Acres, a Hong Kong-based
analyst at Moody''s. The China-based sub-index is skewed toward
real estate, oil and gas and quasi-sovereigns, which together
account for 20.4 percent of total exposure. </p>
<p>China Petrochemical Corp., the parent company of Asia''s
largest oil refiner, raised $5 billion in April in the biggest
offering of notes in the U.S. currency by an Asian issuer in
more than a decade. The amount matched a sale in November 2003
by Hutchison Whampoa Ltd., the Hong Kong conglomerate controlled
by Li Ka Shing, Asia''s richest man. </p>
<p>That same month, Cnooc Ltd., China''s largest offshore
explorer, sold $4 billion of bonds and Tencent Holdings Ltd.,
Asia''s biggest Internet company, priced $2 billion of debt,
making it the busiest month on record for dollar bonds in the
region. </p>
<p>Some banks counter that as transaction sizes swell, bond-sale managers increasingly need a global footprint. </p>
<h2>HSBC No. 1 </h2>
<p>Asian deals are being distributed more globally,
especially in the high-grade space where we''ve seen U.S.
investors in particular increasing their appetite for Asia,
said Hital Desai, a Hong Kong-based director in the Asia debt
syndicate team at Bank of America Corp.''s Merrill Lynch unit.
Having a global distribution platform really allows us to
connect the dots for both issuers and investors. </p>
<p>Bank of America ranked fifth the first six months of the
year, with a 6.9 percent market share that lagged Deutsche Bank
AG''s 7.4 percent. The next highest ranked Chinese bank after
Bank of China was Industrial  Commercial Bank of China Ltd.
with 1.6 percent, followed by Citic Securities Co. with 1.1
percent. </p>
<p>HSBC has held the No. 1 place since 2010, helping to
arrange 11.4 percent of sales in all of 2013 and 13.9 percent in
2012. </p>
<p>Issuers across the region look to us for our consistency,
innovative financing ideas and the full global reach of our
platform, said Alexi Chan, the head of HSBC''s Asia-Pacific
debt capital markets team. We''re on track for another record
year in Asian G3 currencies, assuming the current stable market
conditions continue. </p>
<h2>More Banks </h2>
<p>Along with deal size, the list of banks on larger trades is
also getting longer. China Petrochemical, known as Sinopec
Group, picked 13 banks to underwrite its bond offering this year
compared with 10 in 2013. </p>
<p>The flow from Chinese borrowers looks set to continue into
the second half as property developers press on with their debt
offensive. Shenzhen-based Redco Properties Group Ltd., rated B,
five levels below investment grade, by Standard  Poor''s, began
bond-investor meetings in Hong Kong and Singapore last week,
people familiar with the matter said. The company hasn''t tapped
the U.S.-currency market previously, Bloomberg data show. </p>
<p>With ongoing low rates, the second half is going to be a
busier one for high yield, said Deutsche Bank''s Singapore-based Jacob Gearhart, the head of global risk syndicate for
Asia. I also wouldn''t rule out the class of 2011, five-year
non-call three, issuers seeking to refinance. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Cathy Chan" date="Jul 10, 2014  2:54 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-10/jpmorgan-hires-ubs-s-david-li-as-china-head-replacing-zili-shao.html"><headline>JPMorgan Hires UBS''s David Li as China Head, Replacing Shao</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the biggest
U.S. bank, hired UBS AG (UBSN)''s former China Chairman David Li to lead
the Wall Street firm''s operations in the Asian nation. </p>
<p>As senior country officer for China, Li will be responsible
for JPMorgan''s businesses and products in the country, according
to the memo, which was confirmed by Marie Cheung, a Hong Kong-based spokeswoman. Li, who was also previously UBS''s country
head for China, will join JPMorgan in October and be based in
Beijing, the document showed. </p>
<p>Li replaces Zili Shao, JPMorgan''s former China chairman and
chief executive officer, who was named the bank''s Asia-Pacific
vice chairman in April. Fang Fang, the company''s CEO of
investment banking for China, resigned in March after more than
12 years at the firm amid an investigation by U.S. regulators
into its Asian hiring practices. </p>
<p>Shao, who joined JPMorgan in 2009, oversaw a China
expansion that included the formation of a domestic securities
venture, buying stakes in a trust and a guarantee company, and
establishing a locally incorporated bank. Li spent nine years at
Zurich-based UBS and helped set up UBS Securities Co., the
firm''s Chinese brokerage venture, of which he was chairman until
he left the company. </p>




Photographer: Adam Dean/Bloomberg

<p>
David Li, former chairman and country head for China at UBS AG, seen here in a file photograph in Beijing on June 12, 2009. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Akin Oyedele" date="Jul 11, 2014  3:46 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-11/morgan-stanley-sees-dollar-climbing-versus-canadian-counterpart.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Sees Dollar Climbing Versus Canadian Counterpart</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The U.S. dollar is poised to
strengthen versus its Canadian counterpart after a report showed
Canada''s labor market is lagging behind that of the U.S., Morgan
Stanley said. </p>
<p>The Canadian currency, called the loonie for the image of
the aquatic bird on the C$1 coin, dropped versus all of its 31
major peers today after the government reported the economy
unexpectedly lost jobs in June and the unemployment rate rose.
Hedge funds and other large speculators turned bullish on the
loonie this month after 70 weeks of betting against it. </p>
<p>The big picture is that Canada''s year-to-date labor
market performance has been dire compared to that in the U.S.,
Evan Brown and Calvin Tse, New York-based currency strategists
at the bank, wrote in a client note. The employment report
reinforces our conviction that Canada is not nearly as poised
to gain from U.S. growth as it was in the past. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley said the greenback may rise to C$1.12, a
level last reached on March 25. A bet on it gaining should be
scrapped if the U.S. currency drops to C$1.055, the strategists
said. They couldn''t be reached for further comment. </p>
<p>The U.S. dollar rose 0.8 percent to C$1.0734 and touched
C$1.0737, a two-week high, in Toronto trading. It fell to
C$1.0621 on July 3, a six-month low, after data last month
showed inflation rising above the Bank of Canada''s 2 percent
target in May for the first time since 2012. The greenback
reached a 4 1/2 year high of C$1.1279 in March after Bank of
Canada Governor Stephen Poloz said he couldn''t rule out an
interest-rate cut to spur slowing growth. The BOC''s next policy
decision is due July 16. </p>
<p>The U.S. is Canada''s biggest trade partner. </p>
<p>Canadian employers eliminated 9,400 jobs last month, data
showed, versus a forecast in a Bloomberg survey for a gain of
20,000. The unemployment rate rose to 7.1 percent, versus a
projection it would stay at 7 percent. </p>
<p>U.S. payrolls increased by 288,000 positions in June, and
the jobless rate fell to 6.1 percent, data showed on July 3. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David McLaughlin, Christopher Palmeri and Edmund Lee" date="Jul 11, 2014  6:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-11/disney-cbs-said-to-be-queried-by-u-s-in-comcast-merger.html"><headline>Disney, CBS Queried by U.S. in Comcast Merger</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS), Discovery Communications Inc. (DISCA) and CBS Corp. (CBS) are being asked for information by U.S. antitrust officials probing Comcast Corp. (CMCSA)''s planned purchase of Time Warner Cable Inc., according to three people familiar with the matter. </p> <p>The Justice Department has reached out to the companies as it investigates whether the cable-industry merger is anticompetitive, said the people, who asked not to be named because the review isn''t public. </p> <p>While none of the companies has publicly opposed the acquisition, some have said they want the U.S. to ensure that Comcast won''t favor its own programming over their content if the merger is approved. Other media companies have also been approached, one of the people said. </p> <p>Among other issues, the antitrust division is asking about most-favored-nation clauses, one of the people said. The contracts are used by Philadelphia-based Comcast and other pay-TV providers to ensure competitors can''t get better content-licensing deals with programmers. </p> <p>Media companies can help inform the Justice Department''s assessment of whether the Comcast-Time Warner Cable combination risks hurting competition, said Amanda Wait, an antitrust attorney at Hunton  Williams LLP in Washington. </p> <h2>Expanded Footprint'' </h2> <p>One of the big questions in the Comcast-Time Warner deal is how the expanded footprint of the cable company is going to affect its ability to deal with these content providers, Wait said. </p> <p>The Justice Department has been looking at most-favored-nation clauses, which stipulate that pay-TV operators such as Comcast can match subsequent deals networks get for their programming, for at least two years. In 2012, the antitrust division sent civil investigative demands, similar to subpoenas, to DirecTV and Dish Network Corp. about the agreements as part of a broader probe into whether pay-TV companies were squeezing out Internet-video competitors, people with knowledge of the matter told Bloomberg News at the time. </p> <p>Most-favored-nation contracts were also targeted in the Justice Department''s 2012 lawsuit against Apple Inc. (AAPL) and five publishers over prices of digital books. </p> <h2>Individual Deals </h2> <p>Lions Gate Entertainment Corp. Vice Chairman Michael Burns criticized most-favored-nation clauses in April, saying contracts originally created to help smaller cable-TV companies compete now benefit larger players. The agreements prevent Lions Gate from doing individual deals, such as a promotion with one distributor, he said. That means consumers pay more, according to Burns. </p> <p>Comcast, the largest U.S. cable company, said in February it would spend $45.2 billion for No. 2 Time Warner Cable. In addition to the Justice Department, the Federal Communications Commission is also reviewing the deal. The FCC yesterday started its nonbinding 180-day clock for finishing the review. The Justice Department, which considers the effects on competition, could sue to block the acquisition, approve it with conditions or clear it without requiring changes. </p> <p>We''re all trying to figure out consolidation, what does it mean for all of us in the industry, Discovery Chief Executive Officer David Zaslav said at Allen  Co.''s media retreat in Sun Valley, Idaho, this week. </p> <h2>Higher Rates </h2> <p>Netflix Inc. and Dish, the second-largest U.S. satellite TV provider, oppose the deal. Netflix, the video-streaming service, has said Comcast is already dominant enough to capture unprecedented fees, and would gain more leverage combining with Time Warner Cable. Dish argues Comcast will extract lower prices from programmers, leading to higher rates for smaller competitors. </p> <p>Comcast already won approval for its acquisition of NBCUniversal from the Justice Department in 2011. The company agreed to certain conditions as part of the deal, including making sure NBC''s shows would be available on fair terms to pay-TV rivals such as Dish and DirecTV. Abiding by net neutrality rules were also a condition of the agreement. </p> <p>The Justice Department could extend those same terms as part of any approval for Comcast''s purchase of Time Warner Cable, one of the people said. </p> <p>Officials with Comcast, Disney, CBS, Discovery and the Justice Department declined to comment. </p> <h2>Equal Footing </h2> <p>CBS Chief Executive Officer Les Moonves told Bloomberg in May that equal access for his broadcast and cable channels on Comcast systems was an issue the company was studying. </p> <p>I am sure the DOJ will prevent NBC from getting any advantage or at least we assume so, Moonves said on Bloomberg TV on May 15. We will be equally competitive with them on that basis. </p> <p>21st Century Fox Inc. Chief Operating Officer Chase Carey told Bloomberg News in May his company wants to make sure its online programs could be viewed on an equal footing with those of other services. </p> <p>The Justice Department is using the interviews with the media companies to understand the issues in the merger and guide the investigation, said one of the people. Discussions with the companies will probably be ongoing, the person said. </p> <p>The Justice Department typically has informal talks with third parties and then later can gather testimony under oath, according to Wait, the antitrust lawyer. </p> <p>They have a very complicated industry they''re trying to understand, Wait said. They''re seeing a deal they may want to challenge in the future, so they''re starting to put their ducks in a row in the event they decide to do that. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dalia Fahmy" date="Jul 11, 2014  2:08 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-11/jpmorgan-adding-europe-property-risk-as-safe-prices-rise.html"><headline>JPMorgan Adding Europe Property Risk as Safe Prices Rise</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s asset
management unit intends to quadruple its holdings of European
commercial property in need of renovations or new tenants as
well-occupied buildings in good condition become too expensive. </p>
<p>The company plans to raise its ownership of
opportunistic properties in the region to about 4 billion
euros ($5.4 billion) over three years, according to Peter Reilly, the company''s head of European real estate. During that
time, the New York-based investor will acquire less lower-risk,
or core, real estate. </p>
<p>In the next three years our buying activity will probably
be 80 percent opportunistic, whereas through 2012 it was 80
percent core, Reilly said in an interview. Our buy activity
shifts as the capital market shifts. </p>
<p>Investors like JPMorgan Asset Management, which holds about
$63 billion of real estate, rushed to the safety of Europe''s
most stable income-producing properties after the financial
crisis. Firms are now flocking to riskier office buildings,
shops and warehouses as prices for the safest assets in Europe
climb to their highest level since 2007. </p>
<p>Almost 60 percent of investors were searching for riskier
properties at the end of the first quarter, up from 47 percent a
year earlier, according to a study by London-based research firm
Preqin Ltd. The proportion of buyers seeking the highest quality
buildings with tenants in place dropped to 35 percent from 56
percent. </p>
<h2>International Investment </h2>
<p>JPMorgan Asset Management owns about 3 billion euros of
core properties in Europe, including offices, shops and
warehouses in the U.K., France and Germany, Reilly said. The
majority of its property holdings, about $45.5 billion excluding
real estate investment trusts, is in the U.S. Europe is second
at about $7.8 billion and Asia trails with around $1.1 billion. </p>
<p>Buying properties in need of investment to reach their
earnings potential is easier now because banks are more willing
to sell underperforming loans tied to real estate than they had
been in the aftermath of the financial crisis, he said. </p>
<p>Conversations with banks are more productive today than
they were a couple of years ago, when there was a big
difference between asking prices and bids, Reilly said. That
should accelerate through 2015. </p>
<p>Banks will sell loans with a face value of 83 billion euros
this year, 30 percent more than in 2013, as they clean up their
balance sheets to focus on new business, according to data
compiled by PricewaterhouseCoopers LLP. </p>
<p>The JPMorgan unit will focus on buying offices in large
cities including Paris, Berlin, Hamburg, Munich, Frankfurt and
the English cities of Birmingham and Manchester. High prices in
London make it difficult to find profitable deals there, he
said. </p>
<p>We like troubled assets in really good markets, he
said. So when you fix the asset, you''ve got a core property. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Oliver Renick" date="Jul 14, 2014  4:40 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-14/goldman-lifts-s-p-500-estimate-to-2-050-on-rising-profits.html"><headline>Goldman Lifts S&amp;amp;P 500 Estimate to 2,050 on Rising Profits</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The Standard  Poor''s 500 Index will
climb 4.2 percent to 2,050 by the end of 2014 as economic growth
picks up, Goldman Sachs Group Inc. strategists led by David Kostin forecast, boosting an earlier projection of 1,900. </p>
<p>Stocks with lower valuations will outperform the market
before the Federal Reserve begins tightening interest rates, the
strategists wrote. Goldman Sachs''s year-end projections for the
SP 500 in 2015 and 2016 remained unchanged at 2,100 and 2,200,
respectively. </p>
<p>We expect the equity rally will continue, but the
trajectory will be shallow, the group wrote in a note to
clients dated July 11. Domestic economic growth is
accelerating, and earnings will continue to rise, but further
P/E multiple expansion is unlikely. </p>
<p>Kostin''s new forecast makes Goldman Sachs the fourth most-bullish out of 19 Wall Street firms tracked by Bloomberg. The
SP 500 has been trading above Kostin''s previous year-end
forecast of 1,900 for almost two months amid growing optimism
that the economy was accelerating following a first-quarter
slowdown. </p>
<p>The SP 500 trades for 18.1 times its companies reported
earnings, the highest level since March 2010. </p>
<p>Lower-valuation stocks and those with weak balance sheets,
low returns on capital and low margins will lead the market''s
gains before the Fed''s interest rate tightening, Kostin wrote. </p>
<p>Viewed in relation to bonds, the U.S. equity market still
appears attractively valued, the Goldman group wrote. </p>
<h2>Stocks Rebound </h2>
<p>U.S. stocks advanced today, with the SP adding 0.5 percent
to 1,977.10 at 4 p.m. in New York. The Dow Jones Industrial
Average climbed 111.61 points, or 0.7 percent, to 17,075.42. The
Russell 2000 Index jumped 0.5 percent after its worst weekly
decline in more than two years. </p>
<p>The SP 500 rebounded today following its worst week since
April amid signs of financial stress in Europe and speculation
by firms including Raymond James  Associates Inc. that stocks
may be due for a pullback. </p>
<p>Improving macroeconomic data prompted Goldman economists
earlier in the month to predict the Fed will increase interest
rates in the third quarter of 2015, compared with an earlier
forecast for the first quarter of 2016. The Fed will lift its
benchmark rate to 4 percent by 2018, Goldman wrote. </p>
<p>Goldman is quite confident that the U.S. economy is
accelerating to an above-trend pace, chief economist Jan
Hatzius wrote in a report. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sonia Sirletti and Francisco Marcelino" date="Jul 14, 2014 10:09 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-14/generali-to-sell-bsi-unit-to-btg-pactual-for-1-7-billion.html"><headline>BTG Pactual Buys Generali''s BSI Unit for $1.7 Billion</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Grupo BTG Pactual (BBTG11), the only
investment bank publicly traded in Brazil, agreed to buy
Assicurazioni Generali SpA (G)''s Swiss private-banking unit for 1.5
billion Swiss francs ($1.7 billion) to help build a global
private-banking platform. </p>
<p>BTG will pay for BSI Group with 1.2 billion francs in cash
and 300 million francs of shares in units listed in Sao Paulo,
Generali said in a stock-exchange statement today. The Trieste,
Italy-based company said it will book a loss of about 100
million euros ($136 million) for the transaction, while the deal
will add about 9 percentage points to its Solvency 1 ratio. </p>
<p>The Brazilian lender controlled by billionaire Andre Esteves is expanding internationally as the country''s growth
slows. It''s added units in Mexico and Colombia, and in January
Esteves said he planned to open offices in Geneva, Houston and
Singapore as the firm expanded in commodities. Last week, it
agreed to acquire Global Atlantic Financial Group Ltd.''s
reinsurance unit Ariel Re. </p>
<p>This acquisition reflects our confidence in the tradition
and strength in Switzerland as a global financial center,
Esteves, the bank''s chief executive officer, said in a
statement. It''s an opportunity to build one of the biggest
global private-banking platforms. </p>




Photographer: Simon Dawson/Bloomberg

<p>
Assicurazioni Generali SpA Chief Executive Officer Mario Greco is selling BSI as part of a plan to focus on the company''s main business, strengthen finances and boost profitability. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sonia Sirletti" date="Jul 14, 2014  5:29 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-14/generali-to-sell-bsi-to-btg-pactual-for-1-5-billion-swiss-francs.html"><headline>Generali to Sell BSI Unit to BTG Pactual for $1.7 Billion</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Assicurazioni Generali SpA (G) agreed to
sell its Swiss private-banking unit BSI Group to Grupo BTG
Pactual (BBTG11) for 1.5 billion Swiss francs ($1.7 billion) as Italy''s
biggest insurer seeks to boost capital. </p>
<p>Generali will receive 1.2 billion francs in cash and 300
million francs in BTG units listed in Sao Paulo, Generali said
in a stock-exchange statement today. The Trieste, Italy-based
company will book about a 100 million-euro ($136 million) loss,
while the transaction will add about 9 percentage points to its
Solvency 1 ratio, according to the statement. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Mario Greco sold the unit to focus
on the company''s main business, strengthen finances and boost
profitability. The company, which set a goal of 4 billion euros
of revenue from asset sales by 2015, will have 3.7 billion euros
with this sale, Greco said in the statement. </p>
<p>This sale completes the disposal process aimed at
strengthening the capital base of the group, resolving a key
issue for us, and allowing Generali to focus on driving forward
with its core insurance business, Greco said. This result is
a testament to our team''s ability and commitment to execute a
complex transaction in a challenging environment. </p>
<p>Generali rose as much as 1.4 percent and was up 0.7 percent
to 15.49 euros as of 11:20 a.m. in Milan, giving the insurer a
value of 24.1 billion euros. </p>
<h2>U.S. Fines </h2>
<p>BTG, the Brazilian lender controlled by billionaire Andre Esteves, is expanding internationally as Brazil''s growth slows.
It''s added units in Mexico and Colombia, and in January Esteves
said he plans to open offices in Geneva, Houston and Singapore
as the firm expands in commodities. </p>
<p>Proceeds from the sale, which is scheduled to be completed
by the first half of 2015, may be reduced by any fine
established pursuant to the U.S. Department of Justice''s tax
amnesty program relating to Swiss financial banking institutions
payable by BSI, Generali said. </p>
<p>BSI is one of at least 36 Category 2 Swiss banks seeking to
avoid prosecution for handling undeclared American money by
joining the U.S. Justice Department''s voluntary disclosure
program. The U.S. is scouring Switzerland for names of tax
dodgers who used the world''s largest offshore haven to hide
money from the Internal Revenue Service. </p>
<h2>BSI Loss </h2>
<p>Under a program announced in August, about a third of Swiss
banks with reason to believe they violated tax laws asked
the Justice Department to forgo prosecution. In turn, banks must
hand over data on undeclared accounts and pay penalties. </p>
<p>BSI had a net loss of 722 million Swiss francs last year as
it took writedowns faster than planned because of new
regulations for accounting treatment of goodwill, the bank said
April 28. </p>
<p>Generali''s net income in the three months to March climbed
to 660 million euros from 603 million euros a year earlier, the
company said in May. The first-quarter pro-forma Solvency 1
ratio after the BSI sale will exceed the insurer''s 2015 target
of 160 percent, it said today. </p>
<p>Once the announced sale of BSI is concluded, Generali''s
period of balance sheet repair will be complete, Marcus Rivaldi, an analyst at Morgan Stanley, said in a note today.
Focus now turns to how earnings and dividends can be
improved. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Jul 15, 2014  5:39 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-15/microsoft-said-to-announce-job-cuts-as-soon-as-this-week.html"><headline>Microsoft to Announce Job Cuts as Soon as This Week</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) is planning its biggest round of job cuts in five years, as the software maker looks to slim down and integrate Nokia Oyj''s handset unit, people with knowledge of the company''s plans said. </p> <p>Chief Executive Officer Satya Nadella said in an interview last week that he has preparing to make sweeping changes at Microsoft. The reductions will probably be in engineering, marketing and areas of overlap with Nokia, said the people, who asked not to be identified because the plans aren''t public. </p> <p>The restructuring -- which may be unveiled as soon as this week -- may end up being the biggest in Microsoft history, topping the 5,800 jobs cut in 2009, two of the people said. Some details are still being worked out, two of the people said. </p> <p>Related: Microsoft, Intel to Benefit as Businesses Upgrade PCs</p><p>Nadella, who took over from Steve Ballmer in February, said in the interview that Microsoft would have to become more focused and efficient. The CEO issued his first company mission statement last week, calling for greater emphasis on mobile devices, cloud-computing and productivity software as consumers and businesses buy fewer personal computers to check e-mail, browse the Web and access data and software. </p>




Source: Microsoft Corp. via Bloomberg

<p>
Microsoft employees listen as Satya Nadella, chief executive officer of Microsoft Corp., speaks to employees at Microsoft''s Studio D building in Seattle, Washington, U.S.. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jul 15, 2014  3:46 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-15/goldman-sachs-s-stress-test-stumble-leads-to-repo-cut.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs''s Stress-Test Stumble Leads to Repo Cut</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), which had
to resubmit its capital plan this year after falling below a
minimum leverage ratio, used that experience as motivation to
cut lending through repurchase agreements. </p>
<p>The bank reduced total assets by $56 billion to $860
billion as of June 30, the lowest level since 2009. Goldman
Sachs is cutting back on businesses that have low return on
assets and $25 billion of the reduction came in the firm''s
matched book repo lending, Chief Financial Officer Harvey Schwartz said today in a conference call with analysts after the
New York-based firm reported second-quarter results. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs is facing pressure to reduce assets as the
bank is below the 5 percent minimum ratio in the proposed
supplementary leverage ratio, which measures equity capital
compared to assets unweighted by risk. In March, it also had to
reduce the amount of capital it planned to return in the Federal
Reserve''s stress test, known as CCAR, after dropping below the 4
percent minimum of a separate requirement. </p>
<p>We identified opportunities to reduce balance sheet with
a de minimis impact to our client franchise and earnings
potential, Schwartz said. One of the significant inputs into
the process obviously was CCAR. </p>
<p>In a matched book, banks rely on repurchase agreements and
securities lending to fund clients while using the same
collateral and terms to borrow themselves, often overnight. </p>
<h2>Repo Failures </h2>
<p>Goldman Sachs''s asset reductions also affect other secured
financing for clients, Schwartz said. While the firm didn''t
release a full balance sheet with its quarterly results today,
it had $355.9 billion in secured client financing and secured
financing agreements at the end of March, which represented
about 40 percent of its assets. </p>
<p>The bank hadn''t seen a pressing need to cut back on the
low-margin secured loans before the leverage ratio and stress
test because they were viewed as a low risk way to help clients,
according to a person with direct knowledge of the firm''s
discussions. Clients have been understanding of Goldman Sachs''s
decision to pull back, said the person, who asked to remain
anonymous because the talks were private. </p>
<p>Recent changes in borrowing rates and so-called failures in
the $1.6 trillion-a-day repo market suggest other participants
have trimmed their matched books, the person said. Failures to
deliver Treasuries in repo trades have increased this year and
repo rates on some debt have fallen as low as negative 3
percent. </p>
<p>A lot''s been written about the repo markets, Schwartz
said on the call. Certainly our $25 billion reduction in the
matchbook had no marginal impact in terms of the repo markets,
but I think this will be interesting to watch how it evolves,
because as mentioned earlier, large banks have multiple
constraints. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs''s ratio under the proposed supplementary
leverage ratio is 4.5 percent and will reach 5 percent as the
firm reduces certain fund stakes to comply with the Volcker
Rule, Schwartz said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jul 15, 2014  1:11 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-15/goldman-sachs-beats-estimates-on-fixed-income-trading.html"><headline>Goldman Posts Surprise Profit Gain on Trading, Deal Fees</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) reported a surprise increase in second-quarter profit as fixed-income revenue fell less than many analysts projected and investment-banking fees rose. </p> <p>Net income climbed 5 percent to $2.04 billion, or $4.10 a share, from $1.93 billion, or $3.70, a year earlier, the New York-based company said today in a statement. That beat the $3.09 average estimate of 25 analysts in a Bloomberg survey. </p> <p>Chief Executive Officer Lloyd C. Blankfein, 59, has pledged not to overreact to a trading slump that''s now in its fifth year as he positions the firm to pick up market share from other banks that are pulling back. Blankfein is also relying on underwriting stocks and bonds, which accounted for 14 percent of revenue in the second quarter, the highest portion since 2000. First-half investment-banking fees climbed to a record. </p> <p>We''ve got a strong beat here, primarily revenue-driven, and Goldman is a little more resilient than expected, Devin Ryan, an analyst at JMP Group Inc. in New York, said in a telephone interview. </p> <p>Related: JPMorgan Profit Beats Estimates on Trading, Shares Climb</p><p>Goldman Sachs climbed 1 percent to $168.59 at 12:42 p.m. in New York. The stock dropped 5.8 percent this year through yesterday, making it the worst performer in the Dow Jones Industrial Average. (INDU) </p> <p>Revenue rose 6 percent to $9.13 billion. Compensation, the firm''s biggest expense, climbed to $3.92 billion, or 43 percent of revenue, the same percentage as a year earlier. </p> <h2>Equity Investments </h2> <p>The biggest surprise compared to many analysts'' estimates was the gain on the firm''s equity investments in its Investing and Lending segment, which totaled $1.25 billion. That was almost double the $650 million expected by Barclays Plc''s Jason Goldberg. </p> <p>While Chief Financial Officer Harvey Schwartz said that business has repeatedly been a strong performer, Matthew Burnell, an analyst at Wells Fargo  Co., said investors value such revenue at lower multiples than that of other units because it''s so unpredictable. </p> <p>They had a very good quarter in principally selling some assets in their private-equity portfolio, said Kenneth Leon, an analyst who covers the financial industry for SP Capital IQ. It was the lumpy transactions that really made the revenue stand out. </p> <h2>FICC Results </h2> <p>Fixed-income, currency and commodity trading revenue was $2.22 billion, surpassing estimates of $1.79 billion from Brad Hintz, an analyst at Sanford C. Bernstein  Co., and $2.1 billion from Goldberg at Barclays. </p> <p>The 9 percent second-quarter drop in bond-trading revenue, excluding an accounting adjustment, beat the 24 percent decline predicted by Burnell. JPMorgan Chase  Co. today posted a 15 percent drop in fixed-income revenue. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs''s revenue from the equities division declined 11 percent from a year earlier to $1.63 billion, excluding accounting adjustments. That compared with Hintz''s $1.54 billion estimate and Goldberg''s $1.71 billion projection. </p> <p>While the trading performance was better than expected, it still marked the lowest first-half revenue since the financial crisis in 2008. The bank earned a 10.9 percent return on equity in the quarter, a third of the level before the financial crisis. </p> <h2>Abnormal'' Trading </h2> <p>Goldman Sachs President Gary Cohn, 53, said in May that the current environment is abnormal and features trading clients that are the least active in years. He noted that the 10-year Treasury yield maintained the smallest range in 35 years in the three months ended in May. </p> <p>If markets never move or don''t move, our clients really don''t need to transact, Cohn said. </p> <p>The firm has cut 10 percent of its fixed-income workforce since 2010 and reduced the risk-weighted assets in that business by $90 billion in the past two years. It has also relied on other businesses for growth. </p> <p>Second-quarter revenue from investment banking, the business run globally by Richard J. Gnodde, David M. Solomon and John S. Weinberg, climbed 15 percent to $1.78 billion. That compared with JPMorgan''s $1.77 billion in investment-banking revenue and Citigroup''s $1.34 billion. </p> <p>The Goldman Sachs figure included $506 million of financial-advisory revenue, including fees for takeover advice, an increase of 4 percent. Revenue from underwriting climbed to $1.28 billion in the quarter, including $730 million from debt underwriting and $545 million for equity offerings. </p> <h2>MA Advice </h2> <p>Goldman Sachs held the top spot among arrangers of global equity, equity-linked and rights offerings in the first half, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. It ranked first in advising on announced mergers and acquisitions and fifth in underwriting U.S. bonds, the data show. </p> <p>Investing and Lending posted total second-quarter revenue of $2.07 billion, up from $1.42 billion a year earlier. </p> <p>The firm has about $8 billion of stakes in private-equity funds that it must cut to comply with the Volcker Rule, which limits the amount banks can invest in such funds, Schwartz said. </p> <p>Revenue from asset management, run by Timothy O''Neill and Eric Lane, rose 8 percent to $1.44 billion. Total assets under supervision climbed $59 billion during the quarter to $1.14 trillion. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Anthony Effinger" date="Jul 15, 2014 11:34 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-15/morgan-stanley-loses-brokers-managing-650-million-to-start-up.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Loses Brokers Managing $650 Million to Start-Up</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Craig Stuvland, former president of
Common Sense Investment Management LLC, lured four Morgan
Stanley brokers with $650 million in client assets to a new firm
that supports independent financial advisers. </p>
<p>The team left Morgan Stanley''s Portland office today and
immediately set up Encompass Wealth Advisors using trading
systems, research, lawyers and office space arranged by Tru
Independence LLC, also based in Portland. </p>
<p>Stuvland''s is the latest in a growing number of firms that
help wealth advisers leave large banks and go it alone. Dynasty
Financial Partners LLC, founded in 2010, has 22 companies that
manage $21 billion using its system. HighTower Advisors LLC in
Chicago and Focus Financial Partners LLC in New York also work
to pry brokers out of big firms. </p>
<p>Tru Independence will collect a percentage of Encompass''s
management fees as payment for its services. </p>
<p>You''re not going to go from being a wire-house money
manager to an entrepreneur just by thinking about it at night,
Colin Williams, an Encompass partner and ordained Episcopal
priest, said in an interview. It takes help, he said. </p>
<p>Stuvland is betting that the team''s clients will follow it
out of Morgan Stanley. The Protocol for Broker Recruiting, an
agreement among securities firms, banks and asset managers,
prohibits wealth advisers from telling clients about a move
until after it is completed. Then, they are allowed to take with
them only names, addresses, phone numbers and e-mail addresses,
according to the protocol. </p>
<p>Typically, 95 percent of the assets follow the adviser,
Stuvland, 58, said in an interview. </p>
<h2>Attrition Down </h2>
<p>Morgan Stanley increased its target for profit margins in
the firm''s wealth-management division after the  unit''s pretax
profit jumped 62 percent last year. Greg Fleming, who oversees
the brokerage, has said the attrition among financial advisers
has fallen as the firm completed its technology integration
following the purchase of Smith Barney from Citigroup Inc. </p>
<p>Until last year, Stuvland was a senior partner at Common
Sense, a fund of hedge funds in Portland. He left after founder
James Bisenius was arrested in a prostitution sting in nearby
Tigard, Oregon, in August. The firm managed $3 billion before
the arrest. At the time, Common Sense said Bisenius would remain
at the company. </p>
<p>Before joining Common Sense, Stuvland spent 16 years at
Crabbe Huson Group, a mutual fund company in Portland that
managed $5 billion when he left in 1998. His co-founder in Tru
is Eric Warlick, with whom he worked at Crabbe Huson. Before
Tru, Warlick worked at Fidelity Investments, TD Ameritrade
Holding Corp. and Charles Schwab Corp., selling their services
to brokers going independent. </p>
<p>In addition to Williams, Encompass''s other partners are
advisers Derrick Clouser, 45, Matthew Presjak, 55, Walter Urban,
63, and administrator Mary Minshall, 46. </p>
<p>While at Morgan Stanley, Clouser''s team called itself the
Encompass Group at Morgan Stanley. His is the second broker
departure in Portland this year. David Christian, Jeffrey Krum
and Brian Hefele left Merrill Lynch, a unit of Bank of America
Corp., with $700 million in March. </p>
<p>Clouser built his clientele in part by partnering with
older brokers and then taking over their books of business and
compensating them as they retire, he said. He intends to
continue that strategy as part of Tru. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kristen Haunss" date="Jul 15, 2014 10:19 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-15/jpmorgan-releases-first-u-s-index-to-measure-clo-returns.html"><headline>JPMorgan Releases First U.S. Index to Measure CLO Returns</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) has created the
first U.S. index of its type to measure returns of
collateralized loan obligations, which are on pace for a record
year of issuance. </p>
<p>The CLOIE gauge will be available for use today, according
to Gloria Kim, the head of global index research at the bank in
New York. The measure will allow users to track the price and
total return of CLOs and their debt portions, according to the
bank. </p>
<p>JPMorgan forecasts that as much as a record $100 billion of
the funds that bundle junk-rated loans into securities with
ratings as high as AAA may be sold in the U.S. this year. There
has been $66.6 billion arranged in 2014, according to data from
the bank. CLOs helped finance some of the biggest leveraged
buyouts during the last credit boom. </p>
<p>This is the first time anyone has tried to create a
realistic index with rules that track the price performance and
total return of CLOs, Rishad Ahluwalia, global head of CLO
research at JPMorgan in London, said in a telephone interview.
We want to challenge the market to improve transparency and
while this will evolve over time, we want to help move it
forward as the market develops. </p>
<p>The CLOIE tracks floating-rate CLO securities for deals
dating back to 2004, according to information from the bank.
Additional sub-indexes are divided by ratings AAA through BB.
Pricing for the index is provided by PricingDirect Inc., an
affiliate of JPMorgan, according to the bank. </p>
<h2>Transparent Benchmark'' </h2>
<p>For a while we wanted to create a transparent benchmark
for investors that tracked returns, Ahluwalia said. </p>
<p>The AAA rated portion of CLOs raised after the credit
crisis has returned 1.07 percent this year, according to the
JPMorgan CLOIE Index. That compares with 0.31 percent for all of
2013 and 3.86 percent in 2012. </p>
<p>The CLO measure follows the introduction of the JPMorgan
Asset-Backed Securities Indices in 2013, according to the bank. </p>
<p>CLOs pool high-yield corporate loans and slice them into
securities of varying risk and return, typically from AAA
ratings down to B. The lowest portion, known as the equity
tranche, offers the highest potential returns and the greatest
risk because investors are the first to see their interest
payouts reduced when loans backing the CLO default. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hugh Son" date="Jul 15, 2014  9:37 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-15/jpmorgan-profit-tops-estimates-on-better-than-expected-trading.html"><headline>JPMorgan Profit Beats Estimates on Trading, Shares Climb</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the biggest U.S. bank, posted second-quarter profit that beat estimates as fixed-income trading revenue fell less than analysts expected. The stock climbed the most in eight months. </p> <p>Net income declined 7.9 percent to $5.99 billion, or $1.46 a share, from $6.5 billion, or $1.60, a year earlier, the New York-based firm said today in a statement. Earnings excluding some items were $1.59 a share, topping the $1.31 average estimate of 29 analysts surveyed by Bloomberg. Revenue slid 2.3 percent to $25.4 billion from a year earlier. </p> <p>Quarterly results were overshadowed by questions about the health of Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon, 58, who said July 1 that he would soon undergo radiation and chemotherapy for throat cancer. While Dimon reiterated today that his prognosis is excellent and that he''ll be able to work during eight weeks of treatment, the disclosure raised fresh questions about succession planning at the bank he''s run since 2006. </p> <p>Related: </p>
Dimon Says JPMorgan Prepared for All Scenarios Amid Cancer Fight
Goldman Posts Surprise Profit Gain on Trading, Deal Fees
<p>There''s definitely a Jamie premium in this stock that would come out if the market believed he was going to make a transition, said Marty Mosby, director of bank and equity strategies at Memphis, Tennessee-based broker-dealer Vining Sparks. With someone as strong as Jamie, the trouble is that everybody else was part of a team who reported to him, and there''s not a clear second-in-command or frontrunner to take over. </p>




Photographer: Jason Alden/Bloomberg

<p>
Quarterly results may take a back seat to questions today about the health of Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon, 58, who said July 1 that he would soon undergo radiation and chemotherapy for throat cancer. While Dimon said his prognosis is excellent and he''ll be able to work during his eight-week treatment, the announcement raised fresh questions about succession planning at the bank he''s run since 2006. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ian King, Dina Bass and Adam Satariano" date="Jul 15, 2014 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-15/microsoft-intel-to-benefit-as-businesses-upgrade-pcs.html"><headline>Microsoft, Intel to Benefit as Businesses Upgrade PCs</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The personal-computer industry showed signs of improvement last quarter as businesses bought enough machines to revive sales growth at Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) and fuel Intel Corp. (INTC)''s biggest revenue gain in more than two years. </p> <p>Intel''s sales increased 7 percent in the quarter that ended in June, according to the average of analysts'' estimates compiled by Bloomberg. Microsoft is likely to report that revenue rose 10 percent after stagnating the previous period, the projections show. The software maker may also announce job cuts related to the acquisition of Nokia Oyj''s handset unit, people with knowledge of the matter have said. </p> <p>Corporations are replacing older computers at a faster clip, spurring a 6.9 percent increase in U.S. PC unit sales last quarter, according to researcher IDC. That''s good news for Intel, Microsoft and other companies that rely on demand for PCs and have been slow to adapt to the shift toward mobile devices and software delivered via the Internet. </p> <p>A lot of the growth is in big companies, said Loren Loverde, who heads PC market research at IDC. </p> <p>Intel releases results today, while Microsoft will report earnings on July 22. </p> <p>The smartphone boom, meantime, is benefiting Apple Inc. (AAPL), the largest U.S. maker of these handheld computing devices, as well as Facebook Inc. and Twitter (TWTR) Inc., which make money from ads shown to users of mobile gadgets. Apple will probably report a 7 percent increase in sales, analysts predict. Revenue probably rose 55 percent at Facebook and may have more than doubled at Twitter, according to the projections. </p> <h2>Semiconductors Lead </h2> <p>Among industry groups in the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index, semiconductors are projected the post the strongest revenue growth for the second quarter, with 12 percent. That compares with 4.9 percent sales growth estimated for the broader information-technology group. </p> <p>While PC shipments declined in 2012 and 2013, some markets, such as the U.S., are seeing growth again as companies upgrade Intel-based PCs to get newer versions of Microsoft''s Windows. </p> <p>Intel, the world''s biggest chipmaker, raised its forecast for second-quarter sales last month on improving business demand for PCs, to $13.7 billion, plus or minus $300 million. Analysts are projecting, on average, revenue of $13.7 billion, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. The Santa Clara, California-based company may report revenue of more than $14 billion for the third quarter, projections show, surpassing that threshold for only the second time ever. </p> <h2>Microsoft Jobs </h2> <p>Microsoft is projected to post sales of $22 billion for its fiscal fourth quarter, which ended in June, according to the average of analysts'' estimates. The Redmond, Washington-based software maker in recent quarters has been benefiting from increasing sales in its newer Internet-based programs for the cloud. Since much of Microsoft''s Windows and Office software is used on desktop computers, a recovery in those products could bolster results. </p> <p>A stabilizing PC market could, we believe, drive higher than expected Windows sales, said Mark Moerdler, an analyst at Sanford C. Bernstein  Co. who has the equivalent of a buy rating on Microsoft. </p> <p>Much of the focus will be on what Chief Executive Officer Satya Nadella reveals about the financial and staffing implications of his first mission memo, issued last week. </p> <p>Microsoft is planning its biggest round of job cuts in five years, in divisions such as engineering and marketing, as well as areas of overlap with Nokia Oyj''s handset business, which it acquired this year. The restructuring -- which may be announced as soon as this week -- may end up being the biggest in Microsoft''s history, topping the 5,800 jobs cut in 2009, two of the people said. Some details are still being worked out, two of the people said. </p> <p>Nadella declined to comment about job cuts or any specific steps resulting from the note, saying he''d discuss implementation when Microsoft reports earnings. </p> <p>The cuts could involve 5 percent to 10 percent of a workforce that swelled to about 127,000 employees with the addition of Nokia, according to Rick Sherlund, an analyst at Nomura Securities who has a buy rating on Microsoft. </p> <h2>Apple Products </h2> <p>Apple, the world''s largest technology company by market value, will also report on July 22. Apple''s stock has gained 20 percent this year on investor optimism about a new batch of products on the horizon. Pent-up demand for bigger-screen iPhones will lead to record sales later this year, according to Michael Walkley, an analyst at Canaccord Genuity Group Inc. who has a buy rating on Apple. </p> <p>Analysts project Cupertino, California-based Apple will post an 8 percent rise in net income to $7.45 billion as sales climb to $37.8 billion, fueled by steady demand for the iPhone, which accounts for about half the company''s revenue. </p> <p>The rebound in PCs has coincided with a slowdown in sales of Apple''s iPads as the market becomes increasingly saturated. Bigger smartphones are also partly responsible for the drop and sales of larger iPhones could cut further into tablet purchases, Walkley said. </p> <h2>IBM Challenges </h2> <p>While Microsoft, Intel and Apple are waiting to see if consumer demand will pick up in the second half of the year, technology companies that depend on corporate spending are contending with the growth of cloud computing. Customers are increasingly storing data and software on the Web, rather than on their own hardware, curbing the need for servers and mainframes from International Business Machines Corp. and other computer makers. </p> <p>IBM, reporting on July 17, is projected to post its ninth straight quarterly sales decline, according to the average of analysts'' estimates, as it faces weaker demand for hardware and waning sales in developing countries like China. </p> <p>To meet profit targets, CEO Ginni Rometty is moving IBM''s focus to cloud services and data analytics, while offloading less profitable businesses, such as its low-end server unit. Lenovo Group Ltd. has agreed to buy that division for $2.3 billion, pending a U.S. national security review. She''s cut jobs and reduced the Armonk, New York-based company''s tax rate to help boost earnings. </p> <h2>Web Sales </h2> <p>The transition to mobile computing remains both an opportunity and a challenge for Web companies that depend on advertising to fuel sales. With ads command lower prices on mobile devices than they do on desktop computers, Google Inc. (GOOG) has is boosting the volume of ad sales. The Mountain View, California-based Web-search giant, which will report earnings on July 17, is projected to post second-quarter sales, excluding revenue passed to partners, of $12.3 billion, an 11 percent increase from a year earlier. </p> <p>In the first quarter, Google''s average price per click on an ad slipped 9 percent even as the number of hits on the promotions rose 26 percent. While Google''s search engine is a common tool for surfing the Web on desktop computers, alternative applications are attracting users on smartphones and tablets. EMarketer Inc. predicts that Google''s share of the U.S. mobile-search ad market will decline to 64 percent in 2016, from 83 percent in 2012. </p> <h2>Mobile Ads </h2> <p>U.S. ad spending on tablets and smartphones, meanwhile, will rise 83 percent this year, according to EMarketer. </p> <p>Facebook is faring better in mobile ads, and is projected to make up 22 percent of the market this year, up from 5.4 percent in 2012, according to EMarketer. Ad sales on tablets and smartphones now deliver a majority of Facebook''s ad business, after contributing almost nothing a few years ago. </p> <p>Facebook has become one of the leaders in adapting to the most important Internet industry trend, Mark Mahaney, an analyst at RBC Capital Markets, wrote in a note. He has the equivalent of a buy rating on Menlo Park, California-based Facebook. </p> <h2>Yahoo, Alibaba </h2> <p>Yahoo! Inc. (YHOO)''s report today will provide an update on its turnaround under CEO Marissa Mayer, who has been at the helm for two years. She''s seeking to expand content and ad deals following earlier efforts to attract users and better staff. </p> <p>After adjusted sales fell 1 percent last year, Yahoo said revenue expanded by 1 percent in the first quarter, and analysts on average predict the Sunnyvale, California-based company will match that gain in the second quarter. </p> <p>Still, investors will keep their focus on Yahoo''s stake in Alibaba Group Holding Ltd., the largest Chinese e-commerce company, which is set to hold an initial public offering. Yahoo is projected to bring in about $10 billion from the deal, and shareholders will look for any comments on how much of that, after taxes, will be distributed through buybacks or dividends. Yahoo also could use the money to make acquisitions. </p> <p>The outcome of the highly anticipated Alibaba IPO in August, the tax treatment of the proceeds and use of the new cash are likely to drive the stock short-term, Youssef Squali, an analyst at Cantor Fitzgerald, wrote of Yahoo in a note on July 11. He has a buy rating on Yahoo. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ben Livesey" date="Jul 16, 2014  7:24 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-16/microsoft-xbox-sales-double-in-june-with-lower-price-tag.html"><headline>Microsoft Xbox Sales Double in June With Lower Price Tag</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), chasing Sony Corp. (6758)
for dominance in the U.S. video-game console market, said sales
of its Xbox One doubled last month from May, after it added a
lower-priced version of the machine. </p>
<p>Over the past month, we''ve seen a strong spike in
interest in our Xbox One console options, including the new $399
offering, the Redmond, Washington-based company said in a blog
today. </p>
<p>Microsoft introduced a cheaper machine on June 9 after
struggling to convince gamers that the $499 price tag of the
console is justified. Since both the Xbox One and the
PlayStation 4 were introduced in November, marking a new
generation of gaming consoles, Microsoft''s machine has trailed
Sony''s in sales. </p>
<p>Earlier this year, Microsoft used an entire presentation at
the E3 conference in Los Angeles to focus on hard-core players,
who were alienated by the Xbox One''s debut that focused on non-game entertainment. </p>
<p>The two companies are now gearing up for the year-end
holiday season. Starting in August with the release of Madden
NFL 15, new blockbuster titles will start being released for the
Xbox One, Microsoft said today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ruth David and Manuel Baigorri" date="Jul 16, 2014  6:01 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-16/morgan-stanley-unit-said-to-mull-sale-for-madrilena-red.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Unit Said to Mull Sale for Madrilena Red</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS)''s infrastructure unit is considering selling Spanish gas distributor Madrilena Red de Gas Finance BV, according to three people familiar with the matter. </p> <p>Morgan Stanley Infrastructure Partners, which owns MRDG, is speaking with advisers about a merger or initial public offering in Spain as early as this year, said the people, who asked not to be named as the details aren''t public. MRDG, which operates 11 percent of natural gas connection points in Spain according to its website, may be valued at more than 900 million euros ($1.2 billion) including debt, one person said. The talks are preliminary and no decision has been made, the people said. </p> <p>Applus Services SA and Lar Espana Real Estate Socimi SA (LRE) are among Spanish companies that have helped raise more than $6 billion in IPOs this year, the most since 2011, according to data compiled by Bloomberg, as investors return to peripheral economies in Europe on the promise of a recovery in growth. </p> <p>Spokesmen for the company and for Morgan Stanley declined to comment. </p> <p>Madrilena Red sold 500 million euros of five-year bonds on the Luxembourg Stock Exchange in September 2013 and 275 million euros of 10-year bonds on the exchange in December, according to its annual report. It reported revenue of 176 million euros in 2013. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jul 16, 2014  6:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-16/goldman-sachs-said-to-hold-board-of-directors-meeting-in-germany.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Said to Hold Board of Directors Meeting in Germany</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), which said
a jump in European deals helped it post record underwriting
revenue in the second quarter, is holding its board of directors
meeting this week in Germany, the Continent''s largest economy. </p>
<p>Chairman Lloyd C. Blankfein and the other directors are
traveling to Frankfurt and Berlin, according to two people
briefed on the trip who requested anonymity because the details
weren''t public. The board met with Bundesbank President Jens Weidmann yesterday and will meet with other top German officials
this week, one of the people said. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs''s 13-member board of directors has typically
held a meeting annually outside of the U.S., traveling in past
years to Brazil, Russia, India and China. The New York-based
bank opened its office in Frankfurt in 1990, the year that
Germany last won the World Cup soccer tournament before taking
the title again this week in Brazil. The firm''s analysts
predicted in May that Brazil would win. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs was the second-ranked underwriter of equity
offerings in Europe, the Middle East and Africa, behind Deutsche
Bank AG, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. It advised
Volkswagen AG, Europe''s largest carmaker, on its takeover of
truck producer Scania AB, the second-largest deal this year
involving a German company. </p>
<p>Monika Schaller, a spokeswoman for Goldman Sachs, declined
to comment on the trip and whether board members would meet with
German Chancellor Angela Merkel. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Aoife White" date="Jul 16, 2014  1:11 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-16/microsoft-taking-right-to-be-forgotten-requests-for-bing.html"><headline>Microsoft Taking Right-to-Be-Forgotten Requests for Bing</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. started taking
requests from people in Europe who want its Bing search engine
to hide results from searches on their names, more than two
months after a court created a right to be forgotten. </p>
<p>Microsoft''s online form went live in Europe today to comply
with the European Union''s Court of Justice ruling, Robin Koch, a
spokesman for the company in Brussels, said by phone. The
company will continue to work out the details of the process
we''ll use to evaluate the requests, Koch said in an e-mail. </p>
<p>Google was ordered by the EU''s top court in May to respond
to people seeking details to be removed from its search engine.
Google''s online form went online at the end of May. The world''s
largest search provider got 70,000 take-down requests covering
250,000 requests, its legal chief said last week. </p>
<p>Bing trails Google, which has a market share for search
well above 90 percent in most European countries, the
European Commission said last year. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Glenys Sim" date="Jul 16, 2014  8:02 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-16/goldman-sees-lower-commodity-prices-over-five-years-on-supplies.html"><headline>Goldman Forecasts Lower Commodity Prices as Cycle Ends</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Commodities from iron ore to copper
and Brent crude will drop over the next five years as global
supplies climb, according to Goldman Sachs Group Inc., which
highlighted oil''s recent losses as a sign of increased output. </p>
<p>There will be substantial declines in some metals, energy
and bulk commodities, analysts including Chief Currency
Strategist Robin Brooks wrote in a report. The period of
continued year-on-year price rises for most commodities is over,
they said in the report, which was dated yesterday. </p>
<p>Banks from Citigroup Inc. to Deutsche Bank AG have called
an end to the commodities super-cycle, when China''s surging
demand combined with supply constraints to more than double
prices in the 12 years through 2010. Raw materials rallied this
year from three annual losses as a lack of rain in Brazil lifted
coffee and a ban of ore exports from Indonesia spurred a rally
in nickel. The drop in energy prices since last month showed the
impact of higher global output, Goldman said in the report. </p>
<p>A prolonged period of elevated commodity prices has
catalysed a supply response, the analysts wrote. We do not
expect a collapse in global commodity prices. But we do
anticipate substantial declines. </p>
<p>Copper was forecast to drop to $6,600 a metric ton over
five years, while iron ore was seen at $80 a ton and Brent may
be $100 a barrel, according to Goldman. The steel-making raw
material was at $98 a dry ton in Tianjin, China, today, and
copper traded at $7,123 on the London Metal Exchange today.
Brent was 33 cents higher at $106.35 on the ICE Futures Europe. </p>
<h2>Looser Supply'' </h2>
<p>The Bloomberg Commodity Index of 22 raw materials climbed
3.4 percent this year. That compares with a 0.9 percent drop in
the Bloomberg Dollar Spot Index and 5.3 percent advance in the
MSCI All-Country World Index of equities. </p>
<p>Against a looser supply backdrop, commodity prices should
be much less sensitive to fluctuations in global growth than
they were, Goldman said in the report, entitled Emerging
Market Forex and the End of the Commodity Market Super-Cycle. </p>
<p>Goldman said in a January report the cycle that spurred
higher commodities prices is reversing as increased U.S. shale
oil output keeps energy prices low, and that would eventually
drive raw materials into a bear market. The new cycle would be
the opposite of the super-cycle, it said then. </p>
<p>U.S. production of crude, along with liquids separated from
natural gas, surpassed all other countries this year with daily
output exceeding 11 million barrels in the first quarter, Bank
of America Corp. said in a report July 4. Output climbed as
hydraulic fracturing and horizontal drilling help producers to
pull record volumes of crude out of shale formations. </p>
<h2>Oil Supplies </h2>
<p>Brent rallied to as much as $115.71 a barrel last month as
military gains in Iraq by an al-Qaeda breakaway group stoked
concern that oil supplies from the region may be disrupted.
Prices posted a third weekly loss in the period to July 11, with
Iraqi shipments unaffected and Libya moving to boost exports. </p>
<p>Less than a month has passed since geopolitical risks in
Iraq pushed up oil prices on concerns over a potential oil
supply shock, and the market seems to have absorbed the related
risks reasonably well, Goldman''s analysts wrote. The
expansion in oil supply over the past few years -- primarily
from the expansion of U.S. shale production -- has minimized the
consequences from past disruptions in Libya and Iraq. </p>
<p>Iron ore entered a bear market in March on prospects for a
glut as supplies surged. Rio Tinto Group (RIO), the world''s second-largest mining company, said today iron ore production in the
three months to June gained 11 percent, while Fortescue Metals
Group Ltd. said its shipments were 57 percent higher on year. </p>
<h2>Surplus Market </h2>
<p>We remain bearish on iron ore, and expect a surplus
market to drive the longer-term price down, the Goldman
analysts wrote in yesterday''s report. We see limited upside
for agricultural commodities over the longer run. </p>
<p>Deutsche Bank said last month commodity prices will remain
subdued for years as many of the factors and fears that drove
the super-cycle have dissipated. Citigroup said in April 2013
that death bells would ring for the commodity super-cycle. </p>
<p>Our long-term commodity forecasts suggest that
fundamentals for commodity currencies will deteriorate, the
Goldman analysts wrote. Relative shifts in terms of trade
between commodity importers and exporters will be a key input to
currency determination over the coming years. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jul 16, 2014 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-16/goldman-sachs-s-stress-test-stumble-leads-to-cut-in-repo-lending.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs''s Stress-Test Stumble Leads to Cut in Repo Lending</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), which had
to resubmit its capital plan this year after falling below a
minimum leverage ratio, used that experience as motivation to
cut lending through repurchase agreements. </p>
<p>The bank reduced total assets by $56 billion to $860
billion as of June 30, the lowest level since 2009. Goldman
Sachs is cutting back on businesses that have low return on
assets and $25 billion of the reduction came in the firm''s
matched book repo lending, Chief Financial Officer Harvey Schwartz said yesterday in a conference call with analysts after
the New York-based firm reported second-quarter results. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs is facing pressure to reduce assets as the
bank is below the 5 percent minimum ratio in the proposed
supplementary leverage ratio, which measures equity capital
compared to assets unweighted by risk. In March, it also had to
reduce the amount of capital it planned to return in the Federal
Reserve''s stress test, known as CCAR, after dropping below the 4
percent minimum of a separate requirement. </p>
<p>We identified opportunities to reduce balance sheet with
a de minimis impact to our client franchise and earnings
potential, Schwartz said. One of the significant inputs into
the process obviously was CCAR. </p>
<p>In a matched book, banks rely on repurchase agreements and
securities lending to fund clients while using the same
collateral and terms to borrow themselves, often overnight. </p>
<h2>Repo Failures </h2>
<p>Goldman Sachs''s asset reductions also affect other secured
financing for clients, Schwartz said. While the firm didn''t
release a full balance sheet with its quarterly results
yesterday, it had $355.9 billion in secured client financing and
secured financing agreements at the end of March, which
represented about 40 percent of its assets. </p>
<p>The bank hadn''t seen a pressing need to cut back on the
low-margin secured loans before the leverage ratio and stress
test because they were viewed as a low risk way to help clients,
according to a person with direct knowledge of the firm''s
discussions. Clients have been understanding of Goldman Sachs''s
decision to pull back, said the person, who asked to remain
anonymous because the talks were private. </p>
<p>Recent changes in borrowing rates and so-called failures in
the $1.6 trillion-a-day repo market suggest other participants
have trimmed their matched books, the person said. Failures to
deliver Treasuries in repo trades have increased this year and
repo rates on some debt have fallen as low as negative 3
percent. </p>
<p>A lot''s been written about the repo markets, Schwartz
said on the call. Certainly our $25 billion reduction in the
matchbook had no marginal impact in terms of the repo markets,
but I think this will be interesting to watch how it evolves,
because as mentioned earlier, large banks have multiple
constraints. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs''s ratio under the proposed supplementary
leverage ratio is 4.5 percent and will reach 5 percent as the
firm reduces certain fund stakes to comply with the Volcker
Rule, Schwartz said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Jul 17, 2014  5:15 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-17/microsoft-cuts-18-000-jobs-as-nadella-streamlines-for-cloud-era.html"><headline>Microsoft Eliminating 18,000 Jobs as Nadella Streamlines</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) said it will eliminate as many as 18,000 jobs, the largest round of cuts in its history, as Chief Executive Officer Satya Nadella integrates Nokia Oyj''s handset unit and slims down the software maker. </p> <p>The restructuring, amounting to about 14 percent of its workforce, includes 12,500 Nokia factory and professional positions -- half the number of employees added in the acquisition. At Microsoft, cuts will be in sales, marketing and engineering. The reductions are expected to be completed by June 30, 2015, and will result in a pretax charge of $1.1 billion to $1.6 billion, Microsoft said in a statement today. </p> <p>Nadella, who took over from Steve Ballmer in February, is retooling the company''s structure as it seeks to compete with nimbler rivals offering mobile and Internet-based software and services. He''s also working to wring a promised $600 million in annual savings from Microsoft''s Nokia deal, which added 25,000 workers in April, bringing the total to about 127,100. </p> <p>Related:</p>
Microsoft Xbox Sales Double in June With Lower Price
Apple-IBM Deal Snaps BlackBerry Rally
<p>Microsoft needs to be a leaner tech giant over the coming years in order to strike the right balance of growth and profitability around its cloud and mobile endeavors, said Daniel Ives, an analyst at FBR Capital Markets  Co. who rates Microsoft stock the equivalent of a buy. The cuts are roughly twice as big as Wall Street expected, Ives said in a note today. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
An attendee tries on a Microsoft Corp. branded shirt during the Microsoft Worldwide Partner Conference in Washington, D.C., U.S., on Wednesday, July 16, 2014. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Barinka" date="Jul 17, 2014  5:13 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-17/ibm-sales-top-estimates-as-rometty-advances-toward-profit-goals.html"><headline>IBM Sales Top Estimates as Rometty Moves Toward Profit Goals</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM)''s second-quarter sales topped analysts'' estimates, getting
Chief Executive Officer Ginni Rometty closer to her profit
goals. </p>
<p>While revenue fell 2 percent from a year earlier to $24.4
billion -- the ninth straight quarterly drop -- declines for
products like mainframe servers and markets such as Brazil and
China were less severe than earlier this year, IBM said today in
a statement. The result surpassed the $24.1 billion that
analysts projected on average, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. Adjusted earnings rose to $4.32 a share, 1 cent
higher than analysts'' estimates compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Rometty is banking on a strong second half of the year to
hit her targets for the company''s performance even as IBM adapts
to an industrywide shift to cloud computing, an area that
expanded 50 percent in the first six months of the year from the
same period in 2013. The company reiterated its projection for
2014 adjusted earnings of at least $18 a share. </p>
<p>IBM is contending with technology customers that
increasingly seek to store data and software on cloud-computing
networks, rather than on site. That''s limited clients'' need for
IBM''s servers and mainframes, making it more difficult to reach
profit targets. The company had said before today that it
expected mainframe sales to improve into next year. </p>
<p>IBM aims to reach $20 a share in adjusted earnings by 2015,
up from $11.67 in 2010 -- a pledge instated by former Chief
Executive Officer Sam Palmisano and sustained by Rometty, who
succeeded him in 2012. </p>
<p>Shares of Armonk, New York-based IBM fell 1.4 percent in
late trading. </p>
<h2>Profit Goal </h2>
<p>To meet this year''s projections, Chief Financial Officer
Martin Schroeter said in April that IBM would be 38 percent
toward its profit goal by the end of the second quarter. That
implied second-quarter earnings this year of $4.21 to $4.39 a
share, compared with the $4.32 a share reported today. </p>
<p>Revenue from emerging markets slid 7 percent in the second
quarter, compared to an 11 percent fall in the three months
prior. Sales to Brazil, Russia, India and China also pared
losses, declining 2 percent, compared with an 11 percent drop
last quarter. </p>
<h2>Chinese Market </h2>
<p>The company has faced difficulties in the Chinese market as
tensions over cyberhacking have risen between China and the U.S.
The Chinese government is reviewing whether domestic banks''
reliance on high-end servers from IBM compromises the nation''s
financial security, people familiar with the matter said in May.
IBM said then that it wasn''t aware of any government policy
recommending against use of its servers. </p>
<p>Sales of mainframe servers, the workhorse machines
corporate customers have used for decades to run their crucial
computing tasks, decreased 1 percent -- an improvement from the
40 percent decline in the first quarter. IBM had said it
expected those sales to improve because more customers were
preparing to upgrade their mainframes. </p>
<p>As Rometty tries to navigate the company through the
industry''s changes, she has shifted IBM''s own focus to cloud
services, along with data analytics, in which the company helps
clients mine the digital information they collect to identify
trends. Rometty has also tried to offload less profitable
businesses -- like the low-end server unit that Lenovo Group
Ltd. agreed to buy for $2.3 billion, pending a U.S. national-security review. </p>
<h2>Watson Technology </h2>
<p>In a deal unveiled this week, IBM will help develop more
than 100 mobile-centric applications for businesses catered to
Apple Inc.''s iPhones and iPads to help workers do more with the
devices than check e-mail or calendars. The companies foresee
corporate customers increasingly using handheld devices for
daily workplace tasks like supply chain management and human
resources functions. </p>
<p>Separately, IBM is spending more than $1 billion to create
a new group around its Watson technology, which lets customers
use plain English to analyze large troves of data. To remake its
cloud business, Rometty bought provider SoftLayer Technologies
Inc. in 2013 for $2 billion and this year committed an
additional $1.2 billion to bolster its data centers and
offerings. </p>
<p>Their success is going to be tied to the cloud over the
next five to 10 years, said Daniel Ives, an analyst at FBR
Capital Markets. It''s more of a strategic focus of the
company. </p>
<h2>Cloud Growth </h2>
<p>Cloud offerings delivered as a service are now at an annual
run rate of $2.8 billion, compared with $2.3 billion as of the
first quarter. That''s still a fraction of IBM''s total $100
billion in revenue last year. </p>
<p>As it reshapes itself, IBM will still have to rely on its
older global business services and software units, which
together make up about three-quarters of sales. To boost
earnings in the meantime, Rometty has also sold debt to fund
share buybacks, laid off workers and slashed the company''s tax
rate. </p>
<p>IBM ended the quarter with $9.7 billion in cash on hand,
even with the end of March, after spending $1.1 billion on
dividends and $3.7 billion on share buybacks. </p>
<p>Net income climbed to $4.1 billion, or $4.12 a share, from
$3.2 billion, or $2.91 a share, a year earlier. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hugh Son" date="Jul 17, 2014  5:07 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-17/jpmorgan-s-dimon-gets-37-million-of-crisis-era-options.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Dimon Gets $37 Million of Crisis-Era Options</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) will let Jamie Dimon collect about $37 million in stock options created during the financial crisis, as the board stands by its leader after risk-management lapses and billions of dollars in legal settlements. </p> <p>JPMorgan gave the chief executive officer 2 million stock-appreciation rights in January 2008, saying they would be available in five years if the board still deemed it appropriate. Last year, the firm delayed vesting by 18 months to address flawed internal controls exposed by botched derivatives bets. JPMorgan resolved a variety of probes in the months that followed. </p> <p>The board decided not to further defer the vesting of these options at the July 2014 meeting, Joe Evangelisti, a spokesman for the New York-based bank, said today after the vesting of the grant was disclosed in a regulatory filing. </p> <p>Since the package''s creation, JPMorgan has become the nation''s largest lender, acquiring Bears Stearns Cos. and Washington Mutual Inc.''s bank units at the height of the crisis. As Dimon, 58, navigated the regulatory setbacks, the board signaled support for his work as CEO and chairman, boosting his pay 74 percent to $20 million in January. </p> <p>The options have a $39.83 strike price and expire in January 2018. JPMorgan''s stock closed today at $57.86, giving the award a value of about $37 million, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
Jamie Dimon, chief executive officer of JPMorgan Chase  Co. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jul 17, 2014  4:15 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-17/morgan-stanley-beats-analysts-estimates-on-fixed-income.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Beats Estimates on Investment Banking</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS), owner of the world''s largest brokerage, reported earnings that beat analysts'' estimates as profit from that business rose to a record and fees from investment banking reached a three-year high. </p> <p>Second-quarter net income almost doubled to $1.94 billion, or 94 cents a share, from $980 million, or 41 cents, a year earlier, the New York-based company said today in a statement. Excluding a tax benefit and an accounting adjustment tied to the firm''s own debt, profit was 60 cents a share, topping the 56-cent average estimate of 24 analysts surveyed by Bloomberg. </p> <p>Morgan Stanley, the No. 2 adviser on global announced mergers and acquisitions this year, said investment-banking revenue jumped 33 percent in the second quarter, the biggest increase among its peers. The brokerage''s profit margin increased to 21 percent, the highest since the firm bought Smith Barney from Citigroup Inc. in 2009. </p> <p>The improving profitability in wealth management was the standout for us in the quarter, said Shannon Stemm, an analyst at Edward Jones  Co. Investment banking was the other area of strength. Some of that was just a factor of the market environment; MA has been robust lately, and Morgan is winning their fair share of that. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
James Gorman, chairman and chief executive officer of Morgan Stanley. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Jul 17, 2014  2:27 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-17/microsoft-to-end-tv-production-one-month-after-show-debut.html"><headline>Microsoft to End TV Production One Month After Show Debut</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), which announced its
biggest job cuts ever today, will shutter an ambitious effort to
create original television programs just one month after the
first show rolled out. </p>
<p>The Xbox Entertainment Studio will close in coming months,
Xbox chief Phil Spencer said in an e-mail to employees. Nancy Tellem, the ex-CBS executive brought in to lead the effort two
years ago, will stay on with some of her team to complete shows
in production, such as a Halo series, the company said. </p>
<p>Tellem was hired by former Chief Executive Officer Steve Ballmer to draw more entertainment consumers to Xbox by getting
into original programming, like Amazon.com Inc. and Netflix Inc. (NFLX)
Tellem assembled a team in a Santa Monica, California, and put
together six confirmed series, along with more than a dozen in
development as of April. The first, a street-football reality TV
show, came out last month during the World Cup. </p>
<p>Spencer and Tellem said in March that Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft, with both a new CEO and head of Xbox, remained
committed to the TV effort. </p>
<p>With Microsoft and new CEO Satya Nadella cutting 18,000
positions and trying to focus more closely on selling software
for mobile and the cloud, TV is being jettisoned. </p>
<p>Change is never easy, but I believe the changes announced
today help us better align with our long-term goals, Spencer
wrote. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Camila Russo" date="Jul 17, 2014 12:11 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-17/jpmorgan-hsbc-baml-said-to-be-hired-for-buenos-aires-bond-sale.html"><headline>JPMorgan, HSBC, BAML Said to Manage Buenos Aires Bond Sale</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co., HSBC Holdings
Plc and Bank of America Merrill Lynch were hired by the city of
Buenos Aires to sell as much as $890 million of global bonds,
according to two people with direct knowledge of the plans. </p>
<p>Argentina''s capital city said it received approval from
local lawmakers to sell debt with a minimum maturity of five
years. The funds will be used to pay down $475 million of debt
coming due in 2015 and extend maturities, said the people, who
asked not to be identified because they''re not authorized to
speak publicly about the matter. </p>
<p>The banks handling the sale are waiting for the right
moment to sell the debt, the people said. There''s no date
scheduled for meetings to promote the sale, according to one of
the people, who is an official at the city''s Finance Ministry. </p>
<p>Veronica Espinosa, a spokeswoman for JPMorgan, declined to
comment. BAML officials couldn''t be reached. HSBC press official
Robert Sherman didn''t respond to an e-mail seeking comment. </p>
<p>This would be the city of Buenos Aires'' first international
bond sale since 2012. </p>
<p>Argentine companies and provinces are waiting for lower
interest rates to sell as much as $2 billion of bonds later this
year, according to Puente Sociedad de Bolsa SA. </p>
<p>While average yields hit three-year lows last week, the
government faces a July 30 deadline to settle with holdout
creditors or fall into default on restructured debt. U.S.
District Court judge blocked a $539 million payment due June 30,
saying it violated his orders to pay defaulted bondholders at
the same time. </p>
<p>The city''s 12.5 percent notes due next year fell 0.38 cent
to 101.53 cents on the dollar at 12:51 p.m. in Buenos Aires,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. The yield rose 55 basis
points, or 0.55 percentage point, to 10.14 percent. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jul 17, 2014  7:53 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-17/morgan-stanley-sees-rosneft-deal-surviving-u-s-russia-sanctions.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Sees Rosneft Deal Surviving U.S. Russia Sanctions</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) said it still expects
to complete the sale of its oil-merchanting business to OAO
Rosneft this year after the U.S. imposed new sanctions on the
Russian company. </p>
<p>We don''t believe it applies to our transaction, so we''re
continuing to do the work necessary to close by the end of the
year, Morgan Stanley Chief Financial Officer Ruth Porat said
in a telephone interview today after the New York-based bank
announced second-quarter earnings. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christie Smythe" date="Jul 18, 2014  9:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-18/visa-mastercard-must-face-target-macy-s-swipe-fee-case.html"><headline>Visa, MasterCard Must Face Target, Macy''s Swipe-Fee Case</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Visa Inc. (V) and MasterCard Inc. (MA) lost
their bid to dismiss more than 30 lawsuits by retailers seeking
potentially billions of dollars in damages over fees for
processing transactions. </p>
<p>Merchants including Target Corp. (TGT) and Macy''s Inc. (M) pursued
their cases after dropping out of an earlier $5.7 billion
settlement over the charges known as swipe fees. Today, a
federal judge in Brooklyn, New York, refused to throw out those
lawsuits. He also rejected Visa''s request to dismiss a similar
lawsuit filed by Wal-Mart Stores Inc. (WMT) seeking at least $5
billion in damages. </p>
<p>U.S. District Judge John Gleeson said his decision was in
large part driven by the requirement that I accept all well-pleaded factual allegations as true because the cases were in
the early stages of litigation. It isn''t a ruling on the merits
of the complaints. </p>
<p>Gleeson in December approved the card companies'' settlement
with merchants nationwide following years of antitrust
litigation over the fees. </p>
<p>Dozens of large retailers appealed the approval of the
accord. Many also dropped out of the deal and filed their own
lawsuits, contending it wasn''t enough compensation for the
hundreds of billions of dollars in fees paid. </p>
<h2>Market Power'' </h2>
<p>In a revised complaint filed this month, Target and Macy''s
said the card companies have obtained and maintained market
power in the market for merchant acceptance of credit cards
causing merchants to pay excessive interchange fees. </p>
<p>Wal-Mart alleged in its complaint that Visa''s monopoly
power has enabled it to dictate price and inhibit competition.
The Bentonville, Arkansas-based retailer announced in April that
MasterCard will handle transactions for store-branded credit
cards. MasterCard isn''t named in Wal-Mart''s swipe-fee complaint. </p>
<p>Visa and MasterCard argued that the merchants'' claims for
damages should be barred by legal releases in an earlier
settlement in 2003. They also said the claims should be thrown
out because the merchants don''t directly pay fees to banks that
issue Visa and MasterCard branded cards. The fees are deducted
from payments merchants receive after processing. </p>
<p>Separately, Gleeson also denied requests by Wal-Mart and
another group of merchants to dismiss lawsuits filed against
them by the card firms seeking to stop their litigation over the
fees in its tracks. The request the card firms are making in
those cases is properly invoked, Gleeson said. </p>
<h2>Tactical Advantage'' </h2>
<p>We''re not seeking an unfair tactical advantage, we''re
seeking finality, said Michael Shuster, a lawyer for Visa,
during the hearing today. </p>
<p>Paul Cohen, a spokesman for Foster City, California-based
Visa, declined to comment on the judge''s rulings. </p>
<p>Judge Gleeson''s ruling was at the earliest stage of the
case, Seth Eisen, a spokesman for Purchase, New York-based
MasterCard, said in an e-mail. We look forward to putting this
matter behind us and continuing to work productively with the
merchant community. </p>
<p>The case is In Re: Payment Card Interchange Fee and
Merchant Discount Antitrust Litigation -- Opt Out Cases, 1:14-md-01720, U.S. District Court, Eastern District of New York
(Brooklyn). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Barinka" date="Jul 18, 2014  4:23 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-18/ibm-s-nine-quarter-sales-slump-overshadows-cloud-growth.html"><headline>IBM''s Nine-Quarter Sales Slump Overshadows Cloud Growth</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines Corp. (IBM) reported a ninth straight quarter of declining sales as demand fell for hardware and computer services, underscoring the urgency of its plan to get more revenue from newer businesses like cloud computing. </p> <p>Second-quarter revenue dropped 2 percent from a year earlier to $24.4 billion, compared with the $24.1 billion that analysts projected on average, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. Adjusted earnings rose to $4.32 a share, 1 cent higher than analysts'' estimates, boosted by cost-cutting and share buybacks. </p> <p>Chief Executive Officer Ginni Rometty is betting that businesses want to store their data and software applications remotely, in the cloud, and they need IBM to help mine the piles of data they''re accumulating. She''s preaching patience to investors, plying them with share repurchases to persuade them to wait for an inflection point where the new technology can propel the company back in the right direction. </p> <p>It''s become more of a show-me story, Bill Kreher, an analyst at Edward Jones  Co., said. It leaves investors to gauge how much faith they have in IBM''s ability to execute. At some point, investors look at the quality of earnings and would like to see business momentum at its core franchises. </p> <h2>Cloud Growth </h2> <p>The company maintained its forecasts for $18 a share in adjusted earnings this year and $20 a share next year. Part of that expansion is predicated on the growth of cloud computing sales, which grew 50 percent in the first six months of the year from the same period in 2013. </p> <p>Cloud offerings delivered as a service are now at an annual run rate of $2.8 billion, compared with $2.3 billion as of the first quarter. That''s still a fraction of IBM''s total $100 billion in revenue last year. </p> <p>There were signs of improvement in areas where IBM had been struggling. Sales to Brazil, Russia, India and China pared losses, declining 2 percent, compared with an 11 percent drop last quarter. </p> <p>Sales of mainframe servers, the workhorse machines corporate customers have used for decades to run their crucial computing tasks, decreased 1 percent -- an improvement from the 40 percent decline in the first quarter. </p> <p>Shares of Armonk, New York-based IBM were little changed at $192.50 at the close in New York. Global services sales, which typically make up more than half of IBM''s business, slid 1 percent to $13.9 billion. Software revenue was up 1 percent from a year earlier to $6.5 billion, a slowdown from 2 percent growth in the prior quarter. And even with the improvement in the mainframe business, total hardware sales dropped 11 percent. </p> <h2>Licensing Model </h2> <p>When companies move to cloud computing, software and data can be stored on remote servers, instead of installed on premise. In the past, many software offerings were sold to customers in a licensing model, where clients pay upfront for the right to use the tools for an allotted amount of time. With cloud-based services, many offerings are pay-as-you-use, giving customers the opportunity to be more efficient and lower the total payments. </p> <p>While IBM''s cloud business is growing, the fear is that it could take revenue away from its traditional sales model, said Amit Daryanani, an analyst at RBC Capital Markets. </p> <p>How much of that is new wins and how much is cannibalistic? You don''t know how much of that is coming from cannibalizing their own software versus net new stuff, he said. </p> <p>Services revenue, meanwhile, has been hurt as customers put pressure on IBM to lower its fees. </p> <h2>Pricing Pressure'' </h2> <p>Our performance continues to reflect pricing pressure and client contract renegotiations, as well as a reduction in elective projects, IBM Chief Financial Officer Martin Schroeter said about the company''s outsourcing business on the earnings conference call. </p> <p>IBM''s contract signings for services -- an indicator of expected future revenue -- fell 33 percent from a year earlier to $11 billion, driven by declines in new business for consulting and outsourcing. That falls short of the 6.2 percent gain from rival Accenture Plc. </p> <p>The fall in contract signings could drag on IBM''s services revenue in the second half of the year, said Anurag Rana, an analyst for Bloomberg Industries. </p> <p>Before results were released yesterday, IBM shares had climbed 2.6 percent this year, supported by the company''s repurchases, which brought the number of shares in circulation under 1 billion at the end of June -- the first time they''ve been below that threshold at the close of a quarter since at least 1999. </p> <h2>More Buybacks </h2> <p>IBM ended the quarter with $9.7 billion in cash on hand, little changed from the end of March, after spending $1.1 billion on dividends and $3.7 billion on share buybacks. </p> <p>Net income climbed to $4.1 billion, or $4.12 a share, from $3.2 billion, or $2.91 a share, a year earlier. </p> <p>As Rometty tries to shift IBM''s own focus to cloud services and data analytics, she has also tried to offload less profitable businesses -- like the low-end server unit that Lenovo Group Ltd. agreed to buy for $2.3 billion, pending a U.S. national-security review. </p> <h2>Apple Deal </h2> <p>In a deal unveiled this week, IBM will help develop more than 100 mobile-centric applications for businesses catered to Apple Inc.''s iPhones and iPads to help workers do more with the devices than check e-mail or calendars. The companies foresee corporate customers increasingly using handheld devices for daily workplace tasks like supply chain management and human resources functions. </p> <p>Separately, IBM is spending more than $1 billion to create a new group around its Watson technology, which lets customers use plain English to analyze large troves of data. To remake its cloud business, Rometty bought SoftLayer Technologies Inc. in 2013 for $2 billion and this year committed an additional $1.2 billion to bolster its data centers and offerings. </p> <p>Their success is going to be tied to the cloud over the next five to 10 years, said Daniel Ives, an analyst at FBR Capital Markets. It''s more of a strategic focus of the company. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jenna M. Dagenhart" date="Jul 18, 2014  3:29 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-18/coca-cola-bottler-arca-gains-in-mexico-city-on-consumer-outlook.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Bottler Arca Reaches 11-Month High on Consumer Outlook</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Arca Continental SAB (AC*), the second-largest Coca-Cola bottler in Latin America, rose to an 11-month
high as company executives cited prospects for improved consumer
spending in Mexico and Argentina. </p>
<p>Shares of Arca climbed 3 percent to 92.98 pesos at 2:14
p.m. in Mexico City, the highest level on a closing basis since
August 2013. The gain was the biggest on the benchmark IPC
equity index, which advanced 0.8 percent. </p>
<p>Arca executives said on a conference call yesterday that
they see evidence of increased consumption and reduced sugar
prices although a full recovery from Mexico''s excise tax on
sweet drinks will take a couple of years. Second-quarter
adjusted net income increased 3 percent from a year earlier. </p>
<p>Concerns about commodity costs and consumer confidence
are improving with the more stable environment, Lauren Torres,
an HSBC Holdings Plc analyst, said by phone from New York.
Investors know that if there are going to be price increases
in the future, then they will be selective. </p>
<p>Torres cited Arca''s strategy of raising prices in the first
quarter to cover the excise tax and then adding another increase
in the second quarter to account for inflation. HSBC maintained
its hold rating in a report today. </p>
<p>Mexico began taxing sugary drinks in January at one peso
per liter in an effort to curb obesity. Also this year, the
government applied an 8 percent levy on junk food. </p>
<p>The challenging economic and consumption environments
facing the first half of the year in Mexico and Argentina
require us to be more productive and efficient on the cost and
expense side, Emilio Marcos Charur, the chief financial
officer of Monterrey, Mexico-based Arca, said on the conference
call. We expect a better consumption environment in the coming
months. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Peter Robison" date="Jul 18, 2014 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-18/microsoft-cuts-can-t-cool-seattle-hunger-for-code-writers.html"><headline>Microsoft Job Cuts Can''t Cool Seattle''s Hunger for Code Writers</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The largest job cuts in Microsoft Corp. (MSFT)''s history are a recruiting opportunity for Seattle-area rivals, who see them as a chance to snatch talent. </p> <p>In a measure of the Redmond, Washington-based company''s lessening dominance of a regional software industry it all but created, technology executives say the cuts may only dent a frenzied job market driven by companies from Amazon.com Inc. to Zillow Inc. (Z) Some entice workers with perks such as free lunches, paid dry cleaning and, at one startup, a half-share of a sustainably raised hog for scouting a new software engineer. </p> <p>We all have effectively an infinite number of open positions for software developers, program managers, said Spencer Rascoff, chief executive officer of Zillow. If I somehow magically filled 100 positions we''d open another 100, and Amazon would too. </p> <p>Microsoft, which is cutting as many as 18,000 jobs worldwide, says the initial round will affect 1,351 in the Puget Sound region surrounding Seattle. While those who lost administrative work may not be as fortunate, software engineers can pick from more than 6,000 open positions in the Seattle area, according to the job listings site Indeed.com. </p> <p>Founded by Seattle natives Bill Gates and Paul Allen in 1975, Microsoft put its operating system on most of the world''s desktop computers and helped the region diversify its national identify from airplanes, logging and fish. The software maker is the state''s second-biggest private employer after Boeing Co. (BA), with 43,031 Puget Sound jobs as of June. </p>




Photographer: Mike Kane/Bloomberg

<p>
The Space Needle and buildings stand in the downtown skyline as the sun sets in Seattle, Washington. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Jul 18, 2014 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-18/microsoft-eliminating-18-000-jobs-as-nadella-streamlines.html"><headline>Microsoft Eliminating 18,000 Jobs as Nadella Streamlines</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) said it will
eliminate as many as 18,000 jobs, the largest round of cuts in
its history, as Chief Executive Officer Satya Nadella integrates
Nokia Oyj''s handset unit and slims down the software maker. </p>
<p>The restructuring, amounting to about 14 percent of its
workforce, includes 12,500 Nokia factory and professional
positions -- half the number of employees added in the
acquisition. At Microsoft, cuts will be in sales, marketing and
engineering. The reductions are expected to be completed by June
30, 2015, and will result in a pretax charge of $1.1 billion to
$1.6 billion, Microsoft said in a statement yesterday. </p>
<p>Nadella, who took over from Steve Ballmer in February, is
retooling the company''s structure as it seeks to compete with
nimbler rivals offering mobile and Internet-based software and
services. He''s also working to wring a promised $600 million in
annual savings from Microsoft''s Nokia deal, which added 25,000
workers in April, bringing the total to about 127,100. </p>
<p>Microsoft needs to be a leaner tech giant over the coming
years in order to strike the right balance of growth and
profitability around its cloud and mobile endeavors, said
Daniel Ives, an analyst at FBR Capital Markets  Co. who rates
Microsoft stock the equivalent of a buy. The cuts are roughly
twice as big as Wall Street expected, Ives said in a note. </p>
<p>The shares rose 1 percent to $44.53 at yesterday''s close in
New York. They have advanced 19 percent this year. </p>
<h2>Streamline Management </h2>
<p>The company started with 13,000 cuts yesterday, and the
majority of eliminated workers will be notified in the next six
months, Nadella said in an e-mail to employees. Microsoft will
also have fewer layers of management and will make changes to
its outside vendor staff, he said. </p>
<p>The first step to building the right organization for our
ambitions is to realign our workforce, he wrote. </p>
<p>Last week, in his first mission statement, Nadella said the
Redmond, Washington-based software maker needs to become more
focused and efficient and requires changes to its engineering
teams. He pledged updates on the new plans later this month, and
said he would provide more details when the company reports
earnings on July 22. </p>
<p>Microsoft investors are likely to view the cuts as a
positive sign, illustrating that Nadella is trying to get costs
and headcount under control and that he understands the
challenges facing Microsoft, Ives said. </p>
<h2>Earnings Growth </h2>
<p>We view this as another step in the right direction from
the Street''s perspective, he said in an interview. Nadella
is not wearing rose-colored glasses. </p>
<p>The reductions may add 30 cents a share to Microsoft''s
profit in fiscal 2016, estimated Kirk Materne, an analyst at
Evercore Partners Inc., who rates Microsoft the equivalent of a
buy. </p>
<p>The company has needed to cut costs. Analysts on average
estimate that profit before certain items increased 1 percent in
the fiscal year that ended last month, after a decline in fiscal
2013 and little growth the prior year. </p>
<p>Given the stock''s gains in recent months on optimism about
Nadella''s plans, it''s time for the company to post earnings
growth that validates that enthusiasm, said Brent Thill, an
analyst at UBS AG, who recommends buying the stock. Microsoft
spends far more on product development and research than rivals
such as Apple Inc. (AAPL) and Google Inc. (GOOG) and gets a smaller return for
that investment, he said. </p>
<p>They have been spending on a lot of things that haven''t
come to fruition, he said. The Nadella era will be about
putting more money on bigger hits and not sprinkling a little
everywhere. </p>
<h2>Mobile Focus </h2>
<p>In appearances at company and technology events since he
took the helm, Nadella has reiterated that the company''s
priorities are mobile and cloud products, as he works to shift
Microsoft away from its longtime core business of software for
personal computers. Nadella has signaled a desire to produce
software for rival operating systems, like Apple''s iOS and
Google''s Android, and has shuffled management in areas like
marketing, business development and the Xbox game console. </p>
<p>While Microsoft has implemented smaller, intermittent job
cuts in individual businesses -- for example, trimming a few
hundred positions in advertising sales and marketing in 2012,
and some marketing jobs across the company earlier that same
year -- the 39-year-old company has only undertaken a
companywide restructuring affecting thousands of workers once
before, in 2009, at the start of the recession. Over the course
of that year, the company cut 5,800 jobs, or about 5 percent of
its workforce at the time. </p>
<h2>Cost Savings </h2>
<p>When Microsoft agreed to acquire Nokia''s device unit in
September, the software maker pledged $600 million in yearly
cost savings in the 18 months after the deal closed. While this
week''s layoffs are the company''s biggest ever, excluding the
12,500 positions being eliminated at Nokia, the 5,500 job cuts
at Microsoft are smaller than those in 2009. </p>
<p>Microsoft''s engineering teams have traditionally been split
between program managers, developers and testers. Now, with new
cloud-based methods of building software, it often makes sense
to have the developers test and fix bugs instead of a separate
team of testers, Nadella said in an interview last week after
releasing his memo. </p>
<h2>Nokia Shift </h2>
<p>The Nokia business, now part of Microsoft''s devices group,
will also undergo some product changes as Microsoft ends output
of phones running Google''s Android operating system and targets
the more affordable smartphone segments, wrote devices group
chief Stephen Elop, formerly the CEO of Nokia, in an e-mail
posted on Microsoft''s site. </p>
<p>Microsoft will switch the Nokia X, which uses Android, to
the Windows Phone operating system to broaden its products in
the cheaper smartphone category. It will also align future high-end smartphone releases with major products from Windows and
Microsoft''s applications team, Elop said. </p>
<p>The company will also combine what had been two units at
Nokia -- Smart Devices and Mobile Phones -- into one under
executive Jo Harlow. Phone engineering will be based in Salo,
Finland, for high-end devices, and Tampere, Finland, for cheaper
ones. Engineering work in Oulu, Finland, will be scaled down. </p>
<p>Engineering in Beijing and San Diego will see cuts, and
phone production will be focused mainly in Hanoi. Nokia will
shift repair and manufacturing operations from Hungary. The cuts
may affect 1,100 employees in Finland and about 1,800 in
Hungary, Microsoft said. </p>
<p>Elop''s memo was derided by publications from New York
magazine to the Guardian, which titled a blog How not to cut
12,500 jobs, for starting with the greeting Hello There,
and failing to get to the job cuts until the 11th paragraph of
14. </p>
<h2>TV Programming </h2>
<p>In the Xbox business, the company will shut down an
ambitious effort to create original television programming, just
one month after the debut of its first show. The Xbox
Entertainment Studio will close in coming months, Xbox chief
Phil Spencer said in an e-mail to employees. </p>
<p>Nancy Tellem, the ex-CBS executive brought in to lead the
effort two years ago, will stay on with some of her team to
complete shows in production, such as a Halo series, the
company said. Tellem was hired by former CEO Ballmer to draw
more entertainment consumers to Xbox by getting into original
programming, like Amazon.com Inc. and Netflix Inc. </p>
<p>As the technology industry increasingly shifts toward
mobile computing and cloud-based services, other technology
companies have also sought to keep up by streamlining and firing
workers. Hewlett-Packard Co. in May disclosed 16,000 more job
cuts after reporting an 11th straight quarter of declining
sales, on top of 34,000 in staff reductions already announced.
International Business Machines Corp. also started dismissing
workers earlier this year as part of a $1 billion restructuring
to help it adapt to the industry''s changes. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kathleen M. Howley and Alexis Leondis" date="Jul 18, 2014 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-18/jpmorgan-in-rules-dispute-cedes-loan-share-to-nonbanks.html"><headline>JPMorgan in Rules Dispute Cedes Loan Share to Nonbanks</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Wells Fargo  Co. (WFC) and JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the behemoths of the U.S. mortgage market, are surrendering more business to nonbank lenders. </p> <p>The nation''s two largest originators made 21 percent of home loans in the second quarter, the smallest combined share in more than a decade, down from 30 percent a year ago, according to regulatory filings. They''re ceding ground to companies like Quicken Loans Inc., which grabbed the No. 3 spot from Bank of America Corp. in the first quarter, and LoanDepot.com LLC, whose share surged more than three-fold in the following period. </p> <p>Big banks are exercising caution to avoid losses if their home loans sour and government-controlled Fannie Mae or Freddie Mac force them to repurchase the mortgages. This week, JPMorgan head Jamie Dimon escalated the buyback issue between lenders and the government, saying he questioned whether his bank should end its decades-old relationship with the Federal Housing Administration, a last resort for lower-income Americans seeking mortgages. Nonbank lenders, hungry for mortgages to service, are expanding rapidly to fill the void left by banks. </p> <p>Mortgage banking may just be a smaller players'' game now, said Paul Miller, a banking analyst at FBR Capital Markets Corp. in Arlington, Virginia. They''re able to be more flexible. </p> <p>JPMorgan, the No. 2 U.S. mortgage lender, reported this week that its second-quarter originations fell 66 percent to $16.8 billion, the lowest quarterly result since at least 2005, compared with the year-ago period. The New York-based bank''s share of the market dropped to 5.4 percent in the second quarter, according to data compiled by Bloomberg, from 8.1 percent in the first period. JPMorgan''s market share averaged 10 percent in the prior five years. </p> <h2>JPMorgan Threat </h2> <p>Much of the decline came from a falloff in FHA lending, Dimon said on the bank''s call with analysts. Banks have been in a dispute with Fannie Mae, Freddie Mac and FHA over rules that force the firms to repurchase mortgages that go bad. </p> <p>Our FHA volume was way down and we studied FHA and based upon the lawsuits and the premiums and stuff like that we''ve lost a tremendous sum of money in FHA, Dimon said. The real question to me is should we be in the FHA business at all and we''re still struggling with that. </p> <p>JPMorgan''s loss of market share is part of its long-term plan to pull back from the mortgage business and focus on making loans to the most creditworthy borrowers, said Miller. </p> <h2>Wells Drops </h2> <p>They''re making a strategic decision to shrink, Miller said. They don''t want to do marginal loans they could end up paying the piper on. They''re saying we paid a lot of money and we''re done with it. </p> <p>Wells Fargo last week reported that originations fell 58 percent to $47 billion from a year earlier, the lowest second-quarter result in more than a decade. The San Francisco-based bank''s market share declined to 15.2 percent in the second quarter, based on data compiled by Bloomberg, from 15.9 percent in the first period. The bank''s share averaged 23 percent in the prior five years. </p> <p>Wells Fargo Chief Executive Officer John Stumpf said on a conference call last week that the bank wants to lend to more borrowers even if they don''t have pristine credit. He said Wells Fargo just needs clarity about what triggers a buyback demand. </p> <p>Bank executives are having meetings with Melvin L. Watt, the director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency, about the rules, Stumpf said. FHFA oversees Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac, known as government-sponsored enterprises. Earlier this year, Watt introduced a sunset provision so lenders are not responsible in some cases if loans go sour after three years. </p> <h2>LoanDepot Advantage </h2> <p>You have low rates on one side encouraging borrowing and you have put-backs from the GSEs on the other side that make lenders less willing to lend money, Stumpf said. The goal is to get more credit appropriately to borrowers who want to own homes and who can afford homes. </p> <p>Nonbank lenders like LoanDepot.com that started after the housing crash in 2007 or didn''t make subprime loans are not burdened with the buyback issue, said Anthony Hsieh, chief executive officer of LoanDepot.com. The online lender, which is backed by private-equity firm Parthenon Capital Partners, began in 2010 in compliance with new mortgage regulations compared with established banks that had to adapt to the changes, Hsieh said. </p> <p>We had a clean canvas to build our organization post crisis in a new world of much heavier regulatory scrutiny, said Hsieh, a former president of LendingTree.com. The biggest banks have a much smaller footprint than before and that creates a lot of opportunity for nonbank lenders. </p> <h2>Share Soars </h2> <p>LoanDepot.com, which collects payments on the majority of mortgages it makes, originated $3 billion in loans in the second quarter, a 58 percent jump from a year earlier, according to Hsieh. The Foothill Ranch, California-based firm''s market share rose more than threefold to 1.1 percent in the second period, Hsieh said. </p> <p>Hsieh said the firm is selling products that are compliant with qualified mortgage guidelines, such as debt-to-income ratios below 43 percent. The company will soon announce an offering for loans without government backing to help sustain its rapid growth, he said. </p> <p>Stonegate Mortgage Corp. (SGM), which was founded by Jim Cutillo and his wife Barbara in 2005, survived the subprime meltdown by avoiding these risky loans. The Indianapolis-based firm has been ratcheting up its market share by expanding to states such as California and Virginia, said Cutillo, who was a director for GMAC Residential Funding. </p> <h2>Wholesale Business </h2> <p>The lender and servicer, whose biggest investor is private-equity firm Long Ridge Equity Partners, last year hired a team from Nationstar Mortgage Holdings Inc. to expand its wholesale business -- lending through mortgage brokers. </p> <p>The company''s mortgage origination volume, which includes FHA loans, jumped 27 percent to $2.4 billion in the first quarter compared with a year earlier. Cutillo plans to build the firm''s business in jumbo loans in places like Washington with more expensive real estate. </p> <p>If all the big players were deconsolidating and some small and mid-sized players didn''t have enough capital to build size and scale in any industry, wouldn''t you think there would be a huge opportunity? Cutillo said. We''re arbitraging that and filling a big void the banks have left. </p> <h2>Refinance Plunge </h2> <p>Plaza Home Mortgage Inc. mostly provides wholesale lending -- a business that banks like Wells Fargo exited. Plaza Home Mortgage has been able to increase its originations by working with brokers who focus on purchases. </p> <p>That''s paid off as refinancing has waned, said Kevin Parra, Plaza''s co-founder. Refinancing, a traditional mainstay for banks, fell in April to the lowest level since 2008, according to the Mortgage Bankers Association. </p> <p>The San Diego-based firm benefits from established relationships with mortgage brokers who in turn work with local realtors, Parra said. </p> <p>As the market has moved from refis to purchases, service becomes a bigger factor, and brokers will use us because they know us and trust we will get them to close on time, said Parra. </p> <p>Plaza Home originated $1 billion in mortgages for purchases in the second quarter compared with $780 million a year earlier, and increased its total market share to 0.6 percent, said Parra. </p> <p>The market-share gain of small lenders is increasing financial risks for Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac, according to a report yesterday from the FHFA''s Office of Inspector General. The companies, which were on the brink of insolvency in 2008 and seized by the government, buy mortgages from lenders and package them into securities that are sold to investors. </p> <h2>Limited Capacity'' </h2> <p>Some smaller lenders and nonbank mortgage companies have limited financial capacity, the report said. If loans later prove to have errors in them, the companies may lack the ability to make good on buyback demands, resulting in losses for taxpayers, it said. </p> <p>Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac have recovered almost $100 billion from lenders stemming from buyback demands since the 2008 financial crisis, the report said. </p> <p>Banks may focus more on mortgage lending once there''s more clarity around buybacks and the housing recovery regains momentum, said Hsieh of LoanDepot.com. </p> <p>Wells will always be the 800 pound gorilla, but the nonbank upstarts will make headway and some will be here to stay, said FBR''s Miller. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Julia Verlaine and Michael J. Moore" date="Jul 21, 2014  1:13 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-21/goldman-sachs-managing-director-nicholas-valtz-found-dead.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Managing Director Nicholas Valtz Found Dead</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Nicholas Valtz, a managing director
in cross-asset sales at Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) in New York,
was found dead yesterday by family members who went searching
for him after he didn''t return from a kiteboarding outing. </p>
<p>Valtz, 39, was found in Napeague Harbor near the eastern
end of Long Island, according to the East Hampton, New York,
police. He was a novice kiteboarder and was found floating
in the water secured to his kite, police said in a statement
released yesterday. Other kite gear was found in a grassy area
of the harbor, police said. </p>
<p>We''re deeply saddened by this tragedy and our thoughts
are with Nick''s family, Michael DuVally, a spokesman for
Manhattan-based Goldman Sachs, said in an e-mailed statement. </p>
<p>Valtz, who joined the firm in 2000, was promoted to
managing director in 2010. As a cross-asset sales executive, he
helped manage orders for trading clients and pitch them products
and ideas among different types of securities. His wife, Sashi
Valtz, also works at Goldman Sachs as head of global third-party
research sales, according to her LinkedIn profile. </p>
<p>Nicholas Andrew Valtz was born in September 1974 and
received a bachelor''s degree from Harvard University in 1996,
according to New York voting records and Harvard''s website. The
school lists him as earning letters in fencing for three years. </p>
<p>Police are still investigating the death, according to the
statement. </p>
<h2>Hybrid Sport </h2>
<p>Kiteboarding is a convergence of windsurfing and
paragliding that has attracted technology executives including
Google Inc. co-founders Sergey Brin and Larry Page. Also called
kitesurfing, it propels riders across water at speeds as fast as
40 miles per hour (64 kilometers per hour), on boards about 4
feet to 5 1/2 feet long (1.2 meters to 1.7 meters). </p>
<p>For steering, a crossbar is connected to the kites with
lines. Using waves as ramps, riders can vault 10 feet to 40 feet
out of the water and often spin before landing. They can stop by
pushing the crossbar to deflate the kite, or by ditching in the
surf. </p>
<p>In March 2008, Valtz shaved his head to raise money for
childhood cancer research, according to the website for St.
Baldrick''s Foundation. </p>
<p>Valtz enjoyed technology products and fast cars, according
to the website for his brother-in-law''s 2012 wedding in which he
was a groomsman. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Julia Verlaine and Michael J. Moore" date="Jul 21, 2014  1:13 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-21/goldman-sachs-managing-director-nicholas-valtz-found-dead.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Managing Director Nicholas Valtz Found Dead</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Nicholas Valtz, a managing director
in cross-asset sales at Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) in New York,
was found dead yesterday by family members who went searching
for him after he didn''t return from a kiteboarding outing. </p>
<p>Valtz, 39, was found in Napeague Harbor near the eastern
end of Long Island, according to the East Hampton, New York,
police. He was a novice kiteboarder and was found floating
in the water secured to his kite, police said in a statement
released yesterday. Other kite gear was found in a grassy area
of the harbor, police said. </p>
<p>We''re deeply saddened by this tragedy and our thoughts
are with Nick''s family, Michael DuVally, a spokesman for
Manhattan-based Goldman Sachs, said in an e-mailed statement. </p>
<p>Valtz, who joined the firm in 2000, was promoted to
managing director in 2010. As a cross-asset sales executive, he
helped manage orders for trading clients and pitch them products
and ideas among different types of securities. His wife, Sashi
Valtz, also works at Goldman Sachs as head of global third-party
research sales, according to her LinkedIn profile. </p>
<p>Nicholas Andrew Valtz was born in September 1974 and
received a bachelor''s degree from Harvard University in 1996,
according to New York voting records and Harvard''s website. The
school lists him as earning letters in fencing for three years. </p>
<p>Police are still investigating the death, according to the
statement. </p>
<h2>Hybrid Sport </h2>
<p>Kiteboarding is a convergence of windsurfing and
paragliding that has attracted technology executives including
Google Inc. co-founders Sergey Brin and Larry Page. Also called
kitesurfing, it propels riders across water at speeds as fast as
40 miles per hour (64 kilometers per hour), on boards about 4
feet to 5 1/2 feet long (1.2 meters to 1.7 meters). </p>
<p>For steering, a crossbar is connected to the kites with
lines. Using waves as ramps, riders can vault 10 feet to 40 feet
out of the water and often spin before landing. They can stop by
pushing the crossbar to deflate the kite, or by ditching in the
surf. </p>
<p>In March 2008, Valtz shaved his head to raise money for
childhood cancer research, according to the website for St.
Baldrick''s Foundation. </p>
<p>Valtz enjoyed technology products and fast cars, according
to the website for his brother-in-law''s 2012 wedding in which he
was a groomsman. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Jul 22, 2014  6:52 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-22/microsoft-revenue-misses-estimates-on-weak-demand-from-consumers.html"><headline>Microsoft''s Quarterly Profit Hurt by Nokia Acquisition</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) reported profit that fell short of estimates in the fiscal fourth quarter, weighed down by the acquisition of Nokia Oyj''s handset unit, where about 12,500 jobs will be cut. </p> <p>Net income in the period that ended June 30 was $4.61 billion, or 55 cents a share, including adjustments related to Nokia, the company said in a statement today. Analysts were predicting, on average, profit of 60 cents a share, according to estimates compiled by Bloomberg. Excluding the Nokia-related items and taxes, profit would have been 66 cents a share, beating the average prediction for 64 cents. </p> <p>Chief Executive Officer Satya Nadella, who took over in February, is struggling to cut costs at Nokia after Microsoft completed its 5.44 billion euro ($7.33 billion) acquisition of the mobile-phone operations in April. Microsoft''s main software business topped estimates, owing to strength in Internet-based cloud programs and corporate computer applications. </p> <p>Related: Microsoft CEO, Seeking Growth, Tells Managers: Step It Up</p><p>Nokia continues to be the black cloud over Microsoft, said Daniel Ives, an analyst at FBR Capital Markets  Co. who has the equivalent of a buy rating on the stock. This is the first quarter before the cost cuts. That''s why Nadella took the ax out. </p> <p>The shares of Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft rose 1.3 percent in extended trading following the report. They were little changed at $44.83 at the close in New York. The stock climbed 1.7 percent last quarter, compared with a 4.7 percent increase in the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index. </p> <h2>Nokia Challenge </h2> <p>The Nokia numbers underscore the challenges facing Nadella and his lieutenants as they seek to halt the decline of the handset business and turn it into an asset that can aid Microsoft''s mobile efforts. </p> <p>Satya has taken a number of exciting steps both to reposition the company and to energize it, Microsoft Chief Financial Officer Amy Hood said in an interview. </p> <p>Nadella will cut more costs and prioritize core areas, he said on a conference call today. He also pledged to make the money-losing Bing search engine profitable by fiscal 2016. Nadella said MSN websites, retail stores and hardware production are now considered supporting efforts, where costs will be watched carefully. Hood said Microsoft''s new phone unit, formerly the Nokia handset business, is on track to break even on an operating basis in 2016 as well. </p> <p>Microsoft plans to cut operating costs for the current fiscal year to $34.2 billion to $34.6 billion, Hood said. </p> <h2>Cloud, Enterprise </h2> <p>At the same time, cloud and enterprise software performed well, with revenue doubling for the Web-based versions of Office and Microsoft''s Azure cloud-based service for hosting applications. Commercial cloud products now have an annual run-rate of $4.4 billion, Hood said. Corporate demand for personal computers helped shore up sales of Office and Windows to businesses, with companies signing multiyear licensing deals. </p> <p>Cloud looked strong -- core PC seemed to get an uplift from improving PC demand, Ives said. Office 365 and Azure continue to be pillars of strength. I would call this in-line results. </p> <p>Unearned revenue, which comes from sales of multiyear deals that will be recognized in the future, was $25.2 billion for the quarter, compared with the $24.5 billion average analyst projection, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p> <h2>Restructuring Efforts </h2> <p>In addition to a plan to cut a total of 18,000 jobs as the company integrates Nokia, Nadella has discontinued unpromising products and placed more emphasis on cloud-computing software delivered via the Web. The restructuring will result in $1.1 billion to $1.6 billion in charges in the current fiscal year, according to Microsoft. </p> <p>The company as a whole is galvanized around Satya''s strategy, Hood said. </p> <p>Microsoft is also seeing signs of improvement in the PC market, which drives sales of Windows and Office software. PC shipments declined 1.7 percent in the second quarter, a smaller drop than estimated as businesses upgraded their equipment. Demand in the U.S., Europe and Canada also helped to make up for a drop in Asia, researcher IDC said earlier this month. </p> <p>Intel Corp. also released results last week that topped analysts'' projections. Microsoft''s Hood said the company is seeing similar trends to those reported by Intel. </p> <p>The strength in the enterprise and the comments on the refresh would seem to bode well for Microsoft continuing to have uptake with enterprise sales, said Michael Shinnick, a fund manager at South Bend, Indiana-based Wasatch Advisors Inc., which has $19 billion under management. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Martin" date="Jul 22, 2014  5:19 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-22/general-electric-opens-fuel-cell-pilot-plant-in-new-york.html"><headline>General Electric Opens Fuel Cell Pilot Plant in New York</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>General Electric Co. (GE) opened a fuel-cell testing and research facility in upstate New York that will
produce its first systems by the end of the year. </p>
<p>GE has developed a solid-oxide fuel cell that converts
about 65 percent of the energy in natural gas to electricity
through a chemical reaction, the Fairfield, Connecticut-based
company said today on its website. </p>
<p>When waste heat from the system is used to power a steam
turbine, GE researchers expect to boost the efficiency level to
about 95 percent, Megan Parker, a spokeswoman, said in an
interview today. The systems can reach temperatures of 1,500
degrees Fahrenheit (816 degrees Celsius). </p>
<p>GE''s 17-member fuel-cell team is planning a pilot factory
in Saratoga Springs, New York, and expects to begin commercial
production in 2017, Parker said. The systems will have
capacities ranging from one megawatt to 10 megawatts, depending
on the configuration. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Duane D. Stanford" date="Jul 22, 2014  4:25 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-22/coca-cola-misses-sales-estimates-amid-juice-diet-coke-slowdown.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Misses Sales Estimates Amid Juice, Diet Coke Slide</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Coca-Cola Co. (KO), the world''s largest
beverage company, reported second-quarter sales that missed
analysts'' estimates amid sluggish demand for drinks such as
juice and Diet Coke in North America. </p>
<p>Revenue fell 1.4 percent to $12.6 billion in the period
ended June 27, Atlanta-based Coca-Cola said today in a
statement. Analysts had estimated $12.8 billion on average,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. Global juice sales
volume declined 1 percent, hurt by price increases in North
America to offset higher ingredient costs. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Muhtar Kent is cutting costs and
overhauling marketing as he contends with a slowdown in the
market for fizzy beverages. Coca-Cola also is increasingly
relying on overseas markets to maintain growth. </p>
<p>Coke''s Q2 result was weaker than expected, said Dara Mohsenian, an analyst at Morgan Stanley in New York. The bar
is low for Coke, but with weak topline results, worse than
expected underlying profit, and slight negative EPS guidance
revisions in H2, we would expect the stock to be down today. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola fell 2.9 percent to $41.19 at the close in New
York. The shares have dropped less than 1 percent this year,
compared with a 7.3 percent gain for the Standard  Poor''s 500
Index. </p>




Photographer: Jin Lee/Bloomberg

<p>
Coca-Cola Co. Chief Executive Officer Muhtar Kent said in the statement, We remain focused on the work required to return our business to the level of sustainable growth we and our shareowners expect. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ruth David and Manuel Baigorri" date="Jul 22, 2014  1:35 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-22/morgan-stanley-said-to-win-aena-ipo-role-on-lowest-fees.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Said to Win Aena IPO Role on Lowest Fees</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) won a role on what
may become Europe''s largest initial public offering this year,
the sale of Spanish airport operator Aena Aeropuertos SA, after
offering to charge the lowest fees among global banks, said
three people with knowledge of the matter. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley offered to charge 0.19 percent of the amount
raised in the IPO in fees, said the people, who asked not to be
identified because they weren''t authorized to speak publicly.
Spain''s government said today it will sell 49 percent of Aena,
including 21 percent to so-called anchor investors. The IPO may
value Aena at over 5 billion euros ($6.7 billion), the people
said. </p>
<p>Bank of America Merrill Lynch and Goldman Sachs Group Inc.,
which also won roles after presentations this week, offered to
charge fees of 0.24 percent and 0.45 percent respectively, the
people said. The advisers typically have to adjust their fees
based on the lowest winning bid. </p>
<p>Banks often offer lower fees on IPOs of large state assets
because they bring league table credit and the chance of repeat
business from companies once they are public. Aena''s IPO could
raise about 2.5 billion euros if the government sells 49
percent, making it the largest in Europe this year. </p>
<p>Banks managing the 2 billion-pound ($3.4 billion) sale of
state-run postal service Royal Mail Plc (RMG) in October were paid 0.7
percent in fees, according to data compiled by Freeman  Co., a
New York-based consulting firm. The 866 million-euro IPO of
Belgium''s postal operator bpost SA netted sale managers 1.5
percent in fees in June last year. Banks earned about 3 percent
on average in total IPO fees in Europe in 2013, data compiled by
Bloomberg show. </p>
<p>Spokesmen for Morgan Stanley, Bank of America and Goldman
Sachs declined to comment. </p>
<p>Spain''s government said 70 percent of the banks'' grading
would be based on their fee bid and 30 percent would be based on
their expertise, according to a company spokeswoman for Aena. </p>
<p>Listings in Spain have raised over $6 billion this year,
the most since 2011, data compiled by Bloomberg show, as
investors return to the country''s markets on the hope of an
economic recovery.  Morgan Stanley ranks 7th in managing IPOs in
Spain so far this year, the data show. </p>
<p>The IPO of NN Group NV, the insurance arm of ING Groep NV,
was the largest in Europe this year, raising 1.8 billion euros. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Jul 22, 2014 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-22/microsoft-ceo-seeking-growth-tells-managers-step-it-up.html"><headline>Microsoft CEO, Seeking Growth, Tells Managers: Step It Up</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The day Satya Nadella became Microsoft Corp. (MSFT)''s chief executive officer, he invited several dozen vice presidents to breakfast and had a simple, calm admonition for them: Can you step it up? </p> <p>The engineer''s tone was a departure from the yelling and wild gesticulations favored by his salesman predecessor Steve Ballmer and the razor-sharp interrogations of co-founder Bill Gates. Nadella''s approach underlines the low-key and analytical style he brings as CEO since starting the job in February, as he seeks to revamp the world''s largest software maker. Nadella has unveiled plans to cut more than 18,000 jobs, killed unpromising products and boosted sales of computing tools delivered via the Internet, while seeking to reduce the company''s reliance on software installed on personal computers. </p> <p>He''s one of those people where you just hate to say no to the guy, Jeff Teper, Microsoft''s head of corporate strategy, said of Nadella in an interview in March. Teper hired Nadella into the company in 1992. Steve and Bill are a lot more confrontational -- they challenge you to bring your A game. With him it''s more like well I don''t want to disappoint the guy, let me work a little bit harder here.'' He''s incredibly smart, he''s gracious, but he''s also super-demanding. </p>




Source: Microsoft Corp. via Bloomberg

<p>
Satya Nadella, chief executive officer of Microsoft Corp., speaks to employees at Microsoft''s Studio D building in Seattle, Washington, in a handout photo made available to the media on Feb. 4, 2014. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jonathan D. Salant" date="Jul 23, 2014  4:32 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-23/general-dynamics-beats-second-quarter-profit-estimate.html"><headline>General Dynamics Lifts Forecast as Sales Fall</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>General Dynamics Corp. (GD), the
Pentagon''s No. 3 contractor, raised its full-year profit
forecast while second-quarter sales declined in a slumping
defense market. </p>
<p>Net income from continuing operations rose 1 percent to
$646 million, or $1.88 a share, from $640 million, or $1.81 a
share, a year earlier, the company said in a statement today.
That beat the average estimate of 21 analysts surveyed by
Bloomberg was $1.77. </p>
<p>The contractor increased its profit outlook for the year to
$7.40 to $7.45 a share from April''s forecast of $7.05 to $7.10 a
share. </p>
<p>General Dynamics and other defense suppliers are fighting
for a shrinking pool of federal contracts as the U.S. withdraws
combat troops from Afghanistan and reduces spending under a
process known as sequestration. </p>
<p>Sales fell 4.6 percent to $7.47 billion in the quarter,
trailing the average estimate of $7.53 billion, according to 17
analysts surveyed by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Revenue in the company''s aerospace unit, which includes the
Gulfstream business jet, declined 2.8 percent to $2 billion. The
other three divisions of the Falls Church, Virginia-based
company are marine systems, combat systems and information
systems and technology. </p>
<p>General Dynamics rose 1.8 percent to close at $120.73 in
New York. The shares have jumped 44 percent in the past 12
months, compared with a 17 percent gain in the Standard  Poor''s
500 Index. (SPX) </p>
<h2>Gulfstream Jets </h2>
<p>Phebe Novakovic, chairman and chief executive officer, said
in a statement that robust order activity across the portfolio
of Gulfstream business jets and an increased backlog of
defense orders provided a solid building block for the
future. </p>
<p>Net income from continuing operations in the quarter didn''t
include a one-time $105 million charge for the sale of a
business in the combat systems division. </p>
<p>Lockheed Martin Corp. (LMT), the largest U.S. government
contractor, yesterday reported sales and profit beating
analysts'' estimates for the quarter. The company, based in
Bethesda, Maryland, also boosted its full-year profit outlook. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Jul 23, 2014  4:14 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-23/microsoft-s-quarterly-profit-hurt-by-nokia-acquisition.html"><headline>Microsoft''s Quarterly Profit Hurt by Nokia Acquisition</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT)''s purchase of Nokia Oyj''s mobile business dragged down fiscal fourth-quarter profit, even as the software maker benefits from improving corporate demand for computers and software delivered over the Web. </p> <p>Nokia''s operations, which Microsoft bought for 5.44 billion euros ($7.33 billion) in April, contributed to a 7.1 percent decline in net income to $4.61 billion, or 55 cents a share, for the period that ended June 30, the company said in a statement yesterday. That missed analysts'' average projection for profit of 60 cents a share, according to estimates compiled by Bloomberg. Excluding Nokia-related items and taxes, the profit was 66 cents, beating the average prediction for 64 cents. </p> <p>Chief Executive Officer Satya Nadella, who took over in February, is struggling to reduce costs, with 12,500 of the 18,000 job cuts announced last week related to Nokia. While Microsoft''s main software business topped estimates, the company has made little headway in delivering popular smartphones and tablets. </p> <p>Nokia continues to be the black cloud over Microsoft, said Daniel Ives, an analyst at FBR Capital Markets  Co. who has the equivalent of a buy rating on the stock. This is the first quarter before the cost cuts. That''s why Nadella took the ax out. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
Microsoft Corp. Chief Executive Officer Satya Nadella, who took over in February, is struggling to reduce costs, with 12,500 of the 18,000 job cuts announced last week related to Nokia. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lu Wang" date="Jul 23, 2014  1:44 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-23/jpmorgan-picks-lakos-bujas-as-head-of-u-s-equity-strategy.html"><headline>JPMorgan Picks Lakos-Bujas as Head of U.S. Equity Strategy</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. named Dubravko Lakos-Bujas as the head of U.S. equity and quantitative strategy, assuming the role last held by Thomas Lee. </p> <p>Lakos-Bujas will lead a team of analysts in covering the broad stock market and use mathematical models to analyze trends and find trading opportunities for JPMorgan clients. He will continue to report to Marko Kolanovic, global head of macro derivative and systematic strategies, according to a statement from the New York-based bank. </p> <p>The strategist joins almost two dozen Wall Street forecasters who try to predict the direction of the stock market and advise investors on their equity holdings. The average estimate for the year-end level of the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index is 1,986, based on a Bloomberg News survey of banks and brokerages, implying the equity benchmark will be little changed from now to December. </p> <p>Lakos-Bujas has worked as a quantitative analyst focusing on global markets at JPMorgan and spent six years at Deutsche Bank AG''s asset management division, according to the statement from JPMorgan. He was third-ranked quantitative analyst in Institutional Investor''s survey last year. Lee, who held the job since 2007, left earlier this year. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrea Gerlin" date="Jul 23, 2014 11:27 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-23/goldman-wins-14-6-million-in-singapore-investor-clash.html"><headline>Goldman Wins $14.6 Million in Singapore Investor Clash</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) was awarded
about $14.6 million by a London judge in a dispute with a
Singapore-based investor over shares it held as collateral on a
loan. </p>
<p>James Hong Gee Ho, former executive director of Blumont
Group Ltd. (BLUM), who''d initially sued Goldman Sachs for failing to
get the best price on his shares after a margin call, was
ordered to pay the money by Judge David Mackie today. The amount
included principal and interest on the loan. </p>
<p>Hong was one of several Singapore executives who got into
payment disputes with Goldman Sachs after shares of Blumont,
Asiasons Capital Ltd. (ACAP) and LionGold Corp. (LIGO) plunged during a stock
rout in October. </p>
<p>Hong didn''t appear in court after Goldman Sachs''s legal
team notified a law firm that had represented him that Goldman
would ask to have the case dismissed, said Rebecca Loveridge, a
lawyer representing the bank. </p>
<p>The law firm that had represented Hong, Wiggin LLP, didn''t
return a telephone message and Hong didn''t respond to an e-mail
sent to Blumont''s office in Singapore. </p>
<p>Loveridge said Hong''s lawsuit was a tactic to delay
paying the money he owed. She said Hong hadn''t shown any
interest in continuing the claim and a question had arisen about
whether Wiggin continued to represent him. His original suit
against the bank said Goldman Sachs failed to obtain the best
price for his shares, Loveridge said. </p>
<h2>Ludicrous'' Figure </h2>
<p>Goldman Sachs vigorously denied those claims, Loveridge
said. There was never any dispute that he entered into that
agreement. </p>
<p>The judge declined to order Hong to make a payment toward
an estimated 1 million pounds ($1.7 million) in fees and costs
that Loveridge had requested because he said Goldman Sachs''s
lawyers hadn''t presented evidence. </p>
<p>That figure was ludicrous, Mackie said. You want the
court to make an order of a million pounds? There''s been no
trial. </p>
<p>Hong stepped down as an executive director on July 20 for
personal reasons, Blumont, which invests in minerals and energy,
said in a statement dated July 18. </p>
<p>The case is James Hong Gee Ho v. Goldman Sachs
International, case no. 14-17, U.K. High Court of Justice,
Queen''s Bench Division. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Isis Almeida" date="Jul 23, 2014  6:06 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-23/goldman-sees-eu-using-more-gas-for-power-as-short-lived.html"><headline>Goldman Sees EU Using More Gas for Power as Short-Lived</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Europe''s return to favoring natural
gas for power generation for the first time in almost three
years will be short-lived as Russian and Norwegian gas imports
will be needed for winter, according to Goldman Sachs Group Inc. </p>
<p>An excess of gas in storage is driving efficient power
plants in the U.K. to use more of the fuel at the expense of
coal, the bank said in a report dated yesterday. Power plants in
the U.K., Europe''s biggest gas market, can consume supplementary
inventories before the winter if prices for the fuel are at an
average discount of 5 pence a therm (9 cents a million British
thermal units) to coal, it said. </p>
<p>Price-induced coal to gas switching is likely to only be
a summer phenomenon in Europe, analysts including London-based
Daniel Quigley said in the report. Beyond the summer, we
continue to expect European gas to return to a 2013-like
dynamic, requiring relatively high imports from Russia and
Norway to compensate for 11 billion cubic meters a year of
production cuts from the Dutch Groningen gas field. </p>
<p>Front-month gas on the U.K.''s National Balancing Point fell
46 percent this year to 37.15 pence a therm as Europe''s mildest
winter in seven years left high inventories, according to broker
data compiled by Bloomberg. Prices may fall to average 33 pence
in the next three months in order for coal to gas switching to
balance the market, Goldman forecasts. </p>
<p>Prices may decline further if balancing the market requires
power plants in northwest Europe to also switch to gas, the bank
said. That could happen if U.K. generators don''t switch to using
gas quickly enough or due to strong growth in renewables.
Prices would need to drop below 30 pence a therm before gas-fired units in northwest Europe could compete with coal on a
large scale. </p>
<h2>Price Forecasts </h2>
<p>U.K. gas prices will probably average 34.2 pence in the
third quarter, which will be sufficient to correct its storage
overhang, Goldman said. While the usage of gas at the expense
of coal in Germany starts to be profitable at 32 pence, prices
need to fall further to kick-start this demand in the short
run, according to the report. </p>
<p>Northwest European inventories have an excess of 4 billion
cubic meters (142 billion cubic feet) of gas over 2012 levels,
the bank said. Without coal-to-gas switching or an escalation in
tensions between Russia and Ukraine the surplus will be 2.7
billion cubic meters above 2012 levels at the end of October, it
said. It would take 24 million cubic meters a day of incremental
demand through October to alleviate the glut. </p>
<p>The U.K. has spare gas-fired power capacity to increase
demand for the fuel by 40 million cubic meters a day, according
to the report. Switching to gas for European power generation to
deplete excess gas inventories would result in thermal coal
demand loss of about 5 million metric tons, which could add
further pressure on prices already trading near a multiyear
low, the bank said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Barinka" date="Jul 23, 2014 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-23/ibm-introduces-watson-to-consumers-in-service-for-usaa-clients.html"><headline>IBM Introduces Watson to Consumers in Service for USAA Clients</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM) is putting its Watson natural-language technology to the
test with consumers on a wide scale for the first time. </p>
<p>On the website of financial-services firm USAA, military
customers will be able to use IBM''s tool to ask questions and
seek advice on transitioning back to civilian life. Famous for
being a Jeopardy! game-show champion, Watson analyzes
information and can answer questions in conversational English. </p>
<p>The USAA deal gives IBM its biggest test yet of whether
consumers will embrace Watson, a technology that''s become a
bigger focus of the company''s investments and marketing. IBM
sees data analytics tools like Watson as a source of growth to
counter declining demand for hardware that has led to nine
straight quarters of falling sales. </p>
<p>Traditional methods of providing advice and information
aren''t scaling, John Gordon, vice president of IBM''s Watson
Group, said in an interview. This is a fundamentally different
approach. </p>
<p>While Watson has previously been available to consumers in
some limited tests, such as a mobile application for home cooks,
this is the first service to be widely available, Gordon said. </p>
<p>IBM and USAA, based in San Antonio, worked for about nine
months to develop the tool to answer questions specific to
customers leaving the military, like whether to seek out
veteran''s benefits or how to buy a home, said Eric Engquist,
assistant vice president of military transitions at USAA. More
than 150,000 military members transfer to civilian life a year,
Engquist said. </p>
<h2>Behavior Change </h2>
<p>While persuading customers to turn to a technology for life
coaching will certainly require a change in behavior, the
tool could give customized, 24-hour access that wasn''t possible
with USAA''s website or its employees, Engquist said. It could
also be a test for expanding Watson''s use more broadly at USAA. </p>
<p>As sluggish demand for computer servers has hurt sales, IBM
has focused on more profitable, faster-growing areas such as
data analytics and cloud computing while selling hardware
businesses. </p>
<p>Last year, IBM boosted its expected sales from the data-analysis business to $20 billion in 2015, compared with an
earlier forecast of $16 billion. The company said in January
that it will spend $1 billion to create a new division around
Watson to help spur growth. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Cristiane Lucchesi, Jonathan Levin and Dinesh Nair" date="Jul 24, 2014 11:01 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-24/goldman-adia-said-to-weigh-joining-gavea-in-snagged-fleury-deal.html"><headline>Goldman, ADIA Said to Weigh Joining Gavea in Snagged Fleury Deal</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)''s private-equity arm and Abu Dhabi Investment Authority are considering
joining Gavea Investimentos Ltda. in a bid for Brazilian
medical-services company Fleury SA (FLRY3), people with knowledge of the
matter said. </p>
<p>In joining Gavea, the two investors would be wading into a
bid for a company that has been on the market for more than six
months. Fleury, which has a market value of about 2.6 billion
reais ($1.2 billion), said in March that it was in exclusive
talks with Gavea. </p>
<p>The deal has been held up, as Gavea''s partners in Instituto
Hermes Pardini Ltda. -- a closely held medical lab company that
would be merged with Fleury -- have sought a greater role in the
combined company, three people said, asking not to be identified
discussing private information. It''s still possible that a deal
won''t be reached, the people said. </p>
<p>Rising incomes in Latin America''s most populous country
mean more people are leaving the public health system in favor
of private care. That''s prompting investors to seek ways to
profit from the growing pool of health-care consumers, spurring
deals including the takeover of Amil Participacoes SA by
UnitedHealth Group Inc. last year. </p>
<p>Spokesmen for Fleury, Gavea, Goldman Sachs, ADIA and Hermes
Pardini declined to comment. Gavea, JPMorgan Chase  Co.''s
Brazil private-equity and hedge-fund unit, owns a 30 percent
stake in Hermes Pardini. </p>
<p>Shares of Sao Paulo-based Fleury have retreated 10 percent
this year as the deal has dragged on. Amid the negotiations,
Fleury also posted a net loss in the fourth quarter and missed
sales estimates, further dragging on the stock. </p>
<h2>Pardini Family </h2>
<p>The Pardini family, which controls Hermes Pardini, wants a
higher valuation for their company and a greater role in running
the combined business, the people said. Aurea Pardini, a member
of the family, recently retained financial adviser Greenhill 
Co., while other Pardinis are working with Moelis  Co. to
negotiate those points, the person said. </p>
<p>The family stake at Hermes Pardini could be valued at 1.5
billion reais, one person said. </p>
<p>Banco Itau BBA SA is lining up a four-bank syndicated loan
for Gavea, Goldman and ADIA, one person said. JPMorgan Chase 
Co. is advising Core Participaes SA, the holding company that
controls Fleury. Any acquirer of Fleury would have to make an
offer to buy out the minority shareholders'' stakes at the same
price paid to the controlling stakeholders. </p>
<p>Spokesmen for Itau, Greenhill, and Moelis declined to
comment. Exame earlier reported that the Pardini family is
holding up the deal. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jul 24, 2014  5:36 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-24/goldman-names-ogunlesi-lead-director-as-schiro-retires.html"><headline>Goldman Names Ogunlesi Lead Director as Schiro Retires</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) named
Adebayo O. Ogunlesi as lead director of its board after James Schiro retired to undergo treatment for multiple myeloma. </p>
<p>Ogunlesi, chairman of Global Infrastructure Partners who
joined Goldman Sachs''s board in 2012, also will lead the
corporate governance, nominating and public responsibilities
committee, the New York-based company said today in a statement.
Ogunlesi, 60, was previously head of the risk committee, a role
that will be filled by Michele Burns. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs gave expanded responsibilities to its lead
independent director last year, including setting the board''s
agenda and writing a letter to shareholders in the annual proxy
statement, as part of an agreement with an investor to drop a
proposal that called for an independent board chairman. Chief
Executive Officer Lloyd C. Blankfein also serves as chairman. </p>
<p>Jim Schiro defined what an effective lead director is
through a strong model of corporate governance, and I intend to
follow his extraordinary example, Ogunlesi said in the
statement. </p>
<p>Multiple myeloma is a cancer in white blood cells that
disproportionately affects older people. About 100,000 people in
the U.S. are diagnosed each year with blood cancers, including
leukemia and lymphoma, according to the U.S. Centers for Disease
Control and Prevention in Atlanta. </p>
<p>Schiro, 68, a former CEO of PricewaterhouseCoopers LLP and
Zurich Financial Services AG, joined Goldman Sachs''s board in
2009. He also resigned today from the board of PepsiCo Inc. </p>
<h2>Infrastructure Investments </h2>
<p>Ogunlesi, who was born in Nigeria, previously was head of
global investment banking at Credit Suisse Group AG before his
current role at Global Infrastructure Partners, a private-equity
firm. GIP manages about $18.7 billion and has led an acquisition
of Gatwick Airport Ltd. in the U.K. and had a stake in
Australia''s Port of Brisbane. </p>
<p>Burns, formerly the chief financial officer of Delta Air
Lines Inc. and CEO of the Retirement Policy Center, has served
on the board of directors since 2011. She was head of the
board''s audit committee, and will be replaced in that role by
Apple Inc. CFO Peter Oppenheimer, who joined the board in March. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs''s board of directors now has 12 members, nine
of which are designated as independent. The lead director is
elected by the independent members. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elizabeth Dexheimer" date="Jul 24, 2014  4:09 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-24/visa-profit-beats-estimates-as-card-spending-climbs.html"><headline>Visa Profit Beats Estimates as Card Spending Climbs</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Visa Inc. (V), the world''s largest
payments network, posted a fiscal third-quarter profit that beat
analysts'' estimates as card spending increased. </p>
<p>Net income for the three months ended June 30 rose 11
percent to $1.36 billion, or $2.17 a share, from $1.23 billion,
or $1.88, a year earlier, the Foster City, California-based
company said today in a statement. The average estimate of 30
analysts surveyed by Bloomberg was for adjusted profit of $2.10. </p>
<p>Visa is benefiting as consumers globally replace cash with
credit and debit cards. Chief Executive Officer Charlie Scharf,
49, has focused on strengthening relationships with retailers,
developing technologies to enable digital payments and working
with governments to expand the firm''s reach outside the U.S. </p>
<p>Visa''s business is characterized by recurring revenues,
high incremental margins, low capital expenditures and high free
cash flow, Tien-tsin Huang, a JPMorgan Chase  Co. analyst,
wrote in a July 23 note. The company is a relative safe haven
against macro uncertainty. </p>
<p>The shares rose 0.7 percent to $222.74 at 4 p.m. in New
York and have gained 0.3 percent this year. MasterCard Inc. (MA), the
second-largest payments network, has slid 7.2 percent since Dec.
31. </p>
<p>Discover Financial Services, the fourth-largest payments
network, said July 22 that profit rose 7 percent to $644 million
as card spending increased. American Express Co., the biggest
card issuer by purchases, is scheduled to report earnings on
July 29, with MasterCard following two days later. </p>
<h2>Russia Tensions </h2>
<p>After the U.S. imposed sanctions against Russia in March,
Russian President Vladimir Putin recommended his country create
its own payments system. Visa -- which generates about 2 percent
of its revenue from Russia -- said the tensions may trim
several pennies from this year''s earnings. </p>
<p>The company this month introduced Visa Checkout, which it
said will allow consumers to make purchases faster online. The
product replaces V.me, a digital wallet that Scharf described as
not friendly for clients in a May conference call. </p>
<p>Visa is late to the quick checkout game, Huang said in
a July 16 research note. But it is one of only a few companies
that could establish critical mass given its payment share,
marketing budget and brand equity. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jul 24, 2014  3:12 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-24/morgan-stanley-outlook-lifted-to-postive-as-risk-cut.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Outlook Lifted to Postive as Risk Cut</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) had its credit rating
outlook raised to positive from neutral by Moody''s Investors
Service, two years after the ratings company cut the bank''s
grade by two levels. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley, which topped analysts'' estimates when it
announced second-quarter results last week, has made sustainable
improvements to profitability and lowered risk in its trading
unit, Moody''s said today in a statement. New York-based Morgan
Stanley''s senior debt rating is Baa2, two levels above junk, and
may be upgraded in the medium-term, Moody''s said. </p>
<p>To the extent Morgan Stanley can demonstrate additional,
sustainable progress in growing its profitability without
increasing its risk profile, this could result in a ratings
upgrade, Moody''s Senior Vice President David Fanger said in
the statement. </p>
<p>In 2012, Moody''s threatened to downgrade Morgan Stanley''s
rating by three levels, the most among the biggest U.S. banks,
citing a difficult operating environment and greater regulation.
Moody''s only reduced it two levels after Morgan Stanley Chief
Executive Officer James Gorman made the case that the steeper
cut wasn''t warranted. Still, the bank said some clients stopped
trading with it while the review was pending. </p>
<p>In November, Moody''s cut the grade by an additional level
after deciding the government would be less inclined to help
Morgan Stanley repay creditors in a crisis. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jody Shenn" date="Jul 24, 2014 12:37 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-24/jpmorgan-seen-facing-bigger-fight-with-mortgage-investors.html"><headline>JPMorgan Seen Facing Bigger Fight With Mortgage Investors</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) may need to pay
more than the $4.5 billion it offered to settle investor claims
over faulty mortgages packaged into securities before the U.S.
housing crash, a report prepared for bond trustees shows. </p>
<p>Trustees should reject the accord struck last November with
a group of bondholders for 16 of the 330 deals included, and
it''s a close call for three others, according to the report
posted online this week by Daniel Fischel, president of Compass
Lexecon, which is among firms hired by the securities
administrators to help evaluate the offer. </p>
<p>Based on the reports by the expert advisors, there exists
a meaningful possibility that trustees may not accept the
proposed settlement offer for all 330 trusts, Nomura Holdings
Inc. analysts including Paul Nikodem and Pratik K. Gupta wrote
yesterday in a research note. </p>
<p>JPMorgan negotiated the proposed settlement with 21
institutional investors including BlackRock Inc. (BLK) and Pacific
Investment Management Co. in a bid to move past legal troubles
tied in part to the housing crisis. The accord was announced the
week before the largest U.S. bank agreed to a record $13 billion
settlement with government agencies over faulty mortgage
securities. </p>
<h2>Extended Deadline </h2>
<p>Trustees including Deutsche Bank AG, Wells Fargo  Co. and
Bank of New York Mellon Corp. must decide whether to accept
JPMorgan''s proposal by Aug. 1. The deadline has been pushed back
at least twice from an original date of March 16. </p>
<p>Brian Marchiony, a spokesman for New York-based JPMorgan,
declined to comment, as did Jen Hibbard of Wells Fargo, Kevin Heine of Bank of New York and Renee Calabro of Deutsche Bank.
Kathy Patrick, a lawyer at Gibbs  Bruns LLP representing the
investors who negotiated the deal, didn''t immediately respond to
an e-mail seeking comment. </p>
<p>Hedge fund Fir Tree Partners has said it will seek to
continue separate lawsuits over some of the securities. Law firm
Quinn Emanuel Urquhart  Sullivan LLP is also representing a
group of investors objecting to the agreement for at least some
deals, according to Fischel, also a professor of law and
business emeritus at the University of Chicago Law School. </p>
<h2>Improper Servicing </h2>
<p>The accord sparked claims that JPMorgan and Bear Stearns
Cos., which it bought in 2008, needed to repurchase mortgages
whose quality was misrepresented, as well as pay for mishandling
loans once they''re made. Another expert, Boston Portfolio
Advisors Inc., said in its report the improper servicing boosted
losses by $4 billion and disclosed that many of the loans are
already managed by a separate subservicer, limiting the
benefits to investors of transfers to such entities as called
for by the deal, according to Nomura. </p>
<p> Bank of America Corp., the second-biggest U.S. bank, has
faced opposition in court over an $8.5 billion settlement that
it reached in 2011 with bondholders represented by Gibbs  Bruns
and Bank of New York, as the trustee for more than 500
transactions. A New York state judge largely approved the deal
in January, though the ruling is being appealed by investors
seeking a bigger payout. </p>
<p>The Charlotte, North Carolina-based bank said this month it
would pay $650 million to American International Group Inc., one
of the objectors to the agreement that had also filed a separate
suit over mortgage securities created by Countrywide Financial
Corp., the lender bought by Bank of America in 2008. </p>
<h2>No Windfall'' </h2>
<p>While the proposed JPMorgan settlement is relatively small,
compared with other mortgage-bond agreements, evidence from
markets suggest that it wouldn''t be a windfall for the bank,
Fischel wrote. </p>
<p>The amount offered represents 6.6 percent of past and
potential losses on loans underlying the bonds, compared with
10.8 percent in the Bank of America deal, Barclays Plc analysts
estimated in November. After a $55 million payment by Wells
Fargo to an individual bond trust this year, investors recovered
32 percent of past and future losses, according to Nomura. </p>
<p>Fatan Sabry, an economist at National Economic Research
Associates Inc., wrote in a report for trustees that JPMorgan''s
planned payment exceeds potential losses from violations of so-called representation and warranties under several estimation
methods. </p>
<p>Anthony J. Carpinello, a former New York State Supreme
Court justice, said in a report that the statute of limitations
for all the 330 deals has been extended, which could bolster any
separate demands from investors reluctant to take part in the
accord, according to Nomura. JPMorgan contends that the
extension only applies to some of the deals, according to a
website set up by trustees. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Barinka" date="Jul 24, 2014 12:30 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-24/ibm-wins-deal-to-supply-cloud-computing-to-california-agencies.html"><headline>IBM Wins Deal to Supply Cloud Computing to California Agencies</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM) will supply cloud services to the government of
California, letting more than 400 state and local agencies save
money by pooling their computing resources. </p>
<p>IBM will store data and software on remote servers in a
service called CalCloud, available to all state and local
government bodies, the company said today in a statement. The
arrangement lets agencies pay only for the computing workload
they need. </p>
<p>IBM is counting on cloud computing for growth after nine
straight quarters of declining revenue, dragged down by weak
demand for hardware and falling sales in markets like China.
Cloud technology has been a conundrum for the Armonk, New York-based company because it can reduce demand for hardware, since
companies rent computing power rather than assembling their own
data centers. </p>
<p>The company competes for cloud-computing clients with
Oracle Corp. (ORCL), Microsoft Corp. and Amazon.com Inc., to which IBM
lost a $600 million contract with the U.S. Central Intelligence
Agency last year. </p>
<p>Because government customers have additional data-security
needs, they''ve been slower than corporations in moving to the
cloud because it means surrendering some control over managing
the technology. IBM said it designed CalCloud to comply with the
requirements of the Internal Revenue Service, Social Security
and the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act. </p>
<p>CalCloud is an important step towards providing faster
and more cost-effective IT services to California state
departments and ultimately to the citizens of California,
Marybel Batjer, secretary of the Government Operations Agency,
said in the statement. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Davis" date="Jul 24, 2014 12:29 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-24/goldman-raises-nickel-price-forecast-as-deficit-looms-amid-ban.html"><headline>Goldman Raises Nickel Price Forecast as Deficit Looms Amid Ban</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. raised its
price forecast for nickel as the market is swinging to a deficit
next year following an ore-export ban in Indonesia. </p>
<p>The bank''s 12-month estimate is now $22,000 a metric ton,
up 38 percent from the previous projection of $16,000, analysts
led by Max Layton wrote in a report. They increased zinc and
aluminum by at least 11 percent to $2,500 a ton and $2,100 a
ton, respectively, saying iron ore, gold and copper have the
greatest downside among the mining commodities. </p>
<p>Goldman joins Morgan Stanley and Citigroup Inc. in boosting
the outlook for nickel, already the best-performing base metal
on the London Metal Exchange this year, as supplies are
declining after the Indonesian restriction in January. The
global nickel market will be in deficit of 201,000 tons next
year from an estimated 20,000 ton surplus this year, with demand
exceeding supply for aluminum and zinc this year, Goldman said. </p>
<p>Nickel is being boosted by the attempts of a large
producer (Indonesia) to encourage value-add capacity
domestically, the Goldman analysts said in the report dated
yesterday. We have raised out already bullish zinc, nickel and
aluminum forecasts, and lowered our copper forecasts, reflecting
a quick-than-anticipated shift in the relative fundamentals of
these commodities. </p>
<p>The ban by Indonesia, which accounted for more than 20
percent of global nickel supply in 2013, is unlikely to be eased
until the second half of 2015, Goldman said. </p>
<p>Nickel for delivery in three months on the LME rose 0.7
percent to $19,180 a ton by 11:10 a.m. in Hong Kong, up 38
percent this year. The metal touched $21,625 a ton on May 13,
the highest since February 2012. </p>
<h2>Indonesian Ban </h2>
<p>Earlier this month, Bank of America Corp. raised its 2014
forecast to $18,616, citing the ban and the possible reduction
of Chinese nickel pig iron output. Citigroup raised its 2014
average forecast to $18,550 and Morgan Stanley said the metal
will average $17,640 this year and $19,346 next year. </p>
<p>The global aluminum market has moved into deficit of
579,000 tons this year, with the gap increasing to 619,000 tons
next year, while zinc will have deficit of 154,000 tons in 2015,
according to the Goldman report. </p>
<p>A cyclical upswing in demand in combination with low
supply growth, following years of underinvestment in new
capacity outside of China, has seen zinc and aluminum
outperform in the first half of 2014, said the Goldman
analysts. </p>
<p>Goldman cut the 12-month estimate for copper to $6,200 a
ton from $6,600 previously due to rising production and exposure
to weak property market in China. </p>
<p>Among precious metals, palladium remains the preferred
metal, with prices averaging $925 an ounce in 2015 and rising to
$1,000 in 2016, according to the bank. It reiterated a call for
gold to drop to $1,050 by the end of 2014 as the U.S. economic
recovery accelerates. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ye Xie" date="Jul 25, 2014  8:30 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-25/goldman-sees-wider-ruble-band-after-rate-boost.html"><headline>Goldman Sees Wider Ruble Band After Rate Boost</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Russia''s surprise interest rate
increase paves the way for policy makers to widen the band in
which the currency trades and reduces the need to intervene,
according to Goldman Sachs Group Inc. </p>
<p>The ruble has tumbled almost 4 percent against the dollar
in the past month, the worst performance among 24 emerging-market currencies tracked by Bloomberg, after President Vladimir
Putin''s annexation of Crimea spurred violence along the border
with Ukraine. Bank Rossii boosted the one-week auction rate to 8
percent from 7.5 percent yesterday and may keep raising
borrowing costs as currency weakness spurs inflation, according
to a central bank statement. </p>
<p>The decision gives the bank room to make its exchange-rate
policy more flexible as it moves towards a free-floating rate by
year-end, according to New York-based Goldman Sachs. Enabling
the ruble to strengthen will aid the central bank in its fight
against price increases. </p>
<p>The surprise rate change makes it likely that the central
bank will proceed with further steps towards introduction of
currency flexibility in the short term, with a decision to
reduce the cumulative interventions needed to shift the
intervention corridor, for example, likely as early as next
week, economists led by Clemens Grafe at Goldman Sachs in
Moscow wrote in a note yesterday. </p>
<h2>Wider Band </h2>
<p>The central bank widened the corridor within which it will
not intervene to 5.1 rubles, up from 3.1 rubles last month. It
is required to buy or sell dollars to keep the ruble inside that
range. It aims to abolish the band by year-end. </p>
<p>Russia spent $30.7 billion between Feb. 28 and May 8 to
stem the ruble''s decline. Since then, it hasn''t sold dollars to
support its currency. The country''s foreign reserves fell $39
billion to $472 billion in June, according to central bank data. </p>
<p>Consumer prices grew 7.8 percent from a year earlier in
June, the most since August 2011. Inflation slowed on an annual
basis to 7.5 percent as of July 21, the central bank said,
adding that it will probably decelerate to a range of 6 percent
to 6.5 percent by year-end. </p>
<p>The ruble slipped 0.5 percent to 35.1435 per dollar
yesterday, extending its decline this year to 6.5 percent. </p>
<p>Russia''s policy makers are aiming to let the ruble decline
because a weaker currency will increase the government''s revenue
from energy exports, according to Ian Hague, who helps manage
$1.1 billion including Russian stocks as the founding partner of
New York-based Firebird Management. </p>
<p>We expect the ruble to depreciate, Hague said in a
phone interview yesterday. They are just plugging the holes. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ian King and Alex Barinka" date="Jul 25, 2014  4:26 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-25/ibm-said-to-reject-globalfoundries-offer-for-chip-unit.html"><headline>IBM Said to Reject Globalfoundries Offer for Chip Unit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines Corp. (IBM)''s talks to sell its money-losing chip-manufacturing operations to Globalfoundries Inc. have ended after the two companies failed to agree on terms, according to people familiar with the process. </p> <p>Globalfoundries, owned by an investment arm of the government of Abu Dhabi, made an offer that was rejected by IBM as too low, said the people, who asked not to be identified because the negotiations are private. James Sciales, a spokesman for IBM, and Kevin Kimball, a spokesman for Santa Clara, California-based Globalfoundries, both declined to comment on speculation. </p> <p>The breakdown of the talks is a setback for IBM Chief Executive Officer Ginni Rometty as she attempts to meet 2015 earnings goals by shedding less profitable units and reversing nine straight quarters of revenue declines. Globalfoundries, which has its own plant in New York state, had placed little or no value on IBM''s factories because they are too old, the person said. </p> <p>IBM shares fell 0.4 percent to $194.40 at the close in New York. The stock has risen 3.6 percent this year. </p> <p>Last month, Bloomberg News reported that Globalfoundries was primarily interested in acquiring IBM''s engineers and intellectual property rather than manufacturing facilities, according to people with knowledge of the matter. Globalfoundries would have acted as a supplier for IBM''s microprocessors, the people said at the time. </p>




Photographer: Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
The breakdown of the talks is a setback for IBM Chief Executive Officer Ginni Rometty as she attempts to meet 2015 earnings goals by shedding less profitable units and reversing nine straight quarters of revenue declines. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Katia Dmitrieva" date="Jul 25, 2014  2:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-25/goldman-sachs-hires-mccann-gaspar-joins-brookfield-vlaad-says.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Hires McCann, Gaspar Joins Brookfield, Vlaad Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Neil McCann joined Goldman Sachs
Group Inc. as a vice president of investment banking from
Alberta Investment Management Corp., where he was a portfolio
manager, according to Vlaad and Co., a Toronto-based financial-services recruiting firm. </p>
<p>Other moves in the Bill''s Buzz weekly newsletter
include: </p>
<p>* Benjamin Gaspar, previously with Bank of America Merrill Lynch
as a director of investment banking, joined Brookfield Financial
LLC as a partner. </p>
<p>* Avi Dalfen joined Octagon Capital Corp. as a managing director
of investment banking in clean technology and diversified
industries. He was previously an equity-research analyst at
Macquarie Group Ltd. </p>
<p>* Canadian Imperial Bank of Commerce added Tuc Tuncay as a
director of investment banking, power and utilities. Tuncay was
previously an associate analyst of equity research for energy
infrastructure at Bank of Nova Scotia. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jul 26, 2014 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-26/goldman-sachs-said-in-talks-to-settle-fhfa-mortgage-suit.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Said in Talks to Settle FHFA Mortgage Suit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) is in talks to settle a U.S. regulator''s claims the investment bank sold faulty mortgage-backed securities to Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac and will probably pay $800 million to $1.25 billion, according to a person briefed on the discussions. </p> <p>The high end of the range would be on par with the agreement Morgan Stanley (MS) reached this year after being sued over a similar amount of mortgage bonds as New York-based Goldman Sachs. The final amount may change as an agreement is reached, said the person, who asked not to be identified because the settlement talks are private. </p> <p>The Federal Housing Finance Agency sued 18 banks in 2011 seeking to recoup taxpayer costs from when the government took control of the failing mortgage-finance companies in 2008. Seven banks, including JPMorgan Chase  Co. and Deutsche Bank AG, agreed to pay a total of almost $8 billion last year to settle claims they made misrepresentations about mortgages underlying securities bought by Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac in the lead-up to the credit crisis. </p> <p>The $800 million figure would surpass Goldman Sachs''s $550 million payment in 2010 to settle a Securities and Exchange Commission suit over the marketing of a synthetic collateralized debt obligation dubbed Abacus 2007-AC1. </p> <p>Still, Goldman''s cost could be lower than what rival banks paid, as a percentage of the face value of securities bought by Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac. The FHFA said in its original suit that the two companies bought $11.1 billion from Goldman Sachs, and an $800 million settlement would be 7.2 percent of that total. Some banks have settled at amounts that represented between 12 percent and 20 percent. </p> <h2>JPMorgan, BofA </h2> <p>Morgan Stanley in February agreed to pay $1.25 billion as part of a settlement over $10.6 billion in securities. JPMorgan agreed last year to pay $4 billion to settle claims related to about $33 billion in mortgage bonds. </p> <p>Bank of America Corp. in March announced a $9.5 billion accord, including paying $6.3 billion in cash to Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac and buying back $3.2 billion of mortgage bonds from them. The housing finance companies bought about $57 billion of bonds from Bank of America and its predecessor firms. </p> <p>David Wells, a spokesman for Goldman Sachs, didn''t return messages after normal business hours seeking comment on the possible range of costs, which was previously reported by the Wall Street Journal. Stefanie Johnson, an FHFA spokeswoman, said the agency wouldn''t comment on the Goldman Sachs case. </p> <p>U.S. District Court Judge Denise Cote in Manhattan has set a Sept. 29 trial date for Goldman Sachs. All but four of the FHFA cases have settled, Cote said yesterday in a ruling. The remaining cases involve Goldman Sachs, HSBC North America Holdings Inc., Nomura Holding America Inc. and RBS Securities Inc., she said. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs said earlier this month that it set aside $284 million in the second quarter for litigation and regulatory proceedings, up from $149 million a year earlier. </p> <p>Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac have taken $187.5 billion in U.S. aid and have returned more than $200 billion under terms of their federal conservatorship. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bob Van Voris" date="Jul 28, 2014  6:29 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-28/goldman-sachs-denies-ex-employee-claims-of-sex-bias.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Denies Ex-Employee Claims of Sex Bias</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) denied
gender bias in compensation and tolerating a boys'' club
atmosphere of excessive drinking and strip-club trips as it
sought to quash a bid to unite female associates and vice
presidents in a class action for discrimination. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs rejected claims by former employees Cristina
Chen-Oster and Shanna Orlich, opposing their court request to
expand a lawsuit to represent more than 2,300 current and former
female associates and vice presidents who worked at Goldman
Sachs in the past decade. </p>
<p>To be clear: Goldman Sachs does not tolerate
discrimination of any kind, the firm said in papers filed July
25 in Manhattan federal court. </p>
<p>Chen-Oster and Orlich, who sued in 2010, claim they have
expert statistical analyses that showed a pattern of
discrimination against women in earnings and promotions. They
alleged that the bank tolerated a work environment where women
are treated as second-class employees. </p>
<p>About 36 percent of professionals employed by New York-based Goldman Sachs are women, the firm said on its website,
citing August 2013 figures. Women constitute 23 percent of
officials and managers, and 21 percent of executive and senior
officials and managers, the firm said. </p>
<h2>Percentages </h2>
<p>The former Goldman Sachs employees cited their own
percentages in court filings. They claimed female vice
presidents earned 21 percent less than men, and female
associates made 8 percent less. About 23 percent fewer female
vice presidents were promoted to managing director relative to
their male counterparts, they said in their complaint. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs asked U.S. District Judge Analisa Torres to
rule that Chen-Oster and Orlich should pursue their claims
individually, rather than as representatives of all female
Goldmans Sachs associates and vice presidents. Plaintiffs have
more leverage in class actions because they can pool legal
resources, more easily forcing a settlement. </p>
<p>The bank argued that the women haven''t shown a general
policy of discrimination or evidence that women were affected
negatively as a class. Their allegations are individual claims
that don''t apply to the other women, Goldman Sachs said. </p>
<h2>Denials </h2>
<p>The bank also specifically denied many of the allegations
in the complaint, including claims that male employees took
clients to strip clubs. </p>
<p>The firm said it prohibits employees from business outings
involving sexually oriented entertainment, such as
entertainment at topless bars or lap-dancing bars. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs also submitted statements from female
employees who said they haven''t been discriminated against or
subject to harassment. </p>
<p>The firm said it has conducted diversity training programs
for 20 years. </p>
<p>I have never heard anyone even mention the
possibility of going to a strip club, Samantha Davidson, an
extended managing director, said in a written declaration. I
do not feel excluded from social events, such as events with
clients and informal get-togethers after work with co-workers,
including golf events. </p>
<p>The case is Chen-Oster v. Goldman Sachs  Co., 10-cv-06950,
U.S. District Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bloomberg News" date="Jul 28, 2014  4:05 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-28/microsoft-s-china-offices-visited-by-regulator-sina-reports.html"><headline>Microsoft China Target of Potential Probe, Sina Reports</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chinese regulators met with managers
at Microsoft Corp. (MSFT)''s offices in four cities including Beijing
and Shanghai in preparation for a potential probe into whether
the company engaged in monopolistic practices, Sina.com said. </p>
<p>State Administration for Industry and Commerce officials
also called on Microsoft in Guangzhou and Chengdu yesterday, the
news portal said on its website, citing a Microsoft China
employee it didn''t identify. </p>
<p>Regulators may start a probe into Microsoft''s possible
monopoly in China''s operating system market, Sina.com added,
citing another unidentified person. China is stepping up
scrutiny of U.S. technology companies, and excluded Windows 8
from a government purchasing order in May. U.S. tensions with
China escalated after prosecutors indicted five Chinese military
officers for allegedly stealing secrets of American companies. </p>
<p>Microsoft is happy to answer the government''s
questions, the company said in an e-mailed statement
yesterday, without confirming whether authorities had visited
its local offices in China. </p>
<p>The shares of Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft fell 1.2
percent to $43.97 at the close in New York, leaving them up 18
percent this year. </p>
<p>China said in May it will vet technology companies for
potential national security breaches, after the government
threatened retaliation for a U.S. indictment of Chinese military
officers on cyberspying claims. </p>




Photographer: Nelson Ching/Bloomberg

<p>
Employees work inside Microsoft Corp.''s China headquarters in Beijing, China. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Barinka" date="Jul 28, 2014  3:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-28/ibm-at-t-build-technology-to-move-data-fast-in-disaster.html"><headline>IBM, AT&amp;amp;T Build Technology to Move Data Fast in Disaster</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>When hurricanes come barreling toward land, people, airplanes and ships are relocated to avoid destruction. Now some of the world''s biggest technology companies are making advances in figuring out how to quickly move large amounts of critical data and software out of harm''s way, too. </p> <p>ATT Inc. (T), International Business Machines Corp. (IBM), and Applied Communications Sciences have created a prototype technology to reduce the time needed to connect remote networks from days to seconds. Part of a seven-year program from the U.S. government''s Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency, the latest innovation from the partnership could allow large amounts of information and software to be more quickly shifted between private and public data centers, as well as between cloud services from different providers. </p> <p>Moving data and software to another location could be crucial in coping with events like natural disasters and terrorist attacks as governments and companies have become increasingly reliant on servers, both on premise and in remote locations, to handle their information. The U.S. Department of Defense has expressed interest in the research, IBM said in an e-mail. </p> <p>The key idea here is to have a highly dynamic backbone network, said Adel Saleh, a research professor in electrical and computer engineering at the University of California, Santa Barbara, and a former DARPA project manager. If the network is under physical attack or cyberattack, you can recover from this quickly. </p> <h2>Remaining Hurdles </h2> <p>While many companies and governments already keep data remotely to have redundant systems, the companies'' prototype would let them reconfigure on the fly to handle changes in needs, such as computing bandwidth. </p> <p>The ability to use capacity only when needed could also make cloud computing less expensive, Saleh said in a phone interview. </p> <p>The partnership between ATT, IBM and ACS is a part of a DARPA program called Coronet that was started in 2007 to protect networks against catastrophic failures, in order to help keep the Internet and government services up and running. </p> <p>The technology is still in the proof-of-concept phase, said Dave McQueeney, vice president of computing as a service at IBM Research. Changes would have to be made to optical fiber networks -- including the addition of new switches -- for it to be adopted more broadly, he said. Work also needs to be done within cloud systems to accommodate the connections, McQueeney said. </p> <p>If these changes are made, the technology could be used in military technology infrastructures and eventually for commercial use. </p> <p>Every client I talk to doesn''t want to put all of their IT in one place, McQueeney said. One of the long poles of the tent that needed to get solved was very, very rapid provisioning of huge amounts of bandwidth. Now we can have a vision of a multiple-cloud, hybrid environment where the networking is likely not the main bottleneck. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lulu Yilun Chen" date="Jul 28, 2014  7:03 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-28/microsoft-taps-tencent-and-jd-com-for-xbox-sales-in-china.html"><headline>Microsoft First Out of the Xbox After China''s Ban Falls</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>It''s game on in China, as Microsoft Corp.''s (MSFT) Xbox One becomes the first entertainment console to hit the market after the end of a 13-year ban. </p> <p>Microsoft today began taking orders for its new game console from online retailer JD.com Inc. (JD) via Tencent Holdings Ltd.''s (700) mobile-messaging applications. The pair of Chinese Internet companies hold exclusive rights to pre-sell the locally made Xbox One until July 30, JD.com said in a news release. The console is slated to ship nationwide in September. </p> <p>Microsoft was the industry''s first big player to start production in the country after the Chinese government last year allowed console sales in the new Shanghai free-trade zone and opened up an estimated $10 billion market. The first Xbox didn''t even exist in 2000, when the Communist Party banned game systems over concern they would be bad for kids. It was released a year later. </p> <p>The potential market for Xbox in China is huge, there''s a lot of prospects for growth, said Bill Fan, a Hong Kong-based analyst at China Securities Co. Tencent could cooperate with Microsoft on games in the future, and Xbox can utilize Tencent and JD.com''s distribution channels to generate more sales. </p> <p>Tencent shares rose 3.2 percent to close at HK$128.90 in Hong Kong. Microsoft has gained about 19 percent this year, compared with a 7 percent rise for the SP 500 Index. Microsoft shares rose 0.2 percent to $44.50 in New York yesterday. </p> <h2>Entry Points </h2> <p>The Xbox One pre-orders on JD.com require a deposit of 499 yuan (US$81), and will only be available to those who use the Chinese versions of Tencent''s WeChat and QQ mobile-messaging apps. </p> <p>JD.com spokesman Josh Gartner wouldn''t disclose the number of Xbox Ones the company was selling nor the price. </p> <p>Launching Xbox One sales in China through JD.com''s Weixin and Mobile QQ entry points underscores the strength of these platforms with young and sophisticated Chinese consumers, Du Shuang, vice president of JD.com, said in the news release, using the Chinese name for Tencent''s WeChat. </p> <p>JD.com will begin directly accepting pre-orders for the new Xbox through its website and its exhibition booth at the ChinaJoy Expo in Shanghai on July 31, the company said. </p> <h2>Trade Zone </h2> <p>Game consoles were included on the list of items to be liberalized before Shanghai''s free-trade zone before its creation last September. </p> <p>Around the same time, Microsoft formed a $79 million joint venture with BesTV New Media Co. (600637), a unit of Shanghai Media Group Inc., to begin making Xbox consoles in the free-trade zone for the Chinese market. BesTV invested $40.3 million for a 51 percent stake in the enterprise, while Microsoft put in $38.7 million, according a September filing. </p> <p>The State Council, China''s cabinet, has since temporarily lifted the ban nationwide and announced plans to draft new rules on their sale. The country''s video-game industry will generate about $10 billion in sales next year, according to PricewaterhouseCoopers LLP. </p> <p>Sony Corp. (6758) has similarly agreed to form two ventures with the Shanghai Oriental Pearl (Group) Co., to start making PlayStation consoles in China. Nintendo Co. plans to expand in emerging markets with new devices starting next year, the company''s president, Satoru Iwata, said on May 8. </p> <p>Microsoft has been chasing Sony for dominance in the U.S. video-game console market. It introduced a lower-priced version of its Xbox One costing $399 on June 9 to narrow a $100 price difference with the PS4. </p> <p>Duncan Clark, the Beijing-based chairman of BDA China Ltd., which advises technology companies, said Tencent and JD.com were well-positioned to benefit from the lifting of the ban. For Xbox, Tencent is the most established games distributor, and, for JD, it''s logistics, shipping and quality control, Clark said. So it makes a lot of sense. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Brian Louis" date="Jul 29, 2014  4:21 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-29/general-growth-adds-manhattan-retail-as-rents-increase.html"><headline>General Growth Adds Manhattan Retail as Rents Increase</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>General Growth Properties Inc. (GGP), the
second-largest U.S. mall owner, is spending almost $450 million
for stakes in three Manhattan properties as New York rents soar. </p>
<p>The company acquired half of 685 Fifth Ave. for $260.5
million and agreed to take stakes in two other properties in the
city, it said in a statement yesterday when it announced its
second-quarter financial results. The real estate investment
trust agreed to buy 50 percent of 530 Fifth Ave. for $147.5
million, and half of 218 W. 57th St. for $40.8 million. </p>
<p>General Growth, which has focused on redeveloping and
leasing up its malls to boost growth, also is adding properties
in the major shopping districts of U.S. cities including San
Francisco and Chicago, where the company is based. In New York,
it already owns 200 Lafayette St., a retail and office building. </p>
<p>Flagship street retail assets offer very compelling
opportunities to create shareholder value, Chief Executive
Officer Sandeep Mathrani said on the company''s earnings
conference call today. If we can opportunistically grow our
business in street retail, we will. </p>
<p>Manhattan''s Fifth Avenue, home to stores including Tiffany
 Co., is the most expensive shopping street in the U.S., and
priciest in the world after Causeway Bay in Hong Kong, brokerage
Cushman  Wakefield Inc. said in a November report. </p>
<h2>Record Rents </h2>
<p>On Fifth Avenue from 49th to 59th streets, ground-floor
asking rents have reached a record $3,550 a square foot this
year, up 16 percent from last year, the Real Estate Board of New
York reported in May. Along Fifth Avenue from 42nd Street to
Rockefeller Center, the stretch that includes 530 Fifth Ave.,
average rents have about doubled to more than $1,000 a square
foot in three years. </p>
<p>General Growth views street retail as an extension of
regional malls and will only acquire assets with significant
growth potential, Nathan Isbee, an analyst at Stifel Nicolaus
 Co., wrote in a note to investors today. We think street
retail will remain a small portion of GGP''s retail assets. </p>
<p>General Growth fell 1.7 percent to $23.70 today. The
company, the biggest U.S. mall owner after Simon Property Group
Inc., has climbed 18 percent this year, compared with a 17
percent gain in the Bloomberg REIT Index. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Drew Armstrong" date="Jul 29, 2014  4:14 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-29/pfizer-s-drug-sales-fall-short-as-viagra-struggles.html"><headline>Pfizer CEO Still Hunting for Deals and Willing to Go Big</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Failing to buy AstraZeneca Plc with
the drug industry''s largest-ever deal hasn''t stopped Pfizer
Inc. (PFE)''s Ian Read from looking far and wide for acquisitions. </p>
<p>We continue to look at all types of business development,
regardless of size, that we believe would add value to
shareholders, Read, the company''s chief executive officer,
said today on a conference call after his company announced
second-quarter results. </p>
<p>That may mean a deal that allows New York-based Pfizer to
decamp from the U.S. for a lower-tax jurisdiction overseas, one
of the goals for a merger with London-based AstraZeneca.
American drugmakers are forced abroad by the U.S.''s corporate
tax rate, Read said, the highest in the developed world. </p>
<p>There''s no substantial advantage to being a U.S. company,
to doing business in the U.S., he said by telephone. We are
at a tremendous competitive disadvantage. </p>
<p>U.S.-based drugmakers pay a 35 percent rate on all
earnings, whether made here or abroad. Foreign companies pay
that rate only on profits they earn in the U.S. That''s unfair,
Read said. He''s said he''s tired of criticism directed at
companies and CEOs for doing what he says may be the best
strategy to help shareholders. </p>




Photographer: Chris Ratcliffe/Bloomberg

<p>
Pfizer Chief Executive Officer Ian Read in May offered $117 billion for London-based AstraZeneca and was rejected. He has said that Pfizer has other options to pursue, and investors are watching closely for what could be a transformative deal. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tim Culpan, Ian King and Dina Bass" date="Jul 29, 2014  2:59 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-29/microsoft-probed-by-regulators-in-china-amid-u-s-tension.html"><headline>China Raids Microsoft Offices in Anti-Monopoly Investigation</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>China regulators opened an anti-monopoly investigation into Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), seizing computers and documents from offices in four cities amid escalating tensions with U.S. technology companies. </p> <p>The government also is investigating Microsoft executives in China, including a vice president, according to a statement posted today on the State Administration for Industry  Commerce website. The regulator urged the company to cooperate after almost 100 SAIC staff inspected the offices yesterday, copying contracts and financial statements. </p> <p>China stepped up the pressure on U.S. companies after American prosecutors indicted five Chinese military officers in May for allegedly stealing corporate secrets. Microsoft, Google Inc. and Apple Inc. (AAPL) have since been criticized by state media for allegedly cooperating with a U.S. spying program, and Qualcomm (QCOM) Inc. in November disclosed an investigation related to anti-monopoly law. </p> <p>They''re playing a long game, said Duncan Clark, the Beijing-based chairman of BDA China Ltd., which advises technology companies. China wants to discourage U.S. security agencies from using American technology companies, while also promoting domestic competitors, he said. </p>




Photographer: Akos Stiller/Bloomberg

<p>
Microsoft, the world''s largest software maker, said in May it''s working with the government to evaluate Windows 8 after the software was excluded from a government purchasing order of energy-efficient computers. Part of the reason for the exclusion was concerns over Internet safety, the state-run Xinhua News Agency reported, without citing anyone. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Silla Brush" date="Jul 29, 2014 10:58 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-29/jpmorgan-filed-inaccurate-large-trader-reports-cftc-says.html"><headline>JPMorgan Filed Inaccurate Large Trader Reports, CFTC Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) will pay
$650,000 to settle U.S. regulatory claims that the bank
repeatedly filed inaccurate reports about its clients''
derivatives trades. </p>
<p>The bank''s brokerage unit, JPMorgan Securities LLC, filed
reports between 2012 and this year with hundreds of errors about
clients'' futures and options trades, the Commodity Futures
Trading Commission said in a statement today. The unit continued
to file inaccurate reports even after the agency flagged the
errors to the bank, the CFTC said. </p>
<p>The large trader reports are vital to the CFTC''s role in
monitoring market behavior, Aitan Goelman, the CFTC''s director
of enforcement, said in the statement. The CFTC will be
vigilant in enforcing these rules in order to ensure the
integrity of the regulatory structure and to maintain
transparency in the markets. </p>
<p>Brian Marchiony, a JPMorgan spokesman, declined immediate
comment. </p>
<p>The CFTC requires futures brokers to submit daily reports,
which it uses to assess large traders'' activities and to
determine whether they hold speculative positions that exceed
regulatory limits. The data is also included in weekly reports
on aggregate market activities that are then disclosed to the
public. </p>
<p>JPMorgan has been penalized for inaccurate trade reporting
before. The firm was among at least three dealers to be
sanctioned this year by the Financial Industry Regulatory
Authority for not properly reporting trades to bond-price system
known as Trace. The bank neglected to post trades or missed
deadlines in at least 6,300 instances over a two-year period,
Finra said. </p>
<p>Holding back information on trades can give Wall Street
dealers an advantage over customers seeking a fair price,
undermining Finra''s stated goal of equal access for all
participants to real-time data. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hugh Son" date="Jul 29, 2014  9:55 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-29/jpmorgan-said-to-cut-support-jobs-amid-trading-slump.html"><headline>JPMorgan Said to Cut Support Jobs Amid Trading Slump</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the biggest U.S. lender, is cutting hundreds of technology support employees in its corporate and investment bank amid a revenue decline, people with knowledge of the move said. </p> <p>Workers in locations including New York, Tampa, Chicago and Dubai were notified of the cuts this month, said the people, who asked not to be identified because they weren''t authorized to discuss the matter. Luke Moranda, a managing director in charge of clearing technology, and Dan Cronin, an executive director, were among those let go, the people said. </p> <p>Wall Street firms are trimming expenses by paring support employees and moving personnel to lower-cost locales amid a decline in fixed-income trading. JPMorgan''s corporate and investment bank, run by Daniel Pinto, posted a 12 percent revenue drop to $17.6 billion in the first six months of 2014, while noninterest expenses declined by 1.6 percent to $11.7 billion. </p> <p>We continue to be focused and diligent on managing expenses and operating as efficiently as possible across our businesses, Chief Financial Officer Marianne Lake said this month in a conference call. </p> <p>Related:</p>
Morgan Stanley Said to Boost Junior Banker Salaries 25%
Finance Industry Bonuses Hit in Poll
<p>Moranda and Cronin didn''t respond to e-mailed messages seeking comment. Brian Marchiony, a spokesman for New York-based JPMorgan, declined to comment. </p>




Photographer: Simon Dawson/Bloomberg

<p>
JPMorgan''s corporate and investment bank, run by Daniel Pinto, posted a 12 percent revenue drop to $17.6 billion in the first six months of 2014, while noninterest expenses declined by 1.6 percent to $11.7 billion. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Glenys Sim" date="Jul 29, 2014  9:49 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-29/goldman-sees-nickel-rising-with-palladium-to-beat-iron-ore-soy.html"><headline>Goldman Sees Nickel Rising With Palladium to Beat Soy</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Nickel and palladium are set to
outperform iron ore and soybeans as supply outlooks for
commodities diverge amid a tentative acceleration in global
economic growth, according to Goldman Sachs Group Inc. </p>
<p>The bank kept its 12-month recommendation for commodities
at neutral, analysts including Jeffrey Currie wrote in a report
dated yesterday. They expect the total return for the Standard 
Poor''s GSCI Enhanced Commodity Index to be 0.1 percent in 12
months helped by positive roll yields. </p>
<p>Citigroup Inc. said last month that interest is returning
to the asset class as Societe Generale SA called commodities a
really mixed bag across the sectors. Raw materials are
already trading independently, with a ban on ore exports from
Indonesia spurring a rally in nickel, while expectations for a
deepening global glut have sent iron ore into a bear market. </p>
<p>While cyclical recovery tends to see rising commodity
demand, prices will likely largely be determined by more
structural supply factors, the Goldman Sachs analysts wrote.
Accordingly, not all boats are expected rise with the tide
created by continued improvement in global macroeconomic data. </p>
<p>Commodities as measured by the enhanced index added 2.4
percent this year as global equities increased 5.6 percent and
the Bloomberg U.S. Treasury Bond Index rose 3.5 percent.
Shortages are seen nickel, zinc, aluminum and palladium, while
most other raw materials including copper, iron ore, oil and
soybeans, are expected to be in surplus, Goldman says. Nickel
fell 1.2 percent today and palladium advanced 0.4 percent. </p>
<h2>Increasing Allocations </h2>
<p>We''ve seen increasing allocations from asset managers
this year and some new fund interest come into commodities,
Aakash Doshi, a Citigroup Global Markets vice president in New
York, said in a phone interview June 24. We''ve seen
geopolitics and weather really come to the fore this year. </p>
<p>Societe Generale is overweight agriculture, and energy to a
slightly lesser extent, and massively underweight precious
metals, according to Michael Haigh, head of commodities
research, in a June 17 interview. </p>
<p>While financial markets have reacted favorably to signs of
macroeconomic acceleration in both the U.S. and China, with the
Standard  Poor''s 500 Index reaching a record, commodity indexes
have remained mostly flat on expectations for increases in
supplies in most raw materials, the Goldman analysts said.
Nickel, zinc, aluminum and palladium do not fit into this view
as deficits are predicted over the next three years, they said. </p>
<h2>Carry Return </h2>
<p>Morgan Stanley also expects nickel, zinc and palladium to
advance. While nickel may have run ahead of itself, a
shortage next year may keep its uptrend intact, analysts
including Joel Crane said in a report yesterday. Zinc will
continue to outperform as the shortfall intensifies and solid
supply and demand fundamentals support palladium, they said. </p>
<p>The SP GSCI enhanced index has rebounded in 2014 from two
years of losses as key markets are in backwardation, a structure
where short-term supplies cost more than later deliveries, which
has provided so-called positive carry and continued to generate
returns, according to Goldman. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Benjamin Purvis and Candice Zachariahs" date="Jul 29, 2014  2:17 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-29/goldman-says-china-growth-must-slow-below-7-to-meet-goal.html"><headline>Goldman Says China Growth Must Slow Below 7% to Meet Goal</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>China should allow economic growth
to slow to below 7 percent to reduce reliance on investment
spending, according to Goldman Sachs Group Inc.''s Ha Jiming. </p>
<p>Achieving Premier Li Keqiang''s target of 7.5 percent gross
domestic product growth for this year could further aggravate
imbalances and a rate below 7 percent is roughly what China
needs, said Ha, the Hong Kong-based vice chairman and chief
investment strategist at Goldman''s investment management
division for China. Next year, I hope the target could be
lowered to reflect the need for economic rebalance, he said. </p>
<p>The ruling Communist Party, which last year laid out the
broadest economic changes since the 1990s, has been drawn back
into providing greater support for the economy as expansion is
threatened by a plunge in property construction and weaker home-price gains. The government has brought forward spending, cut
reserve requirements for some lenders and lowered taxes, helping
drive a gauge of manufacturing to an 18-month high. </p>
<p>It''s very difficult for China to strike a balance between
short-term growth and long-term reform needs, Ha said in an
interview yesterday in Sydney. According to my estimate, if
China wants to lower the share of investment in GDP over the
medium term, growth should not exceed 7 percent. </p>
<p>The risks embedded in the current Chinese growth model are
being exacerbated the longer the government seeks to maintain
growth at 7.5 percent, Angus Bell, an investment manager at
Goldman Sachs Asset Management, said yesterday in the same
interview. Goldman Sachs AM invests or advises on assets worth
more than $900 billion, according to its website. </p>
<h2>Slower Growth </h2>
<p>Economists surveyed by Bloomberg News predict that Chinese
GDP will expand by 7.4 percent this year, the slowest pace since
1990. The International Monetary Fund has lowered its forecasts
to 7.4 percent for this year and 7.1 percent for 2015, the
Washington-based fund said this month. </p>
<p>China''s leaders are seeking to rebalance the economy away
from exports and domestic investment, toward services and
consumption. To put the nation on a more sustainable growth
path, the government needs to prevent further excesses in
production capacity, debt and housing supply, according to Ha. </p>
<p>In the first half of this year, I would say the focus was
on safeguarding growth, said Ha. Given that the stimulus
policies are taking effect and growth is likely to be maintained
at the targeted level of 7.5 percent, in the second half of this
year some reform measures as announced a year ago could be put
in place. </p>
<h2>Housing Market </h2>
<p>Liberalization of interest rates and the currency and a
loosening of some regulations on foreign and domestic investors
will probably be among the initial changes considered, he said. </p>
<p>The key risks in China that concern Goldman Sachs Asset
Management center around housing, which is an important source
of demand for various industries and linked to local and central
government revenues, Bell said in Sydney. </p>
<p>Authorities are currently seeking to avert a collapse of
the real-estate market after data showed housing prices fell in
55 of 70 cities last month from May, the most since January 2011
when the government changed the way it compiles the statistics. </p>
<p>UBS AG estimates real-estate accounts for more than a
quarter of final demand in the economy when including property-generated needs for goods including electric machinery and
instruments, chemicals and metals. </p>
<p>The size is very big compared to many other countries,
said Ha, who predicts that home sellers will start to outnumber
buyers as China''s baby-boom generation retires. That
demographic inflection point will have very significant
implications for the Chinese property market and related
industries. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Craig Giammona" date="Jul 30, 2014  4:54 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-30/jpmorgan-names-ferry-to-head-fx-compliance-team.html"><headline>JPMorgan Names Ferry to Head FX Compliance Team</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the biggest
U.S. bank, named Andrew Ferry to lead a compliance team focused
on foreign exchange and rates markets. </p>
<p>Ferry, 46, who previously was in charge of swaps for
Europe, the Middle East and Africa, was promoted to oversee the
newly created team in London, said Brian Marchiony, a spokesman
for the New York-based firm. Tom Prickett, formerly a senior
trader in the Sterling swaps business, took over Ferry''s earlier
duties, Marchiony said. </p>
<p>Regulators and prosecutors in the U.S. and Britain are
investigating allegations the world''s biggest banks, including
JPMorgan, colluded to rig the foreign-currency rates. JPMorgan
also agreed this week to pay $650,000 to settle the Commodity
Futures Trading Commission''s claim that it repeatedly filed
inaccurate reports about clients'' derivatives trades. </p>
<p>Ferry didn''t immediately respond to an e-mail seeking
comment. The Wall Street Journal reported the moves earlier
today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jul 30, 2014 10:50 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-30/morgan-stanley-hires-imf-s-moghadam-for-underwriting.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Hires IMF''s Moghadam for Underwriting</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) hired Reza Moghadam,
the European department director of the International Monetary
Fund, as a vice chairman in its underwriting unit to advise
sovereign clients. </p>
<p>Moghadam will join the firm in the fourth quarter and
report to capital markets co-heads Raj Dhanda and Dan Simkowitz,
New York-based Morgan Stanley said today in a statement. He will
advise governments about financing opportunities and risk-management strategy, the bank said. </p>
<p>Sovereign-bond issuance surged to a record this year,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. Morgan Stanley was an
underwriter on the U.K.''s sale of 5 billion pounds ($8.4
billion) of inflation-linked bonds this week. </p>
<p>Moghadam has worked at the IMF for more than 20 years,
working on issues surrounding the Greek debt crisis and turmoil
in Ukraine. Earlier this year, he said Europe has much work to
do to lay a foundation for stability and growth and called for
deeper and broader capital markets in the region. </p>
<p>Reza has unmatched experience in navigating the landscape
of European and global economic policy, Colm Kelleher, who
leads the firm''s investment-banking and trading division, said
in the statement. In his 20 years at the IMF, Reza has played
a role in the Fund''s response to almost every major crisis. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bloomberg News" date="Jul 30, 2014  4:26 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-30/jpmorgan-says-don-t-fight-pboc-as-stimulus-lifts-stocks.html"><headline>JPMorgan Says Don''t Fight PBOC as Stimulus Lifts Stocks</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Don''t fight the People''s Bank of China. </p> <p>That''s the advice to investors from Adrian Mowat, the Hong Kong-based chief Asia and emerging-market strategist at JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) who raised his rating on Chinese stocks to neutral from underweight in a report dated yesterday. He said shares will rally through October after the Hang Seng China Enterprises Index (HSCEI) entered a bull market on July 28. </p> <p>China''s central bank presided over a bigger-than-estimated surge in new credit in June and has cut reserve requirements for some lenders, while local media reported the PBOC set up a 1 trillion yuan ($162 billion) lending facility with the China Development Bank to fund housing projects. The signs of monetary easing, along with accelerated government spending and gains in manufacturing industries, have spurred mutual fund managers to boost Chinese stock holdings to record highs, according to a July 28 report from HSBC Holdings Plc. (HSBA) </p> <p>The scale of monetary stimulus since June is a surprise, Mowat wrote. All these changes indicate a more aggressive approach to driving growth. </p> <p>Mowat is joining bulls, including Standard Chartered Plc''s Erwin Sanft and Templeton Emerging Markets Group''s Mark Mobius, who predict the rally will extend as low valuations lure investors and the government supports growth. Bears such as Bank of America Corp.''s David Cui say stimulus is delaying the economy''s shift toward a more sustainable model driven by consumption and services. </p> <h2>Winning Streak </h2> <p>The Hang Seng China Enterprises index fell less than 0.1 percent to 11,119.32 at the close in Hong Kong, snapping a sixth straight day of gains. China''s Shanghai Composite Index (SHCOMP) of mainland shares slipped 0.1 percent, paring the biggest monthly advance since 2012. </p> <p>Aggregate financing was 1.97 trillion yuan in June, the PBOC said on July 15, compared with the median estimate of analysts for 1.425 trillion yuan. New local-currency loans were 1.08 trillion yuan and M2 money supply grew 14.7 percent from a year earlier. </p> <p>Premier Li Keqiang said in June that authorities will ensure a minimum annual economic growth rate of 7.5 percent. China''s manufacturing industries expanded at the fastest pace in 18 months in July, according to a preliminary purchasing managers'' index from HSBC Holdings Plc and Markit Economics. Industrial companies reported a 17.9 percent gain in earnings in June from a year earlier, the fastest pace since September. </p> <p>Investors'' sentiment on Chinese stocks has improved over the past few days amid speculation the economy will stabilize in coming quarters, Jason Sun and Minggao Shen, analysts at Citigroup Inc. (C), said in a report yesterday. </p> <h2>Zhou Probe </h2> <p>The ruling Communist Party''s investigation into former security czar Zhou Yongkang could also provide a boost to equities, Lu Ting, head of Greater China economics at Bank of America Corp. (BAC) in Hong Kong, wrote in a report today. </p> <p>With some high-profile arrests under its belt, we believe the focus of the new government can start to shift from the anti-graft campaign to real institutional reforms, which are badly needed for China''s long-term economic health, Lu said. </p> <p>JPMorgan''s Mowat, who cut Chinese stocks to underweight in October, recommends buying high beta stocks including brokerages and property companies with low valuations, along with construction and railroad companies. </p> <p>Our China model portfolio is structured for a bull market, he wrote. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bob Van Voris" date="Jul 31, 2014  8:11 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-31/microsoft-fails-to-block-u-s-warrant-for-ireland-e-mail.html"><headline>Microsoft Fails to Block U.S. Warrant for Ireland E-Mail</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) lost its challenge
to a U.S. government search warrant ordering the software giant
to produce e-mails of an unidentified customer stored in a data
center in Ireland. </p>
<p>U.S. District Judge Loretta Preska in Manhattan today
upheld a federal magistrate''s decision requiring the company to
turn over e-mails in a drug investigation. Preska delayed the
effect of her ruling to give Microsoft time to appeal. </p>
<p>Preska rejected Microsoft''s argument that the warrant,
which requires the company to provide investigators with the
contents of the customer''s MSN.com Web-based e-mail, calls for
an illegal search and seizure outside the U.S. The nation in
which the customer lives wasn''t disclosed. </p>
<p>The judge delivered her ruling from the bench after a two-hour hearing, endorsing an April decision by U.S. Magistrate
Judge James C. Francis IV. Today''s ruling sets up an appeal that
may help dictate how courts apply legal protections to
electronic data, particularly information stored by Internet
service providers outside the U.S. </p>
<p>Congress intended in this statute for ISPs to produce
information under their control, albeit stored abroad, to law
enforcement in the United States, Preska said. As Judge
Francis found, it is a question of control, not a question of
the location of that information. </p>
<h2>Stored Communications </h2>
<p>During the hearing, lawyers for both sides argued over the
reach of the Stored Communications Act, or SCA, part of the
Electronic Communications Privacy Act of 1986. The SCA allows
law enforcement agents to obtain information through subpoenas,
court orders or warrants, depending on the records sought. </p>
<p>The only issue that was certain this morning was that the
district court''s decision would not represent the final step in
this process, Microsoft''s general counsel, Brad Smith, said in
a statement after the hearing. We will appeal promptly and
continue to advocate that people''s e-mail deserves strong
privacy protection in the U.S. and around the world. </p>
<p>Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft argued that the
government should be required to get the e-mails through
procedures dictated by a law-enforcement treaty between the U.S.
and Ireland. </p>
<p>Assistant U.S. Attorney Serrin Turner told Preska that the
treaty process, which can be complicated and time-consuming,
isn''t legally required. </p>
<h2>Right Here'' </h2>
<p>We don''t need to go to a foreign country to get the
records, Turner said. The provider is right here. </p>
<p>E. Joshua Rosenkranz, a lawyer for Microsoft, argued that
the government is seeking to conscript Microsoft here in the
United States to search files abroad. He said that if other
countries required Microsoft to provide them with e-mails of
customers located in the U.S. we would consider that an
astounding infringement of our sovereignty. </p>
<p>That is a very, very dangerous principle that the
government is articulating, Rosenkranz said. </p>
<p>Rosenkranz told Preska that officials in China this week
demanded a password to seek e-mail information in the U.S. </p>
<p>Mr. Turner, what do you say to that? Preska asked.
It''s pretty scary. </p>
<p>Turner said concerns about what other countries may do
should be addressed through political and diplomatic
channels, not by ignoring the terms of the SCA. </p>
<h2>Company Support </h2>
<p>Preska also heard arguments from lawyers representing ATT
Inc. (T), Verizon Communications Inc. (VZ), Apple Inc. (AAPL) and Cisco Systems
Inc. (CSCO), which supported Microsoft''s position. </p>
<p>Today''s decision is a major blow not just for Microsoft,
but for the entire U.S. cloud-computing industry, Christopher Soghoian, the principal technologist for the American Civil
Liberties Union, said in a statement today. If these companies
wish to regain the trust of their global customers, they must
embrace security technologies such as cloud cryptography, which
can provide real privacy protections where the law does not. </p>
<p>The case is In the Matter of a Warrant to Search a Certain
E-Mail Account Controlled and Maintained by Microsoft Corp., 13-mj-02814, U.S. District Court, Southern District of New York
(Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Gabrielle Coppola and Leslie Picker" date="Jul 31, 2014  7:53 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-31/mobileye-raises-890-million-as-largest-israeli-ipo-in-the-u-s-.html"><headline>Mobileye Raises $890 Million as Largest Israeli IPO in the U.S.</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Mobileye NV (MBLY), the Israeli company
creating software for driverless cars, raised $890 million in
its initial public offering in the U.S. </p>
<p>Mobileye, whose software anticipates potential collisions,
and existing shareholders sold 35.6 million shares for $25 each,
above the high end of the marketed range, according to a PR
Newswire statement. The company increased its price range this
week to $21 to $23 apiece. At the IPO price, Mobileye has a
market value of $7.6 billion, data compiled by Bloomberg show. </p>
<p>Jerusalem-based Mobileye''s IPO surpassed Partner
Communication Ltd''s share sale of $525 million in October 1999
to become the biggest U.S. IPO by an Israeli company. Founded by
Hebrew University professor Amnon Shashua and Ziv Aviram 15
years ago, Mobileye makes a chip and a system that alert drivers
to pedestrians and unintended lane departures. The company''s
products will help enable hands-free driving on the highway by
2016, according to the filing. </p>
<p>As of March 31, Mobileye''s technology was installed in
about 3.3 million cars made by manufacturers from Honda Motor
Co. to Tesla Motors Co., the company estimates. Mobileye''s
software is distributed through auto-parts suppliers such as TRW
Automotive Holdings Corp. (TRW) and Delphi Automotive Plc. </p>
<p>Mobileye posted 2013 net income of $19.9 million following
two years of losses, according to the prospectus. Revenue in
2013 was $81.2 million, more than double the figure from 2012.
Mobileye intends to use some of the net proceeds from the IPO to
purchase inventory. </p>
<p>The company counts Goldman Sachs Group Inc., Fidelity
Investments and BlackRock Inc. as investors, according to the
filing. Goldman Sachs is selling shares in the offering, in
addition to some Mobileye executives and other individual
investors. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and Morgan Stanley managed the
offering. The stock, listed on the New York Stock Exchange under
the symbol MBLY, will begin trading tomorrow. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tim Loh" date="Jul 31, 2014  4:28 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-31/walter-says-it-has-enough-liquidity-amid-weak-coal-market.html"><headline>Walter Says It Has Enough Liquidity Amid Weak Coal Market</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walter Energy Inc. (WLT), a metallurgical
coal producer that hasn''t been profitable in two years, said it
has enough liquidity to survive the weak market for the
steelmaking ingredient and that industry efforts to cut excess
supply are working. </p>
<p>Walter had $563.9 million in cash, cash equivalents and
available funds under its credit facilities at the end of the
second quarter, the company said in a statement today. </p>
<p>There''s no liquidity concerns in our company at this
point, Chief Executive Officer Walter J. Scheller III said in
a conference call. There will be no fire sale of assets, he
also said. </p>
<p>Walter is among metallurgical-coal producers contending
with global prices for the commodity that are at a six-year low
because of cooling Chinese demand and new mines coming on line.
Shares of the Birmingham, Alabama-based company have slumped 66
percent this year and Standard  Poor''s said last month that
Walter''s level of debt is unsustainable. </p>
<p>In April, the company started idling Canadian mines that
produced 3.6 million tons of coal in 2013. Industrywide, about
20 million tons of metallurgical-coal cuts have been announced
this year, helping to reduce excess supply, Scheller said. </p>
<p>Given the projects that are coming online and the
announced cuts, I think we might be pretty close to balanced
once it all works its way through, he said. </p>
<p>Most mining companies believe that 10 million to 15 million
tons of additional cutbacks are needed to achieve a balanced
market, Michael Dudas, an analyst for Sterne Agee  Leach Inc.,
said in a July 28 note. </p>
<h2>Forecast Cut </h2>
<p>Walter''s second-quarter net loss widened to $151.4 million,
or $2.33 a share, from $34.5 million, or 55 cents, a year
earlier. Excluding one-time items, the loss was $1.97 a share,
worse than the $1.69 average of 18 analysts'' estimates compiled
by Bloomberg. Sales dropped 14 percent to $378.4 million,
beating the $376.6 million average estimate. </p>
<p>The company reduced its metallurgical-coal sales forecast
for this year to 9.5 million to 10.5 million tons, from 10.5
million to 11.5 million tons previously. Walter said the main
reason was the shutting in June of its principal coal
transportation provider at the Brule mine in Canada. </p>
<p>The company''s $350 million of 11 percent second-lien notes
due April 2020, dropped 5.5 cents on the dollar today to 71.75
cents to yield 19.4 percent at 12:26 p.m. in New York, according
to Trace, the bond-price reporting system of the Financial
Industry Regulatory Authority. Walter shares fell 2.2 percent to
$5.75 in New York. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Carroll" date="Jul 31, 2014  4:19 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-31/exxon-beats-estimates-as-russia-sanctions-effects-queried.html"><headline>Exxon Falls After Reporting Lowest Output in Five Years</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) fell after
reporting oil and natural gas production declined to the lowest
level in almost five years, raising the stakes as it seeks to
pursue crude deposits in Russia. </p>
<p>The world''s largest energy company dropped 4.2 percent to
$98.94 at the close in New York, the biggest slide in almost
three years, after reporting second-quarter earnings that beat
analysts'' estimates. </p>
<p>The company''s oil and gas output decreased 5.7 percent to
the equivalent of 3.84 million barrels a day, the lowest since
the third quarter of 2009, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. Exxon had been expected to post quarterly output
equivalent to 3.96 million barrels, based on six analysts''
estimates. Crude from Exxon wells in Europe and Asia dropped,
while gas production faltered in every region in which the
company does business except Africa and the South Pacific. </p>
<p>Exxon is going after crude in Russia''s Arctic regions in an
effort to extract some of the largest oil reserves and reverse a
trend of declining production for the company. Its allocating
$39.8 billion to capital projects this year, including hundreds
of millions for an exploratory well in Russia''s Kara Sea, as
part of a 29-year agreement signed with Moscow-based OAO Rosneft (ROSN)
in 2011. </p>
<p>Sanctions threaten to halt that progress after the U.S. and
European Union said July 29 they would restrict the export of
technologies for energy production to Russia. The oil-producing
nation holds an estimated $8 trillion worth of crude
underground. </p>
<h2>Profit Rise </h2>
<p>Exxon is awaiting further details on U.S. and EU sanctions
to determine any effects, Vice President David Rosenthal said on
a conference call today. He declined to comment on how the
recently completed Berkut platform, a joint venture with Rosneft
of Russia''s Far East coast, was financed. </p>
<p>Because these new oil technology sanctions imposed by
Europe and the U.S. governments do impose some restrictions on
Arctic drilling technology, it may have an effect on these
Arctic drilling plans, Pavel Molchanov, a Houston-based
analyst for Raymond James  Associates Inc., said in a phone
interview before the results were released. Molchanov rates
Exxon the equivalent of a buy and doesn''t own the shares. </p>
<p>The lower production figures came as the company reported
better-than-expected second-quarter earnings. Excluding one-time
items, per-share profit was 19 cents more than the $1.86 average
of 21 estimates compiled by Bloomberg. Net income climbed 28
percent to $8.78 billion, or $2.05 a share, from $6.86 billion,
or $1.55, a year earlier, the Irving, Texas-based company said
in a statement today. </p>
<h2>Higher Prices </h2>
<p>Earnings were driven by higher fuel prices. Brent crude
futures, a global benchmark, rose 6 percent from a year earlier
to average $109.76 a barrel in the second quarter. Natural gas
futures prices in New York rose 14 percent to average $4.579 per
million British thermal units. </p>
<p>Exxon''s performance has trailed competitors and the
Standard  Poor''s 500 Index for the past year, gaining 7.3
percent, less than half of the SP''s move. The company, which
has a market value of $432 billion, has 14 buy ratings from
analysts, 13 holds and five sells. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Pablo Gonzalez" date="Jul 31, 2014  1:41 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-31/jpmorgan-said-to-have-held-talks-with-argentina-debt-holdouts.html"><headline>JPMorgan Said to Have Talked With Argentina Holdouts</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>(Corrects second paragraph to show that Ambito reported
that holdout creditors were in talks with banks.) </p>
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. met with
holders of Argentina''s defaulted bonds yesterday to discuss
buying the securities in a transaction that would allow the
South American country to resume paying interest on restructured
notes, according to a bank official familiar with the plan. </p>
<p>The talks, which also involve other banks potentially
interested in a deal, are ongoing, according to the person, who
asked not to be identified because the information is private.
Buenos Aires-based newspaper Ambito reported today that banks
including JPMorgan and Citigroup Inc. were in discussions to buy
the notes from Elliott Management Corp. and other holders that
won a court order for full repayment on the debt. </p>
<p>The nation missed a deadline yesterday to pay $539 million
in interest, falling into default after two days of negotiations
in New York failed to produce an accord with Elliott, Aurelius
Capital Management LP and other creditors from its last default
in 2001. Aurelius said in a statement that while it has been
approached by private parties seeking a deal, no agreement has
been reached. </p>
<p>Aurelius has received no such proposal that we considered
worthy of serious consideration, the firm said. Much of what
we have read in the press about such approaches has been, as far
as we are aware, inaccurate or unreliable. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael P. Regan" date="Jul 31, 2014 11:34 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-31/goldman-to-greenspan-catch-equity-acrophobia-in-flat-july.html"><headline>Goldman to Greenspan Catch Equity Acrophobia in Flat July</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Calling for a correction in equities at the right time is about as easy as brushing your teeth with your mustache. Yet that didn''t stop many market watchers in July as U.S. benchmark indexes clung to records. </p> <p>From Goldman Sachs Group Inc. to Alan Greenspan, a fear of heights spread this month as the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index closed in on its third year without a significant dip. The benchmark gauge of volatility reflected the concern, with the VIX jumping 34 percent for its biggest monthly gain since January yet still holding well below its lifetime average. </p> <p>Many potential catalysts were proffered. However, as the final trades of the month hit the tape, none of them have yet proven to be the smoking gun. An interest rate spike caused by the slow drain of the Federal Reserve punch bowl? Treasury 10-year yields held pretty flat below 2.6 percent. An oil shock as the world goes up in flames? Both West Texas Intermediate and Brent crude lost more than 5 percent. </p> <p>But wait! Corn is poised for its biggest monthly decline in almost three years! What calamity could be causing this 13 percent drop and is it the catalyst everyone''s been waiting for to knock the chip off the stock market''s shoulder? Well, as Bloomberg News describes it, the reason for the drop is expectations supplies will be ample amid an outlook for a bumper harvest in the U.S., the top grower. </p> <p>OK fine. Whatever. </p> <h2>Long Time </h2> <p>The main rationale for many of the correction predictions is based on the logic that, well, corrections happen. And we haven''t had one in a long time. </p> <p>Yet the fundamentals are sort of getting in the way. U.S. gross domestic product surged 4 percent last quarter, earnings are up 10 percent for the SP 500 companies that have reported results for the latest quarter and sales have increased 4.9 percent. Signs of growth sent the Bloomberg Dollar Spot Index up 1.9 percent in July, its biggest monthly gain in a year. </p> <p>Meanwhile across the pond, euro-area government bonds were up for a seventh straight month and headed for their longest streak of gains in nine years after weak data signaled the European Central Bank will have to soldier on with stimulus. The Stoxx Europe 600 Index is headed for a 1.8 percent July drop, its worst month since January, while the MSCI Emerging Markets Index is up 1.5 percent in July. </p> <h2>Yield Curve </h2> <p>And not all was flat in the Treasury market. Thirty-year bonds had a nice rally, while five-year notes fell. That sent the yield spread, or curve, between them to the lowest since 2009. That is likely a sign that people are taking this whole Fed tightening thing seriously, if not necessarily worried about inflation. </p> <p>Stocks are falling pretty sharply this morning as the month draws to an end, and there are new catalysts to blame: the Bank of Portugal''s order that Banco Espirito Santo SA must raise capital; Argentina''s default; a handful of lousy earnings reports from some big names. </p> <p>Ten-year Treasury yields surged 10 basis point yesterday and took an early jump today, then came back down to make a cool Sears Tower formation in the daily chart. </p> <p>Today''s drop has left the SP 500 down about 0.6 percent for July, which would mark its first monthly decline since January. However, dips have been bought reliably, so check back at the end of the day to see where the chips fall for July. </p> <p>It does make you wonder if this is the beginning of the correction that will fulfill all the pundit prophecies? Who knows. One thing is sure: people will likely obsess over it in August, just like they did in July. Oh, and in June too... </p> <p>Investors and analysts of all shades and sizes are obsessed with the idea of a correction, Birinyi Associates Inc. wrote in a note to clients at the end of June. We have always held that these efforts to foretell a correction are in vain. </p> <p>Anyway, come to think of it, there are some people who could brush their teeth with their mustache if they want: those with dentures. Hey, no one said coming up with market metaphors was any easier. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tim Loh" date="Jul 31, 2014  8:12 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-31/walter-reports-wider-than-expected-loss-on-low-coal-price.html"><headline>Walter Reports Wider-Than-Expected Loss on Low Coal Price</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walter Energy Inc. (WLT), a producer of
metallurgical coal, reported a wider-than-expected loss in the
second quarter and reduced its full-year forecast for production
of the steelmaking ingredient. </p>
<p>The loss excluding one-time items was $1.97 a share, the
Birmingham, Alabama-based company said today in a statement.
That trailed the average of 18 analysts'' estimates compiled by
Bloomberg for a per-share loss of $1.69. </p>
<p>Walter reduced its forecast for metallurgical coal sales
for this year to 9.5 million to 10.5 million tons, down from the
previous range of 10.5 million to 11.5 million tons. The company
said the main reason for the reduction was the shutting in June
of its principal coal transportation provider at the Brule mine
in Canada. </p>
<p>Walter is contending with a global benchmark for
metallurgical coal of $120 per metric ton, which is down 64
percent since 2011, when Chinese demand was booming for the
commodity. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sonia Sirletti and Francesca Cinelli" date="Jul 31, 2014  4:27 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-31/generali-second-quarter-profit-falls-13-on-bsi-group-sale.html"><headline>Generali May Reach Targets Earlier as Earnings Rise</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Assicurazioni Generali SpA (UCG) expects to reach 2015 targets ahead of schedule and improve its dividend policy, as first-half operating profit of Italy''s biggest insurer rose to the highest in 10 years. </p> <p>Our results show that we are quickly moving toward achieving our targets ahead of plan, Chief Executive Officer Mario Greco said during a conference call today. </p> <p>Greco, who took over as CEO in 2012, has cut costs and sold non-strategic assets to focus on the insurer''s main business, strengthen finances and bolster profitability. He said this month that the firm completed an asset-sales plan, raising 3.7 billion euros. </p> <p>Operating income increased 20 percent in the second quarter to 1.25 billion euros ($1.67 billion), Generali said today, beating analysts'' average expectation of 1.17 billion euros. In the first half, operating income was 2.51 billion euros. At the end of June, the Solvency 1 ratio, a measure of the insurer''s capacity to absorb losses, reached 162 percent, exceeding a 160 percent target for 2015, and would be 164 percent on a pro-forma basis after the BSI Group sale. </p> <p>Generali reported strong first-half results, beating estimates,on both the life and non-life operations,'''' Michael van Wegen, an analyst at BofA Merrill Lynch Global Research, wrote in a note to clients. We estimate Generali to make the most significant progress among the composites in closing the performance gap with the sector. </p> <h2>Shares Up </h2> <p>Generali rose 1 percent to 15.47 euros as of 10:17 a.m. in Milan trading, valuing the company at 24.1 billion euros. Losses so far this year were 8.7 percent, compared with the 33-member Bloomberg Europe 500 Insurance Index''s gain of 1.4 percent. </p> <p>Net income declined to 416 million euros in the three months to June 30 from 478 million euros a year earlier, missing the 504 million-euro average estimate of seven analysts surveyed by Bloomberg. </p> <p>Results were hurt by a 113 million-euro loss from the sale of Swiss private-banking unit BSI Group to Grupo BTG Pactual (BBTG11) of Brazil for 1.5 billion Swiss francs ($1.65 billion), announced earlier this month, and 190 million-euro writedown on the stake in the Russian insurer OEO Ingosstrakh. </p> <p>Operating income in life segment rose 10 percent in the second quarter from a year earlier to 772 million euros as income at the non-life business increased 29 percent to 517 million euros. Claims and costs as a proportion of premiums for non-life premiums, known as the combined ratio, fell to 92.8 percent at the end of June. </p> <h2>2015 Targets </h2> <p>Generali''s operating return on equity was 7 percent in the first half and on track to reach the 2015 target of 13 percent earlier than planned, Greco said. </p> <p>We cannot assume that we will double the operating ROE by year-end, because the second half of the year is usually less profitable for seasonal effects, but we are confident to reach it well before the end of the next year, he said. </p> <p>The CEO also said that the capital restructuring and the targets'' achievement will remove dividend constraints, leading to an improvement of the 40 percent dividend-payout ratio targeted for next year. </p> <p>The insurer''s capital position will allow a more favorable dividend policy, Enrico Esposti, a Milan-based analyst at ICBPI, wrote in a report today. This will positively affect shares. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jiyeun Lee" date="Jul 31, 2014 12:37 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-31/goldman-sees-yuan-trading-in-korea-weakening-won-against-dollar.html"><headline>Goldman Sees Yuan Trading in Korea Weakening Won Against Dollar</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A plan to start direct trading
between the won and China''s yuan will hurt the South Korean
currency by slowing the inflow of dollars, Goldman Sachs Group
Inc. said in a report. </p>
<p>Governments of the two Asian countries agreed on July 3 to
make their currencies mutually exchangeable in Seoul later this
year. The plan supports Goldman''s prediction that the won will
drop to 1,050 per dollar by the end of 2014, from 1,025.65
today, Kwon Goohoon, a Seoul-based economist at the U.S. bank,
wrote in today''s report. </p>
<p>This market will likely increase yuan settlement for
Korean exports to China and expand yuan investments by Korean
investors, weakening the won against the dollar in the
process, Kwon wrote. </p>
<p>South Korea''s trade surplus with China, its biggest export
partner, amounted to $24 billion in the first six months of this
year, according to a July 1 government report. With only 0.3
percent of trade payments settled in the Chinese currency, the
won-yuan market has the potential to grow rapidly, the Goldman
report said. </p>
<p>The value of South Korea''s yuan transactions with China and
Hong Kong has jumped by 5.6 times since June 2013, the Society
for Worldwide Interbank Financial Telecommunications, or Swift,
said in a July 29 statement. Bank of Korea data show yuan
deposits in the country surged 80 percent this year as investors
sought higher interest rates. </p>
<h2>Global Payments </h2>
<p>China''s currency ranked seventh for global payments in
June, according to Swift. The won has appreciated 2.3 percent
against the dollar this year and advanced 4.3 versus the yuan in
the same period, data compiled by Bloomberg show. </p>
<p>The won, which can only trade onshore in South Korea at
present, may also be transacted in China in the future. The two
countries will seek to establish infrastructure enabling direct
trading in Shanghai, according to a July 3 statement by the Bank
of Korea and the finance ministry. </p>
<p>The agreement also awarded South Korea an 80 billion yuan
($13 billion) quota for domestic investors to buy securities in
China under the Renminbi Qualified Foreign Institutional
Investor program. Bank of Communications Co. was appointed as
the yuan clearing bank in Seoul. </p>
<p>South Korea residents held $40.67 billion in dollar-denominated deposits at the end of June, while those in yuan
were equivalent to $11.97 billion, central bank figures show.
Goldman''s Kwon estimates yuan savings in the country can rise
2.5 times during the next 18 months. </p>
<p>South Korean banks are testing won-yuan transactions. Woori
Bank said it traded 1-month forward contracts directly with
Barclays Plc on July 28, while Kookmin Bank said it settled a
transaction with the Industrial  Commercial Bank of China Ltd.
on July 23. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bob Van Voris" date="Aug 01, 2014  8:18 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-01/microsoft-sues-samsung-over-patent-licensing-agreement.html"><headline>Microsoft Sues Samsung Over Patent Licensing Agreement</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. sued Samsung
Electronics Co. (005930), claiming the South Korean smartphone maker
breached a 2011 agreement to share patents. </p>
<p>Under the agreement, the two companies cross-licensed
patents for each other''s products. Microsoft, the world''s
biggest software maker, got royalties from Samsung for phones
and tablets that use some of the U.S. company''s patented
technology. The two companies said they would work together to
develop and market Windows Phone, Microsoft''s mobile software. </p>
<p>The software giant claimed, in a heavily redacted complaint
filed today in Manhattan federal court, that Samsung is using
Microsoft''s April acquisition of Nokia Oyj (NOK1V)''s phone business as
an excuse to stop complying with the contract. </p>
<p>Microsoft said Samsung failed to make a royalty payment on
time and refused to pay interest on the late payment. The
Redmond, Washington-based company claimed Samsung is threatening
to breach the license agreement again because of the Nokia
acquisition. </p>
<p>We don''t take lightly filing a legal action, especially
against a company with which we''ve enjoyed a long and productive
partnership, David Howard, Microsoft''s deputy general counsel,
said today in a company blog. After spending months trying to
resolve our disagreement, Samsung has made clear in a series of
letters and discussions that we have a fundamental disagreement
as to the meaning of our contract. </p>




Photographer: David Paul Morris/Bloomberg

<p>
Microsoft Corp., in a heavily redacted complaint filed today in Manhattan federal court, claimed that Samsung Electronics Co. is using Microsoft''s April acquisition of Nokia Oyj''s phone business as an excuse to stop complying with the contract. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Carroll and Zain Shauk" date="Aug 01, 2014  4:19 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-01/chevron-profit-rises-on-asset-sales-and-higher-brent-oil.html"><headline>Chevron Falls as Output Drops Despie Rising Spending</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX) fell after posting the
lowest second-quarter oil and natural gas output in six years as
spending on new projects surged. </p>
<p>Chevron declined 1 percent to $127.90 at the close in New
York. The production drop overshadowed the biggest quarterly
profit increase in more than a year for the San Ramon,
California-based company. Net income rose to $5.67 billion, or
$2.98 a share, from $5.37 billion, or $2.77, a year earlier,
Chevron said in a statement today. Per-share profit exceeded the
average of 13 analysts'' estimates compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Investors punished the world''s third-largest energy company
by market value after it reported output decreased 1.4 percent
to the equivalent of 2.545 million barrels of oil a day during
the April-to-June period, the weakest performance since 2008.
Capital spending on new floating production platforms, wells,
gas-export plants and other projects jumped 7.8 percent to $10.2
billion for the quarter. </p>
<p>Chevron had been expected to report output of 2.595 million
barrels a day, based on the average of six analysts'' estimates
compiled by Bloomberg. The company cited repair work at its
sprawling Tengizchevroil production facility in Kazakhstan as
well as contracts that reduce its share of output from some
wells when crude prices rise. </p>




Photographer: David Paul Morris/Bloomberg

<p>
A Chevron Corp. fueling station stands in Richmond, California. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Gabrielle Coppola and Leslie Picker" date="Aug 01, 2014 12:10 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-01/mobileye-jumps-after-pricing-largest-israel-ipo-in-u-s-.html"><headline>Mobileye Jumps After Pricing Largest Israel IPO in U.S.</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Mobileye NV (MBLY), the Israeli company
creating software for driverless cars, jumped on its first
trading day after raising $890 million in its initial public
offering in the U.S. </p>
<p>Mobileye, whose software anticipates potential collisions,
surged 55 percent to $38.75 at 11:35 a.m. in New York. The
company and existing shareholders sold 35.6 million shares for
$25 each, above the high end of the marketed range, according to
a press release. The company increased its price range this week
to $21 to $23 apiece. </p>
<p>Jerusalem-based Mobileye''s IPO surpassed Partner
Communication Ltd''s share sale of $525 million in October 1999
to become the biggest U.S. IPO by an Israeli company. Founded by
Hebrew University professor Amnon Shashua and Ziv Aviram 15
years ago, Mobileye makes a chip and a system that alert drivers
to pedestrians and unintended lane departures. The company''s
products will help enable hands-free driving on the highway by
2016, according to the filing. </p>
<p>As of March 31, Mobileye''s technology was installed in
about 3.3 million cars made by manufacturers from Honda Motor
Co. to Tesla Motors Co., the company estimates. Mobileye''s
software is distributed through auto-parts suppliers such as TRW
Automotive Holdings Corp. (TRW) and Delphi Automotive Plc. </p>
<p>Mobileye posted 2013 net income of $19.9 million following
two years of losses, according to the prospectus. Revenue in
2013 was $81.2 million, more than double the figure from 2012.
Mobileye intends to use some of the net proceeds from the IPO to
purchase inventory. </p>
<p>The company counts Goldman Sachs Group Inc., Fidelity
Investments and BlackRock Inc. as investors, according to the
filing. Goldman Sachs is selling shares in the offering, in
addition to some Mobileye executives and other individual
investors. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs and Morgan Stanley managed the offering. The
stock is listed on the New York Stock Exchange under the symbol
MBLY. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Carroll" date="Aug 01, 2014 12:07 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-01/chevron-shrugs-as-apache-quits-kitimat-lng-in-canada.html"><headline>Chevron Shrugs as Apache Quits Kitimat LNG in Canada</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX) said it will seek out a
new partner for a proposed natural gas export terminal on
Canada''s Pacific Coast after Apache Corp. (APA) indicated it will
depart from the project. </p>
<p>Chevron is unconcerned about Apache''s announcement
yesterday that it will divest its stake in the Kitimat liquefied
natural gas project in British Columbia, Chevron Vice Chairman
George Kirkland said during a conference call with analysts
today. </p>
<p>Chevron has already began drilling appraisal wells in the
gas fields that will supply the proposed Kitimat complex,
Kirkland said. The company still is studying how much the
project will cost and how long it will take to construct, key
factors in a final investment decision, he said. </p>
<p>Apache also said yesterday that it will sell its interest
in the Chevron-led Wheatstone LNG venture in Australia. </p>
<p>Chevron, the world''s third-largest energy producer, whose
LNG plans include a $10 billion complex in Angola and the $54
billion Gorgon project in Australia, is betting demand for the
fuel will begin to outpace supplies around the end of this
decade. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jesse Riseborough" date="Aug 01, 2014 11:20 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-01/jpmorgan-blackrock-differ-from-rio-ceo-walsh-on-returns.html"><headline>JPMorgan, BlackRock Differ From Rio CEO Walsh on Returns</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Rio Tinto Group Chief Executive
Officer Sam Walsh last week signaled that mining investor
attitudes toward spending on expansion are starting to shift
after a recovery in metals and share prices. </p>
<p>Investors have started to refocus on growth and expansion
plans rather than concentrating only on returns, Walsh, 64, said
at an industry event in Perth, Australia last week. Mining
companies should retain their focus on giving back excess cash
to shareholders and shy away from mergers and acquisitions, two
of the industry''s largest investors said. </p>
<p>It does seem slightly baffling for him to have come out
with that statement so early on really, James Sutton, a
portfolio manager at JPMorgan Asset Management''s $1.9 billion
Natural Resources Fund in London, said today in a phone
interview. In terms of the worst culprits of capital ill
discipline, I don''t think they''re off the leash yet. </p>
<p>Mining companies have been reining in spending after a $250
billion investment spree marked by poorly timed acquisitions and
asset writedowns sparked investor criticism. As a decade-long
boom in metal prices petered out, producers have focused on
preserving capital and bolstering dividends. </p>
<p>If you look at investors globally, there was certainly a
time when global investors were more focused on returns, Walsh
said. Since the beginning of this year, we''ve actually seen a
shift. I think it''s far more balanced; that we''ve now got
investors refocused on growth, expansion, as well as shareholder
returns. </p>
<h2>Damaging Strategies'' </h2>
<p>Walsh replaced Tom Albanese at the head of the world''s
second-largest mining company in January last year following
failed deals in coal and aluminum. He cut $2.3 billion from
costs last year and is seeking to a further reduction of $1
billion this year. </p>
<p>BlackRock Inc.''s Evy Hambro, who manages the $8 billion
World Mining Fund, said mining CEOs should maintain their
commitment to rewarding investors. Rio is the fourth-largest
holding in Hambro''s Fund at 7.7 percent. The 101-member
Bloomberg World Mining Index advanced 5.4 percent in July to
reach the highest monthly close in 16 months. </p>
<p>Given the recent strength in the sector, the market is
starting to acknowledge managements'' focus on returns for
shareholders, Hambro said in e-mailed comments yesterday. It
would be foolish for the executives and boards to put this
nascent recovery at risk by reverting back to the damaging
strategies of the last cycle. </p>
<p>A London-based spokesman for Rio declined to comment. </p>
<h2>Shareholders Important </h2>
<p>There''s been no change of strategy at Rio, Walsh said at
last week''s event. The company raised its dividend 15 percent in
February after reporting a 43 percent gain in second-half
profit. </p>
<p>Shareholder returns are very important to me and to the
company, he said. That''s why we''re in business: to provide
returns to our shareholders. We should never lose sight of that.
But it''s also, you know, long-term shareholders as well as
short-term shareholders. We need to get that balance right. </p>
<p>Analysts widely expect BHP Billiton Ltd. (BHP) and Rio to
announce share buybacks in the next six months. Macquarie Group
Ltd. analysts have said they''re not convinced a buyback is due
or that it would be a responsible use of funds for BHP. </p>
<p>Rio Tinto this week drew a line under one of its most
disastrous deals by selling its Mozambique coal assets for $50
million. The company bought the projects as part of a $3.7
billion purchase of Riversdale Mining Ltd. in 2011 before
writing them down by $3 billion last year. </p>
<p>I don''t think that the large-cap mining companies have
got the mandate from the generalist investor to go on an
acquisition spree any time soon, JPMorgan''s Sutton said.
They always have to consider their pipeline and to consider
the reserve lives of their various commodity exposures. So it
can''t carry on indefinitely, this halt to capex and
acquisitions. </p>
<p>The JPMorgan Natural Resources has Rio as its fifth-largest
holding, with a 4.6 percent weighting. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Mark Drajem and Justin Doom" date="Aug 01, 2014 11:06 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-01/goldman-s-icy-arbitrage-draws-interest-to-meet-epa-rule.html"><headline>Goldman''s Icy Arbitrage Draws Interest to Meet EPA Rule</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Clustered deep beneath the trading floors of Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)''s Manhattan headquarters are 92 tanks with enough ice for 3.4 million margaritas. </p> <p>Goldman runs chilled anti-freeze through pipes connected to the 11-ton vessels during summer nights -- when power costs less -- to freeze the water. That ice is used the next day in its air-conditioning system, when high-demand electricity comes with a surcharge. </p> <p>Proponents of so-called thermal storage systems such as Goldman''s, which have roots in the New England ice houses of the 18th century, are pushing to expand its use. And they see it as a way to help utilities comply with future carbon rules as well as to store power from rooftop solar panels or wind farms whose output often surges when demand is low. </p> <p>A Global Push to Save the Planet</p><p>We''re going to start phasing out the old coal plants, and replacing them with solar, wind and some nuclear power, said Mark MacCracken, chief executive officer of CALMAC Manufacturing Corp., which made Goldman''s tanks. All of these need to use storage in a big way, and thermal storage is the low-hanging fruit. </p> <p>Getting thermal storage to take off has been a slog, though, as building owners don''t want to invest in power savings that will accrue to their tenants, and utilities exempt most customers, especially residential ones, from pricing based on peak demand periods. Without those pricing cues, government tax breaks or subsidies may be needed to boost the use of ice tanks, said Jim Lazar, a utility consultant in Olympia, Washington, who wrote a report on integrating more renewables in the electric grid. </p>




Photographer: Peter Foley/Bloomberg

<p>
Thermal energy storage or ice tanks, part of the heating and cooling system, sit inside the Goldman Sachs Tower, located at 200 West Street, in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jason Corcoran" date="Aug 01, 2014  4:15 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-01/goldman-sachs-says-russian-banks-will-shift-away-from-fx-lending.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Says Russian Banks Will Shift Away From FX Lending</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Russia lenders will try to diversify
wholesale borrowing away from U.S. and Europe following
sanctions over Ukraine, Goldman Sachs (GS) says in e-mailed report. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs also says: </p>
<p>* Banks will respond to restrictions on their access to
capital markets with combination of more lending in rubles,
diversifying into funding from Asia and higher rates on FX
deposits </p>
<p>* Trend to issue outside of dollars already taking place
with U.S </p>
<p>* Once EU sanctions are implemented, Russian banks will
likely try to concentrate more on Asian markets, particularly on
China </p>
<p>* Over long term, sanctions will probably result in sharp
decline in lending and rise in risk costs </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry></news>