<?xml version='1.0' encoding='us-ascii'?>
<news><entry author="By Mark Shenk" date="Oct 30, 2007  3:31 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-10-30/oil-falls-more-than-3-from-a-record-on-goldman-call-to-sell.html"><headline>Oil Falls More Than $3 From a Record on Goldman Call to Sell</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Crude oil fell more than $3 from a
record in New York after Goldman Sachs Group Inc., the bank that
said in July oil may reach $95 a barrel, told clients it's ``time
to take profits.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``When the lead bull takes a pause, you have to expect the
herd to turn,'' said Michael Lynch, president of Strategic Energy
 Economic Research in Winchester, Massachusetts. ``Prices are so
high that Goldman Sachs can't justify them.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman said in a report it was closing its long position in
New York oil futures. Long positions are bets that prices will
rise. Petroleos Mexicanos will review weather conditions and
release updated production plans today, spokesman Carlos Ramirez
said. The company cut output by 600,000 barrels a day starting
Oct. 28. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crude oil for December delivery fell $3.15, or 3.4 percent,
to settle at $90.38 a barrel at 2:49 p.m. on the New York
Mercantile Exchange. It's the biggest one-day drop since Aug. 6.
Futures climbed to $93.80 yesterday, the highest since trading
began in 1983. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brent crude oil for December settlement fell $2.88, or 3.2
percent, to close at $87.44 a barrel on the London-based ICE
Futures Europe exchange. It was also the biggest decline since
Aug. 6. Brent reached $90.49 a barrel yesterday, the highest
since trading began in 1988. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``This isn't a full-out correction; the market is just
taking a breather,'' said Brad Samples, commodity analyst for
Summit Energy Services Inc. in Louisville, Kentucky. ``When
Goldman makes a call to sell, investors listen, especially since
they have been one of the more vocal bulls in the market.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oil has gained 48 percent this year as hedge funds and other
large speculators increased bets on rising prices. Net-long
positions in New York crude futures in the week ended Aug. 3
jumped to the highest in more than a decade. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Downside Risk &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``The downside risks we have embedded in our end of first
quarter 2008 oil price target of $80 a barrel are beginning to
gain momentum,'' the Goldman said. ``These include increasing
exports, a slowing U.S. economy, an adequate level of heating oil
inventories.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OPEC has a ``duty'' to supply the world with oil at stable
prices, Mohamed al-Hamli, the group's president, said today at an
oil conference in London. Al-Hamli is also the oil minister of
the United Arab Emirates. If the market needs more oil, OPEC will
supply it, while the group's spare capacity stands at 3.5 million
barrels a day, he added. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries agreed
last month to increase output by 500,000 barrels a day starting
Nov. 1 to help ease prices that threaten economic growth. Futures
have surged 18 percent since the Sept. 11 meeting in Vienna. The
group produces 40 percent of the world's oil. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;OPEC Meeting &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The heads of state of OPEC members will meet in Riyadh on
Nov. 17. There won't be any decisions taken regarding oil supply
at the meeting, Al-Hamli said. Still, ministers are likely to
discuss the oil market during the summit, he said. OPEC's next
meeting to set crude-oil production levels is scheduled for Dec.
5 in Abu Dhabi. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An Energy Department report tomorrow is expected to show
that U.S. crude-oil supplies rose 300,000 barrels last week,
according to the median of 15 responses in a Bloomberg News
survey. The report may show that stockpiles of distillate fuel, a
category that includes heating oil and diesel, dropped 1 million
barrels, the survey showed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Mark Shenk in New York at 
mshenk1@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Dan Stets at 
dstets@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Peter J. Brennan" date="Nov 04, 2007  2:38 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-11-04/berkshire-dte-energy-lilly-pfizer-u-s-equity-preview.html"><headline>Berkshire, DTE Energy, Lilly, Pfizer: U.S. Equity Preview</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;The following is a list of companies
whose shares may have unusual price changes in U.S. exchanges
tomorrow. This preview includes news that broke after exchanges
closed. Stock symbols are in parentheses after company names. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abbott Laboratories (ABT) : The drugmaker's experimental
combination pill Simcor worked as well as the two drugs it seeks
to replace in lowering the harmful form of cholesterol and
increasing the beneficial type, a study showed. Abbott stock
fell 7 cents to $54.05 on Nov. 2. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American International Group Inc. (AIG) : The company's
former chief executive, Maurice ``Hank'' Greenberg, began a
campaign to shake up the insurer's management and may seek the
sale of some units, he said Nov. 2 in a filing. The shares of
New York-based AIG, the world's largest insurer, rose $2.43, or
4.1 percent, in extended trading to $61.55. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Berkshire Hathaway Inc. (BRK/A) (BRK/A US): The investment company
controlled by billionaire investor Warren Buffett said third-quarter profit surged 64 percent after gains from its investment
in PetroChina Co. The stock rose $1,250 to $132,500 in regular
trading. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citigroup Inc. (C) : The crisis of leadership at the
largest U.S. bank may hit a climax this weekend amid speculation
that Chief Executive Officer Charles O. ``Chuck'' Prince III
will resign. The company has had widening losses from bad
mortgage debts. The stock gained $1.31, or 3.5 percent, to
$39.04 in extended trading. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delta Petroleum Corp. (DPTR US): The U.S. oil and gas
producer may fall at least 20 percent this year and possibly
into the next without a gas discovery soon, Barron's said,
without citing anyone. Delta Petroleum shares fell 61 cents, or
3.5 percent, to $16.94 on Nov. 2. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DTE Energy Co. (DTE) : The owner of Michigan's largest
utility said operating earnings excluding synthetic fuel are
expected to be $425 million to $450 million this year, down from
a previous forecast of as much as $485 million. The stock rose
27 cents to $48.99 in regular trading on Nov. 2. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eli Lilly  Co. (LLY) : The drugmaker's experimental drug
with Daiichi Sankyo Co., prasugrel, for blocking clot formation
is potentially more dangerous than Plavix, the best-selling
medicine for this condition, a study found. The research
compared prasugrel to Bristol-Myers Squibb Co. (BMY)'s and Sanofi-Aventis SA's Plavix. Lilly shares fell 10 cents to $52.67 in
regular trading, and Bristol-Myers declined 28 cents to $28.88. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Force Protection Inc. (FRPT US): The largest supplier of
blast-resistant trucks to the U.S. Marine Corps said it extended
royalty fees to through 2012 to the Republic of South Africa's
Council for Scientific and Industrial Research for the transfer
of intellectual property rights, according to a regulatory
filing. The stock lost 1 cent to $17.75 in regular trading. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KB Home (KBH) : The homebuilder said in a regulatory
filing that Ray Irani resigned from the company's board. No
reason was given for the move by Irani. The stock fell 77 cents,
or 3 percent, to $25.11 in regular trading on Nov. 2. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kenneth Cole Productions Inc. (KCP US): The designer of
shoes and handbags may reach $50 as it expands into men's
sportswear and clothing, Barron's reported, without citing
anyone. Kenneth Cole gained 9 cents to $18 in regular trading. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mattel Inc. (MAT) : The world's largest toymaker may rise
to $30 in the next 12 months as it rebounds from toy recalls,
Barron's said, citing Linda Bolton Weiser, a toy analyst at
Oppenheimer  Co. Mattel stock fell 4 cents to $20.50 on Nov. 2. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Northern Trust Corp. (NTRS) : The Chicago-based custodian
of financial assets may climb 10 percent or more annually,
because its loans aren't threatened by the upheaval in the
credit and housing markets, Barron's reported, without citing
anyone. Northern Trust gained $1.35 to $72.84. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer Inc. (PFE) : The drugmaker said it will present
new data about its top-selling Lipitor cholesterol pill's
effects on patients' cardiovascular and kidney function tomorrow
and Nov. 6 at a heart conference. The company's stock fell 28
cents to $23.67 on Nov. 2. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seaboard Corp. (SEB) : The second-largest U.S. hog
producer said third-quarter net income fell 14 percent to $52.6
million, or $41.75 a share. The stock rose $6.12 to $1,607.12 in
regular trading. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WellCare Health Plans Inc. (WCG) : The provider of
managed-care services said a board committee will investigate
matters raised in probes by state and federal agencies. WellCare
also will delay filing its quarterly financial report. The
company cited a U.S. Department of Justice press release on Oct.
24 that said review shouldn't ``have any impact upon, the
delivery of any health care service.'' In after hours trading,
the stock rose $6.61, or 24 percent, to $33.98. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Peter J. Brennan in Los Angeles at 
pbrennan3@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Sylvia Wier at  swier@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry></news>