<?xml version='1.0' encoding='us-ascii'?>
<news><entry author="By Carlos Manuel Rodriguez and Thomas Black" date="Sep 07, 2009  1:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-09-07/mexican-soda-tax-may-damp-profit-at-coca-cola-femsa-week-ahead.html"><headline>Mexican Soda Tax May Damp Profit at Coca-Cola Femsa: Week Ahead</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Plans by Mexico's ruling party to
levy a tax on soft drinks would cost Coca-Cola Femsa SAB (KOF), Latin
America's biggest bottler, more than 3 percent in sales and
profit growth, JPMorgan Chase  Co. analyst Alan Alanis said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;If there is an excise tax, they'll have to pass it all to
the consumer,&#8221; New York-based Alanis said in a phone interview. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mexico's Congress will begin to discuss how to offset the
effects of a slowing economy and declining tax revenue on
government income tomorrow, when Finance Minister Agustin Carstens, 51, discloses his 2010 budget. Luis Enrique Mercado, a
lawmaker for the ruling National Action Party, said Sept. 3 that
his bloc would back a soda tax, increased duties on beer and the
elimination of tax exemptions on junk food. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alanis said he had been forecasting earnings before
interest, taxes, depreciation and amortization at Mexico City-based Coca-Cola Femsa would rise next year in line with an
estimated 3 percent to 4 percent increase in sales volume. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;If we put a tax increase of 10 percent, I'll have to put my
volumes essentially flat,&#8221; said Alanis, who has an &#8220;overweight&#8221;
recommendation on Coca-Cola Femsa, which sells 26 brands of soft
drinks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Aug. 28, Reforma newspaper, citing a Finance Ministry
document, said the proposed tax rate for soft drinks was 10
percent. Finance Ministry spokesman Rodrigo Brand declined to
give details of the budget, saying they would be disclosed
tomorrow. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Femsa's profit rose 17 percent in the second
quarter to 2.16 billion pesos ($162 million) as sales climbed 30
percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Arca Sales &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carolina Alvear, a spokeswoman for Fomento Economico
Mexicano SAB, the parent company of Coca-Cola Femsa and the
country's second-largest beer brewer, declined to comment on
possible tax changes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A new levy on sodas would have a similar effect on sales and
profits at Embotelladoras Arca SAB, Mexico's second-largest Coca-Cola bottler, as on Coca-Cola Femsa, said Alanis, who has a
&#8220;neutral&#8221; recommendation on the Monterrey-based company. Arca's
profit fell 6 percent in the second quarter to 766.3 million
pesos. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arca spokesman Guillermo Garza declined to comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mexico's tax collection has fallen as Latin America's
second-biggest economy contracted 10.3 percent in the second
quarter from a year earlier. Oil revenue, which provides the
government with 38 percent of its income, has dropped because of
a 37 percent decline in prices over the past 12 months and
diminishing production at state-owned Petroleos Mexicanos. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The government estimates the deficit will widen to 3 percent
of gross domestic product this year from 2.1 percent in 2008. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;IVA Increase &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mercado ruled out any increase in the 15 percent rate of
value added tax, known as IVA, or an end to the exemption from
the tax for medicines and food, other than those with high
calories and low nutritional value. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The opposition Institutional Revolutionary Party, or PRI,
which has more deputies than any other group in the 500-member
lower house, opposes any increase in IVA, PRI congressman Jesus
Alberto Cano Velez said in an Aug. 11 interview. The party would
support increased duties on beer and tobacco, said Cano Velez. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Nobody wants to touch the IVA, it's a political taboo in
Mexico,&#8221; Jose Antonio Crespo, 54, a political analyst at the
Center for Economic Research and Teaching in Mexico City, said in
a telephone interview. &#8220;Politicians portray the IVA as an attack
on the poor.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sweet rolls, snacks and candies produced by Grupo Bimbo
SAB (BIMBOA), the world's biggest bread maker, would be subject to IVA if
exemptions were lifted for junk food, said Eduardo Estrada Lopez,
an analyst at Citigroup Inc.'s Banamex unit in Mexico City. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Price Increases &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent price increases mean the Mexico City-based food
maker would probably absorb the tax itself rather than risk a
drop in sales by passing it on to consumers. Estrada said he
couldn't calculate the effect on earnings until details of any
new tax were known. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bimbo spokeswoman Monica Breton declined to comment for this
article. Bimbo second-quarter profit rose 70 percent to 1.43
billion pesos. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any increase in the 25 percent excise tax on beer would
probably cause Mexicans to reduce consumption, JPMorgan's Alanis
said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An increase in the duty to 30 percent would reduce sales of
Grupo Modelo SAB (GMODELOA), the country's largest brewer and maker of
Corona, and Fomento Economico Mexicano, by 1.7 percent, Alanis
said. Fomento Economico is the maker of Dos Equis beer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grupo Modelo said it opposes increased duties. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Mexico is currently one of the countries with the highest
beer taxes,&#8221; the Mexico City-based company said in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Markets Last Week &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mexico's Bolsa index fell 1 percent last week to 28309.55.
Grupo Mexico SAB, Mexico's biggest mining company, led advances
in the index, climbing 9 percent after a judge said the company
should be allowed to regain control of its bankrupt U.S. copper
mining unit. Axtel SAB, Mexico's second-largest fixed line phone
operator, dropped 7.4 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mexico's peso weakened 0.9 percent against the dollar last
week. The currency fell to 13.3631 pesos per dollar from 13.2478
pesos on Aug. 28. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yields on Mexico's 10 percent local-currency bond due
December 2024 fell 11 basis points, or 0.11 percentage point, to
8.3 percent last week. The bond's price rose 1.1 centavos to
114.66 centavos per peso, according to Banco Santander SA. &lt;/p&gt;

The following is a list of events in Mexico this week:

Event                                  Date         Forecast
Aug. Consumer Prices Month-on-Month    Sept.  9      +0.25%
Aug. Consumer Prices Year-on-Year      Sept.  9      +5.10%
Aug. Consumer Prices Core              Sept.  9      +0.25%
July Trade Balance                     Sept. 10       ----
June Gross Fixed Investment            Sept. 11      -10.8%
July Industrial Production             Sept. 11       -9.1%

&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Carlos M. Rodriguez in Mexico City at 
carlosmr@bloomberg.net;
Thomas Black in Monterrey at 
tblack@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Adriana Arai at 
aarai1@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Catherine Yang and Saeromi Shin" date="Sep 23, 2009  4:35 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-09-23/yahoo-s-agreement-with-microsoft-covers-china-japan-update1-.html"><headline>Yahoo&#8217;s Agreement With Microsoft Covers China, Japan</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Yahoo! Inc. (YHOO) said the proposed
Internet-search partnership with Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) will cover both
Japan and China, where its operations are run by local partners. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yahoo is discussing requirements for the adoption of
Microsoft&#8217;s Bing search engine with its local partners, Rose Tsou, managing director for Asia at Yahoo, said in a Bloomberg
Television interview in Seoul today. In July, Yahoo agreed to
use the software on its Web sites and sell ads that appear next
to search results, with the two companies splitting the revenue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alibaba Group Holding Ltd., which operates Yahoo&#8217;s portal
in China, hasn&#8217;t said whether it will use the Bing search engine
in the world&#8217;s biggest Internet market by users. Yahoo Japan
Corp., (4689) controlled by Tokyo-based Softbank Corp., (9984) operates the
most-visited Web site in the world&#8217;s second-biggest economy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;We are in a very good position to accelerate growth&#8221; in
Asia, Tsou said. &#8220;In general, Asia is still performing
relatively stronger when it comes to advertising.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertising sales in Asia have partly helped Yahoo
compensate for a slump in the U.S. The Sunnyvale, California-based company is seeking the accord with Microsoft to narrow the
lead of Google Inc., (GOOG) which dominates in the paid-search market. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alibaba, China&#8217;s biggest electronic-commerce company,
hasn&#8217;t yet made a decision about Microsoft Bing, Chairman Jack Ma said on Sept. 11. In 2005, Yahoo paid $1 billion and swapped
its Chinese operations for a 40 percent stake in the Hangzhou,
east China-based company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yahoo last week raised HK$1.14 billion ($147 million) from
selling its stake in Hong Kong-listed Alibaba.com Ltd., in which
Alibaba Group owns a 74 percent stake. The U.S. company retains
its holding in the Chinese parent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Yahoo is very happy with the relationship we have with
Alibaba,&#8221; Tsou said. The disposal of the Alibaba.com stake was
&#8220;just a financial decision,&#8221; she said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporters on this story:
Saeromi Shin in Seoul at 
sshin15@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Young-Sam Cho at  ycho2@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Stephen Kirkland" date="Sep 28, 2009  1:37 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-09-28/telefonica-02-rated-new-sell-at-goldman-on-earnings-concern.html"><headline>Telefonica 02 Rated New &#8216;Sell&#8217; at Goldman on Earnings Concern</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Telefonica 02 Czech AS, the Czech
Republic&#8217;s largest provider of telecommunication services, was
initiated with a &#8220;sell&#8221; recommendation and price estimate of
376 koruna at Goldman Sachs Group Inc., which cited earnings
visibility and cash payout concerns, in a research report. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Stephen Kirkland at 
skirkland@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry></news>