
<news><entry author="By Ye Xie" date="Dec 02, 2013 11:07 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-02/goldman-says-buy-h-shares-amid-growth-china-overnight.html"><headline>Goldman Predicts Biggest China H-Share Advance Since 2009</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chinese stocks traded in Hong Kong
will post the biggest gain since 2009 next year on prospects the
economy will stabilize, Goldman Sachs Group Inc. said. </p>
<p>The Hang Seng China Enterprises Index (HSCEI), also known as the H-share index, will rally 18 percent to 13,600 by the end of 2014,
Noah Weisberger, a New York-based analyst at Goldman Sachs,
wrote in a report yesterday. The advance would be the biggest
since the gauge surged 62 percent in 2009. The measure dropped
0.8 percent to 11,450.55 at the midday break in Hong Kong. </p>
<p>China''s manufacturing growth beat analyst estimates in
November, indicating the nation''s economic recovery is
sustaining momentum amid government efforts to rein in credit
growth. Goldman Sachs''s H-share forecast forms part of a trade
recommendation in which the bank is telling investors to buy
Chinese stocks while selling copper as a bet that commodities
will lag the rally in equities. Goldman Sachs called the trade
its fourth top recommendation for next year. </p>
<p>Equities are our favorite asset class in an environment
where growth is moderate but not overheating, while policy
makers remain accommodative, Weisberger said by phone
yesterday. For the first time in the last several years, we
would argue to own exposure to China through the Chinese equity
market. </p>
<p>China last month vowed to allow more private investment in
state-controlled industries, loosen its one-child policy and
better protect farmers'' rights in the most sweeping reforms in
two decades. The government also pledged to elevate the role of
markets in the world''s second-largest economy. </p>
<h2>H-Share Valuation </h2>
<p>Economists estimate gross domestic product will expand 7.5
percent next year after growing 7.6 percent this year, according
to the median projection in Bloomberg News surveys last month.
The government set a target for 7.5 percent expansion in 2013. </p>
<p>While the H-share index closed yesterday at the highest
level since Feb. 20, it still traded 19 percent below its
average valuation of the last five years, according to data
compiled by Bloomberg based on estimated earnings. </p>
<p>We''ve been positive for China for quite some time and
it''s an overweight country for us, Allan Conway, who oversees
$27 billion as head of emerging market equities at Schroder
Investment Management in London, said in a phone interview
yesterday. Chinese stocks account for about 22 percent of his
portfolio. The market is attractively priced. </p>
<h2>Copper Bet </h2>
<p>The Shanghai Composite Index (SHCOMP) slipped 0.1 percent to
2,205.56 today. The Bloomberg China-US Equity Index of the most-traded Chinese stocks in New York lost 0.1 percent to 108.17
yesterday while the iShares China Large-Cap ETF, the largest
Chinese exchange-traded fund in the U.S., fell 0.9 percent to
$39.79. The Standard  Poor''s 500 Index dropped 0.3 percent. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs''s Weisberger said buying the H-share and
selling copper futures may generate a combined return of 25
percent next year. </p>
<p>While stability in China''s growth is enough to boost risk
sentiment after the H-share index fell 12 percent over the
past three years, it''s insufficient to lift demand for copper as
a supply glut weighs on the market, he said. </p>
<p>We think the current context is a little bit different
whereas whatever growth acceleration we are going to see in the
coming year is going to be a developed market theme, said
Weisberger. When the economic growth is driven by the
developed market, it''s going to leave the commodity behind. </p>
<h2>Treasury Yields </h2>
<p>Weisberger ended a recommendation to buy China''s H shares
in November 2011 after the trade lost 5 percent. The Hang Seng
China index rallied about 22 percent in the three months after
he advised clients to exit the bet. </p>
<p>The H-share wager is the fourth top trade recommended by
Goldman for 2014. The other recommendations include buying SP
500 futures while selling the Australian dollar; betting
European interest rate swaps will decline while five-year
Treasury yields will rise; and selling the Canadian dollar. </p>
<p>In yesterday''s trading in New York, SouFun Holdings Ltd. (SFUN),
the nation''s biggest real estate website owner, gained the most
among Chinese companies, surging 11 percent to $71.85. E-House
China Holdings Ltd. (EJ), a real-estate service provider, rose 6.3
percent to $11.35. </p>
<p>Hollysys Automation Technologies Ltd., (HOLI) an automation system
manufacturer, declined 5.7 percent to $17.90. The company said
on Dec. 1 that Chairman and Chief Executive Officer Changli Wang
resigned. Jianfeng He, who was chief operating officer, was
elected chairman, while Baiqing Shao, a senior vice president,
will become CEO. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sharon Smyth" date="Dec 02, 2013  1:29 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-02/goldman-blackstone-said-to-abandon-madrid-home-auction.html"><headline>Goldman, Blackstone Said to Abandon Madrid Home Auction</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Spain''s bad bank will sell 437
million euros ($592 million) of loans to Realia Business SA (RLIA) at a
46 percent discount to their face value to Fortress Investment
Group LLC (FIG), two people with knowledge of the matter said. </p>
<p>At least nine funds expressed an interest in buying the
debt from Sareb, as the Spanish bank is known, one of the people
said. They both asked not to be identified because the
information is private. </p>
<p>Spain set up Sareb last year to absorb 50.8 billion euros
in real estate assets from lenders including the Bankia group
that took state aid. Sareb has raised 1.7 billion euros this
year, beating its target of 1.5 billion euros, Deputy Economy
Minister Fernando Jimenez Latorre said at a conference in Madrid
last month. </p>
<p>A spokeswoman for Madrid-based Sareb declined to comment. A
spokesman for Fortress, based in New York, also wouldn''t
comment. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Bristow and Andrew Willis" date="Dec 02, 2013 12:42 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-02/cocaine-for-venezuela-fuel-tankers-irks-colombia-tax-boss.html"><headline>Cocaine for Venezuela Fuel Tankers Irks Colombia Tax Boss</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Criminal gangs are shipping the equivalent of 60 to 100 tanker trucks of subsidized Venezuelan fuel per day into Colombia, much of it paid for with cocaine, according to the Colombian government. </p> <p>Between 10 percent and 15 percent of fuel used by Colombian drivers is smuggled from neighboring countries, Juan Ricardo Ortega, the head of the nation''s tax and customs agency DIAN, said in a Nov. 28 interview in Bogota. That''s led to a slump in fuel duties collected by the government and a warning to BHP Billiton Ltd. (BHP), Anglo American Plc. (AAL) and Glencore Xstrata Plc. (GLEN)''s Cerrejon coal complex over the source of fuel for its trucks. Cerrejon said it''s investigating the situation. </p> <p>Tankers are loading up on gasoline and diesel purchased near the border in Venezuela''s Zulia state for about one cent a gallon and driving into Colombia abetted by corrupt government officials and local politicians, according to Ortega. The Colombian state has zero control over the border province of La Guajira in the northeast of the country, which has a centuries-old smuggling tradition, Ortega said. </p> <p>Clearly the DIAN, the Governor of the department, employees of the department and the police are incredibly corrupt, he said. In Venezuela, the state police are particularly involved. They lost all control of the police in Zulia. </p>




Photographer: Jimmy Pirela/AFP via Getty Images

<p>
A member of the National Guard looks after 2.6 tons of cocaine seized in Maracaibo, Zulia state, northwest of Venezuela, on April 25, 2013. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lisa Abramowicz" date="Dec 02, 2013 12:15 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-02/morgan-stanley-adds-junk-debt-analyst-corsair-from-shrinking-ubs.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Adds Junk-Debt Analyst Corsair From Shrinking UBS</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) hired high-yield debt
analyst Todd Corsair from UBS AG as the fourth-largest
underwriter of U.S. corporate bonds bolsters its position and
the Swiss firm reduces the size of its investment bank. </p>
<p>Corsair, who was with UBS for four years, started as an
executive director in Morgan Stanley''s New York office last
week. Lauren Bellmare, a Morgan Stanley spokeswoman, confirmed
the move in a telephone interview. </p>
<p>While Morgan Stanley has grabbed market share as a manager
of dollar-denominated bond sales since its sixth-place ranking
in 2011, UBS has slid to 14th, its lowest position on record,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg that excludes deals in
which banks manage their own offerings. UBS (UBSN) cut its investment-banking staff by 17 percent in the year ended Sept. 30 to 11,877
people globally, regulatory filings show. </p>
<p>New York-based Morgan Stanley hired Daniel Driscoll from
Nomura Holdings Inc. last month for investment-grade bond
trading in the U.S., and increased its staff by 1.5 percent in
six months to 56,101 employees on Sept. 30, Bloomberg data show. </p>
<p>Corsair worked at Bear Stearns Cos. for almost seven years
before joining UBS in August 2009, according to records
maintained by Financial Industry Regulatory Authority. His move
follows the October departure of Daniel Frommer, a junk-debt
trader at UBS since 2009 who had also worked at Bear Stearns,
Finra records show. </p>
<p>Megan Stinson, a UBS spokeswoman, declined to comment on
the departures. </p>
<p>UBS said last year it would exit some debt-related
businesses at the investment bank as Swiss regulators place
tougher capital and liquidity rules on the largest firms.
Switzerland''s biggest bank was the 10th biggest underwriter of
U.S. corporate bonds in 2012, Bloomberg data show. </p>
<p>High-yield, high-risk debt is rated below Baa3 by Moody''s
Investors Service and lower than BBB- at Standard  Poor''s. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Cliff Edwards" date="Dec 03, 2013  7:22 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-03/microsoft-reports-record-xbox-one-sales-11-days-after-debut-1-.html"><headline>Microsoft Reports Record Xbox One Sales Following Debut</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) said it''s selling
every Xbox One player it can make, after introducing the new
game console on Nov. 22. </p>
<p>Sales are setting records, the Redmond, Washington-based
software maker said yesterday in a statement, without being more
specific. Users have already spent more than 50 million hours on
games and entertainment, Microsoft said. </p>
<p>Demand is far exceeding supply in the 13 countries we''ve
launched and we are sold out at retailers around the world,
Yusuf Mehdi, vice president of strategy and marketing for Xbox,
said in the statement. </p>
<p>Microsoft may not want to issue a lower number than the 2.1
million units that Sony Corp. (6758) reported it had sold as of Dec. 1
for the PlayStation 4, said Michael Pachter, an analyst at
Wedbush Securities in Los Angeles. The software maker limited
its Xbox introduction to 13 countries, from 21 initially
planned, to make sure larger markets had sufficient supplies,
and reported first-day sales of more than 1 million. </p>
<p>A spokesman for Microsoft with Edelman public relations
declined to comment yesterday beyond the statement. </p>
<p>Sony (SNE), which introduced the PlayStation 4 starting Nov. 15,
said yesterday its tally included about 700,000 units purchased
by consumers in Europe and Australasian markets after the player
went on sale in those regions Nov. 29. </p>
<p>Each company probably has factory capacity to make
1 million consoles a month, said Pachter. About 55 percent of
the 4.5 million PlayStation 4s produced by the end of January
will go to North American retailers, he estimated. </p>
<p>Microsoft, the world''s largest software maker, fell 0.4
percent to $38.31 yesterday in New York. The stock has gained 43
percent this year. </p>
<p>Sony American depositary receipts fell 1 percent $18.41 and
have gained 64 percent this year. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Gaspard Sebag" date="Dec 03, 2013  7:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-03/jpmorgan-said-to-snub-euribor-deal-as-eu-readies-bank-fines.html"><headline>JPMorgan Said to Snub Euribor Deal as EU Readies Bank Fines</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. and two other banks rejected a European Union deal to end an antitrust probe into the rigging of Euribor lending rates, risking higher fines and challenging the future of the EU''s settlement process. </p> <p>The EU is seeking to announce two sets of settlements as soon as today with banks accused of colluding to rig the London interbank offered rate and Euribor, according to a person familiar with the EU''s probe who asked not to be identified because the process is private. </p> <p>While global fines for rate-rigging have already topped $3.7 billion, the cost to banks may climb as they face lawsuits worldwide. An EU accord includes a finding of liability that can be used in civil cases. </p> <p>JPMorgan joined HSBC Holdings Plc and Credit Agricole SA in pulling out of the Euribor settlement talks, according to the person. ICAP Plc won''t take part in the Libor settlement process, which relates to the yen, the Financial Times reported yesterday, without saying where it got the information. </p> <p>Rejecting a settlement and facing a higher fine could be worth the risk, said Noelle Lenoir, a lawyer at Kramer Levin Naftalis  Frankel LLP in Paris. </p> <p>Companies know full well that admitting to what they are charged with would be a money pit, she said. </p>




Photographer: Peter Foley/Bloomberg

<p>
While JPMorgan, the biggest U.S. lender by assets, decided to pull out of the Euribor deal, the U.S. bank is part of the yen-Libor settlement, according to a person familiar with the probe. The set of evidence is different in both cases, said the person. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Charles Mead" date="Dec 03, 2013  5:59 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-03/microsoft-said-to-plan-benchmark-bond-deals-in-dollars-euros.html"><headline>Microsoft Raises $8 Billion With Bond Offering in Dollars, Euros</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) sold $8 billion of
bonds in dollars and euros, a record offering from the world''s
largest software maker that followed Johnson  Johnson by
issuing AAA rated corporate securities this week. </p>
<p>Microsoft borrowed $3.25 billion with five-, 10- and 30-year notes in the U.S. currency, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. The Redmond, Washington-based company also issued 3.5
billion euros ($4.8 billion) of bonds split between eight- and
15-year portions. </p>
<p>Top-ranked borrowers are seeking to raise cash from the
bond market even as investors favor the higher yields of lower-rated debt amid speculation the Federal Reserve will soon taper
stimulus measures that pushed interest rates to record lows. The
Bank of America Merrill Lynch AAA U.S. Corporate Index has lost
4.2 percent this year, compared with a 6.9 percent gain for
dollar-denominated speculative-grade securities. </p>
<p>Proceeds will fund general corporate purposes, Microsoft
said in regulatory filings today. The euro sale is more than six
times the size of its only previous issue in the currency of 550
million euros in 20-year notes that won a record-low 2.625
percent coupon for similar-maturity nonfinancial corporate bonds
on April 25, Bloomberg data show. That sale coincided with
almost $2 billion of dollar debt issued in three parts. </p>




Photographer: Kiyoshi Ota/Bloomberg

<p>
Microsoft Corp. is marketing 3.5 billion euros ($4.75 billion) of bonds split between eight- and 15-year portions. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Dec 03, 2013  9:26 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-03/morgan-stanley-queried-by-sec-over-accounting-mistakes.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Queried by SEC Over Accounting Mistakes</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The Securities and Exchange
Commission asked Morgan Stanley (MS) about multiple significant
deficiencies in its financial reporting after the firm
corrected accounting errors involving loan cash flows, income
taxes and derivatives contracts. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley said that while its Sarbanes-Oxley program
identified defects that affected risk assessment and monitoring
controls, the overall design and operation of its control
framework was effective, according to letters between the
company and regulator that were released today. </p>
<p>Deficiencies were caught in a timely manner and errors
weren''t material, the New York-based firm said in the letters. </p>
<p>The correspondence cited passages that included Morgan
Stanley''s 10-K annual report for 2012. The SEC said its review
was completed in an Oct. 17 letter. </p>
<p>Wesley McDade, a spokesman for Morgan Stanley in New York,
declined to comment on the filings. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jon Menon" date="Dec 03, 2013  7:44 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-03/jpmorgan-says-paid-gbp7m-to-advise-co-op-bank-on-britannia-deal.html"><headline>JPMorgan Says Paid GBP7m to Advise Co-Op Bank on Britannia Deal</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The company was paid GBP2m on the
announcement of the transaction with the remainder paid on
completion of the deal, Tim Wise, managing director of U.K.
investment banking said.
* Wise told Treasury Committee it is prepared to advise against
deals that aren''t suitable
* Says gave prudent advice to Co-Op on Britannia
* Wise says personal reputational damage is a potential downside
for an adviser when deals don''t work </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Katie Linsell" date="Dec 03, 2013  7:40 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-03/microsoft-boosting-u-s-bond-sales-in-euros-to-most-since-2008.html"><headline>Microsoft Boosting U.S. Bond Sales in Euros to Most Since 2008</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) and Bank of America
Corp. (BAC) are marketing bonds in euros, spurring deals in the
currency from U.S. borrowers to the most since 2008. </p>
<p>American companies have raised 39 billion euros ($53
billion) from debt sales this year, compared with 20 billion
euros in 2012, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. The
average yield gap between investment-grade bonds in euros and
dollars is 1.3 percent, approaching the widest discount for
borrowers in the common currency since Sept. 13, Bank of America
Merrill Lynch index data show. </p>
<p>The European Central Bank''s decision to cut its benchmark
rate last month as it seeks to boost a sputtering recovery in
the 17-nation bloc helped extend the advantage for borrowers in
euros. Speculation the Federal Reserve will start reducing
stimulus increased yesterday when data showed U.S. manufacturing
grew in November at the fastest pace in more than two years. </p>
<p>The euro market is much cheaper than the dollar market
today, said Microsoft Treasurer George Zinn in an e-mailed
response to questions. We are being opportunistic and looking
at rates across the globe. We can use the proceeds from these
bonds for any general, domestic purpose. </p>




Photographer: Mike Fuentes/Bloomberg

<p>
The Redmond, Washington-based company is selling 1.75 billion euros of eight-year bonds at 50 basis points more than the mid-swap rate and 1.75 billion euros of 15-year notes at a spread of 75 basis points. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sharon Smyth" date="Dec 03, 2013  5:53 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-03/goldman-blackstone-said-to-abandon-madrid-home-auction.html"><headline>Spain Sareb Said to Sell Debt to Fortress at 46% Discount</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Spain''s bad bank will sell 437
million euros ($592 million) of loans taken by Realia Business
SA (RLIA) to Fortress Investment Group LLC (FIG) for 46 percent less than
their face value, two people with knowledge of the matter said. </p>
<p>In addition to the New York-based private-equity firm, at
least eight funds expressed interest in buying the debt from the
Madrid-based bank known as Sareb, one of the people said. Both
asked not to be identified because the information is private. </p>
<p>The government set up Sareb last year to absorb 50.8
billion euros in real estate assets from lenders including the
Bankia group that took state aid after the Spanish property
market slumped. Sareb has raised 1.7 billion euros this year,
beating its target of 1.5 billion euros, Deputy Economy Minister
Fernando Jimenez Latorre said at a conference in Madrid last
month. </p>
<p>Realia, Spain''s second-largest publicly traded real estate
company by market value, reported a nine-month net loss of 17.3
million euros and net financial debt of 2.2 billion euros. Last
month, the Bankia group and Fomento de Construcciones y
Contratas SA, which together own about 58 percent of Realia,
hired Goldman Sachs Group Inc. to seek buyers for their stakes. </p>
<p>Realia rose as much as 2.2 percent in Madrid trading and
was up little changed at 91 cents as of 11:52 a.m. The stock has
climbed 21 percent this year, giving the company a market value
of 251 million euros. </p>
<p>A spokeswoman for Sareb declined to comment. A spokesman
for Fortress, based in New York, also wouldn''t comment. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Mariko Ishikawa and Yumi Ikeda" date="Dec 04, 2013 11:59 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-04/morgan-stanley-sees-jgb-drop-meaning-linkers-swaps-recommended.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Sees JGB Decline Meaning Linkers Recommended</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Investors should buy inflation-linked
debt and use swaps for protection against a potentially volatile
drop in Japanese government bonds as the nation exits from
deflation, Morgan Stanley MUFG Securities Co. said. </p>
<p>The main scenario is for gradually higher rates, Tatsuo Ichikawa, the co-head of fixed income in Tokyo at the joint
venture between Morgan Stanley and Mitsubishi UFJ Financial
Group Inc., said in an interview on Dec. 3. But when the JGB
market sells off, it could be volatile. </p>
<p>The recommendation comes as unprecedented monetary easing
by the Bank of Japan bolsters confidence the nation will break
free of a deflationary spiral that had lasted for more than a
decade. An expert panel advising Japan''s Government Pension
Investment Fund, which owns about 7 percent of outstanding JGBs,
said last month the world''s largest manager of retirement
savings should consider buying inflation-linked debt. </p>
<p>The yield gap between nominal paper and similar-maturity
inflation notes signals a 0.98 percent annual increase in
consumer prices over 10 years, about half of BOJ''s 2 percent
target. The rate takes into account the raising of sales tax
starting April and implies about 0.7 percent inflation when
adjusted for the higher levy, Ichikawa said. </p>
<p>Consumer prices excluding fresh food, the BOJ''s gauge for
its target, rose 0.9 percent from a year earlier, a fifth
straight gain and the most since 2008, data showed Nov. 29. </p>
<h2>Asset Swaps </h2>
<p>Investors can also protect against an increase in yields by
receiving the floating rate on swaps while using coupons from
20-year bonds to pay the fixed rate, according to Ichikawa. </p>
<p>The yen will continue to cheapen and that should put more
pressure on long-end swaps relative to JGBs, he said. The
yen could have weakened even without BOJ easing because compared
to last year, the global economy is normalized. It could be that
the BOJ is doing too much too late. </p>
<p>Japan''s 20-year swap rates have risen faster than similar-maturity government bond yields in the past month, with the gap
between the two expanding to 9.2 basis points on Dec. 3, the
widest since May 31. A basis point is 0.01 percentage point. </p>
<p>The yen has fallen 14 percent against a basket of nine
other developed-nation currencies this year, the worst performer
within the Bloomberg Correlation-Weighted Indexes. It traded at
102.23 per dollar at 1:53 p.m. in Tokyo today, after sliding to
103.38 on Dec. 3, the weakest since May 23. </p>
<p>Real gross domestic product will expand next year at 1.55
percent annualized pace in Japan and at 2.6 percent in the U.S.,
economists in Bloomberg polls forecast. </p>
<h2>Cheap Linkers </h2>
<p>The Ministry of Finance resumed selling inflation-linked
bonds in October after a five-year hiatus, offering 300 billion
yen ($2.9 billion) of the securities with an added a guarantee
of the principal upon maturity to sweeten the deal. </p>
<p>Fund managers agree the current JGB linkers are very
cheap Ichikawa said. After the strong CPI print last Friday,
we started to see some buyers of new linkers. </p>
<p>His investment recommendation chimes with that given by the
expert panel advising Japan''s GPIF. </p>
<p>It would be a huge game changer, Ichikawa said of GPIF
buying of inflation-linked debt. Other pension funds will
probably follow. Then there should be huge additional interest
from people who are likely to be buy-and-hold investors. </p>
<p>The 10-year inflation-linked bonds issued on Oct. 8 were
priced at 104.65, higher than the 102.55 estimated by 11 traders
surveyed by Bloomberg News. The Ministry of Finance will next
offer 10-year linkers on Jan. 9. </p>
<p>The BOJ may allow benchmark 10-year bond yields to climb
1.1 percent should inflation stay above 1 percent or even
approach 1.5 percent, Ichikawa said. Benchmark yields won''t
surpass 1 percent until the first quarter of 2015, according to
a Bloomberg poll. The 10-year bond yield was at 0.625 percent
today. It dropped to a record 0.315 percent on April 5. </p>
<p>The longer the BOJ artificially keeps the nominal long-end yields low, the magnitude of the shock when they taper
increases, Ichikawa said. They need to start communicating
to the market or even test the market on how they react. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrea Tan and Chris Dolmetsch" date="Dec 04, 2013 11:01 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-04/goldman-sachs-sued-by-singapore-client-oei-over-loss.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Sued by Singapore Client Oei Over Loss</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) was sued by Singaporean wealth-management client Oei Hong Leong over a $34.3 million loss on Brazilian real-yen options trades he claimed the bank misled him into making. </p> <p>Oei accused the New York-based bank of fraudulent misrepresentation, breach of fiduciary duty, fraudulent inducement and unjust enrichment in papers filed yesterday in New York state court. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs rejected allegations that it acted improperly or cheated him, according to a letter it wrote to Oei in July and filed in a Singapore court, where the businessman is suing a unit of the bank over the same loss. The bank has said it will defend that lawsuit, which it is seeking to halt in favor of private and confidential arbitration. </p> <p>A lot of clients are like me, they trust the big banks like they trust their doctors, Oei, 65, said in an interview today. His friends have had similar experiences and he is suing for justice and fairness for all clients, he said. </p> <p>Andrea Raphael, a spokeswoman for Goldman Sachs in New York, said Oei''s lawsuit is without merit and will be defended. </p> <p>Oei said in the New York lawsuit that he cut dealings with Goldman Sachs in 2011 after it profited on a losing trade it persuaded him to make. He said he resumed transactions after senior executives including President Gary Cohn and Asia head David Ryan visited him in April 2012 and said his interests would be placed first. </p>




Photographer: Daniel Acker/Bloomberg

<p>
A patch bearing the Goldman Sachs Group Inc. logo is pictured on a trading jacket on the floor of the New York Stock Exchange in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Callie Bost" date="Dec 04, 2013  5:37 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-04/general-growth-properties-to-replace-molex-in-s-p-500.html"><headline>General Growth Properties to Replace Molex in S&amp;amp;P 500</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>General Growth Properties Inc., the
second-biggest U.S. mall owner, will replace Molex Inc. in the
Standard  Poor''s 500 Index (SPX), SP Dow Jones Indices said in a
statement today. </p>
<p>General Growth is a Chicago-based real-estate investment
trust with a market value of about $18.5 billion. Its shares
have risen 2.2 percent in 2013, compared with the 26 percent
gain in the SP 500. Molex, a 75-year-old maker of electronic
components, is being removed from the index after agreeing to be
acquired by privately held Koch Industries Inc. </p>
<p>The SP 500 change will take place after the close of
trading on Dec. 9, SP Dow Jones said. The revisions in the
benchmark equity index may prompt money managers to shift
holdings to match it. About $5.14 trillion is benchmarked to the
gauge, according to the SP Dow Jones website. </p>
<p>General Growth shares rose 0.1 percent to $20.28 in regular
trading. The stock jumped 5 percent to $21.30 in extended
trading at 5:26 p.m. New York time after the close of U.S.
exchanges. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Aoife White" date="Dec 04, 2013 12:18 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-04/microsoft-wins-eu-approval-for-5-44-billion-euro-nokia-deal.html"><headline>Microsoft Wins EU Approval for 5.44 Billion-Euro Nokia Deal</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) won European Union
approval for its 5.44 billion-euro ($7.4 billion) bid to take
over Nokia Oyj (NOK1V)''s handset business as regulators warned that they
would monitor Nokia''s licensing practices. </p>
<p>The European Commission said it will remain vigilant and
closely monitor Nokia''s post-merger licensing practices under EU
antitrust rules, according to an e-mailed statement. Any
possible competition concerns over Nokia''s conduct as the owner
of a portfolio of smartphone patents falls outside the scope
of the EU''s review of the Microsoft transaction. </p>
<p>Microsoft''s bid for Nokia''s mobile-phone business didn''t
raise any antitrust issues because the companies'' businesses
only have a minimal overlap, the EU said. Microsoft is
unlikely to restrict the supply of its Windows operating system
for mobile phones or its mobile apps or to restrict rivals''
access to its business mail service. </p>
<p>The world''s largest software maker will pay 3.79 billion
euros for Nokia''s devices division and 1.65 billion euros to
license patents, according to a statement from the companies.
Microsoft and Nokia face an EU antitrust complaint filed by
Google Inc. last year that alleged the companies were using
patents to thwart competition. </p>
<h2>Google Complaint </h2>
<p>Microsoft has also complained in its own name and as part
of industry groups over Google''s Android operating system for
mobile phones and its search engine. </p>
<p>Microsoft is pleased that the European Commission has
cleared the deal without conditions, Robin Koch, a spokesman
for the company in Brussels, said in an e-mail. </p>
<p>The Redmond, Washington-based company won approval from the
EU for the deal more than eight months after it was fined 561
million euros by the same regulator for violating the terms of
an antitrust settlement to give users a choice of Web browsers.
The penalty was the fourth levied on Microsoft by the EU since
it was fined 497 million euros in 2004 for blocking rivals for
server and media programs. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Antony Sguazzin" date="Dec 04, 2013 10:44 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-04/microsoft-co-founder-paul-allen-to-fund-african-elephant-survey.html"><headline>Microsoft Co-Founder Allen to Fund African Elephant Survey</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Paul Allen, who co-founded Microsoft Corp. with Bill Gates, will fund a survey of the number of elephants in Africa to help combat poaching that is claiming the life of one of the pachyderms every 15 minutes. </p> <p>The family trust of Allen, who''s worth $15.7 billion according to the Bloomberg Billionaires Index, will fund an $8 million count of the animals in 13 countries using three fixed-wing airplanes and two helicopters, Botswana-based Elephants Without Borders said today in an e-mailed statement. </p> <p>This is the bleakest time for the elephants, Allen, 60, said in the statement. Statistics on the plight of Africa''s elephants are daunting. </p> <p>A fifth of Africa''s elephants may be wiped out over the next decade if poaching continues at its current pace, with about 22,000 killed last year, the Convention on International Trade in Endangered Species, Traffic and the International Union for Conservation of Nature said in a Dec. 2 statement. The animals are poached for their ivory tusks. </p> <p>Estimates of the African elephant population vary between 410,000 and 650,000 and in some countries there haven''t been surveys for many years, Elephants Without Borders said. They are now found in 35 African nations, down from an initial 46, and in 20 of those they number less than 1,000. </p>




Photographer: Ramin Talaie/Bloomberg

<p>
Microsoft Corp. co-founder Paul Allen said, This is the bleakest time for the elephants. Statistics on the plight of Africa''s elephants are daunting. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Katie Linsell and Charles Mead" date="Dec 04, 2013  6:21 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-04/microsoft-favors-europe-for-record-bond-sale-corporate-finance.html"><headline>Microsoft Favors Europe for Record Bond Sale: Corporate Finance</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), which issued the
first euro-denominated bond in its 38-year history in April, is
favoring the currency in its biggest sale ever, taking advantage
of a widening discount to dollar borrowing costs. </p>
<p>The world''s largest software maker sold 3.5 billion euros
($4.8 billion) of bonds yesterday to account for more than half
of an $8 billion issue. Corporations are paying 1.13 percentage
points less to borrow in euros than dollars for debt of five to
10 years, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. Two years
ago, the relationship was reversed, with euro yields eclipsing
dollar rates by 1.2 percentage points. </p>
<p>When Microsoft sold notes in April, the discount was only
0.47 percentage point, and the company''s debut euro bond
comprised about a quarter of a $2.67 billion issue. The Redmond,
Washington-based company''s newest offering adds to about 40
billion euros of issuance by American companies in 2013, almost
double the amount sold in 2012, as the European Central Bank
cuts interest rates. </p>
<p>You''ve got a confluence of events between monetary
policy, interest rates and overall demand from investors, and an
improving basis, all of which has made it very attractive to
issue in euros, said Jim Glascott, head of global debt capital
markets at Barclays Plc, which helped manage the Microsoft
offering. The demand and the attractiveness of euros is
something that''s definitely going to affect volumes in 2014. </p>




Photographer: Krisztian Bocsi/Bloomberg

<p>
A pedestrian shelters under an umbrella as she passes outside the digital eatery in Microsoft Corp.''s new store in Berlin. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Harris" date="Dec 05, 2013  3:09 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-05/goldman-sachs-suits-over-aluminum-set-for-venue-hearing.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Suits Over Aluminum Set for Venue Hearing</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The bankers are in New York, the
exchange is in London and the aluminum is stored mostly around
Detroit. The buyers of the metal suing over allegations of price
manipulation are scattered across the U.S. </p>
<p>The roughly 25 cases filed in varying combinations against
Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), their
warehousing businesses and the London Metal Exchange should be
fought in New York, New Orleans or elsewhere, lawyers for the
factions argued before a panel of federal judges today. </p>
<p>The defendants are accused of constricting aluminum
supplies to drive up prices in violation of U.S. antitrust law. </p>
<p>The monopoly allegedly occurred in Detroit, said
Christopher Lovell, who filed the first of the lawsuits on Aug.
1 on behalf of Gwinn, Michigan-based aluminum fabricator
Superior Extrusion Inc. </p>
<p>The restraint of trade emanated from Detroit, where
75 percent of the warehoused aluminum in the U.S. is stored,
Lovell told six members of the federal Judicial Panel on
Multidistrict Litigation in federal court in Las Vegas. </p>
<p>Accusing Goldman and LME of tying up 1.5 million tons of
aluminum and then charging above-market rates for its storage,
Superior Extrusion is seeking class status on behalf of buyers
who faced the same situation and unspecified money damages that
would be tripled under federal antitrust laws. </p>
<h2>Later Complaints </h2>
<p>Later complaints make similar allegations and demands. Most
of the suits were filed in Detroit, four were brought in New
York and others in Boston, New Orleans and Los Angeles. </p>
<p>The panel consolidates cases to streamline the pretrial
exchange of evidence and taking of depositions. </p>
<p>The primary means by which defendants accomplished their
goal was to hoard, stockpile and manipulate the supply of
physical aluminum stored in their warehouses in Detroit,
Lovell argued in a court filing. </p>
<p>Michael DuVally, a spokesman for Goldman Sachs and Brian Marchiony, a spokesman for JPMorgan Chase, have each said the
cases are without merit. Both banks are based in New York. </p>
<p>The center of gravity in the United States, if it''s
anywhere, is in New York, attorney Margaret Zwisler argued
before the panel today on behalf of JPMorgan Chase and the
London Metal Exchange. </p>
<h2>Aluminum Rules </h2>
<p>The issue here is who made the rules and how were they
made, Zwisler said. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs waived its right to argue before the panel,
from which appellate Judge Marjorie Rendell was absent. </p>
<p>Detroit is the world''s second-biggest repository for
aluminum stockpiles monitored by LME, the world''s largest
industrial metals marketplace. Goldman Sachs''s Metro
International Trade Services LLC has the most LME-approved
warehouses in the city. </p>
<p>Delays of as long as 16 months in filling aluminum orders
raised prices for consumer-product makers, according to brewer
MillerCoors LLC, which hasn''t sued, and flashlight maker Mag
Instrument Inc., which did. Mag, based in Ontario, California,
named Goldman, Metro International and LME as defendants in a
complaint filed in Los Angeles federal court in August. </p>
<p>Garrett Wotkyns, Mag''s attorney, described a merry-go-round of metal, as warehouse operators shifted inventory from
one site to another to satisfy output requirements without
actually relinquishing control of aluminum stockpiles. Other
lawyers today made similar assertions. </p>
<h2>Not Simple </h2>
<p>Asked by panel member U.S. District Judge Paul Barbadoro
whether the defendants would dispute that such inventory
movements occurred in Detroit, Zwisler replied, it''s not that
simple. </p>
<p>Whether their truck moved from one warehouse to another
does not mean there''s something wrong with that, she said. </p>
<p>Plaintiffs'' lawyer Samuel Rudman, arguing for case
consolidation in New York, where he sued on behalf of Peterson
Industries Inc., said truck drivers won''t necessarily be
witnesses in the case. </p>
<p>LME told members last month it was changing its rules to
accelerate withdrawals from depots where waiting times are
exceeding 50 calendar days. </p>
<p>Under the changes, slated to take effect April 1,
warehouses with excessive delays will be required to ship at
least 1,500 metric tons more metal each day than they take in. </p>
<h2>Warehouse Review </h2>
<p>The exchange also said it would review its warehouse system
every six months and is studying its powers to regulate
warehousing companies'' charges. </p>
<p>Wotkyns, whose client makes the Maglite-brand flashlight,
asked the panel to have the cases heard in Los Angeles, citing
the experience of that court''s judges and its capacity to handle
the caseload. Phillip Howard, an attorney for Jacksonville,
Florida-based pool deck-enclosure maker Master Screens Inc.,
made similar arguments in support of its preferred venue,
Tallahassee, Florida. </p>
<p>The panel heard about 45 minutes of argument today. It
didn''t immediately rule. </p>
<p>The case is In Re Aluminum Warehousing Antitrust
Litigation, MDL No. 2481, Judicial Panel on Multidistrict
Litigation (Las Vegas). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kevin Dugan" date="Dec 05, 2013  2:26 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-05/jpmorgan-s-largest-note-since-2010-tied-to-own-futures-index.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Largest Note Since 2010 Tied to Own Futures Index</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) sold $234.7
million of structured notes tied to a proprietary gauge of seven
futures indexes, its largest U.S. offering in at least four
years. </p>
<p>The five-year securities, issued Nov. 22, yield the gains
and losses of the JPMorgan Enhanced Beta Select Backwardation
Alternative Benchmark Total Return Index, according to a
prospectus filed with the U.S. Securities and Exchange
Commission. The gauge consists of seven other indexes tied to
prices of commodities futures from gold to lean hogs. </p>
<p>The index rebalances monthly, based on weightings of its
members in the Dow Jones-UBS Commodity Index, the most popular
commodity benchmark for structured notes this year, according to
data compiled by Bloomberg. Its level rises and falls with
market prices and its members can change weekly to favor
commodities showing the most backwardation, where earlier
contracts cost more than later deliveries, according to the
prospectus. </p>
<p>A backwardated market is by no means indicative of prices
falling into the future, said Stephen Schork, president of the
Schork Group Inc., a consultant to the energy industry in
Villanova, Pennsylvania. The fact that prices are lower in the
future isn''t an indication that demand is going to fall in the
future. It''s just an indication that demand in the spot market
is very strong. </p>
<p>The index was established Sept. 30, less than two months
before the securities were sold, according to the prospectus.
Since then, it fell 0.4 percent to 101.93 yesterday. </p>
<h2>Investor Fees </h2>
<p>The bank charges 0.85 percent a year in investor fees, so
the index would have to rise from its starting level at least
4.25 percent at maturity for the notes to break even. </p>
<p>Backwardation can provide investors with a so-called roll
yield from buying the earlier monthly contract and then
collecting the difference as they sell and transfer into the
next, cheaper month. </p>
<p>Justin Perras, a spokesman for the bank in New York,
declined to comment on the offering. </p>
<p>Banks create structured notes by packaging debt with
derivatives to offer customized bets to retail investors while
earning fees and raising money. Derivatives are contracts with
values derived from stocks, bonds, commodities and currencies,
or events such as changes in interest rates or the weather. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Peter Levring" date="Dec 05, 2013  5:28 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-05/goldman-obtains-veto-right-through-minority-stake-in-dong-energy.html"><headline>Goldman Obtains Veto Right Through Minority Stake in Dong Energy</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc., which is paying $1.5 billion for a minority stake in Dong Energy A/S, will get veto powers enabling it to block strategic decisions, according to a Danish Finance Ministry document. </p> <p>Goldman will be the only minority owner granted broad veto rights over the government-owned utility, according to the Dec. 3 dated document, which is due to be presented to members of the parliament''s Finance Committee next week in Copenhagen. Dong will only be allowed to sell new shares or hybrid capital, change senior management or make acquisitions if it gets prior approval from Goldman, according to the document. </p> <p>Goldman and Danish pension funds ATP and PFA agreed on Oct. 2 to become owners in Denmark''s largest utility, which is shoring up its balance sheet after losing money on failed natural gas bets. The ministry is also asking the committee to approve a plan to list Dong before 2021. Should the company seek an initial public offering before 2018, Goldman and ATP would need to approve the move. </p> <p>The Finance Ministry said the government will retain 56.1 percent to 60 percent of Dong after the sale, valuing the company at at least 42.5 billion kroner ($7.75 billion). The current minority investors, which include local power companies, have the option to acquire new Dong shares for as much as 2.6 billion kroner to avoid diluting their stakes, according to the document. </p>




Photographer: Freya Ingrid Morales/Bloomberg

<p>
Goldman and Danish pension funds ATP and PFA agreed on Oct. 2 to become owners in Dong Energy A/S, Denmark''s largest utility, which is shoring up its balance sheet after losing money on failed natural gas bets. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Terje Langeland" date="Dec 05, 2013  1:39 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-05/microsoft-to-expand-use-of-encryption-to-protect-against-spying.html"><headline>Microsoft to Expand Use of Encryption to Protect Against Spying</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) will expand the use
of encryption to protect customer information, following reports
that governments are intercepting data traveling between users
and servers or between company data centers. </p>
<p>The company will also step up its legal efforts to protect
private data and will make its software code more transparent so
customers can reassure themselves Microsoft''s products don''t
contain back doors allowing access to their information, the
Redmond, Washington-based software company said in a post on its
official blog today. The encryption enhancements will be
completed by the end of next year, it said. </p>
<p>We are taking steps to ensure governments use legal
process rather than technological brute force to access customer
data, Microsoft said. Government snooping potentially now
constitutes an advanced persistent threat'' alongside
sophisticated malware and cyberattacks. </p>
<p>Yahoo! Inc. and Google Inc. have also announced they''ll
beef up encryption, following reports of spying by the U.S.
National Security Agency. The NSA has tapped fiber-optic cables
abroad to siphon data from Google and Yahoo, circumvented or
cracked encryption, and introduced weaknesses and back doors
into coding, according to reports in the Washington Post, the
New York Times and the U.K.''s Guardian newspaper based on
documents released by former NSA contractor Edward Snowden. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Karen Gullo, Sophia Pearson and Ron Musselman" date="Dec 06, 2013  6:06 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-06/jpmorgan-asks-judge-to-keep-draft-u-s-mortgage-lawsuit-secret.html"><headline>JPMorgan Asks Judge to Keep Draft U.S. Fraud Suit Secret</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) had a hearing
behind closed doors with a Pennsylvania judge in its bid to keep
secret a draft of a government lawsuit related to its $13
billion settlement with the U.S. as well as the identity of an
employee who cooperated in a federal probe. </p>
<p>The company is fighting an Oct. 17 order by Judge Stanton
Wettick in Pittsburgh that it release the document and the
employee''s name to lawyers for the Federal Home Loan Bank of
Pittsburgh, who say the material may provide a more detailed
account of the U.S. Justice Department probe of JPMorgan that
could be used in their lawsuit against the New York-based bank. </p>
<p>FHLB has not set forth any facts supporting why it needs
the draft DOJ complaint or what admissible evidence it might
glean from the allegations of a complaint, Deborah Little, a
lawyer for JPMorgan, said in a court filing. FHLB has not
demonstrated any nexus between the DOJ''s investigation and the
subject matter of this case. </p>
<p>Prior to the start of a hearing today, Wettick closed the
courtroom to the public. Lawyers on both sides declined to
comment after the hearing. </p>
<p>The FHLB lost $2.3 billion on mortgage-backed securities it
purchased from JPMorgan. The losses aren''t covered by the record
U.S. settlement resolving allegations that the bank misled
buyers about the soundness and risks of the investments. </p>
<p>JPMorgan, the biggest U.S. lender by assets, is paying the
record settlement to resolve Justice Department probes into the
bank''s sale of mortgage bonds that officials said helped feed
the financial chaos of 2008. </p>
<h2>FHLB''s Case </h2>
<p>The conduct and deals at issue in the settlement are the
same ones at the heart of the FHLB''s case, David Beehler, an
attorney for the Pittsburgh bank, said in court filings. </p>
<p>JPMorgan acknowledged the settlement''s statement of facts
without admitting violations of law, Chief Financial Officer
Marianne Lake said on a Nov. 19 conference call. In the
statement, the official narrative of events leading to the
infractions, the bank acknowledged that from 2005 to 2007 its
subsidiaries securitized subprime and Alt-A mortgages loans and
sold the resulting mortgaged-backed securities to investors
while failing to disclose that the loans didn''t meet
underwriting standards. </p>
<p>The statement doesn''t refer to specific employees,
documents or events. It also doesn''t provide any details about
the loan programs or vendors. </p>
<p>The Pittsburgh bank is suing JPMorgan and credit rating
companies including Moody''s Investors Service over mortgage-backed securities it bought in 2006 and 2007. </p>
<h2>Draft Complaint </h2>
<p>FHLB attorneys persuaded Wettick in October to order
JPMorgan to turn over the draft civil fraud complaint prepared
by U.S. Attorney Benjamin Wagner in Sacramento, California. The
lawsuit alleged violations of the Financial Institution Reform,
Recovery and Enforcement Act of 1989, known as FIRREA, according
to court filings in the case. </p>
<p>The law allows the government to sue an individual or
group, rather than charge them with a crime, for fraud that
affects a federally insured financial institution. </p>
<p>FHLB agreed to give the bank until Nov. 22 to provide the
document at the request of Justice Department lawyers who said
the agency was close to a settlement, according to court
filings. </p>
<p>The accord was announced Nov. 19, and three days later
JPMorgan attorneys notified the FHLB that it would seek to block
Wettick''s order, according to the filings. </p>
<h2>Fraudulent Conduct'' </h2>
<p>Given JPMorgan''s apparent deep desire to prevent it from
ever seeing the light of day, it would not be at all surprising
if the draft complaint is a much more detailed account of
JPMorgan''s fraudulent conduct, and as such, far more
enlightening than the statement of facts, according to the
filing. </p>
<p>JPMorgan said the draft complaint was provided to it by the
Justice Department as a confidential settlement
communication and it agreed to use it solely for the purpose
of settlement negotiations, according to a court filing.
Allowing the document to be turned over to the FHLB would
violate state and federal law and chill the use of such
materials in future settlement negotiations, JPMorgan said. </p>
<h2>Moody''s Case </h2>
<p>In its case against Moody''s, the Pittsburgh bank is seeking
to question Jerome Fons, a former executive of the ratings
company who criticized credit graders to U.S. lawmakers in 2009. </p>
<p>Lawyers for the FHLB have asked Wettick to allow them to
question Fons on his testimony in a case against Morgan Stanley (MS)
and other banks in federal court in Manhattan. That testimony,
under seal after the case was voluntarily dismissed, was given
to plaintiff lawyers in Pittsburgh. Moody''s argued in court
papers filed Nov. 20 that a deposition of Fons would provide
no evidence relevant to this action and will only place undue
burden on Moody''s. </p>
<p>Fons has no firsthand knowledge of any Moody''s structured
finance analyst ever allowing market share pressure to impact a
particular rating, lawyers for Moody''s said, citing sections
of the sealed testimony transcript. </p>
<h2>House Committee </h2>
<p>Fons told the U.S. House Oversight and Government Reform
Committee in October 2008 that originators of structured
securities typically chose the agency with the lowest standards,
engendering a race to the bottom in terms of rating quality. </p>
<p>The plaintiffs allege Moody''s and other rating companies
assigned the highest possible ratings to mortgage-loan pools so
they could be sold to institutional investors all the while
knowing the certificates were actually junk bonds, according to
court papers. </p>
<p>Fons, formerly a Moody''s managing director for credit, left
the firm in August 2007. Until his departure, he helped set
criteria for how the firm rated the debt of corporations,
financial institutions and countries. </p>
<p>The truth is that the rating agencies did not have
sufficient and reliable information to place a triple-A rating
on the securities, the Pittsburgh bank said in court papers.
The rating agencies and other defendants knew they were
feeding false information into their predictive models and that
those models could not predict the losses on the loans in the
mortgage pools. </p>
<p>The case is Federal Home Loan Bank of Pittsburgh v. J.P.
Morgan Securities LLC, GD09-016892, Court of Common Pleas of
Allegheny County, Pennsylvania (Pittsburgh). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sebastian Boyd" date="Dec 06, 2013  7:36 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-06/goldman-led-hunt-for-corpbanca-suitor-spurs-rally-andes-credit.html"><headline>Goldman-Led Hunt for Corpbanca Suitor Spurs Rally: Andes Credit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Bond investors are signaling they
want Chilean billionaire Alvaro Saieh to sell his bank. </p>
<p>Corpbanca''s $800 million of notes due 2018 have returned
1.9 percent since the Saieh-controlled bank said Nov. 29 that it
was in preliminary talks with potential bidders. The gain is
bigger than that of any other high-grade bond in emerging
markets, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Saieh, 64, is entertaining offers from Sao Paulo-based Itau
Unibanco Holding SA (ITUB4) and Bilbao, Spain-based Banco Bilbao Vizcaya
Argentaria SA (BBVA) as he looks for cash to plow into his retailer SMU
SA after it violated debt agreements and restated earnings.
Colombia-born Saieh, who has a doctorate in economics from the
University of Chicago, has hired Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and
Bank of America Corp. to sell a controlling stake in Corpbanca,
two people familiar with the matter said Nov. 28. </p>
<p>Being taken in by a bigger, more diverse bank is
positive, Aaron Grehan, who helps manage $4.5 billion of
emerging-market debt at Aviva Investors Ltd., said in telephone
interview from London. It''s a credit-improvement story. The
headlines last week caused a change in sentiment. </p>
<p>The extra yield investors demand to own Corpbanca''s
benchmark notes instead of U.S. Treasuries fell to a five-month
low of 3.13 percentage points yesterday after reaching a record
high of 501 basis points on Aug. 29. The peso gained 0.2 percent
to 528.7 per dollar at 7:35 a.m. in New York. </p>
<p>Corpbanca declined to comment on its merger talks,
according to an external press official who asked not to be
named. </p>
<h2>BBVA, Itau </h2>
<p>Itau, Latin America''s biggest lender by market
capitalization, is one of the banks Corpbanca has approached,
said one of the two people, who asked not to be named because
the negotiations are private. Corpbanca, based in Santiago, has
a market value of $4.22 billion. Saieh and his family directly
and indirectly own 76 percent of the bank, according to its most
recent annual report. </p>
<p>Itau declined to comment, according to an official who
asked not to be named in keeping with company policy. </p>
<p>Paul Tobin, a spokesman for BBVA in Madrid, declined to
comment. </p>
<p>Corpbanca''s BBB rating from Standard  Poor''s, the second-lowest investment grade, is in line with Itau''s and one level
above that of BBVA. Itau has subordinated bonds in dollars due
in 2020 that yield 349 basis points more than U.S. Treasuries.
BBVA''s subordinated bonds in dollars due in 2022 yield 336 basis
points more than Treasuries. </p>
<p>Speculation that Itau or BBVA may buy Saieh''s Corpbanca
hasn''t helped SMU''s bonds. The yield on the bonds rose to 18.58
percent yesterday from 18.4 on Nov. 29. It reached 21 percent on
Oct. 30, up from 6.16 percent in April. </p>
<h2>Severe Issues'' </h2>
<p>Saieh has been selling off assets and has pumped $300
million into SMU in an attempt to help bring the grocery chain
into compliance with rules on its bonds that demand lower debt
ratios. At the end of September, Corpbanca had made more than
$400 million of loans and other credits tied to sister companies
owned by Saieh, and the bank accounted for as much as 90 percent
of his conglomerate''s profit. </p>
<p>SMU has had severe issues with working capital and
consuming all its cash, said Soummo Mukherjee, an analyst at
Moody''s Investors Service who this week cut the company to Caa1,
seven levels below investment grade. Any hiccup in liquidity
would lead to an immediate downgrade. </p>
<h2>Smart Guys'' </h2>
<p>Saieh, a former head of research at the central bank,
started his career in banking when he accepted an equity stake
to join the management of Carlos Abumohor''s Banco de Osorno y La
Union. Saieh and Abumohor sold 51 percent of Banco Osorno to
Spain''s Banco Santander SA (SAN) in 1996 and used the profit to build
Corpbanca. In the past 24 months, Saieh has spent $2.5 billion
buying the Colombian operations of Banco Santander and Helm Bank
to expand Corpbanca''s regional presence. </p>
<p>Itau Chief Executive Officer Roberto Setubal told analysts
on an earning conference call on Nov. 12 that Chile is a
priority market and that the bank is considering acquisitions in
Latin America. </p>
<p>Itau has said it wants to be a Latin American bank, but
it''s hard to grow organically so it needs to buy, Anibal Valdes, an analyst at Barclays Plc in New York, said in a
telephone interview. These are smart guys and they''re not
going to pay just any price but it would make sense to be the
third-largest private bank in Chile. The banking business is all
about scale. </p>
<p>Even after the rally, Corpbanca''s bonds still offer a
premium to peers. The 4.17 percent yield on its notes compares
with an average of 3.45 percent for investment-grade banks in
Latin America, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>It trades at a higher spread than the rest of the banks
so the rationale behind the move makes sense, Jaime Achondo,
head trader at Finanzas y Negocios SA Corredores de Bolsa in
Santiago, said in a telephone interview. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Amy Thomson" date="Dec 06, 2013  6:24 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-06/microsoft-helps-fbi-to-attack-click-stealing-zeroaccess-malware.html"><headline>Microsoft Helps FBI to Attack Click-Stealing ZeroAccess Malware</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT)''s digital crime unit
has teamed up with the U.S. Federal Bureau of Investigation and
its European counterpart to fight software that infected more
than 2 million computers to steal revenue from online
advertisers. </p>
<p>They''re working to track down computers that have been
taken over with the malicious software known as ZeroAccess or
Sirefef, and get rid of the malware, Microsoft said in a
statement. While the effort won''t eliminate the threat, it
should significantly reduce the fraud, which has cost online
advertisers an estimated $2.7 million a month, the Redmond,
Washington-based company said. </p>
<p>The botnet, a group of connected programs, is used to
redirect queries in search engines owned by companies such as
Google Inc., Yahoo! Inc. and Microsoft, to certain sites to
steal money generated by ad clicks. It also creates automated
Web traffic that simulates users'' clicks on ads, for which
advertisers pay. </p>
<p>Due to its botnet architecture, ZeroAccess is one of the
most robust and durable botnets in operation today and was built
to be resilient to disruption efforts, Microsoft said in the
statement. The malware relies on a peer-to-peer infrastructure
that allows cybercriminals to remotely control the botnet from
tens of thousands of different computers. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
Microsoft filed a civil suit against those operating ZeroAccess last week and got authorization from the U.S. District Court for the Western District of Texas to block communications between computers that had been identified as being used to commit the schemes. Microsoft also took control of 49 web domains thought to be affiliated with ZeroAccess. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Greg Stohr" date="Dec 09, 2013  7:19 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-09/pfizer-rejected-by-top-court-on-neurontin-marketing-suits.html"><headline>Pfizer Rejected by Top Court on Neurontin Marketing Suits</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The U.S. Supreme Court left intact a
$142 million award against Pfizer Inc. (PFE) and let two similar suits
go forward with claims that the drugmaker defrauded insurers by
illegally marketing its Neurontin epilepsy drug. </p>
<p>The justices without comment today rejected Pfizer''s
appeal, letting stand three connected federal appeals court
decisions. The cases are part of the fallout from a 2004 guilty
plea by Pfizer''s Warner-Lambert unit to charges that it promoted
Neurontin for unapproved off-label'' uses. </p>
<p>The rebuff means a nationwide class-action suit can
proceed, seeking damages on behalf of insurers, union funds and
employers who paid for ineffective dosages of Neurontin. Pfizer
must also defend against a suit by Aetna Inc. (AET), which says it
paid for more than a million off-label Neurontin prescriptions.
In addition, the world''s biggest drugmaker lost its challenge to
a $142 million jury award won by the Kaiser Foundation''s health
plan and hospitals. </p>
<p>Pfizer strategically conducted a decade-long,
multifaceted fraud to make Neurontin a blockbuster drug,
Kaiser argued in court papers. </p>
<p>Pfizer said in a statement that it has strong defenses on
the merits in the cases that will now proceed in the lower
court. </p>
<h2>Unapproved Uses </h2>
<p>At the Supreme Court, Pfizer argued that the Boston-based
appeals court improperly relaxed the standards for winning a
case under the U.S. Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt
Organizations Act, known as RICO. Pfizer said the appeals court
should have required proof that the company''s marketing affected
the prescriptions issued by individual doctors. </p>
<p>The lower court instead said the insurers could rely on
aggregate data showing a link between Pfizer''s promotional
spending for unapproved uses and the number of off-label
prescriptions written. </p>
<p>The appeals court decisions invite an unlimited
escalation in RICO and related cases against pharmaceutical
companies for off-label promotion using the shortcut of
aggregate proof, the New York-based company argued. </p>
<p>The suing insurers say Pfizer pitched Neurontin as a
treatment for bipolar disorders, neuropathic pain and migraines,
while suppressing or misrepresenting clinical studies that
showed the drug wasn''t effective for those treatments. </p>
<h2>Snake Oil'' </h2>
<p>The insurers point to an internal e-mail describing
Neurontin as the snake oil'' of the twentieth century. </p>
<p>The conduct occurred before Pfizer acquired Warner-Lambert
in 2000. In its 2004 plea agreement, Warner-Lambert admitted it
promoted Neurontin for off-label uses. </p>
<p>Federal law bars drugmakers from promoting uses that
haven''t received Food and Drug Administration approval, though
doctors are free to prescribe medicines for off-label purposes. </p>
<p>Warner-Lambert''s marketing increased off-label sales from
15 percent of all Neurontin prescriptions in 1994, its first
year on the market, to 94 percent of Pfizer''s Neurontin sales in
2002, according to federal government court filings. The drug''s
sales hit $2.3 billion in 2002. </p>
<p>The Aetna and class action cases can now go forward in a
federal district court in Boston. </p>
<p>The Supreme Court case is Pfizer v. Kaiser Foundation,
13-289. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri" date="Dec 10, 2013  5:11 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-10/disney-may-expand-shanghai-park-to-meet-demand-after-2015-debut.html"><headline>Disney May Expand Shanghai Park to Meet Demand After 2015 Debut</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS) may quickly enlarge
its Shanghai resort after it opens in late 2015 in order to meet
rising demand in the world''s most populous country, Chief
Financial Officer Jay Rasulo said. </p>
<p>Shanghai Disney Resort will be almost 1,000 acres (404.7
hectares) in size when it opens, putting it third behind Walt
Disney World in Orlando, Florida, and Disneyland Paris among the
company''s resorts, Rasulo said at the UBS Global Media and
Communications Conference in New York yesterday. </p>
<p>We''re opening the park for a pretty healthy number of
attendees but more importantly both we and our partners and the
Shanghai government are eager and willing to expand rapidly
after that, Rasulo said. </p>
<p>Attendance could ultimately top the company''s second-most
popular property, Tokyo Disney Resort, which has 28 million
annual visitors, Rasulo said, reiterating remarks he made in
September. Disney, the world''s largest theme park operator, is
building a 29 billion-yuan ($4.78 billion) resort in Shanghai
that will include two hotels and an outdoor recreational area. </p>
<p>The Burbank, California-based company owns 43 percent of
the venture with the state-owned Shanghai Shendi Group Co., a
consortium of three businesses, holding the rest. </p>
<p>The resort is part of a larger focus by Disney on China,
where entertainment spending by consumers has lagged the growth
of the middle class, Rasulo said. The new park is within a
three-hour drive of 330 million people, many of them young
families, he said. </p>
<h2>New Attractions </h2>
<p>Disney in the past four years invested in new attractions
at its Hong Kong resort, where business is now growing in
leaps and bounds, Rasulo said. </p>
<p>The company said last month that its capital expenditures
in its current 2014 fiscal year may be about $1 billion higher
than 2013 due to the investment in the Shanghai park. </p>
<p>Last week, Disney announced its first corporate sponsor of
the new park. Industrial  Commercial Bank of China Ltd. will
feature its brand in the Garden of the Twelve Friends, part of
an 11-acre compound at the center of the park where each animal
of the Chinese Zodiac will be represented by a Disney or Pixar
character. </p>
<p>We believe we''re developing a park that will absolutely
blow people away, Rasulo said. </p>
<p>Shares of Disney rose 0.6 percent to $71.57 at the close in
New York yesterday. The stock has gained 44 percent this year. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Marie Mawad and Caroline Hyde" date="Dec 10, 2013 10:11 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-10/microsoft-s-nadella-says-he-ll-stay-whatever-ceo-choice.html"><headline>Microsoft''s Nadella Says He''ll Stay Whatever CEO Choice</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT)''s cloud-services
chief, Satya Nadella, said he plans to stay at the software
company regardless of who replaces Chief Executive Officer Steve Ballmer. </p>
<p>Microsoft is an exciting place to be at now. It''s an
amazing spot to be in, Nadella said in an interview with
Bloomberg TV in Paris today, where he''s attending Le Web
Internet conference. Asked whether he will stay at Microsoft for
the long-haul, Nadella said: absolutely. </p>
<p>The executive declined to comment on his status as a
potential successor to Ballmer. Nadella is on a list of more
likely candidates at the Redmond, Washington-based company,
people familiar with the matter have said. </p>
<p>The board is aiming for a quick replacement for Ballmer,
who said in August that he will retire within the next 12
months. Microsoft has seen its software leadership decline amid
a shrinking of the personal-computer market, which was its core
business. Microsoft is shifting its strategy to focus more on
hardware and Internet-based services and away from its software
roots as it competes with Apple Inc. and Google Inc. </p>
<p>The search for a new CEO hasn''t affected day-to-day
business, Nadella said. </p>
<h2>Re-engineer Ourselves'' </h2>
<p>It''s not like there wasn''t any change we had to navigate
over the past 30 years, he said. If we didn''t know how to do
it, we wouldn''t be here. We''ve shown our ability to re-engineer
ourselves. </p>
<p>Part of that push is to compete with Amazon.com Inc. on
selling cloud-computing services to companies. The executive
said he met with customers in France this week to talk about
moving faster to cloud services that can be accessed at a
distance. He said clients are excited, though they''re
increasingly worried about data-privacy issues. </p>
<p>Customers were asking before -- they''re asking more
now, Nadella said about data privacy. It''s actually working
to our advantage because we have the flexibility to tailor to
our customers'' needs. </p>
<p>Microsoft yesterday joined technology companies including
Apple and Google to call on the U.S. government to lead reform
of surveillance practices after revelations the National
Security Agency gained access to private networks to conduct
spying. Other signatories of the statement, addressed to
President Barack Obama and members of Congress, are AOL Inc.,
Facebook Inc. (FB), LinkedIn Corp. (LNKD), Twitter Inc. (TWTR) and Yahoo! Inc. </p>
<p>Encrypting data and storing them on equipment based in
specific countries or regions are among the proposed solutions,
Nadella said today. </p>
<p>Microsoft slipped less than 1 percent to $38.48 at 10:09
a.m. in New York. The stock gained 45 percent this year through
yesterday. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Carroll" date="Dec 11, 2013  5:19 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-11/chevron-2014-spending-to-fall-even-as-gorgon-lng-costs-increase.html"><headline>Chevron 2014 Spending to Fall Even as Gorgon LNG Costs Increase</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX) plans to spend $39.8
billion on capital projects next year amid rising labor costs,
increased drilling expenditures and currency fluctuations from
Canada to Iraq. </p>
<p>The budget for floating platforms, oil-refinery repairs,
pipelines and rig rentals is 5.2 percent less than Chevron''s
2013 estimated outlay of $42 billion, the San Ramon, California-based company said in a statement today. The cost estimate for
the Gorgon natural gas export complex in Australia rose to $54
billion, the second increase in 13 months. Weather and
logistical delays will postpone startup of the project off the
northwest coast by about three months. </p>
<p>Chairman and Chief Executive Officer John S. Watson is
counting on deep-water oil discoveries in the Gulf of Mexico and
gas exports from the Indian and Pacific oceans to boost output
20 percent by the end of 2017. Chevron aspires to become the
world''s third-largest producer of liquefied natural gas, or LNG,
after Qatar and Royal Dutch Shell Plc, by the end of the decade. </p>
<p>Chevron''s full-year 2013 capital spending exceeded the
original $36.7 billion forecast because of acquisitions that
required additional spending, the company said. </p>
<p>Chevron may sell some oil and gas fields that promise
leaner returns than the new prospects, Chief Financial Officer
Pat Yarrington told analysts and investors during a Nov. 1
conference call. Yarrington didn''t specify what the company
might be considering exiting, nor did she provide a time frame. </p>
<p>Chevron said Nov. 22 its 240 million-barrel Rosebank field
off the Scottish coast currently doesn''t make economic sense to
develop. </p>
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) is the largest energy company by market
value, followed by PetroChina Co. (857), according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Dec 11, 2013  1:40 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-11/microsoft-s-xbox-one-sales-hit-2-million-amid-race-to-catch-sony.html"><headline>Microsoft Xbox One Sales Hit 2 Million in Race to Catch Sony</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) said sales of the
new Xbox One video-game console reached more than 2 million in
its first 18 days on the market, as the company vies to keep
pace with Sony Corp.''s PlayStation 4 during the holiday season. </p>
<p>Sony said on Dec. 3 that it had sold 2.1 million of its
machines since they went on sale Nov. 15 in North America.
Microsoft, which introduced Xbox One on Nov. 22 in 13 countries,
is selling pretty much every console it can get into stores and
has aggressive plans to restock, said David Dennis, a
spokesman for Xbox, in an interview yesterday. </p>
<p>Sales of both platforms are basically on par with each
other, said Colin Sebastian, an analyst at Robert W. Baird 
Co. in San Francisco. Production seems to be roughly the same
for both platforms and they''re both doing well at retail. </p>
<p>Microsoft and Sony are trying to attract gamers against a
backdrop of declining console sales. From 2008 to 2012, the
market shrank 32 percent to $13.3 billion, according to
researcher NPD Group Inc. Both the $499 Xbox One and the $399
PlayStation 4 have more powerful graphics and entertainment
applications than older models. To distinguish its machine,
Microsoft has been pitching its motion-sensing camera, the
ability to control live television and exclusive games like
Ryse: Son of Rome and Dead Rising 3. </p>
<p>We''re at 2 million at 18 days, and they were at about 2
million at 18 days, so we are running neck and neck, Dennis
said. He declined to provide a forecast for future sales. </p>
<h2>November Report </h2>
<p>Microsoft expects PlayStation 4 sales to top Xbox One when
NPD releases its November sales data for the U.S. tomorrow,
Dennis said. He attributed the lead to Sony''s extra days on sale
in November. </p>
<p>After replenishing initial inventories, Sony and Redmond,
Washington-based Microsoft each may sell about 3 million
consoles worldwide by the end of the year, according to
projections by Sebastian as well as Michael Olson, an analyst at
Piper Jaffray Cos. in Minneapolis. </p>
<p>Jack Tretton, president and chief executive officer of
Sony''s U.S. computer entertainment division, said Nov. 11 that
the Tokyo-based company is confident it can meet analysts'' sales
estimates of 3 million units by year-end, and its own target of
5 million units by March. Sony expanded sales of the PlayStation
4 on Nov. 29, and it was available in 32 countries as of Dec. 3. </p>
<p>Both consoles sold more than 1 million units in their first
24 hours in stores. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hugh Son and Dawn Kopecki" date="Dec 11, 2013 11:47 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-11/jpmorgan-s-dimon-says-banks-to-reprice-products.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Dimon Says Banks to Reprice Products</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) Chief Executive
Officer Jamie Dimon said banks will have to charge more for
lending to get a fair return as regulators require the
industry to set aside more funds to cushion against losses. </p>
<p>I don''t think that you''re going to have all these banks
around the world holding this amount of capital and the
revolvers will cost the same, Dimon, 57, said today at an
investor conference sponsored by Goldman Sachs Group Inc. in New
York. Revolving loans and repurchase agreements are among
products that use a lot of balance sheet and will have to be
repriced, he said. </p>
<p>U.S. regulators are forcing firms to hold more capital
against assets banks consider low risk by proposing a minimum
leverage ratio of 5 percent as an increased buffer against
potential losses. Market participants have said that would
affect pricing and access to lending in the repurchase
agreement, or repo, market, in which borrowers sell lenders
securities with an agreement to buy them back later. </p>
<p>Wall Street firms face new curbs, including limits on
hedging, designed to prevent financial blowups after the Federal
Reserve and four other regulators yesterday adopted the Volcker
rule, a centerpiece of the 2010 Dodd-Frank Act. The hedging
provision drew more attention in the Volcker rule debate after
JPMorgan lost $6.2 billion last year in bets on credit
derivatives. </p>




Photographer: Pete Marovich/Bloomberg

<p>
Jamie Dimon, chairman, president and chief executive officer of JPMorgan Chase  Co., speaks at the Institute of International Finance Annual Membership Meeting in Washington on Oct. 12, 2013. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matt Robinson" date="Dec 12, 2013  5:13 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-12/jpmorgan-sees-bulls-in-high-grade-debt-arch-coal-selling-bonds.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sees Bulls in High-Grade Debt; Arch Coal Selling Bonds</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Investors surveyed by JPMorgan Chase
 Co. are the most bullish on investment-grade bonds in more
than nine years as they demand the least relative yields since
the start of the financial crisis. Arch Coal Inc. plans to raise
$300 million in a private offering of secured notes. </p>
<p>About 50 percent of investors in the JPMorgan survey are
overweight investment-grade credit in their portfolio, the most
since April 2004, meaning they''re wagering a larger portion than
benchmarks, Eric Beinstein, the bank''s head of high-grade
strategy, said today in a research note. About 5 percent of
respondents are underweight. </p>
<p>The optimistic view on credit comes as the extra cost
investors demand to hold the debt instead of similar-maturity
Treasuries touched the lowest in more than six years yesterday,
according to the Bank of America Merrill Lynch U.S. Corporate
Index. A benchmark gauge of U.S. corporate credit that reached
the lowest since November 2007 at the start of the week was
little changed as growth in retail sales added to speculation
the Federal Reserve will reduce stimulus that''s bolstered credit
markets. </p>
<p>The average relative yield on dollar-denominated,
investment-grade corporate bonds in the Bank of America Merrill
Lynch index fell yesterday to 137 basis points, or 1.37
percentage points, the least since August 2007. The JPMorgan
analysts are forecasting spreads in their bank''s index to
continue tightening next year by another 15 basis points. </p>
<h2>Credit Swaps </h2>
<p>Investment-grade spreads narrowed 0.3 basis point today,
Bloomberg data show. The measure for speculative-grade, or junk-rated, debt tightened 1.1 to 541.6. </p>
<p>Junk bonds are rated below Baa3 by Moody''s Investors
Service and lower than BBB- at Standard  Poor''s. </p>
<p>The Markit CDX North American Investment Grade Index, a
credit-default swaps benchmark used to hedge against losses or
to speculate on creditworthiness, held at 70.3 basis points as
of 5:01 p.m. in New York, according to prices compiled by
Bloomberg. The measure has climbed from 67.3 on Dec. 9, the
lowest closing level since November 2007. </p>
<p>The index has risen as speculation mounts that the Fed is
gearing up to start reducing $85 billion of monthly bond
purchases as the economy improves. The share of economists
predicting the Fed will pare its stimulus in December has
doubled to 34 percent after a Dec. 6 report showing the
unemployment rate fell in November to a five-year low. </p>
<h2>Taper Speculation </h2>
<p>Retail sales rose more than forecast in November as
Americans bought cars and took advantage of discounts going into
the holiday-shopping season. Purchases climbed 0.7 percent, the
most since June, after a 0.6 percent advance in October that was
larger than previously reported, Commerce Department figures
showed today. The median forecast of 83 economists surveyed by
Bloomberg was for a 0.6 percent gain. </p>
<p>The confidence of debt investors in Computer Sciences Corp (CSC),
the technology consultant, fell after the company disclosed that
it may face a regulatory action from the U.S. Securities and
Exchange Commission as part of an accounting probe. Credit swaps
tied to the Falls Church, Virginia-based company''s $2.5 billion
of bonds and loans rose 4.4 basis points to 109.3 basis points. </p>
<p>Credit swaps, which typically rise as investor confidence
deteriorates and fall as it improves, pay the buyer face value
if a borrower fails to meet its obligations, less the value of
the defaulted debt. A basis point equals $1,000 annually on a
contract protecting $10 million of debt. </p>
<h2>Arch Coal </h2>
<p>Arch Coal (ACI) is planning its bond sale as the coal producer
prepares to redeem shorter-maturity securities. The St. Louis-based company intends to issue second-lien notes due in 2019, it
said today in a statement. </p>
<p>The market for corporate borrowing through short-term IOUs
surged the most in 16 months as demand from money-market mutual
funds increased. </p>
<p>The seasonally adjusted amount of U.S. commercial paper
climbed $31.7 billion to $1.081 trillion outstanding in the week
ended yesterday, the Federal Reserve said today on its website.
That''s the biggest jump since an equivalent dollar rise for the
period ended Aug. 1, 2012, and the highest level since the week
ended Oct. 30. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Belinda Cao" date="Dec 12, 2013  5:06 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-12/goldman-buy-call-spurs-e-house-rally-china-overnight.html"><headline>Goldman Buy Call Spurs E-House Rally: China Overnight</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>E-House China Holdings Ltd. (EJ) led
gains in Chinese stocks traded in New York after Goldman Sachs
Group Inc. said the online real estate services provider is
poised to extend its six-month rally as housing prices soar. </p>
<p>The Bloomberg China-US Index of the most traded Chinese
equities in the U.S. rose less than 0.1 percent to 104.55
yesterday, after dropping the most in two years the previous
day. About two stocks rose for every one that fell on the gauge.
Shanghai-based E-House jumped 6.8 percent while hotel chain
China Lodging Group Ltd. (HTHT) posted the biggest advance in a month.
Baidu Inc., China''s biggest search engine, capped the largest
two-day decline since October. </p>
<p>The value of homes sold in China increased 19 percent to
the highest since December 2011, according to government data
released this week. E-House, which has surged 50 percent this
quarter to lead gains on the China-US gauge, stands to benefit
from this trend as a property agent, Shanghai-based Goldman
analysts led by Yi Wang wrote in a report dated Dec. 11. Goldman
also raised its estimate for E-House''s 2014 adjusted earnings by
10 percent. </p>
<p>Rising home sales signal that the government won''t take
irrational steps to curb growth of China''s property sector,
Tian X. Hou, the founder of T.H. Capital LLC, said by phone from
Beijing yesterday. Investors didn''t consider E-House as an
Internet company until this year, after it expanded its e-commerce business. Both government policy and its own business
restructuring have helped the stock''s performance. </p>
<h2>ETF Retreats </h2>
<p>The iShares China Large-Cap ETF, the largest Chinese
exchange-traded fund in the U.S., slipped 1.1 percent to $38.11
in New York, extending its decline to a fourth day. The Standard
 Poor''s 500 Index retreated 0.4 percent as improving economic
data spurred speculation that the Federal Reserve will cut
stimulus as soon as next week. </p>
<p>E-House''s American depositary receipts soared to $13.80,
the highest level since February 2011. Trading volume was twice
the three-month average compiled by Bloomberg. The ADRs have
gained 237 percent in 2013. </p>
<p>The company sold $135 million of 2.75 percent five-year
convertible notes yesterday. The conversion price of the notes
was about $16.80 for each ADR, a 30 percent premium over the
closing level Dec. 11, the company said in a statement. </p>
<p>Goldman lifted its earnings projections for E-House by 11
percent for 2015 and 12 percent for 2016 to reflect potential
benefits from the sharper focus on online expansion and our
estimated dilution impact from its convertible bonds issuance,
according to the note. It also increased a 12-month price target
to $16.77 from $14.39. </p>
<h2>SMIC Gains </h2>
<p>SouFun Holdings Ltd. (SFUN), China''s biggest real-estate
information website, rallied 4.1 percent to $71.82, extending
its gains this quarter to 39 percent. </p>
<p>China Lodging, a budget hotel operator based in Shanghai,
surged 6 percent to $25.76. Phoenix New Media Ltd., a television
and Internet news outlet, climbed 4.7 percent to $8.99, rising
the most in four weeks. </p>
<p>Semiconductor Manufacturing International Corp. (981), a
Shanghai-based chip foundry, climbed 1.6 percent to $3.72 after
retreating 10 percent in a six-day slump. BOC International
Holdings Ltd. analysts led by Cheng Manjiang named the company a
2014 top pick among shares listed in Hong Kong in a report
yesterday. </p>
<p>Baidu''s ADRs slid 1 percent to $171.50 in New York,
retreating 4.7 percent from a two-year high of $108.77 reached
on Dec. 10. The ADRs have jumped 71 percent this year, the best
advance since 2010. </p>
<p>Mindray Medical International Ltd. (MR), a medical device maker
based in Shenzhen, tumbled 11 percent to $35.61, the biggest
decline since August 2010. Volume was four times the 90-day
average. Short interest on its stock was 23 percent of shares
outstanding as of Dec. 10, Markit data showed. </p>
<p>The Hang Seng China Enterprises Index in Hong Kong
retreated 1 percent to a four-week low of 10,962.18, while the
Shanghai Composite Index (SHCOMP) fell less than 0.1 percent to 2,202.80
in a third day of slump. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki and Keri Geiger" date="Dec 12, 2013  4:34 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-12/jpmorgan-said-in-talks-to-pay-2-billion-in-madoff-probes.html"><headline>JPMorgan Said in Talks on $2 Billion Madoff Settlement</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the target of
multiple U.S. Justice Department investigations, tentatively
agreed to pay about $2 billion to resolve probes into whether it
ignored warning signs about Bernard Madoff''s crimes, according
to a person briefed on the matter. </p>
<p>The bank also assented to a deferred-prosecution agreement,
said the person, who asked not to be identified because the
negotiations are private. In such deals, the government agrees
not to prosecute for a specified period and charges are
dismissed if the entity improves its programs and complies with
the law. The talks are in their final stages and the accord
could be announced before year-end, the person said. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon, 57, is seeking to
resolve government probes that have beset JPMorgan, the biggest
U.S. bank, while overhauling internal controls to improve
relations with regulators. Wall Street firms have spent years
fighting off claims brought on behalf of Madoff''s victims,
including accusations that the companies ignored the con man''s
fraud to continue reaping fees. </p>
<p>The Office of Comptroller of the Currency, the bank''s
primary regulator, and Manhattan U.S. Attorney Preet Bharara
have been investigating how New York-based JPMorgan handled
funds controlled by Madoff, whose multibillion-dollar fraud was
the biggest Ponzi scheme in the nation''s history. James Margolin, a Bharara spokesman, and the FBI''s Peter Donald
declined to comment. </p>
<h2>Additional Fines </h2>
<p>The OCC, which sanctioned the lender in January for
violating the Bank Secrecy Act, plans to punish the company for
BSA violations related to Madoff, according to another person
briefed on the probe. The OCC also is likely to fine the bank
for additional anti-money laundering violations, the person
said. Bryan Hubbard, an OCC spokesman, declined to comment. </p>
<p>The 1970 Bank Secrecy Act requires financial institutions
to assist government agencies in detecting and preventing money
laundering, such as reporting cash transactions exceeding
$10,000. </p>
<p>Bloomberg News reported in October that a deferred-prosecution agreement was among options the U.S. had discussed
with the bank. The New York Times reported on the tentative $2
billion accord late yesterday. About half of the penalties will
go toward resolving the Justice Department''s criminal case while
the rest will be paid to federal bank regulators, the newspaper
said, citing people briefed on the case. </p>
<h2>Earlier Deal </h2>
<p>JPMorgan listed at least eight Justice Department probes in
a quarterly filing last month, including the Madoff inquiry, and
investigations into hirings in Asia and the bank''s energy-trading practices. Weeks later, the firm agreed to a record $13
billion settlement to end government investigations of its
mortgage-bond sales. </p>
<p>If JPMorgan enters a deferred-prosecution agreement in the
Madoff case, it would be the second time that Attorney General
Eric Holder has allowed Dimon''s bank to avoid prosecution for
behavior the government has deemed criminal. </p>
<p>The first was in 2011, when the department granted JPMorgan
a non-prosecution agreement for its dealings in the municipal
bond markets. The bank''s employees entered into unlawful
agreements to manipulate the bidding process and rig bids on
municipal investment and related contracts from 2001 through
2006, the Justice Department said at the time. </p>
<h2>Criminal Charges </h2>
<p>In that case, the bank agreed to pay $228 million to
federal and state agencies and to cooperate in the ongoing
probe. The investigation resulted in criminal charges against 18
individuals at firms including JPMorgan. UBS AG (UBSN) and Wells Fargo
 Co.''s Wachovia also agreed to pay penalties and enter into
non-prosecution agreements over the charges of rigging bids in
the municipal bond market. </p>
<p>Other banks that have entered into non- or deferred-prosecution agreements include London-based HSBC Holdings Plc. (HSBA)
Wachovia''s cases focused on conduct before the lender''s 2008
acquisition by Wells Fargo. </p>
<p>Because a deferred-prosecution agreement or a plea
agreement involves oversight by a judge, they are better tools
to fix compliance issues than a non-prosecution agreement that
is never filed in a court, said Brandon Garrett, a professor
at the University of Virginia School of Law who specializes in
corporte crime. </p>
<p>The Justice Department is increasingly calling for
corporate monitors in non- and deferred-prosecution agreements
to review companies'' compliance with the terms of the agreements
and to ensure corporate reform, according to a 2008 department
memo on the topic. The corporate monitors are usually employed
by the firms and approved by the government. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Justin Doom" date="Dec 12, 2013  2:50 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-12/jpmorgan-invests-96-million-in-258-megawatt-texas-wind-project.html"><headline>JPMorgan Invests $96 Million in 258-Megawatt Texas Wind Project</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the largest
U.S. lender by assets, invested $96.2 million in equity
financing for a 258-megawatt wind farm in Texas developed by EON
SE. (EOAN) </p>
<p>JPMorgan also committed to providing additional capital for
the Panther Creek wind farm in Big Spring, Texas, EON''s North
American renewables unit said today in a statement. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Leslie Picker and Michael J. Moore" date="Dec 12, 2013 12:22 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-12/goldman-earns-most-in-hilton-ipo-with-more-than-fees.html"><headline>Goldman Earns Most in Hilton IPO With More Than Fees</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) isn''t the
lead underwriter on Hilton Worldwide Holdings Inc.''s initial
public offering. The investment bank still stands to reap more
than any other firm handling the largest-ever hotel IPO. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs will generate more than $117 million in
proceeds from the $2.35 billion deal as a stakeholder and
lender, based on a description of the bank''s holding in the
sale''s prospectus and Hilton''s statement on the final terms.
That''s on top of fees as an underwriter of the deal. </p>
<p>The windfall stems from the firm''s six-year involvement
with Hilton''s buyout and return to the stock market. The bank
was among lenders providing $20.6 billion of mortgage and
mezzanine debt to finance Blackstone Group LP''s 2007 purchase of
the hotel chain. A 2010 debt restructuring gave Goldman Sachs a
stake in Hilton, and the firm served as a lender in credit
facilities that are being repaid with IPO proceeds. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs, led by Chief Executive Officer Lloyd C. Blankfein, 59, isn''t alone in having multiple roles in the sale.
New York-based Morgan Stanley (MS) also had a stake in the Hilton
holding company and was set to receive stock in the hotel
operator or cash from the IPO, the prospectus shows. That
investment is held by Morgan Stanley''s asset management unit,
according to a person briefed on the matter, who asked not to be
identified because details of the holding aren''t public. </p>




Photographer: Peter Foley/Bloomberg

<p>
Traders work at the Goldman Sachs Group Inc. booth on the floor of the New York Stock Exchange. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dakin Campbell" date="Dec 12, 2013 11:28 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-12/general-motors-divests-8-5-ally-equity-stake-for-900-million.html"><headline>General Motors Sells Ally Financial Stake for $900 Million</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>General Motors Co. (GM) completed the
sale of its 8.5 percent stake in Ally Financial Inc. (ALLY) for about
$900 million as the automaker moves to sever ties from its
former financing arm. </p>
<p>The sale will result in a gain of about $500 million in the
fourth quarter, GM said today in a statement. The buyers weren''t
named. Both companies are based in Detroit. </p>
<p>Ally, formerly known as GMAC, is seeking to regain its
independence after taking a U.S. bailout during the financial
crisis that was designed to keep the auto industry afloat.
Taxpayers still held a 64 percent stake in Ally as of Nov. 20,
according to the company. GM said the carrying amount of its
stake was $397 million and the fair value was $866 million at
the end of September. </p>
<p>This transaction releases capital from a non-core asset
and further enhances our financial flexibility, Dan Ammann,
GM''s chief financial officer, said in the statement. Ally
continues to play an important role in financing our dealers and
customers in the United States. </p>
<p>GM''s stake was held indirectly in an independent trust,
according to the automaker''s quarterly securities filing. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sanat Vallikappen" date="Dec 12, 2013  5:08 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-12/jpmorgan-sees-30-increase-in-asian-m-a-on-china-to-energy-deals.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sees 30% Jump in Asia M&amp;amp;A on China to Energy Deals</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the biggest
U.S. lender by assets, is forecasting a 30 percent surge in the
value of mergers and acquisitions the bank expects to handle in
Asia next year, a rebound from this year''s decline. </p>
<p>Energy companies, financial firms and Asian buyers
expanding in the U.S. and Europe will drive a surge in activity
for JPMorgan, said Rob Sivitilli, 41, who has been head of Asian
MA outside Japan since September 2012. The New York-based bank
climbed this year to No. 2 among advisers in the region from No.
4 in 2012, data compiled by Bloomberg show. </p>
<p>JPMorgan rose in deal rankings by improving communication
between bankers in Asia and colleagues in North America and
Europe, Sivitilli said. Takeover activity declined this year in
the region as slowing economies from India to China curbed
executives'' risk appetite. Mergers involving Asian companies may
fall short of last year''s $311 billion after ending last week at
$298 billion, data compiled by Bloomberg show. </p>
<p>We have enough visibility on first-quarter and second-quarter activity that leads us to project ourselves into a much
higher level of performance in 2014, Sivitilli said in a Nov.
25 interview in Singapore. We continue to see further gains in
market share. </p>




Photographer: Brent Lewin/Bloomberg

<p>
Oil and gas mergers are poised to increase as some Asian countries look to shore up energy reserves, said Rob Sivitilli, head of mergers  acquisitions of JP Morgan Securities Asia Pte. Countries from Singapore to India import at least 80 percent of their oil needs, according to government data. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David Scheer" date="Dec 12, 2013  1:04 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-12/jpmorgan-may-pay-2-billion-to-resolve-madoff-probe-nyt-reports.html"><headline>JPMorgan May Pay $2 Billion to Resolve Madoff Probe, NYT Reports</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) may pay about
$2 billion to resolve U.S. probes into whether the bank ignored
signs of Bernard Madoff''s Ponzi scheme, the New York Times
reported, citing unidentified people briefed on the matter. </p>
<p>The firm is close to a deal that includes a deferred
prosecution agreement and more than $1 billion in penalties to
resolve a criminal case, with remaining sanctions imposed by
federal regulators investigating gaps in the company''s money-laundering safeguards, the newspaper said. </p>
<p>Bloomberg News reported in October that the company was in
settlement talks that may lead to a deferred prosecution
agreement. In such deals, the government agrees not to prosecute
for a specified period and dismisses charges if the entity
improves its programs or complies with the law. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon, 57, is seeking to
resolve government probes that have beset JPMorgan, while
overhauling internal controls to improve relations with
regulators. It''s among Wall Street firms that have spent years
fighting off claims brought on behalf of Madoff''s victims,
including accusations that the companies ignored the con man''s
fraud to continue reaping fees. </p>
<p>Manhattan U.S. Attorney Preet Bharara has been
investigating how New York-based JPMorgan, the biggest U.S. bank
by assets, handled funds controlled by Madoff and whether the
firm turned a blind eye to his multibillion-dollar fraud, the
biggest Ponzi scheme in U.S. history. </p>
<p>Joseph Evangelisti, a JPMorgan spokesman, declined to
comment on the settlement talks. </p>
<p>The bank listed at least eight Justice Department probes in
a quarterly filing last month, ranging from the Madoff inquiry
to investigations of hirings in Asia and its energy-trading
practices. Weeks later, the firm agreed to a record $13 billion
settlement to end government investigations of its mortgage-bond
sales. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dakin Campbell" date="Dec 13, 2013  6:47 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-13/visa-gives-ceo-scharf-10-5-million-compensation-for-fiscal-2013.html"><headline>Visa Awards CEO Scharf $10.5 Million Pay Package for Year</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Visa Inc. (V), the world''s biggest bank-card network, said it awarded Chief Executive Officer Charlie Scharf compensation for fiscal year 2013 valued at $10.5
million. </p>
<p>The pay package included a $950,000 base salary and a bonus
of $3.57 million, Foster City, California-based Visa said today
in a filing. He received $2.97 million in performance shares,
$1.48 million in options and a similar sum in restricted stock,
the filing shows. </p>
<p>Visa has risen 37 percent this year, lagging the 60 percent
return for MasterCard Inc. while outpacing the 24 percent
advance for the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index. The shares are up
about 49 percent since Scharf succeeded Joseph W. Saunders on
Nov. 1, 2012. </p>
<p>Saunders received a pay package valued at $9.7 million in
total compensation for fiscal year 2012, reflecting a formula
based on U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission rules. Scharf
was paid $24.2 million for fiscal year 2013 based on the same
calculation, which differs from the company''s number because it
includes the compensation actually received in the year rather
than what was awarded. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bob Van Voris" date="Dec 13, 2013  5:34 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-13/ibm-sued-over-claim-spy-program-cooperation-hurt-sales.html"><headline>IBM Sued Over Claim Spy Program Cooperation Hurt Sales</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>An International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM) shareholder sued the company over claims its cooperation
with a National Security Agency eavesdropping program caused a
drop in sales in China, hurting investors. </p>
<p>The Louisiana Sheriffs'' Pension and Relief Fund, in a
complaint filed yesterday in Manhattan federal court, accuses
IBM of defrauding investors by concealing that sales slowed
after Edward Snowden disclosed the company was cooperating with
the NSA. </p>
<p>In June, documents released by Snowden revealed the NSA''s
Prism surveillance program, which used information from
technology companies such as IBM, the pension fund said. IBM
also lobbied in favor of a bill that would allow it to share
customers'' personal data, including data from users in China,
with the NSA, according to the complaint. </p>
<p>The company knew but misrepresented or concealed from
investors that the disclosures of its lobbying and its
association with the Prism and NSA spying scandal caused
businesses in China as well as the Chinese government to
abruptly halt doing business with IBM, leading to an immediate,
and precipitous decline in sales, the pension fund said in its
complaint. </p>
<h2>China Sales </h2>
<p>On Oct. 16, IBM, the largest computer-services provider,
reported a 22 percent drop in sales in China compared with the
previous quarter as a result of the Snowden disclosures,
according to the Louisiana fund, which said it pays retirement,
death and disability benefits to more than 20,000 active and
retired employees of sheriff''s offices throughout the state. </p>
<p>The suit is pushing a wild conspiracy theory, IBM''s
general counsel, Robert Weber, said in a statement today. This
lawsuit seeks to confuse IBM''s support for a U.S. cybersecurity
legislative proposal -- which has yet to be enacted -- with the
completely unrelated NSA surveillance program called PRISM,
Weber said in the statement. Even a cursory reading of the
legislative proposal, known as CISPA, makes clear that it has
nothing to do with the recently disclosed NSA surveillance
program. </p>
<p>The pension fund is seeking to represent a class of
investors who bought IBM stock from June 25 to Oct. 16. </p>
<p>The case is Louisiana Sheriffs'' Pension  Relief Fund v.
International Business Machines Corp., 13-cv-08818, U.S.
District Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alexandria Baca" date="Dec 13, 2013  4:15 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-13/microsoft-must-be-terrified-by-penney-lesson-miller-says.html"><headline>Microsoft Must be Terrified by Penney Lesson, MIller Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) directors seeking a
new chief executive officer to reinvigorate the software maker
should be mindful of the lesson of J.C. Penney Co., said Steve Miller, who spent his career helping hobbled companies survive. </p>
<p>What must terrify them is the example, say, of J.C.
Penney, Miller, the chairman of American International Group
Inc. (AIG), told Bloomberg Television''s Stephanie Ruhle and Erik Schatzker in an interview today. They decided they needed to
change, they brought in Ron Johnson, did a radical shift in
their whole strategy, and it was a complete failure. </p>
<p>J.C. Penney hired Johnson from Apple Inc. (AAPL), where he turned
the iPad maker''s stores into a lucrative retail empire. At J.C.
Penney, Johnson scaled back discounts and sought to transform
the department-store chain into collections of boutiques. The
company replaced Johnson with former CEO Mike Ullman in April. </p>
<p>Microsoft, the largest software maker, has been considering
outsiders for the CEO post. Its list of candidates has included
Ford Motor Co. CEO Alan Mulally and Qualcomm Inc. Chief
Operating Officer Steve Mollenkopf, according to people familiar
with the matter. Mollenkopf was removed from the running today
when Qualcomm named him CEO. Microsoft is replacing Steve
Ballmer who took over as CEO in 2000 from Bill Gates. </p>




Photographer: David Paul Morris/Bloomberg

<p>
Microsoft, the largest software maker, has been considering outsiders for the CEO post. Microsoft is replacing Steve Ballmer who took over as CEO in 2000 from Bill Gates. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Boyle and Matt Townsend" date="Dec 13, 2013  1:22 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-13/procter-gamble-said-planning-reorganization-of-overseas-units.html"><headline>Procter &amp;amp; Gamble Said Planning Reorganization of Overseas Units</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Procter  Gamble Co. (PG) plans to re-organize its overseas business units as Chief Executive Officer A.G. Lafley works to cut costs at the world''s largest consumer-products maker, said three people briefed on the matter. </p> <p>The maker of Pampers diapers and Crest toothpaste is weighing a merger of its Western European unit with Eastern and Central Europe to create one group for the continent, said the people, who requested anonymity because the plan won''t be unveiled until 2014. PG''s Indian business will combine with the Middle East and Africa to form another group, the people said. </p> <p>The streamlining, which follows similar moves by other consumer-product companies, is an attempt to accelerate sales growth and reduce costs. Some senior management staff in Europe could lose their jobs, according to two of the people. </p> <p>Currently, Cincinnati-based PG has five geographic units: North America, Latin America, Asia, Western Europe, and CEEMEA, which includes Central and Eastern Europe, the Middle East and Africa. Western Europe accounted for 18 percent of PG''s $84 billion in sales in its most recent fiscal year, according to its annual report, while CEEMEA comprised 15 percent of revenue and Asia 18 percent. </p> <p>The move represents Lafley''s second major shakeup since he returned to run the company in May. The following month, PG streamlined its businesses into four industry-based groups to facilitate faster global expansion of brand and product innovations, the company said at the time. </p> <p>The stock has advanced about 4 percent since Lafley replaced Bob McDonald as CEO. </p> <h2>Cost Savings </h2> <p>We''ve openly discussed our focus on productivity and growth, and this includes reviewing our geographic operations, Paul Fox, a spokesman for PG, said in an interview. Studies are underway to explore the best ways to scale and simplify our global market operations, but no final decisions have been made. </p> <p>At an investor conference in September, Lafley hinted at the coming changes when he said we''ll look to scale operations across all of Europe as part of its plan to accelerate and strengthen our productivity and cost savings. </p> <p>PG is not the first consumer-goods company to redraw its map of the world in the wake of the global recession. Last year, Reckitt Benckiser Group Plc (RB/), the maker of Lysol disinfectants, combined Europe and North America into one business unit to shed costs and speed up decision making. The maker of Nurofen painkillers also placed Latin America and Asia together into the same reporting unit. </p> <h2>Lafley''s Return </h2> <p>Lafley, who had served as president and CEO from 2000 to 2009, returned this year as the company struggled to rekindle growth. The 66-year-old Lafley has said he will continue a turnaround plan that McDonald embarked on that aims to cut $10 billion in costs through 2016 and renews focus on the company''s leading businesses, such as hair care. </p> <p>The maker of Gillette razors and blades entered Europe in 1930 by acquiring a soap company in Newcastle-upon-Tyne, England. Today, more than 40,000 of PG''s 121,000 employees work in Europe, according to company documents. </p> <p>Mary Lynn Ferguson-McHugh is group president for Western Europe, while Laurent Philippe runs the CEEMEA division. Both units are headquartered in Geneva. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Duane D. Stanford" date="Dec 13, 2013 11:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-13/coca-cola-ceo-shakes-up-management-to-speed-u-s-bottling-revamp.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Shakes Up Management to Speed U.S. Bottling Revamp</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Coca-Cola Co. (KO) Chief Executive
Officer Muhtar Kent, trying to speed efforts to improve the
company''s North American distribution system, shook up his
management team, resulting in the departure of a leader once
considered a contender to succeed him. </p>
<p>Steve Cahillane, president of Coca-Cola Americas, will
leave the company as his unit is dissolved, the Atlanta-based
company said in a statement yesterday. North America operations,
including brand marketing, food service and new product
development, will be handed back to 25-year Coke veteran Sandy Douglas, who stepped aside as president of the region in 2012.
Coke''s bottling operations in the U.S. and Canada will be folded
into the company''s international bottling group. </p>
<p>We organized the business to intensify focus on key
markets, streamline reporting lines and provide flexibility to
adjust the business within these geographies in the future,
Kent said in the statement. The changes, he said, will
accelerate the refranchising of our bottling system in our
flagship market. </p>
<p>In 2010, Kent took control of 90 percent of Coca-Cola''s
North American distribution network with the purchase of its
largest bottler, hoping to stem volume sales declines and boost
profit. He is reversing a decades-old model in which Coca-Cola
sold franchises in the U.S. to bottlers who handled everything
from production to distribution, buying beverage concentrates
from Coca-Cola. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
Coke''s bottling operations in the U.S. and Canada will be folded into the company''s international bottling group. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrea Wong" date="Dec 13, 2013  4:10 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-13/goldman-sachs-goes-rogue-on-dollar-in-call-for-drop-currencies.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Goes Against Consensus in Dollar Call</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc.''s Thomas Stolper, who correctly predicted the dollar''s slide against the
euro this year, is deviating from the consensus that the
greenback will be among the best currencies to own in 2014. </p>
<p>The dollar will weaken through 2014, reaching $1.40 per
euro for the first time since October 2011, Goldman''s London-based chief currency strategist said. The mean estimate in a
Bloomberg survey of 46 contributors is for a 7 percent rally to
$1.28 per euro from $1.3758 today. </p>
<p>Firms from BNP Paribas SA to Barclays Plc and Morgan
Stanley say a strengthening U.S. economy will allow the Federal
Reserve to pull back on stimulus measures that include printing
dollars to buy $85 billion of bonds every month. For Stolper,
that will be offset by the Fed keeping its benchmark interest
rates at about zero even as it reduces bond purchases. </p>
<p>Tapering is in the price already, we find it difficult to
see where the dollar strength would come from, Stolper wrote
in an e-mailed response to questions this week. There is
always a risk that stronger growth in the U.S. suddenly pushes
rates even higher as markets anticipate a stronger Fed response.
However, our base case is that we see only marginal support for
the dollar from interest rates. </p>
<h2>Stolper''s Calls </h2>
<p>Stolper, 45, predicted in December 2012 that the dollar
would trade at about $1.33 per euro in June. It averaged $1.32
that month, falling as low as $1.34. He cut his outlook on the
dollar Sept. 12 when it was trading at about $1.33, predicting
it would weaken to $1.38 per euro in three months, from a
previous forecast of $1.34. </p>
<p>Of 46 analysts surveyed by Bloomberg, 42 expect the
greenback to gain against Europe''s common currency next year as
rising Treasury yields lure international investors from lower
returning counterparts. Benchmark 10-year Treasury notes yield
104 basis points, or 1.04 percentage points, more than
comparable maturity German bunds, close to the biggest premium
in about seven years. </p>
<p>The Bloomberg U.S. Dollar Index has risen 1.8 percent from
an eight-month low in October as gains in employment added to
speculation the Fed may slow its quantitative-easing program as
soon as next week''s policy meeting. </p>
<h2>Rising Euro </h2>
<p>The euro has strengthened 4.3 percent this year against the
dollar, making it the best performer among 16 major currencies
tracked by Bloomberg. It got an added boost after European
Central Bank President Mario Draghi left interest rates
unchanged and gave no indication he would take further steps to
ease monetary policy. </p>
<p>We expect all major central banks on hold until at least
late 2015 -- hence, no immediate catalyst for further gains in
the dollar, Stolper said. </p>
<p>While strategists predict broad dollar gains, investors are
hedging their bets ahead of the Dec. 17-18 Fed meeting. </p>
<p>Futures traders reduced net wagers that the dollar will
gain versus eight peers including the euro, yen and pound to
$18.9 billion as of Dec. 3, from $19.1 billion a week earlier,
according to Commodity Futures Trading Commission data compiled
by Societe Generale SA. The net long position on Nov. 26 was the
most since Sept. 10. </p>
<p>Following the end of the first two rounds of quantitative
easing, the dollar showed little momentum. The Bloomberg U.S.
Dollar Index rose 0.4 percent the month after what''s known as
QE1 was completed in March 2010, and fell 1.3 percent the month
after QE2 in June 2011. </p>
<h2>Inflation Change </h2>
<p>The dollar may stay here for a while as the Fed will get
away with the story of inflation is nowhere to be seen, Jose Wynne, the head of foreign-exchange research at Barclays in New
York, said in a phone interview. But this may change in the
second half of next year, when inflation starts to turn
around. </p>
<p>Barclays forecasts the dollar will rally to $1.27 against
the common currency by the end of 2014. </p>
<p>Since reaching a three-year high of 3.9 percent in
September 2011, inflation has slowed. In October, consumer
prices rose 1 percent from a year earlier, the smallest increase
in four years, according to a Nov. 20 Labor Department report. </p>
<p>Better economic growth in the U.S. relative to most
developed nations will support the dollar, according to Morgan
Stanley. The world''s biggest economy will grow 2.6 percent in
2014, versus 1 percent in the euro area and 2.4 percent in the
U.K., according to separate Bloomberg surveys. </p>
<h2>Key Drivers </h2>
<p>In this environment, we believe that relative growth
differentials will be key currency drivers, and these are
dollar-supportive, given that the U.S. private sector has
delevered more than the rest of developed markets, Morgan
Stanley strategists led by Hans Redeker in London wrote in a
Dec. 2 report. </p>
<p>At the same time, a persistent deficit in the current
account, which is the broadest measure of trade because it
includes investment, hurts demand for the dollar, according to
Stolper. The shortfall was $98.9 billion in the second quarter.
The euro area recorded a current-account surplus in September
for the eighth consecutive month. </p>
<p>A growth story convincing enough to see international
investors commit more capital to the U.S. is necessary for a
breakthrough in the dollar, Stolper said. So far, we have seen
mainly capital outflows from the U.S. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bob Van Voris" date="Dec 13, 2013  5:34 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-13/ibm-sued-over-claim-spy-program-cooperation-hurt-sales.html"><headline>IBM Sued Over Claim Spy Program Cooperation Hurt Sales</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>An International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM) shareholder sued the company over claims its cooperation
with a National Security Agency eavesdropping program caused a
drop in sales in China, hurting investors. </p>
<p>The Louisiana Sheriffs'' Pension and Relief Fund, in a
complaint filed yesterday in Manhattan federal court, accuses
IBM of defrauding investors by concealing that sales slowed
after Edward Snowden disclosed the company was cooperating with
the NSA. </p>
<p>In June, documents released by Snowden revealed the NSA''s
Prism surveillance program, which used information from
technology companies such as IBM, the pension fund said. IBM
also lobbied in favor of a bill that would allow it to share
customers'' personal data, including data from users in China,
with the NSA, according to the complaint. </p>
<p>The company knew but misrepresented or concealed from
investors that the disclosures of its lobbying and its
association with the Prism and NSA spying scandal caused
businesses in China as well as the Chinese government to
abruptly halt doing business with IBM, leading to an immediate,
and precipitous decline in sales, the pension fund said in its
complaint. </p>
<h2>China Sales </h2>
<p>On Oct. 16, IBM, the largest computer-services provider,
reported a 22 percent drop in sales in China compared with the
previous quarter as a result of the Snowden disclosures,
according to the Louisiana fund, which said it pays retirement,
death and disability benefits to more than 20,000 active and
retired employees of sheriff''s offices throughout the state. </p>
<p>The suit is pushing a wild conspiracy theory, IBM''s
general counsel, Robert Weber, said in a statement today. This
lawsuit seeks to confuse IBM''s support for a U.S. cybersecurity
legislative proposal -- which has yet to be enacted -- with the
completely unrelated NSA surveillance program called PRISM,
Weber said in the statement. Even a cursory reading of the
legislative proposal, known as CISPA, makes clear that it has
nothing to do with the recently disclosed NSA surveillance
program. </p>
<p>The pension fund is seeking to represent a class of
investors who bought IBM stock from June 25 to Oct. 16. </p>
<p>The case is Louisiana Sheriffs'' Pension  Relief Fund v.
International Business Machines Corp., 13-cv-08818, U.S.
District Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Dec 16, 2013  4:45 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-16/jpmorgan-said-to-seek-sale-of-global-special-opportunities-group.html"><headline>JPMorgan Said to Seek Sale of Global Special Opportunities Group</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the largest
U.S. bank, is seeking to sell a global investment unit in a push
to simplify operations by paring non-essential holdings, a
person familiar with the matter said. </p>
<p>JPMorgan began offering its Global Special Opportunities
unit, which has about $2 billion in assets, to potential buyers
in the past few weeks, said the person, who asked not to be
identified because the talks are confidential. Private-equity
firms Blackstone Group LP (BX), Carlyle Group LP (CG) and KKR  Co. among
possible bidders for the business, which could fetch $1 billion,
the Financial Times reported today, citing unidentified people
familiar with the situation. </p>
<p>The unit, which is based in Hong Kong, employs 35 people
mostly in Asia and is run by Chris Nicholas. It invests the New
York-based bank''s money in distressed debt, non-performing loans
and private equity. Federal bank regulators last week approved
the Volcker Rule, which limits proprietary trading and investing
by deposit-taking banks. </p>
<p>We''re doing a lot of what I call pruning, Chief
Executive Officer Jamie Dimon, 57, told investors at a
conference last week. Simplify, pruning. You should do it all
the time. Every year, businesses should look at what do I need,
what don''t I need, how do I serve my clients. </p>
<p>JPMorgan has already announced plans to spin off its
private-equity unit, sell most of its physical commodities
business and exit student lending. </p>
<p>Jennifer Zuccarelli, a spokeswoman for the bank, declined
to comment, as did Carlyle''s Randy Whitestone and KKR''s Kristi Huller. A Blackstone spokesman didn''t immediately respond to
messages seeking comment. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Webb" date="Dec 16, 2013  8:14 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-16/pfizer-drugs-to-be-paired-with-siemens-tests-as-targeted-therapy.html"><headline>Pfizer Drugs to Be Paired With Siemens Tests as Targeted Therapy</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Siemens AG (SIE) will develop diagnostic
tests for U.S. drugmaker Pfizer Inc. (PFE) in an effort to sell
medicines to the patients most likely to benefit from them. </p>
<p>The Siemens Clinical Laboratory, which is based in
Berkeley, California, will lead product development to ensure
efficacy, Europe''s largest engineering company said in an e-mailed statement. </p>
<p>Companion diagnostics are an important enabler of
targeted therapies, John Hubbard, Pfizer''s global head of
development, said in the statement. </p>
<p>Companion diagnostics is used to evaluate a drug''s
effectiveness on particular patients. Health care companies are
increasingly targeting the segment for future growth as
declining health care budgets prioritize the need to ensure the
efficacy pharmaceuticals before they are prescribed. </p>
<p>The diagnostics division generated an earnings before
interest, taxes, depreciation and amortization margin of 20
percent, making it one of Munich-based Siemens''s most profitable
businesses in the last fiscal year. </p>
<p>Siemens announced similar development deals in 2012 with
HIV drugmaker ViiV Healthcare Ltd. and Tocagen Inc., a developer
of an experimental brain tumor treatment, to create tests that
will determine which patients will benefit from the therapies. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass and Carol Hymowitz" date="Dec 16, 2013 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-16/microsoft-losing-mollenkopf-shows-challenge-of-ceo-hunt.html"><headline>Microsoft Losing Mollenkopf Shows Challenge of CEO Hunt</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. co-founder Bill Gates told shareholders last month the software maker''s chief executive officer is a complex role to fill. As the board seeks a final candidate, it''s finding out just how right he is. </p> <p>Steve Mollenkopf, Qualcomm Inc.''s No. 2 executive, was named CEO Dec. 12, taking the 44-year-old out of the running to replace Steve Ballmer at Microsoft. While Alan Mulally, Ford Motor Co.''s CEO, is considered a candidate to lead Microsoft, his star faded amid concerns about his age, 68, and lack of technology experience, people with knowledge of the search have said. EBay Inc. CEO John Donahoe and former VMware Inc. CEO Paul Maritz declined to be considered, people with knowledge of the matter have said. </p> <p>The challenge of finding a new CEO compounds the obstacles facing the world''s largest software maker as the company undergoes its biggest transition in decades. Microsoft is seeking to transform itself into a provider of devices and services amid declining personal-computer sales. The board is seeking an executive with enough experience to run a large public company and plenty of energy to oversee an overhaul, the people said. </p> <p>Going outside for a CEO is always riskier and always more costly, said Joseph McCool, president of search-committee advisory firm McCool Group in Amherst, New Hampshire. For Microsoft, which has only had two CEOs, naming a new leader is one of the most critical decisions in its history. It has serious long-term implications because so much is hanging in the balance: the brand, the workforce, the customer base and investors. </p> <h2>Pay Package </h2> <p>Another issue that could complicate the search for a new CEO is salary. If CEO pay at other companies is any guide, Microsoft will probably have to offer significantly more than the $1.26 million in compensation that Ballmer received for the fiscal year that ended in June. </p> <p>Ballmer, who holds 4 percent of Microsoft''s outstanding shares, has been paid less than many of his top lieutenants and CEOs at peer companies. Mollenkopf received compensation of $14.2 million last year, according to data compiled by Bloomberg, while Mulally earned about $21 million. </p> <p>Companies typically pay a premium of 30 percent to 40 percent whenever they choose a new outside CEO, especially when they''re recruiting another CEO, McCool said. Such compensation often involves extra equity or cash to make up for unvested stock or incentive plans they''re leaving behind, he said. </p> <h2>Qualified Candidate </h2> <p>The board is also considering at least one external candidate who hasn''t been named publicly, two people familiar with the process have said. </p> <p>Frank Shaw, a spokesman for Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft, declined to comment or make executives or directors available for comment. Ford Director Edsel Ford II said on Dec. 5 that Mulally was staying put through 2014. </p> <p>No change, Mulally told reporters last week, in response to questions about his plans to remain Ford''s CEO. I love serving Ford. </p> <p>It''s a handful of people that can really do the job, said Colin Gillis, an analyst at BGC Partners LP in New York. You need a CEO of a $50 billion market cap company who wants to move to a $200 billion company and who wants to take on the challenge of turning Microsoft around. </p> <p>A spate of departures of senior executives at Microsoft over the last decade means many of Ballmer''s top lieutenants have only served at that level for a handful of years. </p> <h2>Difficult Choice </h2> <p>Satya Nadella, Microsoft''s head of cloud services, is a leading contender, people with knowledge of the search said in November. Even so, he has only run a business unit since 2011. </p> <p>Business development and evangelism chief Tony Bates and former Nokia Oyj CEO Stephen Elop remain in the mix, although they''re considered less likely to be offered the job, the people said last month. </p> <p>Susan Sheehan, a spokeswoman for Nokia, declined to comment. </p> <p>Microsoft with multiple businesses, many management layers and a complex organizational structure, has also been a difficult company for outside executives to fit into, said BGC''s Gillis. At the same time, it''s precisely because of such a culture that some investors want to see an outsider come in and shake it up, he said. </p> <p>This has to be a vexing moment for Microsoft because the qualities they likely want in a new CEO are going to be difficult to find in one person, said Michael Useem, director of the Center for Leadership and Change Management at Wharton School of the University of Pennsylvania in Philadelphia. They''re going to want someone who has managed a big company before and has a proven record for doing a turnaround. </p> <h2>Risky Decision </h2> <p>An outsider still needs to fit in even if the culture needs changing, said McCool. A new Microsoft CEO would have to create alliances with insiders to make changes. </p> <p>To do something transformative, they need someone who will be there for more than three to four years, Useem said. </p> <p>Microsoft directors should be mindful of the lesson of J.C. Penney Co., said Steve Miller, the chairman of American International Group Inc. who spent his career helping hobbled companies survive. </p> <p>What must terrify them is the example, say, of J.C. Penney, Miller told Bloomberg Television''s Stephanie Ruhle and Erik Schatzker in an interview. </p> <p>J.C. Penney hired Johnson from Apple Inc., where he turned the iPad maker''s stores into a lucrative retail empire. At J.C. Penney, Johnson as CEO scaled back discounts and sought to transform the department-store chain, resulting in plummeting sales and Johnson being replaced by former CEO Mike Ullman. </p> <h2>Radical Shift </h2> <p>They decided they needed to change, they brought in Ron Johnson, did a radical shift in their whole strategy, and it was a complete failure, Miller said. </p> <p>Miller, a director at Symantec Corp. since the 1990s, was the person who convinced John Thompson to take the CEO job at Symantec. Thompson is now Microsoft''s lead independent director and heading the search for Ballmer''s replacement. Microsoft''s board should do the same and persuade Thompson to become the company''s CEO, Miller said. </p> <p>Thompson has said publicly that he doesn''t want the job. </p> <p>I think the best candidate for that position is John Thompson himself, because of what I saw him do at Symantec, Miller said. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass and Jeff Green" date="Dec 17, 2013  4:48 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-17/microsoft-says-board-will-complete-ceo-search-in-2014.html"><headline>Microsoft Says Board Will Complete CEO Search in 2014</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), which is seeking a replacement for Chief Executive Officer Steve Ballmer, said it anticipates completing the search in the early part of 2014. </p> <p>Lead independent director John Thompson, who is heading Microsoft''s CEO search committee, wrote in a blog post that the Redmond, Washington-based company has identified more than 100 candidates, talked with several dozen and has since focused on about 20 individuals, whom he deemed extremely impressive in their own right. </p> <p>As you would expect, as this group has narrowed, we''ve done deeper research and investigation, including with the full board, Thompson wrote. We''re moving ahead well, and I expect we''ll complete our work in the early part of 2014. </p> <p>The timeline underscores the hurdles of finding a new leader for the world''s biggest software maker. Ballmer said in August that he planned to retire within a year. With no succession plan in place, the board was working toward speedily finding a successor as early as the end of this year, people with knowledge of the process have said. </p> <p>Related: Microsoft''s Nadella Studies Startup Roadmap Amid Search</p><p>Yet some candidates have dropped out of the running. Steve Mollenkopf, Qualcomm Inc.''s No. 2 executive, was named CEO of the wireless chipmaker on Dec. 12, taking him out of the picture to replace Ballmer. While Alan Mulally, Ford Motor Co.''s CEO, is considered a candidate to lead Microsoft, his star has faded amid concerns about his age, 68, and lack of technology experience, people with knowledge of the search have said. EBay Inc. CEO John Donahoe and former VMware Inc. CEO Paul Maritz declined to be considered, people with knowledge of the matter have said. </p> <h2>Complex Role'' </h2> <p>Other candidates are still in the mix, including Microsoft''s cloud-computing chief Satya Nadella, Executive Vice President Tony Bates and former Nokia Oyj CEO Stephen Elop, the people have said. </p> <p>Last month, Microsoft co-founder Bill Gates said at the company''s shareholder meeting that he and other directors have met with a lot of CEO candidates and that it''s a complex role to fill. </p> <p>The software maker is going through its biggest transition in decades, seeking a new leader while it adopts a new corporate structure focused on devices and services. Microsoft is buying Nokia''s handset unit, its largest acquisition by number of employees, as it adapts to a technology landscape where consumers and businesses favor mobile devices and Web-delivered software. </p> <h2>Two CEOs </h2> <p>Mark Moerdler, an analyst at Sanford C. Bernstein  Co., said it''s important for Microsoft to find a replacement sooner rather than later to resolve investor questions and to formally and finally define the company''s core direction. He rates the shares the equivalent of a buy. </p> <p>Microsoft has only had two CEOs in its 38-year history and both have been company insiders. Gates co-founded the software maker in 1975 and led as CEO until 2000, when he passed the reins to longtime executive Ballmer. </p> <p>Frank Shaw, a spokesman for Microsoft, declined to comment beyond the blog post or to make executives available for interviews. </p> <p>Jay Cooney, a spokesman for Ford, said there is no change from a plan the company laid out in November last year that Mulally would remain its CEO through at least 2014. </p> <p>Alan remains absolutely focused on progressing the One Ford plan, he said. We do not engage in speculation. </p> <p>Susan Sheehan, a spokeswoman for Nokia, declined to comment. </p> <p>Microsoft fell 1 percent to $36.52 at the close in New York. </p> <h2>More Transparency </h2> <p>Companies have been compelled to be more transparent on succession issues, especially as activist investors bring more scrutiny to company management, said Joel Koblentz, senior partner at executive recruiter The Koblentz Group in Atlanta. </p> <p>Investor Bill Ackman''s public campaign to get a new CEO at J.C. Penney Co. prompted the company''s other directors to publicly address the CEO search and the plans for the process. That search is still under way. </p> <p>Chip Wilson, founder of retailer Lululemon Athletica Inc., discussed the search for a CEO in a November Bloomberg television interview before the company announced a decision earlier this month. The maker of exercise apparel had been under pressure from investors after it recalled yoga pants for being too sheer. </p> <p>Microsoft earlier this year struck a cooperation agreement with activist investor ValueAct Holdings LP. A ValueAct executive is set to join the company''s board in early 2014. </p> <p>Boards always want to have an orderly process of succession, but the balance between secrecy and transparency seems to be shifting, James Post, a professor at Boston University School of Management, said in an interview. For sure, there''s no going back to the old way where only private searches are done. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Drew Armstrong" date="Dec 17, 2013  4:22 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-17/pfizer-s-schulman-to-leave-as-head-of-new-drug-unit.html"><headline>Pfizer''s Pick to Head New Drug Division Leaves</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE)''s Amy Schulman, named to
head one of the company''s three new drug units starting next
month, will instead leave the company. </p>
<p>Schulman, a deputy to Chief Executive Officer Ian Read and
Pfizer''s general counsel, was chosen in July to lead one of the
businesses as the New York-based company reorganizes ahead of a
potential breakup. Albert Bourla, a 20-year Pfizer veteran, will
now head the unit, which handles vaccines, oncology and consumer
health products, Pfizer said in a statement today. </p>
<p>Pfizer''s division into two brand-drug and one off-patent
business, set for Jan. 1, will occur as the company divests non-medicine operations. The world''s biggest drugmaker has said it
is narrowing its focus on a smaller group of research areas. </p>
<p>Amy Schulman and Pfizer have agreed to separate, the
company said in a statement today. She will stay at the company
for a transition period, after a five-year tenure there. The
company didn''t give a further reason for her departure or say
she was leaving for another job. </p>
<p>A second unit, to be led by Geno Germano, will get
inflammation and immunology, cardiovascular and metabolic drugs,
neuroscience, pain, rare diseases, and women''s and men''s health
products. John Young will head Pfizer''s established products
business, consisting of drugs that have lost patent protection. </p>
<p>Schulman joined Pfizer as general counsel in 2008. She was
given leadership of the company''s nutrition unit in 2010, when
it had $1.87 billion in sales. After that unit was sold, she
headed the $3.12-billion-a-year consumer business, before being
assigned the newly created drug unit. </p>
<p>I have enjoyed my years at Pfizer and wish the company
and my many friends and colleagues well, Schulman said in an
e-mailed statement provided by the company. </p>
<p>Pfizer declined less than 1 percent to $30.14 at 4 p.m. New
York time. The shares have gained 19 percent in the last 12
months. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Dec 17, 2013  2:05 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-17/jpmorgan-said-to-plan-10-increase-in-number-of-junior-bankers.html"><headline>JPMorgan Said to Plan 10% Increase in Number of Junior Bankers</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. plans to boost the number of junior investment bankers it employs by about 10 percent and provide them with protected weekends to reduce their workload, a person familiar with the matter said. </p> <p>Jeff Urwin, the New York-based company''s global head of investment banking, announced the changes on an internal conference call today, said the person, who didn''t say how many people would be affected and asked not to be identified because the new policies aren''t public. Jennifer Zuccarelli, a spokeswoman for JPMorgan, declined to comment. </p> <p>All of the major Wall Street firms are planning to increase investment-banking staff in 2014, according to Jeanne Branthover, the head of financial-services recruitment at Boyden Global Executive Search in New York. They are also trying to protect their best employees from poaching as average pay at the biggest banks declines. </p> <p>Business is better and they''ve stayed lean for so long, Branthover said. People are burned out. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc., which lowered the amount it set aside for employee compensation by 5 percent in the first nine months of the year, said in October that it was discouraging investment-banking analysts from working weekends. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
A pedestrian walks past JPMorgan Chase  Co. headquarters in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Charles Stein" date="Dec 17, 2013 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-17/goldman-sachs-wins-bond-investors-to-flexible-mutual-fund.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Wins Bond Investors to Flexible Mutual Fund</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) is drawing record deposits into a bond mutual fund that''s making money even as interest rates rise, giving the bank a boost in one of the few Wall Street businesses it hasn''t dominated. </p> <p>The Goldman Sachs Strategic Income Fund (GSZAX) attracted $9.8 billion in the first 11 months of 2013, more than three times the net new cash taken in by the New York-based company''s previous best-selling mutual fund in a calendar year, according to Morningstar Inc. (MORN) data going back to 1993. The $12.5 billion fund returned 5.3 percent in 2013 through Dec. 13, beating 96 percent of rivals, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. The fund has quintupled in size this year. </p> <p>Strategic Income is raising the bank''s profile in the $14.6 trillion U.S. mutual-fund industry by standing out among a breed of bond products whose managers can invest across the fixed-income spectrum, including bets that pay off when interest rates rise. The unconstrained funds have caught on as investors flee conventional fixed-income funds in anticipation of rates climbing further and spurring losses in bonds when the Federal Reserve scales back its asset-buying program. </p> <p>This portfolio has a shot at making money in any rate environment, co-manager Michael Swell said in a telephone interview from New York. You will see money flowing out of traditional fixed income into products like this one. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
A trader works in the Goldman Sachs Group Inc. booth on the floor of the New York Stock Exchange on Nov. 4, 2013. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Duane D. Stanford" date="Dec 18, 2013  4:28 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-18/general-mills-profit-trails-estimates-amid-higher-input-costs.html"><headline>General Mills Profit Trails Estimates Costs Increase</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>General Mills Inc. (GIS), the maker of
Cheerios cereal, reported second-quarter profit that trailed
analysts'' estimates because of higher commodity costs and
unfavorable currency fluctuations. </p>
<p>Adjusted earnings per share for the period ended Nov. 24
were 83 cents, the Minneapolis-based company said in a statement
today. Analysts projected 87 cents, the average of estimates
compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Ken Powell said results in the
quarter were hurt by higher ingredient costs and slowing food
and beverage industry sales. Currency-exchange effects reduced
net sales growth by 3 percentage points in the international
unit, the company said. Gross margin, excluding the increased
value of some commodity positions and grain inventories,
narrowed by 1 percentage point to 35.7 percent. </p>
<p>The quarter featured modest sales growth, but margins
were below our expectations, Christopher Growe, an analyst at
Stifel Financial Corp. in St. Louis, said today in a note. The
margin was pressured this quarter with lower volumes and higher
input cost inflation. </p>
<p>General Mills rose 0.3 percent to $49.73 at the close in
New York. The stock has gained 23 percent this year, compared
with a 27 percent increase for the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index. </p>




Photographer: Daniel Acker/Bloomberg

<p>
General Mills Inc. Cheerios brand cereal sits on display at a supermarket in Princeton, Illinois. While General Mills reaffirmed its forecast for fiscal 2014 adjusted earnings per share of $2.87 to $2.90, the company said foreign-currency effects will now be a greater headwind than originally estimated. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Drew Armstrong and Susan Decker" date="Dec 18, 2013  4:05 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-18/pfizer-s-deal-on-generic-viagra-shows-treatment-changes.html"><headline>Pfizer''s Deal on Generic Viagra Shows Treatment Changes</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Fifteen years after Pfizer (PFE) Inc.''s
Viagra changed the sexual equation for older men, the
blockbuster impotence drug is set to become available in a less
expensive generic form as early as 2017. </p>
<p>Pfizer''s little blue pills, which generally cost about $15
each, replaced treatment that included penile injections, pumps
and surgery. It will be produced generically, probably for a far
lower cost, after Israel-based Teva Pharmaceuticals Industries
Ltd. reached a legal settlement to sell a copy of the drug,
whose chemical name is sildenafil citrate, more than two years
earlier than expected. </p>
<p>More than 18 million Americans older than age 20 suffer
from erectile dysfunction, according to Johns Hopkins
University''s Bloomberg School of Public Health. Viagra, the
first of three medicines to take on the issue, has been one of
the best-known pills sold by Pfizer, the world''s biggest
drugmaker, generating $2.05 billion in 2012, the most ever. </p>
<p>This blue pill changed the way we practiced medicine,
said David Samadi, the chairman of urology at New York''s Lenox
Hill Hospital. </p>
<p>This year, Pfizer began selling the blue pill through a
company-sponsored website to combat counterfeit versions sold
online. Under a settlement announced yesterday, Teva (TEVA), the
world''s largest generic-drug maker, can enter the market on Dec.
11, 2017, and will pay patent royalties through the expiration
of the Viagra patent in April 2020, New York-based Pfizer said
in a statement. Other terms weren''t disclosed, and Teva already
sells generic versions of the drug in some European countries. </p>
<p>Pfizer shares rose 2.1 percent to $30.77 at the close in
New York. The stock has gained 20 percent in the past 12 months. </p>
<h2>Surprising Finding </h2>
<p>The drug was an accident. Pfizer first started looking at
sildenafil citrate to treat high blood pressure and angina.
During testing, though, patients developed erections. The
patent, issued in 2002, is for use of the compound to treat
impotence. </p>
<p>Some aspects of Viagra''s patent were earlier rejected in
2010 because it was similar to a Chinese herb known as Horny
Goat Weed. Teva lost its bid to invalidate the rest of the
patent at trial, and was appealing the case. The U.S. Court of
Appeals for the Federal Circuit yesterday dismissed the appeals. </p>
<p>Erectile dysfunction gets more common as men age. It can
also be caused by cardiovascular problems and a lack of physical
activity. </p>
<h2>Quick Sales </h2>
<p>After it was approved in 1998, Pfizer said 3 million
patients got the drug that year, moving 50 million pills for
$788 million that year, and $1.03 billion in 1999. </p>
<p>It had a particular allure in society, as patients had to
pay for the drug themselves as insurance companies rarely
covered it, said Louis Kavoussi, chairman of urology at the
Arthur Smith Institute for Urology in New Hyde Park, New York. </p>
<p>That gave it more of an aura, Kavoussi said in a
telephone interview. When patients came in, they''d beat around
the bush, and you knew what they were asking for. It was like
they were asking for the Playboy magazine in the back of the
store. </p>
<p>A generic version should cut the cost of the pills. Going
generic is a good thing; it''s very expensive, Kavoussi said.
It is still not covered most of the time. </p>
<p>That price, and the interest in the drug, has also prompted
theft and counterfeiting. When Kavoussi changed offices in 2006,
a demolition crew took apart the old space, he said. When they
did, they found box after empty box of Viagra samples. </p>
<p>They left them in the ceiling -- years later we found
them! Somebody -- likely hospital staff, Kavoussi said -- had
been breaking into the supply closet, taking the pills and
hiding the empties. </p>
<h2>Treatment Revolution </h2>
<p>That aside, it was a revolution in treatment, said the two
doctors. Many patients with sexual dysfunction were diabetics,
whose disease had damaged blood vessels, hurting the ability of
the penis to fill with blood to create an erection. </p>
<p>Others were prostate cancer surgery patients, a side effect
of which can be the inability to become erect. For the prostate
cancer patients, the potential of Viagra to help was
particularly meaningful, Samadi said, since their average age in
his practice was about 50. </p>
<p>These are very young guys, he said. Viagra can be
very successful in restoring function. </p>
<p>Now about 70 percent of patients can be treated with pills,
Samadi said, a category that includes Eli Lilly  Co.''s Cialis
and Bayer AG''s Levitra. Lilly projects generic Cialis will enter
the market in November 2017, though it has other patents on the
medicine that last through 2020. Bayer''s main patent on Levitra
expires in October 2018. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bob Van Voris and Hugh Son" date="Dec 18, 2013  2:57 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-18/jpmorgan-sues-fdic-for-more-than-1-billion-wamu-liabilities-1-.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sues FDIC Over $1 Billion-Plus WaMu Liabilities</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) sued the
Federal Deposit Insurance Corp. claiming the agency is
responsible for more than $1 billion in liabilities faced by the
company as a result of its 2008 takeover of Washington Mutual
Inc.''s bank. </p>
<p>JPMorgan and the FDIC disagree over which side promised to
cover losses related to the takeover at the urging of the
regulator during the financial crisis. JPMorgan''s latest suit
leaves it to a judge to resolve. </p>
<p>JPMorgan said in the complaint filed yesterday in federal
court in Washington that the FDIC agreed to shield it from
liability from lawsuits claiming failures by Washington Mutual.
JPMorgan said it took on only limited liabilities in its
purchase of the Seattle-based bank''s assets. </p>
<p>JPM is simply saying, Wait a minute, we''re not a
punching bag.'' They''re not overreaching in the sense that they
had an agreement, Peter Henning, a former federal prosecutor
and Securities and Exchange Commission attorney who teaches law
at Wayne State University in Detroit. In fairness to them, the
FDIC begged them to come in and rescue WaMu. Now they''re saying,
Wait a minute, you''ve turned on us?'' </p>
<p>JPMorgan has a reasonably good chance of success on its
claim, Henning said, making a settlement likely. </p>
<p>JPMorgan, the biggest U.S. bank by assets, said it is the
subject of numerous lawsuits, including claims by buyers of
securities backed by faulty Washington Mutual residential loans. </p>
<h2>Damages Asked </h2>
<p>The bank is seeking unspecified damages and a court order
declaring that the FDIC is responsible for the claims against
Washington Mutual. </p>
<p>The FDIC''s indemnification obligations that are the
subject of this action are a matter of contract, the New York-based bank said in its complaint. They are promises that the
FDIC made to JPMC to induce JPMC to buy Washington Mutual''s
assets, it said. </p>
<p>The complaint follows JPMorgan''s $13 billion settlement
last month to resolve U.S. probes of its sale of mortgage bonds. </p>
<p>In 2008, the FDIC seized WaMu''s banking operations and sold
them to JPMorgan for $1.9 billion. The bank agreed not to pursue
reimbursement from the FDIC for bad loans issued by WaMu. Which
side has responsibility for other claims against WaMu is less
clear. </p>
<p>The suit filed yesterday is the latest attempt by JPMorgan
to fix responsibility for WaMu liabilities on FDIC, which took
over as receiver in connection with WaMu''s failure, the largest
in history for a U.S. bank. </p>
<h2>2008 Agreement </h2>
<p>The bank bases its claim on a Sept. 25, 2008 Purchase and
Assumption Agreement between FDIC and JPMorgan. One paragraph
of the 39-page document sets out the WaMu liabilities to be
taken on by JPMorgan. </p>
<p>JPMorgan agrees to pay, perform, and discharge, all of
the liabilities of the failed bank which are reflected on the
books and records of the failed bank as of bank closing,
according to the agreement. </p>
<p>It''s got all the worst attributes of a contract dispute -
- a poorly-written document created in a rush, said Henning. </p>
<p>The disagreement between JPMorgan and FDIC over the meaning
of that agreement is the subject of JPMorgan''s new suit as well
as other suits involving both sides. </p>
<p>In a 2010 suit, Deutsche Bank AG, as a mortgage-bond
trustee, sued over $6 billion to $10 billion in securities
backed by flawed WaMu mortgages. One of JPMorgan''s defenses to
the claim was that any money owed in the Deutsche Bank suit was
the responsibility of FDIC. </p>
<h2>No Liability </h2>
<p>JPMorgan said in a November 2010 court filing in the
lawsuit that it never assumed any liability for the claims
asserted by Deutsche Bank and that the FDIC must indemnify
JPMorgan in full. </p>
<p>Last year, JPMorgan sued the FDIC seeking to force it to
pay a $2.65 million settlement of taxes Washington Mutual owed
the state of Connecticut. That case is pending in federal court
in Washington, D.C. And in 2010 the bank asked the court to
shift liability to FDIC for unpaid taxes allegedly owed by
Washington Mutual to North Carolina. </p>
<p>The FDIC is saying, you''re a sophisticated party, you
know what the risks were, everybody understands that when you
buy a failing bank, there''s going to be a lot of carryover
successor liability there, said James Cox, a professor at Duke
University School of Law in Durham, North Carolina. At the end
of the day, this was a good deal for JPMorgan. </p>
<p>Greg Hernandez, an FDIC spokesman, declined to comment on
the bank''s allegations. Brian Marchiony, a JPMorgan spokesman,
declined to comment on the case. </p>
<p>The case is JPMorgan Chase Bank N.A. v. Federal Deposit
Insurance Corp., 13-cv-01997, U.S. District Court, District of
Columbia (Washington). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Phil Milford" date="Dec 18, 2013  1:41 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-18/jpmorgan-sued-by-mississippi-over-debt-collections.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sued by Mississippi Over Debt Collections</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the largest
U.S. bank, was sued by Mississippi over debt-collection
practices that have long plagued consumers, according to a
complaint filed yesterday in state court. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Mary Childs" date="Dec 18, 2013 12:47 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-18/goldman-sachs-high-yield-head-trader-bahl-to-depart-this-week.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs High-Yield Head Trader Bahl to Depart This Week</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Jeff Bahl, the head of U.S. high-yield corporate bond trading at Goldman Sachs Group Inc., plans
to depart from the firm. </p>
<p>Bahl, 34, named a managing director in 2009, will leave his
post on Dec. 20, Tiffany Galvin, a spokeswoman for New York-based Goldman Sachs, confirmed in a telephone interview,
declining further comment. Bahl declined to discuss his move. </p>
<p>Bahl worked at Bank of America Corp. from 2006 to 2008, and
earlier at Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc., according to Financial
Industry Regulatory Authority records. He graduated from
Washington and Lee University in Lexington, Virginia, in 2002. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jason Corcoran" date="Dec 18, 2013 11:45 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-18/goldman-sachs-sees-risks-for-russia-in-ukraine-bond-investment.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Sees Risks for Russia in Ukraine Bond Investment</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Russia''s plans to spend $15 billion
of its oil wealth buying Ukrainian bonds is a risky bet that is
becoming a concern of investors, according to Clemens Grafe,
Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (G)''s chief economist in Russia. </p>
<p>Russia yesterday committed $15 billion, primarily from its
$88 billion National Welfare Fund, to buy Ukrainian bonds as
part of an aid package for its former Soviet neighbor. The
sovereign vehicle is a rainy-day fund built up to stabilize
retirement provisions. </p>
<p>The numbers aren''t insignificant, Grafe said by phone
about the deal. Most of the exposure is coming from the state
and the state-controlled banks. If the bet goes wrong, it will
be seen on the balance sheet. </p>
<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin agreed on the deal with
Ukrainian President Viktor Yanukovych yesterday, after the
smaller country suspended plans to sign a trade agreement with
the European Union. Ukraine is a crucial pipeline transit nation
for Russian natural gas exports to western Europe, while Russia
accounts for about 25 percent of its exports. </p>
<p>Moody''s cited Putin as saying Ukrainian borrowers owed
Russia about $28 billion, according to a report this month,
before the $15 billion of bond purchases. Ratings agencies will
eventually have to look at this exposure, Grafe said. </p>
<h2>Spectacularly Wrong'' </h2>
<p>Charles Seville, director of Fitch Ratings'' sovereign
rating group in London and Kai Stukenbrock, head of sovereign
ratings for the Commonwealth of Independent States and at
Standard  Poor''s, didn''t immediately return calls. </p>
<p>Russia''s investment can go spectacularly wrong if Ukraine
fails to refinance it by 2015, Maxim Tishin, who helps manage
$1 billion as a portfolio manager at UFG Asset Management in
Moscow, said in e-mailed comments. If it places at par, that
would be a bad trade financially, that''s for sure. </p>
<p>Ukraine''s dollar bonds extended the biggest jump on record,
with the yield on notes due in June falling 28 basis points, or
0.28 percentage points, to 8.48 percent by 6:41 p.m. in Kiev,
the lowest since June on a closing basis. The rate dropped more
than six percentage points yesterday. The hryvnia, which is
managed by the central bank, gained 0.1 percent to 8.2850 per
dollar. </p>
<p>The funds may help the smaller nation avoid a default after
its economy sank into the third recession since 2008 and its
foreign reserves sank to a seven-year low. </p>
<h2>Political Moves'' </h2>
<p>Even so, Ukrainians are staging the biggest protests in
almost a decade in Independence Square in Kiev after Yanukovych
rejected signing the EU integration and trade accord last month
to deepen ties with Russia, which had opposed the deal. </p>
<p>Decisions like we have seen yesterday are clearly
dominated by political motives only, Sergey Dergachev, who
helps oversee about $9 billion as a money manager at Union
Investment Privatfonds GmbH in Frankfurt, said in e-mailed
comments. Russia bonded Ukraine much closer to herself, thus
distancing Ukraine from the EU. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Stephanie Tong" date="Dec 18, 2013  1:46 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-18/goldman-sachs-said-to-name-new-global-commodities-metals-heads.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Said to Name Global Commodities, Metals Heads</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) made two
senior appointments for its global commodities and metals
businesses, said a person with knowledge of the matter. </p>
<p>Charles McGarraugh, currently head of European mortgage-product trading, was named global head of metals trading, said
the person, who asked not to be identified because the
information is private. Don Casturo, currently head of
commodities investor products, has been appointed chief
operating officer of global commodities. </p>
<p>The personnel changes are being made at at time when the
world''s biggest banks are employing fewer staff members for
their commodities businesses as tighter regulations and lower
raw-material prices spur cutbacks. Investors pulled a record
$36.3 billion from commodity products this year through
November, according to Barclays Plc, while the Standard  Poor''s
GSCI Index (SPGSCI) of raw-material prices is headed for the first annual
drop since 2008. </p>
<p>Market participants, whether it be corporate, governments
or Wall Street firms such as Goldman, should not back away from
their commitment to this sector, Sandy Mehta, chief executive
officer of Value Investment Principals Ltd. in Hong Kong, wrote
in an e-mail today. Investment banking in commodities should
rebound smartly, predicated on stronger U.S. and Europe growth,
and a flattening out and rebound in key emerging markets. </p>
<p>Michael DuVally, a Goldman Sachs spokesman in New York,
didn''t respond to a request for comment on the appointments
after regular business hours. </p>
<h2>Falling Headcount </h2>
<p>The firm was ranked second to JPMorgan Chase  Co. in terms
of commodity revenue in the first six months of this year,
according to data from Coalition, a London-based analytics
company. Revenue derived from commodities at the 10 largest
banks from Goldman Sachs to Barclays will drop 14 percent to
$4.7 billion this year, the data show. </p>
<p>Total headcount in commodity units at those banks dropped
to 2,290 at the end of September, about 4 percent less than at
the end of 2012, according to Coalition. </p>
<p>JPMorgan is seeking to sell its physical commodity
business, while Deutsche Bank AG announced 200 employee cutbacks
on Dec. 5. Goldman Sachs, which has put its uranium-trading unit
up for sale, has no intention of selling its commodity business,
Chief Financial Officer Harvey Schwartz said in October. </p>
<h2>Fed Review </h2>
<p>It''s natural for banks to keep the commodities business
for hedging opportunities, said Ronald Wan, chief China
adviser at Asian Capital Holdings Ltd. It''s too early for them
to quit this line of business. Demand for commodities and metals
will recover eventually. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs is among banks whose ability to participate
in the commodities markets is being examined by the Federal
Reserve. The Fed is conducting a review while U.S. lawmakers and
regulators raise concerns that banks might abuse their various
roles in physical commodities markets, or that the businesses
pose risks to the firms'' financial stability. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass and Marie Mawad" date="Dec 18, 2013 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-18/microsoft-s-nadella-studies-startup-ethos-amid-ceo-search.html"><headline>Microsoft''s Nadella Studies Startup Roadmap Amid Search</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT)''s cloud-computing chief Satya Nadella, one of the leading contenders for the top job at the world''s largest software maker, took time in Paris last week to huddle with local startups like video-on-demand company Video Futur Entertainment Group SA. </p> <p>It''s important to speak with startups because the tech cycle is such that the small guys make it big and the big guys die, Nadella said in an interview in Paris, where he was attending a technology conference. </p> <p>Nadella, who has emerged as one of the candidates to replace Microsoft Chief Executive Officer Steve Ballmer according to people familiar with the matter, needs to bone up all he can on how to keep a decades-old technology behemoth from getting lapped by upstarts. The board will complete the search for Ballmer''s successor in early 2014, lead independent director John Thompson wrote in a blog post yesterday. </p> <p>Related: Microsoft Says Board Will Complete CEO Search in 2014</p><p>Even if Nadella isn''t appointed CEO, he has said publicly that he absolutely intends to stay at Microsoft. That would set up the 46-year-old as a key lieutenant to whoever becomes the new chief, given Nadella''s 21 years at the company, where he has worked in everything from small business software to the Bing search engine to cloud services. </p>




Photographer: David Paul Morris/Bloomberg

<p>
Following CEO Steve Ballmer''s August announcement that he plans to retire within a year, Satya Nadella, executive vice president of the cloud and enterprise division of Microsoft Corp., has emerged as one of the leading contenders, people familiar with the matter have said. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elisha Bala-Gbogbo" date="Dec 19, 2013  9:06 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-19/chevron-oil-lease-sale-is-halted-by-nigerian-court.html"><headline>Chevron Oil-Lease Sale Is Halted by Nigerian Court</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX)''s planned $1 billion
sale of three oil leases in Nigeria was halted by the country''s
federal high court after a local bidder sued the company. </p>
<p>Justice Mohammed Yunusa issued an interim injunction
preventing Chevron from inviting or accepting further bids for
its 40 percent interest in the leases, court documents show. </p>
<p>Local producer Brittania-U is suing Chevron for failing to
complete deals on three leases after bidding closed Nov. 15,
Brittania-U''s lawyer, Rickey Tarfa, said in a statement. The
principal claim is to validate the sale to Brittania-U and
secure damages for failure to uphold the contract, Tarfa said. </p>
<p>Chevron, the third-largest oil producer in Nigeria, holds
interests in 10 deepwater oil blocks in the country in
partnership with state-owned Nigerian National Petroleum Corp.
In June, it offered its 40 percent stake in five leases with a
view to selling them by year-end. It''s one of several foreign
producers in Nigeria selling assets as their operations are
plagued by persistent unrest, violence and crude theft. </p>
<p>The suit against San Ramon, California-based Chevron was
filed Dec. 12. </p>
<p>The company is aware of a court action in respect of
the leases, Isabel Ordonez, a spokeswoman in Houston, said by e-mail. Chevron is a responsible and law-abiding corporate
organization committed to the laws and regulations guiding the
operations of oil companies in the country. </p>
<p>The case is Brittania-U v. Chevron Nigeria Ltd., Chevron
U.S.A Inc.,  Co., FHC/L/CS/1711/2013. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Carla Main" date="Dec 19, 2013 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-19/jpmorgan-denmark-bitcoins-eu-securities-compliance.html"><headline>JPMorgan, Denmark Bitcoins, EU Securities: Compliance</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The spread of Bitcoins is prompting
regulators in Scandinavia to draft new rules in an effort to
prevent virtual money from slipping into a legal gray zone. </p>
<p>Denmark is the latest nation to prepare standards to
protect its consumers from risks associated with virtual
currencies after the regulator found it lacked authority to
prevent a company creating an exchange for the software. </p>
<p>The most likely outcome would be an amendment to existing
financial legislation so that we have regulation covering it,
Michael Landberg, chief legal adviser at the Financial
Supervisory Authority in Denmark, said Dec. 18 in a phone
interview. </p>
<p>More and more nations are taking an official stance on
virtual currencies that aren''t controlled by any government or
central bank. Norway said this month it won''t recognize Bitcoins
as legal tender and will impose a capital gains tax. Prices sank
as much as 35 percent yesterday after China''s largest Bitcoin
operator, BTC China, said a third-party payment provider gave
notice it will no longer provide deposit services. That followed
a move by China''s central bank to bar financial institutions and
payment companies from handling Bitcoin transactions. </p>
<p>Denmark plans to align itself with other nations in
designing a framework that deals with gray zones created by the
use of Bitcoins and its competitors, Landberg said. The FSA is
preparing draft legislation for lawmakers to consider, he said. </p>
<p>Since their introduction in 2008, Bitcoins have spread
rapidly, with about 12 million in circulation, according to
Bitcoincharts. They''re used to pay for goods and services
ranging from hand-made rugs to window cleaning. </p>
<p>The price of Bitcoins soared above $1,000 earlier this
year, compared with about $12 a year ago, according to Mt. Gox,
an online exchange dealing in Bitcoins. </p>
<h2>Compliance Policy </h2>
<h2>Barnier Welcomes EU Deal on Central Securities Depositaries </h2>
<p>Michel Barnier, the European Union''s financial services
commissioner, said negotiators clinched a provisional deal
yesterday on rules for central securities depositaries. </p>
<p>The rules will introduce safeguards to address the risks
resulting from the provision of banking services ancillary to
the settlement, according to statement by the EU. </p>
<p>The safeguards include an additional capital surcharge for
CSDs and banks providing these banking services to CSD users,
the EU said in the statement. </p>
<h2>Dutch Sign Agreement With U.S. to Fight Tax Avoidance </h2>
<p>The Netherlands and the U.S. signed an agreement on
automatically exchanging information between the tax authorities
of both nations, Deputy Finance Minister Frans Weekers said in a
letter to parliament. </p>
<p>The automatic exchange of information between the two
nations will start in September 2015. </p>
<h2>Courts </h2>
<h2>JPMorgan Sues FDIC Over More Than $1 Billion WaMu Liabilities </h2>
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) sued the Federal Deposit Insurance
Corp. claiming the agency is responsible for more than $1
billion in liabilities faced by the bank as a result of its 2008
takeover of Washington Mutual Inc. </p>
<p>JPMorgan and the FDIC had been arguing over who promised to
cover certain losses related to the bank''s takeover of
Washington Mutual at the urging of the regulator during the
financial crisis. JPMorgan''s filing of the suit will leave it up
to a judge to resolve the dispute. </p>
<p>JPMorgan said in the complaint filed Dec. 18 in federal
court in Washington that the FDIC agreed to shield it from
liability from lawsuits claiming failures by Washington Mutual.
JPMorgan said it took on only limited liabilities in its
purchase of the Seattle-based bank''s assets. </p>
<p>JPMorgan said it is the subject of numerous lawsuits,
including claims by buyers of securities backed by faulty
Washington Mutual residential loans. The bank is seeking
unspecified damages and a court order declaring that the FDIC is
responsible for the claims against Washington Mutual. </p>
<p>Greg Hernandez, an FDIC spokesman, didn''t immediately
respond to voice-mail and e-mail messages seeking comment on the
bank''s allegations. Brian Marchiony, a JPMorgan spokesman,
declined to comment on the case. </p>
<p>The case is JPMorgan Chase Bank NA v. Federal Deposit
Insurance Corp., 13-cv-01997, U.S. District Court, District of
Columbia (Washington). </p>
<p>For more, see Interviews, below. </p>
<h2>Interviews/Meetings </h2>
<h2>SEC Meets on Proposal For ''33 Act Offer-and-Sale Rules </h2>
<p>The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission conducted an
open meeting in Washington yesterday to consider whether to
propose rules and forms related to the offer and sale of
securities under Section 3(b) of the Securities Act of 1933. </p>
<p>The possible rules are being considered as part of the
mandates created by the Jumpstart Our Business Startups Act. </p>
<p>For the video, click here. </p>
<h2>Holland Says JPMorgan Suit Against FDIC Very Clear'' </h2>
<p>Michael Holland, chairman of Holland  Co., talked about
JPMorgan Chase  Co.''s decision to sue the Federal Deposit
Insurance Corp., claiming the agency is responsible for more
than $1 billion in liabilities faced by the bank as a result of
its 2008 takeover of Washington Mutual Inc. </p>
<p>Holland spoke with Scarlet Fu, Alix Steel and Tom Keene on
Bloomberg Television''s Surveillance. </p>
<p>For the video, click here. </p>
<h2>ECB Says Euro Bank-Failure Plan Risks Losing Market Credibility </h2>
<p>European Central Bank Vice President Vitor Constancio said
markets will question the credibility of a planned authority for
euro-area bank failures unless it has rapid-response capability
and the power to borrow. </p>
<p>An urgency procedure should be contemplated in order to
allow a decision in 24 hours, Constancio said. </p>
<p>He made the remarks during a meeting of European Union
finance ministers in Brussels yesterday. </p>
<p>If that is not there, we fear that markets will find the
process too complex and it will not be totally credible that it
can work in certain situations with the speed that is
required. </p>
<p>The proposal for a Single Resolution Mechanism with a
common fund to cover the costs of saving or shuttering lenders
is part of a euro-area effort to break the financial links
between sovereigns and banks by centralizing oversight and
crisis management. The blueprint, presented in July by Michel
Barnier, the EU''s financial services chief, has met with a
barrage of German-led concerns, leading governments to embark on
extensive changes. </p>
<p>Ministers are racing to meet a year-end deadline to broker
a deal on the plans so that negotiations with the European
Parliament can be brought to a conclusion before the assembly
breaks for elections in May. </p>
<p>Governments last week discussed a governance structure for
the resolution authority that would hand the Council of the
European Union, the EU institution that represents nations, a
dispute-resolution role. This conflicts with Barnier''s
blueprint, which made the European Commission, the EU''s
executive arm, the top decision maker. </p>
<p>For more, click here, and click here. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Dec 19, 2013 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-19/microsoft-amazon-propel-washington-to-most-innovative-state.html"><headline>Microsoft, Amazon Propel Washington to Most Innovative State</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The most innovative state in the
U.S. isn''t California, home of Google Inc. (GOOG) and Stanford
University, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. It''s
Washington, where Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) and Amazon.com Inc. (AMZN) are based. </p>
<p>California came in second and Massachusetts third in the
ranking, which looked at criteria such as the percentage of
professionals in science, technology, engineering and
mathematics, and the number of patents and public technology
companies in each state. </p>
<p>Washington, known for rainy Seattle, abundant greenery and
fleece-clad citizens, had the highest total score, not by
topping any of the categories -- California is highest in patent
activity and five states have more skilled workers -- but by
placing near the top. That''s due to the large technology
workforce, high productivity rates and plethora of public
companies in aerospace, biotechnology and computer technology. </p>
<p>I am a big believer in the state of Washington, said
Sunny Gupta, co-founder, president and chief executive officer
of software-maker Apptio Inc. in Bellevue, Washington, who said
he chose to live in the Seattle region over the San Francisco
Bay area. It really comes down to having an incredible network
effect, primarily dominated by Microsoft and Amazon but also a
lot of great entrepreneurial talent. </p>
<p>Technology enterprises make up 21 percent of Washington''s
public companies, according to the ranking, while they comprise
29 percent in California and Massachusetts. </p>
<h2>Engineering Roots </h2>
<p>The state''s strong engineering roots go back to Boeing Co. (BA),
the airplane manufacturer that was based in Seattle until 2001
and still has extensive manufacturing operations in the Puget
Sound area. The company attracted not just employees but also
suppliers to the area, said Ed Lazowska, who holds the Bill and
Melinda Gates chair in computer science and engineering at the
University of Washington in Seattle. </p>
<p>Microsoft''s 1979 move to the suburbs of Seattle from
Albuquerque, New Mexico, attracted computer engineers throughout
the 1980s and 1990s, as did other area companies such as Aldus
Corp., the maker of publishing-software PageMaker. Nintendo Co. (7974)
chose Redmond, Washington, as its U.S. headquarters, pulling in
game developers, Lazowska said. </p>
<p>Former employees of these companies have gone on to found
local startups in and around Seattle. The availability of top
engineers has attracted technology firms such as Google,
Facebook Inc. (FB) and Salesforce.com Inc. (CRM), which have set up large
offices in the area. </p>
<p>These companies move here because we, in fact, have a
phenomenal workforce, Lazowska said. </p>
<h2>Cloud Cover </h2>
<p>Washington state arguably owns the cloud, said
Lazowska, referring to computing services delivered via the Web
that are offered by companies such as Amazon and Microsoft. The
area also boasts a strong presence in segments such as data
analytics and storage. </p>
<p>Internet firms such as Zillow Inc. (Z) and Expedia Inc. (EXPE) merge
the region''s strength in retail -- as seen with local companies
such as Nordstrom Inc., Starbucks Corp. and Costco Wholesale
Corp. -- with technology expertise, Lazowska said. </p>
<p>Engineers are attracted to the Seattle region instead of
Silicon Valley, thanks to more affordable housing and lower
taxes -- Washington has no state income tax -- said Gupta, who
develops software that helps companies manage and monitor their
technology spending. </p>
<p>About 2.8 percent of Washington residents work in science,
technology, engineering and mathematics, more than California''s
2.3 percent, and below Washington DC''s 9.2 percent and 3.4
percent in Massachusetts, the data showed. </p>
<h2>Learning Environment </h2>
<p>Microsoft alums such as Brad Silverberg and Pete Higgins
co-founded venture-capital firms Ignition Partners and Second
Avenue Partners. Rob Glaser founded RealNetworks Inc. after he
left Microsoft and Sujal Patel left RealNetworks to found
storage-company Isilon Systems Inc., which became EMC Corp.''s
biggest acquisition in 2010. </p>
<p>The region also has a strong wireless heritage, owing to
McCaw Cellular Communications Inc., which became ATT Wireless.
McCaw executive Tom Alberg co-founded the venture firm Madrona
Venture Group LLC, which has funded local firms such as Amazon,
Isilon and Gupta''s Apptio. T-Mobile US Inc. (TMUS) is based in
Bellevue. </p>
<p>While Seattle has developed a reputation for rain and
clouds, the region also offers natural beauty and outside
activities, Gupta said. </p>
<p>Skiing is close by. There''s hiking and kayaking and the
landscape, he said. The only negative is the weather. </p>
<h2>Education Challenge </h2>
<p>While the technology industry benefits the state, residents
and lawmakers should have one major concern, said Lazowska --
how poorly Washington does educating local students. The economy
was built by a labor force educated elsewhere, and Washington
rates 49th in the U.S. in the number of students who graduate
with bachelor''s degrees from public universities, he said. There
aren''t enough spots for university students in areas such as
computer science, he said. </p>
<p>It''s a question for the kids that grow up here, he
said. Are they going to be first-tier participants in this
economy, or are they going to be washing people''s cars and
selling them cars? </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Dec 20, 2013  5:32 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-20/morgan-stanley-to-sell-global-oil-merchanting-unit-to-rosneft.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley to Sell Global Oil Merchanting to Rosneft</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley agreed to sell a unit
that stores, trades and transports oil products to a subsidiary
of Russia''s OAO Rosneft (ROSN) as the investment bank backs away from
owning some physical commodities businesses. </p>
<p>The sale of the global oil merchanting business is expected
to be completed in the second half of next year, New York-based
Morgan Stanley said yesterday in a statement that didn''t
disclose financial terms. The firm also said it''s exploring
strategic options for its stake in TransMontaigne Inc., the
Denver-based petroleum and chemical transportation and storage
company. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley Chief Executive Officer James Gorman, 55,
has been deciding what to do with the commodities business for
more than a year amid lower revenue and more scrutiny from
regulators. He''s also seeking to shrink the amount of capital
dedicated to the fixed-income and commodities division in his
quest to boost return on equity. </p>
<p>We view this as positive, as it moves Morgan Stanley
closer to shrinking the less profitable, lower ROE parts of its
FICC business, Brennan Hawken, a UBS AG analyst, wrote in a
note to investors. New capital requirements on these
commodities businesses mean sufficient ROEs will be difficult to
realize, even if the cyclical headwinds become tailwinds. </p>




Photographer: SeongJoon Cho/Bloomberg

<p>
About 100 front-office executives in the U.S., U.K. and Singapore, or one-third of Morgan Stanley''s total commodities front-office personnel, will move to Rosneft Group, the firm said. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Gavin Finch and Trista Kelley" date="Dec 20, 2013  7:26 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-20/goldman-sachs-said-to-ban-multibank-chats-amid-currency-probes.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Said to Ban Multibank Chats Amid Currency Probes</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. followed
competitors in banning traders from using chat rooms involving
counterparts at more than one bank as regulators probe alleged
currency-rigging, said a person with knowledge of the matter. </p>
<p>Traders will still be allowed to communicate one-on-one
with dealers at other firms to discuss business, said the
person, who asked not to be identified because the decision
hasn''t been made public. Fiona Laffan, a spokeswoman for the New
York-based firm, declined to comment on the move. </p>
<p>Banks are clamping down on traders'' use of chat rooms after
regulators used them as evidence in their investigations into
the manipulation of benchmark interest rates and foreign-exchange rates. JPMorgan Chase  Co., Royal Bank of Scotland
Group Plc and Lloyds Banking Group Plc (LLOY) prohibited multidealer
chat rooms this week. Deutsche Bank AG will widen a ban on such
forums to include its entire investment bank and transaction-banking business. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs said in November it''s under investigation by
regulators probing foreign-exchange rates and is cooperating
with those inquiries. Goldman Sachs, JPMorgan and Deutsche Bank
are among almost a dozen firms that are reviewing millions of e-mails, instant messages and phone records of their foreign-exchange employees for evidence of potential manipulation,
people with knowledge of those probes have said. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
Goldman Sachs said in November it''s under investigation by regulators probing foreign-exchange rates and is cooperating with those inquiries. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri" date="Dec 23, 2013  3:31 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-23/disney-elects-twitter-s-dorsey-to-board-of-directors.html"><headline>Disney Elects Twitter''s Dorsey to Board of Directors</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS)''s board elected
Twitter Inc. co-founder and Chairman Jack Dorsey as an
independent director. </p>
<p>He will stand for election with the company''s other
directors at the March 18 annual meeting, the Burbank,
California-based company said today in a statement. </p>
<p>The perspective he brings to Disney and its board is
extremely valuable, given our strategic priorities, which
include utilizing the latest technologies and platforms to reach
more people and to enhance the relationship we have with our
customers, Disney Chief Executive Officer Robert Iger said in
the statement. </p>
<p>Judith Estrin, a former chief technology officer at Cisco
Systems Inc., will not stand for re-election, the company said.
She reached Disney''s 15-year limit on board service. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Henry Goldman" date="Dec 23, 2013  2:50 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-23/goldman-sachs-s-glen-picked-by-de-blasio-to-head-nyc-development.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs''s Glen Appointed New York City Deputy Mayor</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Alicia Glen, head of urban
investment for Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), was named deputy mayor
for housing and economic development by New York Mayor-elect
Bill de Blasio. </p>
<p>Glen, 47, who has run the department since 2002, arranged
government partnerships and financed more than $5 billion in
dozens of residential, mixed-use and commercial projects in the
U.S., according to Columbia University Business School, where
she''s an adjunct faculty member. The urban-investment group also
helped finance New York''s bike-sharing program, the largest in
the U.S. </p>
<p>Alicia is a pioneer in developing innovative financing
and investments that have improved the lives of thousands of New
Yorkers, Goldman Sachs Chief Executive Officer Lloyd Blankfein
said in an e-mail. </p>
<p>De Blasio campaigned for mayor promising to create 200,000
units of below-market affordable housing in the next 10
years. He also vowed to devote his policies to reducing wealth
inequality in a municipality where 46 percent of four-person
households had incomes of $46,000 or less -- about 150 percent
of the city''s 2011 poverty level. The richest 1 percent took
home 39 percent of all earnings in 2012, according to the Fiscal
Policy Institute, a New York-based research group. </p>
<h2>Fresh Ideas'' </h2>
<p>We need to invest in key emerging industries and
affordable housing so New Yorkers have a better shot at working
their way into the middle class, de Blasio, the first Democrat
elected mayor in two decades, said today in a news release.
Alicia has the record, fresh ideas and bold outlook to make
that vision a reality. </p>
<p>Glen replaces Robert Steel, 62, another Goldman Sachs
alumnus, who has been Mayor Michael Bloomberg''s deputy mayor for
economic development since June 2010. The mayor is founder and
majority owner of Bloomberg News parent Bloomberg LP. </p>
<p>We can do so much more to lift people up by investing in
our neighborhoods -- especially in the outer boroughs, Glen
said in a statement. We can raise the floor on workers'' wages,
develop and preserve more affordable housing and give families a
shot to make it here. </p>
<p>Before joining Goldman Sachs, Glen was New York''s assistant
commissioner for finance in the Housing, Preservation and
Development Department from 1998 to 2002, responsible for the
rehabilitation and construction of thousands of units of market-rate, moderate- and low-income housing, according to the
release. </p>
<p>A graduate of Amherst College in Massachusetts and Columbia
Law School, Glen served as an attorney with Brooklyn Legal
Services from 1993 to 1996. She lives on Manhattan''s Upper
West Side. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David Mildenberg" date="Dec 23, 2013 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-23/ibm-exxon-decry-texas-retreat-on-math-standards.html"><headline>IBM, Exxon Decry Texas Retreat on Math Standards</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>When Texas in 2006 became the first
state to require advanced algebra for high-school students,
Governor Rick Perry said the policy would better prepare young
people for success in higher education. </p>
<p>The strategy worked: by 2011, local students who took
advanced algebra had higher average test scores, and fewer
graduates needed to enroll in remedial math classes in college.
Seventeen other states followed suit, and now about 75 percent
of U.S. high school students completed Algebra II in 2012, up
from less than half in 1986, said Jennifer Dounay Zinth, a
policy analyst at the Education Commission of the States, a
Denver-based research group. </p>
<p>Now Texas is rolling back the requirement for Algebra II
under pressure from lawmakers, some educators and business trade
associations. They say advanced math skills aren''t needed for
many jobs, including those in the booming drilling industry. The
move is opposed by a coalition of corporate interests including
IBM Corp. (IBM), Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) and the Texas Association of
Business. </p>
<p>What Texas is doing is absolutely counter the trend,
said Linda Gojak, president of the National Council of
Mathematics Teachers and director of a math and science center
at John Carroll University in University Heights, Ohio. Not
requiring Algebra II is a cop-out. </p>
<h2>Perry''s Reversal </h2>
<p>Supporters of the rollback say businesses need more high-school graduates with vocational skills to take entry-level jobs
in welding, cosmetology and other fields. The emphasis on
preparing students for four-year colleges prompts too many
teenagers to bypass jobs that don''t require a university diploma
or to drop out of school, said Michael Meroney, an Austin
lobbyist who represents the Jobs for Texas Coalition. </p>
<p>Twenty-two trade groups in the coalition, representing
hundreds of Texas businesses, lobbied the state legislature to
ease the math standard and cut back on end-of-course tests
required for graduation. Perry signed the bill in June. </p>
<p>The governor, who supported the tighter algebra requirement
seven years ago, said the changes struck an appropriate
balance between our needs for rigorous academic standards and
the student''s need for flexibility. </p>
<p>Students are now required to complete four years of math,
including Algebra II, though about 20 percent opt out of the
class to earn a diploma that isn''t accepted by four-year
colleges. Under the new rules, Texas will require three years of
mathematics, with students who sign up for Algebra II earning a
new distinguished diploma. </p>
<h2>Educational Gateway </h2>
<p>The Texas State Board of Education, an elected body that
oversees school policies, approved the changes in the graduation
requirements in November, with a final vote scheduled in
January, said Debbie Ratcliffe, a spokeswoman for the agency. </p>
<p>While the value of Algebra II is a decades-old debate, no
better alternative has emerged to help teenagers learn logical
thinking, said Richard Riley, who was U.S. Education Secretary
from 1992 to 2001. Among the states requiring the course for
graduation are Arkansas, Michigan and Tennessee. </p>
<p>I''ve always favored Algebra II as a gateway into higher
education and out of high school, said Riley, a former
governor who now practices law in Greenville, South Carolina. </p>
<p>The boom in hydraulic fracturing that has contributed to
increased oil and natural-gas production means that the industry
faces shortages of welders, truckers and other workers who don''t
need college degrees, said Meroney. </p>
<p>Algebra II isn''t necessarily a good indicator of success
in the future, Meroney said. How it became the panacea, I
don''t know. </p>
<h2>Falling Behind </h2>
<p>The Texas retreat on math standards comes at a time when
the U.S. appears to be falling behind on basic educational
metrics. Math literacy of U.S. students ranked 26th among 34
members of the Paris-based Organization for Economic Cooperation
and Development in 2012, comparable with Hungary, Italy,
Lithuania, Norway, Portugal, Russia, Spain and Sweden, and the
equivalent of at least two years of formal schooling behind top-ranked Shanghai, China. </p>
<p>Some major employers decry the decision to lower math
standards. </p>
<p>IBM, with more than 6,000 workers in Austin, says the state
should be strengthening math and science requirements to help
erase a shortage of technology workers, said Sandy Dochen, the
company''s corporate affairs manager in Texas. </p>
<h2>Getting Prepared </h2>
<p>A kid from Muleshoe, Texas, who moves to Austin or
someone from the Rio Grande Valley who moves to Dallas needs to
be prepared for the world of work, Dochen said. In our haste
to make life a little more bearable and to emphasize good
teaching, let''s not get too soft on our competitiveness. </p>
<p>Math scores of Texas students on the ACT college entrance
exam improved over the past year, while the national average
declined, according to an August 2013 report by the national
testing service. Composite ACT scores were at an all-time high
for blacks, whites and Hispanics, according to the Texas Higher
Education Coordinating Board, a state agency in Austin. </p>
<p>The report also said that 48 percent of Texas students were
deemed ready for college algebra, compared with 44 percent
nationally. The results came even as Texas ranked 49th among
U.S. states in 2012-2013 on per-pupil spending for public
schools, according to the National Education Association''s
annual study on school spending released last December. </p>
<h2>Minimal Route </h2>
<p>What''s happening in Texas is an anomaly, there''s no
question about it, said Bill Hammond, president of the Texas
Association of Business, based in Austin. Too many kids will
figure out how to take the minimal program, or be pushed into
the program by administrators, and they will be prepared for
minimum-wage jobs. </p>
<p>Florida in April joined Texas in dumping the Algebra II
requirement as it created separate diplomas for students seeking
technical training and those who intend to go to college.
Lawmakers had voted in 2010 to require Algebra II for all
students. </p>
<p>Texas has been so good about ratcheting up its standards
and now the state has backed off, said Susan Hull, director of
mathematics and national initiatives at the University of
Texas''s Dana Center, a research group. Our fear is that other
states will back off, following Texas''s lead. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bloomberg News" date="Dec 27, 2013  1:07 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-27/microsoft-s-nokia-deal-said-to-face-china-limits-on-patent-fees.html"><headline>Microsoft''s Nokia Deal Said to Face China Limits on Patent Fees</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chinese mobile phone makers asked
regulators to make sure Microsoft Corp. (MSFT)''s 5.44 billion euro
($7.5 billion) bid to take over Nokia Oyj (NOK1V)''s handset business
doesn''t result in higher patent fees on wireless technology,
said two government officials with knowledge of the matter. </p>
<p>Huawei Technologies Co. and ZTE Corp. (000063) asked China''s
Ministry of Commerce to set conditions on the deal making sure
Microsoft doesn''t raise patent licensing fees afterward, said
the people, who asked not to be identified because they weren''t
authorized to speak publicly about the matter. The ministry is
conducting an anti-monopoly review of the deal. </p>
<p>Microsoft and Nokia announced the planned transaction in
September as the two seek to join forces in the smart-phone
market where both have failed to gain traction amid the
dominance of Apple Inc.''s iPhone, and devices running Google
Inc.''s Android platform. Microsoft won European Union approval
for the bid on Dec. 4, while regulators said they would monitor
Nokia''s licensing practices. </p>
<p>David Dai, a spokesman for Shenzhen-based ZTE, declined to
comment. Huang Man, a Shenzhen-based spokeswoman for Huawei, and
Joanna Li, a Beijing-based spokeswoman for Microsoft, said they
didn''t immediately have information available on the matter.
Calls to the commerce ministry''s press office weren''t
immediately answered. </p>




Photographer: Nelson Ching/Bloomberg

<p>
Stephen Elop, chief executive officer of Nokia Oyj, speaks during the launch of the company''s Lumia Windows smartphones in Beijing, China. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Zeke Faux" date="Dec 30, 2013  1:18 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-30/goldman-shares-worth-239-in-utopian-scenario-bernstein-says.html"><headline>Goldman Shares Worth $239 in Utopian Scenario,'' Bernstein Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), the fifth-biggest U.S. bank by assets, could rise to $239 a share were all
its businesses to peak at once, said Brad Hintz, an analyst at
Sanford C. Bernstein  Co. </p>
<p>Hintz is maintaining an outperform rating on shares of the
New York-based bank, with a price target of $190, he said today
in a report. His valuation for Goldman Sachs would reach the
$239 peak in a utopian scenario where revenue from stock
underwriting matched 2000, trading equaled 2007 and the firm cut
the percentage of compensation it paid to bankers, he said. </p>
<p>Achieving this zenith in the near term is unlikely and
would require a nirvana-like environment, Hintz wrote in the
report. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Lloyd Blankfein said last month at
an investor conference that he''s been working to improve Goldman
Sachs''s return on equity, a measure of how well it invests
profits. The firm, which earned an ROE of about 10 percent so
far this year, is unlikely to surpass 15 percent, given new
regulations, according to Hintz. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs has climbed 38 percent this year to $175.70
at 11:58 a.m. in New York. It''s too early to sell the stock
because revenue for the investment-banking industry will
probably increase next year, Hintz said. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs, which before the financial crisis targeted a
long-term ROE of 20 percent, has declined to set a goal since
then, saying it wanted to see the effects of new rules. Recent
international regulations have required banks to hold more
equity capital, pushing down ROE. </p>
<p>Tiffany Galvin, a bank spokeswoman, declined to comment on
Hintz''s report. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Mary Childs" date="Dec 30, 2013 11:27 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-30/goldman-sachs-leveraged-loan-head-trader-meeker-departs-firm.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Leveraged Loan Head Trader Meeker Departs Firm</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Sean Meeker, the head of loan and
loan credit-default swap trading at Goldman Sachs Group Inc.,
has left the firm. </p>
<p>Tiffany Galvin, a spokeswoman for the New York-based bank,
confirmed the departure in an e-mail. Meeker, who couldn''t be
reached for comment, joined Goldman Sachs in 2003 and was named
a managing director in 2010. </p>
<p>Jeff Bahl, the head of U.S. high-yield corporate bond
trading, also left Goldman Sachs earlier this month, the bank
confirmed at the time. </p>
<p>Leveraged loans and high-yield, high-risk bonds are rated
below Baa3 by Moody''s Investors Service and lower than BBB- at
Standard  Poor''s. Credit swaps pay the buyer face value if a
borrower fails to meet its obligations, less the value of the
defaulted debt. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Barinka" date="Dec 31, 2013  4:12 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-12-31/ibm-s-revenue-slump-turns-stock-into-dow-s-lone-loser-of-2013.html"><headline>IBM''s Sales Slump Turns Stock Into Dow''s Lone Loser of 2013</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines Corp. (IBM), the world''s largest provider of computing services, hasn''t convinced investors that it can pull out of a sales slump, sending the stock to its first annual decline since the financial crisis in 2008. </p> <p>Even as the company boosted its dividend and added about $20 billion to its buyback plan, the stock became the only loser in the Dow Jones Industrial Average (INDU) this year. The shares dropped 2.1 percent this year, compared with a 26 percent gain for the index. </p> <p>Revenue has fallen for six straight quarters, dragged down by sluggish demand for computer hardware. That''s forced Chief Executive Officer Ginni Rometty to rely on job cuts, tax gains and asset sales to keep increasing earnings per share. Technology investors would prefer a company that''s growing, said Todd Lowenstein, a portfolio manager at HighMark Capital Management Inc. </p> <p>We don''t think investors are going to be paying up for financially engineered EPS, said Lowenstein, who helps oversee $17 billion in assets. He no longer holds IBM shares. In tech, most people want to see top-line growth, and IBM is just not part of that trend. IBM is part of the cluster of old tech companies considered dinosaurs of yesteryear. </p> <p>The technology giant, based in Armonk, New York, is coping with an industrywide transition into the cloud era, where information is stored online instead of onsite. While IBM is getting an increasing amount of revenue from cloud services, the shift has spawned a new crop of competitors and eroded demand for traditional hardware and services. </p> <h2>On Target </h2> <p>Still, the company remains on target to reach $20 in adjusted earnings per share in 2015, up from $15.25 last year. Cost reductions and a shift into more profitable businesses have helped maintain the growth. </p> <p>Michael Fay, an IBM spokesman, declined to comment on the stock trading. </p> <p>The company embarked on a restructuring program this year, cutting jobs globally. More than 3,300 workers were dismissed in the U.S. and Canada alone, according to Alliance@IBM, an employee group. Some U.S. contract workers also were ordered to lessen their hours, according to a memo obtained by Bloomberg. </p> <p>In the third quarter, a more favorable tax rate contributed 30 cents a share to earnings, said David Grossman, an analyst with Stifel Nicolaus  Co., in a note at the time. That helped the company boost earnings to $3.99 a share, excluding some items -- 3 cents more than the average of estimates compiled by Bloomberg. </p> <h2>Increasingly Concerned </h2> <p>Even as earnings per share grew, the stock continued to fall, signaling that investors were increasingly concerned that IBM''s strategy was failing to produce growth, said Kulbinder Garcha, an analyst at Credit Suisse Group AG. </p> <p>It''s now coming to a point where they are almost doing everything they can to get to that earnings number, Garcha said. He downgraded IBM''s stock to the equivalent of a sell rating this year. They need to start thinking about some serious reinvestments and repositioning the company. </p> <p>Half of the analysts who covered IBM recommended buying it at the beginning of this year, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. That has fallen to less than a third today. </p> <p>Rometty has identified the nascent cloud industry as one of IBM''s biggest growth opportunities. In her biggest acquisition since taking over as CEO at the beginning of 2012, IBM bought cloud-computing storage company SoftLayer Technologies Inc. this year -- paying about $2 billion. </p> <h2>Cloud Opportunity </h2> <p>IBM reported more than $1 billion in sales from cloud services last quarter, the first time it has disclosed revenue from that segment. That wasn''t enough to keep total sales from falling for a sixth straight quarter, sending the stock sliding in October to a two-year low. IBM responded with another share buyback increase, adding $15 billion to the program. </p> <p>Competitors, meanwhile, have been building their own cloud offerings. Oracle Corp. has spent about $50 billion to acquire roughly 100 companies over the past decade, helping it adjust to the changing industry. Amazon.com Inc. (AMZN), which Gartner Inc. sees as the cloud leader, defeated IBM for a $600 million government cloud-computing contract this year. </p> <p>Oracle shares have gained 15 percent this year, while Amazon''s stock has surged 59 percent. </p> <h2>Losing Weight </h2> <p>IBM was ousted from the top spot in the price-weighted Dow in September, when the index underwent its biggest reshuffling in almost a decade. The benchmark added Goldman Sachs Group Inc., Nike Inc. and Visa Inc. -- in part to reduce IBM''s influence, according to David Blitzer, chairman of the SP Dow Jones index committee. The move means the Dow will be less susceptible to share price swings in IBM. </p> <p>The Dow''s changes had little effect on IBM shares, which had already begun their 2013 decline before the rebalancing, having fallen 2.6 percent at the time. </p> <p>The company''s shares rose less than 1 percent to $187.57 today at the close in New York. </p> <p>IBM still counts some big supporters in its corner, including billionaire Warren Buffett, whose investment company Berkshire Hathaway Inc. was IBM''s biggest shareholder as of September. The company''s price-to-earnings ratio hit a four-year low of 11 earlier this month and is now at 12, a discount to the Dow''s 16. The Standard  Poor''s 500 Information Technology Index, an industry benchmark, trades even higher at about 18. </p> <p>They will have record per-share earnings this year, Buffett said in an interview on the Charlie Rose show on PBS in October. That can be disappointing if you expected more. But it is not a bad record, believe me. </p> <p>IBM may also gain ground in the cloud-computing business, which is still in its early stages, said Joe Foresi, an analyst at Janney Montgomery Scott LLC who has a neutral rating on the shares. The challenge is to keep up with the changing technology industry while maintaining the earnings trajectory investors have come to expect, he said. </p> <p>IBM has to show that they can grow, he said. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Stephen Bierman" date="Jan 02, 2014  7:51 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-01-02/exxon-s-russia-ambitions-show-drilling-trumps-obama-putin-spats.html"><headline>Exxon Russia Ambitions Show Oil Trumps Obama-Putin Spats</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>As Barack Obama and Vladimir Putin
argue over human rights in Russia and the fate of fugitive U.S.
intelligence analyst Edward Snowden, the countries'' biggest oil
companies are preparing to drill for giant discoveries together
in the Arctic Ocean. </p>
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) and OAO Rosneft (ROSN) are set to start their
first Arctic well this year, targeting a deposit that may hold
more oil than Norway''s North Sea. It will kick off a series of
landmark projects and cement an alliance begun in 2011. They
also plan to frack shale fields in Siberia, sink a deep-water
well in the Black Sea and build a natural-gas export terminal in
Russia''s Far East. </p>
<p>We have a unique partnership, Glenn Waller, Exxon''s
Russian chief, said in an interview in Moscow. They have the
world''s biggest reserves and we have the largest market
capitalization. </p>
<p>The deepening alliance shows the two governments'' fractious
relationship is no bar to America''s most valuable energy company
investing billions in Russia. For Rosneft Chief Executive
Officer Igor Sechin, the Irving, Texas-based company brings
financial heft and the expertise needed to drill offshore in
some of the world''s harshest conditions for rigs. </p>
<p>There''s a whole stack of reasons why it''s good that
Rosneft is working with Exxon, said Richard Sakwa, an
associate fellow at Chatham House in London, who writes on
Russia''s oil industry. There''s technology and management.
Between Sechin and Exxon, there''s a degree of trust being built
up that can be nothing but to the good to both and to Russia. </p>




Photographer: Lucian Kim/Bloomberg

<p>
After swallowing smaller rival TNK-BP earlier this year, Moscow-based Rosneft now produces 5 percent of the world''s oil, with more than 30 billion barrels of proven reserves. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dakin Campbell and Ambereen Choudhury" date="Jan 03, 2014  5:51 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-01-03/goldman-sachs-raised-2012-pay-for-top-u-k-bankers-as-rivals-cut.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Raised 2012 Pay for Top U.K. Bankers Amid Cuts</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The average pay for Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)''s top U.K. bankers rose 77 percent in 2012 even as it declined at U.S.-based peers amid calls from governments and the public to reduce executive compensation. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs paid an average of $4.67 million in 2012 to U.K. employees deemed by regulators as risk-takers, as well as their managers, up from $2.64 million in 2011, according to figures disclosed by the firm. For similar staff at Citigroup Inc. (C), average pay climbed 9 percent to $2.38 million. At Bank of America Corp. (BAC) it fell 2 percent to $2.36 million, and at JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) it slid 3 percent to $3.4 million, totals disclosed separately show. </p> <p>The largest U.S. banks reported their figures for 2012 as recently as this week under European disclosure rules that are part of a regulatory push to alter pay practices blamed for contributing to the 2008 financial crisis. The filings show a divergence between Goldman Sachs, which shrank headcount while boosting revenue 19 percent in 2012, and competitors such as JPMorgan, which lost more than $6.2 billion that year on botched derivatives bets by London traders. Figures for 2013 won''t be released until later this year. </p>




Photographer: Jason Alden/Bloomberg

<p>
Goldman Sachs paid an average of $4.67 million in 2012 to U.K. employees deemed by regulators as risk-takers, as well as their managers, up from $2.64 million in 2011, according to figures disclosed by the firm. For similar staff at Citigroup Inc., average pay climbed 32 percent to $4.11 million. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Carla Main" date="Jan 03, 2014  9:14 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-01-03/jpmorgan-latvia-ex-sac-manager-cathay-united-compliance-1-.html"><headline>JPMorgan-Latvia, Ex-SAC Manager, Cathay United: Compliance</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), which has been
told by U.S. regulators to bolster money-laundering safeguards,
has stopped clearing dollar transfers for Latvian lenders,
according to the Baltic nation''s banking association. </p>
<p>Latvia, a hub for ex-Soviet cash, adopted the euro Jan. 1,
focusing the spotlight on $8 billion of non-resident deposits
and claims by Global Witness, a London-based anti-corruption
campaign group, that regulation and client vetting aren''t
adequate. U.S. regulators have reprimanded lenders including
JPMorgan for lax controls over transfers that could allow
terrorists and drug rings to move money around the world. </p>
<p>The exit of the U.S.''s largest bank leaves Deutsche Bank AG
and Commerzbank AG as the only two Western lenders Latvian banks
can use for international dollar transfers. Some local banks
rely on lenders in Russia or Ukraine who have correspondent
accounts with a U.S. partner to clear dollars. </p>
<p>The U.S. Office of the Comptroller of the Currency issued a
consent order in January 2013 after finding JPMorgan has an
inadequate system of internal controls and independent testing
for anti-money-laundering compliance. The bank failed to
identify significant volumes of suspicious activity and to
file reports alerting regulators, according to the order. </p>
<p>JPMorgan didn''t admit or deny wrongdoing in consenting to
the regulatory orders at the time, saying in a statement that
the bank has been  working hard to fully remediate the issues
identified in the consent order. </p>
<p>Officials including Latvian central bank Governor Ilmars
Rimsevics say lenders are being closely monitored. While
regulators fined a local bank in June the maximum 100,000 lati
($195,000) for transferring money in Russia''s biggest known tax
fraud, they didn''t name the bank in question. </p>
<p>As well as imposing more restrictions on demand deposits
and reconsidering tax incentives that bolster non-resident
deposits, the government may also strengthen law-enforcement
efforts to combat money laundering, according to a June letter
published on the Latvian Finance Ministry''s website. </p>
<p>Latvia''s 27 banks had assets of about 20 billion lati in
the third quarter, banking association data show. </p>
<h2>Compliance Policy </h2>
<h2>Finra to Focus on Recidivist Brokers, Cybersecurity in 2014 </h2>
<p>The Financial Industry Regulatory Authority, Wall Street''s
self-funded overseer, released its regulatory and examination
priorities. </p>
<p>The group plans to create an enforcement team to
investigate claims against brokers with a history of customer
complaints. </p>
<p>Finra''s examinations of the largest brokers this year will
include liquidity stress tests, it said. </p>
<p>Priorities for the coming year include broker disclosures
about interest-rate sensitive securities, fees for rolling over
401(k) accounts to IRAs, due diligence conducted by brokers in
assuring investors meet net-income and wealth thresholds for
investing in privately offered securities, the IPO market, money
laundering, crowd funding portals, muni advisers and the
advertising of private placements. </p>
<h2>Germany to Tighten Tax Evasion Declaration, Sueddeutsche Says </h2>
<p>Germany wants to tighten conditions for individuals who
declare tax evasion to avoid prosecution, Sueddeutsche Zeitung
reported, citing Carsten Kuehl, a government official in the
state of Rhineland-Palatinate. </p>
<p>Individuals will have to declare all tax evaded over the
past 10 years rather than the current five years, the newspaper
reported, citing Kuehl''s statement in an interview. </p>
<p>The number of individuals who declared tax evasion tripled
to almost 25,000 last year, Sueddeutsche reported, citing its
own survey of German states. </p>
<h2>Compliance Action </h2>
<h2>Cathay United Bank Gets FSC Approval for Shanghai FTZ Sub-Branch </h2>
<p>Cathay United Bank obtained approval from Taiwan''s
Financial Supervisory Commission for a sub-branch in the
Shanghai free trade zone, the regulator said in a statement on
its website. </p>
<p>The lender is the first local bank to receive approval from
the FSC to establish a presence in the China free-trade zone,
the regulator said in the statement. </p>
<p>The FSC cleared the bank to apply for a sub-branch with
Chinese regulators, according to the statement. </p>
<h2>Saudi Electricity to Offer Investment Sukuk Jan. 9 to Feb. 27 </h2>
<p>Saudi Electricity (SECO) Co., which generates and distributes
electricity throughout Saudi Arabia, will offer investment sukuk
from Jan. 9 to Feb. 27, according to a statement made to the
Saudi bourse. </p>
<p>The value of each unit of the investment sukuk, a form of
Shariah-compliant investing, is to 1m riyals, the company said
in the statement. </p>
<p>The tenor, size of sale, and profit distributions are to be
based on demand. The investment sukuk will be unsecured, the
company said in the statement. </p>
<p>Saudi Electricity has hired HSBC Saudi Arabia and Saudi
Fransi Capital to manage the sale. </p>
<h2>Courts </h2>
<h2>RBS Settles $1.2 Million Bonus Fight With Former Risk Chief </h2>
<p>Royal Bank of Scotland Group Plc settled lawsuits with Gary
Cottle, the former head of risk at its investment banking
division, over a 700,000-pound ($1.2 million) bonus. </p>
<p>RBS said Cottle didn''t deserve the final portion of the
2009 award because he turned down alternative jobs before
leaving the Edinburgh-based bank in 2011, according to its
London lawsuit that sought to block the payment. The terms of
the settlement weren''t disclosed by the court or either party. </p>
<p>Cottle argued that he fell out of favor with RBS after
raising concerns about a toxic debt deal and was never
offered a suitable replacement role. The former risk officer,
who is now head of global markets for Europe at Nomura Holdings
Inc., also sued RBS. Cottle declined to comment on the
settlement. </p>
<p>The parties have resolved their differences, said Sarah
Small, a spokeswoman for RBS. Neither party will make any
further public statement. </p>
<p>U.K. Chancellor of the Exchequer George Osborne said in
November the government would separate RBS''s toxic assets in an
internal bad bank as it seeks an exit for its 81 percent
stake. The lender has made five consecutive years of annual
losses. </p>
<p>The case is Royal Bank of Scotland Group Plc (RBS) v. Cottle,
12-1948, High Court of Justice, Queen''s Bench Division. </p>
<p>SAC''s Cohen Focus of Insider Trial as Martoma Rebuffs U.S. </p>
<p>Mathew Martoma may have the one thing prosecutors have been
unable to find in their probe of SAC Capital Advisors LP: a
direct link between founder Steven Cohen and insider trading.
Having refused to cooperate, Martoma now faces trial for what
the government claims was the biggest illegal trade in U.S.
history. </p>
<p>Jury selection in the prosecution of the ex-SAC portfolio
manager is set for Jan. 6, barring a last-minute plea deal. The
trial is expected to take three weeks. He is accused of
benefitting the hedge fund by $276 million in trades of Wyeth
and Elan Corp., using secret tips from a doctor supervising
trials of an Alzheimer''s drug. The U.S. said SAC reversed a
bullish stance on the drugmakers, liquidating a $700 million
position and selling the stocks short a few days after a 20-minute phone call between Martoma and Cohen in July 2008. </p>
<p>Pressure on Martoma, 39, to cooperate with the probe
included questioning by FBI agents at his home and an indictment
unsealed in 2012 on the Friday before Christmas. A steady
drumbeat of convictions of insider traders in the probe,
including SAC portfolio manager Michael Steinberg last month,
may have further ratcheted up the pressure ahead of the trial
next week in Manhattan federal court. </p>
<p>Cohen, who hasn''t been charged, has said he did nothing
wrong. Jonathan Gasthalter, a spokesman for SAC at Sard
Verbinnen  Co., declined to comment on the Martoma trial. </p>
<p>Mathew continues to fight the charges and is preparing
for trial, his lawyer, Richard Strassberg, said in an e-mail. </p>
<p>In November, SAC agreed to plead guilty to securities fraud
and end its investment advisory business as part of a record
$1.8 billion settlement of the government''s investigation of
insider trading at the firm. The agreement must be approved by a
judge before it can take effect. </p>
<p>If convicted, Martoma, who has pleaded not guilty, faces as
long as 20 years in prison on each of two securities-fraud
counts and five years for a single conspiracy charge. </p>
<p>The case is U.S. v. Steinberg, 12-cr-00121, U.S. District
Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). </p>
<h2>Interviews/Commentary </h2>
<p>Israel''s Sheshinski Sees No Taboo in Changing Resources Taxation </p>
<p>Israel has the right to revise its tax policies, said the
economist leading a review of the country''s natural resources
royalties and tax structure, parrying allegations that a
changing regulatory environment would drive away investment. </p>
<p>The government-appointed panel led by economics professor
emeritus Eytan Sheshinski of The Hebrew University of Jerusalem
is due to hold a public hearing on the matter next week. Its
recommendations will reverberate at Israel Chemicals Ltd. (ICL), which
harvests Dead Sea minerals to make fertilizers, and whose chief
executive, Stefan Borgas, has warned that frequent and
unplanned regulation is poison for the company. </p>
<p>Governments have the right to modify their tax policies,
because while stability and credibility are a worthy cause,
they must be weighed against other objectives, such as ensuring
the public a fair share of the profits, Sheshinski said.
Changing the status quo should not be taboo. </p>
<p>At the same time, firms will have to receive a fair
return on their investment to provide incentives for them to
continue operation in the country, he said. The panel will
consider market conditions and sector risks when making its
recommendations, Sheshinski said. Proposals are due in June. </p>
<p>Finance Minister Yair Lapid appointed the review committee
last June with a mandate to ensure the public receives its due
from natural resources. Recommendations by another Sheshinski-led committee three years ago were the foundation for the
government''s decision to more than double its share of gas and
oil profits. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Carla Main" date="Jan 03, 2014 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-01-03/jpmorgan-latvia-ex-sac-manager-trial-cathay-united-compliance.html"><headline>JPMorgan-Latvia, Ex-SAC Manager Trial, Cathay United: Compliance</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), which has been
told by U.S. regulators to bolster money-laundering safeguards,
has stopped clearing dollar transfers for Latvian lenders,
according to the Baltic nation''s banking association. </p>
<p>Latvia, a hub for ex-Soviet cash, adopted the euro Jan. 1,
focusing the spotlight on $8 billion of non-resident deposits
and claims by Global Witness, a London-based anti-corruption
campaign group, that regulation and client vetting aren''t
adequate. U.S. regulators have reprimanded lenders including
JPMorgan for lax controls over transfers that could allow
terrorists and drug rings to move money around the world. </p>
<p>The exit of the U.S.''s largest bank leaves Deutsche Bank AG
and Commerzbank AG as the only two Western lenders Latvian banks
can use for international dollar transfers. Some local banks
rely on lenders in Russia or Ukraine who have correspondent
accounts with a U.S. partner to clear dollars. Deutsche Bank and
Commerzbank declined to comment on the potential impact of
JPMorgan''s absence on their business.            Latvian banks
have a pretty wide network of currency clearing partners, the
bank association said in a statement yesterday. </p>
<p>The U.S. Office of the Comptroller of the Currency issued a
consent order in January 2013 after finding JPMorgan has an
inadequate system of internal controls and independent testing
for anti-money-laundering compliance. The bank failed to
identify significant volumes of suspicious activity and to
file reports alerting regulators, according to the order. </p>
<p>JPMorgan didn''t admit or deny wrongdoing in consenting to
the regulatory orders at the time, saying in a statement that
the bank has been working hard to fully remediate the issues
identified in the consent order. </p>
<p>Officials including Latvian central bank Governor Ilmars
Rimsevics say lenders are being closely monitored. While
regulators fined a local bank in June the maximum 100,000 lati
($195,000) for transferring money in Russia''s biggest known tax
fraud, they didn''t name the bank in question. </p>
<p>As well as imposing more restrictions on demand deposits
and reconsidering tax incentives that bolster non-resident
deposits, the government may also strengthen law-enforcement
efforts to combat money laundering, according to a June letter
published on the Latvian Finance Ministry''s website. </p>
<p>Latvia''s 27 banks had assets of about 20 billion lati in
the third quarter, banking association data show. </p>
<h2>Compliance Policy </h2>
<h2>Germany to Tighten Tax Evasion Declaration Rules, Paper Says </h2>
<p>Germany wants to tighten conditions for individuals who
self-report tax evasion to avoid prosecution, Sueddeutsche
Zeitung reported, citing Carsten Kuehl, a government official in
the state of Rhineland-Palatinate. </p>
<p>Individuals will have to declare all tax evaded over past
the 10 years rather than the current five years, the newspaper
reported, citing Kuehl''s statement in an interview. </p>
<p>The number of individuals who informed authorities of their
tax evasion tripled to almost 25,000 last year, Sueddeutsche
reported, citing its own survey of German states. </p>
<h2>Compliance Action </h2>
<h2>Cathay United Bank Gets FSC Approval for Shanghai FTZ Sub-branch </h2>
<p>Cathay United Bank obtained approval from Taiwan''s
Financial Supervisory Commission for a sub-branch in the
Shanghai free trade zone, the regulator said in a statement on
its website. </p>
<p>The lender is the first local bank to receive approval from
the FSC to establish a presence in the China free-trade zone,
the regulator said in the statement. </p>
<p>The FSC cleared the bank to apply for a sub-branch with
Chinese regulators, according to the statement. </p>
<h2>Saudi Electricity to Offer Investment Sukuk Jan. 9 to Feb. 27 </h2>
<p>Saudi Electricity (SECO) Co., which generates and distributes
electricity throughout Saudi Arabia, will offer investment sukuk
from Jan. 9 to Feb. 27, according to a statement made to the
Saudi bourse. </p>
<p>The value of each unit of the investment sukuk, a form of
Shariah-compliant investing, is to be 1 million riyals, the
company said in the statement. </p>
<p>The tenor, size of sale, and profit distributions are to be
based on demand. The investment sukuk will be unsecured, the
company said in the statement. </p>
<p>Saudi Electricity has hired HSBC Saudi Arabia and Saudi
Fransi Capital to manage the sale. </p>
<h2>Courts </h2>
<p>SAC''s Cohen Focus of Insider Trial as Martoma Rebuffs U.S. </p>
<p>Mathew Martoma may have the one thing prosecutors have been
unable to find in their probe of SAC Capital Advisors LP: a
direct link between founder Steven Cohen and insider trading.
Having refused to cooperate, Martoma now faces trial for what
the government claims was the biggest illegal trade in U.S.
history. </p>
<p>Jury selection in the prosecution of the ex-SAC portfolio
manager is set for Jan. 6, barring a last-minute plea deal. The
trial is expected to take three weeks. He is accused of
benefiting the hedge fund by $276 million in trades of Wyeth and
Elan Corp., using secret tips from a doctor supervising trials
of an Alzheimer''s drug. The U.S. said SAC reversed a bullish
stance on the drugmakers, liquidating a $700 million position
and selling the stocks short a few days after a 20-minute phone
call between Martoma and Cohen in July 2008. </p>
<p>Pressure on Martoma, 39, to cooperate with the probe
included questioning by FBI agents at his home and an indictment
unsealed in 2012 on the Friday before Christmas. A steady
drumbeat of convictions of insider traders in the probe,
including SAC portfolio manager Michael Steinberg last month,
may have further ratcheted up the pressure ahead of the trial
next week in Manhattan federal court. </p>
<p>Cohen, who hasn''t been charged, has said he did nothing
wrong. Jonathan Gasthalter, a spokesman for SAC at Sard
Verbinnen  Co., declined to comment on the Martoma trial. </p>
<p>Mathew continues to fight the charges and is preparing
for trial, his lawyer, Richard Strassberg, said in an e-mail. </p>
<p>In November, SAC agreed to plead guilty to securities fraud
and end its investment advisory business as part of a record
$1.8 billion settlement of the government''s investigation of
insider trading at the firm. The agreement must be approved by a
judge before it can take effect. </p>
<p>If convicted, Martoma, who has pleaded not guilty, faces as
long as 20 years in prison on each of two securities-fraud
counts and five years for a single conspiracy charge. </p>
<p>The case is U.S. v. Steinberg, 12-cr-00121, U.S. District
Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). </p>
<h2>Interviews/Commentary </h2>
<p>Israel''s Sheshinski Sees No Taboo in Changing Resources Taxation </p>
<p>Israel has the right to revise its tax policies, said the
economist leading a review of the country''s natural resources
royalties and tax structure, parrying allegations that a
changing regulatory environment would drive away investment. </p>
<p>The government-appointed panel led by economics professor
emeritus Eytan Sheshinski of The Hebrew University of Jerusalem
is due to hold a public hearing on the matter next week. Its
recommendations will reverberate at Israel Chemicals Ltd. (ICL), which
harvests Dead Sea minerals to make fertilizers, and whose chief
executive, Stefan Borgas, has warned that frequent and
unplanned regulation is poison for the company. </p>
<p>Governments have the right to modify their tax policies,
because while stability and credibility are a worthy cause,
they must be weighed against other objectives, such as ensuring
the public a fair share of the profits, Sheshinski said.
Changing the status quo should not be taboo. </p>
<p>At the same time, firms will have to receive a fair
return on their investment to provide incentives for them to
continue operation in the country, he said. The panel will
consider market conditions and sector risks when making its
recommendations, Sheshinski said. Proposals are due in June. </p>
<p>Finance Minister Yair Lapid appointed the review committee
last June with a mandate to ensure the public receives its due
from natural resources. Recommendations by another Sheshinski-led committee three years ago were the foundation for the
government''s decision to more than double its share of gas and
oil profits. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Brian Chappatta" date="Jan 03, 2014 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-01-03/morgan-stanley-to-barclays-see-second-yearly-muni-losses.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley to Barclays See Second Yearly Muni Losses</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>State and local bonds are set for
their first back-to-back annual losses in more than three
decades after the $3.7 trillion U.S. municipal market suffered
its worst year since 2008. </p>
<p>Muni yields will rise as the Federal Reserve begins curbing
its bond buying this month, say Michael Zezas, chief muni
strategist at Morgan Stanley and Tom Weyl, director of muni
research at Barclays Plc. (BARC) Zezas estimates munis will lose 1.7
percent to 4.1 percent this year, while Weyl predicts the bonds
will lose 1.45 percent. The last time munis suffered two
straight years of losses was 1980-1981, Barclays data show. </p>
<p>The forecasts contrast with 2011 and 2012, when munis
gained 11 percent and 6.8 percent, respectively, according to
Barclays data. A record wave of withdrawals from muni mutual
funds has shown no signs of letting up, with individuals pulling
$6.6 billion over the past four weeks, the most since September. </p>
<p>If rates rise to the level we expect them to over the
next couple of quarters, you''re still likely to take on negative
returns, said Zezas, who correctly predicted in 2012 that
state and local debt would decline last year. We wouldn''t add
just yet to municipal-bond allocations, he said by telephone
yesterday. </p>




Photographer: Jeff Kowalsky/Bloomberg

<p>
Munis trailed corporate bonds as Detroit filed the largest municipal bankruptcy and Puerto Rico''s credit rating fell to the brink of junk, stoking concerns that the commonwealth won''t be able to repay investors. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry></news>