<?xml version='1.0' encoding='us-ascii'?>
<news><entry author="By Alaric Nightingale and Tony Hopfinger" date="Mar 24, 2009 11:59 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-03-24/valdez-ghost-haunts-exxon-with-spill-prone-ships-update2-.html"><headline>Valdez Ghost Haunts Exxon With Spill-Prone Ships</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Alaskan fisherman J.R. Janneck&#8217;s
boat is 38 feet (12 meters). The SeaRiver Long Beach, the sister
ship of the Exxon Valdez, which caused the worst oil spill in
U.S. history, is 987 feet and carries 1.5 million barrels of
oil. There is another difference. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;My boat is double-hulled,&#8221; Janneck, 63, said as he
worked on his silver salmon fishing boat in Valdez Harbor last
month. Twenty years after the March 24, 1989, disaster, Janneck
still remembers the &#8220;tiger-stripe sheen&#8221; of oil in the water
and the absence of birds around him. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even after 79 percent of the world supertanker fleet has
been replaced by craft with two hulls, Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) remains
the biggest Western user of the older designs. It hired more of
the tankers last year than the rest of the 10 biggest companies
by market value combined, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exxon, the world&#8217;s largest oil company, has kept using
tankers with one hull even as 151 countries have decided two are
better than one for preventing oil spills and pledged to ban
single-hull vessels by 2015. The European Union called the
design &#8220;more accident-prone&#8221; in 2003, when it started a
prohibition that takes full effect next year. London-based BP
Plc (BP/) says it won&#8217;t hire them because of the risk of leaking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Policies Differ &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;U.S. refining rivals, including Sunoco Inc., Chevron Corp. (CVX),
ConocoPhillips (COP) and Koch Industries Inc., and Paris-based Total
SA (FP) didn&#8217;t hire one such vessel last year, the data show. Exxon&#8217;s
use of single-hull ships compared with its nine biggest
competitors is based on more than 12,500 ship-rental deals. The
data were provided by shipbrokers, including Simpson, Spence 
Young Ltd. in London, and shipping-information provider Lloyd&#8217;s
Register-Fairplay in Redhill, England. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Valdez dumped 11 million gallons of oil into Prince
William Sound, damaging at least 700 miles of coastline and
killing more than 36,000 birds, according to the U.S.
Environmental Protection Agency. It took three years and $3.86
billion to clean up the spill and compensate fishermen and other
business owners. The U.S. Supreme Court last year cut the
punitive damages against Exxon to $507.5 million from $2.5
billion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had the supertanker been fitted with a double hull, the
scale of any spill would have been reduced, said Apostolos
Papanikolaou, a ship-design professor at the National Technical
University of Athens. The accident was predominantly because of
navigational error, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Brand Damaged &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;I am very surprised they are still using these tankers
because they are still suffering brand damage from the Exxon
Valdez,&#8221; said Tracey Rembert, a senior corporate governance
analyst at the Service Employees International Union in
Washington, whose largest stockholding is 126,000 shares of
Exxon. &#8220;There are people who still don&#8217;t buy gas at Exxon, and
that was 20 years ago.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Double-hull tankers have an outer layer of steel, normally
about an inch thick and 6.5 feet from the inner one, that acts
as a buffer in an accident. When tankers with one shell are
ruptured, the only place for the oil to go is into the sea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It costs about 20 percent less to hire a single-hull ship.
Exxon&#8217;s estimated savings amounted to less than a cent a share
last year, according to Bloomberg calculations. The Irving,
Texas-based company made a profit of $45.2 billion, or $8.69 a
share, in 2008, the largest in U.S. corporate history. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Exxon&#8217;s Savings &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exxon saved an estimated $18 million last year using
single-hull vessels, based on the number of times it hired such
ships multiplied by 2008 rental rates from Drewry Shipping
Consultants Ltd. and average durations compiled by Bloomberg.
Hiring a double-hull replacement for SeaRiver Long Beach for a
year would have cost about $25 million using the same rates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hull design is only one of &#8220;hundreds of variables&#8221; Exxon
uses in monitoring safety, and cost isn&#8217;t one of them, said Rob Young, a company spokesman. He declined to comment on the
savings question because it would be an &#8220;incorrect
characterization&#8221; to say its motivation in hiring the vessels
was financial. He also declined to comment on whether double-hulls are intrinsically safer than singles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exxon had no oil spills in 2008 and &#8220;less than one
teaspoon per million barrels carried&#8221; in 2007, Young said by e-mail. The company&#8217;s shipping units &#8220;often exceed regulatory
standards to enhance the safety, security and reliability of
marine transportation,&#8221; he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exxon fell 68 cents, or 1 percent, to $69.84 as of 11:30
a.m. in New York, giving the company a market value of $346
billion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Government Action &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the aftermath of the Valdez disaster, the U.S.
government led a global push to outlaw single-hull vessels.
Later accidents involving the Erika off France in 1999, which
had been hired by Total, and the Prestige off the Spanish coast
in 2002, leased by Crown Resources AG of Switzerland, increased
pressure. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S., under the Oil Pollution Act of 1990, will allow
single-hull tankers to sail in its waters either to unload at
the Louisiana Offshore Oil Port or at dedicated unloading areas
out at sea until 2015. The International Maritime Organization,
the shipping division of the United Nations, will ban single-hull tankers starting next year. Member nations can avoid the
prohibition for five more years by outlining their intentions in
a letter to the IMO. Lee Adamson, a spokesman for the IMO, was
unable to say how many have sought such exemptions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;BP Experience &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In deciding to restrict single hulls, the U.S. Congress
considered design studies provided to the IMO that found spills
from double-hull tankers would be &#8220;zero in most accidents,&#8221;
said Robert Gauvin, Washington-based technical adviser at the
U.S. Coast Guard. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A 1992 report to Congress by the Coast Guard found that
double hulls are unequalled for avoiding spills and prevent them
in &#8220;all but the most severe incidents.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;We in the market don&#8217;t understand why Exxon continues to
do this,&#8221; said Per Mansson, a shipbroker at Nor Ocean Stockholm
AB, who&#8217;s been involved in the tanker industry for 30 years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On March 6, a tanker BP hired -- the double-hull SKS
Satilla -- struck an oil rig 65 miles from Galveston, Texas,
that was lost during Hurricane Ike. The incident, which caused
&#8220;multiple punctures&#8221; along a 60-meter (197-foot) by 12-meter
section, didn&#8217;t leak any oil, Coast Guard spokesman Tim Tilghman
said from Galveston. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SKS Satilla had on board about 1 million barrels, or 42
million gallons, of crude oil. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Because of the double hull, there&#8217;s no further
penetration, other than the outer skin,&#8221; Sverre Jacob Mehn, a
spokesman for the ship&#8217;s manager, Kristian Gerhard Jebsen
Skipsrederi AS, said in an interview from Bergen, Norway. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Single Hulls Decline &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proportion of single-hull supertankers has shrunk to 21
percent from 100 percent before Valdez, according to Lloyd&#8217;s
Register-Fairplay, as shipbuilders such as Hyundai Heavy
Industries (009540) in Ulsan, South Korea, the world&#8217;s largest, stopped
making them. A new double-hull supertanker costs about $126
million, while the last mono-hull carrier to change hands, built
in 1994, cost $14 million, according to Oslo-based shipbroker
Fearnleys AS. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exxon last year arranged to hire at least 32 single-hull
very large crude carriers -- or VLCCs -- tankers slightly bigger
than the Exxon Valdez, and one smaller vessel, the data show.
That amounted to 6.1 percent of its overall tanker bookings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking into account vessels Exxon owns and ships it has on
long-term rentals, its single-hull rentals are &#8220;substantially&#8221;
lower than 6 percent, said Young, the company spokesman. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By contrast, Royal Dutch Shell Plc (RDSA), Europe&#8217;s biggest oil
company, moved 1.8 percent of cargoes on single-hull tankers
last year, the data show. Shell was the world&#8217;s largest hirer of
oil tankers in 2008, booking them on at least 855 occasions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Maintenance Matters &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of Shell&#8217;s long-term rental tankers have double hulls,
spokeswoman Catherine Aitken said by e-mail from The Hague.
Sometimes it&#8217;s forced to use single-hull carriers because there
aren&#8217;t enough with two available, she said, adding hull design
isn&#8217;t a &#8220;panacea&#8221; for safety. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maintenance, regular inspections and effective operational
management are also important, said Papanikolaou, the Athens
professor of ship design who has led studies on the relative
safety of both hull configurations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The combined single-hull rentals by Exxon and Shell are
dwarfed by carriers in Asia, including Indian Oil Corp. (IOCL) and Thai
Oil Pcl. (TOP) IOC, based in New Delhi, hired single-hull tankers 130
times in 2008 out of 188 recorded rentals, the data show.
Bangkok-based Thai Oil, the nation&#8217;s largest refiner, booked
them 55 times out of 60, or 92 percent of the time, commercial
manager Pongpun Amornvivat said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2000 Leak &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both companies said they use single-hull ships because of
the savings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;As long as they can be used, we will take advantage of
lower rentals,&#8221; said Basavaraj Ningappa Bankapur, director of
refineries at IOC, India&#8217;s biggest refiner. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exxon&#8217;s single-hull SeaRiver Long Beach regularly calls on
San Francisco and Los Angeles as well as Valdez. The 21-year-old
carrier had a leak from a hairline fracture in 2000 and had to
return to Valdez to unload its cargo. About 10 gallons of crude
spilled into the sea, all of which was cleaned up, said Raymond
Botto, a spokesman for SeaRiver Maritime, an Exxon subsidiary. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like Janneck, the fisherman in Valdez, Leroy Cabana from
Homer 200 miles away remains angry about Exxon two decades
later. That the Exxon Valdez&#8217;s single-hull sister ship continues
to call on Alaska fits a pattern, said Cabana, 53, who was part
of the army of workers hired to clean up the spill. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For him, the accident wasn&#8217;t just caused by a single-hull
tanker. &#8220;It was caused by a reckless company,&#8221; he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporters on this story:
Alaric Nightingale in London at 
Anightingal1@bloomberg.net;
Tony Hopfinger in Anchorage at thopfinger@gci.net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Stuart Wallace at 
swallace6@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry></news>