<?xml version='1.0' encoding='us-ascii'?>
<news><entry author="By David Reilly" date="Feb 02, 2010  9:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-02-02/goldman-sachs-wimps-out-in-buck-breaking-brawl-david-reilly.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Wimps Out in Buck-Breaking Brawl: David Reilly</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the financial crisis,
Goldman Sachs Group Inc. extolled the use of market prices to
value holdings, saying this instills needed discipline. The
firm&#8217;s hard-line stance turned to mush, though, when it came
time to end a market myth that fueled 2008&#8217;s meltdown. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman, along with the mutual-fund industry, argues that
it is fine for money-market funds to use historical values,
rather than market prices, to value holdings. This helps money-
market funds maintain a stable price of $1 a share. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem: the $1 share price gives investors the false
impression that money-market funds are like bank accounts and so
can&#8217;t lose money. That myth was shattered in 2008, and the
resulting panic worsened the credit crunch, forcing the
government to backstop these funds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the face of opposition from the fund industry and from
firms such as Goldman, the Securities and Exchange Commission so
far has failed to force the $3.3 trillion money-market industry
to face reality by requiring the funds to show that their shares
rise and fall in value, even if by miniscule amounts. This
inaction creates the possibility of future market runs and the
need for more government bailouts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a meeting last week, the SEC endorsed beefed-up
disclosures for money-market funds, along with other technical
changes such as requiring funds to boost cash holdings. It
stopped short, though, of even proposing that funds be required
to post values that wouldn&#8217;t always neatly show up as $1 a
share. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More Action Needed &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SEC Chairman Mary Schapiro did say the agency would
continue to evaluate money-market fund reforms, including one to
require floating values. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More forceful action is needed, though, especially given
that there have been calls for more than a year, most notably
from a group run by former Federal Reserve Chairman Paul Volcker, to require that money-market funds either use floating
values -- and so prepare investors for the idea that these
instruments can lose money -- or be regulated as if they are
bank products. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recall that the failure of Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc.
led to losses that caused the $62.5 billion Reserve Primary
Fund, the oldest U.S. money-market fund, to &#8220;break the buck.&#8221;
This meant losses fell outside a preset range, so the value of
its shares suddenly fell below the fixed $1 price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Panicky Investors &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This led to panic as investors realized money-market funds
weren&#8217;t as safe as bank accounts and weren&#8217;t insured by the
Federal Deposit Insurance Corp. The federal government had to
step in and insure money-market investments until September
2009. Fresh memories of the money-market panic even played a
role in the decision to bail out American International Group
Inc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Appearing before Congress last week, Thomas Baxter, general
counsel of the Federal Reserve Bank of New York, submitted
testimony saying that money-market funds couldn&#8217;t have weathered
an AIG failure. While those funds held $5 billion of commercial
paper issued by Lehman, they held about $20 billion in notes
issued by AIG, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Losses to these funds would have had potentially
devastating effects on confidence and would have accelerated the
run on financial institutions of all kinds,&#8221; according to
Baxter&#8217;s testimony. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Requiring money-market fund values to float would help head
off such problems. Investors would learn that these investments
are just like other mutual funds, and so can lose money. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8216;Wake-Up Call&#8217; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Our experience with the Reserve Fund and other funds is a
wake-up call that stable net asset value money funds are
susceptible to runs, and we must more fundamentally rethink how
they are regulated,&#8221; SEC Commissioner Kathleen Casey said at
last week&#8217;s meeting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Casey added that if the funds aren&#8217;t to face bank-like
regulation, they need to move to floating values. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The industry&#8217;s case against floating values is that
investors would pull cash out of money-market funds because they
want investments with a stable value. That, the argument goes,
would deprive American companies of a vital source of funding,
since money-market funds are big buyers of short-term commercial
paper issued by companies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is a well-worn ploy from the financial-services
industry to counter any change that cuts into business. Banks
used this tactic effectively in 2003 and 2004, for instance, to
pressure the Financial Accounting Standards Board to water down
rules that would have limited banks&#8217; ability to use off-balance-
sheet vehicles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman&#8217;s Case &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result was out-of-control securitization and under-
capitalized banks, both of which played huge roles in crashing
the financial system. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman made the exact same &#8220;We can&#8217;t crimp companies&#8217;
funding&#8221; argument in a September comment letter to the SEC on
money-market reforms. Most egregious is that Goldman&#8217;s letter
argues in favor of using historical prices for money-market fund
values, even though the firm has championed the use of market
values for investments and financial holdings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an op-ed article last autumn, Goldman Chief Executive
Officer Lloyd Blankfein wrote, &#8220;Markets, and ultimately
investors, are better served with information that more closely
reflects the judgment of the market rather than the historical
price.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now Blankfein&#8217;s boys are trying to play Jack Nicholson in
&#8220;A Few Good Men,&#8221; screaming at the SEC and investors: &#8220;You
can&#8217;t handle the truth!&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guess what? It&#8217;s Goldman and money-market funds who can&#8217;t
handle the truth. Investors can, if it means they don&#8217;t have to
face more market crashes and government bailouts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(David Reilly is a Bloomberg News columnist. The opinions
expressed are his own.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click on &#8220;Send Comment&#8221; in the sidebar display to send a
letter to the editor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the writer of this column:
David Reilly at  dreilly14@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this column:
James Greiff at  jgreiff@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Michelle Fay Cortez" date="Feb 02, 2010  4:20 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-02-02/mystery-alzheimer-s-drug-may-yield-advance-for-pfizer-update2-.html"><headline>Mystery Alzheimer&#8217;s Drug May Yield Advance for Pfizer</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Doctors may learn next month that
Dimebon, a 27-year-old hay fever treatment and one of the most
mysterious compounds yet tried to fight dementia, is poised to
become their newest and perhaps best weapon against Alzheimer&#8217;s. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medivation Inc. (MDVN), the start-up that persuaded Pfizer Inc. (PFE),
the world&#8217;s biggest drugmaker, to help develop Dimebon, may be
ready to release new research data during the first week of
March, said Bengt Winblad, head of Alzheimer&#8217;s research at the
Karolinska Institute in Stockholm and a leader of the European
trials for the product. The study may confirm a 2008 finding in
Russia that patients functioned better and thought more clearly
after swallowing Dimebon tablets three times a day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data augur a make-or-break moment for San Francisco-based Medivation, which has no products on the market and has
recorded losses exceeding $150 million since 2003. Pfizer, which
hasn&#8217;t brought a new drug to market that generates more than $1
billion a year since the pain pill Lyrica won U.S. clearance in
2004, has pinpointed Alzheimer&#8217;s as one of six focuses of
research. Doctors say millions of patients may benefit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 183-patient Russian study, reported in the Lancet in
July 2008, &#8220;showed the most effective and sustained benefit
that we&#8217;ve ever seen in Alzheimer&#8217;s,&#8221; Samuel Gandy, associate
director of the Alzheimer&#8217;s Disease Research Center at Mount
Sinai School of Medicine in New York, said in a telephone
interview. &#8220;There is nothing that&#8217;s currently approved that
compares to it and nothing else really in the pipeline that
compares to it.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Drug Failures &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some patients were better after taking the drug for 18
months than they were at the start of the trial, something never
previously seen with the progressive disease. Gandy, who wasn&#8217;t
involved in the research, said the drug stands to win approval
even if the next study &#8220;is only half as good as the original.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few Alzheimer&#8217;s candidates beat the odds. There hasn&#8217;t been
a new drug for the disease since Namenda, from New York-based
Forest Laboratories Inc. (FRX), was approved in 2003, and almost a
dozen drugs in mid- to late-stage testing have failed since
then, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drugs that looked exciting in early studies have turned
into disappointments, while others that appeared less promising
ended up successful, said Constantine Lyketsos, chair of
psychiatry at Johns Hopkins Bayview Medical Center in Baltimore. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Ultimately with Dimebon, the data will speak,&#8221; Lyketsos
said. &#8220;Even if it was hugely promising and exciting, it would
be a little while before it ends up on the market. My patients
and families need realistic hope at this point and I&#8217;m not sure
that&#8217;s realistic hope at this point.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Stock Ratings &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now valued at $1.13 billion, Medivation may plunge 35
percent in Nasdaq trading if the study fails, said Ian Sanderson, an analyst at Cowen  Co. in Boston. Success may
propel the stock to rise 20 percent, he said. Sanderson rates
the shares &#8220;neutral.&#8221; Seven other analysts say investors
should buy Medivation and one has a &#8220;sell&#8221; opinion, according
to Bloomberg data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medivation rose $1.88, or 5.6 percent, to $35.70 at 4 p.m.
in Nasdaq Stock Market composite trading. The shares have gained
80 percent in the last 12 months before today as investors
anticipate the study results. Pfizer shares rose 45 cents, or
2.4 percent, to $19.24, and have climbed 29 percent in the past
12 months in New York Stock Exchange composite trading. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Positive results would usher Dimebon into a $4 billion a
year market that may almost triple by 2018, said Matthew Winton,
an analyst at Decision Resources Inc. in Waltham, Massachusetts,
in a telephone interview. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&#8216;Very Excited&#8217; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analysts said they expect Medivation and New York-based
Pfizer to file for regulatory approval of Dimebon in 2011.
Results from the 525-patient Connection study could move that
date forward, company officials said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;We&#8217;re all very excited that we will reproduce exactly
what was seen in the other trial,&#8221; said Briggs Morrison, senior
vice president of Pfizer&#8217;s primary-care development group, in a
telephone interview. &#8220;If that data comes together and in our
conversations with regulators they feel that it&#8217;s a strong
package worthy of filing, we all have a passion to get these
important medicines to patients.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In its initial studies, Dimebon was effective in all five
areas examined and the improvements lasted longer than the
effects seen in separate research on rival therapies. If the
results are confirmed, the drug may generate at least $1.6
billion in annual sales by 2015, Sanderson said. The top spot in
the market is now held by Pfizer and Tokyo-based Eisai Co. (4523)&#8217;s
Aricept, which generates $2.5 billion a year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Russian Researchers &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medivation acquired Dimebon, which has been used since 1983
to treat hay fever in the former Soviet Union, from a company
formed by Sergey Bachurin, a researcher at the Institute of
Psychologically Active Compounds, in Chemogolovka, Russia. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The drug was first identified as a possible way to protect
neurons when the Russian Academy of Science, in Chernogolovka,
Russia, started in the early 1990s to screen libraries of
compounds for their ability to block a key brain receptor.
Belief in the drug was bolstered when researchers found it
improved learning in brain-damaged rodents. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If Dimebon beats the 70 percent failure rate seen in drug
development, the results -- and clearances from the U.S. Food
and Drug Administration and its European counterparts -- may
arrive before scientists pinpoint how the product works. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What Patients Want &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investigators once thought Dimebon combined the activity
seen with the two types of drugs already approved for
Alzheimer&#8217;s disease: medicines such as Pfizer&#8217;s Aricept that
increase levels of a brain chemical that helps transmit messages
between nerves, and drugs such as Forest&#8217;s Namenda, that block
the absorption of toxic levels of another neurotransmitter.
Studies dispelled that hypothesis, and what Dimebon does inside
the brain remains unknown. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patients don&#8217;t care why a drug works -- only if it does. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Many of my patients or their spouses say, &#8216;If I could at
least keep my husband or wife as she is now, I would be very
happy,&#8217; &#8221; said Karolinska&#8217;s Winblad. &#8220;In a way, that&#8217;s what
you do with this drug. You prolong the time to the decline.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dimebon is one of five Alzheimer&#8217;s medicines that may
reach the market in the next decade, Winton said. The drugs,
including products from Johnson  Johnson (JNJ) in New Brunswick, New
Jersey; Elan Corp. in Dublin; Pfizer; Baxter International Inc. (BAX)
in Deerfield, Illinois; and Eli Lilly  Co. (LLY) in Indianapolis, may
spur an $11 billion market by 2018 as prices and the number of
patients climb, Winton said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Approved Drugs &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the potential Dimebon competitors reduce levels of
amyloid plaque, a substance that builds up in the brain of
people with Alzheimer&#8217;s. The four approved drugs, which ease
symptoms for as much as six months, generated $6.3 billion in
the 12-months ended Sept. 30, according to IMS Health Inc., a
research company in Norwalk, Connecticut. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientists have now focused on Dimebon&#8217;s effect on
mitochondria, so-called power plants that generate energy in
cells, with laboratory studies showing it improves cells&#8217;
function and helps them withstand stress. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;The data is really clear, but it is in cell culture,&#8221;
Maria Ankarcrona, a Karolinska researcher, said in an interview.
&#8220;Stressed cells respond more to Dimebon than normal cells.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alzheimer&#8217;s is a progressive disease that starts with mild
forgetfulness and eventually robs patients of memories and
independence. It afflicts 30 million people worldwide, a number
that may exceed 100 million by 2050, according to Alzheimer&#8217;s
Disease International, an advocacy group based in London. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Losing Lipitor &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer, with revenue of $48.3 billion in 2008, needs new
medications to replace the sales it will lose when its biggest-selling drug, the cholesterol-lowering drug Lipitor, loses
patent protection in 2011. The patent on Aricept expires at the
end of this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer paid Medivation $225 million in September 2008 to
help develop Dimebon for Alzheimer&#8217;s and Huntington&#8217;s disease,
and may pay an additional $500 million as the drug proceeds
through the regulatory process. Pfizer is covering 60 percent of
the development costs in the U.S. and will get a like portion of
the profits. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Medivation development program includes five pivotal
trials of Dimebon, for use alone and in combination with
existing drugs, and for patients with disease ranging from mild
to severe. The 183 volunteers in the first such study, in
Russia, were given either Dimebon or a placebo for six months,
while other anti-dementia drugs weren&#8217;t allowed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Additional Research &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The researchers evaluated the last patient enrolled in the
525-patient Connection study in December and are now starting to
analyze the findings, Winblad said. The results should be
available by early March, and Medivation and Pfizer may be able
to release the findings by then, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer&#8217;s Morrison and Medivation CEO David Hung said the
data will be released by July. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;The Connection study is an important study, but it&#8217;s only
one of a number of studies,&#8221; Hung said. &#8220;We have a lot of
shots on goal.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Michelle Fay Cortez in London at 
mcortez@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Phil Serafino at  pserafino@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Bloomberg News" date="Feb 07, 2010  6:20 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-02-07/tencent-rated-new-overweight-at-jpmorgan-chase-on-earnings.html"><headline>Tencent Rated New &#8216;Overweight&#8217; at JPMorgan Chase on Earnings</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Tencent Holdings Ltd. (2988) was rated
&#8220;overweight&#8221; in new coverage at JPMorgan Chase  Co., which
cited potential higher-than-expected growth in its joint
ventures. JPMorgan had a share-price estimate of HK$180. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Chua Kong Ho at 
kchua6@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Aaron Kirchfeld" date="Feb 09, 2010 10:32 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-02-09/deutsche-bank-hires-jpmorgan-s-hooper-in-u-s-cash-equity-sales.html"><headline>Deutsche Bank Hires JPMorgan&#8217;s Hooper in U.S. Cash Equity Sales</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Deutsche Bank AG (DBK), Germany&#8217;s biggest
bank, hired Tim Hooper of JPMorgan Chase  Co. in the U.S. as
managing director and head of Southeast cash equity sales as the
company seeks to gain market share. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hooper, who joins the institutional client group, will be
based in Atlanta and report to Derek Capanna, managing director
and co-global head of cash equity sales, the Frankfurt-based
bank said today in a statement. Deutsche Bank also named
JPMorgan&#8217;s Stacey Biggers as vice president in cash equity
sales, based in Dallas, Texas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investment banking co-head Anshu Jain, 47, who oversees the
Global Markets trading unit, is selectively hiring in the
equities business to reach his goal of being at least top 5 in
global equities. Deutsche Bank in January hired former Credit
Suisse AG executive Jose Marques to be global head of electronic
equity trading and last week added Chris O&#8217;Hea and Robert Garofolo as equity sales traders to the Chicago office. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;The Southeast will continue to be a key component of our
U.S. business, and we are confident in Tim&#8217;s ability to serve
our clients in the region,&#8221; said Robert Ebert, managing
director and head of the institutional client group, equity in
North America. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hooper, who has 17 years of industry experience, joins from
JPMorgan, where he was managing director responsible for the
Southeast and Texas regions. Biggers, who will report to Hooper,
comes from JPMorgan&#8217;s Dallas office, where she was responsible
for institutional equity sales, Deutsche Bank said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deutsche Bank earned 4.97 billion euros ($6.83 billion)
last year after a record loss in 2008, helped by a rebound in
debt and equity trading. The investment bank posted revenue from
equities sales and trading of 2.73 billion euros in 2009 after a
loss in the year-earlier period. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporters on this story:
Aaron Kirchfeld in Frankfurt at 
akirchfeld@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editors responsible for this story:
Frank Connelly at  fconnelly@bloomberg.net;
Edward Evans at  eevans3@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Michael White and Brett Pulley" date="Feb 10, 2010  6:47 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-02-10/lions-gate-interested-in-buying-disney-s-miramax-unit-update1-.html"><headline>Lions Gate Interested in Buying Disney&#8217;s Miramax Unit</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Lions Gate Entertainment Corp. (LGF), the
maker of the &#8220;Saw&#8221; horror movies, is interested in buying
Miramax, the film unit Walt Disney Co. (DIS) is putting up for sale. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;It would be something that we would certainly look at,&#8221;
Lions Gate Vice Chairman Michael Burns said today on a
conference call. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other potential bidders for Miramax include Summit
Entertainment LLC, maker of the &#8220;Twilight&#8221; movies, and Qualia
Capital LLC, a closely held media investment company, a person
with knowledge of the situation said. Miramax is worth about
$500 million, according to David Davis, managing partner at
Arpeggio Partners LLC, an investment advisory firm. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to Miramax, film companies Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer
Inc. and Overture Films LLC may also change hands. Lions Gate is
among the bidders for MGM, the studio that put itself up for
sale after failing to pay interest on $3.7 billion in debt,
people familiar with matter said last week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overture Chief Executive Officer Chris McGurk and Chief
Operating Officer Danny Rosett are seeking investors to help
them purchase the company from John Malone&#8217;s Liberty Media
Corp., a person familiar with the matter said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overture, a unit of Liberty&#8217;s Starz Media, halted
development on films last month, the person said. Any deal to
purchase the studio would include the 14-film library and an
extended pay-TV deal with the Starz channel, the person said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Film Library &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Courtnee Ulrich, a spokeswoman for Englewood, Colorado-based Liberty Media, didn&#8217;t return a phone call seeking comment.
Executives at Los Angeles-based Summit and New York-based Qualia
were unavailable for comment, a spokesman said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miramax, which Disney shut down last month, fits many of
the criteria Lions Gate considers when looking at potential
acquisitions, Burns said. An acquisition would add movies
including &#8220;Pulp Fiction&#8221; and &#8220;No Country for Old Men&#8221; to
Lions Gate&#8217;s 12,000 title library of movies and TV shows. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;We&#8217;ve determined that continuing to invest in Miramax
movies wasn&#8217;t necessarily a core strategy of ours,&#8221; Disney CEO
Robert Iger said on a conference call yesterday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lions Gate, run from Santa Monica, California, fell 11
cents, or 2 percent, to $5.08 today in New York Stock Exchange
Composite trading. Liberty Starz, a tracking stock, dropped 12
cents to $46.58. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Michael White in Los Angeles at 
mwhite8@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Anthony Palazzo at 
apalazzo@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Crayton Harrison" date="Feb 11, 2010  6:09 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-02-11/televisa-purchase-of-nii-holdings-stake-gets-approval-update1-.html"><headline>Televisa Purchase of NII Holdings Stake Gets Approval</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Grupo Televisa SA (TLEVICPO), the world&#8217;s
largest Spanish-language broadcaster, won antitrust approval to
buy a stake of as much as 40 percent of wireless-phone carrier
NII Holdings Inc. (NIHD)&#8217;s Mexican unit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Federal Competition Commission approved Mexico City-based Televisa&#8217;s request in a meeting today, according to the
agency&#8217;s Web site. Televisa and NII Holdings haven&#8217;t publicly
confirmed a transaction, and a Televisa spokeswoman had no
comment on the commission&#8217;s statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking a stake in the NII unit, which operates the Nextel
mobile-phone brand in Latin America, may allow Televisa to add
wireless-phone and Internet service to its communications
offerings in Mexico. The company already markets TV, Internet
and home-phone plans through three cable operators. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NII&#8217;s Nextel Mexico unit is the smallest of Mexico&#8217;s four
wireless carriers, with less than 4 percent of the market.
America Movil SAB (AMXL) leads with 72 percent, followed by Telefonica
SA (TEF) with 20 percent and Grupo Iusacell SA with 4 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Televisa fell 30 centavos to 48.65 pesos today in Mexico
City trading. Reston, Virginia-based NII Holdings rose $1.31 to
$35.10 in Nasdaq Stock Market trading. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Crayton Harrison in Mexico City at 
tharrison5@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Julie Alnwick at  jalnwick@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Crayton Harrison" date="Feb 13, 2010 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-02-13/megacable-to-join-airwaves-auction-without-televisa-ceo-says.html"><headline>Megacable to Join Airwaves Auction Without Televisa, CEO Says</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Megacable Holdings SAB (MEGACPO), Mexico&#8217;s
largest cable-TV provider, will enter an auction of wireless
airwaves without a partner after plans with Grupo Televisa SA
fell through, Chief Executive Officer Enrique Yamuni said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Megacable will register on Feb. 15 for the government&#8217;s
planned auction, which has enough airwaves to allow companies to
build new mobile-phone networks in the country, Yamuni said
yesterday in a phone interview. The Guadalajara, Mexico-based
company is still in talks with partners that it could work with
after the auction to offer wireless service, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Megacable could use the airwaves to add mobile-phone
service to its consumer packages, which already include home-phone, Internet and TV. That could help Megacable attract
customers from Telefonos de Mexico SAB, which doesn&#8217;t sell
wireless or video service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company is participating in the auction to keep its
options open and may choose not to acquire any airwaves, Yamuni
said. The auction process is scheduled to begin on May 25. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yamuni had planned to forge a partnership with Televisa
until the broadcaster, which also controls three Mexican cable
operators, began talks to buy a stake in wireless carrier NII
Holdings Inc. (NIHD)&#8217;s Mexican unit, the CEO said. Buying a stake in
the NII Holdings unit would be &#8220;very expensive&#8221; for Megacable,
he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building a national wireless network could cost more than
$1 billion in a &#8220;worst-case scenario,&#8221; Yamuni said. The
company also could choose to offer mobile-phone service only in
areas where it offers cable or could resell service over the
network of another company, such as Telefonica SA (TEF), he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Televisa Deal &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Megacable still could forge an alliance with Televisa after
the auctions if Televisa doesn&#8217;t complete its agreement with NII
Holdings, Yamuni said. While Mexico&#8217;s antitrust agency approved
Televisa&#8217;s purchase of a stake of as much as 40 percent in the
NII unit, Televisa said today it hasn&#8217;t yet completed an
agreement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Megacable is also in talks with several other companies,
including investment funds and telecommunications companies in
Mexico and abroad, about partnerships that it could enter,
Yamuni said. He declined to name the other parties. He said he
hoped to have an agreement in the next few weeks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Crayton Harrison in Mexico City at 
tharrison5@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Julie Alnwick at  jalnwick@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Crayton Harrison" date="Feb 15, 2010  4:35 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-02-15/televisa-agrees-to-buy-30-stake-in-nii-s-mexico-unit-update3-.html"><headline>Televisa Agrees to Buy 30% Stake in NII&#8217;s Mexico Unit</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Grupo Televisa SA (TLEVICPO), the world&#8217;s
largest Spanish-language broadcaster, agreed to buy a 30 percent
stake in the Mexican unit of mobile carrier NII Holdings Inc. (NIHD)
for $1.44 billion in cash to get access to the wireless market. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The companies will together bid on wireless airwaves in a
government auction planned for May, Mexico City-based Televisa
said in a statement today. Televisa will have the option to buy
an additional stake of 7.5 percent on the third or fourth
anniversary of the deal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Televisa is seeking a mobile-phone and wireless Internet
service to add to the video, Web and home-phone plans it offers
through three Mexican cable-TV carriers. The company aims to
take more customers from Carlos Slim&#8217;s Telefonos de Mexico SAB,
the nation&#8217;s largest landline phone company, which doesn&#8217;t sell
wireless or TV service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;This gives them a partner,&#8221; said Christopher King, an
analyst at Stifel Nicolaus  Co. in Baltimore, about Televisa.
He advises buying shares of NII and doesn&#8217;t have a rating for
Televisa shares. &#8220;It&#8217;s hard to argue that it would&#8217;ve made
sense for them to go headlong into the auction process by
themselves.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NII, the Reston, Virginia-based carrier that uses the
Nextel brand in Latin America, is the smallest of Mexico&#8217;s four
wireless carriers with less than 4 percent of the market.
America Movil SAB (AMXL) leads with 72 percent, followed by Telefonica
SA (TEF) with 20 percent and Grupo Iusacell SA with 4 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Integrated Strategy &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Televisa won approval last week from Mexico&#8217;s antitrust
agency to buy up to 40 percent of the NII unit. Televisa had
28.7 billion pesos ($2.22 billion) in cash and short-term
investments at the end of September. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Televisa gained 0.9 percent to 48.63 pesos at 4:10 p.m. New
York time in Mexico City trading. U.S. markets are closed today
for a holiday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allen  Co. aided Televisa on the transaction and Lazard
Ltd. (LAZ) advised NII. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;It&#8217;s a very interesting bundle we can put together,&#8221;
said Gustavo Cantu, who oversees business development for NII&#8217;s
Mexico unit, in a phone interview. &#8220;This will give us a way
toward a better-integrated media and telecom strategy both for
Televisa and Nextel.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Auction Process &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mexico&#8217;s auction, scheduled to begin May 25, includes 90
megahertz of spectrum in the 1.7 gigahertz band and 30 megahertz
in the 1.9 gigahertz band, airwaves suitable for third-generation wireless services such as high-speed Internet access.
The spectrum is enough to allow for two new nationwide wireless
networks and for current carriers to add more capacity for their
growth plans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nextel and Televisa would be able to offer a new 3G network
about one year after the auction concludes, Televisa Executive
Vice President Alfonso de Angoitia told reporters today on a
conference call. The network would cover the entire country
three years after the auction, he said. He declined to offer an
estimate for the cost to build the network. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Televisa may be interested in expanding the relationship to
other countries where NII Holdings operates after it completes
the auction and business plan for Mexico, de Angoitia said. NII
has operations in Brazil, Argentina, Peru and Chile. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;NII is always evaluating ways we can create bigger
opportunities for profitable growth within our business,&#8221; said
Timothy Perrott, a spokesman for the company. He said he
wouldn&#8217;t discuss specific plans or partners. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Spending Concerns &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mexico agreement with Televisa will eliminate
investors&#8217; concern that NII would spend too much money to build
its new network, King said. The company currently uses a
technology called integrated digital enhanced network, or iDEN,
and must acquire new airwaves and technology to offer more
advanced services such as video downloads. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;They have participated in a niche market, but in that
market they have been very successful,&#8221; de Angoitia said today.
&#8220;They know Mexico and the competition in Mexico.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The price for the Nextel stake implies a value of more than
six times King&#8217;s forecast for 2010 profits, excluding items such
as interest and taxes, the analyst said. He said he plans to
raise his forecast for NII&#8217;s stock price to $60 from $50,
implying an increase of 66 percent over the next 12 months based
on the Feb. 12 closing price of $36.07. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3G Network &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mexico&#8217;s Federal Telecommunications Commission has pushed
for the airwaves auction as a way to increase competition for
America Movil. Televisa and NII will be eligible to bid on two
national blocks of airwaves measuring 30 megahertz each, enough
to start a new network with 3G technology. NII&#8217;s three larger
competitors aren&#8217;t eligible for those 30-megahertz blocks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mexican government has spread the cost of acquiring the
airwaves over a 20-year period. Auction participants will bid
only the down payments. Winners then have to pay annual dues set
by the government. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each winning bidder of a 30-megahertz block will pay a
total of $493 million in dues over the 20-year period, according
to the commission, which used an accounting method that includes
the cash flow the airwaves are expected to generate. Down
payments for the 30-megahertz blocks will start at about $13.7
million. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Crayton Harrison in Mexico City at 
tharrison5@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Julie Alnwick at  jalnwick@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Tal Barak Harif" date="Feb 15, 2010  4:26 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-02-15/mexico-stocks-empresas-ica-grupo-televisa-and-nii-holdings.html"><headline>Mexico Stocks: Empresas ICA, Grupo Televisa and NII Holdings</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;The following companies had unusual
price changes in Mexico trading. Stock symbols are in
parentheses and prices are as of 4 p.m. New York time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bolsa index rose for a third day, increasing 0.1
percent to 31,038.32. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Empresas ICA SAB (ICA*)  fell the most in 3-1/2 months,
dropping 5.5 percent to 29.9 pesos. Mexico&#8217;s largest
construction company said changes in the country&#8217;s tax law will
result in deferred payments of about 2.7 billion pesos ($208.4
million) over five years beginning in 2010, according to a
statement to the Mexican exchange on Feb. 12 after the close. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grupo Televisa SA (TLEVICPO MM) advanced for the first time
in four days, rising 0.9 percent to 48.63 pesos. The world&#8217;s
largest Spanish-language broadcaster agreed to buy a 30 percent
stake in the Mexican unit of mobile carrier NII Holdings Inc. (NIHD)
for $1.44 billion in cash to get access to the wireless market. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NII Holdings (NIHD*)  jumped 7.2 percent to 474.3 pesos. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Tal Barak Harif in New York at 
tbarak@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
David Papadopoulos at 
Papadopoulos@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Rich Jaroslovsky" date="Feb 18, 2010  4:05 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-02-18/google-s-microsoft-takedown-helped-by-rivals-rich-jaroslovsky.html"><headline>Google&#8217;s Microsoft Takedown Helped by Rivals: Rich Jaroslovsky</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;The browser wars are back in full
flower, for which we have Google Inc. and the European Union to
thank. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google&#8217;s big plans for its Chrome browser seem to have
shaken Microsoft Corp. out of its competitive torpor and forced
the software giant to pay fresh attention to its own browser,
Internet Explorer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, starting next month, the EU will require
customers who buy new computers in Europe to be presented with a
screen at startup listing a dozen browsers in random order, and
given a choice of which and how many they want to install. It&#8217;s
all part of an antitrust settlement with Microsoft. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result should be a boon to consumers and to online
innovation. But you don&#8217;t have to be European, or even own a new
PC, to download these free programs and start exploring. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Non-Microsoft software makers are apt to say the biggest
thing that keeps users from switching browsers is ignorance. A
surprising number of people, they say, don&#8217;t understand what a
browser is or does. To them, that big &#8220;e&#8221; on the computer
desktop simply means &#8220;the Internet,&#8221; and they aren&#8217;t aware of
the multitude of alternatives for accessing the Web. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the interest of education, Google has created a Web site
at whatbrowser.org. It includes links to five browsers --
including Microsoft&#8217;s as well as Google&#8217;s -- along with an
informational video, benchmark tests and other resources. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google&#8217;s Strategy &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chrome, which is available in versions for Windows, Mac and
Linux, is a key part of Google&#8217;s strategy to get computer users
comfortable with so-called cloud computing. The idea is for
everyone to spend less money and time on programs they buy from
software companies (Microsoft, say), and rely more on data and
services such as Google Docs, which reside on servers and
storage systems on the &#8216;net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Described this way, Chrome sounds like a Trojan horse to
make us all dependent on Google&#8217;s own services. And so it is.
But for Google&#8217;s plans to work, Chrome has to be good. And so it
is. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The program is fast, flexible and rests lightly atop your
computer&#8217;s operating system -- a fine thing from a security
standpoint, because it makes it harder than Internet Explorer
for hackers to use as an entr&#233;e into your computer&#8217;s innards. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best for Macs &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mac users probably have it easiest: The best browser comes
built right into every computer. It&#8217;s Safari, Apple Inc.&#8217;s own
program. Apple has managed to avoid the controversy stirred by
Microsoft&#8217;s similar bundling of Internet Explorer with the
operating system primarily because it has only a fraction of
Windows&#8217; market share. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Safari is also available in a Windows version that I&#8217;m less
enamored of; I&#8217;m more likely to run into Web sites that don&#8217;t
display properly or work quite right than happens with other
Windows browsers. The blame for that probably rests more with
those site developers than with Apple; still, with so many good
alternatives, it&#8217;s seldom worth the effort to figure out just
what&#8217;s wrong. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I prefer Mozilla Firefox, a descendant of the
Netscape browser that Microsoft vanquished in Browser War I.
Maintained by an open-source community, Firefox is available for
PCs, Macs and Linux computers, and is the second-most-used
browser after Internet Explorer. The program benefits from a
well-developed ecosystem that includes thousands of add-ons for
everything from speeding up YouTube downloads to StumbleUpon,
which adds a button that helps you discover and share Web sites
that match your interests. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Off to the Opera &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opera, from the Norwegian company Opera Software ASA, is
another good choice. Opera, which has been around since the
earliest days of the Web, is available in Mac, Linux and PC
versions. And of course, there&#8217;s Internet Explorer itself. The
current version, IE 8, was released last year with a slew of
enhancements. Microsoft has promised that the next version, will
be faster and harder for bad guys to hack into. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each browser has legions of fans, and I&#8217;m not quite dumb
enough to try to tell you which one is best: I wouldn&#8217;t have
time enough to answer the hate mail from devotees of all the
others. What I can say is that this is the perfect time to break
the shackles of habit and try something different. Better still,
try them all. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Rich Jaroslovsky is a Bloomberg News columnist. The
opinions expressed are his own.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click on &#8220;Send Comment&#8221; in the sidebar display to send a
letter to the editor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the writer of this column:
Rich Jaroslovsky in New York at 
rjaroslovsky@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Bob Van Voris, Cary O&#8217;Reilly and Margaret Cronin Fisk" date="Feb 22, 2010  6:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-02-22/pfizer-begins-trial-of-300-million-neurontin-claim-of-misuse-by-kaiser.html"><headline>Pfizer Begins Trial of $300 Million Neurontin Claim of Misuse by Kaiser</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer Inc. illegally promoted the
epilepsy pill Neurontin for unapproved uses, causing health-care
plans to needlessly pay hundreds of millions of dollars, lawyers
for a California insurer told a jury in federal court. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kaiser Foundation Health Plan Inc. and Kaiser Foundation
Hospitals claim they were misled into believing Neurontin was
effective for migraines, bipolar disorder and other conditions
in addition to epilepsy, for which the U.S. Food and Drug
Administration approved the drug in 1993. Kaiser is seeking
$100 million, an amount that may be tripled under federal civil-
racketeering law. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;This is a case about fraud,&#8221; Thomas Greene, a lawyer for
the plaintiffs, told jurors today in Boston. Pfizer and its
Warner-Lambert unit &#8220;lied about the effectiveness of Neurontin.
My client, Kaiser, paid millions of dollars for a medicine that
was no more effective than sugar pills.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trial began today with jury selection under the
supervision of U.S. District Judge Patti Saris, who is
overseeing federal lawsuits from throughout the U.S. targeting
Pfizer with injury claims and allegations of fraudulent sales
and marketing of the drug. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A verdict in the case may influence other Neurontin suits
against Pfizer, the world&#8217;s largest drugmaker. In a ruling last
year, Saris said that fraud findings against Pfizer could be
binding against the New York-based company in future trials. &lt;/p&gt;




Source:  Pfizer Inc. via Bloomberg

&lt;p&gt;
This is an undated company photo of a bottle of Neurontin 600 mg tablets. Close
&lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By John Mariani" date="Feb 22, 2010 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-02-22/viennese-meat-dishes-waltz-well-with-elusive-blue-frank-wines.html"><headline>Viennese Meat Dishes Waltz Well With Elusive &#8217;Blue Frank&#8217; Wines</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;After a bitter cold morning in
Vienna on a tour of &#8220;The Third Man&#8221; movie locations, I deserved
lunch at Plachutta, which serves the city&#8217;s best tafelspitz of
boiled meats, horseradish and sour cream. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A pleasure as hearty as that demanded a good Austrian wine
-- a sturdy red, not a wimpy white gruener veltliner. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I looked at the wine card and saw several blaufraenkisch
labels, none of which I was familiar with. I chose blindly, a
Johann Heinrich 2008, and was rewarded with a wonderful example
of this little-known wine that makes it out of Austria only in
small amounts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With modest tannins, a distinctive dark, dried-cherry
flavor and rarely more than 14 percent alcohol, blaufraenkisch
is ideal with tafelspitz, Vienna&#8217;s namesake Wiener Schnitzel and
other Austrian meat dishes. I was surprised that young bottlings
from 2007 and 2008 were showing such remarkable zest and
balance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blaufraenkisch (called Lemberger in Germany and Kekfrankos
in Hungary) means &#8220;blue Frank,&#8221; referring to the grape&#8217;s color
and the Franks who established an empire in the Middle Ages. In
Viennese dialect, as in English, &#8220;frank&#8221; also suggests something
honest, and there is nothing flamboyant, over-oaked, overripe or
flabby about these wines. The good acidity keeps the fruit in
check. Occasionally a bit of cabernet sauvignon, merlot or
zweigelt may be mixed in. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After drinking a number of examples of blaufraenkisch in
Austria last month, I learned that the best come from Central
and South Burgenland near the Hungarian border. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scarce Supply &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within those regions, the best of the best are found in
Pottelsdorf, Eisenstadt and Lake Neusiedlersee-Hugelland. They
are not made in large quantities and most are sold within
Austria, largely to restaurants. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the beautiful Zirbelzimmer dining room of the Hotel
Sacher in Salzburg, I enjoyed a blaufraenkisch that the
sommelier said was one of the finest from the area around the
villages of Deutsch Schutzen and Eisenberg, from the fifth-
generation winery Kritzler. Its Perwolff 2005, which has a
little cabernet sauvignon blended in, was clearly made with
great care, its balance perfect, its aging in oak timed
perfectly to moderate the tannins. It went beautifully with a
dinner that included a beef consomme with root vegetables, and
an Alpine loin and braised knuckle of lamb in a light garlic
sauce. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the charming, barrel-vaulted restaurant Blaue Gans in
Salzburg, I had a choice of lighter or richer styles, the former
aged in stainless steel, the latter in barriques, a type of
French barrel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Better by Law &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Austrian wines have improved during the last two decades
because of changes in the Austrian Wine Act,&#8221; said Christina
Schachner, the restaurant&#8217;s food and beverage assistant.
&#8220;Quantity limitation and investments into modern producing
standards such as steel cylinders, oak barrels and electronic
devices improved the quality in general and the blaufraenkisch
in particular.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As to the wines&#8217; aging, she said, &#8220;a classic blaufraenkisch
reaches its drinking age after three to (better) five years. A
good blaufraenkisch can also take up to ten years.&#8221; Examples
that old are hard to find, since the wines tend to get drunk
soon after their release. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Austria has built up a considerable reputation in the
world market with its gruener veltliners, a white wine I find
rarely rises to the quality of red blaufraenkisch (although
after sampling a few older vintages in Austria, I&#8217;m beginning to
believe gruener gets better after five years or more in bottle). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Versatile Red &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Austria produces enormous amounts of gruener and little of
blaufraenkisch for export. But blaufraenkisch is well worth
searching out, not as the noblest wine of eastern Europe but as
one of the best buys and most versatile reds. In the U.S., where
good wine shops carry one or two examples, blaufraenkisch rarely
sells for more than $25, usually more like $17. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you can find them, the 2001 and 2002 vintages were
outstanding for Austrian red wines. And if you want a crash
course in blaufraenkisch or any other Austrian wines, book a
room at Vienna&#8217;s Hotel Rathhaus Wein  Design, where the rooms
are named after 39 vintners whose wines may be tasted with
director Conrad Schropel on request and whose wineries may be
visited during day-trips arranged by the hotel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(John Mariani writes on wine for Bloomberg News. The
opinions expressed are his own.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the writer of this column:
John Mariani at john@johnmariani.com. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By David Pauly" date="Feb 23, 2010  9:01 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-02-23/exxon-buffett-stir-takeover-pot-for-good-or-bad-david-pauly.html"><headline>Exxon, Buffett Stir Takeover Pot, for Good or Bad: David Pauly</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Wall Street&#8217;s mergers and
acquisitions machine is recovering from its recession doldrums,
raising the old question of whether the takeovers investment
banks foster do anything more than make companies bigger and
harder to manage.
     Schlumberger Ltd. this week said it would buy oil-field
services rival Smith International Inc. for about $11 billion
and, according to Bloomberg News, Thermo Fisher Scientific Inc.
is offering about $6 billion for Millipore Corp., adding
biotechnology customers to its market for laboratory equipment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There already have been some eye-popping deals. Exxon Mobil
Corp., the biggest U.S. oil company, in December offered about
$31 billion for XTO Energy Inc., to add the target company&#8217;s
huge reserves of natural gas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warren Buffett&#8217;s Berkshire Hathaway Inc. on Feb. 12
completed its $26.7 billion offer for full control of Burlington
Northern Santa Fe Corp., which vies with Union Pacific Corp. as
the nation&#8217;s biggest railroad. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Takeovers are good for Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and Citigroup Inc., which currently top the 2010 list of U.S. merger
advisers. It&#8217;s good too if corporate executives have renewed
confidence in the economy -- though acquisitions usually destroy
jobs rather than create them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spectacle of hostile takeovers such as Kraft Foods
Inc.&#8217;s contested acquisition of British candy maker Cadbury Plc
might spark investor interest in the stock market. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bad-mouthing &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A similar battle for control was brewing this week. Airgas
Inc., the largest distributor of industrial gases in the U.S.,
blew off an unsolicited $5.1 billion bid from Air Products 
Chemicals Inc. &#8220;We are concerned about Air Products&#8217; ability to
manage the business,&#8221; said Airgas Chief Executive Officer Peter McCausland, who owns 9.34 percent of his company&#8217;s shares. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the merger parade accelerates, investors will buy
shares of other oil, chemical, food and railroad companies
betting they will also be taken over. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CEOs and their Wall Street advisers always rationalize
their deals -- never mentioning such things as empire-building
or increased pay for running bigger companies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schlumberger says it needs Smith International&#8217;s drill bits
added to its drilling, logging and seismic businesses to compete
as the search for crude oil moves into more difficult areas both
on land and at sea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#8217;s enough similarity in the companies&#8217; products that
some will have to be divested to satisfy government antitrust
officials. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Power Moves &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electric utility FirstEnergy Corp.&#8217;s plan to buy Allegheny
Energy Inc. for $4.7 billion in stock gives the buyer access to
Allegheny&#8217;s cheaper power and gives the seller access to capital
for expansion. It had better work: FirstEnergy offered a 32
percent premium for Allegheny shares. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Walgreen Co. is the biggest U.S. drugstore chain but it&#8217;s
nowhere in New York City. Last week, it offered $618 million for
Duane Reade Holdings Inc., which has 257 stores in the largest
pharmacy market in the country. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Walgreen used to open new stores on its own, buying
Duane Reade was a quick entry into New York and the seller,
leveraged buyout firm Oak Hill Capital Partners, no doubt was
eager to get out. Walgreen&#8217;s offer was less than the $680
million the LBO outfit paid for the New York stores in 2004. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, there&#8217;s no historical record to praise
takeovers or to condemn them. Though studies show the stocks of
buyers tend to decline in the short run, it&#8217;s impossible to say
how merged companies would have done if they hadn&#8217;t combined. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are obvious successes, like Exxon&#8217;s acquisition of
Mobil, and clear disasters such as Time Warner Inc. and what&#8217;s
now AOL Inc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Takeovers are part of the corporate psyche in any case. The
best thing about the latest batch is that they indicate the
economy is approaching normalcy. Whether it&#8217;s shooting free
throws in the last seconds of a basketball game or risking
millions on a new factory, confidence is the key. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(David Pauly is a columnist for Bloomberg News. Opinions
expressed are his.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click on &#8220;Send Comment&#8221; in the sidebar display to send a
letter to the editor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the writer of this column:
David Pauly in Fort Myers, Florida at 
dpauly@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this column:
James Greiff at  jgreiff@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Mark Gilbert" date="Feb 24, 2010  7:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-02-24/goldman-sachs-is-innocent-of-greece-s-swap-crimes-mark-gilbert.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Is Innocent of Greece&#8217;s Swap Crimes: Mark Gilbert</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;For once, the whipping boys and
girls of finance are innocent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The European Union is investigating Goldman Sachs Group
Inc.&#8217;s role in the financial sleight of hand that helped Greece
use swaps to postpone the day of economic reckoning past its
ascension to euro membership. Goldman says, rightly, there was
&#8220;nothing inappropriate&#8221; in the transactions it facilitated. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the elements of a crime are present. There&#8217;s a
victim -- trust in the common-currency project. There&#8217;s a
weapon, in the form of the derivatives that trimmed 2.37 billion
euros ($3.2 billion) off the nation&#8217;s debt burden. And there&#8217;s a
perpetrator, the Greek government, which knew its finances were
too shaky to ditch its currency, the drachma. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There also seems to be an accomplice -- Goldman Sachs,
which had the financial-engineering skills to crack open
Greece&#8217;s budget deficit and spirit enough of its obligations
away to a future date to ensure it qualified to join the euro. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&#8217;s missing is any broken law. The architects of
European integration knowingly and with malice aforethought
added the words &#8220;additional measures&#8221; in a footnote to the
blueprint, letting Italy fudge its numbers to get into the club. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slapping Kittens &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#8217;s the same loophole Greece was able to exploit, in
line with the rules, aided and abetted by Goldman Sachs. So
while German Chancellor Angela Merkel said this month &#8220;it&#8217;s a
scandal if it turned out that the same banks that brought us to
the brink of the abyss helped fake the statistics,&#8221; she&#8217;s
wagging her finger at the wrong party. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DNA of investment bankers drives them to find and
exploit malleable clauses, bend rules, take maximum advantage of
the unintended consequences of legislation. Chastising Goldman
Sachs for flexing its muscles on behalf of a customer is akin to
slapping a kitten for its adventures with a ball of wool. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Society doesn&#8217;t want to outlaw investment banking (not yet,
anyway), any more than it wants to euthanize wool-bothering
kittens. The trick is to keep the knitting supplies locked in a
cupboard; the EU cannot leave the door ajar for reasons of
Italian political expediency, and then complain when the floor
ends up resembling a Jackson Pollock. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Balance-Sheet Shifts &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Creative accounting -- which is just a polite way to talk
about cooking the books -- is nothing new for countries. Italy
used a yen-denominated swap to give its finances a one-time puff
and avoid the ignominy of failing to qualify for the euro. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the U.K., so-called public-private partnerships and
private finance initiatives allow the government to shift the
burden of costly infrastructure onto the balance sheets of
companies that tender successfully to manage and build the
projects. The companies get access to rampant profit potential,
in return for the government suppressing its debt burden. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greece is a particularly apt subject for the old joke about
lies, damned lies and statistics. In September 2004, the nation
had to revise up its deficits for 2000, 2001 and 2002. The gap
for the first year was more than doubled to 4.1 percent, while
that of the two later years almost tripled to 3.7 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put bluntly, it turned out that the country had missed the
3 percent deficit threshold for euro membership in every single
year since joining the common currency -- transgressions that
went unpunished. So no one should be surprised that Greek
Finance Minister George Papaconstantinou confessed to &#8220;some
sleight of hand&#8221; in Greece&#8217;s 2009 deficit numbers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sovereign Risk &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Greece debacle is likely to hasten and worsen increased
oversight of the derivatives market. In particular, contracts
where the buyer doesn&#8217;t have any skin in the game are akin to
writing auto insurance for people who don&#8217;t own a car and don&#8217;t
even have a driver&#8217;s license, but who nevertheless fancy a bet
on the likelihood of a car crash. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Financial authorities will probably outlaw such behavior,
ignoring the difficulties of differentiating between efficient
risk management and risk creation. Moreover, governments are
clearly uncomfortable with the concept of investors being able
to bet against a country&#8217;s creditworthiness in the credit-
default swaps market. This may spur an unwelcome and unnecessary
intervention by the dead hand of regulation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trick Goldman Sachs employed to help Greece massage its
debt figures hinged on using historical, rather than prevailing,
currency rates in a series of swap transactions. While that
undoubtedly comes under the heading of fast-and-loose, it&#8217;s not
illegal; swaps are over-the-counter contracts between consenting
adults, so no matter how divorced the values are from reality,
it really isn&#8217;t anybody else&#8217;s business. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman Sachs has become the lightning rod for public anger
about the global bailout of the finance industry. The vexation
is appropriate; there&#8217;s too little humility and too much
arrogance, and scant recognition that every financial firm, no
matter how clever its partners, would be dead without an ocean
of taxpayers&#8217; money keeping the system afloat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the case of Greece&#8217;s swaps, though, Goldman Sachs has
done nothing wrong. The EU&#8217;s forensics squad should be looking
closer to home for its culprit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Mark Gilbert, author of &#8220;Complicit: How Greed and
Collusion Made the Credit Crisis Unstoppable,&#8221; is the London
bureau chief and a columnist for Bloomberg News. The opinions
expressed are his own.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click on &#8220;Send Comment&#8221; in the sidebar display to send a
letter to the editor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the writer of this column:
Mark Gilbert in London at 
magilbert@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this column:
James Greiff at  jgreiff@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Patrick Cole" date="Feb 25, 2010 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-02-25/goldman-s-dean-backer-helps-hedge-funds-care-on-2-million-goal.html"><headline>Goldman&#8217;s Dean Backer Helps Hedge Funds Care on $2 Million Goal</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Growing up in the Long Island, New
York, village of Seaford, Dean Backer went door-to-door with his
mother on Friday evenings seeking donations for a cancer
charity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;At a very early age, my parents instilled in us the need
to give back in any way we could,&#8221; said Backer, 43, a Goldman
Sachs Group Inc. executive for two decades. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#8217;s a conviction he took to Goldman, where he is global
head of sales and capital introduction for its securities
services, a job that includes working with hedge funds. For 12
years Backer has been involved in New York-based Hedge Funds
Care, a nonprofit that funds organizations working with child
abuse, and last month he became a board member. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;It&#8217;s an issue that doesn&#8217;t get a lot of press,&#8221; Backer
said in a telephone interview. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backer will serve as a co-chairman for tonight&#8217;s 12th
annual &#8220;Open Your Heart to the Children&#8221; Gala at Cipriani 42nd
Street, which seeks to raise about $2 million. About 1,100
hedge-fund and finance-industry workers are expected to attend
the cocktail reception. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard H. Baker, president and chief executive officer of
the Washington-based Managed Funds Association, an organization
of hedge-fund managers, is also a co-chairman for the event. At
tonight&#8217;s benefit, the Hedge Funds Care Award for Caring will be
given to Michael Novogratz, president of the buyout and hedge-
fund firm Fortress Investment Group LLC, and supermodel Liya
Kebede, who heads her own charity, the Liya Kebede Foundation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8216;Precious&#8217; Director &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lee Daniels, director of the Oscar-nominated film
&#8220;Precious: Based on the Novel &#8216;Push&#8217; by Sapphire,&#8221; will
receive Hedge Funds Care&#8217;s Founders Award. A representative for
Daniels will accept the award for him. &#8220;Precious&#8221; is the story
of Claireece Precious Jones, a 16-year-old girl who is
impregnated twice by her father and abused by her mother. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in 1998, New York-based Hedge Fund Cares has
counted on the generosity of hedge funds so it can award grants
to nonprofits in New York, New Jersey and Connecticut.
Recipients include the Coalition on Child Abuse and Neglect and
Girls Educational and Mentoring Services. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backer has also donated time and money to the Robin Hood
Foundation, which supports poverty-fighting organizations, and
he serves on the board of Comprehensive Development Inc., a
nonprofit that prepares older high-school students to enter the
job market. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ve seen a more difficult climate than
last year,&#8221; he said. &#8220;But even in difficult times, you do see
the good in people come out. I do think this is one of those
occasions where people dig deep down into their pockets.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hedge Funds Care &#8220;Open Your Heart to the Children&#8221;
benefit is tonight at 6 p.m. at Cipriani 42nd Street, 110 E.
42nd St. in Manhattan. Tickets are $1,500. Information: 1-212-
991-9600, ext. 342; or http://www.hedgefundscare.org. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the writer on this story:
Patrick Cole in New York at 
pcole3@Bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Lu Wang" date="Feb 26, 2010  4:42 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-02-26/cke-jpmorgan-mohawk-pmfg-rockwell-vse-u-s-equity-movers.html"><headline>CKE, JPMorgan, Mohawk, PMFG, Rockwell, VSE: U.S. Equity Movers</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Shares of the following companies
are having unusual moves in U.S. trading. Stock symbols are in
parentheses. Prices are as of 1:15 p.m. in New York. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     3D Systems Corp. (TDSC US) rose 7.6 percent to $14.16, the
highest price since September 2008. The maker of systems to
create three-dimensional models was raised to &#8220;buy&#8221; from
&#8220;hold&#8221; at Canaccord Adams, which said the company is poised to
expand its share of the military aerospace market. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American International Group Inc. (AIG)  fell the most in
the Standard  Poor&#8217;s 500 Index, dropping 10 percent to $24.77.
The insurer rescued by the U.S. posted a fourth-quarter loss on
charges tied to paying down its bailout debt and boosting
commercial insurance reserves. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Athenahealth Inc. (ATHN)  tumbled 15 percent to $36.84,
the biggest drop since February 2009. The provider of Internet-based services for medical practices postponed the release of
its fourth-quarter and 2009 financial results and said it will
conduct an accounting policy review. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BancorpSouth Inc. (BXS)  slumped 14 percent to $19.47,
the biggest decline since December 2008. The holding company for
BancorpSouth Bank said it will delay filing its 2009 financial
results because it&#8217;s reviewing its asset quality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Calgon Carbon Corp. (CCC)  increased 12 percent to
$15.51, the biggest gain since February 2009. The Pittsburgh-based water-purification company reported fourth-quarter profit
excluding some items of 23 cents a share, beating the average
analyst estimate by 44 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CKE Restaurants Inc. (CKR US) climbed 28 percent to $11.37,
the most since December 2000. The owner of the Carl&#8217;s Jr. and
Hardee&#8217;s fast-food chains agreed to be bought by Thomas H. Lee
Partners LP for about $619 million in cash. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cogent Inc. (COGT US) dropped 5.2 percent to $9.90, the
biggest slide since May 20. The maker of fingerprint-identification systems reported fourth-quarter earnings
excluding some items of 11 cents a share, missing the average
analyst estimate in a Bloomberg survey by 8.3 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crocs Inc. (CROX)  tumbled 9.5 percent, the most since
Nov. 6, to $7.05. The maker of colorful clogs with holes
reported a fourth quarter net loss excluding some items of 4
cents a share. It also named John McCarvel president and chief
executive officer effective March 1. He succeeds John Duerden,
who is retiring from the company and resigning as president and
CEO and also as a director. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deckers Outdoor Corp. (DECK)  gained 13 percent to
$120.20, the highest price since August 2008. The maker of Ugg
boots reported fourth-quarter profit excluding some items of
$5.22 a share, beating estimates by 22 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diamond Foods Inc. (DMND)  fell 10 percent to $34.85, the
lowest level in a month. The seller of Diamond and Emerald nuts
and snacks agreed to buy Kettle Foods, the maker of potato
chips, for $615 million in cash. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fluor Corp. (FLR)  fell 5 percent to $42.80 and dropped
7.1 percent earlier, the biggest intraday since Nov. 10. The
largest publicly traded U.S. construction company lowered its
2010 earnings forecast to $2.80 to $3.20, from an earlier
forecast of $3.20 to $3.60. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FTI Consulting Inc. (FCN)  slumped 11 percent, the
biggest drop in three weeks, to $37.45. The provider of forensic
accounting forecast 2010 earnings excluding some items of $3.25
a share at most, trailing the average analyst estimate of $3.30. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gap Inc. (GPS)  rose 5.4 percent, the largest advance
since Sept. 3, to $21.50. The operator of the Old Navy and
Banana Republic clothing chains forecast full-year profit of
$1.70 to $1.75 a share. Analysts surveyed by Bloomberg estimated
$1.69 on average. Gap also said it plans to increase its annual
dividend to 40 cents a share from 34 cents and will buy back an
additional $1 billion in stock. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Insituform Technologies Inc. (INSU US) surged 9.1 percent
to $24.56 its highest level since March 2007. The sewer pipeline
contractor forecast 2010 earnings excluding some items of at
least $1.45 a share. On average, the analysts surveyed by
Bloomberg estimate profit of $1.32. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;     Interpublic Group of Cos. (IPG US) had the biggest gain in
the SP 500, surging 11 percent, the most since March 23, to
$7.50. The owner of advertising firms reported fourth-quarter
revenue of $1.8 billion, beating the average analyst estimate in
a Bloomberg survey by 3.5 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)  rose the most in the Dow
Jones Industrial Average, advancing 3.3 percent to $41.97. The
second-largest U.S. bank by assets offers &#8220;an attractive buying
opportunity&#8221; as the stock traded at about 6 to 7 times
normalized earnings, compared with a multiple of 9 for its
peers, Barclays Plc said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magellan Health Services Inc. (MGLN)  surged 6.1 percent
to $41.92, the highest in more than a month. The provider of
medical services including treatment for mental illnesses
reported fourth quarter net income of $1.25 a share, beating
analysts&#8217; average estimate of $1.08 a share in a Bloomberg
survey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mohawk Industries Inc. (MHK)  jumped 8 percent to $51.58
for the third-biggest gain in the Russell 1000 Index. The carpet
and tile maker posted fourth-quarter earnings excluding some
items of 56 cents a share, beating the average analyst estimate
by 72 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Navigators Group Inc. (NAVG)  dropped 12 percent to
$37.64, after falling to $37.62 earlier, the lowest intraday
price since October 2005. The international insurance-holding
company posted fourth-quarter profit excluding some items of 30
cents a share, trailing the average analyst estimate by 75
percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Novatel Wireless Inc. (NVTL)  dropped 9.1 percent to
$6.68, the lowest since April 28. The maker of wireless data-access cards for personal computers reported fourth-quarter
profit and sales that missed estimates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OSI Systems Inc. (OSIS)  advanced 5.2 percent to $30.84,
the most since Jan. 8. The maker of gear to scan carry-on
luggage was raised to &#8220;outperform&#8221; from &#8220;market perform&#8221; at
Morgan Keegan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PMFG Inc. (PMFG)  plunged 12 percent to $14. The provider
of energy delivery systems said it&#8217;s selling 1.3 million shares
at $11.50 each, raising money to repay debt. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rockwell Medical Technologies Inc. (RMTI)  slumped 27
percent, the most since April 2002, to $5.96 for the biggest
loss in the Russell 2000 Index. (RTY) The maker of products to clean
blood and replace nutrients in patients&#8217; bloodstreams said an
investigational product failed to meet its target in a clinical
study. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rosetta Stone Inc. (RST)  rose the third-most in Russell
2000 Index, jumping 27 percent to $22. The provider of education
software was upgraded to &#8220;buy&#8221; from &#8220;hold&#8221; by Jefferies
Group Inc. after posting fourth-quarter earnings that topped the
average analyst estimate by 46 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SandRidge Energy Inc. (SD)  declined 5.5 percent to $7.94
the lowest since June 24. The producer of natural gas and crude
oil reported fourth-quarter earnings excluding some items of 14
cents a share, missing the average analyst estimate in a
Bloomberg survey by 32 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VSE Corp. (VSEC)  slumped 17 percent to $42.53, the
lowest price Dec. 14. The defense contractor reported a decline
in fourth-quarter earnings, citing &#8220;headwinds&#8217; from delays in
the awarding of federal government contracts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weight Watchers International Inc. (WTW)  lost 15
percent, the most since it went public in November 2001, to
$25.72. The provider of weight control programs forecast 2010
earnings excluding some items of $2.50 a share at most, below
the average analyst estimate in a Bloomberg survey of $2.78. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;World Fuel Services Corp. (INT)  rallied 9 percent, the
most since Aug. 7, to $26.42. The seller of fuel to airlines and
ships reported fourth-quarter net income excluding some items of
62 cents a share. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Lu Wang at  lwang8@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Nick Baker at  nbaker7@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry></news>