
<news><entry author="By Edmond Lococo and Susanna Ray" date="Mar 07, 2008  4:04 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-03-07/boeing-787-may-be-further-delayed-goldman-sachs-says-update4-.html"><headline>Boeing 787 May Be Further Delayed, Goldman Sachs Says</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Boeing Co. (BA), which has twice delayed
its new 787 Dreamliner, may further postpone delivery of the
aircraft, according to analysts including Richard Safran of
Goldman Sachs Group Inc. The shares fell the most in two months. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial powering up of the jet scheduled for the end of
March may be delayed until the end of June, which would push
back the first flight, Safran wrote in a note today. Deliveries
may then start in the third quarter of 2009 instead of Chicago-based Boeing''s current target of ''''early 2009,'''' he wrote. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 787 is already about eight months behind schedule
because of problems with parts shortages and unfinished work by
suppliers. Concerns over an additional setback prompted Safran
to lower his 2009 delivery projection by 38 percent and reduce
his profit forecast for next year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boeing ''''continues to underestimate the amount of work
required on the 787,'''' wrote Safran, who cited unnamed sources
in his note and said he expects the company to notify suppliers
of new production targets shortly. ''''Changes to the airplane
have caused a delay in completing wiring of the aircraft.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company is ''''working hard to meet milestones'''' and will
not comment on the Goldman projections, Yvonne Leach, a Boeing
spokeswoman, said in a phone interview. Powering of the first
plane will allow fuller testing of the aircraft''s basic systems. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Safran lowered his estimate for 2009 Dreamliner deliveries
to 50 jets from 80, cut his per-share profit forecast for the
year by 10 cents to $6.90 and reduced his six-month price target
for the shares to $88 from $98. He rates the stock ''''neutral.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boeing fell $2.91, or 3.7 percent, to $76.60 at 4:01 p.m.
in New York Stock Exchange composite trading, the biggest
decline since Jan. 15. The stock has dropped 12 percent this
year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;`Almost Guaranteed'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A third delay is ''''almost guaranteed,'''' said Richard Aboulafia, vice president of Teal Group, a Fairfax, Virginia-based aerospace consultant. ''''The general feeling is that it
takes a year between first flight and entry into service. So
that first-quarter 2009 guidance wasn''t generally believed.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boeing delayed the 787 delivery schedule on Oct. 10 and
again on Jan. 16. The company had 857 orders for the 787 valued
at $144 billion from 56 airlines as of Feb. 15, making the fuel-efficient aircraft Boeing''s most successful sales campaign ever. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The planemaker continues to work on a detailed evaluation
of the 787 delivery schedule and ''''will communicate to customers
on this around the end of the first quarter,'''' Leach said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Nuts and Bolts &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last month, some work on the short-haul version of the
Dreamliner, which wasn''t scheduled to go into service until
2010, was suspended so workers could focus on the larger model
that''s garnered more orders and has a more pressing deadline.
Boeing also said in February that stress tests performed on the
787''s fuselage barrel were successful and final assembly on the
second flight-test plane had begun. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Production of the plane, which uses light carbon-fiber
construction in its wings and fuselage instead of traditional
aluminum, has been hampered by the new manufacturing process
Boeing is using, including relying more on vendors. The company
has struggled in particular with a shortage of fasteners needed
to assemble the aircraft. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scott Carson, Boeing''s top commercial-aircraft executive,
said Feb. 6 that the first flight was still scheduled for June,
unless bad weather pushed it back to July. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Elizabeth Amon" date="Mar 07, 2008  7:58 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-03-07/bank-of-america-exxon-doral-shell-in-court-news-update1-.html"><headline>Bank of America, Exxon, Doral, Shell in Court News</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Some directors of Bank of America
Corp., the second-biggest U.S. bank, were sued by a shareholder
who claims mismanagement of mortgage-backed securities led to a
33 percent drop in the stock price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shares fell from a closing high of $54.05 in February
2007 to $35.97 on Jan. 18 because of losses on collateralized
debt obligations, Kenneth Slater, manager of KT Investments LLC,
said in a complaint filed March 4 in Delaware Chancery Court. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''Defendants knew or should have known that they needed to
hedge the large risks associated with issuing and investing in
subprime CDOs,'''' Slater, based in Boston, said in the complaint. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bank of America, based in Charlotte, North Carolina, said
Jan. 22 that fourth-quarter profit fell 95 percent after more
than $5 billion in mortgage-related writedowns. The same month,
Bank of America said it would acquire Countrywide Financial
Corp., the largest U.S. mortgage lender, for about $4 billion in
stock. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slater''s so-called derivative lawsuit, which seeks to
recover money for the company, names as defendants some directors
and senior managers during the past year, including Chairman and
Chief Executive Officer Kenneth D. Lewis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slater asked a judge to order the officials to return
salaries and pay Bank of America damages for ''''waste of corporate
assets and unjust enrichment.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bank of America spokeswoman Shirley Norton said the company
was reviewing the lawsuit and had no comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Kenneth Slater v. Kenneth Lewis and Bank of
America Corp. (BAC), CA3596, Delaware Chancery Court (Wilmington). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Suruga Bank Sues IBM Over Loss From Uncompleted System Upgrade &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suruga Bank Ltd. (8358) is seeking 11.1 billion yen ($107 million)
in compensation from International Business Machines Corp. (IBM), the
world''s biggest provider of computer services, for a loss related
to the bank''s online system. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suruga filed suit in Tokyo yesterday charging IBM caused it
a loss by failing to complete installation of a new operations
system, according to a statement the bank filed to the Tokyo
Stock Exchange. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IBM has confirmed the filing and has no intention to pay
compensation to the bank, said Kazuhiro Kaneko, a Tokyo-based
spokesman at IBM Japan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suruga, a regional firm that operates in the greater Tokyo
area, hired IBM in September 2004 to upgrade its main system, the
bank said. It was forced to halt the project due to failures by
IBM, spokesman Hiroaki Momose said, declining to give details. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bank ordered the computer company to provide services
not covered by the contract, IBM Japan''s Kaneko said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more new suits news from yesterday, click here. For copies of
recent civil complaints, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lawsuits &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;U.K. Ruling in Exxon Freeze of PDVSA Funds Delayed One Week &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) must wait one more week to see whether a
U.K. judge will uphold a freeze it sought on as much as $12
billion of assets belonging to Petroleos de Venezuela SA, though
a lawyer for the Venezuelan oil company said his client might
defy the ruling. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Judge Paul Walker in London told lawyers yesterday he would
likely issue a ruling by the end of next week, said Gordon Pollock QC, the English barrister for PDVSA. A judgment had
originally been slated for earlier this week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exxon is seeking compensation for Venezuela''s seizure last
year of its interests in a joint venture in the South American
country. Pollock said his client may ignore a ruling confirming
the asset freeze, which was sought to guarantee that PDVSA has
funds to pay off Exxon should a New York arbitration panel rule
in its favor in a related case. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''Defiance of this court would simply enhance our reputation
in the areas where it mattered: in the corridors of OPEC,''''
Pollock said. The Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries
yesterday lent its support to Venezuela in the fight with Irving,
Texas-based Exxon. The lawyer warned March 5 that PDVSA was
unable to conclude refinancing of a separate energy project
because of the unavailability of the assets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exxon said last month that courts in the U.K., Netherlands
and Netherlands Antilles issued orders freezing as much as $12
billion in PDVSA assets, a move Pollock labeled ''''legal
terrorism.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In court documents, Exxon said there was a risk that PDVSA
would spend its assets before any decision was made by the
arbitration panel. PDVSA is seeking to have the freeze order
overturned or reduced in size. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exxon Mobil''s Texas-based spokeswoman Margaret Ross declined
to immediately comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Doral''s Mario Levis Is Accused of Fraud by U.S. Prosecutors &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A former senior executive of Doral Financial Corp. (DRL), the
Puerto Rico bank-holding company rescued from the brink of
bankruptcy last year, was charged with a securities fraud that
cost investors $4 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Former Treasurer Mario Levis, 44, manipulated the value of
company assets to inflate the price of Doral stock, prosecutors
said in the indictment unsealed yesterday in Manhattan federal
court. In March 2005, Levis owned 2.4 percent of the company, and
his family collectively owned 8.2 percent, prosecutors said. The
family stake was valued at more than $450 million. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''Between 2001 and 2005, Levis corrupted the process by
which Doral determined the publicly reported value of certain
non-cash assets carried on Doral''s financial books -- so-called
interest-only strips,'''' Acting U.S. Attorney Lev Dassin in New
York said in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Levis, who says he remains one of Doral''s largest individual
shareholders, said in a statement that he''s ''''astonished by'''' and
''''adamantly denies'''' the charges. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''It is clear that the mortgage market has suffered horribly
these past years,'''' Levis spokesman Mario Emmanuelli Jove said in
the statement. ''''Why then has Doral and Mario been singled out?'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''The Levises are no longer affiliated with the company and
have not been since August 2005,'''' Doral spokeswoman Lucienne Gigante said, declining further comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doral announced in September 2005 that it would restate its
finances up to the end of 2004 and cut shareholder equity by $720
million because of overvalued assets. The company eventually paid
$129 million to settle an investor lawsuit and a $25 million fine
to the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In July, Doral received a $610 million investment from a
group led by Bear Stearns Cos. that enabled it to avoid
defaulting on a bond payment. Last month, Doral agreed to improve
its protections against money laundering after a U.S. bank
regulator found weaknesses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dassin said the company lost about $4 billion in shareholder
value after the scheme unraveled. Levis was charged with one
count of securities fraud and three counts of wire fraud, each of
which carries a maximum penalty of 20 years in prison. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is U.S. v. Levis, U.S. District Court, Southern
District of New York (Manhattan). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more lawsuits news from yesterday, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Trials &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hynix Executive Gary Swanson Wins Mistrial in Price-Fixing Case &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hynix Semiconductor Inc. (000660) Senior Vice President Gary Swanson
won a mistrial in the first prosecution in a federal probe of a
global conspiracy to drive up semiconductor prices in 2000 and
2001. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swanson must be retried in April if the U.S. wants again to
pursue charges of fixing prices of memory chips, U.S. District 
Judge Phyllis Hamilton in San Francisco said yesterday after
declaring a mistrial. Nine jurors told her further deliberations
wouldn''t yield a verdict. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''The defense is disappointed there wasn''t an acquittal,''''
Swanson''s lawyer, Robert Bunzel, said in an interview. ''''Mr.
Swanson was expecting an acquittal and so were his lawyers.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swanson was the first executive to face trial in a six-year-old investigation of a conspiracy by semiconductor companies to
fix prices for dynamic random-access memory, the main memory chip
in personal computers, laptops and other electronics. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Swanson, 52, head of sales for Hynix''s U.S. unit based in
San Jose, California, was charged in 2006 with participating in
the scheme. Ichon, South Korea-based Hynix, the world''s second-largest maker of memory chips after Samsung Electronics Co.,
pleaded guilty to price-fixing claims and was ordered to pay a
$185 million fine in May 2005. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Park Hyun, a spokesman at Hynix in Seoul, declined to
comment yesterday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Samsung and two other firms also have been charged, at least
16 people have pleaded guilty, and the U.S. government has levied
$731 million in fines as part of the probe. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Government lawyers claimed Swanson, the head of Hynix''s U.S.
sales, agreed to fix prices with his counterpart at Micron
Technology Inc., the biggest U.S. maker of memory chips. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prosecutors also argued Swanson directed his sales staff to
gather pricing information from competitors so chipmakers could
agree to simultaneously raise prices for Apple Inc., Dell Inc.,
International Business Machines Corp. and other U.S. companies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hamilton yesterday told Niall Lynch, assistant chief of the
Justice Department''s antitrust office in San Francisco, to tell
the court on March 12 whether the U.S. will retry the case. She
told government lawyers that if the U.S. wants a retrial, she
wants it to start in April. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is U.S. v. Gary Swanson, 06-692, U.S. District
Court, Northern District of California (San Francisco). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more trial news from yesterday, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Verdicts/Settlements &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wyeth, Pfizer Ordered to Pay $27 Million in Punitives &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wyeth and a Pfizer Inc. (PFE) unit must pay $27.1 million in
punitive damages for mishandling menopause drugs that caused a
woman''s breast cancer, an Arkansas jury said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jurors in federal court in Little Rock deliberated about
five hours yesterday before finding that Wyeth and Pfizer''s
Pharmacia  Upjohn showed ''''reckless disregard'''' for the health
risks posed by their hormone-replacement drugs and should be
punished. The panel awarded $2.75 million in compensatory damages
to Arkansas resident Donna Scroggin on Feb. 25. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Punitive damages are justified because ''''the companies will
not accept personal responsibility'''' for harming women, Jim Morris, an Austin, Texas-based lawyer representing Scroggin, said
after the verdict. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It''s the second time Wyeth has been ordered to pay punitive
damages over its handling of the drugs, Premarin and Prempro. A
Nevada jury in October awarded $99 million in such damages to
three women after finding that the treatments caused their breast
cancers. A judge slashed the award to $58 million last month. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Arkansas verdict might not stand either, Barbara Ryan,
an analyst with Deutsche Bank AG in Greenwich, Connecticut, said
in a telephone interview. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''I would guess it would be overturned,'''' said Ryan, who
doesn''t own shares in either company. ''''The risks are clearly
documented on the label for these drugs.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scroggin was among 6 million women who took the pills to
treat menopause symptoms such as hot flashes, night sweats and
mood swings. She sued Wyeth and Upjohn in November 2004,
according to court records. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lawyers for both companies said they will appeal yesterday''s
jury finding. Wyeth, based in Madison, New Jersey, was ordered to
pay $19.3 million in punitive damages. New York-based Pfizer was
told to pay more than $7.7 million. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''We don''t believe there was any evidence that warranted
punitive damages being considered in this case,'''' said Lyn Pruitt, a Little Rock-based lawyer for Wyeth. ''''The evidence in
this case showed that Wyeth properly warned Ms. Scroggin about
the increased risk of breast cancer.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''While we have great sympathy for Ms. Scroggin, the verdict
in this case is not supported by the evidence at trial or by
medical science,'''' Sandra Phillips, Pfizer''s associate general
counsel, said in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Scroggin v. Wyeth, 04-1169, U.S. District Court
for the Eastern District of Arkansas (Little Rock). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shell Settles Oil, Gas Reserve Lawsuit With Investors in U.S. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Royal Dutch Shell Plc (RDSA), Europe''s largest oil company, agreed
to pay $89.5 million to settle a lawsuit by U.S.-based investors
over its 2004 restatement of oil and natural-gas reserves. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shell also will pay an additional $28.3 million to investors
in a European settlement, raising the company''s total payout over
the restatement to $470 million, spokesman Adam Newton said
yesterday in a phone interview. The U.S. accord requires approval
by a federal judge in New Jersey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''With this settlement, together with the settlement pending
in an Amsterdam court, we made a huge step toward closing the
chapter of legal disputes and controversies around the
recategorization of our hydrocarbon reserves,'''' Beat Hess, group
legal director for The Hague-based Shell, said in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shell is waiting for the Amsterdam Court of Appeals to
approve a $352.6 million settlement reached last year with
investors outside the U.S. Shell slashed its proven oil and gas
reserve estimates in January 2004, leading to regulatory fines,
investor lawsuits, and the ouster of the company''s top three
executives, including Chairman Phil Watts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The restatement pushed the company''s shares lower and
prompted Shell to reorganize its corporate and management
structure and step up spending on exploration. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The New Jersey settlement resolves a class-action, or group,
lawsuit led by the Pennsylvania State Employees'' Retirement
System and the Pennsylvania Public School Employees'' Retirement
System. Investors in the settlements will receive interest on the
amount owed from April 1 until they are paid by Shell, said the
Pennsylvania funds'' lead attorney, Stanley Bernstein. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The settlement is ''''an excellent recovery on behalf of Shell
investors,'''' Bernstein said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is In re: Royal Dutch/Shell Transport Securities
Litigation, 04-cv-374, U.S. District Court, District of New
Jersey (Trenton). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lehman''s $7.3 Million Mortgage Case Award Thrown Out &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc., the fourth-largest U.S.
securities firm, lost a $7.3 million verdict it won last year
from a Florida jury over bad loans it made to investors in a
senior living community. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Dec. 13, jurors in Tampa said a Lehman unit was deceived
by two Florida companies that allegedly conspired to get it to
fund millions of dollars in mortgage loans secured by properties
worth a fraction of their sales price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''Plaintiff''s calculation consists of `fuzzy math''''''
relating to the verdict, U.S. District Judge Susan C. Bucklew
said in a March 3 ruling that reduced liabilities against
Equitable Title of Florida Inc. and Passarelli  Potts Appraisal
Service Inc. to ''''zero.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the verdict, Equitable, based in Clermont, was ordered to
pay $2.8 million for breach of contract, and Winter Park-based
Passarelli was told to pay $4.5 million for negligence. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lehman was ''''pleased the court agreed with the jury''s
conclusion that the defendants committed wrongdoing,'''' spokesman
Brian Finnegan said in a statement. The New York-based firm may
seek a review of the judge''s decision to eliminate the jury
award, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''It was the right thing to do,'''' said Eric Lanigan, a
lawyer for Passarelli  Potts. ''''We felt all along there was a
significant amount of negligence and improper conduct on Lehman''s
part.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''We expected this,'''' said Equitable lawyer Howard Marks.
''''The jury found Lehman Brothers responsible at least 30 percent
for any damages it claimed.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Lehman Brothers Holdings v. Equitable Title of
Florida Inc., 06-02030, U.S. District Court, Middle District of
Florida (Tampa). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more verdict and settlement news from yesterday, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Litigation Departments &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;McGuire Woods, Indicted Former Partner Sued Over Trading &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A former client of McGuireWoods sued the 750-attorney
Richmond, Virginia, law firm and an ex-partner who has been
criminally charged with securities fraud. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The firm should have been able to prevent the former
partner, Louis Zehil, 42, from illegally trading stock from a
private placement he worked on for Alternative Energy Sources
Inc., the ethanol startup company said in its complaint. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''McGuireWoods failed to have in place the necessary
policies and procedures,'''' Kansas City, Missouri-based
Alternative Energy said in the complaint filed Jan. 31 in a
Missouri state court. McGuireWoods moved the case to federal
court in Kansas City on March 4. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zehil was charged by federal prosecutors in February 2007
with illegally trading the shares of seven companies whose
private investment in public equity transactions he worked on
beginning in January 2006. He pleaded not guilty. He''s also been
sued by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission, which said
he made illegal profits of $17 million. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McGuireWoods alerted its clients to Zehil''s trades upon
learning about them and has cooperated with federal officials in
their investigations, William Allcott, a McGuireWoods attorney,
said in an interview. Allcott declined to comment on the
Alternative Energy lawsuit, which is in mediation, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zehil declined to comment. Thomas M. Mullaney and Andrew
Lawler, his lawyers in New York, didn''t return calls seeking
comment. Zehil resigned from McGuireWoods in February 2007,
according to a firm statement last year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Alternative Energy Sources Inc. v. McGuireWoods,
08cv154, U.S. District Court, Western District of Missouri
(Kansas City). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more litigation department news from yesterday, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;On The Docket &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Liberty Dispute With IAC/InterActiveCorp Goes to Trial March 10 &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liberty Media Corp.''s billionaire Chairman John Malone will
face off with IAC/InterActiveCorp (IACI) Chairman Barry Diller in a
battle to control the entertainment company at a trial March 10
before Delaware Chancery Court Judge Stephen Lamb. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Malone opposes Diller''s plan to split IAC into five
companies without maintaining a stock structure that gives
Liberty control. Liberty holds 30 percent of IAC''s shares and 62
percent of its voting power. Liberty claims Diller, who controls
the voting rights of Liberty''s IAC shares through a proxy
agreement, is contractually obligated to vote against the spinoff
proposal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is LMC Silver King Inc. v. IAC/InterActiveCorp, CA
3501, Delaware Chancery Court (Wilmington). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Bloomberg articles by lawyers on litigation topics, click
here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For news about bankruptcy litigation, click here. For news about
intellectual property litigation click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Fabio Alves" date="Mar 14, 2008  4:51 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-03-14/general-motors-microsoft-mylan-talbots-u-s-equity-movers.html"><headline>General Motors, Microsoft, Mylan, Talbots: U.S. Equity Movers</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;The following is a list of companies
whose shares had unusual price changes in U.S. markets. Stock
symbols are in parentheses after company names, and prices are as
of 4 p.m. in New York. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advance America Cash Advance Centers Inc. (AEA US) dropped 16
percent to $5.98, the lowest since December 2004. The provider of
short-term loans to individuals was reduced to ''''equalweight'''' from
''''overweight'''' by analyst Dennis Telzrow at Stephens Inc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allion Healhcare Inc. (ALLI US) fell for the first time in
four days, sinking 3.8 percent to $5.31. The pharmacy operator
signed a definitive agreement to buy Biomed America Inc, which
provides specialized biopharmaceutical medications and services to
chronically ill patients. Melville, New York-based Allion said in a
statement after the market closed yesterday it will pay $117.8
million for Biomed. The price includes $48 million of cash as well
an offering of common and preferred shares. The company will also
assume as much as $18.6 million of Biomed''s debt. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; AnnTaylor Stores Corp. (ANN)  declined the most since Jan.
10, sliding 8.2 percent to $21.95. The clothing retailer geared
toward women 25 to 55 forecast profit of 35 cents to 40 cents a
share in the first quarter. That missed the average estimate of 42
cents, according to a Bloomberg survey of analysts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bear Stearns Cos. (BSC US) had its biggest drop since its
initial public offering in October 1985, falling 47 percent to $30.
The securities firm, to which JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)  and the
New York Federal Reserve agreed to provide funding, said its cash
position has ''''significantly deteriorated.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other financial shares also tumbled. JPMorgan dropped 4.1
percent to $36.54. American Express Co. (AXP)  retreated 4
percent to $40.01. Bank of America Corp. (BAC US) declined 3.9
percent to $35.69. Citigroup Inc. (C US) slipped 6.1 percent to
$19.78. Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. (LEH US) fell 15 percent, the
most since April 2000, to $39.20. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boeing Co. (BA)  had the only gain in the Dow Jones
Industrial Average, climbing 2.7 percent to $76.23. The world''s
second-largest commercial-aircraft maker was raised to
''''overweight'''' from ''''equal weight'''' at Morgan Stanley, which said
the Chicago-based company may win 600 aircraft orders this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Cenveo Inc. (CVO)  dropped the most since May 2003, sliding
16 percent to $11.53. The Stamford, Connecticut-based commercial
printer reported revenue of $584.4 million in the fourth quarter.
That trailed the average estimate of $596.5 million from analysts
in a Bloomberg survey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diodes Inc. (DIOD)  fell 8.3 percent to $20.22, the lowest
since December 2005. The maker of electronic components used in
computers and DVD players lowered its first-quarter revenue
forecast, predicting the slowest growth in six years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DynCorp International Inc. (DCP US) gained the most since
Feb.19, adding 8.8. percent to $16.85. The provider of security
guards in Iraq said it''s resuming work on a $4.6 billion contract
to provide translation services for the U.S. Army after a protest
by losing bidder L-3 Communications Holdings Inc. (LLL US) was
withdrawn. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GameStop Corp. (GME)  gained 4 percent to $49.05, the
biggest advance in the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index. Credit Suisse
Group analyst Gary Balter reiterated his ''''outperform'''' rating for
the world''s largest video-game retailer, saying that he expects a
''''strong'''' first quarter on accelerating software growth. Gamestop,
which is reporting fourth-quarter results on March 18, may say it
earned $1.12 a share, according to Bloomberg estimates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gannett Co. (GCI)  dropped 5.1 percent to $28.43, the lowest
since November 1995. The largest U.S. newspaper company said pro
forma revenue fell 7.2 percent last month as classified advertising
sales declined. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;General Motors Corp. (GM) (GM US) tumbled 5.4 percent to $19.22,
the lowest since April 2006. The world''s biggest automaker is
recalling 208,000 Buick Regal and Pontiac Grand Prix sedans because
of oil leaks that may lead to engine fires, Carolyn Markey, a
spokeswoman for Detroit-based GM, said in an interview today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ICx Technologies Inc. (ICXT US) dropped the most since its
Nov. 7 initial public offering, sliding 30 percent to $4.39. The
developer of technology to detect chemical and explosive materials
was cut to ''''market perform'''' from ''''outperform'''' by analyst Brian W. Ruttenbur at Morgan Keegan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MoneyGram International Inc. (MGI)  slipped 15 percent to
$2, the lowest ever. The money-transfer company''s debt rating was
cut by the Standard  Poor''s. An additional downgrade is possible,
SP said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Corp. (MSFT)  lost the most since Feb. 29,
retreating 2.3 percent to $27.96. The world''s biggest software
maker said it agreed to buy Rapt Inc., which helps clients such as
Expedia Inc. and CNET Networks Inc. place and sell ads and examine
their performance. Microsoft didn''t disclose the terms of the deal
for closely held Rapt, based in San Francisco. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mylan Inc. (MYL)  gained the most since Jan. 9, adding 3.6
percent to $11.07. Citigroup Inc. (C) raised its recommendation on the
largest U.S. maker of generic drugs to ''''buy'''' from ''''hold.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National City Corp. (NCC US) fell 12 percent to $13.15, the
most since January 1984. The largest bank in Ohio had its debt
rating cut by Moody''s Investors Service, which cited the company''s
''''sizable exposure'''' to the U.S. housing market and possible
''''material losses'''' as a result. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NDS Group Plc (NNDS US) gained the most since Feb. 13,
advancing 5.4 percent to $49.30. The company, whose technology
enables access to pay-television services, was raised to ''''buy'''' by
Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and added to the firm''s ''''conviction buy''''
list. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Newcastle Investment Corp. (NCT)  slumped the most since
October 2002, falling 16 percent to $8.86. The New York-based real
estate investment trust cut its dividend by almost two-thirds to 25
cents a share. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security Capital Assurance Ltd. (SCA US) surged the most since
Jan. 23, rising 20 percent to 79 cents. The company, stripped of
its AAA bond insurer ratings, said it''s trying to cancel insurance
it wrote on $3.1 billion of collateralized debt obligations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shire Plc (SHP) American depositary receipts (SHPGY US) climbed 2.9
percent to $58.96, the biggest gain since Feb.22. The U.K.''s third-largest drugmaker climbed on speculation it''s the target of a 1,300
pence-a-share bid by Pfizer Inc., the world''s biggest
pharmaceutical company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SkillSoft Plc (SKIL US) rose the most since Nov. 26, climbing
13 percent to $9.84. The maker of employee training software
forecast full-year revenue of $328 million to $336 million. Five
analysts estimated $319.6 million, on average, in a Bloomberg
survey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talbots Inc. (TLB US) advanced to the highest since Jan. 3,
rising 8.3 percent to $9.93. The women''s clothing store chain named
Lori Wagner as executive vice president and chief marketing
officer, in a statement today. Wagner joined Talbot from Cole Haan,
a division of Nike Inc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Universal Display Corp. (OLED)  lost 12 percent to $14.83,
the lowest since Sept. 7. The developer of technologies used in
flat-panels reported fourth-quarter loss of 9 cents a share,
trailing analysts'' estimates by 25 percent, according to Bloomberg
data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Washington Mutual Inc. (WM)  fell the most since Nov. 7,
losing 13 percent to $10.59. The largest U.S. savings and loan had
its senior unsecured credit rating cut to Baa3 from Baa2 by Moody''s
Investors Service because of the weakening housing market. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zumiez Inc. (ZUMZ)  gained the most since Feb. 7, adding 8.1
percent to $15.24. The specialty sports apparel and accessories
retailer said it earned 42 cents a share in the fourth quarter.
That beat the 38-cent average estimate from analysts in a Bloomberg
survey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Elizabeth Stanton" date="Mar 19, 2008  4:59 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-03-19/alcoa-bear-stearns-exxon-mobil-lehman-u-s-equity-movers.html"><headline>Alcoa, Bear Stearns, Exxon Mobil, Lehman: U.S. Equity Movers</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;The following is a list of companies
whose shares had unusual price changes in U.S. markets. Stock
symbols are in parentheses after company names, and prices are as
of 4 p.m. in New York. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commodity producers fell the most of any group in the SP 500,
as gold, silver, copper and aluminum prices tumbled. Gold for April
delivery fell 5.9 percent from a record $1,004.30 an ounce to
$945.30. Silver for May delivery fell 7.6 percent to $18.44 an
ounce. Copper for May delivery fell 3 percent to $3.63 a pound.
Alumimum fell 2.5 percent to $2,920 a ton. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Freeport-McMoRan Copper  Gold Inc. (FCX)  had its biggest
drop since October 2002, sliding 11 percent to $87.60. Barrick Gold
Corp. (ABX)  declined 8.8 percent to $45.25. Goldcorp Inc. (GG)  lost 6.3 percent to $38.71. Alcoa Inc. (AA)  fell 7.7
percent, the most in the Dow Jones Industrial Average, to $35.62. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM)  and ConocoPhillips (COP)  led a
decline in energy shares as crude oil and natural gas prices
tumbled. Exxon Mobil fell 4.6 percent to $84.43, the biggest drop
since Aug. 9. ConocoPhillips slid 6 percent to $73.61. Crude oil
for May delivery fell 4.5 percent to $104.48 a barrel. Natural gas
for April delivery fell 4.1 percent to $9.03 per 1 million British
thermal units. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3Com Corp. (COMS US) fell 22 percent to $2.22, the lowest
since June 1994. The maker of network equipment said it hasn''t yet
come to an agreement on reviving a $2.2 billion takeover by Bain
Capital Partners LLC. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adobe Systems Inc. (ADBE)  rose the most since September
2006, gaining 9 percent to $34.75. The biggest maker of design
software said first-quarter profit climbed 53 percent as more
customers bought the latest version of its Creative Suite programs.
Excluding costs such as stock-based compensation, profit was 48
cents a share, beating the 45-cent average analyst estimate in a
Bloomberg survey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Amerigroup Corp. (AGP US) fell the most since September 2005,
declining 17 percent to $26.59. The provider of managed health care
for low-income Americans reduced its profit forecast for 2008,
saying earnings will probably be as much as $2.61 a share. The
company earlier predicted as much as $2.73. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bear Stearns Cos. (BSC US) dropped for the fifth time in six
days, shedding 9.8 percent to $5.33. Bear agreed to sell itself for
$2 a share after customer withdrawals depleted its capital. Efforts
to secure a rival bid are likely to fail, a report by RiskMetrics
Group Inc. said. The firm advises investors on proxy votes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capital Corp of the West (CCOW US) slumped the most since
April 1994, falling 65 percent to $3.76. The owner of County Bank,
in California''s Central Valley, delayed filing its annual report
because of a ''''rapid decline'''' in real estate values in the area it
serves. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Centene Corp. (CNC)  fell 22 percent, the most since July
2006, to $13.86. The provider of managed care said it may not meet
its earnings forecast for the quarter because of costs related to
the worst flu season in 10 years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charming Shoppes Inc. (CHRS US) fell 12 percent to $4.65, the
lowest since Jan. 16. The owner of the Lane Bryant and Fashion Bug
clothing chains forecast first-quarter sales of $720 million to
$730 million. Soleil Securities analyst Jeffery Stein estimated
sales of $780.6 million. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clear Channel Communications Inc. (CCU)  dropped the most
since August 2002, losing 8.9 percent to $33.03. The radio
company''s buyout by Thomas H. Lee Partners LP and Bain Capital LLC
isn''t likely to close this week, CNBC reported, citing people close
to the buyout group. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company has said it expects the deal to close during the
first quarter. It doesn''t plan to comment on the CNBC report,
spokeswoman Michele Clarke said in an e-mail. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Darden Restaurants Inc. (DRI)  gained the most since Feb.
11, adding 6.6 percent to $31.83. The owner of restaurant chains
such as Red Lobster reported third-quarter profit that exceeded
analysts'' estimates on a sales boost from acquisitions and its
Olive Garden locations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deutsche Telekom AG (DTE) American depositary receipts (DT US)
dropped 9.6 percent, the most since July 2002, to $16.28. Europe''s
largest telephone company said the decline in sales and earnings at
its combined Internet and fixed-line unit in Germany will slow this
year from 2007 as it slashes costs and adds customers for Web
services and bundled phone, Internet and television packages. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discover Financial Services (DFS)  fell 15 percent to
$15.20, its steepest decline to date. The credit-card company
that''s lost more than a third of its market value since being spun
off by Morgan Stanley in June said profit fell 65 percent on
charges tied to selling a U.K. unit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ericsson AB (ERIC) ADRs fell 10 percent, the most since
Nov. 20, to $17.39. The company''s handset unit, Sony Ericsson
Mobile Communications Ltd., said first-quarter earnings and revenue
will fall on slower handset sales, higher research costs and a
component shortage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nokia Oyj (NOK) ADRs lost 10 percent to $29.33. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fannie Mae (FNM US) gained 8.8 percent to $30.71, the highest
since Feb. 13. The world''s largest mortgage company and smaller
rival Freddie Mac (FRE US) had their surplus capital requirement
eased by regulators to 20 percent from 30 percent, to help expand
their combined $1.5 trillion in mortgage investments and revive the
home-loan market. Freddie Mac jumped 15 percent to $29.90. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internap Network Services Corp. (INAP)  fell the most since
March 2001, sliding 33 percent to $4.09. The provider of Internet
management and distribution services fell after it said it would
delay filing its yearend report and a Merriman Curhan Ford  Co.
analyst cut his rating of the stock. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. (LEH US) fell for a third time
in four days, dropping 9.2 percent to $42.23. Sanford C. Bernstein
 Co. analyst Brad Hintz said the fourth-biggest U.S. securities
firm''s first-quarter earnings release yesterday revealed $87
billion in ''''troubled'''' mortgage-related assets that will probably
cause more losses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lindsay Corp. (LNN)  gained 18 percent to $87.46, the
highest since October 1988. The maker of GrowSmart irrigation
equipment said second-quarter earnings more than tripled on demand
from farmers overseas and acquisitions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merrill Lynch  Co. (MER US) fell the most since September
2001, dropping 11 percent, to $41.45. The world''s largest brokerage
sued XL Capital Assurance Inc. over default protection on $3
billion on collateralized debt obligations that the bond-insurance
unit of Security Capital Assurance Ltd. is seeking to void. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monsanto Co. (MON)  fell 12 percent, the most since March
2003, to $98.87. The world''s biggest seed producer and French
farmers lost a bid to have France''s highest court overturn a ban on
genetically modified corn. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monster Worldwide Inc. (MNST)  fell the most in 11 months,
losing 9.4 percent to $22.28. The largest online provider of job
listings said first-quarter costs may exceed analysts'' average
estimates because of extra spending on marketing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morgan Stanley (MS)  rose 1.4 percent to $43.45, the highest
since Feb. 28. The second-biggest U.S. securities firm said first-quarter net income dropped to $1.55 billion, or $1.45 a share, from
$2.67 billion, or $2.51, a year earlier. Earnings fell 42 percent
less than analysts estimated, according to a Bloomberg survey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SI International Inc. (SINT US) had its biggest decline since
November 2002, dropping 20 percent to $19.54. The provider of
computer services to the federal government cut its first-quarter
earnings-per-share forecast to between 24 and 27 cents because of
''''unexpected'''' funding delays. The average analyst estimate,
according to a survey by Bloomberg, was 33 cents a share. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thornburg Mortgage Inc. (TMA US) dropped the most since March
10, sliding 50 percent to $1.50. The ''''jumbo'''' mortgage specialist
struggling to meet margin calls said it suspended its dividend as
part of an agreement with five lenders to freeze demands for more
collateral through March 2009. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Visa Inc. (V)  jumped 28 percent to $56.50 on the first day
of trading. The largest payment-card network set a record for U.S.
initial public offerings yesterday by raising $17.9 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;National City Corp. (NCC US) advanced 8.7 percent to $9.48.
Ohio''s largest bank said it expects a $450 million benefit from
selling part of its stake in Visa. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Andrea Rothman" date="Mar 19, 2008  4:33 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-03-19/boeing-787-delivery-may-slip-again-jpmorgan-says-update3-.html"><headline>Boeing 787 Delivery May Slip Again, JPMorgan Says</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Boeing Co. (BA) has to make design
changes to its 787 Dreamliner that may further delay the plane''s
entry into service, JPMorgan said, citing International Lease
Finance Corp., the new model''s biggest customer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ILFC Chairman Steven Udvar-Hazy told a JPMorgan conference
yesterday that the state of the 787 program is ''''not pretty'''' and
that he doesn''t expect the first plane to be handed over until
the third quarter of next year, Joseph B. Nadol, an analyst at
the bank, wrote in a note to investors. Boeing, the world''s
second-biggest commercial aircraft maker, has said the Dreamliner
will be ready ''''early'''' in 2009. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dreamliner, originally due for first delivery this May,
has already been twice delayed by parts shortages. One main
reason for another likely delay, Udvar-Hazy told investors, is
Boeing needs to make structural design changes to the center wing
box, Nadol wrote. ILFC has ordered 74 Dreamliners, making it the
biggest buyer for Chicago-based Boeing''s fastest-selling plane. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''Boeing''s made two projections so far that turned out to be
wrong,'''' said Hans Weber, chief executive of Tecop International,
a San Diego-based consulting company. ''''If a further projection
turns out to be wrong too, then in the sense that it''s three
strikes and you''re out, that would be detrimental and really hurt
their credibility.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boeing will give an update including timing once an
assessment of the 787 schedule is complete, expected sometime
around the end of this quarter, said Yvonne Leach, a spokeswoman
in Seattle. The assessment includes some parts redesign,
including the wing box, ''''common'''' for any new plane, she said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;`Complete Picture'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''We continue to do the work on our assessment,'''' Leach
said. In the briefing, Boeing will provide ''''a complete picture
of what''s happening.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Udvar-Hazy was traveling today and unavailable for comment,
his assistant said. The Los Angeles-based company is owned by
American International Group Inc. (AIG), the world''s largest insurer by
assets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''The changes will require retrofits of the first several
787s produced,'''' JPMorgan''s Nadol wrote in the note, meaning that
Boeing will have to go back and rebuild parts of the planes
already assembled. The wing box is a section inside the fuselage
where the two wings are joined. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nadol cut his 2009 delivery forecast for the twin-aisle,
long-haul jetliner to 30 planes from 60 and reduced his earnings
estimate for the year by 30 cents to $6.85 a share. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Program Margins &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''We are mainly concerned with two issues,'''' Nadol wrote.
''''The certification timeline is still uncertain, as the first
plane has yet to fly, and the large number of 787s sold at low
prices, combined with rising recurring costs, are steadily eating
away at program margins and long-term program profitability.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boeing fell $3.08, or 4 percent, to $73.45 at 4:15 p.m. in
New York Stock Exchange composite trading, the biggest drop since
Jan. 15. The shares have declined 19 percent this year. Airbus
SAS is the world''s biggest commercial-aircraft maker. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boeing''s last specific delivery forecast for 2009 was 109
planes. Boeing''s chief executive for commercial aircraft, Scott Carson, said Jan. 16 that the planemaker would no longer be able
to make that number and hasn''t given a new figure. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analyst Richard Safran of Goldman Sachs Group Inc. on March
7 predicted that the initial powering up of the 787, scheduled
for the end of March, may be delayed until the end of June, which
would push back the first flight, and also deliveries, which may
not start until the third quarter of 2009. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Pierre Paulden" date="Mar 19, 2008  4:20 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-03-19/goldman-lehman-reduce-loan-backlog-with-discounts-update2-.html"><headline>Goldman, Lehman Reduce Loan Backlog With Discounts</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;U.S. banks from Goldman Sachs (GS) Group
Inc. to Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. have whittled their
holdings of leveraged buyout loans to $129 billion from $163
billion at the beginning of the year by offering the debt at
discounts, according to analysts at Bank of America Corp. (BAC) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decline is a ''''ray of hope'''' for banks amid a slump in
credit markets and a slowing economy, said analysts led by
Jeffrey Rosenberg. The firms also have $73.6 billion of high-yield bonds they need to sell, they said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banks have been breaking ranks from their lending groups and
offering their own pieces of the LBO loans at as little as 80
cents on the dollar to get the debt off their books. New York-based Lehman yesterday said it has reduced its LBO backlog by
$6.1 billion to $17.8 billion since the beginning of the year.
Goldman Sachs halved its holdings to $20 billion and Morgan
Stanley (MS) reduced its pipeline by 20 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The buyout industry, including Blackstone Group (BX), Apollo
Management LP and Kohlberg, Kravis Roberts  Co. (KKR), all based in
New York, negotiated more than $370 billion in financing to back
acquisitions such as the $32 billion purchase of Texas power
producer TXU Corp. and the $46.8 billion sale of Canadian
telecommunications company BCE Inc. (BCE) to an investor group led by
the Ontario Teachers Pension Plan, the largest buyout ever. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Plunging Demand &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investor demand for the debt plummeted in July as losses on
U.S. subprime securities spread to other asset classes. The
average price of a leveraged loan fell from par to a record low
of 86.28 last month, according to Standard  Poor''s data. Prices
have since climbed to 87.32 cents on the dollar. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banks began tackling the backlog in September, when lenders
for KKR sold $9.4 billion of loans at a discount of up to 4
percent for its takeover of Greenwood Village, Colorado-based
First Data Corp., the biggest processor of credit card payments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman, the world''s biggest securities firm by market
value, is selling its portion of Chrysler LLC''s $7 billion in
loans for as little as 72 cents on the dollar, said investors,
who declined to be identified because the terms are private.
Goldman spokesman Michael DuVally declined to comment on
individual sales. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cerberus Capital Management LP bought Chrysler Group LLC
last August. Bankers for the Auburn Hills, Michigan-based
automaker twice failed to sell the Chrysler loans. JPMorgan Chase
 Co. (JPM), Citigroup, Morgan Stanley, Bear Stearns Cos. and Goldman,
all of New York, tried in November to sell $4 billion of the
loans at 97.5 cents on the dollar. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The loan is priced at 400 basis points more than the three-month London interbank offered rate, or Libor (US0003M), a borrowing
benchmark. Three-month Libor is 2.6 percent. A basis point is
0.01 percentage point. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Backlogs Reduced &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman reduced its backlog of loans by $20 billion in the
past quarter from $43 billion, chief financial officer David Viniar said on an investor call yesterday. The New York-based
firm, which booked a loss of $1 billion on the loans, also added
$4 billion of new commitments during the period. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lehman, the fourth-biggest U.S. securities firm, booked
losses of $500 million on leveraged loans last quarter, CFO Erin Callan said on a conference call with investors yesterday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morgan Stanley, the second-biggest U.S. securities firm,
reduced its leveraged finance pipeline to $16 billion from $20
billion during the first quarter, CFO Colm Kelleher said in an
interview today after the company reported first-quarter profit
fell 42 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Royal Bank of Scotland Group Plc, Morgan Stanley and Credit
Suisse Group have each sought buyers for their portion of Clear
Channel Communications Inc.''s $22 billion buyout financing, said
people with knowledge of the situation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;LBO Buyers &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the same LBO firms that generated the debt in the
first place are raising funds to buy it back at reduced prices.
Blackstone raised a $1.4 billion fund last November to buy bank
loans, and Leon Black''s Apollo  has bought $1 billion of
distressed loans and bonds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''The leveraged loan forward calendar continues to
decline,'''' Rosenberg wrote in the report on March 17. ''''The
ongoing raising of distressed debt funds,'''' including Apollo''s,
''''appears to support these efforts.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the buyout firms, traditional loan investors
and hedge funds are also buying the debt. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dallas-based Highland Capital Management LP has raised $1
billion in the past four months from pension funds and sovereign
wealth funds, to invest in debt, including bank loans, according
to Mark Okada, co-founder and chief investment officer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''We are more willing to participate in new issues at these
distressed prices,'''' said Scott D''Orsi, a partner at Boston-based
Feingold O''Keeffe Capital, which has $1.25 billion in assets.
''''It''s been a waiting game between the buy side and the banks
over the past several months, with pricing moving in favor of
investors.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Michael Quint" date="Mar 24, 2008  9:40 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-03-24/goldman-citi-get-fees-for-failed-auction-rate-bonds-update1-.html"><headline>Goldman, Citi Get Fees for Failed Auction-Rate Bonds</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;New York paid 10 securities firms
more than $600,000 since mid-February to handle bids for
auction-bonds even though the sales failed, saddling the state
with penalty interest rates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citigroup Inc. (C), Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and eight more
firms receive $10 million a year to oversee periodic bidding
that sets rates on about $4 billion of auction bonds. When there
aren''t enough buyers, the yields rise. A total of 188 of the
state''s 201 auctions since Feb. 12 have failed, according to
data supplied by the state. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''We are contractually obligated to pay these fees
regardless of whether the auction fails, and we will fulfill our
commitment,'''' Matt Anderson, a spokesman for New York''s Division
of Budget said in an e-mailed statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;State and local governments pay almost $8 million a week in
fees to banks for auctions-rate bonds, based on standard fees.
About two-thirds of auctions in the $330 billion market have
failed since mid-February, including periodic sales of preferred
stock for closed-end bond funds, Bloomberg data show. Securities
firms are receiving the same fee even when investors who wanted
to sell are unable to do so because bankers haven''t found enough
bidders. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;`Systemic Problems'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banks covered shortfalls in demand at auctions in the $330
billion market buy purchasing bonds for their own account, even
though they weren''t obliged to. They didn''t tell investors or
issuers about the extent of the activity, which was one of the
practices cited by the Securities and Exchange Commission in
2006 when it fined 15 banks a total of $13 million for bid-rigging. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New York isn''t trying to renegotiate the contracts with the
10 broker-dealers it uses for auction bonds, Anderson said. The
firms also include Bank of America Corp., Wachovia Corp., UBS
AG, JPMorgan Chase  Co., Merrill Lynch  Co., Bear Stearns Cos.
Morgan Stanley and Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''These failed auctions were not caused by these banks, but
by systemic problems within this market beyond their control,''''
he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A spokeswoman for New York-based Citigroup, Danielle Romero-Apsilos, declined to comment, as did Michael DuVally, a
spokesman for New York-based Goldman. Citigroup was the biggest
underwriter of auction-rate debt from 2000 to 2007, according to
Thomson Financial. Goldman is the most profitable investment
bank. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Higher Rates &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When there aren''t enough bidders in auctions that typically
take place every seven, 28 or 35 days, rates get set by formulas
spelled out when the debt is issued. In New York, the penalty
rates ranged from 3.59 percent to 5.64 percent in the week ended
March 14. That compares with yields on the variable-rate demand
bonds, an alternative to auction-rate notes, that were less than
3 percent for 27 of 43 issues, according to state data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seven-day auction rates averaged 4.36 percent on March 19
for borrowers in New York, New Jersey, California and
Massachusetts, up from 3.47 percent on Feb. 6, the last week
before New York auctions began failing, according to index data
published by the Securities Industry and Financial Markets
Association. The rate peaked at 5.98 percent March 5. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the failures, auction-rate bonds were a way to sell
long-term bonds at money market rates. They were the least
expensive kind of borrowing for New York until demand began to
weaken in September, according to a state report. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bank Contracts &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anderson said copies of the contracts with banks handling
the auction bonds weren''t available. Anderson and Ronald
Greenberg, a first deputy director of the budget, said state
officials are in daily contact with bankers about auction bonds.
He declined to respond to questions about the shortage of
bidders since Feb. 12. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''Contracts for handling auctions are written by broker
dealers and presented to issuers as part of a negotiated
transaction,'''' said Joseph Fichera, chief executive officer of
Saber Partners, a New York based adviser to companies and
governments. ''''They can be terminated or renegotiated, like any
contract.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fichera, a financial adviser to the New York State
Dormitory Authority, declined to comment on the state''s bonds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is precedent for broker-dealer agreements that don''t
pay banks a fee when auctions fail. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After auctions failed to attract enough bidders in 1990 for
bonds of Tucson Electric Power Co., now a unit of Unisource
Energy Corp. (UNS), Fichera arranged a new contract that rewarded
bankers with a higher fee for selling bonds that resulted in a
lower auction rate, and no fee if bonds sold at the highest
permitted rate. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Lu Wang" date="Mar 26, 2008  4:43 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-03-26/ameron-bj-halliburton-jp-morgan-rambus-u-s-equity-movers.html"><headline>Ameron, BJ, Halliburton, JP Morgan, Rambus: U.S. Equity Movers</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;The following is a list of companies
whose shares had unusual price changes in U.S. markets. Stock
symbols are in parentheses after company names, and prices are as
of 4 p.m. in New York. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Airlines fell after crude oil rose by more than $4 a barrel in
New York, signaling increased costs. AMR Corp. (AMR US) declined 10
percent to $8.62. Continental Airlines Inc. (CAL US) retreated 8.9
percent to $19.29. Delta Air Lines Inc. (DAL)  slipped 12 percent
to $8.74. ExpressJet Holdings Inc. (XJT US) slumped 7.2 percent to
$2.57. Northwest Airlines Corp. (NWA US) dropped 8.4 percent to
$9.20. UAL Corp. (UAUA US) lost 8.9 percent to $21.99. US Airways
Group Inc. (LCC US) decreased 6.7 percent to $8.51. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Financial shares dropped after Oppenheimer  Co. analyst
Meredith Whitney slashed earnings estimates for ''''large cap'''' U.S.
banks, cutting her first quarter, 2008 and 2009 projections for the
group by an average of 84 percent. The analyst said Citigroup Inc. (C)
, the biggest U.S. bank by assets, may post a $1.15-a-share
loss in the first quarter and a 15 cent loss this year. Citigroup
fell 5.9 percent to $22.05. Bank of America Corp. (BAC US), the
second-biggest U.S. bank by assets, slid 2.8 percent to $39.84.
Wells Fargo  Co. (WFC)  declined 3.9 percent to $30.81. Wachovia
Corp. (WB)  lost 6.7 percent to $28.02. JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM
US) slipped 4.2 percent to $44.11. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Ameron International Corp. (AMN US) had the steepest drop
since at least 1980, losing 25 percent to $91.49. The maker of
steel and concrete pipes reported first-quarter per-share profit
that missed the average analyst estimate by 17 percent, according
to Bloomberg data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apache Corp. (APA)  had the biggest gain in the Standard 
Poor''s 500 Index, rising 6 percent to $119.75. The oil and natural-gas producer was boosted to ''''outperform'''' from ''''market perform''''
by analyst Benjamin Dell at Sanford C. Bernstein  Co. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Energy stocks rallied the most in a week after oil prices rose
5 percent to $106.27 a barrel. XTO Energy Inc. (XTO US) rose 2.3
percent to $62.27 and EnCana Corp. (ECA)  increased 2.2 percent
to 75.60, after they were upgraded at Sanford C. Bernstein. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BJ Services Co. (BJS US) rose 5.11 percent to $27.78.
Schlumberger Ltd. (SLB)  gained 4.7 percent to $86.52. Devon
Energy Corp. (DVN) added 4.5 percent to $107.59. Halliburton Co. (HAL) 
jumped 4.1 percent to $38.97. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Charlotte Russe Holding Inc. (CHIC US) dropped the most since
July 26, dropping 13 percent to $17.42. The clothing retailer
targeting women in their teens and 20s forecast profit of as much
as 30 cents a share in the fiscal third quarter. That trailed the
40-cent average estimate from analysts in a Bloomberg survey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cia. Vale do Rio Doce American depositary receipts (RIO US)
rose 5 percent to $34.68, the highest since March 5. The world''s
biggest iron-ore producer said yesterday negotiations to take over
Xstrata Plc broke down because of demands by that company''s biggest
shareholder, Glencore International AG. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clear Channel Communications Inc. (CCU)  dropped 17 percent,
the most since June 1989, to $26.92. The company''s planned private-equity buyout is close to falling apart, the Wall Street Journal
reported, citing people it didn''t name who are familiar with the
matter. Clear Channel isn''t commenting, spokeswoman Michele Clarke
said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comerica Inc. (CMA)  fell a third day, sliding 4.8 percent
to $37.30. The Dallas-based lender was added to Goldman Sachs Group
Inc.''s ''''conviction sell'''' list. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Consol Energy Inc. (CNX)  gained 3.4 percent to $70.59, the
highest since March 13. The third-largest U.S. coal producer was
raised to ''''buy'''' from ''''neutral'''' by Goldman Sachs Group Inc.,
which cited higher prices for coal used in steelmaking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analyst Michael Molnar also upgraded Alpha Natural Resources
Inc. (ANR) . The stock climbed 7.78 percent to $42.34. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Cooper Tire  Rubber Co. (CTB)  fell the most since Nov. 7,
declining 10 percent to $15.50. The second-largest U.S. tiremaker
was cut to ''''hold'''' from ''''aggressive buy'''' by analyst Saul Ludwig
at KeyBanc Capital Markets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Corus Bankshares Inc. (CORS US) declined for the first time in
four days, dropping 3.8 percent to $11.20. The Chicago-based bank
specializing in condominium construction faces difficulties in
coming months because the condo market may decline, the Wall Street
Journal reported. Eighty-three percent of the bank''s loans were in
cities such as Miami, Las Vegas and Atlanta that now face housing
gluts, the newspaper said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jabil Circuit Inc. (JBL)  fell 18 percent to $9.29, the
lowest since October 1998. The maker of phones and electronics for
other companies said that, excluding some items, it expects to earn
as much as 22 cents a share in the third quarter. Analysts, on
average, anticipated profit of 34 cents, according to a Bloomberg
survey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Motorola Inc. (MOT US) gained for a third day, adding 2.7
percent to $10.02. The biggest U.S. mobile-phone maker plans to
split into two independent publicly traded companies. One company
will focus on handsets and the other will sell broadband networking
devices, Motorola said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rambus Inc. (RMBS)  jumped 39 percent, the most since
January 2003, to $25.86. The designer of chips for Sony Corp.''s
PlayStation video-game console won the final  phase of its patent
suit against Hynix Semiconductor Inc., the first step toward
collecting royalties from other manufacturers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waters Corp. (WAT)  gained the most since Feb. 1, adding 4.7
percent to $56.19. The supplier of products for use in chemical
testing was raised to ''''overweight'''' from ''''neutral'''' by JPMorgan
Chase  Co. (JPM) analyst Tycho Peterson. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By William Freebairn" date="Apr 03, 2008  4:45 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-04-03/televisa-films-chinese-version-of-colombian-tv-show-update1-.html"><headline>Televisa Films Chinese Version of Colombian TV Show</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Grupo Televisa SAB (TLEVICPO), the largest
Spanish-language broadcaster, began filming a Chinese version of
Latin American soap opera ''''La Fea Mas Bella.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The show is being produced in China and will air on Hunan
Satellite television starting in September, Mexico City-based
Televisa said in a statement today. The project, being made in
partnership with Hunan, Colombia''s RCN Television and China''s
Nesound, will cost $20 million, Televisa said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Televisa is expanding production of its ''''telenovelas''''
outside Latin America in a bid to export its dominance in soap
operas. The Chinese soap opera is based on ''''Betty la Fea,'''' a
Colombian program re-made in Mexico last year and airing in the
U.S. as ''''Ugly Betty'''' on Walt Disney Co. (DIS)''s ABC network. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The production is the first of several planned for China,
Televisa Vice President Jose Baston said in the statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chinese version will have 400 half-hour episodes, the
same as the Mexican program, the company said. Hunan Satellite
reaches almost 900 million viewers, the statement said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Televisa has an estimated 70 percent market share of
viewers in Mexico, according to its October quarterly earnings
statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Televisa shares fell 1.8 percent to 52.25 pesos in Mexico
City trading. The shares are little changed this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Joe Carroll" date="Apr 03, 2008  4:42 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-04-03/druckenmiller-bets-on-revival-of-failed-exxon-well-update4-.html"><headline>Druckenmiller Bets on Revival of Failed Exxon Well</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;McMoRan Exploration Co. (MMR) and an
energy firm backed by hedge fund managers Stanley Druckenmiller
and Lief Rosenblatt resumed drilling a Gulf of Mexico well
abandoned last year by Exxon Mobil (XOM) Corp. after a failed bid to
bore the world''s deepest well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Orleans-based McMoRan plans to extend the Blackbeard
West well to 31,267 feet (9,530 meters), 1,200 feet beyond the
depth reached by Exxon Mobil, the company said today in a
statement. Exxon Mobil, the world''s biggest energy company,
halted the project in August 2006 and handed control to McMoRan
a year later. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McMoRan, under pressure to drill at Blackbeard before
federal leases that cover the prospect expire in about five
months, received $5.5 million from Energy XXI (Bermuda) Ltd.
for rights to participate in the re-entry of the well, the
statement said. Unless the company took steps to resume work,
it may not have been allowed to extend the leases. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hamilton, Bermuda-based Enegry XXI''s biggest investors are
Satellite Asset Management LP, a hedge fund founded by former
Soros Fund Management managing directors Rosenblatt, Gabriel Nechamkin and Mark Sonnino, and Druckenmiller''s Pittsburgh-
based Duquesne Capital Management LLC. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Houston-based Plains Exploration  Production Co. paid
$9.7 million for similar participation rights, the statement
said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Chevron Record &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If McMoRan reaches its target depth at Blackbeard, it will
break the Gulf of Mexico depth record set by Chevron Corp. (CVX)
three years ago at the 30,589-foot Knotty Head well. The
deepest well ever drilled anywhere in the world was the Bertha
Rogers in Oklahoma which got to 31,441 feet in 1974. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McMoRan rose 18 cents, or 1 percent, to $19.16 in New York
Stock Exchange composite trading. The shares increased almost
46 percent this year. Plains climbed 3.5 percent to $56.50. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rowan Cos.'' Gorilla IV rig began drilling on March 18
through cement used to plug the well at 26,650 feet when Exxon
Mobil quit the project, the statement said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Energy companies are expanding the search for natural gas
to more remote regions and subterranean depths unreachable with
the technology that existed a decade ago as demand rises faster
than new production. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;U.S. consumption of the fuel is expected to increase by
2.1 percent during the next 10 years, outpacing an estimated
1.8 percent rise in domestic output, according to the Energy
Department in Washington. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Rising Demand &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gas futures traded in New York used as benchmarks for U.S.
wholesale prices rose 30 percent this year after a 19 percent
increase in 2007. Gas has risen fivefold since the 1990s amid
soaring demand from electricity generators for an alternative
to coal, which creates more greenhouse gases. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gas is the most widely used U.S. furnace fuel and the
third-biggest source of electricity behind coal and nuclear,
Energy Department figures showed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Irving, Texas-based Exxon Mobil and its partners on
Blackbeard spent as much as $200 million on the unsuccessful
well, according to JP Morgan Securities Inc. estimates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exxon Mobil failed to reach its target of 32,000 feet
before it halted drilling at Blackbeard. The well terminated at
30,067 feet below the sea floor after pipes and drill bits
encountered more pressure and heat than they could bear. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Testing Limits &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The well was intended to test the limits of drilling
technology by delving into natural-gas deposits locked within
rock formations where temperatures can reach 600 degrees
Fahrenheit (316 Celsius). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company''s engineers spent 12 months evaluating
Blackbeard data before the project was abandoned. McMoRan
acquired control of Blackbeard in August as part of its $1.08
billion purchase of 124 oil and gas properties from Newfield
Exploration Co. (NFX), one of Exxon Mobil''s partners in the field. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McMoRan has a market value of about $1 billion, compared
with Exxon Mobil''s world-leading $474 billion valuation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry></news>