<?xml version='1.0' encoding='us-ascii'?>
<news><entry author="By David Reilly" date="Dec 10, 2009  9:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-12-10/bonus-bashers-shouldn-t-stop-at-goldman-sachs-david-reilly.html"><headline>Bonus Bashers Shouldn&#8217;t Stop at Goldman Sachs: David Reilly</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Bonuses are in the firing line
again, with the U.K., U.S., France and even Goldman Sachs Group
Inc. looking to trim banker pay. While the debate over excessive
compensation started on Wall Street, it shouldn&#8217;t end there. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bonuses, lavish benefits and perks subsidized by taxpayers
aren&#8217;t the sole preserve of bankers. You only need look in your
own backyard for examples of excessive compensation that may
contribute to future crises, just as skewed rewards on Wall
Street fueled the current one. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#8217;s what I discovered reading a New Jersey Commission of
Investigation report issued this month on wasteful compensation
in local governments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were plenty of sweet deals that the vast majority of
bank workers -- who don&#8217;t get seven-figure compensation -- might
be happy to land. These range from $200,000-plus payouts for
unused days to paid time-off to go Christmas shopping. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the report put it, &#8220;Startling amounts of taxpayer-
funded booty continue to be dispensed across New Jersey without
regard for the common good.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, I hear you say, anything lavished on public workers
can&#8217;t come close to Wall Street excess. True, no government
workers land the kind of $67.9 million bonus that Goldman Chief
Executive Officer Lloyd Blankfein got for 2007. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then again, most folks on Wall Street or in big banks will
never see that kind of bonanza either. The vast majority toiling
on Wall Street and in big banks are worker bees who receive
good, but not astronomical, pay. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;$1 Million Club &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consider that in 2008, eight of the country&#8217;s biggest
financial institutions paid 4,311 individuals more than $1
million in bonuses, according to a report by New York State
Attorney General Andrew Cuomo. Yet they represent just 0.3
percent of the 1.27 million workers at those firms. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even if they&#8217;re not in the ranks of top earners, many
bank workers face the threat of getting swept up in the populist
outrage over banker pay. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.K. said earlier this week that it would impose a 50
percent tax on discretionary payments to bank workers of more
than $40,000. (The tax will be paid by the institution, not the
employee.) France may follow suit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That sets a pretty low bar for who gets caught up in the
bonus dragnet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. isn&#8217;t likely to go that far, although the
clampdown by pay czar Kenneth Feinberg has prodded banks such as
Bank of America Corp. and Citigroup Inc. to try and pay back
their Troubled Asset Relief Program funds as quickly as
possible. Even Goldman said Thursday that 30 top executives
won&#8217;t receive cash bonuses for 2009, although they will receive
pay in restricted stock. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Less Stress, Too &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Local government jobs with lucrative payouts don&#8217;t draw
this kind of heat. They also don&#8217;t involve 70-hour weeks and the
never-ending pressure of trying to churn out profit. There is
also less chance of being downsized. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn&#8217;t to say there aren&#8217;t plenty of examples of
outrageous, and egregious, pay practices on Wall Street. Or that
misguided banker incentives didn&#8217;t help foment the financial
crisis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, bloated compensation among state and local
government workers also poses an economic threat. You only have
to look at California&#8217;s budget travails or at Illinois, whose
bonds this week were downgraded by Moody&#8217;s Investors Service and
Standard  Poor&#8217;s, to see that state and local government
finances are in tatters. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More Bailouts &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excessive pay, along with massive pension and retiree
health-care obligations, is a big reason. The danger is that the
federal government eventually may be called to bail out shredded
state-and local-government finances. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While that possibility may seem remote, it was a real worry
earlier this year when California was forced to start paying
some bills with IOUs. If the federal government ever had to ride
to the rescue, the dollar would get walloped, Treasuries would
tumble and any incipient economic recovery may get nipped in the
bud. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The alternative is that struggling consumers will have to
pay for deficit-ridden state and local governments through
higher taxes, increased fees and service cutbacks. That doesn&#8217;t
bode well for economic growth either. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The New Jersey report on local government pay waste
provides a window onto the wider problem. Some examples: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public Service &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- From 2004 to 2008, 160 retiring Atlantic City police
officers and firefighters were paid more than $13.7 million for
unused sick leave. One &#8220;walked away with a check for
$222,910.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- Camden, one of New Jersey&#8217;s poorest cities, paid a
retiring police chief and deputy police chief a combined
$477,000 for accrued sick and vacation time and other benefits.
The city also makes severance payments to any employee who
leaves the city&#8217;s payroll -- &#8220;essentially no-strings-attached
departure bonuses.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- In 2006 and 2008, five employees of Englewood Cliffs
received a combined $1.2 million in lump-sum cash benefits at
retirement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;-- In Union City, municipal employees get a paid day off
for Christmas shopping. Hoboken police officers can get as many
as five days off a year for donating blood. And in Parsippany-
Troy Hills, police officers get eight days for their wedding and
civilian employees get three. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the commission examined only 75 municipal agencies,
it found &#8220;more than $39 million worth of excessive cash benefit
payouts.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looked at in terms of all of New Jersey, &#8220;action to
curtail such extravagance would result in enormous savings --
especially given the fact that, in addition to state aid, nearly
$40 billion is spent by local taxpayers every year&#8221; on
government agencies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Multiply that across 50 states and you see why taxpayers
shouldn&#8217;t be worried about compensation just on Wall Street. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(David Reilly is a Bloomberg News columnist. The opinions
expressed are his own.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click on &#8220;Send Comment&#8221; in the sidebar display to send a
letter to the editor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the writer of this column:
David Reilly at  dreilly14@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this column:
James Greiff at  jgreiff@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By David Reilly" date="Dec 17, 2009  9:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-12-17/goldman-s-inner-conflicts-also-need-unraveling-david-reilly.html"><headline>Goldman&#8217;s Inner Conflicts Also Need Unraveling: David Reilly</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Let&#8217;s make banking boring again. That
is the noble goal of those calling for a return to the days when
the Glass-Steagall Act separated commercial and investment
banking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea is that banks taking deposits insured by the
Federal Deposit Insurance Corp., and so backed by taxpayers,
shouldn&#8217;t play in the capital-markets casino. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To really achieve this, though, legislators may have to do
more than restrict what banks can do. They may have to bring
Wall Street back to life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That would be the natural consequence of forcing some too-
big-to-fail banks to go back to their commercial-banking roots,
as envisaged by legislation proposed earlier this week by
Senators John McCain and Maria Cantwell. JPMorgan Chase  Co.
would have to spin off Bear Stearns. Bank of America Corp. would
have to shed Merrill Lynch. Citigroup Inc. would have to hive
off its own investment-banking activities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given all that&#8217;s happened over the past two years this
might sound crazy. Actually, it can make lots of sense if
Congress simultaneously splits up Wall Street titans such as
Goldman Sachs Group Inc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And let&#8217;s not forget that the Glass-Steagall separation
worked for more than 60 years, from its passage in 1933 until
its repeal in 1999. The prohibition even gave birth to firms
such as Morgan Stanley, which in 1935 was spun off from what is
now JPMorgan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, though, a practical question: does such legislation
have any chance at success? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long Odds &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The odds are against it. Yet the politics of Wall Street,
bailouts and the economy are fluid, especially since 2010 will
see Congressional elections. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus, McCain and Cantwell aren&#8217;t the only ones buzzing
about Glass-Steagall. Earlier this week, House Majority Leader
Steny Hoyer said a return to that system &#8220;is certainly under
discussion.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No wonder analysts at FBR Capital Markets in a research
note yesterday hedged their bets on just how far this may go.
While a forced breakup of banks may prove &#8220;too big to swallow&#8221;
for Congress, they wrote, &#8220;this debate is going to garner the
spotlight much more quickly than we expected.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Politics aside, a renewed embrace of Glass-Steagall would
give current reform legislation real teeth. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bills now in Congress provide for more stringent
regulation of financial institutions and impose rules such as
stronger capital requirements and a cap on the amount of
borrowed money firms can use to juice profit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Falling Short &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet they don&#8217;t tackle the issue of too big to fail.
Instead, by saying only that regulators can break them up as a
last resort, the legislation in the House gives the firms a
privileged status and doesn&#8217;t remove the threat that taxpayers
may again have to rescue them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the current strictures were combined with a new Glass-
Steagall-like provision, reform would have muscle. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granted, Glass-Steagall isn&#8217;t a silver bullet. Plenty of
banks got into trouble in their bread-and-butter business of
lending to homeowners and businesses; Washington Mutual was a
good example. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#8217;s why the provisions in existing legislation for
beefed up regulation and capital are important, even if they
don&#8217;t go far enough on their own. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congress shouldn&#8217;t stop there, though. Simply saying that
Goldman Sachs and Morgan Stanley are no longer bank-holding
companies (a coveted status they received last fall that allows
them to borrow at the Federal Reserve&#8217;s discount window), as
would likely happen under a Glass-Steagall-like split, won&#8217;t go
far enough. A newly reconstituted Wall Street would need to be
further divided. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bundles of Conflicts &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As things now stand, Wall Street and big banks are bundles
of conflicts that too often pit firms against their customers.
That led to some of the riskier practices that helped fuel the
financial crisis. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investment houses underwrote and sold investors complex
bundles of mortgages, for example, even as they bet the housing
market would crater. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This needs to change. Either a firm is an adviser, a
broker, an asset manager or a hedge fund. It can&#8217;t be all things
to all customers. Nor can a firm be all those things and not
create the kind of linkages that threaten the stability of the
financial system. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So firms should have to choose between being, say, brokers
and investment bankers versus proprietary trading shops or asset
managers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making a Choice &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that case, if Goldman Sachs wants to be a giant hedge
fund, that&#8217;s all it should be. After all, some smaller, focused
players such as hedge funds failed during the crisis but didn&#8217;t
require taxpayer bailouts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Splitting up Wall Street would also make finance easier to
regulate. In their current agglomerated state, too many firms
are impenetrable black boxes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regulators don&#8217;t really know what&#8217;s going on inside.
Neither do investors. And it often seems management is clueless
as well. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be sure, changes along these lines would be painful and
bitterly opposed by banks and Wall Street. They would also be
tough to swallow since foreign banks wouldn&#8217;t face similar
restrictions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even former Federal Reserve Chairman Paul Volcker, who for
months seemed like a lone voice in favor of Glass-Steagall, has
admitted it&#8217;s tough to draw the line between certain banking and
trading activities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, it&#8217;s worth a try. The result, as McCain said, may be
&#8220;a larger number of smaller, more aggressive companies that are
not so big that their failure would bring the entire economy
down.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That would be good for markets, competition, the economy,
and ultimately banks themselves. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus, if Congress isn&#8217;t willing to find a new way to end
the threat of too-big-to-fail firms, why not revisit a proven
antidote. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(David Reilly is a Bloomberg News columnist. The opinions
expressed are his own.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click on &#8220;Send Comment&#8221; in the sidebar display to send a
letter to the editor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the writer of this column:
David Reilly at  dreilly14@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this column:
James Greiff at  jgreiff@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry></news>