
<news><entry author="By Drew Armstrong" date="Jul 01, 2013  4:16 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-01/pfizer-s-eliquis-stops-blood-clots-as-well-as-standard.html"><headline>Pfizer''s Eliquis Stops Blood Clots as Well as Standard</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Eliquis, the blood thinner sold by
Pfizer Inc. (PFE) and Bristol-Myers Squibb Co. (BMY), was as good as the
current standard of care in preventing blood clots and with
fewer bleeding complications, according to a study. </p>
<p>In a trial of 5,400 people, the drug was found to be
equivalent to the generic warfarin at preventing new clots and
death in patients who had a venous thromboembolism, or VTE. In
VTE, clots form in the body''s large arteries, often in the legs
or pelvis. The clots can then break off and travel into the
lungs, causing a potentially deadly pulmonary embolism. </p>
<p>Eliquis is one of three in a new class of blood thinners
that may replace warfarin, a half-century old therapy that needs
regular monitoring and requires patients to avoid certain foods.
Bristol-Myers and Pfizer will use the results of the study to
apply to regulators for using Eliquis in short- and long-term
treatment of VTE. It''s already approved for stroke prevention in
patients with irregular heartbeat. </p>
<p>We have data to support a real change in clinical
practice, said Giancarlo Agnelli, a professor of internal
medicine at Italy''s University of Perugia who led the trial.
Current therapy has some limitations, he said. With Eliquis,
we have a new compound and a new way to give it that''s much,
much easier. </p>
<p>Bristol-Myers and Pfizer, both based in New York, sponsored
the trial. It is being published in the New England Journal of
Medicine and presented at the Congress of the International
Society on Thrombosis and Haemostasis in Amsterdam. </p>
<p>Pfizer shares fell less than 1 percent to $27.78 at the
close in New York. Bristol-Myers rose less than 1 percent to
$44.82. </p>
<h2>Study Findings </h2>
<p>Patients in the study were given Eliquis or warfarin for
six months after being diagnosed with a VTE that came on
suddenly, instead of from an expected cause such as surgery or
childbirth. Of the patients on Eliquis, 2.3 percent died or had
another clot, compared with 2.7 percent on warfarin. The
warfarin patients also typically received heparin, another blood
thinner typically given in a hospital, in the early part of
treatment. </p>
<p>This population is of very high risk of recurrence,
Agnelli, referring to a deep-vein thrombosis, said in a
telephone interview. If you have deep-vein thrombosis after
surgery, the recurrence rate is much lower. </p>
<p>Eliquis was better than warfarin in terms of safety, the
trial also found. In the study, 0.6 percent of patients on
Eliquis had major bleeding -- for example inside the eye, skull,
gastro-intestinal tract or in other major organs -- compared
with 1.8 percent of patients on warfarin. </p>
<h2>Competing Drugs </h2>
<p>Xarelto, a competing drug sold by Leverkusen, Germany-based
Bayer AG (BAYN) and New Brunswick, New Jersey-based Johnson  Johnson (JNJ),
already is approved for VTE. Boehringer Ingelheim''s Pradaxa,
also one of the new wave of blood thinners, isn''t yet approved
in the U.S. for VTE. </p>
<p>New treatments for VTE can help save money because they can
shorten the time patients are taking the heparin, often the
first treatment they get before warfarin, and staying in the
hospital, said Seamus Fernandez, an analyst with Leerink Swann 
Co. Venous thrombosis treatment with Xarelto is a big cost-saver for hospitals, driving incremental access and uptake, he
said in an April 5 note to clients. Success in VTE treatment
could be a major boon to BMY/PFE''s Eliquis, Fernandez said. </p>
<p>From 300,000 to 900,000 people in the U.S. have a venous
thromboembolism each year, according to the Centers for Disease
Control and Prevention in Atlanta. About half of those occur
after a hospital stay or surgery, according to the CDC. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Zeke Faux" date="Jul 01, 2013 10:37 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-01/morgan-stanley-gets-770-million-for-private-equity-fund.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Gets $770 Million for Private-Equity Fund</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS), owner of the world''s
largest brokerage, said its money-management division raised
$770 million for a pool that will buy interests in private-equity funds in the secondary market. </p>
<p>The division of the New York-based bank said today in a
statement that it exceeded its $600 million target for the fund,
called Morgan Stanley Global Secondary Opportunities Fund LP II.
The pool will invest in off-market deals such as smaller
buyouts and special situations, according to the statement. </p>
<p>We recently completed several restructuring deals and
believe these types of deals are an ever-important and growing
part of the broader secondary market, Jon Costello, senior
portfolio manager at Morgan Stanley Alternative Investment
Partners, said in the statement. </p>
<p>Investors include existing clients of Morgan Stanley
Alternative Investment Partners as well as new limited partners
that include wealthy individuals, insurance companies,
endowments and pension plans, according to the statement. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Jul 01, 2013 10:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-01/microsoft-to-sell-surface-to-businesses-to-boost-demand.html"><headline>Microsoft to Sell Surface to Businesses to Boost Demand</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), facing lackluster
sales of its Surface tablet, will begin selling the devices to
large businesses through resellers like CDW Corp. in a bid to
improve sales by targeting corporate customers. </p>
<p>The company will also start a new program called
AppsForSurface to provide corporate software makers with devices
and funding to get them to adapt their programs to Surface.
Citrix Systems Inc. (CTXS) and Houghton Mifflin Harcourt Publishing Co.
are among those who have signed up, Microsoft said in a blog
post today. </p>
<p>Microsoft is trying to broaden the audience for Surface to
corporate and education customers after the tablet, released in
October, met poor demand from consumers. The company sold
900,000 Surfaces in each of the fourth and first quarters,
according to researcher IDC. Brent Thill, an analyst at UBS AG,
had initially projected Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft
would sell 2 million units in the December quarter alone. </p>
<p>The company had expected greater initial sales as well.
While Microsoft didn''t give a forecast and hasn''t disclosed how
many Surface units have been sold, the company placed an initial
order for 3 million devices from the manufacturer, people
familiar with the matter said in March. </p>
<p>That''s left Microsoft struggling to find groups and types
of customer who may be ripe targets for Surface. Last month the
company announced a price cut to $199 from a $499 starting price
for schools purchasing the Surface RT model directly from
Microsoft. That offer runs until the end of August and is
available in 26 countries. </p>
<p>Until now Surface has been sold only in retail stores and
apps have focused on consumers and individual business users
rather than corporate programs, making the device less appealing
for wide-scale company use and harder to purchase if a
corporation wanted a large number. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri" date="Jul 02, 2013  4:38 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-02/disney-delays-ceo-succession-by-extending-iger-term-to-2016-1-.html"><headline>Disney Delays CEO Succession by Extending Iger Term to 2016</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS) extended Robert Iger''s tenure as chief executive officer of the world''s largest
entertainment company to June 2016, a move that delays his
planned succession for 15 months. </p>
<p>Iger, 62, will now continue in both the chairman and CEO
positions until mid-2016, Burbank, California-based Disney said
yesterday in a statement. He was scheduled to relinquish the CEO
title on April 1, 2015. </p>
<p>The company cited a need for continuity and Iger''s record
of success. Analysts have long cited Chief Financial Officer Jay Rasulo and Tom Staggs, who leads the parks and resorts division,
as probable replacements. The two swapped roles in January 2010.
This year, Disney amended its compensation plan to allow for the
creation of new senior positions, such as chief operating
officer or president. </p>
<p>Either the company does not believe that its current CEO
candidates are ready to take the helm or that Iger is not ready
to step down, said Janna Sampson, co-chief investment officer
of Lisle, Illinois-based OakBrook Investments LLC, which
reported owning about 441,000 Disney shares as of June 28. I
doubt the Disney board would force Iger to retire at this point
anyway. </p>
<p>The company credits Iger''s leadership for total shareholder
return of 193 percent during his tenure, beating the 54 percent
return for the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index, said Orin Smith,
Disney''s independent lead director. Iger was named CEO in
September 2005. </p>
<h2>Disney Shares </h2>
<p>Now, Disney will continue to have the full benefit of Mr.
Iger''s leadership as CEO and chairman for the duration of his
tenure, Smith said in the statement, adding that the board
remains focused on finding a successor when his term ends. </p>
<p>Disney fell 1.1 percent to $63.26 at the close in New York.
The shares have risen 27 percent this year, compared with 13
percent for the SP 500. </p>
<p>The company said there will be no change to the terms of
Iger''s compensation. He earned $40.2 million in 2012 in total
compensation last year, based on regulatory reporting rules, a
20 percent increase from the previous year. The company says 92
percent of his 2012 pay was performance based. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri and Michael White" date="Jul 02, 2013  4:36 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-02/disney-rides-into-box-office-ambush-with-depp-s-lone-ranger-.html"><headline>Disney Rides Into Box-Office Ambush With The Lone Ranger''</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Johnny Depp''s The Lone Ranger, opening in theaters tomorrow to negative reviews and tough competition, looks poised to become Walt Disney Co. (DIS)''s biggest flop since last year''s $200 million loss from John Carter. </p> <p>The movie, based on the 1930s radio show and 1950s TV series, is the type of project that''s worked well in Hollywood of late. It features well-known characters and a proven star in Depp, with potential for sequels and merchandise sales. </p> <p>Still, Disney will struggle to turn a profit, after the budget climbed to $225 million and the film earned mostly unfavorable early reviews. The task is more challenging because The Lone Ranger opens on a competitive summer weekend, against Universal Pictures'' animated Despicable Me 2 and holdovers that include Monsters University, from Disney''s Pixar, and the zombie thriller World War Z. </p> <p>It is a huge gamble, said Doug Creutz, an analyst with Cowen  Co. in San Francisco, who predicts a $100 million write-off for Disney. You need the film to be really good. </p> <p>Critics have been harsh. Of 62 reviews compiled by the website Rottentomatoes.com, 79 percent were labeled negative. That compares with 49 percent rotten out of 218 reviews of John Carter, Disney''s March 2012 sci-fi fantasy about a Civil War veteran transported to Mars. </p>




Photographer: Patrick T. Fallon/Bloomberg

<p>
A plastic figurine of the Lone Ranger, a character from Walt Disney Co.''s "The Lone Ranger" film, stands on a base unit of the Disney Infinity video game system during a Disney Interactive event in Los Angeles. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri and Michael White" date="Jul 02, 2013  4:03 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-02/disney-buys-rights-to-four-marvel-movies-from-viacom-s-paramount.html"><headline>Disney Buys Rights to Marvel Movies From Viacom''s Paramount</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS), the owner of Marvel Entertainment, acquired the rights to four Marvel superhero movies held by Viacom Inc. (VIAB)''s Paramount Pictures, the studio that released the films from 2008 to 2011. </p> <p>The agreement covers the first two Iron Man movies, Thor and Captain America: The First Avenger, according to a statement today from Burbank, California-based Disney and Los Angeles-based Paramount. Terms weren''t given. </p> <p>The deal gives Disney, the world''s largest entertainment company, more control over Marvel''s film library as it seeks to expand those characters into television shows and theme-park attractions. Disney acquired the comic book and movie company in December 2009 for $4.2 billion in cash and stock. </p> <p>Disney later purchased the distribution and marketing rights to 2012''s Marvel''s The Avengers and this year''s Iron Man 3. Both were held by Paramount. Disney paid Paramount at least $115 million at the time. </p> <p>Marvel''s The Avengers was the top-grossing film last year, with $1.5 billion in worldwide ticket sales, according to Box Office Mojo, an industry researcher. Iron Man 3 leads this year with $1.2 billion in worldwide box office. </p> <p>Sony Corp (SNE). makes Spider-Man movies under a longstanding agreement with Marvel. Amy Pascal, co-chairwoman of Sony Pictures Entertainment, said in a May 22 interview with the fan website Ain''t it Cool News, that the studio had no intention of selling Spider-Man rights. </p> <p>21st Century Fox has made the X-Men and Wolverine films under a similar arrangement. </p> <p>Disney fell 1.1 percent to $63.26 at the close in New York. The stock is up 27 percent this year. Viacom, based in New York, declined 0.4 percent to $67.54 and is up 28 percent. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kevin Dugan" date="Jul 02, 2013  1:15 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-02/morgan-stanley-sells-its-biggest-range-accrual-note-in-15-months.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Sells Its Biggest Range-Accrual Note in 15 Months</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) sold $25 million of
notes that pay investors the most when the difference between
long- and short-term rates widens so long as stocks don''t
plummet, its biggest range-accrual offering in 15 months. </p>
<p>The 15-year securities, issued June 25, are tied to the gap
between 30- and five-year constant maturity swap rates. After
two years of yielding 10.5 percent, they pay an annual rate of
five times the rate spread, capped at 10.5 percent, for every
day the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index is at least 1,100, which was
69 percent of its value at the time of sale, according to a
prospectus filed with the U.S. Securities and Exchange
Commission. </p>
<p>The spreads for such notes may tighten, with the prospect
of Federal Reserve tapering sending intermediate Treasury
yields higher, said Richard Gilhooly, an interest-rate
strategist at Toronto-Dominion Bank''s TD Securities unit in New
York. On June 19, Fed Chairman Ben S. Bernanke said that the
central bank may begin reducing its $85 billion in monthly bond
purchases later this year. </p>
<p>While the 30-year dollar swap rate has climbed 19 basis
points since June 18, the five-year rate has risen 31 basis
points. That means the Treasury yield curve has become flatter,
not steeper, which is what the buyers of the Morgan Stanley
notes want. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley, which received a 3 percent fee for selling
the securities, estimated their value to be 13.5 percent less
than what investors paid. </p>
<h2>Previous Sale </h2>
<p>The bank sold $50 million of similar notes on March 27,
2012, the most recent such offering that was larger. </p>
<p>Those securities, which also mature in 15 years, yield 11
percent for the first two years, then pay an annual rate of five
times the difference between the 30- and two-year swap rates,
capped at 11 percent, for each day the SP 500 Index (SPX) is at or
above 935, according to a prospectus filed with the SEC. </p>
<p>Range-accrual notes typically pay a fixed annual rate for
each day an asset''s price remains within certain boundaries. </p>
<p>Lauren Bellmare, a spokeswoman for the largest U.S.
structured note issuer by volume, declined to comment on the
security. </p>
<p>Banks create structured notes by packaging debt with
derivatives to offer customized bets to retail investors while
earning fees and raising money. Derivatives are contracts whose
value is derived from stocks, bonds, commodities and currencies,
or events such as changes in interest rates or the weather. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jonathan Browning" date="Jul 02, 2013  4:42 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-02/goldman-sachs-names-hitchner-as-asia-president-replacing-ryan.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Names Hitchner as Asia Head, Replacing Ryan</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), the top
underwriter of share sales in Asia excluding Japan this year,
said Ken Hitchner will become president for the region after
David Ryan retires later this year. </p>
<p>Hitchner, who currently runs health-care banking and is co-head of the technology, media and telecommunications group, will
be based in Hong Kong, New York-based Goldman Sachs said in an
e-mailed statement. Ryan, 43, will become a senior director, the
bank said, without providing a reason for his retirement after
two years in the role. </p>
<p>The Wall Street firm, which this year ceded its position as
the top mergers adviser for Asia excluding Japan, hired Kate Richdale from Morgan Stanley (MS) in March to strengthen investment
banking services. Hitchner will also work with Mark Schwartz,
who rejoined the firm last year as chairman of the Asia-Pacific
business, and Masa Mochida, who oversees Japan. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs has been pretty good at regularly rotating
people through the top positions, said Philippe Espinasse, a
Hong Kong-based former equity capital markets banker at UBS AG
and Nomura Holdings Inc. Hiring someone with mergers experience,
is probably a function of the maturity of the Asian market
now. </p>
<h2>Navy Pilot </h2>
<p>Revenue for Goldman Sachs in Asia climbed 16 percent to
$5.39 billion last year, data compiled by Bloomberg show. </p>
<p>Hitchner, a 53-year-old former U.S. Navy pilot, has been
with Goldman Sachs since 1991. As a banker in the health-care
industry for more than 15 years, he has advised clients
including Johnson  Johnson (JNJ) on its $19.7 billion takeover of
Synthes Inc. in 2012. He will oversee the day-to-day operations
of Asia-Pacific businesses, excluding Japan, the bank said. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs is the top-ranked adviser for equity and
equity-linked offerings in Asia, excluding Japan, this year,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. That''s up from No. 5
last year, the data show. The bank slipped to fourth in Asian
MA advisory this year, excluding Japan, after having held the
top spot for the past two years, the data show. </p>
<p>Ryan, a former head of the Asian financing group, was named
co-president of the bank''s Asian operations in 2011, along with
Yusuf Alireza, who has since left the firm. During his tenure,
the bank exited its seven-year investment in Industrial 
Commercial Bank of China Ltd., the world''s largest lender by
market value. He has been with the firm since 1992. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jesse Hamilton" date="Jul 03, 2013  3:11 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-03/goldman-sachs-granted-two-year-phase-out-for-some-swaps-trading.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Given Two-Year Phase-Out for Some Swaps Trades</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) will have
another two years to separate derivatives trading from units
that get federal backing, according to a letter to the bank
posted on the Federal Reserve website. </p>
<p>The Fed said in the letter that the New York-based bank
must determine whether to kill the swaps activity or move it to
properly capitalized affiliates. Under the Dodd-Frank Act rule
requiring the swaps push-out, interest-rate and some credit
swaps can still be traded inside the bank. </p>
<p>The potential impact of granting a 24-month transition
period is less adverse than the potential impact of denying the
transition period, Robert Frierson, secretary of the board,
wrote in the letter dated yesterday. Giving Goldman Sachs the
transition time lowers the probability of operational problems
and market disruption, Frierson wrote. </p>
<p>Dodd-Frank overhauled swaps trading in an effort to make
the industry less vulnerable to a crisis such as the one that
struck in 2008. The law requires equity, some commodity and non-cleared credit derivatives be pushed out of bank units with
access to deposit insurance and the Fed''s discount window. </p>
<p>Andrew Williams, a spokesman for Goldman Sachs in New York,
declined to comment on the extension. </p>




Photographer: Daniel Acker/Bloomberg

<p>
The Federal Reserve said in the letter that Goldman Sachs Group Inc. must determine whether to kill the swaps activity or move it to properly capitalized affiliates. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jeremy Hodges" date="Jul 03, 2013 11:55 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-03/jpmorgan-internal-probe-cleared-hannam-of-market-abuse-he-says.html"><headline>JPMorgan Internal Probe Cleared Hannam of Market Abuse, He Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Ian Hannam, formerly one of JPMorgan
Chase  Co. (JPM)''s top merger advisers, said the bank cleared him in
an internal investigation before the U.K. finance regulator
fined him for disclosing inside information. </p>
<p>JPMorgan believed that I had not done market abuse,
Hannam testified at a London court today, where he is fighting
the 450,000-pound ($687,000) fine. They carried out this very
serious investigation and I assure you that if they had found I
had broken any regulatory rules, I would not have been an
employee there. </p>
<p>Two e-mail messages form the basis of a proposed civil
market-abuse fine against Hannam by the U.K. Financial Conduct
Authority, which considers the content insider information.
Hannam, formerly JPMorgan''s global chairman of equity capital
markets, said the notes were in the best interest of his
client, Heritage Oil Plc (HOIL), and is challenging the sanction at a
court hearing at the Upper Tribunal in London that started
yesterday. </p>
<p>Hannam, who resigned from the New York-based bank after the
fine, is one of the highest-profile finance workers the
regulator has targeted. Hannam was among the bankers advising
Xstrata Plc before it was acquired by Glencore International
Plc. (GLEN) </p>
<p>I particularly enjoyed working for JPMorgan, Hannam
said. I would probably still be at JPMorgan. </p>
<p>Hannam, Heritage CEO Tony Buckingham and Chief Financial
Officer Paul Atherton are scheduled to testify at the trial,
which could last as long as two weeks. </p>
<p>Hannam, a former soldier, graduated from Imperial College
London and London Business School, and trained at Salomon
Brothers. In 1992, he joined Robert Fleming  Co., which was
bought by Chase Manhattan in 2000. Four years later, he helped
to set up JPMorgan''s joint venture with London-based Cazenove
Group Ltd. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chanyaporn Chanjaroen and Michelle Yun" date="Jul 03, 2013  1:06 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-03/jpmorgan-names-katz-rubinstein-oil-trade-heads-as-frase-leaves.html"><headline>JPMorgan Names Katz, Rubinstein Oil Trade Heads as Frase Leaves</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co (JPM), the biggest U.S.
bank, appointed Jeff Katz and Mitch Rubinstein co-heads of
global oil trading to replace Jeff Frase, according to an
internal memo. </p>
<p>Katz and Rubinstein will report to Blythe Masters, the
bank''s global commodities head, New York-based Masters said in
the July 2 memo obtained by Bloomberg News. Marie Cheung, a
JPMorgan spokeswoman in Hong Kong, declined to comment when
contacted by phone today. </p>
<p>Frase will join Noble Group Ltd. (NOBL) as the head of oil liquids
trading, based in the U.S., said a person with knowledge of the
move who asked not to be identified because the information
isn''t public. Frase couldn''t be reached on his office phone in
New York after normal business hours. </p>
<p>SparkSpread reported the appointments earlier. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Harry Suhartono" date="Jul 04, 2013 12:06 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-04/morgan-stanley-says-cut-indonesia-stocks-on-capital-flight-risk.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Says Cut Indonesia Stocks on Capital Flight Risk</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Indonesia''s stock market is the most
vulnerable in Southeast Asia to capital flight amid expensive
valuations and large holdings by foreign investors, Morgan
Stanley said. </p>
<p>The country''s equities were reduced to underweight from
equalweight in a report today by Jonathan Garner, the New York-based bank''s head of Asia and emerging-market strategy. PT CIMB
Securities Indonesia cut its recommendation on the nation''s
stocks two days ago, citing concern that rising fuel prices will
spur inflation. </p>
<p>Foreign investors, who bought a net $16 billion of
Indonesian shares during the past seven years, have sold about
$210 million so far in 2013, data compiled by Bloomberg show.
The Jakarta Composite Index (JCI) is valued at 2.8 times net assets,
the highest level among 17 Asia equity measures, even after
falling 11 percent from its May 20 peak. The gauge rose 1.3
percent to 4,638.40 as of 10:50 a.m. in Jakarta, after a 3.2
drop yesterday. </p>
<p>Indonesia is still a relatively overowned country wrote
Garner and his Hong Kong-based colleagues Yang Bai and Pankaj Mataney. The nation is likely to be the most vulnerable equity
market within ASEAN in a sudden stop of capital flows
scenario. Asean refers to the Association of Southeast Asian
Nations. </p>
<p>The Jakarta gauge, which has more than doubled during the
past four years, tumbled yesterday as foreign money managers
sold about $88 million of shares amid speculation Indonesia''s
central bank will boost borrowing costs. Policy makers are
scheduled to announce an interest-rate decision on July 11. </p>
<h2>Volatility Surges </h2>
<p>The World Bank cut its 2013 forecast for Indonesian growth
to 5.9 percent this month, saying accelerating inflation could
hurt domestic demand as exports and investment cool. The
government raised domestic fuel prices for the first time since
2008 last month. </p>
<p>Higher energy costs, combined with monetary policy
tightening, will probably hit already weakening investment
growth and drag economic expansion to 5.7 percent in 2013,
according to Credit Suisse Group AG. </p>
<p>The Jakarta gauge''s 30-day historical volatility rose to
33.3 today, highest level since November 2011, according to data
compiled by Bloomberg. Price swings have increased amid concern
the U.S. Federal Reserve will reduce monetary stimulus that has
fueled demand for riskier assets in emerging markets. </p>
<p>CIMB Securities Indonesia, the nation''s most-active
brokerage in May by trading volume, lowered its recommendation
on Indonesian stocks to neutral from overweight on July 2 and
trimmed the year-end target for the Jakarta index to 5,075 from
5,250. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Thomas Black, Leslie Picker and Callie Bost" date="Jul 05, 2013 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-05/goldman-sachs-to-microsoft-s-support-for-gays-pressures-states.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs to Microsoft''s Support for Gays Pressures States</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Support for gay marriage by companies as varied as Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) and Starbucks Corp. (SBUX) is gathering steam to change policies in states that bar same-sex couples from tying the knot. </p> <p>Two U.S. Supreme Court decisions on June 26 heartened supporters of the cause while showing an increased willingness of business to back the effort. In one case, more than 200 companies signed a brief against a federal law that denied benefits to same-sex couples. Five years ago, only a handful had lobbied against California''s Proposition 8 ban on same-sex marriages, the target of the high court''s other decision. </p> <p>State legislators stand to feel the heat as more businesses speak out against laws in states including Texas, Florida and Michigan that recognize only heterosexual marriage. While fewer than half the companies in the Standard  Poor''s 500 (SPX) are based in states that allow gays to wed, most already have policies that ban discrimination based on sexual orientation. </p> <p>Companies do have the choice where they locate, where they set up shop, said Kellie McElhaney, founding faculty director of the Center for Responsible Business at the University of California Berkeley. Local policies on sexual orientation will eventually become part of the choice process. </p>




Photographer: Robyn Beck/AFP via Getty Images

<p>
A same sex marriage ceremony on July 1, 2013 in West Hollywood, California. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Gwen Ackerman" date="Jul 07, 2013  5:15 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-07/mobileye-of-israel-adds-institutional-investors-considers-ipo.html"><headline>Israel''s Mobileye Adds Investors in Potential IPO Prelude</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Mobileye NV, a company whose Israeli-developed technology helps stop car accidents, added five
investors, including U.S. global asset managers and a Chinese
firm, in a $400 million sale of equity that is a step toward an
initial public offering. </p>
<p>The transaction valued Amsterdam-based Mobileye at about
$1.5 billion and is likely to close in August, the company said
in an e-mailed statement today. It didn''t identify the new
investors. </p>
<p>This successful transaction is a testament to the
strength of our business and the company''s future prospects,
Chief Executive Officer Ziv Aviram said in the statement. </p>
<p>Founded in 1999, Mobileye makes a chip and a system that
alert drivers to pedestrians, unintended lane departure and
speed limit violations among others. It can also execute active
breaking to prevent an accident. General Motors Co. (GM) and
Bayerische Motoren Werke AG are among the company''s customers. </p>
<p>The equity sale allowed early investors to exit and brought
in more prominent stakeholders who can help the company move
toward an IPO, said a shareholder, who asked not to be
identified because the new investors haven''t been announced
publicly. </p>
<p>The Chinese government-affiliated financial investor can
help Mobileye expand its sales in China, the shareholder said.
The shareholder named BlackRock Inc. (BLK) as one of the new investors
in Mobileye. Brian Beades, a spokesman for the New York-based
company, the world''s largest money manager, declined comment. </p>
<h2>$35 a Share Report </h2>
<p>According to the Israeli financial daily Calcalist,
investors that bought into Mobileye at $15 a share sold at $35
in the transaction. While it wasn''t immediately clear which of
the company''s 280 shareholders sold out, existing investors
include Goldman Sachs Group Inc., Migdal Insurance  Financial
Holding Ltd. (MGDL) and Africa-Israel Investments Ltd.''s Chairman Lev Leviev. </p>
<p>With the slogan Our vision. Your safety, Mobileye''s
technology is currently installed in cars made by 19
manufacturers, including Volvo, GM, BMW and Hyundai Motor Co.,
according to the company''s website. </p>
<p>Mobileye was co-founded by a professor of computer science
at the Hebrew University of Jerusalem and employs about 200
people. Its research and development center is in Jerusalem and
it has offices in the Netherlands, U.S., Japan and Cyprus. It''s
focusing now on technology that will compete with Google Inc.''s
self-driving car. </p>
<p>Mobileye would join other Israeli companies such as website
developer Wixpress Ltd., commercially known as Wix.com, and
Kamada Ltd. (KMDA), which makes medical treatments, looking to list in
the U.S. </p>
<p>The Bloomberg Israel-U.S. Equity Index of 24 stocks
increased 16 percent in the past 12 months, compared with a 21
percent gain for the Nasdaq Composite Index. (CCMP) </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Khalid Al-Ansary and Nayla Razzouk" date="Jul 07, 2013  8:21 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-07/jpmorgan-deepens-iraq-business-after-citi-standard-chartered.html"><headline>JPMorgan Deepens Iraq Business After Citi, Standard Chartered</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) is the latest
international bank after Citigroup Inc. (C) and Standard Chartered
Plc (STAN) to expand business in Iraq as OPEC''s second-largest producer
boosts crude oil output and rebuilds its economy. </p>
<p>JPMorgan signed a one-year agreement yesterday to help the
Trade Bank of Iraq finance imports of goods and services, John Gibbons, managing director and EMEA regional executive for the
New York-based bank, said in an interview in Baghdad. </p>
<p>Our focus is to open more letters of credit through the
Trade Bank of Iraq on behalf of the government and its
ministries, he said. </p>
<p>Iraq, with the world''s fifth-largest proven oil reserves,
is modernizing its infrastructure and energy industry after
decades of sanctions, war and neglect. It produced 3.2 million
barrels a day of crude in June, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg, and targets output of 3.5 million barrels by the end
of the year. The government is boosting spending by 18 percent
in 2013 to $118 billion, and the International Monetary Fund
forecasts an annual economic growth rate of 9 percent, the
fastest after Libya among 18 countries in the region. </p>
<p>Iraqi officials are in talks with international banks about
the opening of offices and branches in the country, Abdul-Basit Turki, acting governor of Iraq''s central bank, said today in an
interview in Baghdad. It is a rich market and the investment
opportunities are huge, Turki said. </p>
<h2>Banking Growth </h2>
<p>Foreign banks were barred from the country until after the
2003 U.S.-led invasion ousted the government of Saddam Hussein.
Today, 15 international banks operate in Iraq, competing with
seven state banks, 23 private lenders and nine banks operating
under Islamic rules, according to the central bank''s website. </p>
<p>Citigroup plans to open representative offices and branches
in Baghdad and the cities of Basra and Erbil to benefit from an
estimated $1 trillion of infrastructure spending, Mayank Malik,
the U.S. bank''s chief executive officer for Jordan, Iraq, Syria
and the Palestinian territories, said in a June 27 interview.
The lender is among international banks seeking to finance a
pipeline to export Iraqi oil and natural gas through Jordan,
Nateq Balasem Khalaf, deputy director general of Iraq''s State
Company for Oil Projects, said July 4. </p>
<p>Standard Chartered has said it will open branches this year
in Baghdad and Erbil, followed by a third office next year in
Basra, a southern oil hub. </p>
<h2>Import Payments </h2>
<p>The agreement with JPMorgan will help the Trade Bank of
Iraq open more letters of credit that we''re in need of,
TBI chairman and president Hamdiyah Al Jaff said in an interview
in Baghdad yesterday. JPMorgan helped set up TBI, the country''s
largest bank for trade finance, to facilitate imports needed for
Iraq''s postwar reconstruction. </p>
<p>Banks in the country are set for growth in earnings and
assets as a surge in lending in Iraq outpaces much of the Middle
East, according to Singapore-based Sansar Capital Management
LLC, which runs a fund with $30 million invested in Iraqi
equities. </p>
<p>Iraq''s rising oil exports and a drop in the prime lending
rate to 6 percent from 17 percent in 2008 are feeding the
expansion. The five largest privately owned banks boosted their
combined net income by 207 percent from 2010 to 2012 and more
than doubled earnings per share. </p>
<p>Iraq''s stock exchange drew investors in February when
mobile operator Asiacell Communications PJSC listed after a $1.3
billion share sale, in the Middle East''s biggest initial public
offering since 2008. The country''s two other mobile operators,
Zain Iraq and Korek Telecom, plan to sell shares in IPOs to
comply with their license requirements. </p>
<p>Iraq is the biggest oil producer, after Saudi Arabia, in
the Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dana El Baltaji" date="Jul 08, 2013  4:33 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-08/jpmorgan-touts-nakheel-saying-default-doubtful-islamic-finance.html"><headline>JPMorgan Touts Nakheel Saying Default Doubtful: Islamic Finance</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. is advising
clients to buy Nakheel PJSC''s Islamic bonds after last month''s
record slump as new projects boost the Dubai developer''s
earnings, while government backing makes a default improbable. </p>
<p>State-run Nakheel''s 4.27 billion dirhams ($1.2 billion) of
sukuk yielded 9.88 percent at 12:30 p.m. in Dubai, down seven
basis points this month, after surging 179 basis points in June.
That''s more than twice the average gain in yields on corporate
Islamic debt tracked by HSBC/Nasdaq Dubai indexes. JPMorgan
listed Nakheel in a July 4 research note as its top overweight
recommendation among Dubai real-estate debt. </p>
<p>Nakheel will manage to pay or refinance as much as half of
the $3 billion of debt due in 2016 as it generates at least $1
billion from new projects and land sales, JPMorgan said.
Investors have demanded higher yields to hold Nakheel''s bonds
since the company drove Dubai to the brink of default in 2009,
prompting the government to extend a bailout. </p>
<p>The government is quite unlikely to let Nakheel default
on its bond obligations in 2016 after supporting the company
under much more difficult circumstances, JPMorgan analyst
Zafar Nazim wrote in the note. Nakheel has been a beneficiary
of real-estate recovery in Dubai. We believe that new project
launches and plot sales were not baked in the original
restructuring plan that was agreed in 2010. </p>
<h2>Home Prices </h2>
<p>Nakheel, known for building an island shaped like the frond
of a palm tree and another like a world map off Dubai''s coast,
has received at least $8 billion of cash from the government
since announcing a standstill agreement with creditors in 2009,
JPMorgan said. </p>
<p>The real estate industry in Dubai, one of seven sheikhdoms
of the United Arab Emirates, has started recovering from a crash
that sent prices plunging more than 65 percent. New projects
such as the world''s biggest Ferris wheel, a new district with
100 hotels and the world''s largest mall were unveiled in the
past year. </p>
<p>Sale prices for residential units have risen 28 percent
from a trough in January 2011, according to an index tracked by
Jones Lang LaSalle. Dubai''s economy grew 4.4 percent in 2012,
the fastest pace in five years. Against this backdrop, JPMorgan
also recommends Islamic debt of Emaar Properties PJSC (EMAAR), developer
of the world''s tallest tower, and Jebel Ali Free Zone Authority
FZE, which leases commercial real estate in Dubai. </p>
<h2>Averting Default </h2>
<p>The yield on Emaar''s 6.4 percent securities due in July
2019 has declined 25 basis points this month to 5.59 percent
today, while Jafza''s 7 percent sukuk due a month earlier yielded
5.43 percent, down 30 basis points. The yield on HSBC/Nasdaq
Dubai''s Corporate U.S. Dollar Sukuk Index advanced 73 basis
points last month. </p>
<p>Dubai was able to avert bond default in all of its
government-related entities and its economy has recovered to
pre-crisis levels, JPMorgan said. Nakheel has been a
beneficiary of real-estate recovery in Dubai. </p>
<p>Dubai''s credit risk returned this year to levels it hasn''t
seen since late 2008 amid the global credit crisis, after state-linked companies paid or refinanced at least $3.75 billion since
the start of 2012. Five-year credit default swaps, which protect
investors against non-payment of debt, dropped 130 basis points
in the past year to 220 on July 5, according to CMA. Middle East
contracts fell 13 basis points, on average, to 302 in the
period. </p>
<h2>Risky Sector'' </h2>
<p>Still, property prices in Dubai are likely to ease due to
high levels of future supply, limited debt availability and more
mature market regulations, Alan Robertson, chief executive
officer for the Middle East and North Africa at Jones Lang
LaSalle, said by e-mail yesterday. </p>
<p>Investors dumping emerging-market assets sold debt of Dubai
property companies last month amid an emerging-market rout
triggered by Federal Reserve plans to trim its bond-buying
program. Nakheel''s debt isn''t rated, while Emaar''s bonds non-investment grade at Moody''s Investors Service and Standard 
Poor''s. </p>
<p>Dubai''s real estate is still considered a risky sector,
said Montasser Khelifi, Dubai-based senior manager for global
markets at Quantum Investment Bank Ltd. When there''s turmoil
in the bond market, investors sell the debt, even though new
projects in Dubai are announced regularly these days. </p>
<p>Nakheel''s business prospects are improving. The company
said in May it sold 471 villas valued at almost 1.9 billion
dirhams. The developer also expects to sign an agreement with
banks to extend the maturity by eight years from 2015 on 8
billion dirhams of debt, a spokeswoman said last month. </p>
<p>Investing in Nakheel''s sukuk may be a risk worth taking,
Khelifi said. While its very possible Nakheel won''t have the
money to repay the bonds, it''s good news that they''re seeking to
refinance their debt, he said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chou Hui Hong" date="Jul 08, 2013  4:09 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-08/goldman-sachs-cuts-2013-forecast-for-u-s-gas-on-higher-supplies.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Cuts 2013 Forecast for U.S. Gas on Higher Supplies</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>U.S. natural gas will average $3.85
per million British thermal units in the third quarter and $4.25
in the fourth quarter, below earlier forecasts as supply
increases, Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) said. </p>
<p>Debottlenecking at the Marcellus shale sites in West
Virginia and Pennsylvania are among the drivers of supply gains,
Goldman Sachs analysts led by Damien Courvalin in New York said
in an e-mailed report today. Goldman previously forecast U.S.
natural gas prices would be $4.50 in the third and fourth
quarters. </p>
<p>Production gains may be temporary because the number of
gas rigs operating is low, Goldman said. Natural gas prices need
to increase to $4.25 per million Btu by 2014 to bring rigs back
into active production and keep the market balanced, Courvalin
said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jonathan Browning and Zijing Wu" date="Jul 08, 2013  3:22 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-08/goldman-temasek-said-to-invest-in-shanda-s-cloudary.html"><headline>Goldman, Temasek Said to Invest in Shanda''s Cloudary</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) and Temasek
Holdings Pte agreed to buy a minority stake in China''s Cloudary
Corp. (READ) at a 25 percent lower valuation than in a previous funding
round, said two people with knowledge of the matter. </p>
<p>The private placement values the operator of literary
websites at about $600 million, less than an earlier valuation
of $800 million, the people said, asking not to be identified
because the information is private. Cloudary is controlled by
Shanda Interactive Entertainment Ltd. </p>
<p>Cloudary, which filed for a U.S. initial public offering
more than two years ago, has yet to start the share sale. A
gauge of Chinese stocks listed in the U.S. last month traded at
the widest discount since 2008 to the Nasdaq Composite Index as
measured by price-to-earnings ratios, data compiled by Bloomberg
show. </p>
<p>Equity funds managed by Orbis bought 1.875 percent of
Cloudary in May 2012 for $15 million, according to a filing with
the Securities and Exchange Commission last year. The deal
valued the company at $800 million. </p>
<p>It wasn''t clear exactly how the investment in Cloudary will
be carried out. Officials at Temasek, Goldman Sachs and Shanda
declined to comment or weren''t immediately available. Sina.com
reported on the investment by Goldman Sachs and Temasek earlier
today, without saying where it got the information. </p>
<p>Cloudary, based in Shanghai, applied for a $200 million New
York IPO in May 2011. Goldman Sachs had been named to help
manage the listing in July 2011 though is no longer involved in
the process. The company, led by former Bank of America Corp.
banker Robert Chiu, hired Bank of America, Citic Securities Co.
and CICC HK Securities as underwriters, according to a filing
last year. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Eric Martin" date="Jul 09, 2013  4:01 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-09/cocaine-output-in-andes-region-falls-10-amid-eradication-effort.html"><headline>Cocaine Output in Andes Region Falls 10% Amid Eradication Effort</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Cocaine output in the Andes region
fell 10 percent last year as Colombia and Peru increased efforts
to eradicate production and enforce the law, the U.S. government
said today. </p>
<p>Pure cocaine production in Bolivia fell 18 percent to 155
metric tons (341,717 pounds) in 2012, the White House Office of
National Drug Control Policy said today in an e-mailed
statement. Colombian output dropped 7.9 percent to 175 metric
tons and Peru''s production slid 4.9 percent to 290 metric tons,
according to the statement. The three nations are the world''s
biggest producers of the drug, while the U.S. is its top
consumer. Cocaine production has dropped 41 percent in the past
decade, the U.S. report says. </p>
<p>The reductions can be traced to factors including the
strengthened partnership between the U.S. and Colombia and
Peruvian President Ollanta Humala''s increased commitment to
counter-narcotics cooperation and security, the office said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Carter Dougherty" date="Jul 09, 2013  2:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-09/jpmorgan-backed-debt-collector-to-pay-3-2-million-over-ftc-case.html"><headline>JPMorgan-Backed Debt Collector to Pay $3.2 Million Over FTC Case</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A debt-collection firm backed by
JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s private equity unit agreed to pay $3.2
million to settle a Federal Trade Commission complaint that it
illegally harassed consumers. </p>
<p>The fine, the largest levied by the FTC against a third-party debt collector according to an agency news release today,
stems from charges that it used tactics including calling
consumers multiple times a day, calling them early in the
morning or late at night, and calling at consumers'' workplaces.
The company, Expert Global Solutions Inc., was also accused by
the FTC of continuing to call consumers who denied owing a debt
to its clients. </p>
<p>Under the settlement, if a consumer disputes the validity
of the debt, the company must either end collection efforts or
suspend them until they''ve conducted a reasonable
investigation to establish the debt''s validity. The agreement
also prohibits the company from treating consumers in the manner
outlined in the FTC''s charges, according to the agency''s
statement. </p>
<p>Tom Hoy, a spokesman for the Expert Global, did not
immediately respond to a request for comment. The FTC news
release describes the company as the world''s largest debt
collection operation. </p>
<p>JPMorgan''s stake in the firm  is held by its private
investment arm, One Equity Partners. According to the JPMorgan
investment unit''s website, Expert Global is based in Horsham,
Pennsylvania, and has revenues of about $2 billion dollars, and
40,000 employees in 14 countries. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Eduardo Thomson" date="Jul 09, 2013 12:19 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-09/jpmorgan-says-credicorp-top-peru-pick-in-bet-on-economic-growth.html"><headline>JPMorgan Says Credicorp Top Peru Pick in Bet on Economic Growth</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Credicorp Ltd. (BAP), owner of Peru''s
largest bank, may gain 32 percent by the end of the year as the
Andean nation''s economy grows, according to JPMorgan Chase  Co. </p>
<p>JPMorgan included Lima-based Credicorp, owner of Banco de
Credito del Peru, in its list of top picks for the region after
a 27 percent fall since April 1, saying economic growth will
keep supporting earnings in the country''s banking industry,
according to an e-mailed note to clients dated yesterday. </p>
<p>We like the long-term secular growth story for financial
services penetration in Peru, Saul Martinez, an analyst at
JPMorgan, said in the note. Credicorp will sustain healthy
profitable levels, on average, in the coming years. </p>
<p>JPMorgan maintained a year-end 2013 price target of $158
per share for Credicorp, according to the note. The stock rose
50 cents to $120 at 11:03 a.m. today in Lima. </p>
<p>Credicorp is trading at 11.4 times its estimated earnings
for the current year, 15 percent below its average estimated
price-to-earnings ratio of the last four years. </p>
<p>Peru''s gross domestic product will grow 5.75 percent in
2013 and 6 percent in 2014, the fastest of any major Latin
American country after Panama, according to economists''
estimates compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lisa Abramowicz" date="Jul 09, 2013 12:15 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-09/jpmorgan-as-biggest-underwriter-sees-more-losses-credit-markets.html"><headline>JPMorgan as Biggest Underwriter Sees More Losses: Credit Markets</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The chief market strategist at
JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the world''s biggest underwriter of
corporate bonds, says the worst first half of the year on record
for the securities may only deepen. </p>
<p>The notes have lost 3.7 percent on average since May 22
when Federal Reserve Chairman Ben S. Bernanke told Congress the
central bank may begin curtailing its unprecedented stimulus
program if economic conditions warrant, Bank of America Merrill
Lynch index data show. The losses compare with a drop of 2.9
percent for government securities. </p>
<p>The performance is a shock to bulls who expected the extra
yield offered by corporates relative to government bonds to
cushion any selloff that stemmed from the prospects for higher
interest rates and a stronger economy. Instead, diminished
dealer inventories of the securities brought on by regulatory
changes has caused liquidity to drop, exacerbating the price
declines. </p>
<p>Through a whole set of new, post-crisis regulations, the
potential buyers do not have the same capacity to absorb credit
risk, said Jan Loeys, who heads a global asset allocation
strategy team at JPMorgan in New York, in a telephone interview.
The banks don''t have the same ability to absorb this
anymore. </p>




Photographer: Victor J. Blue/Bloomberg

<p>
The JPMorgan Chase  Co. logo is displayed at the company''s offices in New York. JPMorgan underwrote $140 billion of corporate debt this year, or 6.9 percent of the market, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Carroll" date="Jul 10, 2013  5:13 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-10/chevron-says-april-may-production-fell-from-second-quarter-2012.html"><headline>Chevron Says April-May Production Fell From Second Quarter 2012</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX), the second-largest
energy company by market value, said crude oil and natural gas
output declined 2.1 percent during April and May compared with
the second quarter of last year. </p>
<p>Chevron reported selected second-quarter data in a
statement distributed on Business Wire today. The San Ramon,
California-based company is scheduled to announce full quarterly
results on Aug. 2. </p>
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. is the biggest energy producer by market
value. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Patrick Gower and Jeffrey St.Onge" date="Jul 10, 2013  5:59 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-10/morgan-stanley-teams-with-barratt-to-construct-770-london-homes.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Teams With Barratt to Construct 770 London Homes</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A fund managed by Morgan Stanley (MS)
will team with U.K. homebuilder Barratt Developments Plc (BDEV) and
construct 770 homes to revive a former London industrial site by
the River Thames. </p>
<p>The project in the borough of Greenwich will have a gross
development value of about 275 million pounds ($410 million),
Barratt, the second-biggest U.K. homebuilder by market value,
said in a statement today. Morgan Stanley''s real estate
investing unit will also build a cruise terminal, a 250-room
hotel and a commercial building on the site with developer West
Properties, according to the statement. </p>
<p>U.K. homebuilders are developing disused sites on the banks
of the Thames in east London to gain from demand for river views
from workers seeking to live near the Canary Wharf and City of
London financial districts. News Corp.''s News International
unit, publisher of the Sun and London-based Times newspapers,
sold its former headquarters in London''s Wapping district to
homebuilder Berkeley Group Holdings Plc (BKG) in May 2012. </p>
<p>The 8.9-acre (3.6-hectare) site at Greenwich is close to
the O2 Arena, a concert venue that was used for the 2012 Olympic
Games. </p>
<p>Barratt''s fiscal 2013 profit before items beat analyst
estimates as government support for buyers helped the company
exceed sales targets, the company said today in a separate
statement. Pretax profit before taxes and one-time items was
about 192 million pounds in the 12 months through June, the
company said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass and Callie Bost" date="Jul 11, 2013  5:16 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-11/microsoft-pares-unuits-to-emphasize-devices-web-services.html"><headline>Microsoft Revamps Business Units Playing Catchup on Web</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) Chief Executive Officer Steve Ballmer unveiled his biggest reorganization since 2002 to speed development of hardware and services at a company plagued by anemic growth and competition in mobile computing. </p> <p>The software maker reduced the number of business units to four and said Windows chief Julie Larson-Green will oversee all hardware, including the Surface tablet and Xbox console and related games. Windows Phone software head Terry Myerson will add responsibility for the Windows and Xbox operating systems. </p> <p>Ballmer is concentrating divisions around hardware and Internet services to appeal to customers who increasingly use mobile devices for tasks once done on desktop machines. As demand for Microsoft''s flagship Windows software ebbs amid a global personal-computer slump, Ballmer needs to slice away management layers that have hampered product development. </p> <p>First and foremost this is an attempt to address the fact that they are behind in tablet and mobile, said Colin Gillis, an analyst at BGC Partners LP in New York. They''re effectively saying, We have some problems we need to address and we need to make radical changes to accomplish it.'' </p> <p>The shares rose 2.8 percent to $35.69 in New York, the highest closing price since 2007. The stock has gained 34 percent this year, compared with a 17 percent gain for the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index. </p>




Photographer: Bryan Mitchell/Bloomberg

<p>
Microsoft Corp. Chief Executive Officer Steve Ballmer, center, and employees cheer during the grand opening of a company store in Troy, Michigan, on June 28, 2013. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Susan Decker and Tom Schoenberg" date="Jul 12, 2013  9:06 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-12/microsoft-sues-u-s-customs-for-failed-google-phone-ban.html"><headline>Microsoft Sues U.S. Customs for Failed Google Phone Ban</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) accused U.S. Customs
officials of refusing to follow a trade agency''s order to block
imports of phones made by Google Inc. (GOOG)''s Motorola Mobility unit
in a lawsuit that seeks to alter how such cases are handled. </p>
<p>The U.S. International Trade Commission in Washington
issued the import ban in May 2012 after deciding that Motorola
Mobility devices infringed a Microsoft patent for a way mobile
phones synchronize calendar events with other computers.
Microsoft''s lawsuit, filed yesterday in Washington, says that
order isn''t being enforced. </p>
<p>U.S. Customs and Border Protection, after having secret
meetings with Google, continued to let the Motorola Mobility
mobile phones enter the country even though Google has done
nothing to remove the feature at the heart of the ITC case,
Microsoft said in the complaint. The case illustrates what
Lexmark International Inc. (LXK) and Lutron Electronics Co. in May
called an increasingly ineffective and unpredictable
enforcement of import bans imposed by the trade agency. </p>
<p>Customs has a clear responsibility to carry out ITC
decisions, which are reached after a full trial and rigorous
legal review, Microsoft Deputy General Counsel David Howard
said in a statement. Here Customs repeatedly ignored its
obligation and did so based on secret discussions. </p>




Photographer: Simon Dawson/Bloomberg

<p>
The U.S. International Trade Commission in Washington issued the import ban in May 2012 after deciding that Google Inc.''s Motorola Mobility unit devices infringed a Microsoft Corp. patent for a way mobile phones synchronize calendar events with other computers. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Susan Decker and Tom Schoenberg" date="Jul 12, 2013  2:19 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-12/microsoft-sues-u-s-customs-for-not-enforcing-google-phone-ban.html"><headline>Microsoft Sues U.S. Customs for Not Enforcing Google Phone Ban</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) filed a lawsuit
today accusing U.S. Customs officials of refusing to follow a
trade agency''s order to block imports of phones made by Google
Inc. (GOOG)''s Motorola Mobility unit. </p>
<p>The U.S. International Trade Commission in Washington
issued the import ban in May 2012 after deciding that Motorola
Mobility devices infringed a Microsoft patent for a way mobile
phones synchronize calendar events with other computers. </p>
<p>U.S. Customs and Border Protection, after having secret
meetings with Google, continued to let the Motorola Mobility
mobile phones enter the country even though Google has done
nothing to remove the feature at the heart of the ITC case,
Microsoft said in the complaint. The case illustrates what
Lexmark International Inc. and Lutron Electronics Co. in May
called an increasingly ineffective and unpredictable
enforcement of import bans imposed by the trade agency. </p>
<p>Customs has a clear responsibility to carry out ITC
decisions, which are reached after a full trial and rigorous
legal review, Microsoft Deputy General Counsel David Howard
said in a statement. Here Customs repeatedly ignored its
obligation and did so based on secret discussions. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jul 12, 2013 12:52 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-12/jpmorgan-s-dimon-sees-banks-hurt-by-emerging-market-drop.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Dimon Sees Banks Hurt by Emerging Market Drop</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) Chief Executive
Officer Jamie Dimon praised his traders'' handling of a plunge in
emerging-market assets last month and cautioned that other banks
may not have fared as well. </p>
<p>Our folks in emerging markets also did a spectacularly
good job, because I think you might see some real
differentiation there from some other folks on how their numbers
come out, Dimon said today on a conference call with analysts
after the New York-based bank reported second-quarter earnings.
Obviously, when spreads widen out, certain businesses are more
at risk than others. In emerging markets, we probably saw the
most volatility. </p>
<p>Risk premiums on emerging market debt widened after Federal
Reserve Chairman Ben S. Bernanke indicated the central bank
might taper its $85 billion in monthly bond purchases, which
have boosted demand for higher yielding assets. Prices of
emerging-market government and corporate bonds fell 6.23 percent
in the quarter, according to Bank of America Corp. data. </p>
<p>Stocks also fell as manufacturing in China contracted and
protests erupted in Brazil and Turkey. The MSCI Emerging Markets
Index dropped 16 percent from May 21 to June 24. </p>
<p>JPMorgan, whose emerging-markets trading is overseen by
London-based James Kenny, generated $4.08 billion in revenue
from fixed-income trading during the quarter, up 17 percent from
a year earlier. That topped the 5 percent increase expected by
Deutsche Bank AG analyst Matt O''Connor and the 4 percent rise
predicted by Wells Fargo  Co. (WFC)''s Matt Burnell. Equity-trading
revenue rose 24 percent from a year earlier to $1.3 billion. </p>
<h2>Goldman Sachs </h2>
<p>While Dimon warned about divergence among banks'' trading
performance, some analysts took the firm''s better-than-expected
revenue as a good sign for the industry, including Goldman Sachs
Group Inc. (GS), which reports results on July 16. </p>
<p>Traders know how to manage money in a volatile fixed-income environment -- nothing really blew up, Brad Hintz, an
analyst at Sanford C. Bernstein  Co., said on The Hays
Advantage Bloomberg Radio program. So I''m optimistic about
Goldman going forward, because if Jamie did well, this is
usually a good sign that the other trading house did well. </p>
<p>JPMorgan''s results in June weren''t as strong as those in
April and May, Chief Financial Officer Marianne Lake said. That
month featured declines in the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index and
corporate and Treasury bonds after Bernanke said the Fed would
consider cutting back stimulus efforts if economic growth
improves. </p>
<p>The bank''s value-at-risk, an estimate of potential trading
losses, fell to $40 million in its corporate and investment bank
during the quarter, the lowest since JPMorgan bought Bank One
Corp. in 2004. The drop in the measure, which climbed in June,
was driven by lower volatility in asset prices and a reduction
in JPMorgan''s own risk appetite, Lake said. </p>
<p>The client flows, they held up, Lake said on the call.
So if you surround that with robust and strong trading risk
discipline, that''s pretty much how it panned out. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jul 12, 2013 11:25 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-12/jpmorgan-trails-proposed-u-s-capital-rule-dimon-dislikes.html"><headline>JPMorgan Trails Proposed U.S. Capital Rule Dimon Dislikes</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s ratio of
capital to total assets falls short of a proposed U.S. minimum
that Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon criticized for
diverging from the standard other nations'' lenders face. </p>
<p>JPMorgan''s so-called leverage ratio at its holding company
is 4.7 percent, below the 5 percent proposed U.S. minimum, the
New York-based bank said today in a presentation. The ratio at
its deposit-taking subsidiary is even lower, creating a wider
gap to the 6 percent proposed standard for those units, Chief
Financial Officer Marianne Lake said on a conference call. </p>
<p>The U.S. plan goes beyond the 3 percent global minimum
requirement that the Basel Committee on Banking Supervision
approved to help prevent a repeat of the 2008 financial crisis.
The changes would make lenders fund more assets with capital
that can absorb losses instead of using borrowed money. </p>
<p>If one is 3 percent and one is 6 percent, that becomes
just too big, and over time it can have huge competitive
effects, Dimon said on the conference call with analysts. We
always ran with higher capital and liquidity than most of our
competitors. </p>
<p>JPMorgan said it plans to be in line with the holding
company standard by the first quarter of 2015. The company plans
to bring the federally insured bank subsidiary into compliance
by the end of that year, Lake said. </p>
<h2>Dividends </h2>
<p>The bank said it can increase its holding company leverage
ratio by 60 basis points, or 0.6 percentage points, with capital
generated from earnings through the next six quarters if it
keeps payouts to shareholders constant. JPMorgan could also
boost the ratio as much as 1 percentage point by issuing
preferred shares and making adjustments such as unwinding
derivative bets, according to the bank''s presentation. </p>
<p>Dimon said the company can achieve the new ratios and
accelerate share buybacks and dividends over the next few years. </p>
<p>The proposed U.S. rule will add unfunded commitments and
some derivatives exposure to banks'' stated assets. That will
increase JPMorgan''s total assets by about $1 trillion from the
$2.4 trillion on its balance sheet. </p>
<p>The Basel committee has proposed additional increases to
asset calculations, which Lake said could have a not
insignificant impact on the ratio. Lake also said there is a
strong argument that the firm''s more than $450 billion of
cash and highly liquid assets should be excluded from the
calculation. </p>
<p>The leverage ratio provides an additional measure of
capital to Basel III ratios that weight assets based on risk,
which results in an asset figure that is half of that under the
leverage ratio. The firm said its Basel III Tier 1 common ratio
climbed to 9.3 percent and plans to reach 9.5 percent by the end
of the year. </p>
<p>We believe the leverage ratio is an appropriate
complement to a Tier 1 common ratio, if properly calibrated,
Lake said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki and Michael J. Moore" date="Jul 12, 2013  7:12 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-12/jpmorgan-investment-bank-s-1st-half-pay-little-changed.html"><headline>JPMorgan Investment Bank''s 1st-Half Pay Little Changed</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s corporate and
investment bank allocated almost the same amount of money for
employees in the first half from a year earlier as the
division''s revenue climbed 9 percent. </p>
<p>The unit''s $6.36 billion in first-half compensation costs
amounted to 33 percent of revenue, excluding accounting
adjustments, down from 34 percent in the prior year, according
to figures posted today on the New York-based firm''s website.
The amount is equal to $122,926 for each of the division''s
51,771 employees in the six months. The unit had 52,336
employees a year ago. </p>
<p>JPMorgan, the biggest U.S. bank by assets, combined its
investment bank with the corporate bank and treasury and
securities-services units last year under co-heads Mike Cavanagh, 47, and Daniel Pinto, 50. The group has more than
twice as many employees as the investment bank. </p>
<p>The amount set aside for compensation includes salaries,
bonuses, benefits and the cost of deferred pay from previous
years. Figures for average pay don''t represent what individuals
actually receive and are calculated by dividing the total
compensation expense by the number of employees. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bloomberg News" date="Jul 12, 2013  5:18 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-12/general-motors-outsells-volkswagen-in-china-in-first-six-months.html"><headline>General Motors Outsells Volkswagen in China in First Six Months</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>General Motors Co. (GM) outsold
Volkswagen AG (VOW) in China in the first half, helped by an increase
in demand for Buick and Cadillac vehicles. </p>
<p>Volkswagen, which unlike GM includes Hong Kong and Macau in
its China figures, today reported first-half sales in China rose
19 percent to 1.54 million vehicles. That compares with the 1.57
million deliveries reported by GM. </p>
<p>The result keeps GM on track to maintain its annual sales
lead among foreign automakers in China for a ninth straight
year. Both companies count the country as their largest market
and have forecast sales of about three million vehicles each
this year. They are locked in a race with Toyota Motor Corp. (7203) to
be the world''s biggest automaker. </p>
<p>Volkswagen, whose stable of brands include its namesake
marque and the premium Audi nameplate, joined GM in outpacing
the 14 percent gain in total Chinese passenger-vehicle sales in
the January-to-June period. </p>
<p>We plan to keep adding new and refreshed models this year
to maintain growth momentum and meet rising demand in China,
Bob Socia, president of GM China, said in a statement. </p>
<p>Both automakers have announced more investments in China to
expand production. GM, which broke ground on a Cadillac assembly
plant in Shanghai last month, will spend $11 billion in China by
2016 on new plants and products, while Volkswagen plans to spend
9.8 billion euros ($12.8 billion) by 2015. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Victoria Slind-Flor" date="Jul 15, 2013 10:47 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-15/microsoft-bskyb-orthodox-union-intellectual-property.html"><headline>Microsoft, BSkyB, Orthodox Union: Intellectual Property</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. filed a lawsuit July
12 accusing U.S. Customs officials of refusing to follow a trade
agency''s order to block imports of phones made by Google Inc.''s
Motorola Mobility unit. </p>
<p>The U.S. International Trade Commission in Washington
issued the import ban in May 2012 after deciding that Motorola
Mobility devices infringed a Microsoft patent for a way mobile
phones synchronize calendar events with other computers. </p>
<p>U.S. Customs and Border Protection, after secret meetings
with Google, continued to let the Motorola Mobility phones enter
the country even though Google has done nothing to remove the
feature at the heart of the ITC case, Microsoft said in its
complaint. The case illustrates what Lexmark International Inc. (LXK)
and Lutron Electronics Co. in May called increasingly
ineffective and unpredictable enforcement of import bans
imposed by the trade agency. </p>
<p>Motorola Mobility convinced the agency that the order
didn''t apply to syncing through Google rather than Microsoft
servers, and to give it a grace period to allow changes to take
effect. Both of those requests had previously been rejected by
the ITC, according to Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft. </p>
<p>The ITC order is in effect until Microsoft''s patent expires
in April 2018. An appeal in the case is scheduled to be heard
Aug. 6 in Washington. </p>
<p>Meetings between Mountain View, California-based Google and
Customs were held in secret in April, with Microsoft not privy
to their existence until after the Customs decision June 24
allowing the continued importation of the phones, according to
Microsoft''s filings asking the court to halt the Motorola
Mobility shipments. </p>
<p>The ITC''s job is to protect U.S. markets from unfair
competition, including infringement of patents or theft of trade
secrets. It has become a key forum for disputes between
smartphone makers. </p>
<p>Once the import bans are ordered, it''s common for both
patent owners and importers to lobby Customs and neither side is
told what the other is saying for fear of exposing trade
secrets, lawyers involved in ITC cases said in March. </p>
<p>The trade agency is compiling information on how well its
orders are being enforced and President Barack Obama last month
called for a review of procedures within the ITC and Customs. In
their joint letter to the ITC, Lexmark and Lutron said the
current problems with enforcement of orders requires immediate
attention. </p>
<p>The case is Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) v. Department of Homeland
Security, 13-cv-01063, U.S. District Court, District of Columbia
(Washington). </p>
<h2>Faro, Nikon Metrology Settle Suit Over Scanning Technology </h2>
<p>Faro Technologies Inc. (FARO) and Nikon Metrology NV settled a
five-year-old lawsuit over two patents related to scanning
apparatus. </p>
<p>The suit was filed by Nikon Metrology, formerly Metris USA
Inc., in July 2009. The companies compete in the business of
computer-aided three-dimensional measurement technology. In a
July 12 filing in federal court in Boston, Faro said it reached
a settlement with Nikon Metrology and withdrew its motion for
attorney fees. No other details were given </p>
<p>In August, a jury in Boston found that Lake Mary, Florida-based Faro hadn''t infringed patent 7,313,264. The court
previously found, on a motion by Faro, that patent 6,611,617
wasn''t infringed. </p>
<p>Nikon Metrology, based in Leuven, Belgium, asked the court
to overturn the verdict or grant a new trial. When both those
requests were rejected, the company turned to the U.S. Court of
Appeals for the Federal Circuit, the Washington-based court that
hears appeals of patent disputes. </p>
<p>Faro said in a statement that the parties to the settlement
agreement agreed to keep the terms confidential. </p>
<p>The case is Metris U.S.A. Inc. v. Faro Technologies, 08-cv-11187, U.S. District Court, District of Massachusetts
(Boston). </p>
<p>For more patent news, click here. </p>
<h2>Trademark </h2>
<p>BSkyB Says M7 Group''s Skylink Service Infringes Sky'' Trademarks </p>
<p>British Sky Broadcasting Group Plc (BSY) is challenging
Luxembourg''s M7 Group''s use of Skylink for its direct-to-home satellite television program in the Czech Republic and
Slovakia, the Advanced Television news website reported. </p>
<p>The U.K.-based British Sky claims the term infringed its
sky trademark used with its BSkyB TV services, according to
Advanced Television. </p>
<p>Earlier a U.K. court found that Microsoft Corp.''s use of
Skydrive for its cloud storage system infringed British
Sky''s U.K. and European Union trademarks, the website reported. </p>
<p>A spokesman for British Sky told Advanced Television that
the Middlesex, U.K.-based company regarded any unauthorized use
of Sky as an infringement. </p>
<p>Namco Bandai Seeks European Registration for Lost Swords'' Mark </p>
<p>Namco Bandai Holdings Inc. (7832)''s Namco Bandai Games unit has
applied to register Lost Swords as a trademark in Europe. </p>
<p>The Japanese maker of computer games said in its
application that the name would be used for video-game machines,
amusement-park services, and games and related software. </p>
<p>Among the games produced by the Tokyo-based company are
Ultimate Ninja, Pac-Man and the Ghostly Adventures, Dark Souls
and Armored Core Verdict Day. </p>
<p>The company produces games for consoles produced by Sony
Corp. (6758), Nintendo Co. and Microsoft Corp., as well as Apple Inc.''s
iPhone and mobile phones using Google Inc.''s (GOOG) Android operating
system. </p>
<h2>Orthodox Group Sues Israeli Company Over Use of Kosher Mark </h2>
<p>The Union of Orthodox Jewish Congregations in America''s OU
Kashruth unit filed a trademark infringement suit against
Israeli food manufacturer Better  Different Ltd., Jewish
Business News reported. </p>
<p>The suit, which was filed in Israel, claims that Better 
Different of Maale Edummim used the Union''s trademark
designating kosher food -- the letter U circled by the letter O
-- without paying licensing fees, according to Jewish Business
News. </p>
<p>The Union said Better  Different continued to use the mark
during 2012 and 2013, Jewish Business News reported. </p>
<p>The Union has asked the court to order the destruction of
infringing packaging, the recall of products bearing the mark
without authorization, licensing fees for the allegedly
unauthorized use of the mark for the past three years and money
damages, according to Jewish Business News. </p>
<p>For more trademark news, click here. </p>
<h2>Copyright </h2>
<h2>Marilyn Monroe Photo Auction to Include Copyrights </h2>
<p>More than 3,700 unpublished black-and-white and color
negatives and slides from photographer Milton H. Greene''s images
of the late Marilyn Monroe are going up for auction in Los
Angeles on July 27, the Associated Press reported. </p>
<p>What makes the auction unusual is that in addition to the
images themselves, the copyrights are also being sold, making it
possible for the buyer to create additional prints and sell or
license them, AP said. </p>
<p>Greene shot more than 5,000 images of the actress, who died
in August 1962. He didn''t commercialize his work and only a
handful of pictures were published in his lifetime, Joseph
Madelena told AP. </p>
<p>Madelena is the owner of Profiles in History, the auction
house that is holding the sale, AP reported. </p>
<h2>Vatican Should Use Creative Commons for Encyclical, Blogger Says </h2>
<p>A blogger who made downloadable copies of Pope Francis''s
recent encyclical -- Lumen Fides -- available on his website
is calling for new guidelines for the release of papal documents
after being warned he was infringing the Vatican''s copyright. </p>
<p>Brandon Vogt, author of The Church and New Media:
Blogging Converts, Online Activists, and Bishops Who Tweet,
put the text to the encyclical on BrandonVogt.com July 5, the
date the Vatican released this papal letter to the Roman
Catholic Church and to the world. </p>
<p>Vogt had converted the text to multiple formats for
downloading, including for Apple Inc. (AAPL)''s iPad, Amazon.com Inc.''s
Kindle e-reader and Barnes  Noble Inc. (BKS)''s Nook. The letter is
unusual in that it''s the work of both Pope Francis and his
immediate predecessor, the recently retired Pope Benedict XVI. </p>
<p>Vogt said that within hours he heard from both the U.S.
Conference of Catholic Bishops and the Vatican, who accused him
of violating both civil and moral law and stealing from
the pope. They ordered him to remove the document from his
blog immediately. </p>
<p>In a response on his blog, he said that while he was clear
the Vatican and the bishops'' conference weren''t wrong to assert
their copyright to the encyclical, there must be a better way to
make the text available. </p>
<p>Vogt suggested that all such church documents be released
under a Creative Commons license. That would protect the
integrity of the document, while allowing people free access to
share it. </p>
<p>He said that under a Creative Commons license, people may
copy, distribute, display, and perform only verbatim copies of
the work and that according to the Creative Commons website,
more than 400 million licenses have deployed. </p>
<p>For more copyright news, click here. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Grant Smith" date="Jul 15, 2013 10:08 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-15/goldman-sees-risk-of-oil-prices-gaining-amid-opec-supply-losses.html"><headline>Goldman Sees Risk of Oil Prices Gaining Amid OPEC Supply Losses</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) said price
risks for Brent crude in the second half of the year have
changed to the upside amid production losses in some OPEC
nations and political threats to supply. </p>
<p>Reductions in output from Libya, Iraq and Nigeria have the
potential to limit availability, the bank said today in an e-mailed report. Even so, increased production outside the
Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries will probably keep
global markets adequately supplied this year, said Goldman,
which forecasts Brent crude to average $105 a barrel in the
second half. Brent futures traded at about $108 a barrel in
London today. </p>
<p>The risks have shifted more to the upside over the short
term due to the possibility of continuing OPEC production
shortfalls and increased geopolitical risks, Jeff Currie, the
head of commodities research in New York, said in the report. </p>
<p>OPEC output fell by 370,000 barrels a day in June amid
unrest and violence in Libya, Iraq and Nigeria, the
International Energy Agency said in its most recent monthly
market report on July 11. The losses come just as increasing
seasonal demand for motor fuels is pushing up global oil
consumption, Goldman said. OPEC supplies about 40 percent of the
world''s crude. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Phil Milford" date="Jul 15, 2013 10:07 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-15/disney-settles-antitrust-suit-over-recruiting-from-rivals.html"><headline>Disney Settles Antitrust Suit Over Recruiting From Rivals</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Units of Walt Disney Co. (DIS), the
world''s largest theme-park operator, tentatively settled a
lawsuit alleging they violated U.S. antitrust law by agreeing
with competitors not to recruit one another''s employees. </p>
<p>Animation studio Pixar and visual-effects specialist
Lucasfilm Ltd. told U.S. District Judge Lucy Koh in San Jose,
California, they agreed to settle all claims, according to court
papers filed July 12. </p>
<p>The parties anticipate completing documentation of the
proposed settlement and presenting it for the court''s
consideration in the near future, plaintiffs'' lawyers said in
a letter to Koh. </p>
<p>A group of high-tech employees sued the companies
complaining that industry agreements not to pursue cross-hires
amounted to a conspiracy to fix and suppress the compensation
of their employees, according to an amended complaint filed on
Sept. 13, 2011. </p>
<p>Zenia Mucha, a spokeswoman for Burbank, California-based
Disney, didn''t immediately reply to an e-mail and a voice-mail
message seeking comment on the settlement. </p>
<p>The case is In Re High-Tech Employee Antitrust Litigation,
11-cv-02509, U.S. District Court, Northern District of
California (San Jose). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sherine El Madany" date="Jul 15, 2013  7:17 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-15/goldman-buy-rating-spurs-air-arabia-to-5-year-high-dubai-mover.html"><headline>Goldman Buy Rating Spurs Air Arabia to 5-Year High: Dubai Mover</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Air Arabia PJSC (AIRARABI) surged to the
highest level in almost five years as volume jumped after
Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) upgraded the Middle East''s biggest no-frills carrier to buy. </p>
<p>Shares of the airline jumped 5.1 percent to 1.23 dirhams,
the strongest since October 2008, at the close in Dubai as
volume increased to 122 million shares, 4.9 times the stock''s
three-month daily average. Air Arabia was the biggest gainer in
percentage terms on the benchmark DFM General Index (DFMGI), which rose
0.7 percent, taking an eight-day rally to 8.7 percent. </p>
<p>Air Arabia''s stock has advanced 7.9 percent in the two days
since Goldman Sachs raised the shares to buy from neutral with a
price estimate of 1.54 dirhams, a 25 percent premium to today''s
closing price. Nine out of 13 analysts have a buy rating on the
carrier, which is based in Sharjah, United Arab Emirates,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. The U.A.E. and Qatar
were upgraded to emerging-market status last month by MSCI Inc. (MSCI) </p>
<p>Both the rating upgrade and the MSCI emerging-markets
inclusion spurred the shares today, according to Amer Khan, a
Dubai-based director at Shuaa Asset Management. Dubai''s bid to
host the World Expo 2020 may be the next catalyst, which would
bode particularly well for the likes of Air Arabia, he said. </p>
<p>Dubai plans to double the number of visitors to 20 million
by 2020 and triple annual revenue from the industry to 300
billion dirhams ($82 billion) amid an economic recovery, the
government said in May. </p>
<p>Air Arabia''s first-quarter passenger traffic rose to a
record 1.45 million, the airline said in April. The company said
last month it plans to start flights to the capital of Armenia
in August, the fifth new route in 2013 and its 86th globally
from Sharjah, Egypt and Morocco. </p>
<p>The airline may post a 9 percent increase in full-year
profit to 457 million dirhams, according to the mean estimate of
eight analysts compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bob Van Voris" date="Jul 15, 2013 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-15/goldman-sachs-s-fabulous-fab-faces-sec-fraud-trial-today.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs''s Fabulous Fab Faces SEC Fraud Trial Today</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Fabrice Tourre, the ex-Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) vice president whose congressional testimony put a face on the complex structured investments that contributed to the 2008 financial crisis, is set to face trial today on allegations he misled investors. </p> <p>Tourre, dubbed Fabulous Fab by a friend, faces fraud claims in a U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission lawsuit over his role in Abacus 2007-AC1, a synthetic collateralized debt obligation tied to home mortgages. The trial comes three years to the day after the SEC announced Goldman Sachs''s agreement to pay a then-record $550 million settlement and admit mistakes in marketing Abacus. </p> <p>Jurors will want to know whether Tourre intentionally misled customers, said Ernest Badway, a former SEC enforcement attorney with the Philadelphia-based law firm Fox Rothschild LLP. They''re going to look to see if he said something that he knew to be untrue, Badway said. </p> <p>Tourre, now studying for a doctorate in economics at the University of Chicago, spent part of the time waiting for trial working for a relief organization in Kigali, Rwanda. Since Goldman Sachs settled, he has stood alone against the government''s claims that he misled investors by failing to tell them that the hedge fund Paulson  Co. helped select the assets underlying Abacus while betting they would decline in value. </p>




Photographer: Jin Lee/Bloomberg

<p>
Fabrice Tourre, former trader with Goldman Sachs Group Inc., now studying for a doctorate in economics at the University of Chicago, spent part of the time waiting for trial working for a relief organization in Kigali, Rwanda. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Patricia Hurtado" date="Jul 16, 2013  8:56 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-16/chevron-judge-denies-ecuadoreans-request-for-trial-delay.html"><headline>Chevron Judge Denies Ecuadoreans'' Request for Trial Delay</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX)''s civil racketeering
case against Ecuadoreans it accuses of fabricating evidence to
win a $19 billion verdict in a pollution lawsuit will go to
trial on Oct. 15, a judge said in rejecting a defense request
for a delay. </p>
<p>Chevron sued Ecuadoreans who had earlier claimed the San
Ramon, California-based company was responsible for pollution in
the Amazon rainforest. The company said the Ecuadoreans and
their New York-based lawyer, Steven Donziger, made up evidence
in the initial case. The trial will be held in Manhattan federal
court. </p>
<p>U.S. District Judge Lewis Kaplan today denied Donziger''s
request to delay the trial in order to find a new attorney.
Kaplan said Donziger has had four months to hire a new lawyer
since his prior counsel, John Keker, asked to leave the case
because he hadn''t been paid. </p>
<p>It is unclear whether he has money to pay counsel but
chooses not to spend it, or whether he in fact does not have
money, Kaplan said of Donziger in a written opinion. Donziger
has offered no competent evidence of his financial
situation, the judge said. </p>
<p>Chevron was ordered by an Ecuadorean court in 2011 to pay
as much as $18.2 billion in damages for Texaco''s alleged dumping
of toxic drilling waste in the jungle from 1964 to about 1992.
Chevron acquired Texaco in 2000. </p>
<h2>$19 Billion </h2>
<p>The judgment came in an 18-year lawsuit decided by a judge
in Lago Agrio, a provincial capital near the Colombian border.
With interest, the judgment is now worth $19 billion. </p>
<p>Chevron denied wrongdoing, saying Texaco cleaned up its
share of pollution at oil fields that were later taken over
PetroEcuador, Ecuador''s state-owned oil company. Chevron says it
was released from liability by an agreement between Texaco and
Ecuador. </p>
<p>In denying the defense request to postpone the October
trial, Kaplan today said the Ecuadorean plaintiffs are still
financing litigation in courts around the world. </p>
<p>Donziger and the plaintiffs claim they are out of
money, Kaplan said. To the contrary, the record establishes
that they have raised millions of dollars in exchange for shares
of any recovery. </p>
<h2>Claims Influence </h2>
<p>Chevron accuses Donziger of improperly influencing a court
expert whose findings were relied upon by the judge in Ecuador. </p>
<p>Donziger denies wrongdoing, and plaintiffs in the pollution
case said the company is attacking him to avoid paying damages. </p>
<p>Bill Hamilton of Fenton Communications, a spokesman for the
Ecuadorean plaintiffs, declined to comment on Kaplan''s ruling. </p>
<p>We look forward to detailing the extent of fraud and
misconduct carried out by the plaintiffs and their U.S.-based
lawyers at trial in October, Morgan Crinklaw, a Chevron
spokesman, said in an e-mailed statement. '' </p>
<p>The racketeering case is Chevron v. Donziger, 1:11-cv-00691, U.S. District Court, Southern District of New York
(Manhattan). The case in Ecuador is Aquinda v. Chevron,
002-2003, Superior Court of Nueva Loja, Lago Agrio, Ecuador. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Jul 16, 2013  6:37 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-16/microsoft-says-it-doesn-t-hand-nsa-secret-encryption-keys.html"><headline>Microsoft Says It Doesn''t Give NSA Secret Encryption Keys</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), addressing
persistent concerns that it has helped the U.S. government
gather customer information, said it doesn''t provide direct
access to e-mails, instant messages or Skype calls and refuses
to grant agencies the ability to break its encryption. </p>
<p>In a letter today to U.S. Attorney General Eric Holder, the
company asked for permission to share more information on its
communication with government agencies, saying it has a
constitutional right to do so. Microsoft said such permission
has been delayed and asked Holder for personal help. </p>
<p>Microsoft and technology companies Apple Inc. (AAPL), Facebook
Inc. (FB) and Yahoo! Inc. have come under scrutiny since a former
U.S. National Security Agency contractor said publicly last
month that the NSA is collecting user data. Microsoft said that
while it''s limited in what it can disclose about communications,
the company doesn''t grant access to servers and only provides
governments with specific information about requests. That
includes data from its SkyDrive cloud service. </p>
<p>We do not provide any government with the ability to
break the encryption, nor do we provide the government with the
encryption keys, Microsoft General Counsel Brad Smith said in
a blog post today. When we are legally obligated to comply
with demands, we pull the specified content from our servers
where it sits in an unencrypted state, and then we provide it to
the government agency. </p>
<p>Brian Fallon, Holder''s spokesman, didn''t have an immediate
comment on the letter. </p>
<h2>Guardian Report </h2>
<p>Last week, the Guardian reported that Microsoft has helped
the NSA get around the company''s own encryption, citing
documents obtained by the newspaper. </p>
<p>Microsoft, the world''s biggest software maker, also said
that when it receives a request for information held by a
corporate customer, the company redirects the government to the
client, unless prohibited from doing so. The Redmond,
Washington-based company said it has never provided information
on a corporate customer for national security purposes and
complied with four requests in 2012 related to criminal law
enforcement. </p>
<p>Since the NSA documents were leaked, Microsoft has held
talks with the Justice Department, Federal Bureau of
Investigation and others in the intelligence community about
which issues the company can publicly address, Smith wrote in
the letter. </p>
<p>Microsoft rose 0.3 percent to $36.27 at the close in New
York and has gained 36 percent this year. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chris Dolmetsch" date="Jul 16, 2013  4:41 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-16/morgan-stanley-told-to-face-metlife-mortgage-securities-suit.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Told to Face MetLife MBS Suit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) was ordered by a New
York judge to face a suit by MetLife Inc., the largest U.S. life
insurer, over $758 million in residential mortgage-backed
securities. </p>
<p>Justice Eileen Bransten in state Supreme Court in Manhattan
denied New York-based Morgan Stanley''s motion to dismiss
MetLife''s (MET) claims of fraud, fraudulent inducement and aiding and
abetting fraud. The July 8 ruling was made public today. </p>
<p>MetLife, based in New York, sued Morgan Stanley in April
2012, accusing the investment bank of fraud and other claims
involving in residential mortgage-backed securities purchased in
nine offerings in 2006 and 2007. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley didn''t immediately respond to an e-mail
seeking comment on the ruling. </p>
<p>The case is Metropolitan Life Insurance Co. v. Morgan
Stanley, 651360/2012, New York State Supreme Court, New York
County (Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Daniel Cancel" date="Jul 16, 2013  4:39 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-16/chevron-shale-talk-makes-ypf-best-performer-buenos-aires-mover.html"><headline>Chevron Shale Talk Makes YPF Best Performer: Buenos Aires Mover</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>YPF SA rose the most among major
Argentine stocks on speculation the state-run energy company
will sign the first binding partnership to develop shale oil and
natural gas since its nationalization a year ago. </p>
<p>The shares gained 3.5 percent to 137.50 pesos in Buenos
Aires, the highest closing price since March last year.
Argentina''s benchmark index rose 1.4 percent. </p>
<p>YPF, the best performer this month among 15 global peers
tracked by Bloomberg, will sign today an accord with Chevron
Corp. (CVX) in a ceremony to be attended by President Cristina Fernandez de Kirchner and Chevron Chairman and Chief Executive
Officer John Watson, newspaper El Cronista reported, citing a
government official it didn''t identify. Yesterday the government
said it will offer energy companies incentives if they invest $1
billion or more over a five-year period. </p>
<p>The stock is rallying on the Chevron agreement and the
government decree, Carlos Aszpis, an equity strategist at
Schweber  Cia. Sociedad de Bolsa SA, said by telephone from
Buenos Aires. There''s been a nice combination of headlines
driving the move. </p>
<p>A definitive deal with Chevron, the world''s second-biggest
oil company, would help YPF tap the world''s second-largest shale
gas deposit and fourth-largest shale oil reservoir as the
country struggles to lift output and pare fuel imports. In a
preliminary arrangement, the ventures''s initial investments were
estimated at $1.5 billion. </p>
<h2>Independence Goal </h2>
<p>Watson will travel to Argentina to sign the deal between
July 15 and July 16, Jorge Sapag, governor of Neuquen province
where the Vaca Muerta shale formation is located, said on June
26. Jim Craig, a spokesman for Chevron, couldn''t immediately be
reached by phone for comment today. A YPF official who isn''t
authorized to speak publicly said he didn''t have any information
on when the agreement will be signed. </p>
<p>Fernandez''s government seized a 51 percent stake in YPF
from Spain''s Repsol SA (REP) in April 2012 to stem fuel imports that
doubled to $9.4 billion in 2011 and are expected to rise to as
much as $15 billion this year. </p>
<p>Chevron''s investment will help make Argentina energy
independent, Ali Moshiri, Chevron''s head of Latin America,
Middle East and Africa, said May 16, after touring the shale
formation in southwestern Argentina. </p>
<p>Vaca Muerta, Spanish for dead cow, may hold at least 23
billion barrels of oil equivalent, according to a report by
independent auditor Ryder Scott released in February 2012 by
YPF. </p>
<p>YPF''s American depositary receipts rose 2.3 percent to
$16.27 in New York, the highest since Feb. 20. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Duane D. Stanford" date="Jul 16, 2013  4:19 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-16/coca-cola-profit-declines-as-european-sales-volumes-fall.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Profit Hit as Global Economy, Weather Misbehave</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Coca-Cola Co. (KO) said profit fell 4 percent last quarter, the second decline in a row, as sales were sapped by economic weakness in China and Europe, shifting tastes in the U.S. and unseasonable weather in places such as India. </p> <p>Coca-Cola has long touted its broad geographic reach and ability to make up for sluggish sales in one market with increases elsewhere. The second-quarter results show there''s a limit to that strategy, especially when Mother Nature and global economic forces refuse to cooperate. </p> <p>This was a confluence of events, Chief Executive Officer Muhtar Kent said today during a conference call. The portfolio effect of our global business did not work in our favor in this particular case. </p> <p>To counter slower growth, Kent said he''s speeding up efforts in China and other emerging markets to expand Coca-Cola''s reach by adding smaller, more affordable package sizes. He said the company has not pulled back on marketing and advertising to blunt losses. </p> <p>This is more of an anomaly, we should not see this as a trend or a systemic issue, Kent said. </p> <p>In India, for example, monsoons swamped sales, especially given unusually high growth one year ago after the monsoon season came late, Kent said. In Brazil, consumer spending was depressed by a credit crisis, he said. </p>




Photographer: Patrick Fallon/Bloomberg

<p>
Chief Executive Officer Muhtar Kent has tried to raise pricing to make up for weaker demand. Sales volume in Europe declined 4 percent, hurt by a slow economy, Coca-Cola said. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarika Gangar" date="Jul 16, 2013  4:19 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-16/goldman-sachs-raises-2-5-billion-with-sale-of-five-year-bonds.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Raises $2.5 Billion With Sale of Five-Year Bonds</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), the Wall
Street bank that generates most of its revenue from trading,
sold $2.5 billion of five-year bonds after reporting second-quarter profits that beat analysts'' estimates. </p>
<p>The 2.9 percent notes, expected to be rated A3 by Moody''s
Investors Service, yield 155 basis points more than similar-maturity Treasuries, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs sold $2.75 billion of 2.375 percent
debentures due 2018 in January that were priced to yield 165
basis points more than benchmarks, Bloomberg data show. Those
securities traded yesterday at 98.8 cents on the dollar to yield
2.66 percent, or a 127.7 basis-point spread, according to Trace,
the bond-price reporting system of the Financial Industry
Regulatory Authority. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs said today that earnings doubled on a surge
in underwriting revenue and gains from the firm''s own
investments. Second-quarter net income rose to $1.93 billion, or
$3.70 a share, from $962 million, or $1.78, a year earlier. That
beat the $2.89 average estimate of 27 analysts in a Bloomberg
survey. </p>
<p>Proceeds will be used for general corporate purposes,
according to a person with knowledge of the transaction who
asked not to be identified because terms aren''t set. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jul 16, 2013  4:06 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-16/goldman-beats-estimates-on-rise-in-trading-investment-banking.html"><headline>Goldman Beats Estimates on Investment Banking, Debt Gains</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) said earnings doubled, beating analysts'' estimates on a surge in underwriting revenue and gains from the firm''s own investments. </p> <p>Second-quarter net income rose to $1.93 billion, or $3.70 a share, from $962 million, or $1.78, a year earlier, the New York-based company said today in a statement. That beat the $2.89 average estimate of 27 analysts in a Bloomberg survey. </p> <p>Gains from debt investments almost tripled and fixed-income trading climbed 12 percent as Chief Executive Officer Lloyd C. Blankfein, 58, led Goldman Sachs through a drop in bond prices sparked by indications in May that the Federal Reserve may ease economic-stimulus measures. The bank has said it will benefit from expense cuts completed last year and a rebound in the U.S. economy that could fuel stock gains. </p> <p>Look ahead, and the opportunity is really on risk-taking moving from debt to equity, and that plays very much into Goldman''s strengths, Kenneth Leon, an analyst at Standard  Poor''s Capital IQ unit, told Erik Schatzker and Sara Eisen in an interview on Bloomberg Television. Directionally Goldman looks good. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs fell $2.76, or 1.7 percent, to $160.24 at 4:04 p.m. in New York. The stock had gained 28 percent this year through yesterday after advancing 41 percent in 2012. The shares are still below their pre-crisis peak of $247.92 on Oct. 31, 2007. </p>




Photographer: Jin Lee/Bloomberg

<p>
Goldman Sachs Group Inc. signage is displayed on the floor of the New York Stock Exchange in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elizabeth Douglass And David Hasemyer" date="Jul 16, 2013  1:12 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-16/exxon-secrecy-over-ruptured-pipeline-may-mask-national-danger.html"><headline>Exxon Secrecy Over Ruptured Pipeline May Mask National Danger</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>InsideClimateNews.org -- The 1940s-era construction process that ExxonMobil said caused an oil pipe to rupture in Arkansas earlier this year is a common and well-documented problem the pipeline industry has battled for decadesand one the industry believes can be detected and controlled with appropriate vigilance.</p><p>"With proper inspection and maintenance, these catastrophic events can be prevented," said Mohammad Najafi, a pipeline construction expert and engineering professor at the University of Texas at Arlington. "As pipelines exceed their design lives, they need more maintenance and a proper asset management strategy to prevent or minimize these ruptures."</p><p>That leaves the public and regulators with two critical questions: Did Exxon manage and test its broken Pegasus pipeline according to established guidelines? And, if it did, is the Arkansas accident a warning that other pipelines might be at risk?</p><p>If so, the repercussions would be nationwide, since many of the nation''s liquid fuel and natural gas pipelines are of similar vintage and were built using the same inferior construction techniques. The gas line that ruptured in San Bruno, Calif. in September 2010, killing eight people and destroying 38 homes, included segments made with the same process as the Pegasus pipe. Investigators foundthat the pipeline''s owner, Pacific Gas  Electric, had neglected to properly inspect and repair the line and that regulators issued testing exemptions and placed "blind trust" in the company''s assurances.</p><p>Recent maintenance and testing records for the Pegasus, as well as the metal analysis report that blamed the accident primarily on a 65-year-old manufacturing defect, would offer important insight into why the pipeline failed. Those documents, however, are being withheld from the public as well as from a Congressional committee, two Arkansas Congressmen and a water utility worried that the pipeline could foul drinking water for nearly half a million people.</p><p>Exxon has given pertinent data to the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration (PHMSA), the federal agency that regulates the nation''s pipelines, and to Arkansas Attorney General Dustin McDaniel (in response to a subpoena). But Exxon says the two most recent inspections it conducted on the Pegasus are proprietary and confidential, so they shouldn''t be shared with the public.</p><p>InsideClimate News has filed a formal request with PHMSA for the metallurgy report, along with a Federal Freedom of Information Act request for additional documents connected to the spill investigation.</p><p>PHMSA hasn''t responded to the Freedom of Information Act request, which was filed in early June, and has refused to release the metallurgy report, citing the agency''s ongoing investigation of the accident. Exxon spokesman Aaron Stryk said the company is concerned only about keeping the inspection reports private. As far as the metallurgy report is concerned, "it is up to PHMSA when to make that publicly available," he said.</p><p>Jonathan Phillips, senior policy adviser for the House Natural Resources Committee, rejects the notion that the records should be kept from public view. </p><p>"If there is information about the chance of this becoming a pattern, then it is information that should be made known," he said. "Without that information, how do you know?"</p><blockquote>"You can only play the secrecy card for so long."<blockquote/><p>Exxon tested the Pegasus just a few weeks before the spill by sending a sophisticated inspection device called a pig through the line to look for flaws from the inside. Pipeline owners and regulators rely on pigs to detect corrosion, and specialized pigs are increasingly used to find potentially dangerous seam weld and other pipeline cracks. </p><p>If the pigs used by Exxon in 2010 and 2013 both failed to detect the crack that turned into a 22-foot breach, it will cast doubt on their reliability for seam weld inspection.</p><p>Carl Weimer, executive director of the Pipeline Safety Trust, a nonprofit watchdog organization based in Bellingham, Wash., said Exxon''s February test should have flagged the defect that ripped open the pipe.</p><p>"If it wasn''t detected, then that says maybe there is no way of finding these flaws," Weimer said.</p><p>The section that failed was constructed using low frequency electric resistance welded (ERW) pipe to create long seams down the length of the pipe. The technique was discontinued by 1970.</p><p>Not all the pipelines of that vintage and built that way have defects, but they are all suspect and require constant monitoring to avoid disaster, experts say. Several industry reports offer step-by-step guidelines for monitoring and maintaining pipelines with these specific flaws.</p><p>Richard Kuprewicz, president of the pipeline consulting firm Accufacts Inc., said the known pipe manufacturing defects is like being predisposed to a grave illness.</p><p>"It may be a dormant gene or it may be an active gene," Kuprewicz said. Depending on how you treat and test the pipeline, "It may go to cancer, or you could live your entire life and it''s not a problem."</p><p>Worrisome Regulatory Gap</p><p>Interest in the information being withheld from public view is keenest in Mayflower, Ark., where the Pegasus pipeline split open on March 29, sending an estimated 5,000 barrelsor 210,000 gallonsof sticky oil-like Canadian diluted bitumen, or dilbit, into a nearby lake and neighborhood, sickening residents and forcing 22 families to flee their homes. It''s also been a longtime concern for Central Arkansas Water, because more than 13 miles of the Pegasus line cross through a utility watershed that serves 400,000 people in the Little Rock area.</p><p>"We need to know what factors led to the rupture, and [have] assurances that those factors do not exist in the watershed," said John Tynan, watershed protection manager for Central Arkansas Water. "We want to do this through our own third party evaluation of the information."</p><p>Officials at Central Arkansas Water asked to review Pegasus inspection records, but the request was rebuffed. The water utility wants the pipeline re-routed around the watershed. </p><p>The Pegasus pipeline stretches 850 miles from Illinois to Texas, and carries up to 90,000 barrels per day of dilbit from Alberta''s landlocked tar sands. Its unusually long outagefour months so faris already costly for Exxon, and threatens to become more so as its actions are scrutinized by regulators, the public and theEnvironmental Protection Agency, which has sued Exxon alleging that it violated the Clean Water Act. A second lawsuit, filed by the state of Arkansas, accuses the company of violating state environmental regulations.</p><p>For Canadian oil producers, the idled pipeline is exacerbating a costly gap between pipeline capacity and booming production. What''s more, the Pegasus rupture gives more ammunition to those who oppose construction of the controversial Keystone XL pipeline, which would carry dilbit from Canada to Texas.</p><p>Last week, Exxon said the metallurgy report from an independent laboratoryfound that "original manufacturing defects" caused the Pegasus pipe seam to break apart in Arkansas. The lab also found that the pipeline was especially brittle, which limits the metal''s ability to flex with changes in pressure or flow inside the line. Exxon said the report included "no findings that indicate internal or external corrosion contributed to the failure."</p><p>Exxon and PHMSA are conducting further tests to determine what else might have contributed to the pipeline''s failure.</p><p>The section of the pipeline that burst was built in the late 1940s and originally ferried crude oil from the Gulf northward. After joining together with segments built in 1954 and 1973, the Pegasus carried oil from Nederland, Texas north to Patoka, Ill. For four years, from 2002 to 2006, the pipeline went unused. Then Exxon reversed the pipeline''s flow so it could carry a different product, Canadian dilbit, to Gulf Coast refineries.</p><p>Three years later, in 2009, Exxon reactivated and upgraded pumping stations and other equipment so it could push 50 percent more dilbit through the 20-inch Pegasus line. The capacity expansion would have included a significant jump in operating pressure and stress on the pipeline, according to Najafi, the engineering professor at University of Texas-Arlington.</p><p>That series of changes did not trigger any regulatory reviews or special testing. PHMSA merely requires pipeline operators to conduct tests at least every five years. The testing methods are at the discretion of pipeline owners. </p><p>"If it''s sound pipe, and you''ve got a good handle on the threat, [reversing flows or increasing pressure] won''t make a difference," said Kuprewicz. "But if you''ve lost control of the anomalies, either by assumptions or you just don''t get it, you are increasing the risk that the pipeline will fail. Is it illegal? No. It''s a judgment call by the pipeline operator."</p><p>That regulatory gap might become more of an issue as more pipeline operators repurpose aging pipelines by reversing the flow and converting natural gas pipelines to carry oil and dilbit.</p><p>A study by the National Petroleum Council for the Department of Energy noted that "integrity issues will become more common dues to a number of age-related issues" such as corrosion and weld seam failures.</p><p>"Pipelines operating outside of their design parameters such as those carrying commodities for which they were not initially designed, or high flow pipelines, are at the greatest risk of integrity issues in the future due to the nature of their operation," the report said.</p><p>There may be special risks for pipelines moving dilbit. In a presentation to the petroleum council earlier this year, PHMSA''s Jeffrey Wiese said a thorough review is needed.</p><p>One of the slides presented by Wiese, the agency''s associate administrator for pipeline safety, said: "We strongly support a rigorous analysis of the unique risks associated with dilbit transportation. Threats posed by this different commodity require thorough understanding. Risk controls for these threats must be robust."</p><p>In 2006, when Exxon reversed the Pegasus line to carry dilbit, it completed a hydrostatic test of the line that caused 12 pipe failures before it passed. The test is designed to force failures to eliminate vulnerabilities that could cause spills when the pipeline is in use. The company''s tests in 2010 and 2013 used the pipeline inspection tools known as pigs, which got their nickname from early models that squealed as they passed through pipes.</p><p>Several industry reports have found that seam failures similar to the Pegasus rupture were caused by "pressure cycle-induced fatigue," a condition that develops when there are large and frequent swings in a pipeline''s internal pressure and flow.</p><p>Pipelines carrying dilbit are prone to more pronounced pressure swings that can activate and accelerate pipeline flaws, according to Kuprewicz. That''s because the chemical composition and viscosity of the product varies by the batch, depending on how much and what type of diluent is mixed into the tar sands.</p><p>In Exxon''s case, the Pegasus failed while operating below its allowed operating pressures, Kuprewicz said. "Which means this seam anomaly grew to a point where even normal operations put it at risk to rupture."</p><p>In the wake of the pipeline accident, PHMSA issued an order that prohibits Exxon from restarting the pipeline until the cause of the rupture is fully understood and adequate protections are in place. Once shipments resume, the pipeline must operate at a lower pressure, PHMSA said.</p><p>Bruce Bullock, director of the Maguire Energy Institute at SMU Cox School of Business in Dallas, said the government and Exxon will need to investigate everything about the pipeline in the coming months, beginning in 1948 when the pipeline was first installed. He likened it to a CSIcrime scene investigationfor pipelines. </p><p>"They have to look at every little detail because in those details might be the clues to what happened," he said.</p><p>"They should be looking at the product that has been put through the line over the years, the operating pressures and checking for any anomalies noted; those kinds of things."</p><p>Kuprewicz said that as the investigation proceeds the public and outside experts should have access to the pertinent reports.</p><p>"You can only play the secrecy card for so long," he said. By denying public access to key information, "all you''re doing is adding suspicion to this."</p><p>Republished with the permission of InsideClimate News, a Pulitzer Prize-winning non-profit news organization that covers energy and climate change issues. Analysis and commentary on The Grid are the views of the author and don''t necessarily reflect the views of Bloomberg News. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jul 16, 2013 12:58 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-16/goldman-sachs-is-comfortable-with-u-s-leverage-ratio.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Is Comfortable'' With U.S. Leverage Ratio</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) Chief
Financial Officer Harvey Schwartz said the firm is very
comfortable with its ability to meet a proposed U.S. minimum
ratio of capital to assets. </p>
<p>Schwartz, speaking on a conference call with analysts and
investors today, declined to estimate where the leverage ratio
stands for the parent company or the bank subsidiary. Under the
U.S. plan, the company would need capital equal to 5 percent of
assets and the bank unit must have 6 percent. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs will wait to see how the U.S. proposal
changes before taking action, Schwartz said. Earlier this year,
he told investors the New York-based bank had benefited from not
acting on a proposed rule on risk weighting for mortgages, a
regulation that was later softened. </p>
<p>This is a proposed rule, so let''s see how the dialogue
goes with regulators, Schwartz said. Predicting rules and
responding can be incredibly costly, you can get wildly
misdirected. </p>
<p>The proposed leverage ratios for the biggest U.S. banks go
beyond the 3 percent global minimum requirement that the Basel
Committee on Banking Supervision approved to help prevent
another financial crisis. The changes would make eight lenders
fund more of their assets with capital that can absorb losses
instead of with borrowed money. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
Goldman Sachs Group Inc., led by Chief Executive Officer Lloyd C. Blankfein, returned $5.55 billion to shareholders last year, according to its annual regulatory filing. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David Voreacos and Patricia Hurtado" date="Jul 16, 2013 12:28 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-16/morgan-stanley-deserves-repayment-from-skowron-court-rules-1-.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Deserves Repayment From Skowron, Court Rules</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley is entitled to
$10.2 million in restitution from Joseph Chip Skowron, a
former hedge fund manager serving a five-year prison term for
insider trading, a U.S. appeals court ruled. </p>
<p>Skowron, 44, asked the U.S. Court of Appeals in Manhattan
to overturn a restitution order imposed by a judge after he
pleaded guilty to conspiring to commit securities fraud and
obstruct justice. U.S. District Judge Denise Cote said Skowron
owed the New York-based bank 20 percent of his salary from 2007
to 2010, or $6.4 million, and $3.8 million in legal fees. </p>
<p>The appellate court today upheld Cote''s ruling that the
compensation is bank property because Skowron manifestly
failed to provide the honest services for which Morgan Stanley
compensated him. Skowron was a manager at Morgan Stanley''s (MS)
FrontPoint Partners LLC until he was charged in April 2011 with
using inside information to avoid $30 million in losses. </p>
<p>Skowron deprived Morgan Stanley of his honest services by
participating in a bribery scheme to obtain inside information
about the progression of medical clinical trials, a three-judge
appellate panel wrote in the opinion. </p>
<p>The bank also deserves payment of its legal fees stemming
from a Securities and Exchange Commission investigation,
according to the panel. Morgan Stanley paid $33 million to
settle with the SEC over Skowron''s illegal trades. </p>




Photographer: Victor J. Blue/Bloomberg

<p>
Morgan Stanley signage is displayed outside of the company''s headquarters in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore and Laura Marcinek" date="Jul 16, 2013  8:02 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-16/goldman-sachs-raises-first-half-pay-less-than-revenue.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Raises First-Half Pay Less Than Revenue</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), the bank that gets most of its revenue from trading, set aside a smaller portion for staff pay in the first half and cut 300 jobs in the second quarter as it seeks to pare expenses. </p> <p>Compensation, which includes salaries, benefits, bonuses and the expense of deferred pay awarded in prior years, rose 10 percent to $8.04 billion in the first six months, the New York-based company said today in a statement. Revenue in the same period increased 13 percent to $18.7 billion. </p> <p>Chief Executive Officer Lloyd C. Blankfein, 58, is controlling expenses to boost return on equity, a measure of profitability, above last year''s 10.7 percent. Compensation was 38 percent of revenue in 2012, the second-lowest since Goldman Sachs has been a public company. The ratio of pay to revenue fell in the first half to 43 percent from 44 percent in the same period last year. </p> <p>The culture around compensation is really making sure that we continue to attract and retain all the best people, Chief Financial Officer Harvey Schwartz said at an investor conference in May. The firm now is running with 75 percent more capital now than it was before the crisis, and so we want to make sure that we do our best to get the balance right for our shareholders. </p> <p>The first-half compensation expense is enough to pay each of Goldman Sachs''s 31,700 employees $253,691 for the first six months of the year. The firm set aside $7.29 billion in the same period of 2012, equal to an average $225,789 for each of the 32,300 people employed by Goldman Sachs at the time. </p> <p>Compensation for corporate and investment bankers at JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the largest U.S. lender, was almost unchanged in the first half from a year earlier. The $6.36 billion represented 33 percent of revenue at the unit, which was created last year when the company combined its investment bank with the corporate bank and treasury and securities-services units. </p> <p>Figures for average pay don''t represent what any employee actually receives and are calculated by dividing the total compensation expense by the number of workers. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Victoria Slind-Flor" date="Jul 16, 2013  7:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-16/microsoft-green-mountain-weather-intellectual-property.html"><headline>Microsoft, Green Mountain, Weather: Intellectual Property</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Even as they battle in court over
smartphone and video technology, Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) and Google Inc. (GOOG)
have discovered a common foe: patent owners who try to sue their
customers or go after an entire industry. </p>
<p>Both companies are seeking to curb the litigation practices
of firms that buy patents with the sole purpose of demanding
royalties from as many end-users as they can, even if it means
suing a pizza parlor or nonprofit. Anger has united a cross-section of retailers, finance companies, public-transit
operators and hotels, and even caught the attention of President
Barack Obama, who last month announced corrective measures. </p>
<p>Focusing on the issue could create pressure in Congress for
legislation and action by U.S. courts -- as long as companies
avoid the squabbling that marred the previous effort to change
patent law. That took almost a decade and pitted industries, and
even technology companies, against each other. </p>
<p>Going after bad litigation behavior is an approach we can
all agree on, said Tim Molino, director of government
relations for Washington-based BSA - The Software Alliance,
whose members include Microsoft and Oracle Corp. </p>
<p>Google spokesman Matt Kallman referred questions about
patent legislation to the Coalition for Patent Fairness, a
Washington-based lobbying group backed by Google, Cisco Systems
Inc. and Intel Corp. Each month, the group has a meeting with an
increasing number of organizations to discuss ways to get
legislative change. </p>
<p>The increased political attention is due to patent owners
who started going after product end-users, demanding cheap
settlements from a large number of companies. A White House-commissioned report estimated that more than 100,000 companies
were threatened last year, including members of politically
connected Washington trade groups like the National Retail
Federation and Financial Services Roundtable. </p>
<p>Members of Congress have proposed legislation to limit some
patent owners from seeking product import bans at the U.S.
International Trade Commission, expand reviews of business
method patents and force certain patent owners who lose at trial
to pay legal fees of those they accused of infringement. </p>
<p>The courts have also been trying to curb abuses. The ITC, a
quasi-judicial agency in Washington, set up a program to resolve
certain patent cases more quickly. The chief judge of the
federal appeals court that specializes in patent law co-wrote a
New York Times opinion piece advocating sanctions for litigation
abuses. </p>
<p>Getting a consensus could mean avoiding more controversial
issues such as curbing software patents, and ensuring that any
changes don''t have unintended consequences that hurt
universities needing legal protection for their research and
patent-reliant businesses. </p>
<h2>Samsung Gets Patent on Mobile Phone That Docks With Tablet
Device </h2>
<p>Samsung Electronics Co. (005930), the Korean maker of smartphones
and other electronic devices, received a patent for a mobile
telephone that docks into a tablet device, according to the
database of the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office. </p>
<p>Patent D685774, issued July 9, is described as a terminal
for wireless communication. According to the patent drawings,
the mobile phone appears to have a USB port and a jack for a
headphone. The phone flares at the top and has rounded lower
edges. </p>
<p>Seocho-gu, South Korea-based Samsung applied for the patent
in June 2012, with the assistance of NSIP Law of Washington. </p>
<p>The company said in a statement yesterday that it was
seeking the cause of an explosion of one of its mobile phones.
Samsung said it was focused on quality control and customer
safety. </p>
<p>For more patent news, click here. </p>
<h2>Trademark </h2>
<h2>Green Mountain Unit Seeks Trademark for Home Soda Machine </h2>
<p>Green Mountain Coffee Roasters Inc. (GMCR)''s Keurig unit filed an
application to register a trademark to be used with soda
machines, according to the database of the U.S. Patent and
Trademark Office. </p>
<p>The application, filed July 3, is to register Karbon as
a trademark for machines for the production of cold water,
soda, still, carbonated and sparkling beverages. A second
application filed that day is to register Bolt, to be used
for carafes. </p>
<p>Keurig''s soda machine would compete with those made by
Israel''s SodaStream International Ltd. (SODA) </p>
<p>We are not going to comment on this specific trademark,
Suzanne DuLong, a spokeswoman for Waterbury, Vermont-based Green
Mountain, said in an e-mail. As we continue to grow, we are
likely to seek any number of trademarks. </p>
<p>Flipboard Sued by Company Seeking to Use Flowboard'' Trademark </p>
<p>Flipboard Inc., a maker of software for use on mobile
devices, was sued over a trademark by a Seattle-based software
company. </p>
<p>According to the complaint filed July 11 in federal court
in Seattle, Treemo Inc. is seeking a court declaration that its
Flowboard mark doesn''t infringe Flipboard''s trademarks. </p>
<p>Treemo said it has been contacted by counsel for Flipboard
threatening legal action over the trademark. </p>
<p>In court papers, Treemo said that during the process of
applying to register Flowboard as a trademark, the U.S. Patent
and Trademark Office found no conflicting marks that would bar
registration. The company is also arguing that the two marks
are used for different purposes. </p>
<p>Flowboard is used for a software product for the creation
of side-scrolling presentations with images, text, video links
and photo galleries, according to the complaint. Flipboard is
used with social networking services, something Treemo says it
doesn''t offer under its Flowboard mark. </p>
<p>Additionally, Treemo argued that the patent office database
contains almost 600 registrations or pending applications that
contain some form of the word board. The initial portions of
the respective marks -- Flow and Flip --connote substantially
different images in the minds of ordinary consumers, Treemo
said in its pleadings. </p>
<p>Flipboard, based in Palo Alto, California, sent a statement
to the TechCrunch website saying that it had wanted to resolve
the dispute with Treemo amicably and that it''s concerned about
the likelihood of confusion. </p>
<p>The case is Treemo Inc., v. Flipboard Inc., 13-cv-01218,
U.S. District Court, Western District of Washington (Seattle). </p>
<p>For more trademark news, click here. </p>
<h2>Copyright </h2>
<h2>Goodreads Sued for Copyright Infringement Over Boy Band Photo </h2>
<p>Goodreads Inc., whose website lets readers share book
recommendations, was sued for copyright infringement by a
company that owns and licenses celebrity photos. </p>
<p>The suit, filed July 5 in federal court in Los Angeles, is
one of more than 20 brought since March 1 by BWP Media USA Inc.
of Los Angeles. The company is represented in all these suits by
Sanders Law Pllc of Garden City, New Jersey. </p>
<p>BWP said in its complaint that photos of a member of the
boy band IM5 were posted on Goodreads without authorization and
in willful violation of its copyrights. </p>
<p>Goodreads, based in Santa Monica, California, didn''t
respond immediately to an e-mailed request for comment on the
suit. </p>
<p>BWP asked the court money damages, attorney fees and
litigation costs. </p>
<p>The case is BWP Media USA Inc., v. Goodreads Inc., 2:13-cv-04851-E, U.S. District Court, Central District of California
(Los Angeles). </p>
<p>For more copyright news, click here. </p>
<h2>Trade Secrets/Industrial Espionage </h2>
<h2>Trade Secrets Case Against Weather Channel to Proceed </h2>
<p>Weather Channel LLC, the television network owned by Bain
Capital LLC, Blackstone Group LP and NBC Universal International
Ltd., failed to persuade a federal court to dismiss a trade-secrets case. </p>
<p>Events Media Network Inc. of Shamong, New Jersey, sued
Weather Channel in Pennsylvania state court in March 2012,
claiming it violated a confidentiality agreement with respect to
its events database. The database had been licensed to Weather
Channel through May 1, 2011. </p>
<p>Weather Channel used this confidential information both
after the license expired and for purposes not covered by the
agreement, Events Media said in its pleadings. </p>
<p>The case was moved to federal court in Pennsylvania in May
2012 before heading to a New Jersey federal court in November. </p>
<p>The Weather Channel asked that the case be dismissed,
saying that the database didn''t qualify for trade-secrets
protection because it contained information that was publicly
available and that Events Media didn''t take enough care to
protect its secrecy. </p>
<p>U.S. District Judge Robert B. Kugler in Camden, New Jersey,
on July 12 rejected Weather Channel''s arguments. He said the
trade-secrets claims were made under Georgia law, which
specifically covers compilations of what may be available to the
public. </p>
<p>The judge also concluded that Events Media took care to
protect the confidentiality of the database and found that the
license agreement with Weather Channel specifically limited the
ways the information could be disclosed. The agreement also
required reporting any inadvertent or improper use of the data. </p>
<p>The case is Events Media Network Inc. v. Weather Channel
Interactive Inc., 13-cv-00003, U.S. District Court, District of
New Jersey (Camden). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bloomberg Television" date="Jul 17, 2013  7:36 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-17/mobile-game-developers-chase-china.html"><headline>Mobile Game Developers Chase China</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The popularity of mobile gaming is exploding in China, and with smartphone penetration still in its early stages, gaming app developers are tapping into soaring demand. Rosalind Chin reports on Bloomberg Television.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Donal Griffin" date="Jul 17, 2013  5:49 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-17/jpmorgan-nearing-ferc-market-rigging-settlement-wsj-says.html"><headline>JPMorgan Nearing FERC Market-Rigging Settlement, WSJ Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the biggest
U.S. bank, is near a deal with the Federal Energy Regulatory
Commission to settle allegations that the lender rigged
electricity markets, the Wall Street Journal reported. </p>
<p>The deal, which would resolve claims that the bank
manipulated power prices in California and the Midwest, could
require the largest payout in the agency''s history, according to
the report, which cited people familiar with the discussions.
Joseph Evangelisti, a spokesman for New York-based JPMorgan, and
Mary O''Driscoll, a FERC spokeswoman, declined to comment. </p>
<p>Previous negotiations between JPMorgan and the regulator
involved a payout figure close to $1 billion, according to the
Wall Street Journal. A deal could cost the bank $500 million,
the New York Times reported today, citing people briefed on the
matter. </p>
<p>FERC warned JPMorgan in March that its personnel and two
subsidiaries may face claims stemming from a probe into its
bidding practices, according to a regulatory disclosure from the
bank in May. Claims may include alleged violations of FERC
rules and the rules of certain independent system operators,
the lender said at the time, without elaborating. </p>
<p>FERC Chairman Jon Wellinghoff has stepped up scrutiny of
corporations as the agency wields policing powers that were
expanded in the wake of Enron Corp.''s 2001 collapse.
Wellinghoff, whose term was due to expire June 30, submitted his
resignation in May. President Barack Obama asked him to stay
until a new commissioner is confirmed by the Senate. </p>
<p>Yesterday the regulator ordered Barclays Plc (BARC) and four
former traders to pay a combined $487.9 million in fines and
penalties for engaging in what the agency said was a scheme to
manipulate energy markets in the Western U.S. from November 2006
to December 2008. London-based Barclays said it would
vigorously fight the penalties. </p>
<p>Agency investigators may seek to hold JPMorgan traders and
commodities-unit chief Blythe Masters individually liable,
the New York Times reported in May, citing a 70-page document
the watchdog sent the bank in March. </p>
<p>The FERC revoked a JPMorgan unit''s right to trade power for
six months in November after accusing the firm of providing
misleading information to a California energy authority. The
suspension, which took effect in April, marked the first such
sanction for an active market participant. </p>
<p>Deutsche Bank AG is among companies that have settled with
FERC. The Frankfurt-based lender agreed on Jan. 22 to pay $1.6
million to resolve FERC claims that an energy-trading unit
manipulated markets in 2010. The bank, Germany''s biggest, didn''t
admit or deny wrongdoing. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lu Wang and Sarah Frier" date="Jul 17, 2013 11:42 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-17/ibm-contracts-most-expensive-since-2005-as-sales-slump.html"><headline>IBM Contracts Most Expensive Since 2005 as Sales Slump</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Options (IBM) traders are paying the most
since 2005 to protect against stock swings in International
Business Machines Corp. relative to its peers on concern profit
will trail analyst estimates for a second quarter as sales drop. </p>
<p>Implied volatility for contracts with an exercise price
closest to the company''s stock was 1.44 times the Technology
Select Sector SPDR Fund, the highest since September 2005,
according to three-month data compiled by Bloomberg. IBM shares
have slumped 8.6 percent over the past three months, the most in
the Dow Jones Industrial Average. </p>
<p>While Chief Executive Officer Ginni Rometty has pushed the
company into faster-growing markets like data analysis and
repurchased shares, IBM is contending with sluggish demand for
hardware and consulting work. IBM missed earnings estimates in
April for the first time in eight years and will probably say
today that second-quarter revenue fell 2 percent, based on
analysts'' estimates tracked by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>You''ve got to meet these earnings numbers, otherwise you
get penalized, Edward Painvin, chief investment officer of
Chase Investment Counsel Corp., said by phone from
Charlottesville, Virginia, on July 15. His firm oversees $500
million and doesn''t own IBM shares. It''s difficult to do for a
name of this size with very, very little top line growth. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
IBM missed earnings estimates in April for the first time in eight years and will probably say today that second-quarter revenue fell 2 percent, based on analysts'' estimates tracked by Bloomberg. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lu Wang and Christine Harper" date="Jul 17, 2013 11:40 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-17/goldman-sachs-sells-redi-stake-to-group-of-wall-street-firms-1-.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Sells Redi Stake to Group of Wall Street Firms</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) said it
agreed to sell a majority stake in Redi, a unit that provides
trading technology, to a group of Wall Street firms. </p>
<p>The buyers include Bank of America Corp. (BAC)''s Merrill Lynch
unit, Barclays Plc, BNP Paribas SA (BNP), Citadel LLC and Lightyear
Capital LLC, according to a statement today. New York-based
Goldman Sachs will keep a significant minority equity stake
in the company. Financial terms were not disclosed. Rishi
Nangalia, who previously co-managed Goldman Sachs''s electronic
trading business development group, will serve as the company''s
chief executive officer. </p>
<p>The diversification of Redi''s ownership may make the unit
more attractive to clients compared with being controlled by a
single brokerage, according to Jamie Selway, head of electronic
brokerage and sales at Investment Technology Group Inc. </p>
<p>Goldman is heading toward a consortium approach, Selway
said in a phone interview. Clients are more comfortable with
broker neutrality in the context of independent technology
providers or consortium of broker dealers. The operation of
these systems requires a technology culture and can be
expensive. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs acquired the software that formed the basis
for Redi when it purchased New York Stock Exchange specialist
Spear, Leeds  Kellogg LP in 2000 and has expanded it to handle
trades in asset classes such as currencies and interest rates. </p>
<h2>RealTick </h2>
<p>Goldman Sachs''s plans come about two years after London-based Barclays Plc (BARC) sold the RealTick trading platform, which
lets customers access services from multiple brokers, to New
York-based ConvergEx Inc. Barclays said in December 2010 that it
planned to use the system within its investment banking unit and
offer the platform to customers. The bank got RealTick when it
acquired parts of Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. in 2008. </p>
<p>Citigroup Inc., JPMorgan Chase  Co., Knight Capital Group
Inc. and other securities firms bought execution-management
systems starting in the mid-2000s to give mutual funds and other
clients access to exchanges and algorithms, or trading
strategies that allow them to process larger orders in small
pieces over a preset period, along with other transaction
services. Some platforms were open to the algorithms of multiple
brokers or technology providers while others focused on those
from a single firm. </p>
<p>Investment Technology Group (ITG) and Instinet Inc., a subsidiary
of Tokyo-based Nomura Holdings Inc., offer execution platforms
to customers. Both firms are execution-only brokers that don''t
trade with their own money. Bloomberg LP, the parent of
Bloomberg News, offers similar systems. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Cliff Edwards" date="Jul 18, 2013  6:15 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-18/microsoft-s-xbox-tops-june-u-s-retail-home-console-sales.html"><headline>Microsoft''s Xbox Tops June U.S. Retail Home Console Sales</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) said U.S. retailers
sold 140,000 Xbox 360 units in June, helping it retain the top-selling spot for game consoles for the 30th straight month. </p>
<p>June spending on all Xbox products, including the console,
Kinect motion-sensing peripheral and software, totaled $197
million, Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft said today in an e-mail, citing NPD Group Inc. data. </p>
<p>Sales of the console fell 46 percent compared with a year
earlier, when it sold 257,000 consoles. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Frier" date="Jul 18, 2013  5:06 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-18/ibm-boosts-annual-forecast-after-earnings-beat-estimates-2-.html"><headline>IBM Boosts Annual Forecast After Earnings Beat Estimates</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM), the largest computer-services company, raised its annual
forecast after second-quarter earnings topped analysts''
estimates, lifted by cost cuts and share buybacks. </p>
<p>Excluding a $1 billion restructuring expense, profit was
$3.91 a share last quarter, the Armonk, New York-based company
said yesterday in a statement. That beat the $3.78 that analysts
projected on average, according to data compiled by Bloomberg.
IBM now expects to earn at least $16.90 a share in 2013, up from
the $16.70 it forecast earlier this year. </p>
<p>IBM has managed to increase profit by shifting away from
low-margin businesses, cutting jobs and repurchasing stock --
even as revenue declines. The company is betting that faster-growing areas such as cloud computing and data analysis can
offset a broader slowdown in information-technology spending. </p>
<p>We have to take them at their word that they''re going to
see some productivity improvements due to the workforce changes,
and some strength in software and services, said Josh Olson,
an analyst with Edward Jones  Co. in Des Peres, Missouri.
They''re getting a benefit from software growing at a faster
pace than the other businesses, and that''s contributing to the
profit beat. </p>
<p>The shares climbed 1.8 percent to $197.99 at the close in
New York. The stock is up 3.4 percent this year, trailing an 18
percent gain for the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index. </p>
<h2>Earlier Shortfall </h2>
<p>By beating earnings estimates, IBM rebounds from a rare
stumble in the previous quarter, when its profit missed
projections for the first time in eight years. Even so, revenue
continued to decline, falling 3.3 percent to $24.9 billion from
a year earlier. Analysts had expected $25.3 billion. Sales
declined in every IBM business division other than software. </p>
<p>In addition to a slump in demand, currency changes took a
toll on IBM''s results last quarter. In Japan, where the company
made about 10 percent of its sales last year, the yen fell 5
percent versus the dollar in the second quarter. The company was
significantly impacted by the yen''s weakness, Chief
Financial Officer Mark Loughridge said on a conference call. </p>
<p>Because our business in Japan is more heavily skewed to
local services, we have less ability to hedge cross-border cash
flows as compared to most other countries, Loughridge said. </p>
<h2>Intel, Accenture </h2>
<p>Other technology companies are suffering as well. Intel
Corp., the world''s largest chipmaker, reported its fourth
straight revenue decline yesterday as customers shunned personal
computers, choosing tablets and smartphones instead. </p>
<p>Accenture Plc (ACN), the world''s largest technology-consulting
company after IBM, gave a sales forecast last month that missed
analysts'' estimates. Accenture blamed customers deferring
decisions on long-term contracts. Oracle Corp. (ORCL), meanwhile, has
missed sales estimates for two straight quarters, hurt by
slumping hardware revenue and a shift by customers to
applications delivered online. </p>
<p>IBM said today that one recent deal with UniCredit SpA is
indicative of how it aims to transform its business. The 10-year
outsourcing deal, worth multiple billions, will employ analytics
and cloud computing to devise new ways for the bank to do
business. </p>
<p>IBM prioritizes earnings over revenue growth in its five-year road map, which is targeting profit of $20 a share by 2015,
up from the $15.25 earned last year. The plan calls for a
combination of buybacks, acquisitions and investments in faster-growing markets to reach that goal. </p>
<h2>Hardware Shakeup </h2>
<p>Following the previous quarter''s earnings shortfall, Chief
Executive Officer Ginni Rometty shook up the management of IBM''s
struggling hardware division. She replaced Rod Adkins with Tom Rosamilia, who had been overseeing corporate strategy. That
division saw a 12 percent decrease in sales last quarter, an
improvement from the 17 percent drop in the first quarter. </p>
<p>IBM also embarked on a restructuring program last quarter,
cutting jobs globally. More than 3,300 workers were dismissed in
the U.S. and Canada alone, according to Alliance@IBM, an
employee group. </p>
<p>The company said in April that divestitures would help
offset the $1 billion cost of the restructuring. At the time,
IBM was in talks to sell parts of its server division to Lenovo
Group Ltd. (992), according to people familiar with the discussions.
The negotiations broke down in early May due to disagreements
over price, one person said. </p>
<h2>Active Discussions'' </h2>
<p>Yesterday the company said it was reducing its expectations
for second-half gains from a divestiture. </p>
<p>The substantial second-half gain that we were counting on
in our view of EPS will not likely close at the end of this
year, but we''re still in active discussions, Loughridge said.
We have a very disciplined MA process. We''re not going to
underprice or rush a divestiture simply to close within 2013. </p>
<p>Second-quarter net income fell 17 percent to $3.23 billion,
or $2.91 a share, from $3.88 billion, or $3.34, a year earlier.
The company paid $1 billion in dividends and made $3.6 billion
in stock buybacks in the period, boosting earnings per share. </p>
<p>The company is seeing growth in high-margin businesses and
bookings look promising, Loughridge said. </p>
<p>We''re exiting the quarter stronger than we entered, he
said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri" date="Jul 18, 2013  4:25 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-18/disney-phases-out-executive-car-perks-in-iger-profit-push.html"><headline>Disney Phases Out Executive Car Perks in Iger Profit Push</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS) is eliminating perks including executive car allowances as the world''s biggest entertainment company looks to further boost profitability. </p> <p>We''re phasing them out, Chief Financial Officer Jay Rasulo said of the car allowances in an interview at last week''s Allen  Co. conference in Sun Valley, Idaho. </p> <p>Disney has been reducing costs by firing hundreds of workers, closing offices and outsourcing duties like video-game development as it looks to widen profit margins and extend a more than doubling of the stock price in the past five years. Rasulo, who has been conducting a company-wide review of expenses, said he''s seeking to modernize operations at Burbank, California-based Disney. </p> <p>We looked at the way technology is changing our businesses, said Rasulo, who didn''t discuss specifics. We''re removing vestigial parts. </p> <p>Chairman and Chief Executive Officer Robert Iger has focused on efficiency since becoming CEO in 2005, said Robin Diedrich, an analyst with Edward Jones in St. Louis who recommends the stock. </p> <p>Operating margin, a measure of profitability, widened to 21 percent of sales in the most recent fiscal year from 13 percent in fiscal 2005, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. Net income has more than doubled to $5.68 billion, outpacing the 35 percent gain in sales. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
Walt Disney Co. Chairman and Chief Executive Officer Robert Iger speaks during a Magic of Healthy Living event at the Newseum in Washington, D.C., on June 5, 2012. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jul 18, 2013  4:15 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-18/morgan-stanley-tops-analysts-estimates-on-trading-revenue-jump.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Jumps as Earnings Beat Analysts'' Estimates</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley climbed to the highest price in more than two years after second-quarter earnings beat estimates and the firm said it will buy back $500 million in stock. </p> <p>The shares rose 4.4 percent to $27.70 at 4:15 p.m. in New York. While that''s the highest since April 2011, it''s still below the $29.60 price at the end of 2009, when Chief Executive Officer James Gorman took over. </p> <p>Record brokerage revenue and an 18.5 percent pretax margin show progress toward the higher profitability targets Gorman laid out for the unit when Morgan Stanley bought the remaining stake in the venture last month. The firm also posted the highest equity-trading revenue among its peers for the first time in at least two years. </p> <p>The revenue beat was pretty much across the board, with investment banking, trading and commissions all doing a bit better than expected, Chris Kotowski, an Oppenheimer  Co. analyst who expects the stock to perform in line with the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index over the next 12 to 18 months, wrote today in a report. </p> <p>The firm said it will start buying back stock after receiving no objections from the Federal Reserve. Chief Financial Officer Ruth Porat, 55, said in an interview that Morgan Stanley (MS) sought regulatory approval for the buyback after it completed the brokerage purchase at the end of June. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
Morgan Stanley signage is displayed outside of the company''s headquarters in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bob Van Voris" date="Jul 18, 2013  3:48 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-18/goldman-witness-says-tourre-didn-t-disclose-paulson-role.html"><headline>Goldman Witness Says Tourre Didn''t Disclose Paulson Role</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)
employee who ran the firm''s mortgage correlation trading desk
testified that Fabrice Tourre failed to tell investors about the
role of Paulson  Co. in the deal at the center of the U.S.
Securities and Exchange Commission''s fraud case against him. </p>
<p>Jonathan Egol, now a Goldman Sachs managing director, told
jurors in Manhattan federal court today that he is not aware
of any disclosures to investors that Paulson, the New York
hedge fund that stood to make money from the failure of Abacus
2007-AC1, a synthetic collateralized debt obligation, helped
select the mortgage-backed assets underlying it. </p>
<p>Egol said Tourre did make sure to tell a superior that
Paulson helped pick the portfolio of 90 subprime mortgage-backed
securities when Goldman''s money was at risk. </p>
<p>The SEC sued Tourre and Goldman Sachs in 2010 over the
Abacus transaction. Paulson, run by billionaire John Paulson,
used the deal to bet against mortgage-backed securities.
Investors on the other side of the bet lost more than $1
billion. Goldman Sachs, based in New York, paid a then-record
$550 million to settle the case. </p>
<p>The SEC sued Tourre after dropping a plan to file claims
against Egol, according to interviews with SEC enforcement staff
conducted by the agency''s inspector general, which were made
available to Bloomberg News through a Freedom of Information Act
request. Egol testified yesterday that Tourre was the Goldman
Sachs employee primarily responsible for the Abacus transaction. </p>
<h2>Four Hours </h2>
<p>Egol testified for about four hours, yesterday and today,
under questioning from SEC lawyer Matthew Martens. He''s being
questioned by Tourre''s lawyers this afternoon. The SEC told U.S.
District Judge Katherine Forrest yesterday that after Egol, it
plans to call former Goldman Sachs saleswoman Gail Kreitman as a
witness and play a Jan. 17, 2007, recorded call between Kreitman
and ACA Financial Guaranty Corp.''s Lucas Westreich. </p>
<p>The SEC claims Kreitman told Westreich that Paulson was
taking a long, rather than a purely short, position in Abacus,
passing along false information she got from Tourre. The agency
says ACA, which lost money in a long bet on the transaction,
would have refused to serve as portfolio selection agent and
wouldn''t have invested in the transaction if it had known that
Paulson stood to gain from its failure. </p>
<p>The SEC said it expects Kreitman to testify that she
doesn''t recall who told her Paulson was buying the equity
tranche in Abacus, but that she generally recalls Tourre was the
most likely source of the false information. </p>
<h2>Streamlining Case </h2>
<p>The SEC had planned to call David Gerst, another one of
Tourre''s former Goldman Sachs colleagues, after Egol. SEC
lawyers told Forrest they moved up Kreitman as part of an effort
to streamline their case. </p>
<p>The change in the SEC witness list came after Martens spent
most of yesterday battling with Paolo Pellegrini, the former
Paulson executive who helped Paulson''s fund make more than $15
billion shorting subprime mortgages. </p>
<p>Pellegrini frequently argued with Martens and claimed the
SEC tricked and intimidated him in its investigation into the
Abacus transaction. </p>
<p>The case is SEC v. Tourre, 10-cv-03229, U.S. District
Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jul 18, 2013 12:29 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-18/morgan-stanley-says-leverage-ratio-fell-short-of-minimum.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Says Leverage Ratio Fell Short of Minimum</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS), owner of the world''s
largest brokerage, said it fell short of a minimum leverage
ratio proposed by U.S. regulators last week that measures a
firm''s ability to withstand losses. </p>
<p>The company''s supplementary leverage ratio, a gauge of
capital to total assets, was 4.2 percent in the second quarter,
below the proposed 5 percent minimum, Chief Financial Officer
Ruth Porat said on a conference call with analysts today. The
ratio at Morgan Stanley''s deposit-taking bank subsidiary was
above the proposed 6 percent minimum, she said. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley will exceed both requirements by 2015, Porat
said. The company announced plans earlier today to buy back $500
million in stock, and Porat said the firm''s plan to reach 5
percent by 2015 includes further capital returns to
shareholders. </p>
<p>The large banks will all manage against the new leverage
ratio well in advance of the ultimate application, which I think
is 2018, Chief Executive Officer James Gorman said in a
Bloomberg Television interview with Erik Schatzker. Our
capital plans will reflect the accretion of earnings. </p>
<p>While banks would have more than four years to comply,
lenders may have to retain some capital to meet the requirements
that they otherwise could pay out through dividends or share
repurchases. Gorman has said his plan to boost return on equity
to 10 percent by next year depends on regulators allowing the
firm to return a reasonable amount of capital to
shareholders. </p>
<h2>Basel Rule </h2>
<p>The U.S. proposal surpasses the 3 percent global minimum
that the Basel Committee on Banking Supervision approved to help
prevent another financial crisis. The changes would force
lenders to fund more assets with capital that can absorb losses
instead of with borrowed money. </p>
<p>This is a continuation of trying to find the right
position for this industry, which is the backbone of any
economy, to make it safe and stable and at the same time leave
it in a position where it can drive economic growth, Gorman
said in the interview. </p>
<p>Gorman said regulators should be very thoughtful about
whether to exclude certain assets, such as Treasuries, from the
calculation. Morgan Stanley would probably be in compliance with
the rule if U.S. government securities were excluded, Goldman
Sachs Group Inc. analysts led by Richard Ramsden said in a July
10 note. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley can probably boost its leverage ratio by
reducing fixed-income assets and moving derivative contracts to
central clearinghouses, Porat said. </p>
<h2>Basel III </h2>
<p>While Morgan Stanley trails rivals on its leverage ratio,
it surpasses some of them on risk-based capital ratios. The
firm''s Basel III Tier 1 Common ratio was 9.9 percent in the
second quarter, the second-highest among the six largest U.S.
lenders. </p>
<p>Bank of America Corp., the second-largest U.S. bank, said
yesterday that its supplementary leverage ratio was between 4.9
percent and 5 percent in the second-quarter. The ratios at the
Charlotte, North Carolina-based lender''s U.S. deposit-taking and
credit-card units exceed 6 percent, Chief Financial Officer
Bruce Thompson told reporters. </p>
<p>Citigroup Inc., the third-biggest U.S. bank, said its ratio
averaged 4.9 percent in the second quarter and in June exceeded
the 5 percent minimum. The New York-based company hasn''t
calculated a ratio for its deposit-taking unit, CFO John Gerspach said July 15. He said the ratio was about 6 percent in
March. </p>
<h2>Wells Fargo </h2>
<p>Wells Fargo  Co. (WFC), the largest home lender, exceeds both
minimums, CEO John Stumpf said last week. Goldman Sachs Group
Inc. said it''s very comfortable with its ability to meet the
new U.S. minimum, without giving the current level. </p>
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the biggest U.S. bank, said last week
that both its holding company, which had a 4.7 percent ratio,
and deposit-taking subsidiary fall short of the proposed
minimums. CEO Jamie Dimon criticized the plan for going further
than international requirements. </p>
<p>If one is 3 percent and one is 6 percent, that becomes
just too big, and over time it can have huge competitive
effects, Dimon said on a July 12 conference call. We always
ran with higher capital and liquidity than most of our
competitors. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore and Zeke Faux" date="Jul 18, 2013  9:19 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-18/morgan-stanley-cuts-investment-bank-pay-to-43-of-revenue.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Cuts Investment Bank Pay to 43% of Revenue</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley, owner of the world''s
biggest brokerage, set aside 1.4 percent less to pay people at
its investment-banking and trading division in the first half. </p>
<p>Compensation for staff at the institutional securities unit
was $3.66 billion, according to figures posted today on the New
York-based firm''s website. Salaries, bonuses and previous
deferred awards equaled 43 percent of adjusted revenue, down
from 46 percent a year earlier. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley has cut pay and jobs, deferred bonuses and
toughened clawback rules as Chief Executive Officer James Gorman, 55, copes with increases in capital requirements and
regulation. Chief Financial Officer Ruth Porat said in April
that the bank seeks to set aside about 40 percent of revenue for
pay in institutional securities. </p>
<p>The bank today reported a 66 percent quarterly earnings
increase that beat analysts'' estimates as stock-trading revenue
jumped and wealth-management profit margins climbed to a record.
Its shares rose to $27.72 at 8:55 a.m. in New York from $26.54
yesterday. </p>
<p>Companywide compensation and benefits rose 3.2 percent to
$8.32 billion in the first half as adjusted revenue increased
8.4 percent to $16.8 billion. That revenue figure excludes
accounting charges known as debt-valuation adjustments. Those
changes stem from increases in the value of the company''s debt,
under the theory that it would be more expensive to buy back the
securities. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
The bank''s total compensation cost was enough to pay each of the firm''s 55,610 employees $149,631 on average for the six months, more than the $137,496 it set aside for each of the 58,627 employees a year earlier, figures released today show. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Max Abelson" date="Jul 19, 2013  7:56 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-19/jpmorgan-says-risk-committee-members-futter-cote-to-leave-board.html"><headline>JPMorgan Risk Committee Cut in Half as Futter, Cote Leave</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan (JPM) Chase  Co., the largest
U.S. bank, said Ellen V. Futter and David M. Cote, two of the
firm''s four risk-committee members, left the board. </p>
<p>Futter, president of the American Museum of Natural
History, is leaving after 16 years with the bank, while
Honeywell International Inc. (HON) Chief Executive Officer Cote, 62,
is retiring after more than five, the New York-based firm said
yesterday in a statement. </p>
<p>Cote and Futter were among three risk committee members who
narrowly won re-election to the board in May, overcoming
opposition from some shareholders after a London unit''s loss of
more than $6 billion exposed risk-management failures. None of
the three had worked at a bank or as financial risk managers,
Bloomberg News reported in May 2012. A fourth was added to the
committee after the loss. </p>
<p>I am proud to have served as a member of JPMorgan Chase''s
board during such a historic time, Futter, 63, said in the
statement. She was the only director who didn''t attend the
annual shareholder meeting in May. She was re-elected with 53
percent of the vote, the smallest margin. </p>
<p>I think she just got tired of the criticism, John H. Biggs, who served as a JPMorgan director with Futter until 2007,
said in an interview. She was long on judgment but short on
technical knowledge, and that''s OK by me. </p>




Photographer: Daniel Acker/Bloomberg

<p>
David Cote, who served on JPMorgan Chase  Co.''s risk-policy committee has retired from the company''s board of directors. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Julia Leite" date="Jul 19, 2013  4:58 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-19/goldman-says-batista-exit-makes-mpx-a-buy-as-eon-takes-over-1-.html"><headline>Goldman Says Batista Exit Makes MPX a Buy as EON Takes Over</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Billionaire Eike Batista''s loss of
control of MPX Energia SA (MPXE3) to Germany''s EON SE is making the
Brazilian power producer a buy to Goldman Sachs Group Inc. </p>
<p>Goldman, which had not rated Rio de Janeiro-based MPX''s
shares since March, set its price target for the utility at 10
reais. The stock rose 1.2 percent to 6.99 reais at the close of
trading in Sao Paulo. The shares have fallen 31 percent in the
past year, the least among the six publicly traded companies
founded by Batista, which have declined as much as 91 percent. </p>
<p>Batista, who rode a surge in Brazilian stocks to become the
world''s eighth-richest person in March 2012, quit as MPX''s
chairman earlier this month after EON increased its stake to 36
percent. A selloff of shares in Batista''s energy, commodities
and cargo companies erased more than $30 billion of his fortune
after they failed to meet output targets. </p>
<p>We expect a gradual de-risking of MPX shares, Bruno Pascon, the Goldman Sachs analyst who took over primary coverage
from Felipe Mattar, wrote in a research note dated yesterday.
EON''s controlling stake and MPX''s contracted revenues should
meaningfully reduce any overhang related to concerns over the
EBX Group. EBX is Batista''s holding company. </p>
<h2>''Not Compatible'' </h2>
<p>A credibility crisis that started with his flagship oil
producer OGX Petroleo  Gas Participacoes SA is obscuring the
achievements of companies like MPX, Batista wrote in an opinion
piece published in the newspaper Valor Economico today. MPX''s
current market value is not compatible with what the company
has to offer, he said. MPX''s market value is $2.2 billion,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>MPX has the biggest portfolio of licensed projects in the
country, he wrote. The company has become a model for
thermal power producers along the coast, and generates enough
electricity to power the city of Rio de Janeiro, according to
Batista. </p>
<p>Goldman''s Pascon said MPX has a solid balance sheet and
will have above average free cash flow starting in 2014. </p>
<p>MPX has five buy recommendations from analysts, four holds
and one sell, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Goldman had rated MPX a buy from May 2012 through March,
when it changed the stock''s designation to not rated. The
New York-based investment bank includes stocks on that list when
it''s acting in an advisory capacity in a merger or strategic
transaction involving this company and in certain other
circumstances, according to the report. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Leising" date="Jul 21, 2013  1:09 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-21/coca-cola-workers-end-strike-at-ontario-bottle-plant-union-says.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Workers End 3-Week Strike in Ontario, Union Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Workers at a Brampton, Ontario-based
bottling plant operated by Coca-Cola Co. (KO), the world''s largest
soda maker, ended a three-week strike after approving a three-year contract, the Canadian Auto Workers Union said in a
statement today. </p>
<p>Production at the plant will resume tomorrow after the deal
was approved by 83 percent of workers, according to the
statement. Workers will receive pay increases in the second and
third years of the contract and won an agreement that would
end demands to outsource existing work. </p>
<p>The real fight here was over the defined benefit pension
plan, with Coca-Cola pushing us to move to a defined
contribution plan, Jerry Dias, assistant to the CAW National
President, said in the statement. We were ultimately
successful in keeping the defined benefit pension plan and
improving upon it. </p>
<p>The union also negotiated a weekend-worker program that
includes two 12-hour premium shifts to allow for 24-hour, seven
day-a-week production, according to the statement. </p>
<p>A call to Kent Landers, a spokesman for Atlanta-based Coca-Cola, wasn''t immediately returned. </p>
<p>The Canadian Auto Workers Union represents about 700
employees at the bottling plant, according to the statement. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Mario Parker" date="Jul 21, 2013 10:58 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-21/chevron-phillips-flares-gases-after-unit-shut-at-sweeny-complex.html"><headline>Chevron Phillips Flares Gases After Unit Shut at Sweeny Complex</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Phillips Chemical Co.
reported that it released emissions after a unit was shut at its
Sweeny chemical plant in Texas, according to a filing with state
regulators. </p>
<p>The ethylene unit was shut down after it lost a gas-fired
turbine compressor, the company said in a filing with the Texas
Commission on Environmental Quality. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Pashley" date="Jul 22, 2013  3:42 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-22/goldman-sachs-bankers-race-traders-at-sea-for-boys-cancer-jabs.html"><headline>London Bankers Race Traders at Sea to Push Boys'' Cancer Jabs</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>London financiers will swap suits for Lycra today as two teams race rowing boats from Barcelona to Ibiza in a campaign to include boys in vaccinations for a cancer-causing virus. </p> <p>Bankers, commodities traders and one Olympic rower will brave searing heat and shipping lanes for three days in an effort to raise money and change public health policy on human papillomavirus. One aim of the 10-strong group is to lobby to change the U.K. vaccination program, which only treats girls. </p> <p>Men in 10 years'' time are more likely to have HPV-related cancer than women, said Tristan Almada, a hedge fund executive who founded the campaign and is president of the HPV and Anal Cancer Foundation. This is a gender-neutral virus that requires a gender-neutral vaccine. </p> <p>For two of the men, HPV is personal. Almada''s mother died of the virus-related anal cancer in 2010, and fellow rower Pierre Andurand''s mother is undergoing treatment. Their mothers'' names, Isabel and Danielle, have been given to the boats. HPV also causes cervical and penile cancer and may trigger 5 percent of all cancers, according to the NoMan is an Island campaign. </p> <p>The cause is attracting senior figures from the finance world. Andurand founded hedge fund Andurand Capital Management LLP. Other rowers include Pierre Lacaze, chief executive officer of LCM Commodities, and executives from Goldman Sachs Group Inc. </p> <h2>Urgent Issue </h2> <p>HPV-related cancer can be prevented through vaccination. Yet stigma surrounding sexually-transmitted disease and HPV''s characterization as a woman''s issue, because of its links to cervical cancer, have prevented universal inoculation, Almada said. He has petitioned the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention in the U.S. since 2010 and has reported to the Joint Committee on Vaccination and Immunization, a body of the U.K. department of health, though policy remains unchanged. </p> <p>The 200-mile Row to End HPV is designed to get people engaged with the issue, and convey the urgency that got the world behind polio and smallpox, said Almada, whose day job is at derivatives hedge fund Taurosso Capital, which he co-founded. The event will also raise money for grants and to collaborate with the medical profession in research. </p> <p>The rowers range in age from 28 to 41, and while they include veterans of Ironman competitions and mountain climbing, all but two are novices on water. Even Mark Hunter, who won a gold medal for the U.K. in Beijing, confesses to having little experience of rowing at sea. Teams of two will row in two-hour shifts and navigate themselves. A support boat will be on standby. </p> <p>The teams had raised about $700,000 toward their $1 million target on Friday. The race will be an annual event, Almada said. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Richter and Agnieszka Troszkiewicz" date="Jul 23, 2013  7:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-23/goldman-sachs-lme-dispute-beer-maker-on-aluminum-price.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs, LME Dispute Beer Maker on Aluminum Price</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman (GS) Sachs Group Inc., the owner
of the one of the biggest U.S. aluminum-warehouse networks, and
the London Metal Exchange say commodity prices fell in recent
years, countering claims of rising costs by beverage companies. </p>
<p>Delivered aluminum prices are nearly 40 percent lower
than they were in 2006, Goldman said yesterday in a statement,
and the LME said there is no reported shortage of the metal. </p>
<p>MillerCoors LLC, a SABMiller Plc (SAB) and Molson Coors Brewing
Co. venture, said at a Senate subcommittee hearing yesterday
that unfair LME rules used by Goldman, JPMorgan Chase  Co. and
other warehouse owners boost costs and delay shipments. Senator
Sherrod Brown, the committee chairman, plans to ask the Federal
Reserve to explain why it allows banks to control raw-material
supplies while trading in commodity markets. </p>
<p>The real question isn''t whether prices have fallen the
past few years, but whether prices are a true reflection of
supply-and-demand conditions, Jorge Vazquez, a managing
director at Harbor Intelligence, an Austin, Texas-based research
company, said in a telephone interview after the hearing.
Looking at the warehouse-business model is relevant.
Significant changes in the system could improve fairness and
efficiency. </p>




Photographer: Woohae Cho/Bloomberg

<p>
About 95 percent of the aluminum used in manufacturing comes from producers and dealers outside of the London Metal Exchange warehouse system, Goldman Sachs Group Inc. said. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Simon Casey" date="Jul 23, 2013  5:42 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-23/walter-energy-cuts-dividend-to-1-cent-as-it-amends-credit-pact.html"><headline>Walter Energy Cuts Dividend to 1 Cent as It Amends Credit Pact</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walter Energy Inc. (WLT), a metallurgical-coal producer, cut its quarterly dividend to 1 cent from 12.5
cents as a condition for amending a $2.73 billion credit pact. </p>
<p>The move was among changes to covenants agreed with
lenders, the Birmingham, Alabama-based company said today in a
filing. </p>
<p>Walter''s net senior secured leverage will rise to more than
5.5 times this quarter, the level needed to remain in compliance
with the debt agreement, Benjamin Nelson, a New York-based
analyst at Moody''s Investors Service, said in a June 19 report. </p>
<p>Second-quarter metallurgical coal output was about 2.9
million metric tons, about 7 percent more than in the preceding
period, Walter said in a separate statement. Cash production
costs fell more than 10 percent in the same comparison, it said.
The company didn''t provide year-earlier numbers. </p>
<p>The short-term outlook for global met coal pricing
remains depressed, Chief Executive Officer Walt Scheller said
in the statement. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lynn Doan" date="Jul 23, 2013  4:27 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-23/morgan-stanley-oil-tankers-raise-market-power-concern-at-hearing.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Oil Tankers Raise Market Power Concern at Hearing</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS)''s involvement in an
oil tanker business, petroleum transportation service and crude
markets raised concerns at a Senate hearing today that the owner
of the world''s largest brokerage wields too much market power. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s ownership stake in tanker operator Heidmar
Inc. and fuel distributor and marketer TransMontaigne Inc. could
be giving the bank an advantage over others trading oil, Sherrod Brown, an Ohio Democrat and chairman of the Senate''s
Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Protection,
said in a hearing. Brown''s panel took testimony at the meeting
on whether banks should control commodities assets. </p>
<p>You scale back the number of those tankers delivering
oil, and you''re also in a position to wager on oil prices,
Brown said. Is that a concern to you? </p>
<p>The subcommittee''s meeting came as the Federal Reserve
reconsiders whether banks including Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS),
Morgan Stanley and JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) should be allowed to
store, transport and trade raw materials. Goldman Sachs alone
has contracts for fuel from least five U.S. refineries, totaling
586,200 barrels a day in capacity, while JPMorgan had a stake in
power plants across the U.S. last year with a generating
capacity of almost 8,000 megawatts, federal filings show. </p>
<h2>Oil Tankers </h2>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s involvement in oil tanker, distribution
and trading businesses raises serious concerns, Randall Guynn, head of Davis Polk  Wardwell LLP''s financial
institutions group, said at the hearing in response to Brown''s
question. Obviously, if they have market share and abuse it, I
suppose that could be a problem. </p>
<p>Regulatory agencies exist to investigate potential abuses
of market power, Guynn said. </p>
<p>Unlike the 19th century, we have the Sherman Act now,
he said. If there are any gaps in regulation, I would''ve
thought that a legitimate thing to look at and make sure that
any sort of bad behavior did not occur. </p>
<p>The Sherman Act prohibits business activities that federal
regulators deem to be anticompetitive. </p>
<p>Lauren Bellmare, a spokeswoman for Morgan Stanley in New
York, declined by telephone to comment on the company''s
petroleum assets. </p>
<p>Guynn said federal policy makers shouldn''t curb banks''
involvement in commodity markets as nothing has proven their
activity is risking the stability of the country''s financial
system. The public benefits of their participation, such as
increased competition, liquidity and efficiency, outweigh the
potential adverse effects, he said. </p>
<h2>Asset Ownership </h2>
<p>Morgan Stanley has a minority interest in Heidmar, whose
clients include some of the world''s best-known oil and energy
companies, according to Heidmar''s website. Its infrastructure
group bought the Southern Star (SSEY) Central Gas Pipeline in the U.S.
Midwest in 2010. TransMontaigne has petroleum terminals across
the U.S. </p>
<p>Units of Goldman Sachs, Citigroup Inc. (C) and Bank of America
Corp. owned power plants across the U.S. that generate renewable
energy such as solar and wind, according to 2012 plant ownership
data compiled by the Energy Information Administration, the
Energy Department''s statistical arm. </p>
<p>A Citigroup subsidiary had a 25 percent ownership stake in
three wind power farms in Minnesota and New Mexico, the EIA data
show. Banc of America Leasing  Capital LLC owned solar power
plants in Oregon and California. </p>
<h2>Physical Markets </h2>
<p>Stripping banks of their energy assets would handicap them
in physical markets, where they trade with refiners, pipeline
operators and producers, who often own infrastructure and carry
supplies that dwarf theirs, Phil Flynn, senior market analyst at
the Price Futures Group in Chicago, said by telephone yesterday.
Should banks be pushed out of the markets, less regulated hedge
funds would probably step in to take their place, he said. </p>
<p>You''re probably just going to get the people at the big
banks joining hedge funds to do it, Flynn said. You''ll move
some of this stuff into the dark markets, and that''s another
concern. </p>
<p>A disaster at a bank-owned commodities asset would be
catastrophic to the reputation of the company and the
Federal Reserve, Joshua Rosner, managing director at Graham
Fisher  Co., said at the hearing. An incident such as a major
oil spill would trigger calls for more collateral, cut liquidity
and require the government to step in and stabilize systemic
risk to the financial system, he said. </p>
<p>Rosner told the subcommittee today that commodity risks
should be kept out of the nation''s banking systems and warned
that the failure of bank-backed commodities would threaten the
flow of money and bring the financial system to a
standstill. </p>
<p>We''re destined to view 2008 as the first financial crisis
and not the worst, he said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chanyaporn Chanjaroen" date="Jul 23, 2013 12:29 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-23/goldman-reduces-12-month-commodity-forecast-after-crude-s-rally.html"><headline>Goldman Pares 12-Month Commodity Outlook After Crude''s Rally</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. pared its
12-month commodity return forecast to almost flat after oil
rallied, keeping a neutral recommendation on raw materials while
predicting losses for gold and gains for base metals. </p>
<p>The Standard  Poor''s GSCI Enhanced Commodity Index will
return 0.1 percent over the period, the New York-based bank said
in a report dated yesterday. That compares with a forecast gain
of 2.3 percent over 12 months in a report on June 12. </p>
<p>The so-called strategic case for holding commodities
remains strong, partly because raw materials are a hedge against
geopolitical risks, analysts led by Jeffrey Currie wrote in the
report. Commodities as tracked by the enhanced index advanced to
the highest level since February last week as West Texas
Intermediate crude oil traded at the highest price in 16 months. </p>
<p>Our current outlook is extremely benign with returns
expected to be mostly flat over the next 12 months, the
Goldman analysts wrote. Precious metals and agricultural
commodities may drop 8 percent over the period, while base
metals advance 6 percent, the bank said. </p>
<p>Crude in New York rallied 11 percent this month through
yesterday, and settled at $108.05 a barrel July 19, the highest
since March 2012. Political upheaval in Egypt spurred concern
that unrest may spread, potentially disrupting shipments from
the Middle East. The U.S., the largest oil consumer, also showed
signs of recovery, helping to boost prices as inventories fell.
WTI traded at $106.89 a barrel today. </p>
<h2>UBS''s Outlook </h2>
<p>The neutral recommendation from Goldman contrasts with the
position from UBS AG, Switzerland''s largest bank, which rated
commodities as underweight, according to a report on July 2.
Slow economic growth in the U.S. will boost equities more than
raw materials, according to UBS, which is bearish on gold. </p>
<p>Bullion is heading for the first annual drop in 13 years
amid speculation the U.S. Federal Reserve will rein in stimulus
as the largest economy improves. Chairman Ben S. Bernanke will
trim monthly bond buying to $65 billion in September from $85
billion, according to economists surveyed by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Gold in New York may decline to $1,050 an ounce at the end
of 2014, Goldman said, restating a forecast from June 24. Gold
for December delivery traded at $1,335.60 an ounce today. Most-active prices have declined 2 percent in 2013. </p>
<p>Corn will decline this half as increased U.S. acreage
boosts output, bolstering reserves, said Goldman. The 12-month
estimate is $4.75 a bushel, 1.6 percent lower than today. Prices
have retreated 31 percent this year. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alexandria Baca" date="Jul 23, 2013 10:07 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-23/morgan-stanley-s-reinhart-sees-two-speed-expansion-favoring-rich.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley''s Reinhart Sees Two-Speed Expansion Favoring Rich</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The U.S. economic expansion is
two-speed, favoring those who are already well-off
financially, said Vincent Reinhart, the chief U.S. economist at
Morgan Stanley. </p>
<p>Income inequality is increasing, Reinhart said today on
the television program Bloomberg Surveillance with Tom Keene
and Sara Eisen. Real wages, except at the very highest
incomes, are actually stagnant to going down. </p>
<p>The weekly Bloomberg Consumer Comfort index has shown
optimism among lower-income Americans has deteriorated. The
index for households earning less than $15,000 fell in the
period ended July 14 to minus 69.2, its worst since January,
from minus 66.6 a week earlier. For households earning more than
$100,000, the index eased to 14.9 after 21 in the prior week,
which matched the highest level since November 2007. </p>
<p>It''s been a two-speed recovery, Reinhart said. The
upper''s done better than lower. </p>
<p>Still, strong capital spending and the housing market
signal the expansion will continue, Reinhart said. The U.S.
added 195,000 jobs for a second month in June, the Labor
Department reported earlier this month. </p>
<p>The data are mixed for sure, but the composition of the
first half makes us a little more encouraged that we have
durability going into the second half, Reinhart said. </p>
<h2>QE Risky'' </h2>
<p>The former director of the Federal Reserve''s Division of
Monetary Affairs said the Fed''s quantitative easing program
is unconventional and risky. </p>
<p>It is recently unchartered waters for central banking,
Reinhart said. The program now consists of $85 billion a month
in bond purchases. </p>
<p>The Fed is currently considering reducing those purchases
even with unemployment at 7.6 percent and the Fed''s preferred
inflation index showing prices rising 1 percent from a year
earlier, below the central bank''s 2 percent goal. </p>
<p>Half of economists in a Bloomberg survey July 18 to July 22
said the Fed will begin tapering in September. </p>
<p>The world''s largest economy grew at a 1.8 percent
annualized rate in the first quarter, according to the Commerce
Department. </p>
<p>Reinhart has served as Morgan Stanley''s chief U.S.
economist in New York since 2011. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Isis Almeida" date="Jul 23, 2013  5:22 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-23/goldman-cuts-coffee-price-forecast-as-inventories-at-5-year-high.html"><headline>Goldman Cuts Coffee Price Forecast as Inventories at 5-Year High</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) cut its
price forecast for arabica coffee futures traded in New York,
citing a surplus that will take stockpiles to a five-year high
at the end of the 2013-14 season. </p>
<p>Arabica coffee will be at $1.30 a pound on the ICE Futures
U.S. exchange in three, six and 12 months, the bank said in a
report e-mailed today. That''s down from a previous forecast of
$1.45 a pound. The beans fell 12 percent this year to $1.263 a
pound by 4:26 a.m. in New York. </p>
<p>Global coffee production will exceed demand by 4.46 million
bags in 2013-14, from a 10 million-bag surplus a year earlier,
according to the U.S. Department of Agriculture. Inventories
will reach a five-year high of 30.53 million bags, the USDA
predicts. A bag of coffee weighs 132 pounds. </p>
<p>The expected 2013-14 surplus that would bring stocks to
their highest level in five years is leading us to lower once
again our three- to 12-month forecasts, Damien Courvalin, an
analyst at the bank, wrote in the report. Potential for prices
to rebound from their current levels include weather risks in
Brazil, the potential for further cuts to Central American
production and short covering flows of near-record short net
speculative positions. </p>
<p>Arabica coffee gained 2.8 percent last week as a forecast
for a cold front that may bring freezing temperatures to some
coffee areas in Brazil, the world''s top producer, resulted in
speculators closing bets on lower prices. Some coffee growing
areas may get freezing temperatures today and tomorrow,
forecaster Somar Meteorologia said on July 18. </p>
<h2>Net-Short Positions </h2>
<p>Large and small speculators excluding index funds reduced
their net-short positions, or bets on lower prices, on arabica
coffee to 28,452 contracts in the week ended July 16, data from
the U.S. Commodity Futures Trading Commission compiled by
Bloomberg showed. That''s down from a net-short position of
32,941 lots a week earlier. </p>
<p>Prices of raw sugar traded in New York will also be lower
than previously forecast, the bank said, citing a record crop in
Brazil''s center south, the main growing region of the world''s
leading producer, and a promising start to the monsoon in
second-ranking India. </p>
<p>Sugar will be at 16.50 cents a pound on ICE in three
months, down from a previous forecast of 17.50 cents a pounds.
Prices will gain to 17.50 cents a pound in six months and to 19
cents a pound in 12 months, the bank said, adding that it sees
downside to its medium-term forecast. Raw sugar was down 16
percent this year to 16.39 cents a pound. </p>
<p>Potential support to prices could come either from rain in
Brazil or weather and, or production disappointments in India
later this year, according to the Goldman Sachs report. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dakin Campbell" date="Jul 24, 2013  4:59 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-24/visa-profit-beats-estimates-as-credit-card-spending-increases.html"><headline>Visa Profit Beats Estimates as Credit-Card Spending Rises</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Visa Inc. (V), the biggest bank-card
network, reported a fiscal third-quarter profit that beat
analysts'' estimates as worldwide spending on credit and debit
cards climbed. </p>
<p>Net income for the three months ended June 30 was $1.23
billion, or $1.88 a share, compared with a loss of $1.84
billion, or $2.74, a year earlier that included a litigation
expense, the Foster City, California-based company said today in
a statement. The average estimate of 33 analysts surveyed by
Bloomberg was for earnings of $1.80 a share. Profit excluding
special items from the third quarter of 2012 climbed 16 percent. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Charlie Scharf is seeking to
bolster Visa''s business outside the U.S., where it gets more
than half its revenue, as consumers worldwide continue to
migrate from cash and checks to electronic payments. The company
has returned more than $15 billion to shareholders since 2008. </p>
<p>From a longer-term perspective, we continue to believe
that Visa is the single best way to harness returns amid the
shift away from cash, Greg Smith, an analyst at Sterne Agee 
Leach Inc., wrote in a July 21 report. We expect the company
to consistently generate at least mid-teens earnings-per-share
growth, he said. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
Last year, Visa Inc. and No. 2 network MasterCard Inc. agreed to a $7.25 billion settlement over the fees charged to merchants when consumers pay with credit cards. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Nick Taborek" date="Jul 24, 2013  4:20 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-24/general-dynamics-second-quarter-profit-beats-estimates.html"><headline>General Dynamics Second-Quarter Profit Beats Estimates</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>General Dynamics Corp. (GD) reported
second-quarter profit that beat analysts'' estimates as higher
Gulfstream business-jet sales helped offset declining revenue at
the unit that produces military vehicles and munitions. </p>
<p>Net income increased 1 percent to $640 million, or $1.81 a
share, compared with $634 million, or $1.77 a share, a year
earlier, the Falls Church, Virginia-based company said today in
a statement. Analysts predicted $1.62 a share, the average of 18
estimates compiled by Bloomberg. Sales fell less than 1 percent
to $7.91 billion. </p>
<p>Sales at General Dynamics'' aerospace unit, which produces
the Gulfstream jets, gained 29 percent from a year earlier on
rising deliveries, while revenue declined 28 percent at the
combat-systems division. </p>
<p>The company received orders for every Gulfstream aircraft
model in second-quarter 2013, demonstrating continued demand
across its portfolio of business-jet products, according to
the statement. </p>
<p>General Dynamics rose 1.5 percent to close at $85.31, the
highest price since Sept. 8, 2008. The shares have gained 23
percent this year. </p>
<p>The company, which makes Abrams tanks, is consolidating its
defense business into fewer units and seeking international
sales as automatic U.S. budget cuts known as sequestration are
stripping $37 billion from Pentagon programs this fiscal year. </p>
<p>Lockheed Martin Corp. (LMT), the world''s largest defense
contractor, raised its full-year profit forecast yesterday as it
reported second-quarter earnings that exceeded analysts''
estimates. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Naureen S. Malik" date="Jul 24, 2013 11:22 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-24/electricity-from-washington-to-new-york-slumps-amid-lower-demand.html"><headline>Electricity From Washington to New York Slumps Amid Lower Demand</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Spot wholesale power slumped in the
Northeast and mid-Atlantic states as moderating summer heat
reduced demand. </p>
<p>PJM Interconnection LLC, which serves more than 60 million
people from New Jersey to North Carolina and Illinois, expects
peak demand on its network to slump 11 percent. The New York
Independent System Operator Inc. sees power use in Manhattan and
its neighboring four boroughs dropping by 7.5 percent. </p>
<p>The high temperature in Washington today will be 86 degrees
Fahrenheit (30 Celsius), 2 below normal, with chances of
thunderstorms, according to AccuWeather Inc. in State College,
Pennsylvania. Manhattan may also see a high of 86 degrees, 2
higher than the historical average. </p>
<p>Spot electricity for PJM''s Western hub, which includes
deliveries to Washington, slumped $8.07, or 20 percent, to
$32.06 a megawatt-hour during the hour ended at 10 a.m., grid
data compiled by Bloomberg show. New York City was down 9 cents
at $45.27. </p>
<p>Demand on the 13-state PJM network will peak at 120,234
megawatts during the hour ending at 5 p.m. Yesterday''s high was
135,322 megawatts at 4:55 p.m. Peak demand in New York City will
drop to 9,440 megawatts during the 4 p.m. hour versus 10,210
megawatts during the same hour yesterday, according to data from
the New York ISO. </p>
<p>Prices rose from Maine to Connecticut as demand treaded
above the grid operator''s forecasts. </p>
<p>Boston spot power increased $1.05, or 2.9 percent, to
$37.64 a megawatt-hour during the hour ended at 10 a.m. from the
same time yesterday. </p>
<p>ISO New England Inc. said demand was 20,108 megawatts at
9:30 a.m. on the six-state network, 1.7 percent higher than its
projection for the hour, according to its website. </p>
<p>The region''s power consumption will peak at 22,600
megawatts versus yesterday''s high of 21,922 megawatts, ISO New
England said in a daily report. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dakin Campbell" date="Jul 25, 2013 10:16 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-25/visa-advances-as-net-income-beats-estimates-san-francisco-mover.html"><headline>Visa Advances as Net Income Beats Estimates: San Francisco Mover</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Visa Inc. (V) gained the most since May
after reporting fiscal third-quarter profit that beat analysts''
estimates as consumers stepped up use of credit and debit cards. </p>
<p>Visa rose 4.6 percent to $195.33 at 10 a.m. in New York,
the second-best performer on the Standard  Poor''s 500
Information Technology Index. The shares gained 29 percent this
year, outpacing the 9.4 percent advance of the 70-company index. </p>
<p>Net income for the three months ended June 30 was $1.23
billion, or $1.88 a share, compared with a loss of $1.84
billion, or $2.74, a year earlier that included a litigation
expense, the Foster City, California-based firm said yesterday
in a statement. The average estimate of 33 analysts surveyed by
Bloomberg was for earnings of $1.80 a share. Profit excluding
special items from the third quarter of 2012 climbed 16 percent. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Charlie Scharf is seeking to
bolster Visa''s business outside the U.S., where it gets more
than half its revenue, as consumers worldwide continue to
migrate from cash and checks to electronic payments. The company
has returned more than $15 billion to shareholders since 2008. </p>
<p>The opportunity to move transactions from cash to
electronic means is still huge, Scharf, 48, said yesterday in
a conference call with analysts. This is true in both the
developed and the developing parts of the world. </p>
<h2>Share Repurchases </h2>
<p>The company repurchased $981 million of its stock during
the quarter at an average of $176.75 a share and may buy back an
additional $1.5 billion through next July, according to the
statement. </p>
<p>Third-quarter operating revenue climbed 17 percent to $3
billion, beating the $2.89 billion average estimate of analysts
surveyed by Bloomberg. Revenue will increase about 13 percent
this fiscal year, according to the statement. Earnings per share
will rise by more than 20 percent, the company said, after an
earlier forecast of around 20 percent. </p>
<p>Worldwide spending on Visa cards climbed 13 percent to
$1.09 trillion, adjusted for currency fluctuations, according to
the statement. Processed transactions rose 14 percent to 15
billion. Cross-border purchases, or spending by cardholders
outside their home countries, advanced 11 percent. </p>
<p>In the U.S., debit-card purchases advanced 12 percent to
$300 billion, and credit-card spending increased 10 percent to
$270 billion, according to the statement. </p>
<h2>Legal Settlement </h2>
<p>Visa and No. 2 network MasterCard Inc. (MA) agreed last year to
a $7.25 billion settlement over the fees charged to merchants
when consumers pay with credit cards. Visa sued Wal-Mart Stores
Inc. last month to stop the biggest U.S. retailer from filing a
lawsuit that would prolong the eight-year legal battle the
settlement seeks to end. </p>
<p>American Express Co. (AXP), the New York-based card issuer that
also runs the third-largest U.S. bank-card network, said July 18
that second-quarter profit rose 4.9 percent to $1.41 billion as
customer purchases increased. Riverwoods, Illinois-based
Discover Financial Services (DFS), the No. 4 network, said yesterday
that quarterly net income climbed 15 percent to $602 million.
MasterCard is set to report results July 31. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dakin Campbell" date="Jul 25, 2013 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-25/visa-posts-profit-beating-estimates-as-card-spending-increases.html"><headline>Visa Posts Profit Beating Estimates as Card Spending Increases</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Visa Inc. (V), the biggest bank-card
network, reported a fiscal third-quarter profit that beat
analysts'' estimates as worldwide spending on credit and debit
cards climbed. </p>
<p>Net income for the three months ended June 30 was $1.23
billion, or $1.88 a share, compared with a loss of $1.84
billion, or $2.74, a year earlier that included a litigation
expense, the Foster City, California-based firm said yesterday
in a statement. The average estimate of 33 analysts surveyed by
Bloomberg was for earnings of $1.80 a share. Profit excluding
special items from the third quarter of 2012 climbed 16 percent. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Charlie Scharf is seeking to
bolster Visa''s business outside the U.S., where it gets more
than half its revenue, as consumers worldwide continue to
migrate from cash and checks to electronic payments. The company
has returned more than $15 billion to shareholders since 2008. </p>
<p>The opportunity to move transactions from cash to
electronic means is still huge, Scharf said in a conference
call with analysts. This is true in both the developed and the
developing parts of the world. </p>
<p>Visa rose 2 percent to $190.50 in extended trading in New
York yesterday after results were announced. The shares climbed
23 percent this year through the close of regular trading,
outpacing the 9.3 percent advance for the 70-company Standard 
Poor''s 500 Information Technology Index. </p>
<h2>Share Repurchases </h2>
<p>The company repurchased $981 million of its stock during
the quarter at an average of $176.75 a share and may buy back an
additional $1.5 billion through next July, according to the
statement. </p>
<p>Third-quarter operating revenue climbed 17 percent to $3
billion, beating the $2.89 billion average estimate of analysts
surveyed by Bloomberg. Revenue will increase about 13 percent
this fiscal year, according to the statement. Earnings per share
will rise by more than 20 percent, the company said, after an
earlier forecast of around 20 percent. </p>
<p>Worldwide spending on Visa cards climbed 13 percent to
$1.09 trillion, adjusted for currency fluctuations, according to
the statement. Processed transactions rose 14 percent to 15
billion. Cross-border purchases, or spending by cardholders
outside their home countries, advanced 11 percent. </p>
<h2>U.S. Performance </h2>
<p>In the U.S., debit-card purchases advanced 12 percent to
$300 billion, and credit-card spending increased 10 percent to
$270 billion, according to the statement. </p>
<p>Visa and No. 2 network MasterCard Inc. agreed last year to
a $7.25 billion settlement over the fees charged to merchants
when consumers pay with credit cards. Visa sued Wal-Mart Stores
Inc. last month to stop the biggest U.S. retailer from filing a
lawsuit that would prolong the eight-year legal battle the
settlement seeks to end. </p>
<p>Scharf, 48, has pledged to be more flexible in responding
to the demands of Visa''s business partners and in February the
company reached agreement with JPMorgan Chase  Co., the biggest
U.S. card issuer, to let the lender tailor payment solutions for
merchants. </p>
<p>American Express Co., the New York-based card issuer that
also runs the third-largest U.S. bank-card network, said July 18
that second-quarter profit rose 4.9 percent to $1.41 billion as
customer purchases increased. Riverwoods, Illinois-based
Discover Financial Services, the No. 4 network, said yesterday
that quarterly net income climbed 15 percent to $602 million.
MasterCard is set to report results July 31. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David Voreacos and Patricia Hurtado" date="Jul 26, 2013  7:37 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-26/morgan-stanley-can-pursue-skowron-fraud-claim-judge-says.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Can Pursue Skowron Fraud Claim, Judge Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) can pursue a fraud
claim as it seeks to recover damages from Joseph Chip Skowron, a former hedge fund manager serving a five-year prison
term for insider trading, a federal judge ruled. </p>
<p>Skowron managed Morgan Stanley''s FrontPoint Partners LLC
until he was charged in 2011 with using inside information to
avoid $30 million in losses. The New York-based bank sued
Skowron after he pleaded guilty to conspiring to commit
securities fraud and obstruct justice, seeking to recover $33
million it paid U.S. regulators and the $32 million it paid him. </p>
<p>Skowron, 44, asked U.S. District Judge Shira Scheindlin in
Manhattan to dismiss three of Morgan Stanley''s claims, including
that he defrauded the bank and breached his fiduciary duty. The
judge ruled that the bank can seek to prove its fraud claim,
while dismissing its fiduciary duty claim. She said Skowron
covered up his crimes as the bank and U.S. government
investigated. </p>
<p>I decline to impose on Morgan Stanley the duty to ferret
out the truth from a man who lied for years not only to Morgan
Stanley but also to his own lawyers and to the government,
Scheindlin ruled July 23 in federal court in New York. </p>
<p>The judge also granted Skowron''s motion to dismiss Morgan
Stanley''s breach of fiduciary duty claim relating to the bank''s
payment of $33 million to settle with the U.S. Securities and
Exchange Commission. Morgan Stanley had agreed to cover any
liabilities incurred by FrontPoint for alleged violations of the
law, according to the judge. </p>
<h2>Losses Avoided'' </h2>
<p>That the losses were avoided because of Skowron''s insider
trading and not Morgan Stanley''s wrongdoing does not alter the
conclusion that the settlement amount represented money which
FrontPoint and Morgan Stanley were never entitled to retain,
according to the judge. </p>
<p>Josh Epstein, a lawyer for Skowron, didn''t immediately
return a call seeking comment about the ruling. </p>
<p>Kevin Marino, a lawyer for Morgan Stanley, said We''re
very pleased that the court rejected Mr. Skowron''s attempt to
escape the consequences of his fraud and look forward to
pursuing this case to a successful resolution. </p>
<p>On July 16, the U.S. Court of Appeals in Manhattan ruled
that Morgan Stanley is entitled to $10.2 million in restitution
from Skowron. The court upheld a judge''s ruling that Skowron
owed the bank 20 percent of his salary from 2007 to 2010, or
$6.4 million, and $3.8 million in legal fees. </p>
<h2>Secret Tips </h2>
<p>In August 2011, Skowron admitted to helping FrontPoint
avoid more than $30 million in trading losses on Human Genome
Sciences Inc., a Rockville, Maryland, pharmaceutical firm that
was acquired by GlaxoSmithKline Plc. (GSK) </p>
<p>Skowron admitted he got secret tips from a French
physician, Yves Benhamou, who helped oversee a clinical trial of
a Human Genome hepatitis drug, Albuferon. After Benhamou told
Skowron about disappointing results in the drug trial, Skowron
sold Human Genome shares in FrontPoint''s funds. </p>
<p>Skowron, a Yale University and Harvard University-trained
doctor who quit medicine for Wall Street, is serving his term at
McKean Federal Correction Institution in northwestern
Pennsylvania, according to the Federal Bureau of Prisons
website. </p>
<p>The District Court case is U.S. v. Skowron, 1:11-cr-00699,
U.S. District Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan).
The appeal is U.S. v. Skowron, 12-1284, U.S. Court of Appeals
for the Second Circuit (Manhattan). Morgan Stanley''s suit is
Morgan Stanley v. Skowron, 12-cv-8016, U.S. District Court,
Southern District of New York (Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore and Hugh Son" date="Jul 26, 2013  2:45 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-26/morgan-stanley-to-jpmorgan-said-to-keep-trading-with-sac.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley to JPMorgan Said to Keep Trading With SAC</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Bank of America Corp., JPMorgan (JPM)
Chase  Co. and Morgan Stanley are among Wall Street banks
continuing to trade with SAC Capital Advisors LP after U.S.
prosecutors indicted the hedge fund for insider trading,
according to four people briefed on the matter. </p>
<p>The firms are still providing trading and prime brokerage
services to the hedge fund founded by Steven A. Cohen, said the
people, who asked not to be identified talking about a specific
client. The government has no plan to freeze fund assets,
prevent redemptions or affect interests of SAC counterparties,
Stamford, Connecticut-based SAC said yesterday after the
government''s criminal charges were made public. </p>
<p>Banks have been grappling with the reputational and
financial consequences of continuing their dealings with SAC,
one of Wall Street''s largest trading clients. The $14 billion
hedge fund was indicted for perpetrating what prosecutors called
an unprecedented insider-trading scheme. </p>
<p>You''re always between a rock and a hard place when you''re
the credit guy trying to decide to what to do, said James Rickards, senior managing director at Tangent Capital Partners
LLC and former general counsel at Long-Term Capital Management
LP, which was one of the world''s biggest hedge funds before
losing $4 billion in 1998. </p>
<p>Banks have to ask themselves what is the risk that I lose
money? What is the risk that they get into stress and I don''t
get paid? What is the risk that the regulator criticizes me or
my reputation is tarnished? Rickards said. The other side is
I like the commissions and I want to be a stand-up guy, and I
don''t want to be perceived as a guy who cut and run. </p>
<h2>Protective Measures </h2>
<p>It''s unclear whether other lenders including Goldman Sachs (GS)
Group Inc., Deutsche Bank AG (DBK) and Citigroup Inc. (C) had changed any
of their dealings with SAC. Spokesmen for the banks declined to
comment. </p>
<p>Banks may continue to deal with the hedge-fund firm while
protecting themselves by reducing credit limits, requiring more
collateral and halting trades in over-the-counter products, said
Rickards, who was a credit officer at Greenwich Capital Markets
when junk-bond powerhouse Drexel Burnham Lambert Inc. collapsed
in 1990. </p>
<p>There''s a lot of things you can do between doing nothing
and cutting them off completely to improve your position, said
Rickards. If everyone hangs together, and everyone does some
common-sense things, it''s business as usual. But if one domino
falls, the rest of them will fall very quickly, and that''s why
everyone is on eggshells. </p>
<h2>Allegations Denied </h2>
<p>SAC denied it encouraged or tolerated insider trading and
said it will continue to operate as it works through the
allegations. The Securities and Exchange Commission filed an
administrative complaint against Cohen last week, seeking to ban
him from overseeing investor funds for allegedly failing to
supervise employees and prevent them from engaging in insider
trading. </p>
<p>No major financial-services firm has survived a criminal
indictment in the U.S. While Cohen has vowed to keep open the
most successful equity hedge-fund manager, clients have already
pulled billions from its funds. SAC Capital said in a regulatory
filing this week that it managed $13.9 billion of net assets as
of July 1. </p>
<p>The hedge fund has been among the largest trading clients
for New York-based Morgan Stanley (MS) and Goldman Sachs, according
to people with knowledge of the relationships. SAC has used
those firms, along with JPMorgan, Credit Suisse Group AG (CSGN) and
Barclays Plc (BARC), as prime brokers, Reuters reported in 2011. </p>
<h2>Reputational Risk </h2>
<p>Some of the world''s biggest banks have been emphasizing
their efforts to behave ethically, put clients first, cooperate
with regulators and temper risk-taking after reputations were
damaged during the credit crisis, government-funded bailouts and
scandals throughout the financial industry. </p>
<p>There is definitely reputational risk at this point that
didn''t exist before as a result of the indictment, Rickards
said. I know we''re innocent until proven guilty, and I respect
that, but there''s no requirement that a counterparty be good to
the last drop. You''re allowed to make sensible business
decisions. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Mark Drajem" date="Jul 26, 2013  1:27 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-26/exxon-among-targets-of-divestiture-push-in-climate-push.html"><headline>Exxon Among Targets for Divestiture in Climate Push</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Activist Bill McKibben, who helped turn an obscure oil pipeline project into a high-profile political fight, has a new target for his effort to curb global warming: energy companies such as Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) </p> <p>McKibben''s group, 350.org, is asking colleges, cities and churches to divest their financial holdings from a group of 200 companies that produce coal, oil or natural gas. So far six schools, 16 cities and 11 religious institutions have agreed to divest from those companies, according to his group. </p> <p>We know we can''t bankrupt Exxon, McKibben said in a meeting with Bloomberg News in Washington. But we think we can politically bankrupt them. </p> <p>McKibben''s group has modeled its campaign after the 1980s divestment effort aimed at companies working with the apartheid regime in South Africa. Unless these companies can be persuaded to leave 80 percent of the available fossil fuels in the ground, climate change will proceed at a pace that would be catastrophic for the planet, they say. </p> <p>Students at more than 300 campuses, including the eight Ivy League schools, have joined the movement, which got a mention from Obama during his climate speech last month. They are demanding that over the next five years schools purge their endowments of investments in 200 publicly traded companies with the largest reserves of oil, gas and coal. </p> <h2>Exxon Reacts </h2> <p>Exxon says divestment is the wrong approach to deal with greenhouse-gas emissions. We take great offense to being compared to an apartheid regime, Alan Jeffers, a company spokesman, said. We don''t think it''s an effective part of the debate to focus on divestment, he said. </p> <p>McKibben should instead be trumpeting the growth of natural gas, which emits half the carbon-dioxide as coal when burned for electricity, he said. We are surprised the environmental community doesn''t embrace natural gas more, he said. </p> <p>The effort is a shift in approach for McKibben, who started 350.org in 2008, focusing much of its energy on defeating the TransCanada Corp. (TRP)''s application to build the Keystone XL pipeline. The pipeline would carry the oil produced from the tar sands of Alberta to U.S. refineries along the Gulf of Mexico. That oil is especially carbon-heavy, and locking in production of the tar sands for the next 40 years is especially problematic, McKibben says. </p> <p>If we can bottle up this stuff, then we can buy some time, McKibben said. If we can block Keystone, then the tar sands is basically a dead letter. </p> <p>What''s not clear is if President Barack Obama will agree with McKibben. A State Department analysis found that the tar sands will be developed with or without the pipeline, as producers will use other pipelines or trains to transport the product to refineries. And lawmakers from both political parties are pressing Obama to green-light the application. </p> <p>In a major climate speech, Obama said Keystone would not be in the U.S. national interest if it will, significantly exacerbate the problem of carbon pollution. </p> <p>If that is applied in good faith, there is no way this thing could be approved, McKibben said. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Don Jeffrey" date="Jul 26, 2013 12:46 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-26/exxon-mobil-s-105-million-mtbe-defeat-upheld-by-u-s-court-1-.html"><headline>Exxon Mobil''s $105 Million MTBE Defeat Upheld on Appeal</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A U.S. jury''s $104.7 million damage
award against Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) for contaminating New York City
wells with the gasoline additive MTBE was upheld by a federal
appeals court. </p>
<p>The award for compensatory damages to clean up contaminated
wells was proper, the U.S. Court of Appeals in Manhattan said in
a ruling today, denying Exxon Mobil''s challenge to the 2009
verdict. The Irving, Texas-based company said it plans to appeal
the ruling to the U.S. Supreme Court. </p>
<p>We reject Exxon''s argument that the jury''s verdict
conflicts with and is therefore pre-empted by the Clean Air Act
Amendments of 1990, the appeals panel said, adding that the
jury properly offset the award by amounts attributed to cleanup
of other contaminants. </p>
<p>New York sued Exxon Mobil and other oil companies in 2003,
alleging that they knew the gasoline additive methyl tertiary
butyl ether, or MTBE, would pollute groundwater. Exxon Mobil
argued that state laws are pre-empted by the Clean Air Act,
which required oil companies to reformulate gasoline to reduce
air pollution from vehicle emissions. Oil companies added MTBE
to make it burn more thoroughly. </p>
<p>MTBE has not been used for seven years, cleanup
successfully continues and the myriad of data shows MTBE
detections decreasing, Todd Spitler, a spokesman for Exxon
Mobil, said in an e-mail. The company will be filing an appeal
to the United States Supreme Court, he said. </p>
<h2>Consolidated Cases </h2>
<p>This case is one of scores around the country by
municipalities, states and individuals against oil refiners,
distributors and retailers over MTBE. Many, including New York
City''s, were consolidated in New York federal court for
evidence-gathering. </p>
<p>A state appeals court in Maryland in February reversed two
jury awards totaling $1.65 billion against Exxon Mobil over MTBE
contamination, ruling that the company hadn''t made fraudulent
statements and the property owners who sued hadn''t demonstrated
physical harm. </p>
<p>A jury in New Hampshire state court in April ordered Exxon
Mobil to pay $236 million in damages for contaminating
groundwater with MTBE. The company has appealed that verdict. </p>
<p>The New York jury determined that it would cost
$250.5 million to treat the water and remove MTBE, which can
give water a bad odor and taste and cause cancer in rodents. </p>
<h2>No Punitives </h2>
<p>U.S. District Judge Shira Scheindlin ruled that Exxon Mobil
shouldn''t be liable for the entire cleanup cost because the
wells contained pollutants not from gasoline. She also denied
punitive damages because the company hadn''t recklessly
disregarded risks. The wells hadn''t been used for drinking
water. </p>
<p>The appeals court today rejected cross-appeals by the city.
It said the lower court was correct both in ordering that the
damage award take into account pollution from other sources and
in denying punitive damages. </p>
<p>The appeals court rejected Exxon Mobil''s request for a
retrial on the ground of juror misconduct. The company argued
Scheindlin should have declared a mistrial after one juror
complained that she was threatened by another. The threatened
juror was released while the one who allegedly made the threat
was not. Exxon Mobil claimed the dismissed juror was harassed
because her opinion differed from fellow jurors''. </p>
<p>The trial lasted 11 weeks and the jury deliberated for 11
days. It focused on a representative sample of five wells in the
New York City neighborhood of Jamaica, Queens. All other
defendants had settled with the city. </p>
<p>The appeal is In re Methyl Tertiary Butyl Ether Products
Liability Litigation, 10-4329, U.S. Court of Appeals for the
Second Circuit (Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jeremy Hodges" date="Jul 26, 2013 11:02 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-26/visa-sued-over-card-fees-by-u-k-retailers-from-asda-to-arcadia.html"><headline>Visa Sued Over Card Fees by U.K. Retailers Including Asda</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Visa Inc., which operates the
world''s biggest electronic-payments network, was sued by Wal-Mart Stores Inc. (WMT)''s Asda unit, William Morrison Supermarkets Plc
and Arcadia Group Plc over payment-processing fees. </p>
<p>The three companies sued Visa and its former European
affiliate Visa Europe Ltd., at a London court on July 23,
according to court records. </p>
<p>The European Union proposed caps this week on such levies,
known as interchange fees, that banks can demand from retailers
at 0.2 percent for debit card payments and 0.3 percent for
credit cards. MasterCard Inc. (MA) is also being sued by more than a
dozen companies over the fees in the U.K., including Asda and
Morrison, the U.K.''s fourth-largest grocery store chain. </p>
<p>We have not seen this claim, a spokesman for Visa
Europe, Mark Hooper, said in an e-mail. We are surprised that
a case might be brought and, if it was, would strongly contest
it. </p>
<p>Tania Foster-Brown, a spokeswoman for Arcadia, Russell Craig, a spokesman for Asda, and James French, a spokesman for
Morrison, declined to comment beyond confirming the subject of
the lawsuits. Comet Group Ltd., Iceland Foods Group Ltd., and
six others also filed lawsuits on the same day. </p>
<p>The EU''s antitrust regulators have been reviewing credit
and debit card fees for over a decade, warning that the way the
charges are agreed is anti-competitive. The bloc''s agency said
in 2007 that MasterCard''s fees for cross-border card payments
violated antitrust rules, unfairly inflating the fees paid by
retailers for processing payments. </p>
<p>While interchange fees can be agreed on by banks, card
companies such as Visa and MasterCard provide default ones that
are used unless lenders comes to their own bilateral
arrangements. </p>
<p>Visa Europe split from Visa Inc. (V) before the U.S. card
company''s initial public offering in early 2008. </p>
<p>The case is Asda Stores Ltd. v Visa Inc.  Ors, case no.
13-984, U.K. High Court of Justice, Queen''s Bench Division. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Natalie Obiko Pearson" date="Jul 28, 2013  2:30 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-28/goldman-s-renew-warns-india-wind-order-will-prompt-losses.html"><headline>Goldman''s ReNew Warns India Wind Order Will Prompt Losses</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc.''s ReNew
Wind Power Pvt. said an Indian rule requiring wind farms to
predict output will lead to penalties that will wipe out profits
in the industry. </p>
<p>ReNew joins Tata Power Co. (TPWR), both among India''s largest
renewable-energy utilities, in voicing concern as wind-farm
developers seek a court injunction against the directive
ordering day-ahead forecasts for generation. India''s electricity
regulator will fine developers if predictions aren''t correct. </p>
<p>The level of accuracy they''re asking for isn''t
possible, said Sumant Sinha, chief executive officer of ReNew,
which is backed by a $385 million investment from Goldman Sachs.
Most people will end up paying very significant charges. </p>
<p>The Central Electricity Regulatory Commission imposed the
order this month. The directive, applying to farms built since
May 3, 2010, will affect developers including ReNew, Tata, CLP
Holdings Ltd. (2) and Morgan Stanley-backed Continuum Wind Energy
Pte, which have added some of the largest projects in that time. </p>
<p>Penalties may amount to as much as 15 percent of revenue,
destroying profitability in an industry that has attracted about
$10 billion of investment since 2011, Sinha said. ReNew, which
doesn''t disclose its operating capacity, will find it tough
to meet its own target of adding 200 megawatts a year, he said. </p>
<h2>Court Injunction </h2>
<p>The Wind Independent Power Producers Association has filed
for an injunction at the Delhi High Court, Sunil Jain, the
lobby''s president, said in a July 25 e-mail. Another industry
body, the Chennai-based Independent Wind Power Association, is
considering doing similar, said Chairman K. Kasthurirangaian. </p>
<p>Objections from the industry have already delayed the order
by two years and developers have had sufficient time to prepare,
Rajiv Bansal, the regulator''s secretary, said by phone. </p>
<p>Forecasting of wind generation, an intermittent energy
source, is carried out in parts of Europe and the U.S. to help
stabilize the grid. In India, scheduling will allow wind power
to be sold across states and help authorities prepare network
upgrades to accept more clean energy. </p>
<p>Wind farms of 10 megawatts or more will predict their
generation for the following day every 15 minutes. Missing
estimates by more than 30 percent will incur penalties. </p>
<p>Foreign wind-forecasting specialists such as GL Garrad
Hassan and AWS Truepower can''t guarantee that kind of precision,
Sinha said. In the low-wind season, generation would only have
to swing by a 3 percent margin to incur fines because of
seasonal variations in turbine efficiency, he said. </p>
<p>Nowhere else do they do it at this granular level, he
said. </p>
<p>The measure is necessary for the industry''s long-term
growth, said V. Subramanian, chairman of the Indian Wind Energy
Association. It''s not a question of possible or impossible,
he said in an e-mail. The Indian power sector works with
scheduling of generation and consumption at 15-minute intervals.
Renewable energy cannot be different from other sources of
energy. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hui-yong Yu" date="Jul 29, 2013  6:47 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-29/general-growth-to-sell-its-stakes-in-brazil-s-aliansce.html"><headline>General Growth to Sell Its Stakes in Brazil''s Aliansce</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>General Growth Properties Inc. (GGP), the
second-largest U.S. shopping mall owner, agreed to sell its
stakes in Brazil''s Aliansce Shopping Centers SA (ALSC3) to two buyers
for about $690 million. </p>
<p>Canada Pension Plan Investment Board is buying a 27.6
percent stake in the Brazilian retail landlord and developer for
about $480 million, Toronto-based CPPIB said today in a
statement. Rique Empreendimentos e Participacoes Ltda is buying
General Growth''s remaining stake, according to a statement by
the Chicago-based company. General Growth didn''t disclose the
dollar value of the individual transactions. </p>
<p>Two General Growth entities own about 40 percent of
Aliansce combined, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. The
U.S. company in October bought a 14 percent stake in Aliansce
from Pershing Square Capital Management LP for $195.2 million. </p>
<p>Aliansce, based in Rio de Janeiro, owns 17 shopping centers
and two development projects around the country. Formed in 2004,
the company owns or manages properties totaling more than
800,000 square meters (8.6 million square feet). The assets are
located in areas including Sao Paulo, Rio de Janeiro, Salvador,
Belem and Belo Horizonte. </p>
<p>General Growth expects the sales of its stakes to be
completed in the third quarter. A spokesman, David Keating,
declined to comment on the deals. The company is the biggest
U.S. mall owner after Indianapolis-based Simon Property Group
Inc. (SPG) </p>
<p>CPPIB''s purchase gives it assets in the economically
dominant Southeast and fast-growing Northeast regions of Brazil,
said Peter Ballon, vice president and head of Americas real
estate investments for CPPIB. The company has stakes in
Brazilian real estate valued at more than C$900 million ($877
million), including retail, office and warehouse properties. </p>
<p>CPPIB plans to buy more real estate in Brazil in
partnership with local companies, Ballon said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Brian Wingfield and Dawn Kopecki" date="Jul 29, 2013  6:18 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-29/jpmorgan-accused-of-energy-market-manipulation-by-u-s-agency.html"><headline>JPMorgan Accused of Energy-Market Manipulation by U.S. Agency</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) manipulated power markets in California and the Midwest from September 2010 to June 2011, obtaining tens of millions of dollars in overpayments from grid operators, the U.S. Federal Energy Regulatory Commission alleged today. </p> <p>The agency said in a Notice of Alleged Violations that it had preliminarily determined a JPMorgan trading unit had engaged in eight manipulative bidding strategies. </p> <p>The New York-based bank has agreed to sanctions including a fine of about $400 million in a settlement that may be announced as early as tomorrow, according to a person familiar with the case who asked not to be identified because the terms aren''t yet public. Other sanctions may include forfeiting profits, this person said. </p> <p>Brian Marchiony, a JPMorgan spokesman, declined to comment on the FERC action. </p> <p>The case marks another setback for the biggest U.S.-based bank, which sailed through the 2008 financial crisis without a single quarterly loss. Last year JPMorgan lost more than $6.2 billion from wrong-way derivatives bets placed by traders in London. The incident prompted a U.S. Senate investigation, the departure of two senior executives and a debate over whether Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon should keep his chairman role. In May shareholders re-elected him as chairman. </p>




Photographer: Victor J. Blue/Bloomberg

<p>
Pedestrians walk by the offices of JPMorgan Chase  Co. in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarika Gangar and Matt Robinson" date="Jul 29, 2013  4:39 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-29/ibm-said-to-plan-2-15-billion-bonds-in-two-10-year-sale-1-.html"><headline>IBM Issues $2.15 Billion of Bonds With Two-, 10-Year Offering</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM), the largest computer-services provider, raised $2.15
billion in a two-part bond sale. </p>
<p>The information technology business issued $650 million of
two-year floating-rate notes to yield 3 basis points more than
the three-month London interbank offered rate and $1.5 billion
of 3.375 percent, fixed-rate securities due 2023 priced to yield
83 basis points more than similar-maturity Treasuries, according
to data compiled by Bloomberg. The bonds, the first to be
offered by the company since May 2, may be rated Aa3 by Moody''s
Investors Service, the data show. </p>
<p>IBM''s $1 billion of 1.875 percent, 10-year debentures,
which it issued in July 2012 to yield 65 basis points more than
government bonds, traded on July 25 at 89.99 cents on the dollar
to yield 3.16 percent, according to Trace, the bond-price
reporting system of the Financial Industry Regulatory Authority. </p>
<p>Citigroup Inc., Credit Suisse Group AG, JPMorgan Chase 
Co. and Morgan Stanley managed the offering for the Armonk, New
York-based company, Bloomberg data show. Proceeds will be used
for general corporate purposes. </p>
<p>Libor is the rate at which banks say they can borrow in
dollars from each other. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Drew Armstrong" date="Jul 29, 2013  4:14 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-29/pfizer-to-split-internal-operations-ahead-of-possible-breakup.html"><headline>Pfizer Splits Up Operations Ahead of Possible Breakup</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE), the world''s biggest
drugmaker, said it will split up its three major internal
businesses and shuffle the management that leads them, part of
the company''s preparation for a further break up. </p>
<p>Pfizer in 2012 sold its infant nutrition business to Nestle
SA (NESN) for $11.9 billion and this year spun off its $4.3 billion-a-year animal-health unit. The latest reorganization divides
what''s left of the company into two brand-name drug units and a
generics business, the company said in a statement today. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Ian Read is positioning the New
York-based drugmaker for a potential breakup that may leave just
two units intact: A brand-name drug business with higher margins
and growth, and a cash-generating value business composed of
the company''s off-patent products. Such a split could happen in
two to three years, Read has said. </p>
<p>This represents the next steps in Pfizer''s journey to
further revitalize our innovative core, Read said in the
statement. Our new commercial operating model will provide
each business with an enhanced ability to respond to market
dynamics, greater visibility and focus, and distinctive
capabilities. </p>
<p>Pfizer shares rose less than 1 percent to $29.54 at 4 p.m.
New York time, after jumping 24 percent over the last 12 months.
The company reports second-quarter earnings tomorrow. </p>
<h2>New Leaders </h2>
<p>The changes will give investors a detailed look at the
financial results of each segment to help them assess a split.
Geno Germano, who previously ran Pfizer''s specialty and oncology
units, will head one, the company said. Amy Schulman, the
company''s top lawyer who also ran the drugmaker''s consumer unit,
will head another. John Young, who ran Pfizer''s primary care
business, will head the generics business. </p>
<p>Germano''s business unit will have drugs in inflammation and
immunology, cardiovascular disease, rare disease, men''s and
women''s health, pain and neurosciences, and rare diseases. That
would include new potential blockbusters Eliquis, a blood
thinner, and Xeljanz, a rheumatoid arthritis drug. </p>
<p>Schulman''s business will include vaccines and cancer drugs,
as well as consumer products. Palbociclib, an experimental
therapy being studied in breast and other cancers, has the
potential to be one of Pfizer''s biggest future products. It
would also include Prevnar, a pneumococcal disease vaccine that
was the company''s fourth-biggest product in 2012. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Brian Wingfield" date="Jul 30, 2013  5:55 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-30/jpmorgan-energy-traders-spur-inquiries-from-agencies.html"><headline>JPMorgan Energy Traders Spur Inquiries From Agencies</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) energy traders
who avoided individual penalties in a $410 million settlement
with a federal regulator may face action by other agencies. </p>
<p>Federal and state agencies are free to pursue penalties
against the bank''s employees if they choose, Jon Wellinghoff,
chairman of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, said today
in an interview. He said the FERC would cooperate with other
agencies, which he didn''t identify. </p>
<p>We have had some discussions with some agencies that I
can''t disclose at this time, Wellinghoff said. </p>
<p>JPMorgan, the largest U.S. bank by market value, agreed
today to pay $410 million to resolve FERC accusations that its
traders manipulated power markets in California and the Midwest
from 2010 to 2012. The agency decided not to pursue sanctions
against individuals, though it named them in the settlement. </p>
<p>The decision was made to move forward in this case from a
standpoint of expeditiously settling the matter not to punish
individuals, Wellinghoff said. The FERC has previously reached
agreements to end an investigation without sanctioning
individuals, he said. </p>
<p>Asked in a separate interview with Bloomberg Television
today if he was aware of any investigations being conducted by
other agencies, the FERC chairman said he knew of none. </p>
<p>JPMorgan traders Francis Dunleavy, Andrew Kittell and John
Bartholomew are still employed with the bank, according to the
FERC settlement documents. They worked in JPMorgan''s commodities
unit, run by Blythe Masters, the FERC order showed. </p>
<h2>Lawful Conduct </h2>
<p>Dunleavy, Kittell and Bartholomew didn''t settle with the
commission. The agency decided not to sanction them after they
explained to the commission that their conduct was lawful,
according to a statement from Gibson, Dunn  Crutcher LLP, the
law firm representing them. </p>
<p>The commission''s decision to voluntarily settle with
JPMorgan and not proceed against the individuals can only be
read as the commission correctly concluding that no case or
findings against the individuals could be sustained in a court
of law, William Scherman, their lawyer, said in the statement. </p>
<p>He declined to comment on Wellinghoff''s interview. </p>
<p>Steven Greenlee, a spokesman for the California Independent
System Operator, declined to comment whether the state grid
authority was conducting its own investigation or has received
any inquiries from government agencies. </p>
<p>FERC on July 16 announced $18 million in civil penalties
for four former traders for Barclays Plc (BARC), over allegations of
market manipulation. The sanctions were part of $488 million in
fines and penalties levied at Barclays and the individuals,
which the bank has vowed to fight. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Jul 30, 2013  5:47 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-30/microsoft-sold-853-million-in-surface-tablets.html"><headline>Microsoft Sold $853 Million in Surface Tablets</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) sold $853 million
worth of Surface tablets in its latest fiscal year, as the maker
of Windows software struggles to capitalize on a shift by
consumers toward handheld devices. </p>
<p>Microsoft disclosed Surface sales, which weren''t specified
in the company''s latest earnings report, in a regulatory filing
today. </p>
<p>Earnings in the period that ended in June were hit by a
$900 million writedown of inventory related to Surface, a mobile
touch-screen computer introduced by Microsoft in October to
compete with Apple Inc. (AAPL)''s iPad and tablets running Google Inc. (GOOG)''s
Android operating system. </p>
<p>Windows sales have been besieged by poor demand for PCs,
reflected in five consecutive quarters of declining shipments,
according to researcher IDC. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Drew Armstrong" date="Jul 30, 2013  4:13 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-30/pfizer-beats-estimates-as-company-prepares-for-split.html"><headline>Pfizer Beats Estimates as Company Prepares for Split</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE)''s two new brand-drug
units will operate on a separate basis, reporting independent
profits and losses, under the leaders that Chief Executive
Officer Ian Read elevated to head them. </p>
<p>The businesses, along with an established products line
that could be split from the company after 2017, will report
separate results that will show investors how each line of
drugs, and the leaders managing them, are performing. </p>
<p>I wanted to focus great executive talent on both of those
segments of the business, Read said in a telephone interview
today after the New York-based company reported second-quarter
earnings. The units, led by Geno Germano and Amy Schulman, have
different needs and strategies, Read said. </p>
<p>Pfizer is in the middle of a transition that may see the
world''s largest drugmaker broken up into a brand-medicine
company, which Read calls the innovative core, and a
generics business. Such a split almost certainly wouldn''t happen
until at least 2017, in part because Pfizer needs three years of
audited financial statements, as well as time to get the
businesses running smoothly on a separate basis. </p>
<p>Our current thinking is that this is about getting all
three of these businesses to hum internally, Chief Financial
Officer Frank D''Amelio said today on a conference call. D''Amelio
said it would be difficult to split the company before 2017 if
Pfizer decides to take that ultimate step. </p>




Photographer: Peter Foley/Bloomberg

<p>
Pedestrians walk past Pfizer Inc. headquarters in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Brian Wingfield and Dawn Kopecki" date="Jul 30, 2013  3:09 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-30/jpmorgan-to-pay-410-million-in-u-s-ferc-settlement.html"><headline>JPMorgan to Pay $410 Million in U.S. FERC Settlement</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) will pay $410 million to settle U.S. Federal Energy Regulatory Commission allegations that the bank manipulated power markets, enriching itself at the expense of consumers in California and the Midwest from 2010 to 2012. </p> <p>The bank agreed to pay a U.S. civil penalty of $285 million and return $125 million in ill-gotten profits to electricity ratepayers, according to a FERC order today. JPMorgan also agreed to give up claims to $262 million worth of disputed payments from California''s grid operator, the state authority said in a separate statement. </p> <p>We''re pleased to have this matter behind us, Brian Marchiony, a spokesman for New York-based JPMorgan, the largest U.S. bank by market value, said in a phone interview. </p> <p>The case marks another setback for JPMorgan, which sailed through the 2008 financial crisis without a single quarterly loss. Last year JPMorgan lost more than $6.2 billion from wrong-way derivatives bets placed by traders in London. The incident prompted a U.S. Senate investigation, the departure of two senior executives and a debate over whether Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon, 57, should keep his chairman role. In May shareholders re-elected him as chairman. </p>




Photographer: Victor J. Blue/Bloomberg

<p>
JPMorgan Chase  Co. said July 26 it was considering the sale or spin off of its physical commodities business, including energy trading, three days after a congressional hearing examined whether banks are using their ownership of raw materials to manipulate markets. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jul 30, 2013 10:40 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-30/morgan-stanley-settles-with-new-jersey-over-etf-sales.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Settles With New Jersey Over ETF Sales</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) agreed to pay
$100,000 to the New Jersey Bureau of Securities for violating
state laws by selling non-traditional exchange-traded funds to
investors. </p>
<p>The amount includes $65,000 in civil penalties, $25,000 to
reimburse the bureau''s investigative costs and $10,000 for the
bureau to use for investor education, according to a statement
from the New Jersey Office of the Attorney General. The firm
previously paid $96,940.34 to reimburse New Jersey investors,
according to the statement. </p>
<p>The bureau''s investigation found that Morgan Stanley
advisers recommended non-traditional ETFs to elderly investors
who were looking for assets that offered income, according to
the statement. The investors lost money on the unsuitable
offerings. Morgan Stanley didn''t admit or deny the bureau''s
findings. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley is pleased to reach this resolution with
the state of New Jersey, Christine Jockle, a spokeswoman for
the New York-based firm, said in an e-mailed statement. The
settlement covers the period of January 2007 to June 2009, and
Morgan Stanley revamped its processes regarding these products
over four years ago. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Brian Wingfield" date="Jul 30, 2013  8:24 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-30/jpmorgan-agrees-to-pay-410-million-to-settle-u-s-energy-probe.html"><headline>JPMorgan Agrees to Pay $410 Million to Settle U.S. Energy Probe</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) agreed to pay
$410 million, including giving up $125 million in profits, to
settle a U.S. Federal Energy Regulatory Commission investigation
of energy-market manipulation in California and the Midwest. </p>
<p>The FERC announced the settlement with the New York-based
bank today in a statement, a day after the agency''s staff
formally accused a JPMorgan trading unit of wrongdoing from
September 2010 to June 2011. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Benjamin Purvis" date="Jul 30, 2013  3:30 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-30/goldman-sachs-prices-its-biggest-australian-bond-sale-since-2011.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Prices Its Biggest Australian Bond Sale Since 2011</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) raised
A$750 million ($680 million) in its biggest Australian bond sale
in more than two years. </p>
<p>The five-year debt transaction was priced to yield 170
basis points more than swaps, according to Goldman Sachs
spokeswoman Hayley Morris. The bank sold A$450 million of fixed-rate notes and A$300 million of floating-rate securities. </p>
<p>The Wall Street lender that generates most of its revenue
from trading last sold similar debt in November, when it priced
A$600 million of bonds with the same tenor at a 195 basis-point
spread, data compiled by Bloomberg show. It sold A$1.25 billion
of notes in May 2011. </p>
<p>Bank of America Corp. was the last U.S. bank to sell bonds
in Australia, pricing A$850 million of 2018 notes on May 14,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. Following record debt
sales in May, issuance in the South Pacific nation dropped to
the least since December 2011 last month as concern the Federal
Reserve will reduce stimulus roiled global markets. </p>
<p>The average spread for financial-company bonds in Australia
spiked to as high as 130 basis points more than swaps on July 2
before narrowing to 114 yesterday, Bank of America Merrill Lynch
index data show. While the premium is nearing its level before
Fed Chairman Ben S. Bernanke spoke about tapering at his June 19
news conference, issuance has remained muted. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs holds the seventh-highest credit rating at
Moody''s Investors Service and Standard  Poor''s. Bank of America
carries the same A- ranking as Goldman Sachs at SP and is
graded two levels lower at Moody''s. The 5-1/4 year paper it sold
in May was priced at a spread of 190 basis points. </p>
<p>Today''s Goldman Sachs transaction was managed by the lender
itself, Australia  New Zealand Banking Group Ltd., National
Australia Bank Ltd. and Royal Bank of Canada. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Frier" date="Jul 31, 2013  4:33 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-31/ibm-says-sec-investigating-its-cloud-computing-revenue-figures.html"><headline>IBM Defends Cloud-Computing Accounting Amid SEC Probe</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines Corp. (IBM), facing a U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission investigation into how it reports revenue from offsite cloud services, said it stands by its accounting methods. </p> <p>IBM is cooperating with the SEC in the probe, which it learned about in May, it said today in a filing. The company books its revenue from cloud services, such as storing customers'' data and software applications remotely, under generally accepted accounting principles, said Ed Barbini, a spokesman for Armonk, New York-based IBM. </p> <p>IBM''s reporting of cloud revenue is the result of a rigorous and disciplined process, and we are confident that the information we have provided has been consistently accurate, Barbini said. </p> <p>Chief Executive Officer Ginni Rometty has identified cloud computing as one of IBM''s chief sources of growth amid a slowdown in demand for hardware and for consulting services. The investigation at the company, known for consistently meeting analysts'' earnings estimates, underscores confusion about how cloud revenue should be booked, said Michael Cusumano, a management professor at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology''s Sloan School of Management. </p> <p>This is a murky area where the rules aren''t really established, Cusumano said. Companies treat cloud-computing revenue in different ways. </p> <p>About half of publicly traded software companies since 1990 have had to restate revenue because of misclassification of sales and product returns, or because they categorized ongoing payments for tech-support services as a sale of a product license, Cusumano said. </p> <h2>Disciplined Process'' </h2> <p>While IBM doesn''t disclose its revenue from cloud services, it said the sales rose 70 percent in the first half of 2013 from a year earlier. In its filing today, the company didn''t provide details on what information the SEC was seeking. </p> <p>IBM has robust systems and controls to identify and validate what products and services count as cloud revenue, Barbini said. IBM accounts for cloud transactions exactly the same way as it would account for those transactions if they were not cloud -- in accordance with GAAP. </p> <p>Florence Harmon, an SEC spokeswoman, declined to comment. </p> <p>IBM has beat analysts'' earnings expectations in 32 of the past 33 quarters, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. On the other hand, it has missed sales estimates in seven of the past eight quarters. </p> <p>More Probes? </p> <p>The investigation may be the first in a series of probes into companies in the same industry as the SEC tries to clear up confusion and differences in standards, said Jack Ciesielski, owner of investment firm R.G. Associates Inc. in Baltimore and the publisher of the Analyst''s Accounting Observer. </p> <p>The company has a goal of reaching $7 billion in cloud revenue by 2015, with about $3 billion from new business and the rest from current contracts shifting over to the cloud category. </p> <p>IBM''s 70 percent growth rate for cloud-computing services in the first six months of 2013 was a slowdown from 80 percent last year. IBM has also said cloud revenue, which is spread across several divisions, tripled in 2011 from 2010. </p> <p>IBM shares fell 1 percent to $195.04 at the close in New York. The stock has gained 1.8 percent this year. </p> <p>The disclosure of the probe comes days after IBM won court approval for a $10 million settlement with the SEC for accusations of bribery in China and South Korea. IBM said earlier this year it''s the subject of a U.S. Justice Department bribery investigation related to contracts in Poland, Argentina, Bangladesh and Ukraine. </p> <h2>Autonomy Writedown </h2> <p>Hewlett-Packard Co. (HPQ), IBM''s archrival in the computer-services business, took an $8.8 billion charge last year to write down the value of Autonomy, a software company it acquired, amid allegations of accounting improprieties within the unit. Autonomy, whose products organize corporate customers'' data, had used aggressive tactics to inflate its results, a former executive told Bloomberg News last year. </p> <p>Earlier this month, IBM acquired SoftLayer Technologies Inc., a cloud-computing storage provider. IBM paid almost $2 billion for Dallas-based SoftLayer, according to a person familiar with the deal. </p> <p>Market researcher IDC estimates the cloud-computing market may more than double to $105 billion by 2016 from last year. SoftLayer specializes in public clouds -- data-center networks that manage computing and software for businesses remotely. IBM is pairing those capabilities with private-cloud operations, building dedicated systems for individual customers. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore and Agnieszka Troszkiewicz" date="Jul 31, 2013  4:16 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-31/goldman-sachs-offers-aluminum-to-clients-stuck-in-queue.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Offers Aluminum to Clients Stuck in Queue</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) offered to
speed up delivery of aluminum to users of the metal and proposed
changes to industry rules amid claims that its warehouse unit
created shortages and drove up prices. </p>
<p>So far no client has accepted the bank''s offer to swap
their metal stuck in queues for immediately available aluminum,
Goldman Sachs President Gary D. Cohn, 52, said today in a CNBC
interview. Consumers should have priority over other clients in
getting aluminum out of warehouses and the London Metal Exchange
system needs more transparency, Goldman Sachs said in a
statement. </p>
<p>We feel horrible for consumers if they can''t get metal,
Cohn said. We don''t believe that to be the fact. </p>
<p>The beverage industry has complained that banks and other
warehouse owners are manipulating aluminum supplies and slowing
deliveries to drive up the price. Goldman Sachs said that while
longer queues in recent years have been a factor in the premium
of physical metal over the spot price, the waits are not driving
up the price of aluminum, which has fallen since 2006. </p>
<p>It''s a recognition of a longstanding problem in the
market that needs to be solved, said Diego Valiante, head of
capital markets at the Center for European Policy Studies in
Brussels. Clearly there is also the understanding of the
urgency in solving this issue. </p>
<h2>Premiums Surge </h2>
<p>Detroit, New Orleans, the Dutch port of Vlissingen, the
Belgian city of Antwerp and Malaysia''s Johor have the longest
waits for metal, according to Barclays Plc. Detroit is dominated
by Goldman Sachs''s Metro International Trade Services LLC, while
Glencore Xstrata Plc (GLEN)''s Pacorini Metals has the most storage
units in Vlissingen, New Orleans and Johor. In Antwerp, it is
NEMS, a unit of Trafigura Beheer BV. </p>
<p>Aluminum for delivery in three months fell 13 percent this
year on the LME as stockpiles in warehouses monitored by the
exchange neared a record. The premiums added to the LME price
surged to a record 12 cents to 13 cents a pound in June, almost
double the 6.5 cents in the summer of 2010, according to data
from Austin, Texas-based researcher Harbor Intelligence. The
surcharge fell for the first time this year in the week ending
July 19, according to Harbor. </p>
<p>Glencore, the largest owner of LME warehouses, declined to
comment through a spokesman. Trafigura continues to offer prompt
delivery of metal to its customers, an official at the
Singapore-based commodities trader said. Henry Bath warehouses,
owned by JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), don''t currently have queues,
according to a person familiar with the business who wasn''t
authorized to comment and requested anonymity. </p>
<h2>Costs Inflated </h2>
<p>Goldman Sachs''s offer is great news and any pricing
manifestations due to warehousing issues will hopefully resolve
going forward, said Bart Chilton, a member of the Commodity
Futures Trading Commission. This entire matter continues to
raise the larger issue of banks owning physical commodities,
warehousing and delivery mechanisms. </p>
<p>Costs were inflated by $3 billion worldwide in the past
year because of the backup in aluminum supplies, Tim Weiner, a
global risk manager at brewer MillerCoors LLC, told a U.S.
Senate panel last week. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs has secured metal directly from producers to
be able to swap with end-user clients, Cohn said. The firm has
made the offer at the LME spot price with no premium, according
to a person briefed on the talks who asked not to be named
because the offers were private. </p>
<h2>Considered Selling </h2>
<p>We are consulting with the metals trade and industry on a
proposal to amend the delivery out obligations of warehouse
companies with long queues, and we encourage market users to
contact us with their views, Miriam Heywood, a spokeswoman for
the LME, said in an e-mailed statement. </p>
<p>In February 2010, Goldman Sachs bought Romulus, Michigan-based Metro International Trade Services LLC, which as of July
11 operated 34 out of 39 storage facilities licensed by the LME
in the Detroit area, according to exchange data. Goldman Sachs
said in today''s statement that it isn''t involved with the daily
management of the company. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs earlier this year considered selling Metro,
according to a person briefed on the discussions. The bank must
sell the company within 10 years of its purchase, it said today. </p>
<p>JPMorgan said last week that it plans to get out of the
business of owning and trading physical commodities ranging from
metals to oil, days after a Senate panel questioned whether
banks are abusing their ownership of raw materials to manipulate
markets. </p>
<h2>Incentives Offered </h2>
<p>Cohn said that while his firm will sell Metro at the
appropriate time, it doesn''t have plans to exit other
commodity businesses. </p>
<p>Commodity hedging is a core competency and one of the
most important things we do in the firm, and our clients really
need us to be in that business, Cohn said. We are staying in
the commodity-hedging business. </p>
<p>Low interest rates have encouraged some investors to buy
and store aluminum with the intent of selling it at a later
date, Goldman Sachs said in its statement. Warehousing
companies, which don''t own the metal they hold, offered
incentives to attract supply, according to research from Societe
Generale SA. </p>
<p>Many market participants have sought to move metal to non-LME warehouses, where storage rates are lower, prompting the
longer queues, Goldman Sachs said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jul 31, 2013  1:41 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-31/goldman-sachs-s-cohn-says-sac-capital-is-a-great-counterparty-.html"><headline>Goldman''s Gary Cohn Says SAC Capital Great Counterparty''</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) President
Gary Cohn said his firm continues to do business with SAC
Capital Advisors LP, the hedge fund that was indicted on charges
of insider trading last week. </p>
<p>They''re an important client to us, they have been an
important client to us, Cohn, 52, said today in an interview
on CNBC. We continue to trade with them, and they''re a great
counterparty. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs, which gets more than half its revenue from
trading, is the first Wall Street firm to comment publicly on
its dealings with the $14 billion hedge fund company founded by
Steven A. Cohen. Bank of America Corp., JPMorgan Chase  Co. and
Morgan Stanley (MS) were among firms that were continuing to trade
with SAC Capital after the indictment, four people briefed on
the matter said last week. </p>
<p>SAC Capital denied it encouraged or tolerated insider
trading and said it will continue to operate as it works through
the allegations. The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission
filed an administrative complaint against Cohen, seeking to ban
him from overseeing investor funds for allegedly failing to
supervise employees and prevent them from engaging in insider
trading. </p>
<p>The hedge fund has been among the largest trading clients
for New York-based Morgan Stanley and Goldman Sachs, according
to people with knowledge of the relationships. SAC Capital,
based in Stamford, Connecticut, has used those firms, along with
JPMorgan, Credit Suisse Group AG and Barclays Plc, as prime
brokers, Reuters reported in 2011. </p>




Photographer: Peter Foley/Bloomberg

<p>
Goldman Sachs Group Inc. President Gary Cohn speaks during an interview in New York, June 20, 2012. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Donal Griffin" date="Jul 31, 2013  1:01 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-31/visa-falls-after-court-ruling-on-swipe-fees-san-francisco-mover.html"><headline>Visa Falls After Court Ruling on Swipe Fees: San Francisco Mover</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Visa Inc. (V), the world''s biggest
payment network, fell the most in two years after a judge ruled
that the Federal Reserve had erred by inflating the debit-card
fees that banks can charge retailers. </p>
<p>Visa fell as much as 11 percent in New York trading before
dropping 5.9 percent to $180.15 at 12:43 p.m., the most since
August 2011. Swipe, or interchange fees, are set by Foster City,
California-based Visa and MasterCard (MA) Inc., which collect the
money and remit it to card-issuing member banks. </p>
<p>U.S. District Court Judge Richard Leon in Washington ruled
today that the Fed considered data it wasn''t allowed to use in
setting a 21-cent cap on debit-card fees under the Dodd-Frank
Act of 2010. The decision handed a victory to retailers who
challenged the fees as being too high. </p>
<p>MasterCard, the second-biggest U.S. network, slid as much
as 5.7 percent before falling 0.2 percent to $600.38. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kevin Dugan" date="Jul 31, 2013 12:35 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-31/jpmorgan-commodity-tied-note-sales-climb-to-largest-with-add-on.html"><headline>JPMorgan Commodity-Tied Note Sales Climb to Largest With Add-On</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) sold $195
million of structured notes tied to an index of commodity
futures, the largest such note in more than three and a half
years after the size was increased twice. </p>
<p>The four-year securities, $40 million of which were issued
on July 23, yield the gains and losses of the Dow Jones-UBS
Commodity Index 3 Month Forward Total Return minus a fee with
all capital at risk, according to a prospectus filed with the
U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. The bank originally
sold $65 million of the notes on Nov. 18, 2010, and an
additional $90 million on Feb. 28 this year. </p>
<p>The Dow Jones-UBS benchmark, which tracks natural gas and
19 other commodities, declined 9.4 percent this year to 546.7 at
the close of trading yesterday. The index would have to rise
more than 8 percent from the day the securities were most
recently issued in order to reach the initial level from
November 2010. </p>
<p>America''s power needs are only increasing with
population, as well as the general trend of people moving from
colder states to the Sun Belt, said Aaron Calder, senior
market analyst at Gelber  Associates in Houston. U.S.
regulations could decrease coal production, boosting prices for
other energy sources, he said. </p>
<p>Investors have bought $760.5 million of commodity-tied
notes this year, the slowest period since Bloomberg started
collecting data on the securities in 2010. Globally, banks have
sold about $2 billion of the securities this year, the least
since 2004, Bloomberg data show. </p>
<p>Justin Perras, a spokesman for JPMorgan in New York,
declined to comment on the notes. </p>
<p>Bloomberg started collecting comprehensive data on the
securities in January 2010. </p>
<p>Banks create structured notes by packaging debt with
derivatives to offer customized bets to retail investors while
earning fees and raising money. Derivatives are contracts whose
value is derived from stocks, bonds, commodities and currencies,
or events such as changes in interest rates or the weather. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sergio Di Pasquale, Sonia Sirletti and Elisa Martinuzzi" date="Jul 31, 2013 12:17 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-31/jpmorgan-accused-by-siena-prosecutors-in-monte-paschi-probe-1-.html"><headline>JPMorgan Accused by Siena Prosecutors in Monte Paschi Probe</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Siena prosecutors accused JPMorgan
Chase  Co. (JPM) and at least one of its employees of obstructing
regulators as part of a wider probe into Banca Monte dei Paschi
di Siena SpA''s purchase of Banca Antonveneta SpA. </p>
<p>Prosecutors allege an unidentified person at JPMorgan
Securities Ltd., a unit of the New York-based bank, withheld
information from regulators about a 1 billion-euro ($1.3
billion) financing arranged for Monte Paschi''s takeover of
Antonveneta in 2008, a July 30 court filing obtained by
Bloomberg News showed. The U.S. bank failed to oversee its
employees properly, according to the filing. </p>
<p>JPMorgan arranged a sale of bonds exchangeable into shares
of Monte Paschi to finance the deal. The lender, which benefited
from the alleged crime by earning commissions, didn''t inform the
Bank of Italy that it signed a so-called indemnity agreement
with Monte Paschi, protecting JPMorgan from potential losses
linked to the securities, according to prosecutors. By hiding
the agreement, Monte Paschi (BMPS) was able to count the funding as
equity instead of debt and boost capital. </p>
<p>The documents mark the final stage before the authorities
can request formal indictments, and it brings them a step closer
to reconstructing how Monte Paschi''s former managers allegedly
colluded to misrepresent the lender''s finances in the years
before it sought a government bailout. </p>




Photographer: Alessia Pierdomenico/Bloomberg

<p>
A logo sits on a sign outside Banca Monte dei Paschi di Siena SpA''s administrative offices in Siena. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kana Nishizawa" date="Jul 31, 2013  3:51 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-31/goldman-likes-china-banks-as-earnings-growth-to-exceed-market.html"><headline>Goldman Likes China Banks as Earnings Growth to Exceed Market</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Investors should buy Chinese banks
as earnings may beat projections for the MSCI China Index while
reforms to interest rates fail to crimp profit margins,
according to Goldman Sachs Group Inc. </p>
<p>Chinese lenders may have high single-digit earnings growth
this year compared with Goldman Sachs''s 4 percent estimate for
companies in the MSCI China Index, Helen Zhu, the bank''s chief
China strategist said yesterday. A measure of financial
companies that accounts for 40 percent of the MSCI China has
slumped 13 percent this year through yesterday, compared with a
35 percent surge by information-technology shares and 17 percent
rise by utilities. </p>
<p>Chinese listed banks may see net-income growth slowing to
around 8 percent this year, the official Xinhua News Agency
reported yesterday, citing a report released by the China
Banking Association. While the People''s Bank of China scrapped a
floor on borrowing costs on July 19, the central bank said the
country isn''t ready to do the same with a cap on what banks can
pay for deposits. </p>
<p>We''re looking for banks'' earnings to grow faster than the
overall market-earnings growth this year, said Zhu. Banks''
preparation for a cyclical downturn, sufficient coverage ratios
and a slower loosening of interest-rate controls for deposits
may support their earnings, she said. </p>
<p>Expectations that deregulation of rates would compress net
interest margins -- the difference between what banks pay for
deposits and charge for loans -- may be misplaced, Zhu said.
Lenders hadn''t previously taken advantage of leeway they had to
charge less, suggesting that even more freedom won''t translate
into lower profit, she said. </p>
<h2>Lending Statistics </h2>
<p>In the first quarter of 2013, about 11 percent of bank
loans were made below the benchmark rate, and about 64 percent
above it, PBOC data show. The central bank currently sets the
one-year lending rate at 6 percent, with a one-year deposit rate
of 3 percent, which banks aren''t allowed to exceed by more than
10 percent. </p>
<p>China''s two biggest lenders, Industrial  Commercial Bank
of China Ltd. (601398) and China Construction Bank Corp. (939), reported first-quarter profit growth of 12 percent and 16 percent,
respectively, while net income at the third- and fourth- largest
banks increased 8.2 percent. </p>
<p>The four largest lenders, which include Agricultural Bank
of China Ltd. (1288) and Bank of China Ltd. (3988), traded at 5.21 times
estimated earnings on average, compared with their five-year
average of 8.24 times and MSCI China''s 11.6 times. </p>
<p>Goldman''s 12-month forward target for MSCI China is 59,
according to Zhu. That''s 3.5 percent higher than yesterday''s
close. The target for the Hang Seng China Enterprises Index (HSCEI) is
10,200, a 5.5 percent increase from yesterday. Previous targets
for the indexes were 69 and 12,400. </p>
<p>The key driver of the trend is not going to be beta but
it''s going to be alpha, it''s going to be looking for
structurally appealing areas and stocks that will have reform-driven upside, Zhu said. A lot of these potential reform
impacts are not currently reflected in the earnings consensus so
we see a lot of opportunity for earnings to be revised. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Eliot Caroom" date="Aug 01, 2013  2:01 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-01/exxon-pegasus-pipeline-cracks-may-have-worsened-with-age.html"><headline>Exxon Pegasus Pipeline Cracks May Have Worsened With Age</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM)''s Pegasus pipeline
failed because of original manufacturing defects that may have
worsened, according to a report paid for by Exxon and released
by regulators today. </p>
<p>It is highly probable that some micro-cracking within the
upset/heat-affected zones might have occurred immediately
following the pipe manufacturing, Hurst Metallurgical Research
Laboratory of Euless, Texas, said in the report. The micro-cracks then likely would have merged by further cracking through
the adjacent areas during service. </p>
<p>Exxon doesn''t have a timetable for restarting the line,
David Rosenthal, vice president of investor relations, said
today on a conference call to discuss second-quarter earnings. </p>
<p>The line, which was built in the 1940s and delivers 96,000
barrels a day to Gulf Coast refineries from Patoka, Illinois,
was shut March 29 after spilling 5,000 barrels of oil in
Arkansas. Exxon said on July 11 that the report showed the line
failed because of original manufacturing defects. </p>
<p>The Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration,
released the Hurst report and has finished an initial review of
it, said Damon Hill, a spokesman based in Washington. </p>
<p>The (Hurst) study is one part of our overall ongoing
investigation, as we continue working to identify the underlying
cause of the failure, Hill said by e-mail today. The
pipeline will remain shut down until PHMSA is convinced it can
be restarted safely. </p>
<p>The failed seam was electric resistance-welded, Exxon said
in its statement. ERW seams in pipelines built before 1970 are
known to have defects, according to a 1989 federal report, and
the process was changed in the 1960s to use higher-frequency
current. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Carroll" date="Aug 01, 2013  8:11 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-01/exxon-second-quarter-profit-declines-on-lower-oil-prices.html"><headline>Exxon Second-Quarter Profit Declines On Lower Oil Prices</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) said second-quarter
profit fell for the first time in four years as crude oil prices
declined along with returns from its gasoline and diesel
manufacturing business. </p>
<p>Net income was $6.86 billion, or $1.55 a share, compared
with $15.9 billion, or $3.41, a year earlier, the Irving, Texas-based company said in an e-mailed statement today. The year-earlier quarter included a $7.5 billion net gain from tax-related items and divestments including the sale of part of its
stake in a Japanese refining business. </p>
<p>Brent crude futures, a global benchmark, averaged $103.35 a
barrel during the second quarter, down 5 percent from $108.76 a
year earlier. The average margin from processing crude into
transportation fuels narrowed by 12 percent during the April-to-June period as gasoline demand and prices declined in the U.S.
market that burns one of every five barrels of the world''s crude
supply, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Exxon Chairman and Chief Executive Officer Rex Tillerson
has been steering exploration to Russia, Liberia and the U.S.
Gulf of Mexico to revive crude production after $52 billion in
natural gas investments during the past three years floundered
amid depressed prices for the furnace and power plant fuel. </p>
<p>Exxon, the world''s largest publicly traded energy company,
said in March that its combined oil and gas output will fall for
a second straight year as the company constructs new platforms
and pipelines to bring recent discoveries online. </p>
<h2>Production vs. Demand </h2>
<p>Tillerson reduced the full-year capital projects budget by
4.5 percent this year to $38 billion. The company has
underperformed its biggest U.S. rival, Chevron Corp. (CVX), and the
broader market this year, with shares advancing 8.3 percent.
During that period, Chevron increased 16 percent and the
Standard  Poor''s 500 Index rose 18 percent. </p>
<p>Global oil prices declined during the second quarter as
crude production growth outpaced the expansion in demand by an
almost 6-to-1 margin, according to data from the International
Energy Agency in Paris. The world''s oil supply increased by an
average of 590,000 barrels a day, overshadowing the 100,000-barrel rise in daily demand, the IEA said in a July 11 report. </p>
<p>Rising natural gas prices in the U.S. failed to offset all
of the impact on profit from weaker crude and motor fuel prices
for Exxon, the largest U.S. gas producer. Benchmark New York
Mercantile Exchange gas futures jumped 71 percent to an average
of $4.018 per million British thermal units in the quarter, from
$2.354 a year earlier. </p>
<p>Gas comprised more than 48 percent of Exxon''s overall
output in 2012, up from 41 percent before the company acquired
XTO Energy Inc. for $34.9 billion in 2010 to tap into the North
American shale drilling revolution. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sonia Sirletti and Francesca Cinelli" date="Aug 01, 2013  6:19 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-01/generali-second-quarter-profit-rises-as-non-life-income-climbs.html"><headline>Generali Second-Quarter Net Climbs 74% on Non-Life Business</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Assicurazioni Generali SpA (UCG), Italy''s
biggest insurer, said second-quarter profit rose 74 percent as
higher non-life earnings outweighed a drop at its life business. </p>
<p>Net income climbed to 478 million euros ($634 million) from
274 million euros a year earlier, Trieste, Italy-based Generali
said today. That matched the average estimate of six analysts
surveyed by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Mario Greco is selling non-strategic assets and refocusing on Generali''s core business to
strengthen finances and boost profitability. The insurer is more
than half way to its goal of raising 4 billion euros from asset
sales by 2015, after selling its U.S. reinsurance unit and
Mexican businesses. </p>
<p>Generali published mixed results, Raphael Caruso, an
analyst at Raymond James Euro Equities, wrote in an e-mailed
report to clients. Earnings were supported by the strong
performance of the non-life insurance segment. Nonetheless, the
life insurance segment''s earnings were significantly hampered by
low investment results. </p>
<p>Generali shares declined 0.9 percent to 14.68 euros as of
11:49 a.m., giving the company a market value of 22.9 billion
euros. The stock has advanced 6.8 percent this year compared
with the 16 percent gain in the 30-company Bloomberg Europe 500
Insurance Index. </p>
<h2>Italian Operations </h2>
<p>We have taken significant strides in strengthening our
capital position and improving our operational and financial
performance, Greco, who took over as CEO last year, said in a
statement. Generali is more focused and profitable than it was
a year ago and we are well on track to achieve the targets we
have set ourselves, he said, reiterating that Generali expects
to report higher operating results this year. </p>
<p>Generali yesterday replaced Raffaele Agrusti with Philippe
Donnet as CEO of its Italian operations, which are being
restructured. </p>
<p>The Italian unit restructuring starts now a new step to
develop business, which will require several years, Greco said
on a conference call. It was the right move to have a manager
with long-term prospective. </p>
<p>Greco said Generali''s 6.8 percent stake in Telecom Italia
SpA, Italy''s biggest phone company, is among the assets that
will be sold  under right conditions. Generali, which is the
second-biggest shareholder of Telecom Italia, may consider
exiting Telco SpA, the group controlling the phone company in
September, even if no decision has been taken yet, Greco
said. </p>
<h2>BSI Sale </h2>
<p>The Italian insurer is also selling its Swiss asset-management unit BSI Group as part of a plan approved in January. </p>
<p>BSI is a good asset and we want to sell non-core assets
at the right price, Greco said. There is a complicated
market at the moment, so a sale at a fair value takes time,
requires negotiating, and this is what we are continuing to
do. </p>
<p>Bankinter SA of Spain may buy BSI, CEO Maria Dolores Dancausa said in April. The firm offered 1.5 billion euros in
partnership with U.S.-based Apollo Global Management, Swiss
newspaper L''Agefi reported in March. Generali has said the unit
has a book value of 2.3 billion euros. </p>
<p>The company is on track to achieve attractive earnings
growth and returns, driven by the ongoing restructuring,
Michael van Wegen, an analyst at Bank of America Merrill Lynch,
wrote in a note to clients. Although the Italian macro remains
challenging, in our view Generali still is an attractive
investment case for investors comfortable with exposure to
Italy. </p>
<h2>Mixed Results </h2>
<p>Non-life operating profit increased 23 percent to 389
million euros as the insurer reduced costs. Claims and costs as
a proportion of premiums, known as the combined ratio, improved
to 94.7 percent in the first half from 97.1 percent a year
earlier. </p>
<p>Total operating earnings rose 1.7 percent to 1.05 billion
euros in the second quarter from a year earlier as profit at the
life business fell almost 13 percent to 683 million euros. </p>
<p>Generali''s solvency ratio, a measure of its capacity to
absorb losses, rose to 139 percent by June 30 from 130 percent a
year earlier, the insurer said. As of mid-July, the ratio was
142 percent, excluding a contribution from the sale of Mexican
minorities and U.S. assets, the company said. </p>
<p>Generali was one of nine insurers designated systemically
important by global financial rule makers last month, which may
mean it will face tougher capital standards and tighter
regulation. Greco said today the implications of being a
systemically important insurer aren''t clear and that the company
may not be included on the list in the future. </p>
<p>Generali was put on the list because of its non-insurance
activities, said Greco, adding that the position in that list
might change over time as they are focusing on core insurance
activities, and disposing of non-core assets. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Carroll" date="Aug 02, 2013 10:25 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-02/chevron-profit-declines-as-crude-prices-fall-with-output.html"><headline>Chevron Profit Declines as Crude Prices Fall With Output</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX), the world''s second-largest energy company by market value, posted its biggest
second-quarter profit decline in four years and missed analysts''
estimates as crude oil prices and production fell. </p>
<p>Net income dropped by 26 percent to $5.37 billion, or $2.77
a share, from $7.21 billion, or $3.66, a year earlier, San
Ramon, California-based Chevron said in a statement today. The
per-share result was 19 cents below the average of 21 estimates,
excluding one-time gains and losses, compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Chevron''s oil and natural gas output fell 1.6 percent to
the lowest second-quarter average in half a decade as new wells
in Angola, the Gulf of Mexico and Pennsylvania failed to make up
for declining production from older fields, according to the
statement. The price the company fetched for crude sold overseas
dropped 5 percent, while profit from refining crude into fuels
tumbled 59 percent. </p>
<p>Chevron is looking at a natural decline in its resource
base of 6 to 10 percent a year before they even do anything, so
it''s kind of like running up a down escalator, Edmund Cowart,
who helps manage $22 billion, including Chevron shares, at Eagle
Asset Management Inc. in St. Petersburg, Florida, said in a
telephone interview today. Refining''s been tough for
everybody. </p>
<p>Sales dropped by 8.4 percent to $57.4 billion. Chevron fell
2.4 percent to $123.40 at 9:54 a.m. in New York. </p>
<h2>Shrinking Margins </h2>
<p>Chevron received an average of $94 a barrel for non-U.S.
crude during the quarter, compared with $99 a year earlier,
according to the statement. The company''s so-called upstream
earnings fell 12 percent during the April-to-June period as
worldwide demand for petroleum-based fuels failed to keep pace
with production growth. </p>
<p>Chevron''s refineries posted a $766 million profit compared
with $1.88 billion a year earlier as prices for transportation
fuels fell faster than crude, and the lingering effects of a
California refinery fire hindered production. </p>
<p>Refining margins in the U.S., the world''s largest motor-fuels market, narrowed as lower gasoline use reduced retail
prices by 3.6 percent to a quarterly average of $3.601 a gallon,
based on Energy Department figures. </p>
<p>Chevron Chairman and Chief Executive Officer John S. Watson
pledged in March to raise oil and gas output by one-fifth to the
equivalent of 3.3 million barrels a day by the end of 2017
through mega-projects such as the $47 billion Gorgon gas-export
development in Australia. Last month, Watson signed a $1.24
billion agreement with Argentina''s state-controlled YPF SA to
explore a shale formation in the Latin American nation for oil
and gas. </p>
<h2>Global Production </h2>
<p>Chevron estimated in March that its global output this year
will rise 1.5 percent to an average of 2.65 million barrels a
day, assuming crude prices around $112 a barrel. </p>
<p>Chevron has been the best-performer among the largest
international oil producers this year with a 17 percent increase
in its share price through yesterday. Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM), the
biggest oil company, has risen 7.1 percent, followed by Royal
Dutch Shell Plc (RDSA)''s 0.5 percent gain, Total SA''s 3.8 percent rise
and BP Plc (BP/)''s 7.9 percent increase. PetroChina Co. Ltd. has
fallen 17 percent. </p>
<p>Brent crude averaged $103.35 a barrel during the quarter,
compared with $108.76 a year earlier, according to data compiled
by Bloomberg. Prices fell as worldwide oil production rose 0.6
percent at a time when demand increased by 0.1 percent.
Consumption increases in expanding economies such as China and
India were more than offset by demand declines in the U.S.,
western Europe and Japan, according to figures published by the
International Energy Agency in Paris. </p>
<h2>Gas Prices </h2>
<p>U.S. natural gas prices climbed 71 percent to an average of
$4.018 per million British thermal units during the April-to-June period from a year earlier, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Chevron has been raising gas production in the Marcellus
Shale formation in the eastern U.S. since its 2011 acquisition
of Atlas Energy Inc. The transaction included a previously
signed joint venture between Atlas and Reliance Industries Ltd. (RIL)
that committed the Indian company to cover most of the drilling
costs in exchange for a stake in each well. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Toshiro Hasegawa and Anna Kitanaka" date="Aug 02, 2013  1:24 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-08-02/jpx-says-it-s-in-talks-with-tocom-on-trading-system.html"><headline>JPX Says It''s in Talks With Tocom on Trading System</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Japan Exchange Group Inc. (8697), the
operator of the world''s second-biggest stock market, said it''s
in talks to provide its trading system to Tokyo Commodity
Exchange Inc. </p>
<p>Tocom, as the bourse for gold, rubber and soybean contracts
is known, is examining options beyond next May when its five-year contract to use the trading platform of Nasdaq OMX Group
Inc. comes up for renewal, said spokeswoman Sayaka Sato. It may
keep and upgrade the Nasdaq system or shift to a platform
provided by a different domestic or overseas exchange, she said. </p>
<p>JPX is in discussions with Tocom, said Naoya Takahashi,
a spokesman for the exchange. Nothing has been decided at this
time. Sharing systems would bring revenue for JPX and reduce
Tocom''s systems development costs, he said. </p>
<p>About 25.5 million contracts changed hands through Tocom in
2012, down from a recent peak of 87.3 million in 2003, according
to the bourse''s website. The exchange reported net income of 20
million yen ($201,126) for the year ended March 31, compared
with a 205 million yen loss the previous year, as investors
increased holdings of risk assets and gold prices reached new
highs in February, amid receding risks from Europe''s debt crisis
and economic-growth concerns in developing countries, the bourse
said. </p>
<h2>Tocom, CME </h2>
<p>Tocom President Tadashi Ezaki said on July 12 the bourse is
also in talks with CME Group Inc. about the possibility of
sharing trading systems and met with CME Chief Executive Officer
Phupinder Gill. CME has tentatively offered the use of its
trading systems for around 8.5 billion yen over five years, the
Nikkei newspaper reported today without attribution. JPX is
asking for as much as 7 billion yen for the same period, Nikkei
said. </p>
<p>JPX subsidiary Osaka Securities Exchange Co. uses the J-Gate trading system, also developed by Nasdaq OMX, for
derivatives. The Osaka bourse and Tocom agreed in December 2010
that the commodity exchange can use the OSE''s J-Gate backup
facilities in case of emergencies. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry></news>