
<news><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Aug 12, 2009 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-08-12/jpmorgan-hedge-funds-may-lose-as-derivatives-proposal-advances.html"><headline>JPMorgan, Hedge Funds May Lose as Derivatives Proposal Advances</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;President Barack Obama sent Congress
his plan to rein in the $592 trillion over-the-counter
derivatives industry, a measure that would cut into a profitable
market for banks led by Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) and JPMorgan
Chase  Co. (JPM) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proposal issued yesterday would pressure derivatives
users such as banks and hedge funds to move away from opaque
customized contracts by imposing higher capital and margin
requirements on the instruments. Standardized derivatives would
be moved to regulated exchanges or trading platforms and sent
through official clearinghouses, according to the draft measure. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;The big broker dealers make a lot of money trading these
customized derivatives,&#8221; said Paul Miller, a banking analyst
for FBR Capital Markets in Arlington, Virginia. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Custom derivatives are more profitable than contracts
traded over an exchange, so the dealers will work to get the
legislation &#8220;watered down,&#8221; Miller said. The derivatives
proposal is part of a broader overhaul of financial industry
rules meant to prevent a repeat of last year, when the collapse
of Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. and American International
Group Inc. (AIG) froze credit markets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;These markets have largely gone unregulated since their
inception,&#8221; the U.S. Treasury said in a statement yesterday.
&#8220;Enormous risks built up in these markets -- substantially out
of the view or control of regulators -- and these risks
contributed to the collapse of major financial firms in the past
year and severe stress throughout the financial system.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Biggest Users &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New York-based JPMorgan was the largest derivatives user
among U.S. banks as of March 31, with $81.2 trillion in notional
contracts, according to the Office of the Comptroller of the
Currency. New York-based Goldman Sachs was the second-biggest
with $39.9 trillion, followed by Bank of America Corp. with
$38.9 trillion and Citibank N.A. with $29.6 trillion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The draft legislation would require the Securities and
Exchange Commission and the Commodity Futures Trading Commission
to set capital and margin requirements for non-bank swap dealers
and &#8220;major swap participants&#8221; that are &#8220;as strict or
stricter&#8221; than those set for U.S. depository institutions by
federal bank examiners, according to the proposal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hedge funds and private equity firms would be among the
hardest hit, said Karen Shaw Petrou, a managing partner at
research firm Federal Financial Analytics in Washington. Unlike
federally insured banks, hedge funds and other corporations
aren&#8217;t currently subject to capital standards. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;A lot of the big counterparties, like AIG, lack the
capital to back their bets,&#8221; Petrou said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&#8216;Back Your Debts&#8217; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Hedge funds and private equity players would be the ones
for which the capital requirement would be the highest reach,&#8221;
she said. &#8220;It makes it hard to be a trader when you have to put
up capital to back your debts.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derivatives are contracts used to hedge against changes in
stocks, bonds, currencies, commodities, interest rates and
weather. Credit-default swaps are derivatives created primarily
to protect lenders and bondholders from company defaults. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Obama legislation sent to Capitol Hill yesterday
mirrors the administration&#8217;s preliminary proposals by asking
Congress to impose higher capital and margin requirements, move
most derivatives to regulated exchanges and clearinghouses and
impose supervision over all dealers. The legislation also aims
to &#8220;better protect&#8221; small municipalities and &#8220;unsophisticated
investors&#8221; by limiting their eligibility to trade derivatives. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Justice Department is investigating at least seven
former JPMorgan bankers for possible violations for selling
unregulated derivatives to local governments, according to
Financial Industry Regulatory Authority records. Former bankers
from Wachovia Corp. and Bear Stearns Cos. are also under
investigation, according to filings with Finra, the largest
self-regulator for securities firms doing business in the U.S. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Frank&#8217;s Support &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;House Financial Services Committee Chairman Barney Frank, a
Massachusetts Democrat, told reporters last month he supports
proposals to restrict derivatives sales to municipalities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banks that are derivatives dealers and major market
participants would be regulated by federal banking agencies,
while non-bank investors would be regulated by the SEC and the
CFTC, according to the Treasury statement. The industry would be
subject to greater disclosure requirements, giving regulators
confidential access to data on transactions and open positions
and giving the public aggregate data and trading volumes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;What&#8217;s really starting to hit home is how bifurcated the
regulatory environment&#8217;s going to be for the OTC swap market,&#8221;
said Kevin McPartland, a senior analyst in New York at TABB
Group, a financial-market research and advisory firm. The dual
regulators will create &#8220;a reporting registration nightmare,&#8221;
he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&#8216;Complicated and Costly&#8217; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Operationally and legally, at least for a few years, it
seems like it&#8217;s going to be complicated and costly,&#8221; he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congress, which is scheduled to return from recess on Sept.
8, must reconcile the Obama administration&#8217;s ideas with other
legislative proposals already under consideration. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frank and House Agriculture Committee Chairman Collin Peterson, a Minnesota Democrat, have already embraced many of
Obama&#8217;s plans for derivatives markets, according to a three-page
proposal they released last month. Lawmakers still need to
decide how to split oversight and enforcement between the SEC
and CFTC. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Opaque financial products, including some derivatives,
contributed to almost $1.6 trillion in writedowns and losses at
the world&#8217;s biggest banks, brokers and insurers since the start
of 2007, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Eric Pooley" date="Aug 24, 2009  9:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-08-24/exxon-works-up-new-recipe-for-frying-the-planet-eric-pooley.html"><headline>Exxon Works Up New Recipe for Frying the Planet: Eric Pooley</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Exxon Mobil Corp. is trying to put
one over on you. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world&#8217;s biggest publicly traded oil company wants you
to believe that it actually supports the fight against global
warming. But its tactics, which have been unfolding on opposite
sides of the globe, are just another recipe for cooking the
planet in three easy steps. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exxon&#8217;s old formula wasn&#8217;t working anymore. The oil giant
used to bankroll scientists who claimed all that stuff about
starving polar bears and melting ice caps was just mumbo jumbo.
In a 1998 memo, the American Petroleum Institute -- the industry
group in which Exxon has long been dominant -- said it would
achieve &#8220;victory&#8221; when doubts about climate science become
&#8220;part of the &#8216;conventional wisdom.&#8217;&#8221; That helped create a
noisy minority of skeptics, but it won&#8217;t block climate
legislation forever. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So now Exxon is playing a more subtle game. It runs plenty
of ads featuring people in lab coats talking about clean energy.
It spent $15 million on Washington lobbyists in the first half
of this year -- more than all the solar and wind companies
combined. And it has created its new three-step program, which
is based on bad economics instead of shady science. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step One: Gin up some frightening numbers, and use scare
tactics and lobbying muscle to kill the Obama administration&#8217;s
proposed mandatory cap on carbon emissions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Job-Killer &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the U.S. Senate begins work on the climate-change bill,
which squeaked through the House of Representatives in June,
Exxon is among those denouncing the plan to cap emissions as a
stealth tax that would destroy jobs and drive up energy costs.
How does the oil producer know this? Because think tanks funded
by Exxon and others say so. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company announced last year that it had stopped giving
money to global-warming skeptics who &#8220;divert attention&#8221; from
the need for clean energy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, it supports groups such as the American Council
for Capital Formation and the National Center for Policy
Analysis, which issue industry-friendly research. One study
released in May by the Heritage Foundation, which received at
least $50,000 from Exxon last year, claims that by putting a
price on carbon, the measure will kill millions of jobs and send
gasoline soaring. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The study has been criticized for making wildly pessimistic
economic assumptions -- no energy efficiency gains, no increased
use of renewables -- and for ignoring the bill&#8217;s many cost
containment provisions. The non-partisan Congressional Budget
Office found that middle-class households would pay only $175 a
year more in 2020 because of the legislation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doomsday Study &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But let&#8217;s look closer. This doomsday study claims the
measure would drive gasoline prices to $4 a gallon -- in 2035!
If we don&#8217;t develop alternative energy, which is the whole point
of climate legislation, a gallon of gas will cost a lot more
than that in 25 years. The price of inaction is far higher than
the cost of acting now, though that&#8217;s not a discussion Exxon
wants to have. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step Two: Organize demonstrations. On Aug. 18, about 3,500
people rallied in Houston against the bill -- the first of some
20 such &#8220;Energy Citizen&#8221; events sponsored by API and other
industry groups. The participants were energy industry workers,
many of whom wore T-shirts saying, &#8220;I&#8217;ll Pass on $4 Gas.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How did they come to be there? A leaked memo from API
president Jack Gerard asked the group&#8217;s member companies to send
employees to the rallies to &#8220;focus our message&#8221; against
&#8220;Waxman-Markey-like legislation, tax increases, and (energy)
access limitations.&#8221; He also asked them to keep it quiet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Legislative Caricature &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Royal Dutch Shell and BP refused to participate in the
events because they support cap and trade, but Chevron,
ConocoPhillips and Anadarko Petroleum are involved, along with
more than 60 other businesses and associations. Exxon advised
its workers that attendance was &#8220;at their own discretion and
not required,&#8221; spokesman Rob Young told me, while saying that
Exxon &#8220;opposes this deeply flawed legislation&#8221; and agrees with
the rally&#8217;s job-killer message. How could it not? It helped pay
for studies that &#8220;prove&#8221; the point. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Step 3: Offer a seemingly sensible alternative policy.
Having caricatured the legislation, Exxon then offers a
compromise. That&#8217;s what it did in Australia earlier this month,
after the legislature shot down Prime Minister Kevin Rudd&#8217;s
climate proposal. Last week the chairman of Exxon&#8217;s Australian
unit, John Dashwood, called for replacing cap and trade with a
carbon tax. Echoing a January 2009 speech against cap and trade
by Chief Executive Rex Tillerson, Dashwood said the carbon tax
&#8220;is more transparent to consumers, will achieve greater
environmental benefits and is more difficult to manipulate than
a cap-and-trade program.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tax Without Change &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#8217;s get this straight. Exxon is demonstrating against a
climate bill in the U.S. because it is supposedly a hidden tax,
and on the other side of the globe it is lobbying for a tax.
This may seem contradictory, but it&#8217;s not. I believe the company
simply recognizes what so many others have missed in the debate
over the tax versus the cap: The cap requires economy-wide
emissions reductions, and the tax doesn&#8217;t. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exxon doesn&#8217;t want to do business in a world where cuts in
carbon dioxide are mandatory. It would prefer to pay a modest
tax and keep on polluting. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A tax wouldn&#8217;t guarantee any carbon reductions, let alone
bring about the steep cuts needed to stave off the worst climate
changes. By calling for a small tax instead of a mandatory cap,
that&#8217;s exactly the kind of solution Exxon is proposing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Eric Pooley, a former managing editor of Fortune magazine
who is writing a book about the politics of global warming, is a
Bloomberg News columnist. The opinions expressed are his own.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Ben Sharples and Gemma Daley" date="Aug 26, 2009 12:39 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-08-26/chevron-a-50-billion-project-wins-australia-approval-update1-.html"><headline>Chevron A$50 Billion Project Wins Australia Approval</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Australia approved Chevron Corp. (CVX)&#8217;s
A$50 billion ($42 billion) liquefied natural gas venture on a
remote island, adding stricter conditions to quell environmental
concerns about the nation&#8217;s biggest resources project. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The additional terms for the Gorgon project will enable it
to proceed within a nature reserve &#8220;without unacceptable
impacts,&#8221; Environment Minister Peter Garrett said in Canberra
today. Chevron has said the venture off the northwest shelf may
produce its first LNG in 2014. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decision clears one of the final obstacles to Chevron,
Royal Dutch Shell Plc (RDSA) and Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) building the venture
on Barrow Island, 50 kilometers (32 miles) off the West
Australian coast. Gorgon has contracts to supply fuel to China,
India and Japan and is among more than 12 LNG projects in the
region competing for Asian buyers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Gorgon is big and going to fill the available hole&#8221; for
LNG demand, said Peter Arden, a Melbourne-based analyst at Ord
Minnett Ltd., an affiliate of JPMorgan Chase  Co. &#8220;There&#8217;s a
case for some of the proposed projects that if they don&#8217;t move
quickly then it may get congested and some might not make it.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gorgon partners will make a development decision after
they win production licenses from the Australian government and
development approvals from the Western Australian state
government, Nicole Hodgson, a Chevron spokeswoman, said today in
an e-mailed response to questions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Australia&#8217;s LNG Ambition &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combined with Woodside Petroleum Ltd. (WPL)&#8217;s Pluto project due
to come on line in 2011, Gorgon would leapfrog Australia to
second place behind Qatar among global LNG producers. Australia
ranked sixth among LNG exporters in 2008, according to BP Plc&#8217;s
2009 statistical review of energy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gorgon will have capacity to produce 15 million metric tons
of LNG a year, according to Chevron. Current Australian LNG
output of 20 million tons a year may eventually reach 100
million tons, Peter Cleary, president of North West Shelf LNG,
said this month, more than double Qatar&#8217;s current output. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Environmentalists have opposed developing Gorgon and an oil
spill in the Timor Sea off the coast of Australia&#8217;s Kimberley
wilderness region five days ago renewed concerns over
exploration. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Australian Greens Senator Rachel Siewert attacked today&#8217;s
decision, claiming Garrett is &#8220;signing off on the destruction
of this unique environment.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&#8216;Australia&#8217;s Ark&#8217; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Barrow Island is an A-Class Nature Reserve,&#8221; Siewert
said in an e-mailed statement. &#8220;It has been dubbed &#8216;Australia&#8217;s
Ark&#8217; for its unique range of endangered species.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 202 square-kilometer (78 square-mile) island is a home
to flatback turtles, along with the burrowing bettong, a type of
small kangaroo that lives underground and has died out on the
mainland. The government describes flatbacks as &#8220;vulnerable.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chevron must submit plans for approval covering the
protection of animals such as the spectacled hare-wallaby, the
bettong and the golden bandicoot among 28 additional conditions
for the project, Garrett said today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The San Ramon, California-based company must set up a
monitoring program to detect changes in the turtle population
and take measures to avoid impact on flatbacks, particularly
from light and noise, Garrett said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The venture, which Chevron says has enough gas to last 40
years, will pipe the fuel to Barrow Island from 11 fields that
contain about 40 trillion cubic feet, Exxon says on its Web site. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Carbon Capture &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carbon dioxide generated as the gas is turned into liquid
form will be captured and stored underground, reducing
greenhouse gas emissions by 40 percent, Chevron says on its Web
site. The federal and Western Australian governments have agreed
to jointly pay any long-term liability arising from this plan,
Prime Minister Kevin Rudd said Aug. 17. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ruling brings the three companies closer to building a
venture that on Aug. 18 secured Australia&#8217;s record export
contract with China at a time of tension between the countries.
PetroChina Co. will pay Irving, Texas-based Exxon $41 billion
over two decades for gas from Gorgon, the Australian government
said Aug. 18. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China&#8217;s detention of Rio Tinto Group executives last month
and a visit by Uighur leader Rebiya Kadeer to Australia have
strained relations between the two countries. Stern Hu, an
Australian passport holder, and three other Rio executives were
detained for allegedly stealing commercial secrets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;PetroChina, Petronet &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Petronet LNG Ltd. (PLNG), India&#8217;s biggest importer of liquefied
natural gas, also signed an agreement with Exxon to buy 1.5
million metric tons of the fuel from Gorgon, the company said
Aug. 10 in a statement to the Bombay Stock Exchange. The venture
also has accords to supply the fuel to Japanese utilities Tokyo
Gas Co., Osaka Gas Co., and Chubu Electric Power Co. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gorgon will generate about A$40 billion in revenue for the
Western Australian and federal governments that will be used to
build schools, hospitals and roads, Rudd said on Aug. 17. About
6,000 jobs will be created at the peak of construction, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Western Australia will earn about A$100 million a year from
Gorgon revenue, state Premier Colin Barnett said today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Gorgon partners will buy about A$33 billion worth of
goods and services and sell LNG valued at around A$300 billion
to customers in the Asia-Pacific region over the next 20 years,
Rudd said. Chevron estimates the venture&#8217;s contribution to
Australia&#8217;s gross domestic product at A$64 billion, according to
its Web site. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chevron and its venture partners applied to resources and
Energy Minister Martin Ferguson for production licenses on Aug.
18, Rudd said in Parliament on Aug 20. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Timor Sea Spill &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;The Gorgon Project has been deliberately sited to avoid
areas of particular conservation significance,&#8221; Roy Krzywosinski, managing director of Chevron&#8217;s Australia unit,
said today in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Western Australian Premier Barnett made the A$50 billion
estimate of Gorgon&#8217;s construction costs in March, a figure that
would make it the country&#8217;s biggest resources project. The
venture has yet to release its own projection. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PTT Exploration  Production Pcl (PTTEP), Thailand&#8217;s only publicly
traded exploration company, said it may take 50 days to stop an
oil and gas leak about 250 kilometers from the coast in an area
some 800 kilometers north of Barrow Island. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LNG is natural gas that has been chilled to liquid form,
reducing it to one-six-hundredth of its original volume at minus
161 degrees Celsius (minus 259 Fahrenheit), for transportation
by ship to destinations not connected by pipeline. On arrival,
it&#8217;s turned back into gas for distribution to power plants,
factories and households. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry></news>