
<news><entry author="By Katherine Greene" date="Aug 12, 2008  4:45 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-08-12/aci-fossil-jpmorgan-sonus-unionbancal-u-s-equity-movers.html"><headline>ACI, Fossil, JPMorgan, Sonus, UnionBanCal: U.S. Equity Movers</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;The following companies had unusual
price changes in U.S. markets. Stock symbols are in parentheses
after company names, and prices are as of 4 p.m. in New York. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Financial companies fell after JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) 
reported a $1.5 billion loss on mortgaged-back assets and
Wachovia Corp. (WB)  said its second-quarter loss was bigger
than reported in July. JPMorgan slid 9.5 percent, the most since
July 2002, to $37.92. Wachovia plunged 12 percent to $16. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wells Fargo  Co. (WFC)  fell 3.9 percent to $30.38. Bank
of America Corp. (BAC)  dropped 6.7 percent to $31.13.
Citigroup Inc. (C)  lost 6.5 percent to $18.54. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)  and Morgan Stanley (MS US),
the two biggest U.S. securities firms, had their third-quarter
profit estimates lowered by analysts who cited weaker revenue
from underwriting and equity capital markets. Goldman slid 6
percent to $167.30. Morgan Stanley (MS) sank 6.4 percent to $42.50. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ACI Worldwide Inc. (ACIW)  dropped the most since April
2000, tumbling 31 percent to $14.56. The maker of electronic-transaction software for banks reported second-quarter profit
that was 83 percent less than analysts estimated before one-time
items, according to Bloomberg data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comverge Inc. (COMV US) plunged 27 percent, the most since
its April 2007 initial public offering, to $6.55. The provider of
electric demand reduction systems reported a second-quarter loss
of 45 cents, wider than the average estimate of 38 cents, based
on a Bloomberg survey of 12 analysts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Constellation Energy Group Inc. (CEG US) plunged 16 percent,
the most in seven years, to $61.21. The biggest U.S. power
marketer doubled its estimates of the collateral it would need if
its senior unsecured debt is cut below investment grade. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fluor Corp. (FLR)  fell 6 percent to $71.64, the lowest
since March 31. The largest publicly traded U.S. engineering firm
was cut to ''''hold'''' from ''''buy'''' at Citigroup Inc. Analyst Brian Chin said the stock is trading at a higher valuation than its
construction and engineering peer group. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fossil Inc. (FOSL)  gained the most since November, adding
11 percent to $31.94. The seller of namesake watches and
accessories reported second-quarter earnings and sales and an
annual profit forecast that topped analysts'' estimates. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LDK Solar Co. (LDK US) jumped the most since March, rising
17 percent to $39.37. The Chinese maker of silicon wafers said
net income rose more than fivefold, beating estimates, as it
expanded output faster than expected. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McDermott International Inc. (MDR)  slid the most since
March 2004, losing 14 percent to $36.21. The energy-services
company that''s expanding its nuclear-fuel business reported
second-quarter sales that were 2.9 percent lower than analysts''
average estimate, according to Bloomberg data. The shortfall was
McDermott''s biggest since the final three months of 2005. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nelnet Inc. (NNI)  climbed 6.9 percent to $12.50, a two-month high. The student loan provider reported second-quarter
profit of 54 cents a share before one-time costs, nearly three
times the average analyst estimate of 19 cents. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PNM Resources Inc. (PNM)  fell 12 percent, the most since
March 7, to $11.31. The owner of New Mexico''s biggest utility
reported a $143.5 million second-quarter loss and cut its
dividend by 46 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schawk Inc. (SGK)  dropped the most in a month, falling
8.2 percent to $12.74. The digital-imaging service said second-quarter operating profit dropped from a year earlier on lower
sales and costs for restructuring and asset impairment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sonus Networks Inc. (SONS)  slid the most since November
2005, declining 17 percent to $3.49. The maker of software used
for Internet-based phone calls said it wouldn''t achieve its
forecast for 20 percent sales growth this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TurboChef Technologies Inc. (OVEN US) jumped 6.8 percent to
$5.98. Middleby Corp. (MIDD) , the maker of Toastmaster ovens
and commercial kitchen equipment, said it would buy the designer
of high-speed ovens in a cash and stock deal valued at $6.47 a
share based on yesterday''s closing prices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Middleby fell 7.9 percent, the most in three months, to
$53.07. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UnionBanCal Corp. (UB US) climbed the most since July 16,
gaining 13 percent to $65.50. California''s second-largest bank
got a $3 billion offer to sell its remaining stock at $63 a share
to its biggest shareholder, Mitsubishi UFJ Financial Group Inc. (8306)
UnionBanCal said it is assessing the bid. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zoltek Cos. (ZOLT US) dropped the most in six month, losing
15 percent to $15.52. The maker of carbon fibers for windmill
blades reported third-quarter profit and sales that trailed
analysts'' estimates after failing to win ''''significant''''
contracts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Thompson and Louisa Nesbitt" date="Aug 13, 2008  4:57 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-08-13/dsg-falls-as-jpmorgan-casts-doubt-on-asset-sales-cuts-rating.html"><headline>DSG Falls as JPMorgan Casts Doubt on Asset Sales, Cuts Rating</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;DSG International Plc fell the most
in seven months in London trading after JPMorgan Chase  Co. cast
doubt on the retailer''s ability to raise money by selling assets
and advised investors to pare holdings of the stock. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DSG slid as much as 12 percent, wiping 190 million pounds ($361
million) off its market value. Optimism that the U.K.''s largest
seller of consumer electronics may be able to improve its finances
with asset sales is ''''misplaced,'''' JPMorgan said today, cutting its
recommendation to ''''underweight'''' from ''''neutral.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stock in Hemel Hempstead, England-based DSG has lost 44
percent this year as higher food and fuel bills prompt Europeans
to reduce spending on electronics and make purchases on the Web
or from supermarkets. DSG, owner of PC World and Currys stores,
reported its first annual loss since 1994 in June and expressed
caution about consumer confidence in several markets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The retailer''s ''''Spanish and Italian operations are
leasehold and loss-making, and operating in markets that are
likely to remain challenging for some time,'''' Simon Irwin, an
analyst at JPMorgan in London, said in a research report. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DSG fell 6.07 pence, or 9.9 percent, to 55.25 pence at 9:51
a.m. local time, posting the fourth-biggest loss in the 666-company FTSE All-Share Index. (ASX) At yesterday''s close, the stock
had jumped by four-fifths in four weeks, a gain that JPMorgan
said stemmed partly from optimism about asset sales. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The retailer was today''s worst performer in the 19-company
FTSE 350 General Retailers Index, which fell the most among the
39 industry groups. Kesa Electricals Plc, the owner of the U.K.
Comet chain, lost as much as 4.8 percent, while Home Retail
Group Plc (HOME), owner of the Argos and Homebase chains, dropped as
much as 7.3 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JPMorgan set a share-price estimate of 50 pence for shares
of DSG. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Thompson" date="Aug 13, 2008  2:05 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-08-13/dsg-international-shares-lowered-to-underweight-at-jpmorgan.html"><headline>DSG International Shares Lowered to `Underweight'' at JPMorgan</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;DSG International Plc, the U.K.''s
largest consumer-electronics retailer, was downgraded to
''''underweight'''' from ''''neutral'''' at JPMorgan Chase  Co. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DSG shares have rallied 86 percent since July 7 ''''in part on
hopes that DSG could ease its financial situation through asset
sales,'''' the analysts, including Simon Irwin, wrote in a research
note dated today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''We believe these hopes are misplaced,'''' the team added, as
''''DSG''s Spanish and Italian operations are leasehold and loss
making, and operating in markets that we think are likely to
remain challenging for some time.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As opposed to selling these assets, ''''we believe that DSG
may have to invest in them to close or restructure.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JPMorgan set a share-price estimate of 50 pence. The stock
closed yesterday 8.4 percent higher at 64.75 pence. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Dermot Doherty" date="Aug 15, 2008 11:38 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-08-15/cytos-rises-most-in-five-weeks-on-pfizer-agreement-update2-.html"><headline>Cytos Rises Most in Five Weeks on Pfizer Agreement</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Cytos Biotechnology AG (CYTN), the Swiss
developer of allergy vaccines, rose the most in five weeks in
Swiss trading after it sold Pfizer Inc. (PFE) rights to experimental
drugs for as much as 150 million Swiss francs ($137 million). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cytos climbed 5.3 Swiss francs, or 10 percent, to 57.5
francs, its biggest gain since July 10. The shares have fallen 32
percent this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer will make an upfront payment of 10 million francs and
may pay an additional 140 million francs in milestone and
transfer fees for immune-response technology, Schlieren,
Switzerland-based Cytos said in an e-mailed statement today.
Cytos will also get research funding and royalty payments, which
may rise to more than 10 percent depending on product sales. The
company didn''t specify which diseases the accord covers. The deal
follows the sale last year of rights to an experimental nicotine
vaccine to Novartis AG. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''This is very important for Cytos because it''s a validation
of the technology on a broader base as a means of developing
therapeutic vaccines, and it bodes well for the licensing of its
other vaccines,'''' Markus Metzger, an analyst at Bank Vontobel,
said in a telephone interview. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer will be responsible for preclinical and clinical
development of the vaccines, as well as manufacturing and
marketing. The medicines will be developed for diseases not
currently covered by Cytos'' own drug development program. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Retain Rights &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Swiss company, which already works with Pfizer in animal
health, will retain the right to develop vaccines that target the
same diseases in a different way. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''The vaccines market, including therapeutic vaccines,
represents an increasingly attractive segment of the health care
market,'''' Mark Dyer, vice president of business development at
Cytos, said in the statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The existing accord with Novartis covers a new treatment for
Alzheimer''s disease that will begin advanced testing this year.
Cytos is testing another compound that may replace the need for
patients with high blood pressure to take daily pills. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cytos is also working on an experimental dust-mite and cat
allergy vaccine. The Swiss company said July 10 the compound
performed better than a placebo in a study. In November, Cytos
said its experimental skin cancer medicine showed positive
results in a clinical trial. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Maren Naess Olsen" date="Aug 15, 2008  4:40 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-08-15/european-oil-services-stocks-raised-to-attractive-at-goldman.html"><headline>European Oil-Services Stocks Raised to `Attractive'' at Goldman</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;European oil services companies were
raised to ''''attractive'''' from ''''neutral'''' by Goldman Sachs Group
Inc., on prospects for contract awards to pick up in 2009. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''We expect the sector to perform better as companies
confirm their growth outlook for 2009, driven by the oil
industry''s continuing need to invest to create greater spare
capacity,'''' Goldman said in a report published today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.K.''s Petrofac Ltd. (PFC) and Aker Solutions ASA of Norway
were kept on Goldman''s ''''Conviction Buy'''' list. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saipem SpA (SPM), Europe''s biggest oil-field services provider,
was cut to ''''sell'''' from ''''neutral'''' by Goldman because it''s
overvalued compared with its peers, as was Norway''s Sevan Marine
ASA. (SEVAN) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Dermot Doherty" date="Aug 15, 2008  3:34 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-08-15/cytos-rises-most-in-five-weeks-on-pfizer-vaccine-agreement.html"><headline>Cytos Rises Most in Five Weeks on Pfizer Vaccine Agreement</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Cytos Biotechnology AG (CYTN), the Swiss
developer of allergy vaccines, rose the most in five weeks in
Zurich trading after it sold Pfizer Inc. (PFE) rights to experimental
drugs for as much as 150 million Swiss francs ($137 million). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cytos climbed as much as 5.1 francs, or 9.8 percent, its
biggest gain since July 10. The stock increased 4.3 francs, or
8.2 percent, to 56.5 francs as of 9:30 a.m. The shares had lost
38 percent this year before today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer will make an upfront payment of 10 million francs and
may pay an additional 140 million francs in milestone and
transfer fees for immune-response technology, Schlieren,
Switzerland-based Cytos said in an e-mailed statement today.
Cytos will also get research funding and royalty payments, which
may rise to more than 10 percent depending on product sales. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Tim Culpan" date="Aug 18, 2008  3:37 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-08-18/microsoft-under-antitrust-probe-in-taiwan-over-vista-update1-.html"><headline>Microsoft Under Antitrust Probe in Taiwan Over Vista</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), the world''s largest
software maker, is being probed by Taiwan''s Fair Trade Commission
after an activist group filed a complaint saying consumers are
being forced to buy its Windows Vista operating system. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''We have received the complaint and are now conducting our
own investigation, which may last around six months,'''' Chou Ya-shu, the antitrust regulator''s spokeswoman, said in a telephone
interview today. Microsoft can face fines of as much as NT$25
million ($796,000) and be ordered to halt illicit practices if
found guilty of fair-trade breaches, she said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sophia Chang, a spokeswoman for Microsoft in Taipei, denied
the company forces people to buy Vista and declined to comment
further on the case. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft should be fined for using its monopoly to force
consumers to adopt Vista after the company ended sales of Windows
XP in June, Taiwan''s Consumer Foundation, a non-profit group,
said in its complaint posted on its Web site on Aug. 15. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft, based in Redmond, Washington, stopped selling XP
individually and pre-installing the operating system in most
computers in June to spur Vista sales. Vista, which was released
for consumers in January last year, requires more memory capacity
and greater processing power than XP. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''It would be a very unusual and creative interpretation of
antitrust law to say that a company is obliged to keep selling a
product,'''' said Brendon Carr, an attorney who advises
multinational companies on antitrust issues at the law firm Hwang
Mok Park in Seoul. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Demand For XP &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Consumer Foundation said its research showed 56 percent
of consumers buying a computer with Vista would reinstall XP,
while 67 percent oppose Microsoft ending the sale of the earlier
operating system. Windows XP remains available preinstalled in
some low-cost computers such as Acer Inc. (2353)''s Aspire One laptop. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under Taiwan''s Fair Trade Act, a company may not ''''use
incentives or other devious means to induce a business to alter a
consumer''s shopping choices,'''' the foundation said in the
statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''The Fair Trade Commission should fine Microsoft a large
enough amount that would strip away its profits from selling
Vista,'''' the foundation said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Carla Main" date="Aug 19, 2008  8:32 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-08-19/greenoak-intel-n-data-nfl-microsoft-in-court-news-update1-.html"><headline>Greenoak, Intel, N-Data, NFL, Microsoft in Court News</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Intel Corp. (INTC), the world''s largest
semiconductor maker, sued Negotiated Data Solutions LLC to
protect customers including Dell Inc. from royalty demands on the
industry standard for Ethernet computer networking. The
technology allows computers to work together in a local network. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intel said Negotiated Data, more commonly known as N-Data,
sued Dell, and Intel has pledged to cover any liability Dell
incurs. It wants a court to rule that the N-Data patents are
invalid or that they were already paid for under an agreement
with National Semiconductor Corp. (NSM), the original patent owner. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;N-Data earlier this year settled a U.S. Federal Trade
Commission complaint that it was trying to hold up the computer
industry by demanding high royalties for the Ethernet standard.
N-Data agreed to limits on how much it can collect. Intel
contends in a complaint filed Aug. 15 in federal court in
Marshall, Texas, that N-Data shouldn''t be allowed to collect
anything from Intel customers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Intel Corp. v. Negotiated Data Solutions LLC,
08cv319, U.S. District Court, Eastern District of Texas
(Marshall). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cuomo Auction-Rate Accords May Exclude Some Holders &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New York State Attorney General Andrew Cuomo''s effort to
force buybacks by Wall Street banks and brokers of auction-rate
securities may not help some individual investors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last two weeks, Cuomo reached agreements with
Citigroup (C) Inc., UBS (UBSN) AG, Morgan Stanley, JPMorgan (JPM) Chase  Co. and
Wachovia (WB) Corp. to begin buying back $42 billion of the debt they
sold directly to individuals. The accords don''t extend to
investors holding most of the remaining $160 billion bought
through mutual fund firms or brokers that didn''t underwrite the
debt. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cuomo, 50, said in a statement on Aug. 15 that New York-based Goldman Sachs Group Inc. is still negotiating with
regulators. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investors have been stuck in the securities since the market
collapsed in February. Dealers, who for two decades bought debt
that went unsold at auctions, suddenly pulled back because of
widening credit-market losses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investors who were told the debt was as safe and liquid as
money-market funds were left with depreciating securities they
couldn''t sell as auctions failed. Cuomo says the brokerages
continued to market the debt as cash equivalents even though they
knew demand was weakening. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The auction-rate probes focused on the biggest underwriters
because those banks have the largest concentration of clients
holding the debt, Cuomo said. Citigroup was the market''s biggest
underwriter, followed by UBS, according to data from Thomson
Reuters. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph Evangelisti, a spokesman for New York-based JPMorgan,
which agreed to buy back $3 billion, said its settlement didn''t
extend to customers of other firms. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Missouri Secretary of State Robin Carnahan confirmed the
settlement with Charlotte, North Carolina-based Wachovia is
limited to the bank''s clients. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merrill Lynch  Co. is negotiating a settlement with
regulators after offering on Aug. 7 to redeem $10 billion from
its clients starting in January, according to Massachusetts
Secretary of State William Galvin, who sued the New York-based
company over its auction-rate sales practices on July 31. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drawing the line on who should be forced to buy back
securities can be a challenge because brokerages with a
significant wealth management practices put clients into auction
rate securities, noted Barry Silbert, chief executive officer of
New York-based Restricted Stock Partners, which operates a
trading system for hard-to-sell securities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cuomo said he subpoenaed about 25 companies that sold
auction-rate securities. There are also 12 states coordinating
probes into the collapse of the market, as well as the U.S.
Securities and Exchange Commission. Cuomo''s investigation has
expanded to include Fidelity Investments and Charles Schwab Corp.
of San Francisco, CNBC reported on Aug. 15, citing people with
knowledge of the situation it didn''t name. The attorney general
said in an interview Aug. 15 ''''we''re working our way'''' down the
list of brokerages and they expect to get to the smaller
brokerages ''''eventually.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smaller brokerages and mutual fund companies say they were
misled by Wall Street banks about the health of the market and
are not in the same situation as the firms that are offering to
buy back securities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oppenheimer Inc., a broker-dealer based in New York, told
its clients last week it is working with the Washington-based
Regional Bond Dealers Association to press for SEC intervention
in the probes so banks that neither underwrote securities nor
brokered auctions are not forced to buy them back from customers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;North Principal Hedge Fund Sues Greenoak Over German Wind Farms &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;North Principal Investment Fund Ltd., a Cayman Island-registered hedge fund, is suing private equity firm Greenoak
Group in London over a 75-million-euro ($110 million) sale of
permits to build German wind farms. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greenoak contends it controls 80 percent of the permits
through Germany''s Sandbank Power GmbH. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NPI claims veto rights over the permits, which could be
worth as much as 150 million euros to investors seeking to profit
from alternative energy markets, according to documents filed in
London''s High Court and lawyers'' comments at an Aug. 15 hearing
before Judge David Richard on whether to overturn an injunction
related to the sale. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard said he would rule on the dispute Aug. 28, two weeks
before a deadline Greenoak faces to sell the permits to investors
who haven''t been publicly identified. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Richard lifted an order from seven months ago that required
either NPI or the court to approve any eventual sale. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of the world''s biggest private equity firms are
investing in Europe''s wind farms. Blackstone Group LP (BX), manager of
the world''s largest leveraged buyout fund, said last month it
would build a 1 billion-euro offshore wind farm in Germany. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is North Principal Investment Fund Ltd. v. Greenoak
Power Ltd. and Greenoak Renewable Energy Ltd. HC07C3344. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;DFL to Sue Cartel Office Over TV Rights, Handelsblatt Reports &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DFL German soccer league plans to sue the German cartel
office over restrictions on how it can market its television
rights, Handelsblatt newspaper reported, citing DFL vice
President Peter Peters. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By insisting that free-to-air broadcasts of Bundesliga game
highlights must be made available before 8 p.m., the cartel
office undermined the basis of a five-year contract between the
DFL and Sirius agency valued at three billion euros
($4.4 billion), Peters told Handelsblatt. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the DFL lawsuit is unsuccessful and the contract with
Sirius dissolved, the league will invite new bids for Bundesliga
TV rights, Handelsblatt said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Chrysler Sues Johnson Controls Over Lead-Overcharging Claims &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chrysler LLC, the third-largest U.S. automaker, sued battery
maker Johnson Controls Inc. (JCI) over claims it overcharged the
automaker for lead that wasn''t in the batteries it delivered this
year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The suit seeks at total of $18.2 million. The complaint
filed Aug. 14 in state court in Pontiac, Michigan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chrysler seeks $15.1 million for batteries already delivered
in 2008 and $3.1 million for batteries scheduled for delivery
during the rest of the year. Johnson Controls is the world''s
largest producer of automotive batteries and the world''s largest
buyer of lead. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lead prices have fallen 34 percent this year, the most of
the six main London Metal Exchange metals. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more new suits news from yesterday, click here. For copies of
recent civil complaints, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lawsuits/Pretrial &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ex-Lehman Broker, Former Exec in Plea Talks in Squawk-Box Case &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Former Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. stockbroker David Ghysels is negotiating to plead guilty on a charge he conspired
to commit fraud by allowing day traders to eavesdrop on internal
''''squawk boxes,'''' a U.S. prosecutor said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Former A.B. Watley Group Inc. (ABWG) executive Keevin Leonard, one
of the day traders charged in the case, is also in plea talks,
his lawyer, Thomas Dunn, said at a hearing yesterday before U.S.
District Judge Jack B. Weinstein in Brooklyn, New York. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is U.S. v. Mahaffy, 05-0613, U.S. District Court,
Eastern District of New York (Brooklyn). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more lawsuits news from yesterday, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Trials/Appeals &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;NFL, Reebok Win U.S. Appeals Court Ruling Over Team Logo Hats &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The National Football League didn''t violate antitrust laws
in granting Reebok International Ltd. an exclusive license to
make hats featuring logos of the league''s 32 teams, a federal
appeals court ruled. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 7th U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals in Chicago, upholding
the lower court, rejected the argument of cap maker American
Needle Inc. that the league''s franchises illegally conspired to
restrain trade. The appeals court found the league speaks with
one voice in its marketing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;U.S. Circuit Judge Michael Kanne wrote that the NFL teams
are a ''''single source of economic power'''' when promoting the
football league. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The New York-based league, its 32 teams and their licensing
arm, NFL Properties LLC, were all sued in 2004 by Buffalo Grove,
Illinois-based American Needle. The company had held a license to
make NFL team logo hats for more than 20 years before sportswear
maker Reebok won the exclusive contract in 2001, according to the
appeals court ruling. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reebok, based in Canton, Massachusetts, was acquired in 2006
by Adidas AG (ADS) of Herzogenaurach, Germany. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is American Needle Inc. v. National Football
League, 07-4006, 7th U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals (Chicago). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more trial news from yesterday, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Verdicts/Settlements &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;General Dynamics Pays $4 Million to Settle U.S. Billing Lawsuit &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;General Dynamics Corp. (GD), the largest maker of armored
vehicles for the U.S. military, agreed to pay $4 million to
settle a lawsuit claiming a unit fraudulently billed the
government for defectively manufactured parts used in Navy
aircraft and submarines. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The government alleged that from September 2001 to August
2003 the division known as General Dynamics Armament and
Technical Products defectively manufactured or failed to test
parts used in Navy aircraft, such as the C-141 transport plane.
The unit, based in Glen Cove, New York, closed in 2004. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is U.S. ex rel. McMillan v. General Dynamics
Armament and Technical Products Inc., 03-CV-4090, Eastern
District of New York (Brooklyn). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more verdict and settlement news from yesterday, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Litigation Departments &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;U.S. Firm Partners With U.K. Cartel Insurer, LegalWeek Says &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cohen, Milstein, Hausfeld  Toll, a U.S. law firm with a
London office, has entered into a deal with U.K. insurance
company FirstAssist Legal Protection to provide insurance as a
way of making antitrust claims more accessible in the U.K.,
LegalWeek.com reported. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The deal has been dubbed ''''Cartel Key.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So-called cartel claims, as antitrust claims are called in
the U.K., are rarely brought because the plaintiff bears the
defendant''s legal fees and costs as well as his own if he doesn''t
win. The insurance deal, which is the first of its kind, will
insure claimants against paying the defendant''s legal fees as
well as insuring the client against his own costs, LegalWeek
said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the client wins, Cohen Milstein pays a premium to
FirstAssist, the newspaper said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cohen Milstein specializes in class-action, or group,
lawsuits, according to the firm''s Web site. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cohen Milstein plans to take cartel cases on a contingency
fee basis. The insurance is expected to serve as an incentive to
settle in order to keep costs low, the newspaper reported. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more litigation department news from yesterday, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Court News &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Joseph Ziccardi, an attorney, was turned down in his bid
yesterday to have the federal court in Philadelphia reconsider
the sanctions it imposed on him for failing to rein in an out-of-control client during a deposition, Law.com reported. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The client used the four-letter ''''F'''' word 73 times while
his deposition was being taken. Judge Eduardo Robreno of the U.S.
District Court in Philadelphia imposed $29,000 in sanctions on
Ziccardi, ruling that he should have exerted more control over
his client, whom the judge described as ''''hostile, uncivil and
vulgar'''' during a deposition, Law.com said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ziccardi argued that sanctions were unfair because there was
no specific section of the federal rules of civil procedure that
he was sanctioned under and he was therefore unable to adequately
defend himself. The court rejected the argument, and imposed the
sanctions under Rules 30(d)(2) and 37(a)(5)(A) of the Federal
Rules of Civil Procedure. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The court relied in part on a videotape of the deposition,
which showed the client repeatedly using foul language in
addressing opposing counsel. Ziccardi argued in his own defense
that he made efforts, during off-camera breaks in the deposition,
to calm his client, the news service reported. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sanctions matter was followed closely on legal blogs,
LegalWeek.com said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;On the Docket &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Microsoft Under Antitrust Probe in Taiwan Over Vista &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), the world''s largest software maker, is
being probed by Taiwan''s Fair Trade Commission after an activist
group filed a complaint saying consumers are being forced to buy
its Windows Vista operating system. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The investigation, which is now being conducted, should be
concluded in about six months, Chou Ya-shu, the antitrust
regulator''s spokeswoman, said in a telephone interview yesterday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft can face fines of as much as NT$25 million
($796,000) and be ordered to halt illicit practices if found
guilty of fair-trade breaches, Chou said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sophia Chang, a spokeswoman for Microsoft in Taipei, denied
the company forces people to buy Vista and declined to comment
further on the case. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The complaint was posted on the Web site of Taiwan''s Consumer
Foundation, a non-profit group, on Aug. 15. It said Microsoft
should be fined for using its monopoly to force consumers to
adopt Vista after the company ended sales of Windows XP in June. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft, based in Redmond, Washington, stopped selling XP
individually and pre-installing the operating system in most
computers in June to spur Vista sales. Vista, which was released
for consumers in January last year, requires more memory capacity
and greater processing power than XP. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Consumer Foundation said its research showed 56 percent
of consumers buying a computer with Vista would reinstall XP,
while 67 percent oppose Microsoft ending the sale of the earlier
operating system. Windows XP remains available preinstalled in
some low-cost computers such as Acer Inc. (2353)''s Aspire One laptop. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bloomberg Law Report &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A products liability decision was the subject of a Bloomberg
Law Report yesterday. Connetics Corp., the maker of Velac Gel
acne medication, must defend a suit against it on some of the
claims relating to fraud. The plaintiffs claimed that Connetics
knew that the medication causes cancerous skin tumors in mice but
concealed the finding from investors and analysts in violation of
securities law. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The court ruled that Connetics is protected by the safe
harbor provision of the Private Securities Law Reform Act with
respect to claims of violations of the Securities Exchange Act of
1934 for making forward-looking statements relating to approval
of the gel by the Food and Drug Administration. Those claims were
dismissed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The court found that there were sufficient allegations to
let the case go forward on claims of fraud relating to Velac''s
safety, because the complaint ''''properly alleged that Connetics
`had actual knowledge of undisclosed facts tending to seriously
undermine the accuracy of those statements.'''''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is In re Connetics Corp. Securities Litigation, 07-02940, U.S. District Court, Northern District of California. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Bloomberg articles by lawyers on litigation topics, click
here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For news about bankruptcy litigation, click here. For news about
intellectual property litigation click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry></news>