
<news><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki and Hugh Son" date="Nov 01, 2013 10:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-01/jpmorgan-discloses-eight-doj-probes-from-asia-to-madoff.html"><headline>JPMorgan Discloses Eight DOJ Probes From Asia to Madoff</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) said that the
U.S. Department of Justice is conducting at least eight separate
investigations into the bank''s activities, ranging from
recruitment in Asia to its relationship with Ponzi scheme
operator Bernard Madoff. </p>
<p>The largest U.S. bank disclosed for the first time in a 
filing yesterday that the Justice Department is examining its
energy-trading practices, which were subject to a $410 million
civil settlement with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission
in July. Investigations are also focusing on mortgage-bond
sales, interest-rate rigging, the credit-derivatives market, and
the bank''s trading loss last year, according to the filing. </p>
<p>U.S. Attorney General Eric Holder has said that it''s a
priority for his department and for President Barack Obama to
hold banks accountable. Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon
visited Holder in September to try to negotiate a settlement of
mortgage-related cases against the bank. </p>
<p>The scope and breadth of risky practices at JPMorgan are
mind-boggling, said Mark Williams, a former Federal Reserve
bank examiner who teaches risk management at Boston University.
Some of these probes are criminal, they''re not even just civil
anymore, and I think it''s very telling about the broad risk-taking culture that was allowed under Jamie Dimon. </p>
<h2>Currency Trading </h2>
<p>The eight Justice Department investigations disclosed in
JPMorgan''s filing compare with one in Citigroup Inc.''s.
Citigroup has disclosed two other investigations that weren''t
included in the latest filing because there was no material
change. </p>
<p>Disclosures don''t always specify whether the Justice
Department is involved. For instance, both JPMorgan and
Citigroup said they''re cooperating with inquiries into the
currency market without saying who''s doing the investigating.
The Justice Department is taking a leading role in the global
probe into possible manipulation of the $5.3 trillion-a-day
foreign-exchange market, a department official said earlier this
week. </p>
<p>JPMorgan, whose $2.4 trillion in assets make it the biggest
U.S. bank, last month reported its first quarterly loss under
Dimon, 57, after taking a $7.2 billion after-tax charge to cover
the cost of mounting litigation and regulatory probes. </p>
<p>The bank has tapped $8 billion of $28 billion in reserves
set aside since 2010 to cover legal costs. JPMorgan said
yesterday it may need as much as $5.7 billion more to cover
reasonably possible losses in excess of the reserve, even
after it added $9.2 billion in pretax cash to its litigation
funds in the third quarter. </p>
<h2>Wrong Message'' </h2>
<p>JPMorgan''s purchase of Bear Stearns Cos. and some of
Washington Mutual Inc.''s assets during the financial crisis have
contributed to the bank''s legal costs. American International
Group Inc. CEO Robert Benmosche said the tough line taken
against JPMorgan fails to account for the role that borrowers,
regulators and government played in the crisis and may dissuade
companies from making similar purchases in the future. </p>
<p>No good deed will go unpunished, and I think it''s the
wrong message to send, but the politicians want to punish
someone here, Benmosche, 69, said in an interview with Betty
Liu on Bloomberg Television yesterday. We''ve got to stop the
rhetoric about We''ve got to get the bad guys,'' because I think
most of us were the bad guys. </p>
<h2>Mortgage Settlement </h2>
<p>JPMorgan last week agreed to pay $5.1 billion to settle
claims from the Federal Housing Finance Agency that the bank
misrepresented the quality of mortgage bonds it sold to Fannie
Mae and Freddie Mac. That resolved part of a $13 billion
settlement the company is seeking with state and federal
authorities to close multiple investigations into its mortgage-securities sales practices. The U.S. Attorney''s Office in
Sacramento, California, is leading a criminal probe of the
bank''s mortgage business. </p>
<p>Authorities in the U.S. and overseas are also looking at
the bank''s employment of people referred by clients, potential
clients and government officials as well as hiring of certain
former employees in Hong Kong, its business relationships with
certain related clients in the Asia Pacific region and its
engagement of consultants in the Asia Pacific region,
according to JPMorgan''s filing yesterday. </p>
<p>The U.S. Attorney''s office in Manhattan, run by Preet Bharara, is examining whether JPMorgan violated criminal anti-bribery laws in hiring the children and other relatives of well-connected politicians and clients in hopes of steering business
to the firm, a person with knowledge of the investigation said
in August. JPMorgan said it was cooperating with the
investigations. </p>
<h2>Madoff Role </h2>
<p>South Korea, Singapore and India are among the locations
where hiring practices are being scrutinized, the New York Times
reported yesterday, citing unidentified people briefed on the
matter. Investigators include authorities in the U.K., it said. </p>
<p>Bharara''s office is also is conducting an investigation
into how JPMorgan handled Madoff''s funds and whether it turned a
blind eye to his multibillion-dollar fraud, the biggest Ponzi
scheme in U.S. history. Bharara is weighing a deferred
prosecution agreement or fine for JPMorgan in the Madoff probe,
a person familiar with the matter said last week. </p>
<p>JPMorgan disclosed yesterday that Bharara''s office is
examining whether the bank manipulated the electricity market.
The Federal Bureau of Investigation is looking into JPMorgan''s
settlement with the FERC to see if any individuals committed any
crimes, a person briefed on the matter said in August. </p>
<p>The office is also conducting an investigation into
JPMorgan''s record trading loss last year by Bruno Iksil, who
became known as the London whale because of the size of his
trading bets. </p>
<h2>Libor, CDS </h2>
<p>Former JPMorgan trader Julien Grout and his former boss,
Javier Martin-Artajo, both of whom are in Europe and worked with
Iksil, were indicted on securities fraud charges after being
accused of trying to hide some of the more than $6.2 billion in
losses in their unit last year. Grout and Martin-Artajo have
denied wrongdoing, while Iksil is cooperating in the
investigation. </p>
<p>Additionally, JPMorgan is part of an industrywide
investigation by the Justice Department and others looking at
whether banks in the U.S. and abroad rigged benchmark interest
rates tied to the London interbank offered rate, or Libor. The
bank is cooperating with a probe of the credit-default swaps
market that started in 2009, the company said. </p>
<p>The bank said that it''s also facing a civil investigation
into its compliance with the Federal Housing Administration''s
direct endorsement program, which streamlines origination of
federally insured home loans by banks and other lenders. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lisa Abramowicz" date="Nov 01, 2013 12:39 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-01/jpmorgan-fund-sparks-biggest-high-grade-bond-outflow-since-june.html"><headline>JPMorgan Fund Sparks Biggest High-Grade Bond Outflow Since June</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s Core Bond Fund
reported a $2.3 billion withdrawal this week that spurred the
biggest weekly outflow from U.S. investment-grade debt funds
since June. </p>
<p>The fund''s net assets dropped 9.2 percent to $22.38 billion
on Oct. 28, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. Investment-grade funds reported a $2.67 billion outflow during the past
week, with most of it coming from one fund, Bank of America
Corp. (BAC) credit strategists Hans Mikkelsen and Yuriy Shchuchinov
said in an Oct. 31 report, citing data from EPFR Global. </p>
<p>The withdrawal reported was likely a one-off event and no
signal of a broader rotation out of high-grade bond funds, the
analysts wrote. </p>
<p>Investment-grade bonds in the U.S. gained 1.5 percent in
October as speculation mounted that the Federal Reserve will
maintain its $85 billion of monthly asset purchases through
March. Companies have sold $991.4 billion of the debt so far
this year, on pace for the most ever, from $945.4 billion during
the same period last year, Bloomberg data show. </p>
<p>The JPMorgan Core Bond Fund (WOBDX) was started on Dec. 31, 1983,
and focuses on investment-grade notes with medium-term
maturities, according to the data. It had 25 percent of its
assets in corporate bonds and 55.8 percent in mortgage debt as
of Aug. 31, Bloomberg data show. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
People stand in the lobby of JPMorgan Chase  Co. headquarters in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Carroll" date="Nov 01, 2013 11:53 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-01/chevron-to-sell-oilfields-as-new-exploration-prospects-acquired.html"><headline>Chevron To Sell Oilfields as New Exploration Prospects Acquired</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. plans to sell some oil
and natural-gas assets as newly-acquired exploration prospects
in places such as Iraq, Canada and Australia take precedence.
Some of the new projects may move to the top of the San Ramon,
California-based company''s development queue because they
promise richer returns, Chief Financial Officer Pat Yarrington
said during a conference call with analysts today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Laura Marcinek" date="Nov 01, 2013 11:08 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-01/morgan-stanley-ceo-gorman-says-he-doesn-t-see-market-bubbles-1-.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley CEO Gorman Says He Doesn''t See Market Bubbles</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley Chief Executive
Officer James P. Gorman said he doesn''t see evidence of market
bubbles developing and that investors should celebrate when the
Federal Reserve starts to reduce extra support to the economy. </p>
<p>There''s a lot of robustness, Gorman said today during
an interview on Bloomberg Television with Erik Schatzker. The
indices have obviously rebounded tremendously, but from very low
levels. </p>
<p>Gorman, whose New York-based company runs the world''s
largest brokerage, was responding to remarks by BlackRock Inc. (BLK)
CEO Laurence D. Fink, who said Oct. 29 that the Fed''s effort to
boost the economy by holding down interest rates has fueled
bubble-like markets. The Standard  Poor''s 500 Index (SPX) has
risen 23 percent this year and set a record high the day Fink
spoke. His firm is the world''s biggest money manager. </p>
<p>While the Fed''s program of bond buying has created a
flood of money in the debt markets, it''s been necessary to
get this country back in balance, said Gorman, 55. </p>
<p>The reason they''re keeping it in place is because the
economy is not growing and the economy is not doing what it''s
supposed to do, which is creating jobs, Gorman said. Reducing
the central bank''s $85 billion in monthly bond purchases would
mean employment is back to where it should be, he said. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
Morgan Stanley Chief Executive Officer James Gorman. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki and Dakin Campbell" date="Nov 01, 2013  9:03 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-01/jpmorgan-joins-citigroup-in-responding-to-currency-probes.html"><headline>JPMorgan Joins Citigroup in Responding to Currency Probes</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) and Citigroup
Inc. (C), two of the three largest U.S. banks, said they''re
cooperating with various probes into the firms'' foreign-exchange
trading businesses. </p>
<p>These investigations are in the early stages and the firm
is cooperating with the relevant authorities, New York-based
JPMorgan said today in a quarterly filing with the U.S.
Securities and Exchange Commission. Citigroup, also based in New
York, said in its 10-Q filing that it''s responding to requests
for information on probes by government agencies in the U.S. and
other jurisdictions. </p>
<p>Regulators in London, Zurich, the U.S. and Asia are probing
the foreign-exchange market after Bloomberg News reported in
June that dealers in the industry said they had been front-running client orders, attempting to rig the benchmark
WM/Reuters rates by colluding with counterparts and pushing
through trades before and during the 60-second windows when the
benchmarks are set. </p>
<p>Both JPMorgan and Citigroup put their top London currency
dealers on leave after regulators started investigating the
traders'' use of an instant-message group, three people with
knowledge of the moves said this week. Barclays Plc suspended
three foreign-exchange traders, including a chief dealer in
London, a person with knowledge of the decision said today. </p>




Photographer: Alessia Pierdomenico/Bloomberg

<p>
Regulators in London, Zurich, the U.S. and Asia are probing the foreign-exchange market after Bloomberg News reported in June that dealers in the industry said they had been front-running client orders, attempting to rig the benchmark WM/Reuters rates by colluding with counterparts and pushing through trades before and during the 60-second windows when the benchmarks are set. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Carroll" date="Nov 01, 2013  8:42 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-01/chevron-third-quarter-profit-misses-estimates-on-refining.html"><headline>Chevron Third-Quarter Profit Misses Estimates on Refining</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX), the second-largest
U.S. energy producer by market value, reported third-quarter
profit below estimates as weaker refining margins eroded gains
from higher commodity prices and output from wells. </p>
<p>Net income was $4.95 billion, or $2.57 a share, compared
with $5.25 billion, or $2.69, a year earlier, the San Ramon,
California-based company said in a statement today. The per-share result was 13 cents lower than the $2.70 average of 21
analysts'' estimates compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Chevron warned in an Oct. 9 statement that quarterly profit
had been eroded by significantly lower earnings in its so-called downstream business, which includes refining and filling
stations. Maintenance work at the company''s El Segundo,
California, refinery mostly offset an increase in fuel
production at a separate Chevron plant near San Francisco,
according to the statement. </p>
<p>Chairman and Chief Executive Officer John S. Watson is
spending $36.7 billion this year in a push to raise oil and
natural gas production by 1.5 percent to the equivalent of 2.65
million barrels of oil a day. The capital spending budget
represents a 7.3 percent increase from 2012. </p>
<p>Chevron''s stock has increased 11 percent this year,
outperforming the company''s bigger U.S. rival, Exxon Mobil
Corp. (XOM), which has gained less than 3 percent. Today''s statement
was released before the opening of regular U.S. stock trading.
Chevron fell 0.3 percent to $119.96 in New York yesterday. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki and Hugh Son" date="Nov 01, 2013  8:20 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-01/jpmorgan-says-u-s-foreign-authorities-probing-hiring.html"><headline>JPMorgan Says U.S., Foreign Authorities Probing Hiring</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the biggest
U.S. bank, disclosed that authorities in the U.S. and abroad are
investigating the lender''s hiring practices in Asia. </p>
<p>The bank has received subpoenas from the Securities and
Exchange Commission and document requests from both the SEC and
the U.S. Department of Justice, according to a company filing
today. </p>
<p>Authorities in the U.S. and abroad are looking at the
bank''s employment of people referred by clients, potential
clients and government officials as well as hiring of certain
former employees in Hong Kong, its business relationships with
certain related clients in the Asia Pacific region and its
engagement of consultants in the Asia Pacific region, the bank
said in its filing. </p>
<p>The Justice Department and SEC are examining whether
JPMorgan hired the children and other relatives of well-connected politicians and clients in hopes of steering business
to the firm, possibly violating anti-bribery laws, a person with
knowledge of the investigation said in August. </p>
<p>The firm is cooperating with these investigations, the
New York-based bank said in the filing today. Separate
inquiries on these or similar topics have been made by other
authorities, including authorities in other jurisdictions, and
the firm is responding to those inquiries. </p>




Photographer: Jerome Favre/Bloomberg

<p>
Signage for JPMorgan Chase  Co. is displayed atop Chater House in the central business district of Hong Kong, China, on Thursday, Aug. 29, 2013. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore and Zeke Faux" date="Nov 01, 2013  8:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-01/morgan-stanley-pledges-1-billion-to-boost-sustainability.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Pledges $1 Billion to Boost Sustainability</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) said it will invest $1
billion to help improve affordable housing as part of a broader
push to encourage investment in efforts that aid economic,
social and environmental sustainability. </p>
<p>The bank is also seeking to attract $10 billion of client
assets to fund investments designed to provide social benefits
in addition to financial returns, New York-based Morgan Stanley
said today in an e-mailed statement. Audrey Choi, who leads the
bank''s sustainable finance group, will serve as chief executive
officer of the newly established Morgan Stanley Institute for
Sustainable Investing. </p>
<p>The biggest U.S. banks have sought to combine their
abilities of advising companies and allocating capital with
socially minded pursuits in the wake of public outrage and
government rescues resulting from the financial crisis. Goldman
Sachs Group Inc. announced earlier this year that it was
investing in so-called social-impact bonds that funded early
education in the U.S. </p>
<p>The most effective solutions to sustainability challenges
are those that can be brought to scale, Morgan Stanley CEO
James Gorman, 55, said in the statement. Our clients are
increasingly turning their attention to what it takes to secure
the lasting and safe supplies of food, energy, water and shelter
necessary for sustainable prosperity. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
James Gorman, chief executive officer of of Morgan Stanley, said in a statement that "The most effective solutions to sustainability challenges are those that can be brought to scale." Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki and Hugh Son" date="Nov 01, 2013  7:42 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-01/jpmorgan-chase-traders-extend-perfect-record-into-third-quarter.html"><headline>JPMorgan Chase Traders Extend Perfect Record Into Third Quarter</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) traders
generated profits every day in the third quarter, extending
their perfect record for 2013 as the Federal Reserve backed off
plans to curtail a bond-purchase program. </p>
<p>Traders made more than $200 million on three days this
year, JPMorgan said today in a regulatory filing. The New York-based company is the biggest U.S. lender by assets. </p>
<p>Wall Street has been whipsawed as the Federal Reserve
debates whether the economy is strong enough to justify reducing
monthly bond purchases of about $85 billion that have kept
borrowing costs low. Ten-year Treasury yields, which are used to
set rates for some consumer and corporate loans, rose from this
year''s low of 1.63 percent on May 2 to 3 percent on Sept. 5. </p>
<p>Trading revenue at JPMorgan''s corporate and investment
bank, run by Daniel Pinto and Michael Cavanagh, fell 2 percent
to $4.69 billion in the third quarter, the bank said when it
reported earnings on Oct. 11. Fixed-income trading revenue
declined 8 percent to $3.44 billion from a year earlier while
equity-trading revenue rose 20 percent to $1.25 billion. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki and Hugh Son" date="Nov 01, 2013  7:31 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-01/jpmorgan-says-it-s-cooperating-with-currency-trading-probes.html"><headline>JPMorgan Says It''s Cooperating With Currency-Trading Probes</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the largest
U.S. bank, said it''s cooperating with various government
authorities investigating the firm''s foreign-exchange trading
business. </p>
<p>These investigations are in the early stages and the firm
is cooperating with the relevant authorities, the New York-based company said today in a quarterly filing with the U.S.
Securities and Exchange Commission. </p>
<p>JPMorgan and Citigroup Inc. (C) put their top London currency
dealers on leave after regulators probing the manipulation of
foreign-exchange rates started investigating the traders'' use of
an instant-message group, three people with knowledge of the
moves said this week. </p>
<p>Regulators are focusing on an instant-message group the
traders set up to share information about their positions and
client orders over a period of at least three years, four people
with knowledge of the probe said last month. The roster of banks
in the group changed as the men moved firms and also included
Barclays Plc, Royal Bank of Scotland Group Plc and UBS AG, three
people with knowledge of the communications said. </p>
<p>Investigators are weighing whether the messages amounted to
attempts to manipulate the market, two people said. The five
firms account for about 47 percent of the $5.3 trillion-a-day
foreign-exchange market, according to a May survey by Euromoney
Institutional Investor Plc. Two other traders, who weren''t part
of the conversations and who asked to not be identified because
they do business with those involved, said that they and others
in the market referred to the message group as The Cartel. </p>




Photographer: Victor J. Blue/Bloomberg

<p>
JPMorgan disclosed in August that the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission had sought information on hiring practices in Asia. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hugh Son and Michael J. Moore" date="Nov 04, 2013  7:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-04/goldman-sachs-to-bofa-said-to-trade-with-sac-after-guilty-plea.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs to BofA Are Said to Trade With SAC After Plea Deal</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc., JPMorgan
Chase  Co. (JPM) and Bank of America Corp. (BAC) are among Wall Street
firms still catering to SAC Capital Advisors LP after the hedge
fund agreed to plead guilty to insider trading charges. </p>
<p>The banks, which also include Morgan Stanley, continue to
provide trading and prime-brokerage services to SAC, said people
briefed on the matter, who requested anonymity when discussing
specific clients. The hedge-fund firm, run by billionaire Steven A. Cohen, agreed yesterday to pay $1.8 billion -- a record
penalty for insider trading -- to settle allegations it
illicitly reaped hundreds of millions of dollars since 1999. </p>
<p>The presumption is that if JPMorgan should resign the
business, then someone else would do it, said Roy Smith, a
finance professor at New York University''s Stern School of
Business and a former Goldman Sachs partner. These people all
say we serve our clients, so if our clients get into trouble, we
serve them as long as we can. </p>
<p>Banks are weighing the potential damage to their
reputations and finances if they continue dealing with Stamford,
Connecticut-based SAC, one of Wall Street''s largest trading
clients. While SAC agreed to stop managing money for outsiders,
it may continue investing Cohen''s personal fortune of about $9
billion. </p>




Photographer: Chris Ware/Bloomberg

<p>
The offices of SAC Capital Advisors LP stand in Stamford, Connecticut. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bei Hu" date="Nov 05, 2013  7:14 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-05/goldman-sachs-asia-fund-chairman-bolitho-to-leave-company.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Asia Fund Chairman Bolitho to Leave Company</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Oliver Bolitho, chairman of Goldman
Sachs Group Inc.''s fund management division in Asia, is leaving
after 15 years at the company, according to an internal memo. </p>
<p>Bolitho will become an advisory director after his
retirement at the end of the year, according to the Nov. 4 memo
obtained by Bloomberg. Christopher Jun, a spokesman for Goldman
Sachs in Seoul, confirmed the contents of the memo. </p>
<p>Bolitho, a U.K. citizen, served as head of Goldman Sachs''s
U.K. and Irish institutional business from 2001 until moving to
Hong Kong in 2007 to run the fund business in Asia outside of
Japan. A partner since 2008, Bolitho became chairman of Goldman
Sachs Asset Management last year. </p>
<p>His departure comes almost a year after Goldman Sachs Asset
Management moved Sheila Patel to Singapore from London to lead
the fund business in Asia outside of Japan and said that Bolitho
would report to Patel. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs had $878 billion of assets under management
as of Sept. 30, according to the New York-based company''s third-quarter earnings report. The company doesn''t report how much of
that is in Asia. </p>
<p>AsianInvestor, a Hong Kong-based trade journal, reported
Bolitho''s pending departure on its website earlier today. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs Asset Management runs hedge funds, private
equity and real estate investments alongside those in fixed
income, stocks, money markets and commodities, according to its
website. The unit employs more than 700 investment specialists
in 32 offices worldwide. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs agreed to buy Benchmark Asset Management Co.,
India''s largest provider of index-tracking funds, in March 2011,
after setting up its own mutual-fund unit in the country in
2008. </p>
<p>It also teamed up with RHB Capital Bhd. (RHBC), Malaysia''s fifth-largest banking group, in 2010 to jointly develop fund
management products. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Nov 05, 2013 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-05/morgan-stanley-says-aig-may-sue-over-mortgage-investments-1-.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Says AIG May Sue Over Mortgage-Linked Investments</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS), the sixth-largest
U.S. bank by assets, said it may be sued by American
International Group Inc. (AIG) over mortgage-backed securities that
the insurer purchased before the financial crisis. </p>
<p>AIG bought $3.7 billion in mortgage pass-through
certificates that were sponsored or underwritten by Morgan
Stanley in 2005 through 2007, the New York-based investment bank
said yesterday in a regulatory filing. AIG terminated an
agreement that had given it more time to bring claims, and the
pact will end Nov. 7, according to the filing. </p>
<p>AIG, which repaid a government bailout last year, sued Bank
of America Corp. (BAC) in August 2011 over $10 billion in losses on
mortgage-bond investments, saying it was the victim of a
massive fraud. Morgan Stanley has set aside $549 million for
litigation in the first nine months this year, up from $381
million in the same period last year. </p>
<p>The company expects future litigation accruals in general
to continue to be elevated, Morgan Stanley said in the filing.
Changes in accruals from period to period may fluctuate
significantly given the current environment regarding financial
crisis-related government investigations and private litigation
affecting global financial services firms, including the
company. </p>
<p>AIG was bailed out by taxpayers in 2008 after the New York-based insurer was overwhelmed by losses on property bets. Matt Gallagher, a spokesman for AIG, declined to comment. Charlotte,
North Carolina-based Bank of America has disputed the insurer''s
claims. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley helped advise the U.S. government on its
rescue of AIG and was one of top underwriters as the U.S.
divested its majority stake through public offerings. It also
helped AIG dispose of a stake in reinsurer Transatlantic
Holdings Inc. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Nov 06, 2013  1:16 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-06/goldman-sachs-surpasses-liquidity-minimum-under-fed-plan.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Surpasses Liquidity Minimum Under Fed Plan</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)''s liquidity
coverage ratio, a measure of its ability to survive a credit-market freeze, surpasses the minimum proposed by the Federal
Reserve last month, said Treasurer Liz Beshel Robinson. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs would top the minimum even under the Fed''s
proposed stricter guidelines and therefore wouldn''t be affected
by a shorter timeline than international banks may face,
Robinson said today on a conference-call with fixed-income
investors. </p>
<p>The Fed last month proposed rules to require the biggest
banks to hold 30 days of easy-to-sell assets to make the
companies safer in the event of a credit crisis like the one in
2008. The plan had a shorter timeline than non-U.S. banks will
face and was more restrictive in what U.S. banks can include
among their assets. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Duane D. Stanford and Leslie Patton" date="Nov 07, 2013  4:55 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-07/general-mills-to-mcdonald-s-got-jump-on-fda-with-trans-fats-cuts.html"><headline>General Mills to McDonald''s Got Jump on FDA Trans Fats Cuts</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The U.S. government''s decision to
deem artificial trans fats unsafe for human consumption may have
little impact on foodmakers and restaurant chains because
they''ve been phasing them out for years. </p>
<p>Under pressure from activists such as the American Heart
Association and city and state governments, companies from
General Mills Inc. (GIS) to McDonald''s Corp. have been ridding their
products of partially hydrogenated oils, which contain trans
fats linked to a type of artery-clogging cholesterol. </p>
<p>Foodmakers have lowered trans fats in their products by 73
percent since 2005, according to Washington-based Grocery
Manufacturers Association. More than 90 percent of General Mills
U.S. retail products are labeled as having zero grams of trans
fat, Kirstie Foster, a spokeswoman, said today in an e-mail. </p>
<p>I can''t tell you the last time I bought crackers or
cookies, you name it, that I even saw any trans fat, Brian Yarbrough, an analyst for Edward Jones  Co. in St. Louis, said
today in an interview. It''s a positive from the standpoint of
consumers, as trans fats are obviously bad for your health, but
for investors and the companies I don''t know it changes much. </p>
<p>Trans fats are no longer generally recognized as safe,
according to a tentative determination published today by the
U.S. Food and Drug Administration. The decision, while not yet
final, would lead to regulations that prevent food companies
from using the ingredient. </p>
<p>ConAgra Foods Inc. has removed trans fat from products such
as Orville Redenbacher''s popcorn, Teresa Paulsen, a spokeswoman,
said in an e-mail. </p>
<p>We took steps to remove partially hydrogenated oils from
many foods in our portfolio years ago, she said. We look
forward to learning more about the FDA proposal. </p>
<h2>Hydrogenated Oils </h2>
<p>It won''t have much impact on quick-service restaurants,
most of which use limited amounts of trans fats and hydrogenated
oils, Bob Goldin, executive vice president at Chicago-based
restaurant researcher Technomic Inc., said in an interview. I
don''t think it''s a big issue. </p>
<p>The FDA''s ruling may force companies to clean up the rest
of their portfolios faster than they may have planned. Burger
King Worldwide Inc. (BKW)''s breaded chicken patties and molten fudge
bites have partially hydrogenated oils, according to the
company''s website. </p>
<h2>Cinnabon Delights </h2>
<p>Yum! Brands Inc. (YUM)''s KFC sells BBQ baked beans, mashed
potatoes, gravy and some dipping sauces, such as fiery buffalo
wings, with partially hydrogenated vegetable oils. Partially
hydrogenated soybean and cottonseed oils also can be found in
caramel apple empanadas, Cinnabon delights and green tomatillo
sauce at Yum''s Taco Bell. </p>
<p>The FDA began requiring food companies to include trans
fats on their labels in 2006 after more than a decade of
pressure from the Center for Science in the Public Interest, a
Washington, D.C.-based health advocacy group. Consumers began
turning away from foods with the fats soon after, the agency
said. </p>
<p>New York City in 2006 began a ban on trans fats in
restaurants, and California followed suit in 2008. </p>
<p>General Mills declined 1.5 percent to $50.40 at the close
in New York. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Nov 07, 2013  4:02 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-07/jpmorgan-executive-dunleavy-named-in-ferc-complaint-retires.html"><headline>JPMorgan Executive Dunleavy Named in FERC Complaint Retires</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Francis Dunleavy, the JPMorgan Chase
 Co. (JPM) energy executive who ran the Houston unit that developed
trading strategies deemed illegal by the U.S. Federal Energy
Regulatory Commission, has retired. </p>
<p>The move, ending a career spanning more than three decades,
took effect last month, Brian Marchiony, a spokesman for the New
York-based bank, said today. </p>
<p>Dunleavy, as head of JPMorgan''s principal investments unit,
oversaw bidding strategies that the FERC said manipulated power
markets. JPMorgan agreed in July to pay $410 million and forgo
collecting on $262 million in disputed payments from
California''s grid operator to settle the charges. </p>
<p>Dunleavy was a Bear Stearns Cos. veteran, joining that firm
in 1982 and becoming one of its senior energy executives,
according to Financial Industry Regulatory Authority records.
JPMorgan, the biggest U.S. bank by assets, acquired Bear Stearns
in 2008. Andrew Kittell and John Bartholomew, who both reported
to Dunleavy, still work for the bank, Marchiony said. </p>
<p>While the FERC didn''t sanction individuals in the case, the
Federal Bureau of Investigation opened a separate probe to see
if anyone committed crimes, a person briefed on the matter said
in August. </p>
<p>Dunleavy resigned from JPMorgan warehouse operator Henry
Bath  Son Ltd., effective Oct. 25, according to a filing
earlier this week. </p>
<p>William Scherman, an attorney for Dunleavy at Gibson Dunn 
Crutcher LLP in Washington, said his client wasn''t available to
comment. Reuters reported on Dunleavy''s departure from JPMorgan
earlier today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Leslie Picker and Lee Spears" date="Nov 07, 2013  2:41 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-07/goldman-led-twitter-underwriters-to-make-59-2-million-from-ipo.html"><headline>Goldman-Led Twitter Underwriters Share $59.2 Million in IPO Fees</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and other underwriters on Twitter Inc. (TWTR)''s initial public offering will share about $59.2 million for managing the sale after accepting one of the smallest fee rates for a U.S. IPO this year. </p> <p>The banks are receiving 3.25 percent of the $1.82 billion that Twitter raised in its IPO, according to a regulatory filing today. Goldman Sachs led the sale, with help from firms including Morgan Stanley and JPMorgan Chase  Co. The fee pool is typically split unevenly among underwriters, with larger shares going to banks more actively involved in the process. </p> <p>Twitter''s banker fees reflect a smaller proportion than underwriters have received in nearly every U.S. initial offering this year, data compiled by Bloomberg show. While investment banks use fee income as a major measure of success in deal underwriting, firms are sometimes willing to take a smaller share of proceeds for high-profile sales that may generate future business. </p> <p>Goldman being the first name on the S-1 has little to do with fees, Max Wolff, chief economist and strategist at ZT Wealth, said by phone from New York. This is about Goldman rebalancing itself as a serious leader and competing with Morgan Stanley''s dominant position in technology. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
Goldman Sachs is leading Twitter''s IPO, with help from firms including Morgan Stanley and JPMorgan Chase  Co., regulatory filings show. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri and Nick Turner" date="Nov 07, 2013  1:57 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-07/disney-to-create-four-series-for-netflix-using-marvel-characters.html"><headline>Disney to Create Four Series With Marvel Heroes for Netflix</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS) agreed to create four
television series for Netflix Inc. (NFLX) using Marvel characters such
as Daredevil, adding to the online-streaming service''s growing
lineup of original content. </p>
<p>Disney''s Marvel TV will start bringing the shows to Netflix
in 2015, according to a statement today. They will focus on
heroes battling villains in New York''s Hell''s Kitchen. Netflix
committed to a minimum of four 13-episode series, culminating in
the miniseries The Defenders. </p>
<p>The multiyear deal extends Marvel''s push into live-action
TV, following the September debut of Marvel''s Agents of
S.H.I.E.L.D. on Disney''s ABC network. Netflix gains more
Disney content following an agreement last year for rights to
show movies including Marvel, Pixar and Lucasfilm titles. </p>
<p>What''s exciting for a company like Disney and us is the
willingness to try something new, Netflix Chief Content
Officer Ted Sarandos said Nov. 4 at the Business of
Entertainment event in Los Angeles, sponsored by Bloomberg and
the Tribeca Film Festival. </p>
<p>Disney is mining deeper in Marvel''s library following box-office success since purchasing the comic-book company in 2009.
Marvel''s The Avengers and Iron Man 3 were the top-grossing films of 2012 and 2013 respectively. Guardians of the
Galaxy, about a team of superheroes in space, is planned for
next year, and an Ant-Man movie is scheduled for 2015. </p>




<p>
Ben Affleck in "Daredevil." Photograph: 20th Century Fox Film Corp./Everett Collection Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jim Polson" date="Nov 07, 2013  1:30 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-07/exxon-bp-among-explorers-urged-to-disclose-more-fracking-data.html"><headline>Exxon, BP Among Explorers Urged to Disclose More Fracking Data</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>North American shale explorers led by
Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) and BP Plc (BP/) are failing to disclose enough data
on how they''re reducing risks associated with hydraulic
fracturing, according to a study. </p>
<p>Hydraulic fracturing operations are under intense
scrutiny for potential harm to neighboring communities and the
environment -- from air and water pollution to increased noise,
traffic and crime, Danielle Fugere, president of As You Sow
Foundation, a non-profit focused on environmental and corporate
responsibility, said in a statement today. </p>
<p>No company disclosed information on even half of the 32
indicators that investors need to assess business risk, the
report showed. Exxon, based in Irving, Texas, and London-based
BP placed near the bottom of 24 companies evaluated. Encana
Corp. (ECA), the best performer, provided information on only 14 of
the 32 indicators. Only one company, Chevron Corp. (CVX), quantified
its reductions in the use of toxic chemicals and it failed in 29
other categories. </p>
<p>Hydraulic fracturing, or fracking, cracks rock with a
mixture of millions of gallons of water, sand and chemicals so
oil and natural gas will flow. Coupled with horizontal drilling
that exposes thousands of feet of petroleum-bearing rock to well
bores, it has revived growth in U.S. oil and gas production.
Checklist items in today''s report range from the absence of
diesel fuels in fracturing fluids to traffic congestion policy
and disclosure of fines. </p>
<p>The report was released by Boston Common Asset Management
LLC, Green Century (GCEQX) Capital Management Inc., Investor
Environmental Health Network and As You Sow. </p>
<h2>Reduce Disruptions </h2>
<p>Companies that disclose steps to reduce disruptions by
fracking will reduce regulatory and reputational risks;
enhance their likelihood of securing and maintaining their
social license to operate; reduce liabilities associated with
poor performance, spills, contamination, and lawsuits; and
thereby increase their access to capital, the authors wrote. </p>
<p>One of the co-authors was Richard Liroff of Investor
Environmental Health Network, whose 2011 report on fracking was
the basis for the checklist. </p>
<p>Investors thrive on quantitative information, Liroff
said today in a phone interview. It gives us a sense of the
extent to which various practices are being adopted that can,
one, reduce environmental risk and community impact and, two,
save the companies money. </p>
<p>The report defined disclosure as public information on
company websites and financial statements. </p>
<p>As You Sow is based in Oakland, California, Boston Common (BCAMX)
Asset Management and Green Century are based in Boston and the
Investor Environmental Health Network is based in Falls Church,
Virginia. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Nov 07, 2013  1:24 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-07/goldman-names-sherwood-to-lead-emerging-markets-as-evans-retires.html"><headline>Goldman Names Sherwood to Lead Emerging Markets as Evans Retires</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Michael Sherwood, co-head of Goldman
Sachs Group Inc. (GS)''s European business, will oversee operations in
emerging markets as he takes over for J. Michael Evans, who''s
retiring. </p>
<p>Sherwood, a London-based vice chairman, will coordinate the
company''s units in so-called growth markets, Chief Executive
Officer Lloyd C. Blankfein and President Gary D. Cohn said today
in a memo to employees. Michael DuVally, a spokesman for the New
York-based bank, confirmed the memo''s contents. </p>
<p>Sherwood, 48, will help drive our strategy, identify new
commercial opportunities and allocate resources in countries
experiencing stronger economic growth and rapid business and
capital markets development, Blankfein and Cohn wrote in the
memo. Michael will also oversee the performance of our
businesses, including their footprint and pace of growth. </p>
<p>Sherwood, a Briton, joined Goldman Sachs in 1986 and became
a partner in 1994, according to the memo. He was promoted to
vice chairman in February 2008, at the same time as Evans, and
kept his role as co-CEO of Goldman Sachs International. </p>
<p>Sherwood rose through the ranks of the fixed-income
department like Blankfein, 59, and Cohn, 53. He was co-head of
the trading business from 2003 to 2008. He''s currently chairman
of the partnership committee. </p>




Photographer: Jason Alden/Bloomberg

<p>
Employees walks across the interconnecting walkway linking the two Goldman Sachs offices at 120 -133 Fleet Street in London. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Nov 07, 2013 11:41 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-07/goldman-sachs-traders-had-15-losing-days-in-3rd-quarter.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Traders Had 15 Losing Days in 3rd Quarter</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), which had
the steepest drop in trading revenue among Wall Street''s largest
banks, posted losses from that business on 15 days during the
third quarter, the most since 2011. </p>
<p>Traders made more than $100 million on four days in the
three months ended Sept. 30, down from seven days in the year-earlier period, the New York-based company said in a regulatory
filing today. None of the losses were more than $50 million and
none topped the bank''s so-called value-at-risk, an estimate of
potential trading losses. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs generated $2.86 billion from its trading
division in the third quarter, a 32 percent decrease from the
year-earlier period. Client activity fell and the firm struggled
to manage inventory amid speculation about whether the Federal
Reserve would ease its economic stimulus. </p>
<p>Concerns about the global economic outlook created a more
difficult operating environment for our clients in the third
quarter, Chief Financial Officer Harvey Schwartz said on a
conference call last month. These challenges were amplified by
the seasonal slowdown traditionally impacting client activity in
July and August. </p>
<p>The firm''s inventory fell to $244.3 billion, a 25 percent
drop from a year earlier and a 12 percent decline from the end
of the second quarter. The was the biggest decline and the
lowest absolute amount since the bank started disclosing the
figure at the end of 2010. </p>
<p>The number of days with losses was the highest since the
firm had 17 such days in the fourth quarter of 2011. The four
days of gains of more than $100 million were the fewest since
the second quarter of 2012. Goldman Sachs hasn''t had fewer than
four such days in a quarter since 2005. </p>
<p>Bank of America Corp. posted daily losses twice during the
quarter, including a $21 million misstep. Morgan Stanley posted
losses on seven days, including two that topped $25 million. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bloomberg News" date="Nov 07, 2013 11:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-07/coca-cola-to-invest-more-than-4-billion-in-china-from-2015-2017.html"><headline>Coca-Cola to Invest More Than $4 Billion in China From 2015-2017</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Coca-Cola Co. (KO), the world''s largest
beverage company, plans to invest more than $4 billion in China
from 2015 to 2017 as it builds factories and adds new products
to meet demand and counter rising competition. </p>
<p>The Atlanta-based company is also open to acquisitions in
China and may consider deals with complementary businesses, such
as makers of juices or plant-protein drinks like almond milk,
David Brooks, president of Coca-Cola''s Greater China and Korea
business unit, said in an Nov. 6 interview in Shanghai. </p>
<p>You will see an absolute increase in investment on an
annual basis and on a three-year basis, Brooks said,
commenting on the company''s future plan for China. Coca-Cola is
investing $4 billion in the country for 2012-2014. </p>
<p>The U.S. soda maker is ramping up its China investment as
the company and its bottlers seek to double global revenues to
$200 billion in the 10 years to 2020. While it is the country''s
largest soft-drink maker, it faces competition from companies
including PepsiCo Inc. (PEP) and the local Hangzhou Wahaha Group as it
seeks to expand in the most populous nation. </p>
<p>PepsiCo, the world''s second-largest soft-drink maker, is
stepping up its push into China. The company has also opened new
factories and sought to expand distribution through a tie-up
with Tingyi Cayman Islands Holding Corp. (322) </p>
<p>Competition in China''s beverage industry is intense and the
sector is one with low growth and weak profitability,
analyst Jean Chan from Sanford C. Bernstein  Co. wrote in a
Sept. 25 report. Sales are typically driven by promotions, she
said. </p>
<h2>China Sales </h2>
<p>Coca-Cola said in July that its second-quarter sales volume
in China was little changed after rising 7 percent a year ago.
Sales in the third quarter have shown improvements, and this will
continue over the next several quarters, Brooks
said. </p>
<p>The Asian nation has pared economic growth projections to
an average of 7 percent this decade, compared with 10.5 percent
in the previous 10 years. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola plans to open as many as two facilities each year
in China over the next decade, Brooks said. In the nearer term,
it will invest about $40 million in a new pulp blending factory
in Shanghai, and likely open a plant in the southwestern Guizhou
province in the next two years, Brooks said. </p>
<p>The beverage market in China is still very fragmented,
the executive said. No company has predominant market share,
and there is a huge amount of untapped opportunity left to
grow. </p>
<h2>Chinese Flavors </h2>
<p>The company also plans to expand its offerings of Chinese-style beverages, with traditional Chinese items such as wolf
berries and herbal ingredients all being considered in future
drinks, Brooks said, declining to elaborate further. It will
also roll out more low-calorie and no-calorie drinks as it
caters to an aging population, he said. </p>
<p>People like new flavors, Chan, the analyst, said.
Going forward, product innovations will help you expand your
categories and also drive growth. </p>
<p>Chinese consumers are buying more juices and ready-to-drink
teas and fewer carbonated drinks as they seek a healthier
lifestyle, Chan said. </p>
<p>China regulators blocked the Coca-Cola''s planned $2.3
billion buyout of China Huiyuan Juice Group Ltd. in 2009. </p>
<p>Emerging markets are increasingly important to the U.S.
company, which got about 79 percent of its operating income
outside North America last year, data compiled by Bloomberg
show. In the U.S., beverage makers have come under scrutiny in
recent years as public officials in several states have looked
to curb high obesity rates by slowing consumption of sugary soft
drinks with proposed restrictions and excise taxes. </p>
<h2>Local Cooking </h2>
<p>Coca-Cola, which broke ground on the first of its 43
factories on the mainland in 1980, already sells snow-pear fruit
drinks and sour-plum sparkling beverages there. On its website,
there are suggested recipes including sweet and spicy hoisin
spare ribs with Coca-Cola, encouraging consumers to incorporate
the carbonated beverage into local cooking. </p>
<p>The maker of drinks ranging from green teas and milk-based
Minute Maid Milky Pulpy had a 15.7 percent share in China''s 67.5
billion litre soft-drink market in 2012, according to industry
researcher Euromonitor International. </p>
<p>Taiwan''s Ting Hsin International Group, which partly owns
Tingyi, ranked second with 12.8 percent, while PepsiCo had 4.5
percent. Wahaha Group, controlled by the nation''s second richest
man, Zong Qinghou, had a 7.3 percent share. </p>
<p>Low per-capita consumption and rising incomes will boost
beverage demand in China, helping the Asian nation become Coca-Cola''s largest market by sales volume by 2020, from third-largest today, Brooks said. </p>
<h2>China Plenum </h2>
<p>China''s third plenum, a meeting of Communist Party leaders
to discuss economic-policy reforms, begins this week in Beijing.
The outcome of the conclave will be closely watched by foreign
investors as it would give an indication of the country''s
roadmap for the next 10 years, said Brooks, who has lived and
worked in Greater China since 1975. </p>
<p>The overall trend of opening and continuing to become
more transparent is very clear, he said. Market forces
playing a stronger role in the economy going forward is good for
all players whether you are a foreign company or state-owned
enterprise. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Gavin Finch and Michael J. Moore" date="Nov 07, 2013  9:29 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-07/goldman-sachs-is-under-investigation-in-currency-probe.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Under Investigation in Currency Probe</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), the world''s
most profitable securities firm before the financial crisis,
said it''s under investigation by regulators probing the
potential manipulation of foreign-exchange rates. </p>
<p>Currencies and commodities were added to a list of
financial products and related activities that are subject to
investigation, according to a regulatory filing published by the
New York-based company today. The filing also added options
trading and technology systems and controls to the list. </p>
<p>Investigators are looking at the firm''s trading
activities and communications in connection with the
establishment of benchmark rates, Goldman Sachs said in the
filing. The company is cooperating with all such regulatory
investigations and reviews. </p>
<p>At least eight banks including Citigroup Inc. (C) and JPMorgan
Chase  Co. (JPM) have said they''re being investigated by authorities
examining the $5.3 trillion-a-day foreign-exchange market and
are cooperating. Citigroup, JPMorgan and Barclays Plc (BARC) have
suspended or put on leave some of their most senior currency
traders amid the inquiry. No one has been accused of wrongdoing. </p>
<p>The U.S. Federal Reserve is examining legal and regulatory
exemptions that have allowed banks including Goldman Sachs to
trade and own raw materials such as oil, coal and metals, a
person with knowledge of the matter said last month. </p>




Photographer: Victor J. Blue/Bloomberg

<p>
Goldman Sachs Group Inc.''s headquarters stands in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Gavin Finch" date="Nov 07, 2013  6:27 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-07/goldman-sachs-being-investigated-in-currency-probe-filing-shows.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Being Investigated in Currency Probe, Filing Shows</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. disclosed in
a quarterly filing that it''s cooperating with an investigation
into currency trading. </p>
<p>The firm''s filing today added currencies and commodities to
a list of financial products and related activities that are
subject to investigation. </p>
<p>Regulators around the world have been looking into whether
banks have rigged currency rates. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Neal Armstrong" date="Nov 07, 2013  4:06 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-07/jpmorgan-leads-u-s-banks-boosting-share-of-european-bond-market.html"><headline>JPMorgan Leads U.S. Banks Boosting Share of European Bond Market</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>U.S. banks increased their share of
Europe''s fixed-income market at the expense of local competitors
as trading volumes slid in 2013, Greenwich Associates said in an
annual survey report. </p>
<p>Barclays Plc (BARC) retained its position as the biggest
secondary-market trader of European fixed-income products, with
a 12.8 percent market share, down from 13.3 percent in 2012,
Stamford, Connecticut-based Greenwich said on its website today.
Second-placed Deutsche Bank AG (DBK)''s portion shrank to 10.5 percent
from 11.9 percent, while JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) increased its
share to 9.3 percent from 8.5 percent and Citigroup Inc. (C) had 7.7
percent, up from about 6 percent. </p>
<p>Investors reported reduced liquidity in bond markets in the
second half of 2013, according to Greenwich, as speculation that
the Federal Reserve would reduce the pace of its $85 billion of
monthly asset purchases damped demand. UBS AG (UBSN) exited most fixed-income markets, while other European banks scaled back to comply
with Basel III regulatory requirements, it said. </p>
<p>It has become more difficult for many institutions to
execute trades, and our data suggest that they are reaching out
to new dealers in an attempt to source needed liquidity, Peter D''Amario, a Greenwich Associate consultant, said in the report. </p>
<p>European banks are increasing the number of trading
counterparties to gain access to liquidity, according to
Greenwich. They averaged nine counterparties in this year''s
survey versus 8.4 in 2012. This increase benefited U.S banks and
European institutions including UniCredit SpA (UCG), Commerzbank AG,
Banca IMI SpA and Rabobank Groep, the Greenwich report said. </p>
<p>Barclays, Britain''s second-biggest lender by assets, was
Greenwich''s 2013 Quality Leader in European fixed-income
trading, sales and overall service in rates products. JPMorgan
was the 2013 Quality Leader in European fixed-income
research and overall European service in credit products. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sonia Sirletti and Francesca Cinelli" date="Nov 07, 2013  1:33 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-07/generali-third-quarter-profit-rises-as-operating-income-climbs.html"><headline>Generali Third-Quarter Profit Rises as Operating Income Climbs</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Assicurazioni Generali SpA (G), Italy''s
biggest insurer, said third-quarter profit rose 75 percent as it
earned more from its life segment and property and casualty
operations. </p>
<p>Net income rose to 510 million euros ($690 million) from
291 million euros a year earlier, Trieste, Italy-based Generali
said in a statement today. Earnings beat the 411 million-euro
average estimate of seven analysts surveyed by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>We are making good progress with the transformation of
our group and today''s results demonstrate that we are on track
to reach our targets, Chief Executive Officer Mario Greco said
in a statement. Now we will work with even greater focus on
improving our profitability, he said, reiterating that
Generali expects higher operating results this year. </p>
<p>Greco, who took over as CEO last year, is selling non-strategic assets and focusing on the company''s main business to
strengthen finances and boost profitability. The insurer is more
than half way to reaching its goal of raising 4 billion euros
from disposals by 2015, after selling its U.S. reinsurance unit
and Mexican businesses earlier this year. </p>
<p>We are positive on the company''s new more-focused
strategy and believe that the value this creates more than
offsets the downside risk of raising equity capital, Andreas
van Embden, an analyst at JPMorgan Chase  Co., wrote in a note
last week. </p>
<p>Non-life operating profit increased 12 percent to 430
million euros as the insurer reduced costs. Claims and costs as
a proportion of premiums, known as the combined ratio, improved
to 95.1 percent in the first nine months of the year from 96.6
percent a year earlier. </p>
<p>Operating income rose 8.5 percent in the third quarter from
a year earlier to 984 million euros as income at the life
business rose 13 percent to 591 million euros. </p>
<p>Generali''s solvency ratio, a measure of its capacity to
absorb losses, rose to 143 percent by Sept. 30 from 139 percent
in June, the insurer said. As of the end of October, the ratio
was 152 percent, the company said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri and Jonathan Erlichman" date="Nov 08, 2013  5:49 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-08/disney-falls-after-cable-division-registers-profit-drop.html"><headline>Disney Profit Beats Expectations on Gains From Parks</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS), the world''s largest entertainment company, said fiscal fourth-quarter profit rose 12 percent, beating analysts'' estimates as the company''s theme parks and consumer products boosted income. </p> <p>Net income grew to $1.39 billion, or 77 cents a share, from $1.24 billion, or 68 cents, a year earlier, Disney said yesterday in a statement, topping the 76-cent average of 27 analysts'' estimates compiled by Bloomberg. Revenue increased 7.3 percent to $11.6 billion in the period ended Sept. 28, beating the $11.4 billion average of estimates. </p> <p>Investments in new attractions spurred higher guest spending and occupancy at Disney''s U.S. resorts, letting the company increase ticket prices. Disney, based in Burbank, California, is working on Star Wars rides in Orlando, Florida, and California, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer Robert Iger told Bloomberg Television. </p> <p>There is a fair amount of development going on at Disney Imagineering right now to expand the Star Wars'' presence in California and in Orlando, and eventually in other parks around the world, Iger said. </p> <p>Profit at Disney''s parks and resorts division increased 15 percent to $571 million in the quarter, as revenue grew 8.5 percent, the company said. </p>




Photographer: Patrick Fallon/Bloomberg

<p>
Guests walk towards the Magic Castle at Walt Disney Co.''s Disneyland Park in Anaheim, California. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Erik Larson" date="Nov 08, 2013 10:41 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-08/jpmorgan-banker-backed-200-million-madoff-loan-in-november-2008.html"><headline>JPMorgan Banker Backed $200 Million Madoff Loan in 2008</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A former JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) banker
who managed Bernard Madoff''s account said the con man was on
track to receive a $200 million loan less than a month before
his arrest if the request hadn''t been dropped. </p>
<p>Daniel Bonventre, one of five ex-Madoff employees on trial
for allegedly aiding the fraud, asked JPMorgan in November 2008
to borrow twice Madoff''s credit limit of $100 million, with U.S.
Treasuries as collateral, Mark Doctoroff, who left the bank last
year, testified yesterday in federal court in Manhattan. </p>
<p>They are doing well financially, Doctoroff said of
Madoff''s securities firm in an e-mail to JPMorgan''s credit
department on Nov. 17, 2008. They are looking at the current
market as an opportunity to make investments, true to their
value investing style. </p>
<p>The five former employees are accused of helping Madoff
hide his fraud from customers, banks and regulators for years,
and getting rich in the process. It''s the first criminal trial
stemming from the scheme, which prosecutors say started in the
early 1970s and imploded at the peak of the financial crisis. </p>
<p>The loan was part of a last-ditch attempt by Madoff to
secure cash as his Ponzi scheme was collapsing and Bonventre''s
role in the application process was one of the many examples of
his involvement in the fraud, prosecutors have said. </p>




Photographer: Peter Foley/Bloomberg

<p>
Daniel Bonventre, who oversaw the broker-dealer and proprietary trading operations of Madoff''s company, where real trading took place, pleaded not guilty and has denied involvement in the fraud, saying he was duped like thousands of others. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Peter Burrows and Dina Bass" date="Nov 08, 2013  9:29 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-08/microsoft-ceo-candidate-elop-said-to-mull-windows-shift.html"><headline>Microsoft CEO Candidate Elop Said to Mull Windows Shift</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Stephen Elop, a candidate to replace Steve Ballmer as Microsoft Corp.''s chief executive officer, would consider breaking with decades of tradition by focusing the company''s strategy around making the popular Office software programs like Word, Excel and PowerPoint available on a broad variety of smartphones and tablets, including those made by Apple Inc. and Google Inc., said three people with knowledge of his thinking. </p> <p>Elop would probably move away from Microsoft''s strategy of using these programs to drive demand for its flagship Windows operating system on personal computers and mobile devices, said the people, who asked not to be identified because the 49-year-old executive hasn''t finalized or publicly discussed his analysis of the business. Most of Microsoft''s software has been tied to running on Windows. </p> <p>Microsoft became the world''s largest software provider under Ballmer and co-founder Bill Gates by making Windows-based PCs running Office applications an industry standard. When the Redmond, Washington-based company failed to come up with hit Windows-based phones and tablets, that left it with little role in the mobile market. Its refusal to adapt Office for Apple and devices based on Google''s Android operating system hasn''t helped its software usage. </p>




Photographer: Casper Hedberg/Bloomberg

<p>
Stephen Elop resigned as Nokia''s CEO when the sale was announced, and said he would become head of a new Microsoft devices unit responsible for hardware such as the Surface tablet and Xbox game console. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elizabeth Amon" date="Nov 08, 2013 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-08/microsoft-patent-chief-to-join-shook-hardy-business-of-law.html"><headline>Microsoft Patent Chief to Join Shook Hardy: Business of Law</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Former Microsoft Corp. chief patent
counsel Bart Eppenauer is joining Shook, Hardy  Bacon LLP as a
partner and will be the managing partner of the firm''s new
Seattle office, opening Dec. 1. </p>
<p>Eppenauer, who was chief patent counsel at Microsoft
starting in 2003, led the patent group in the legal and
corporate affairs department, where he developed Microsoft''s
portfolio of more than 35,000 issued patents worldwide, the firm
said. He also managed a team of more than 100 patent
professionals and worked closely with government and judicial
officials, academics and industry leaders on IP policy issues. </p>
<p>Eppenauer was an associate for three years in Shook''s
intellectual property practice before leaving to join
Microsoft''s legal team in 1997. </p>
<p>We are extremely excited to be opening a Seattle office
and to have Bart rejoining the firm, Shook Chairman John
Murphy said in a statement. Bart''s legal and business
experience is unparalleled and this was a truly unique
opportunity for us to open an office in a region in which we
already have a substantial footprint from a practice
standpoint. </p>
<p>Shook is among Microsoft''s premier provider firms for
legal services, the firm said. The firm''s intellectual property
group includes 58 attorneys, 42 of whom are registered to
practice before the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office. </p>
<p>I have worked closely with Shook''s intellectual property
group for more than a decade in my role at Microsoft and I am
very pleased to be rejoining them, Eppenauer said in a
statement. Shook is a standout, forward-looking firm in terms
of delivering creative, efficient and highly effective legal
services to their clients. </p>
<p>The Seattle office will be Shook''s ninth in the U.S. and
11th worldwide. The firm has more than 440 attorneys. </p>
<p>It will be a smaller office at the outset, but offer the
highest quality in terms of experience and service to our
clients, Murphy said. That has been a successful blueprint
throughout the history of our firm. </p>
<h2>Latham Environmental Lawyer Nominated for Interior Post </h2>
<p>President Obama will nominate Janice Schneider, a partner
in law firm Latham  Watkins LLP, to be assistant secretary for
land and minerals management in the Interior Department,
Bloomberg BNA''s Alan Kovski reports, citing a White House
statement. </p>
<p>If confirmed, Schneider will oversee the Bureau of Land
Management, Bureau of Ocean Energy Management, Bureau of Safety
and Environmental Enforcement, and Office of Surface Mining
Reclamation and Enforcement. </p>
<p>Schneider, a partner in Latham''s Washington office, is
global co-chairman of the firm''s energy and infrastructure
project siting and defense practice and local department
chairman of the environment, land and resources department. </p>
<p>Before joining Latham in 2001, Schneider worked for the
U.S. Department of the Interior and the U.S. Justice Department
and was counselor to the Deputy Secretary of the Interior,
according to her firm biography. </p>
<h2>News </h2>
<h2>New York Lawyer Wells to Lead NFL''s Workplace Probe of Dolphins </h2>
<p>National Football League Commissioner Roger Goodell said
there''s no time limit for an independent probe into alleged
harassment in the Miami Dolphins'' workplace, which will be led
by New York attorney Ted Wells. </p>
<p>Wells, a senior partner in the law firm of Paul Weiss
Rifkind Wharton  Garrison LLP, will direct a thorough and
objective investigation and submit a report to Goodell, the
NFL said in an e-mailed statement. </p>
<p>Ted Wells will have full authority to investigate as he
deems appropriate, Goodell said. Consistent with doing a
thorough investigation, we have not imposed a specific timetable
on him. </p>
<p>The Dolphins asked the NFL to investigate allegations that
harassment led Jonathan Martin to leave the team. Fellow
offensive lineman Richie Incognito was indefinitely suspended. </p>
<p>I am committed to creating a professional environment for
all of the members of the Dolphins family, Dolphins owner
Stephen Ross said in an e-mailed statement. Once the review is
completed and I have all of the facts, we will respond
accordingly. </p>
<p>Ross said the Dolphins will be fully cooperating with the
review, while Miami coach Joe Philbin said the team will take
all necessary steps to correct anything that Wells finds
amiss. </p>
<p>ESPN reported that Incognito, 30, asked Martin, 24, to
contribute financially to an unofficial team trip to Las Vegas
that Martin didn''t attend. The network also said the Dolphins
and the NFL have a copy of a voice message from April in which
Incognito used a racial slur and threatened Martin''s life. </p>
<p>David Dunn, Incognito''s agent, hasn''t responded to multiple
e-mails and a message left at his office seeking comment on the
ESPN reports. </p>
<p>Billy Hunter''s firing in February as head of the National
Basketball Players Association came after an audit of the union
overseen by Wells. </p>
<p>The review concluded that, while Hunter did nothing
illegal, he failed to manage conflicts of interest, lacked
proper corporate governance and didn''t disclose that his $3
million-a-year contract wasn''t properly ratified. </p>
<p>Wells also was involved in an internal investigation into
the men''s basketball program at Syracuse University, where
federal prosecutors in November 2012 dropped a yearlong probe
into former assistant coach Bernie Fine, saying there wasn''t
enough evidence against him to support allegations of sexual
abuse. </p>
<p>My task is to assemble the facts and present my findings
to the commissioner, said Wells, whose report for Goodell will
be made public. I will do so fairly and comprehensively so
that Commissioner Goodell can address this matter properly. I
will begin my work immediately and report my findings to the
commissioner as soon as practical. </p>
<h2>Deals </h2>
<h2>Cravath Represents Toll Brothers on Shapell Acquisition </h2>
<p>Cravath, Swaine  Moore LLP represented Toll Brothers Inc. (TOL)
on its agreement to buy Shapell Industries Inc.''s homebuilding
business for about $1.6 billion, gaining 5,200 lots in the Los
Angeles and San Francisco Bay areas as buyer demand for housing
rises. Gibson Dunn  Crutcher LLP advised Shapell. </p>
<p>The Cravath team included partners Eric L. Schiele, mergers
and acquisitions; Stephen L. Gordon, tax; and Kevin J. Grehan,
real estate. </p>
<p>Gibson Dunn''s team is co-led by Los Angeles real estate
partners Michael Sfregola and Dhiya El-Saden and includes the
following partners: Paul Issler, tax; Patrick Dennis, co-chairman of the environmental litigation and mass tort practice
group; Maurice Suh, litigation; and Sean Feller, benefits. </p>
<p>Toll, the largest U.S. luxury-home builder, will pay for
Beverly Hills, California-based Shapell with debt and a share
offering, the companies said yesterday in a statement. The deal
will more than double the number of California lots controlled
by Toll to about 9,200, with most in coastal markets where
vacant land is hard to come by, Chief Executive Officer Douglas Yearley Jr. said. </p>
<p>Developers are stocking up on land as U.S. home values
climb at their fastest pace in seven years. Earlier this week,
Barry Sternlicht''s Irvine, California-based Tri Pointe Homes
Inc. agreed to buy the homebuilding division of Weyerhaeuser Co.
for $2.7 billion. </p>
<p>In the Shapell deal, 10 percent to 15 percent of the
purchase price will be covered by issuing new Toll shares, and
Toll plans to sell about $500 million of land from the Shapell
portfolio. The Horsham, Pennsylvania-based builder also stands
to make money immediately by selling homes in Shapell''s backlog. </p>
<p>Toll will keep about 150 Shapell employees. Others with the
company will continue to work for the family''s commercial real
estate division, which wasn''t sold to Toll. </p>
<p>For more, click here. </p>
<h2>Moves </h2>
<h2>Katten Hires Hedge Fund and Private-Equity Specialist </h2>
<p>Katten Muchin Rosenman UK LLP said Barry Breen will join
the London office as a partner in the financial-services
practice. He was previously at Sidley Austin LLP. </p>
<p>Breen will continue his focus on advising investment
management and fund clients on hedge fund, infrastructure and
private-equity matters, the firm said in a statement. </p>
<p>Barry''s proven diversity of know-how in the field of
hedge fund investments, operations and regulation broadens and
deepens the already wide array of services we offer our growing
list of clients in this area, Katten Chairman Vince A.F. Sergi
said in the statement. </p>
<p>Katten Muchin Rosenman UK is the London affiliate of Katten
Muchin Rosenman, which has 600 attorneys in the U.S. and in
Asia. The London teamacts for clients in the financial
services, real estate and corporate sectors. </p>
<h2>Pryor Cashman Adds Trusts and Estates With New York Partner </h2>
<p>Pryor Cashman LLP saidDaniel J. Scott joined the firm as a
partner in the trust and estates group in New York. He
previously was withChadbourne  Parke LLP. </p>
<p>In addition to trusts and estates matters, Scott''s work
includes planning forcelebrities, athletes, artists,
entrepreneurs and high net-worth individuals, their families and
businesses.He also advises clients on the structuring,
administration and transfer of closely held businesses. </p>
<p>He brings energy, enthusiasm and a comprehensive skill
set in the area of wealth planning and preservation to our
esteemed client base,Ronald H. Shechtman, Pryor Cashman''s
managing partner, said in a statement. </p>
<p>Pryor Cashman has more than 130 attorneys in its main
office in New York and a site in Los Angeles. </p>
<h2>Davis Wright Adds Health-Care Partner in Seattle </h2>
<p>Health-care lawyer Emily Studebaker joined Davis Wright
Tremaine LLP as a partner in Seattle. She was previously at
Garvey Schubert Barer, where she focused on counseling
ambulatory surgery centers and physician practices. She
currently is general counsel and executive director of the
Washington Ambulatory Surgery Center Association. </p>
<p>We are very pleased to add to the firm her deep
understanding of the continued evolution of health care
regulation in general, and of the ambulatory surgery industry in
particular, Rick Ellingsen, chairman of the health-care
practice at Davis Wright, said in a statement. </p>
<p>Studebaker''s regulatory work has included counseling
ambulatory surgery centers and physicians on fraud and abuse
laws, as well as assisting with licensing, accreditation, and
certification. In the transaction area, she has represented
clients in acquisitions, divestitures and joint ventures. </p>
<p>Davis Wright has about 500 lawyers at nine offices in the
U.S. and Shanghai. </p>
<h2>Freeborn Expands Private-Equity Team With New Partner Jungels </h2>
<p>The Chicago-based law firmFreeborn  Peters LLPhired Gary A. Jungels as a partner in both the private equity and venture
capital industry team and the corporate practice group. He was
formerly a partner at Mayer Brown LLP. </p>
<p>Jungels has experience in private equity and venture
capital as well as fund formations and joint ventures. He has
represented fund sponsors and management teams in structuring,
negotiating and closing funds, the firm said. </p>
<p>His experience with fund formations will provide a
valuable service to our private equity and venture capital
clients, Jeff Mattson, co-leader of the firm''s corporate
practice group and its private equity and venture capital
industry team, said in a statement. </p>
<p>Freeborn  Peters has more than 200 professionals at two
Illinois offices. </p>
<h2>Litigation </h2>
<h2>Police Found Blunkett Voice Mails in News Corp. Lawyer''s Safe </h2>
<p>Recordings of voice mails left by former Home Secretary
David Blunkett on the phone of a woman he was having an affair
with were discovered in the safe of News Corp. (NWSA)''s U.K. lawyer. </p>
<p>Police found the tapes and a draft News of the World
article about Blunkett''s three-year relationship with Kimberly
Quinn in Tom Crone''s safe at News Corp.''s U.K. unit, Andrew
Edis, a prosecution lawyer, told the jury yesterday. The
prosecution said the story, which was published in 2004, was the
result of phone hacking. </p>
<p>Rebekah Brooks, the former chief executive officer of News
Corp.''s U.K. unit and Andy Coulson, a 45-year-old former editor
of the now defunct News of the World, are among eight people
standing trial for a string of offenses stemming from wrongdoing
at News Corp. U.K. tabloids. Crone, the company''s former lawyer,
isn''t accused of wrongdoing. </p>
<p>Rupert Murdoch, the company''s chairman, closed the News of
the World tabloid in July 2011 in a bid to defuse a scandal over
revelations journalists had hacked the phone of a missing
teenager, Milly Dowler, who was later found murdered. </p>
<p>The messages related to Blunkett were deeply personal and
intrusive, Detective Constable Tim Hargreaves told the court. </p>
<p>Edis played a recording of a conversation in which Coulson
confronted the lawmaker before the story was published. Coulson
refused to reveal his sources and said he was sure it was
right. </p>
<p>I wouldn''t be exposing myself in this way unless I
believed the story to be true, Coulson, who later became a
media adviser to Prime Minister David Cameron, said to Blunkett.
I am confident. </p>
<p>The other defendants include Stuart Kuttner, the 73-year-old former managing editor of the News of the World, and Ian Edmondson, a 44-year-old former news editor, who are both
accused of phone hacking. The newspaper''s one-time royal
reporter, Clive Goodman, 56, is charged with conspiring to
commit misconduct in a public office. </p>
<p>Brooks''s husband, her former assistant Cheryl Carter, and
the U.K. unit''s former head of security, Mark Hanna, face
charges of conspiring to pervert the course of justice. </p>
<h2>Video </h2>
<h2>Stop-And-Frisk Judge Removed, Fights Back </h2>
<p>Last month, a federal appeals court panel put a hold on
changes to the New York Police Department''s stop-and-frisk
practices and created a controversy by removing Judge Shira
Scheindlin, who had ordered the changes. </p>
<p>The panel said Scheindlin ran afoul of judicial ethics
rules by encouraging lawyers to bring the stop-and-frisk case,
which she would hear as related to others on her docket, and
by speaking to reporters while the case was under way. </p>
<p>Many lawyers have come to the judge''s defense. Nancy
Gertner, a former federal judge says that the panel, not
Scheindlin, violated the rules since no party had moved to
disqualify her. </p>
<p>For video link, click here. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kitty Donaldson" date="Nov 10, 2013  9:56 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-10/general-tax-call-from-davey-for-green-levies-played-down.html"><headline>General Tax Call From Davey for Green Levies Played Down</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A call from Energy Secretary Ed Davey to move two of the levies on gas and electricity bills
into general taxation was played down by a person familiar with
Chancellor of the Exchequer George Osborne''s budget plans, who
indicated the matter had yet to be decided. </p>
<p>Liberal Democrat Davey used an interview in the Sunday
Telegraph today to suggest the taxpayer could foot the bill for
two of the so-called green levies currently paid for through
energy bills. The newspaper said that if the largest levy, the
Energy Companies'' Obligation, is removed prices might
immediately fall by 7 percent. </p>
<p>Energy and climate change policies add about 9 percent, or
112 pounds ($179), to current annual bills for gas and power,
the Department for Energy and Climate Change says. The biggest
contribution of the policies to average annual bills is 47
pounds from the Energy Company Obligation that means suppliers
must offer efficiency measures to vulnerable families. Other
levies include the Warm Home Discount and carbon taxes. </p>
<p>Davey told the paper he is happy to have a debate about
how green energy policies are funded, adding: We can maybe
find there are other ways of paying for them. There may be ways
and means. </p>
<p>As winter approaches, the U.K. is debating how to tackle
energy prices that are outstripping inflation. Last month four
of the Big Six energy firms raised prices. Prime Minister
David Cameron has ordered a review of environmental charges
levied on domestic bills in an effort to regain the political
initiative after the opposition Labour Party promised to freeze
power prices if elected in 2015. </p>
<h2>Coalition Works </h2>
<p>Davey''s Liberal Democrats are in a coalition with Cameron
and Osborne''s Conservatives. A person familiar with the budget
negotiations poured cold water on the suggestion that there
could be a new tax to pay for green subsidies. Osborne will set
out his tax and spending plans on Dec. 4. </p>
<p>The Telegraph today said Osborne would have to raise taxes
to pay for the suggestion or find savings elsewhere. The
chancellor has repeatedly said he favors spending reductions
rather than tax increases as Britain consolidates its austerity
program. </p>
<p>This is all just speculation, a spokesman for Osborne
said on condition of anonymity in line with U.K. government
rules. We have been clear while we are dealing with Labour''s
deficit and fixing the public finances that we will do whatever
we can along the way to help hardworking people. Details will be
coming in due course. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri" date="Nov 11, 2013  4:09 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-11/disney-names-pitaro-sole-interactive-head-pleasants-out.html"><headline>Disney Names Pitaro Sole Interactive Head, Pleasants Out</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS) named Jimmy Pitaro
sole president of its interactive business, assuming duties held
by John Pleasants in a shake-up less than a week after the unit
reported its second-ever quarterly profit. </p>
<p>Disney is merging the games and media operations within
interactive as part of the change, the Burbank, California-based
company said today in an e-mailed statement. Pleasants, who was
co-president with Pitaro, becomes a consultant. </p>
<p>The company is consolidating the interactive business under
a single leader after the successful introduction of the Disney
Infinity game system that Pleasants oversaw. The moves comes as
Infinity, combining collectibles with video games, gears up to
challenge the Skylanders products from Activision Blizzard
Inc. during the holiday season. </p>
<p>Disney''s stated goal is to improve the profitability of
that division, and I would expect that to continue to be the
primary focus, said Laura Martin, an analyst with Needham 
Co. in Los Angeles who has a hold rating on the stock. </p>
<p>The change isn''t likely to have a meaningful impact on
Disney''s earnings over the next 12 months, Martin said. </p>
<p>Disney fell 0.4 percent to $68.34 at the close in New York.
The stock has gained 37 percent this year, compared with 20
percent for the Dow Jones Industrial Average. </p>
<h2>Interactive Profit </h2>
<p>The interactive division posted a profit of $16 million in
the fourth quarter ended Sept. 28, as sales more than doubled to
$396 million with the release of the Infinity system, Disney
said on Nov. 7. The unit lost $76 million in the same quarter a
year earlier. </p>
<p>This successful launch drove Disney Interactive''s swing
to profitability in Q4 and all indications suggest the strong
demand for Disney Infinity will continue, Chairman and Chief
Executive Officer Robert Iger said on a conference call last
week. </p>
<p>Disney named the two men co-presidents of interactive in
October 2010. Pitaro hailed from Yahoo! Inc.''s media unit, while
Pleasants led Playdom, a games company that was purchased by
Disney in 2010 for as much as $563 million. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Nov 11, 2013  3:28 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-11/jpmorgan-said-to-consider-chat-room-ban-amid-regulatory-scrutiny.html"><headline>JPMorgan Said to Weigh Chat-Room Ban Amid Regulatory Probes</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co., the biggest U.S. bank by assets, is weighing whether to ban traders from using electronic chat rooms to communicate with peers at other firms as the forums draw scrutiny from global regulators, according to a person with knowledge of the matter. </p> <p>JPMorgan''s deliberations, which should be complete by early 2014, focus on multi-dealer chat rooms for currencies and other asset classes, said the person, who requested anonymity because the talks are private. Royal Bank of Scotland Group Plc, Britain''s biggest publicly owned lender, and Zurich-based Credit Suisse Group AG, Switzerland''s second-largest bank, also are reviewing chat-room use, two other people said. </p> <p>Regulators have targeted traders'' electronic messages, using them as evidence of wrongdoing in their investigations into the manipulation of benchmark interest rates and foreign-exchange markets. During a visit to London last month, JPMorgan Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon called on employees to be vigilant about language in e-mails and instant messages, two people with knowledge of the matter said then. </p> <p>JPMorgan may encourage traders to use phones and e-mails rather than chat rooms to assist clients in large currency transactions, the person with knowledge of the matter said. </p>




Photographer: Peter Foley/Bloomberg

<p>
The JPMorgan Chase  Co. headquarters in New York City. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Victoria Slind-Flor" date="Nov 11, 2013  7:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-11/disney-piggy-pushers-dunlop-intellectual-property.html"><headline>Disney, Piggy Pushers, Dunlop: Intellectual Property</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS) and other movie and
TV studios have asked a federal court to dismiss their
copyright-infringement case against the file-sharing website
Lime Wire LLC and its founder, Mark Gorton, according to a Nov.
7 court filing. </p>
<p>The studios, including Viacom Inc. (VIAB), News Corp.''s Twentieth
Century Fox Film and Time Warner Inc.''s Warner Bros.
Entertainment, filed the suit in federal court in New York in
February 2012. They claimed a staggering amount of
infringement took place through the site, and that millions of
users copied billions of files using Lime Wire without paying
anything to copyright owners. </p>
<p>Lime Wire developed peer-to-peer software that let people
share digital entertainment files on their computers with other
people over the Internet. TV shows such as South Park and
Desperate Housewives and movies including Avatar and the
Harry Potter films were among the material allegedly
infringed, according to the filing. </p>
<p>Gorton operates Tower Capital Research LLC, a New York-based hedge fund that trades securities based on mathematical
algorithms it developed. Gorton directed and benefited from
Lime Wire''s inducement of infringement, the entertainment
companies said in one of their filings. </p>
<p>U.S. District Judge Kimba Wood in May 2010 found Lime Wire
and Gorton liable for inducing infringement of copyrights for
recorded music. The site was shut down by an October 2010 court
order. Lime Wire settled with the recording industry for $105
million in May 2011 during a trial in Manhattan to determine
damages. </p>
<p>No terms for the settlement of the case brought by the
studios were disclosed. </p>
<p>The case is Twentieth Century Fox Film Corp. v. Lime Wire
LLC, 12-cv-00818, U.S. District Court, Southern District of New
York (Manhattan). </p>
<p>The earlier case is Arista Records LLC v. Lime Wire LLC,
06-cv-05936, U.S. District Court, Southern District of New York
(Manhattan). </p>
<p>For more copyright news, click here. </p>
<h2>Patents </h2>
<h2>Piggy Pushers'' Sock Patent Not Infringed, Appeals Court Rules </h2>
<p>A federal appeals court affirmed a lower-court ruling that
a patent wasn''t infringed based on its understanding of the
difference between a sock and a shoe. </p>
<p>The case, filed in a Michigan federal court in July 2010,
was between two makers of footwear for infants. Piggy Pushers of
Holland, Michigan, claimed that products made by Skidders
Footwear Inc. infringed patent 6,385,779. </p>
<p>The patent covers a sock for a crawling infant. According
to the patent, which was issued in May 2002, the sock has a
gripper element in both the upper and lower surface that
increases friction and makes it possible for a baby to crawl on
slippery surfaces. </p>
<p>The product made by New York-based Skidders has a foot-surrounding sock bonded to a rubber outsole. In May 2012 the
lower court said there was nothing in the language of the patent
that could suggest the inventor meant sock to mean anything
other than the ordinary definition. </p>
<p>The lower court said the Skidders products had a number of
differences from socks, including having a durable outsole, and
left- and right-foot designations. </p>
<p>In its Nov. 8 ruling, the Washington-based U.S. Court of
Appeals for the Federal Circuit said the lower court was
correct. Piggy Pushers, the court said, failed to present
evidence refuting Skidders'' claim that its product didn''t fit
the definition of a sock. </p>
<p>The appeal is Piggy Pushers LLC v. Skidders Footwear LLC,
2013-1107, U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit
(Washington). </p>
<p>The lower court case is Piggy Pushers LLC v. Skidders
Footwear Inc., 1:10-cv-00644, U.S. District Court, Western
District of Michigan (Grand Rapids). </p>
<h2>Furuno Complaint Against Garmin, Navico to Be Investigated </h2>
<p>The U.S. International Trade Commission said Nov. 8 that it
will investigate a complaint filed in September by Furuno
Electric Co. (6814) </p>
<p>Hygo, Japan-based  Furuno said that GPS, navigation and
radar devices made by Garmin Ltd., Navico Holdings A/S and Flir
Systems Inc.''s Raymarine unit infringe four patents. Furuno is
seeking an import ban against all three companies'' devices. </p>
<p>The devices are used in cars, airplanes and ships. The
patents cover systems, devices and methods for improving
navigation, radar and map displays, according to the complaint. </p>
<p>The Washington-based ITC has the power to exclude the
importation of items that infringe U.S. patents. Last week the
commission also said that it would investigate a complaint
Navico made against Flir fish-finding devices. </p>
<p>For more patent news, click here. </p>
<h2>Trademark </h2>
<h2>Dunlop''s Cleveland Golf Unit Sues Callaway Over Golf Club Name </h2>
<p>Dunlop Sports Co. (7825)''s Roger Cleveland Golf unit sued Callaway
Golf Co. (ELY) for trademark infringement. </p>
<p>The suit, filed in federal court in Santa Ana, California,
is related to the use of the phrase Designed by Roger
Cleveland on some of Callaway''s golf clubs. </p>
<p>According to the complaint, Roger Cleveland founded the
Roger Cleveland Golf Co. in 1979. The company owns a number of
trademark registrations for Cleveland and Cleveland
Golf. </p>
<p>Cleveland left the company in 1995 and, according to court
papers, departed with no rights in or to the Cleveland
trademarks. He went to work for rival Callaway, where he is now
chief of golf club design. </p>
<p>In July 2013, Callaway began marketing a club bearing Roger
Cleveland''s name, the Roger Cleveland Mac Daddy 2. Roger
Cleveland Golf said consumers have been confused by Callaway''s
use of the name, and that, to no avail, it has sent cease-and-desist notices to Carlsbad, California-based Callaway. </p>
<p>It asked the court to bar Callaway''s use of the Cleveland
name, and for awards of money damages, including profits
attributable to the alleged infringement, together with attorney
fees and litigation costs. </p>
<p>Callaway didn''t respond immediately to an e-mailed request
for comment. </p>
<p>The case is Roger Cleveland Golf Co. v. Callaway Golf Co.,
8:13-cv-01642, U.S. District Court, Central District of
California (Santa Ana). </p>
<p>Famous Jameis'' Trademark Filing Is Made by Alabama Football Fan </p>
<p>An Alabama football fan has applied to register the phrase
Famous Jameis as a trademark. The phrase has been used to
describe Florida State University quarterback Jameis Winston,
the Heisman Trophy favorite. </p>
<p>Mukul Mehra, 40, filed the trademark request on Oct. 24,
according to the database of the U.S. Patent and Trademark
Office. </p>
<p>Mehra said in a telephone interview he has no connection to
Winston, a redshirt freshman from Bessemer, Alabama, a suburb of
Birmingham. </p>
<p>It''s not necessarily geared toward him, said Mehra, who
has a medical degree from the University of Alabama School of
Medicine in Birmingham. I don''t know what our intent
completely is. We haven''t worked all of that out. </p>
<p>Pamela Deese, a partner at the Washington law firm Arent
Fox, said in a telephone interview that Winston probably would
be awarded the trademark if he moved to register it. </p>
<p>We would hope the examiner is savvy enough to recognize
that Famous Jameis refers to the potential Heisman Trophy
winner, said Deese, whose clients include Houston Rockets
guard Jeremy Lin. You can''t register a trademark for somebody
else''s name without their permission, which is what happened
with Jeremy. </p>
<p>Mehra said he has contacted a local sports marketing
company about producing Famous Jameis T-shirts. He also said
he''s open to a partnership with Winston or Florida State. If
it''s something they''re interested in using we could potentially
market it together, Mehra said. </p>
<p>The 6-foot-4, 228-pound Winston, at -500, is the favorite
at sportsbook.com to win the Heisman Trophy, which is given
annually to college football''s best player. A $50 bet would win
$10. </p>
<p>Winston has completed 149 of 212 passes for 2,502 yards and
24 touchdowns, fifth in college football''s top level. He''s also
thrown six interceptions and run for three touchdowns. </p>
<p>Deese said it would behoove Winston to move quickly on the
trademark. </p>
<p>The longer you wait, the more costly it gets, she said. </p>
<h2>Second AIDS Group Vies for Defunct Charity''s Mark, Blade Says </h2>
<p>A second AIDS-related charity has made an offer to buy the
trademark of the now-defunct National Association of People with
AIDS, the Washington Blade reported. </p>
<p>The Washington-based Community Education Group made an
offer to the bankruptcy court buy to buy the trademark rights to
six different names, the Blade reported. </p>
<p>The marks include National HIV Testing Day, National
Gay Men''s Awareness Day, National Gay Men''s HIV/AIDS
Awareness Day, Healthy Living Summit'''' and AIDS Watch,''''
according to the Blade. </p>
<p>Earlier Health HIV, also based in Washington, offered
$3,000 for the rights to just one of the marks, National Gay
Men''s HIV/AIDS Awareness Day,'''' according to the newspaper. </p>
<h2>New Yorkers Charged Over Fake Polo, Lacoste Clothes, WABC Says </h2>
<p>Six New York residents have been charged with trademark
counterfeiting and conspiracy, WABC-TV reported. </p>
<p>They were accused of selling versions of Ralph Loren
Corp. (RL)''s Polo, Lacoste SA, VF Inc. (VFC)''s North Face, and True
Religion Apparel Inc.''s clothing with a suggested retail price
of more than $13.4 million to smaller distributors, according to
the New York-based television station. </p>
<p>The charges followed the seizure of more than 2,000 boxes
of counterfeit trademarked clothing from a storage facility in
Queens, New York, in July, WABC-TV reported. </p>
<p>New York Police Department Commissioner Ray Kelly told
WABC-TV that this counterfeit-clothing operation was of
particular importance because of indications that the proceeds
went to areas in southern Lebanon that were of concern to
the intelligence bureau. </p>
<p>For more trademark news, click here. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Nov 13, 2013  1:26 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-13/goldman-names-managing-directors-in-biennial-promotions.html"><headline>Goldman Names Managing Directors in Biennial Promotions</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), the fifth-biggest U.S. bank by assets, promoted 280 employees to managing
director, up from 266 last year, as it begins making the
selections every two years instead of annually. </p>
<p>The promotions disclosed today on the company''s website
take effect Jan. 1 and won''t happen again until 2015, after the
bank decided earlier this year to change to a biennial process.
New York-based Goldman Sachs last year named 70 people to its
partnership, the fewest since the firm became a public company
in 1999, and won''t promote new partners until next year. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Lloyd C. Blankfein said yesterday
that the firm is always focused on recruiting and retaining top
talent, even as it sets aside a lower portion of revenue for
compensation. Blankfein, 59, said the average tenure for
employees with a title of vice president or higher is 9.1 years,
up from 7.6 years in 2001. Managing director is the second-highest title among non-executives. </p>
<p>The insight and perspective that is gained by living
through several cycles is impossible to quantify, and having a
group of professionals who have experienced those cycles
together also carries an immeasurable benefit, Blankfein said
yesterday at an investor conference in New York. </p>
<h2>The Federation'' </h2>
<p>The securities division has the most new managing directors
with 94, while 51 are in investment banking, 39 in investment
management, 14 in research and eight in merchant banking, said
David Wells, a bank spokesman. The other 74 work for the firm''s
administrative arm, known as The Federation. </p>
<p>About 56 percent of those just promoted are based in the
Americas, 27 percent in Europe, Middle East and Africa, 15
percent in Asia-Pacific and 2 percent in India, Wells said. Last
year, about 58 percent were in the Americas, 26 percent in EMEA
and 17 percent in Asia. </p>
<p>Women comprise 20 percent of the incoming class of managing
directors, compared with 23 percent in 2012 and 19 percent in
2011. </p>
<p>Average compensation cost per employee at Goldman Sachs
fell 5 percent to $319,755 in the first nine months of 2013,
even as revenue climbed 2 percent. The company employed 32,600
people at the end of September, 3,100 fewer than at the end of
2010. </p>
<h2>Rigorous Exercise'' </h2>
<p>Managing directors typically receive a base salary of
$500,000, lower than the $900,000 granted to partners. Both also
get bonuses that can boost total compensation into the millions
of dollars. </p>
<p>About 7 percent of Goldman Sachs''s employees hold the
managing director title. The firm created a non-partner managing
director title in 1996 to recognize top workers who weren''t yet
partners, and decided in March to switch from the annual
tradition. </p>
<p>A biennial process will allow us to invest more in the
managing-director selection process so that it will continue to
be a disciplined and rigorous exercise, the bank said in a
March memo to employees. This will help to ensure that the
managing director title remains as aspirational as it should be
for our top performers. </p>
<p>The firm''s first class of 87 managing directors included
William C. Dudley, now president of the Federal Reserve Bank of
New York; Clifford S. Asness, who left in 1998 to start hedge
fund AQR Capital Management LLC; and Richard J. Gnodde, who was
named co-head of global investment banking at Goldman Sachs in
May 2011. </p>
<p>The following is a list of the new managing directors: </p>

Katherine Abrat
Afsheen Afshar
Puneet Agarwal
Sergio Akselrad
Philip Aldis
Jean Altier Bohm
Margaret Anadu
Vishweshwar Anantharam
Alexi Antolovich
Silvia Ardagna
Matthew Armas
Anthony Arnold
Yacov Arnopolin
Celine Assouline
Roberto Awad
Amin Azmoudeh
Davie Baccei
Eric Bai
Taran Bakker
Paddy Balasubramanian
Kevin Barker
Lindsay Basloe
Peter Beckman
Collin Bell
Navtej Bhullar
Francois-Xavier Bouillet
Douglas Bouquard
David Bowen
Elizabeth Bowyer
Sarah Brungs
Michael Bruun
Beat Cabiallavetta
Niharika Cabiallavetta
John Cahill
Greg Calnon
Robert Camacho
David Campbell
Thomas Campbell
Michael Casey
John Cassidy
Pascal Cerf
Tiffani Chambers
Sharmini Chetwode
Patricia Chew
Travis Chmelka
Lisa Coar
Charles Cognata
Dahlia Cohen
Rod Colburn
Peter Colven
Stuart Connolly
Stephen Considine
Damien Courvalin
Nora Creedon
Alicia Crighton
Adam Crook
Piers Curle
Michael D''Addario
Aneesh Daga
Matt Dailey
Viktor Danielson
Eric Dann
Suzanne de Verdelon
Banu Demirkiran
Michael Deninno
Stratford Dennis
Anthony DeRose
Arun Dhar
Scott Diamond
Rachel Diller
Lin Ding
Rohan Doctor
Anthony Duggan
Sinead Dunphy
Michael Durso
Michael Eakins
Mike Ebeling
Kene Ejikeme
Simon Ennis
Ashley Everett
Amir Fais
Joseph Femenia
Ivan Fillon
Andrew Fisher
Andrew Flahive
Brian Fortson
Bridget Fraser
Olivier Frendo
Gedaliah Friedenberg
Nicolas Friedman
James Fulton
Roger Gardiner
Grace Ge
Matija Gergolet
Phil Giuca
Brian Glass
Ward Glassmeyer
Craig Glassner
Nicholas Godfrey
Lawrence Grassi
Jett Greenberg
David Gribble
Benjamin Grizzle
Anil Grover
Fredrik Grunberger
Dominic Gurney
David Ha
Kirsten Hagen
Digboloy Halder
Phillip Han
Sarah Harper
Nick Hartley
Hunter Henry
Debra Herschmann
Michael Hickey
Michael Higgins
Axel Hoefer
Judy Hong
Tim Hooley
Erdit Hoxha
James Huckaby
Michael Husson
Maximos Iakovlev
Inci Isikli
Omer Ismail
Glade Jacobsen
Sumedh Jaiswal
Michael Jalkut
Channa Jayaweera
Derek Jean-Baptiste
Chito Jeyarajah
Jessica Jones
Sami Kamhawi
Geraldine Keefe
Zaid Khaldi
Talat Khan
Gautam Khanna
Robert Kimmel
Hiroki Kimoto
Gil Klemann
Victor Klimchenko
Gordon Kluzak
Heidi Kniesel
Kimiyasu Kono
Joseph Konzelmann
Eric Kramer
Pavel Krotkov
Rohit Kumar
Yojiro Kunitomo
David LaBianca
Jonathan Lamm
Adam Lane
Risa Lederhandler
Andrei Legostaev
Matt Leisen
Vincenzo Lento
Wesley LePatner
Xufa Liao
Brian Liloia
Reginaldo Lima
Marcel Liplijn
Malcolm MacDonald
John Marshall
Jonathan Matz
Patty McCarthy
Michael McGinn
Alan McLean
Olympia McNerney
Scott Mehling
Noa Meyer
Alexandra Miani
Jung Min
Jerry Minier
Anthony Mirabile
Anindya Mohinta
Mike Mooney
Sam Morgan
Will Morgan
Peter Morreale
Rick Morris
Piyush Mubayi
Kaushik Murali
Mark Najarian
Josh Newsome
Logan Nicholson
Mike Nickols
Sergei Nodelman
Jolie Norris
Edward Oakley
Timothy O''Donovan
Brian O''Keeffe
Mark Olivier
Stephen Orr
Bartosz Ostenda
Enrico Ottavian
Hiroshi Ozawa
Matthew Papas
Muir Paterson
Cyrille Perard
Chris Perez
Amit Pilowsky
Nick Pomponi
Brandon Press
Ken Prince
Elizabeth Pritchard
Grant Purtell
Don Raab
Radovan Radman
Mohan Rajagopal
Neema Raphael
Michael Rendel
Osmin Rivera
Ludovic Rodhain
Javier Rodriguez-Alarcon
Cosmo Roe
Andrew Rosivach
Jennifer Roth
Armin Rothauser
Jonathan Rousse
John Ryan
Yassaman Salas
Tom Scarpati
Joao Schmidt
Rachel Schnoll
Marc Schreiber
Bruce Schwartz
Lyle Schwartz
Anshul Sehgal
John Semczuk
Hideyuki Seo
Jonathan Shapiro
Johann Shudlick
Andrew Silverman
Brian Singer
Jeremie Sokolowsky
Simone Song
William Stamatakis
Jari Stehn
Jeremy Stent
Alan Stewart
Daniel Strack
Alexandra Stubbings
Masato Sunaga
Takaaki Suzuki
Chia Min Tan
Robert Tau
Sujay Telang
Baris Temelkuran
Rene Theriault
Bart Thomson
Cassandra Tok
Alex Tomas
Karen Trapani
Kamakshya Trivedi
Emma Tsui
Ervin Tu
John Tully
Thomas Turner
Michael Ungari
Krishnamurthy Vaidyanathan
Anilu Vazquez-Ubarri
Sofie Wacha
Scott Walter
Bryce Wan
James Wang
Kent Wasson
Michael Watts
Stephen Waxman
Connie Wen
Colin White
Kyle Williams
Stephen Withnell
Audrey Woon
Chiharu Yamagami
Suzzanne Yao
Rana Yared
Bervan Yeh
Tony Yip
Emi Yoshibe
Vladimir Zakharov

<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki and Hugh Son" date="Nov 13, 2013  1:15 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-13/jpmorgan-says-fourth-quarter-trading-revenue-is-lower.html"><headline>JPMorgan Says Fourth-Quarter Trading Revenue Is Lower</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s fourth-quarter trading revenue will be slightly down from last year,
according to Michael Cavanagh, who co-runs the bank''s corporate
and investment bank. </p>
<p>Fixed income and equities are tracking very well versus
client volumes, which are down slightly from last year,
Cavanagh said at an investor conference in New York today. </p>
<p>Investment-banking fees for underwriting bond and equity
issuance and advising on mergers and acquisitions are
healthy this quarter and may be close to the previous three
months, when JPMorgan generated $1.5 billion in fees, he said. </p>
<p>Last year''s fourth quarter was a particularly strong
underwriting quarter. I don''t think we''ll achieve that again,
but it''s a healthy quarter, Cavanagh said, adding that the
final figure might come in looking something similar to the
third quarter. </p>
<p>Cavanagh and Daniel Pinto run the corporate and investment
bank, whose traders compiled a perfect record in the first nine
months of this year by generating profits every day the markets
were open. On three of those days, traders made more than $200
million, JPMorgan said in a regulatory filing this month. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Mulholland" date="Nov 13, 2013 12:53 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-13/goldman-sachs-pulls-loan-from-commercial-mortgage-bond-deal-1-.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Pulls Loan From Commercial Mortgage Bond Deal</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. pulled a
loan from a commercial-mortgage bond deal sold last week after
investors balked at the debt amid concern that underwriting
standards are slipping in the $550 billion market. </p>
<p>The $47.5 million loan, linked to 10 shopping malls in
Nebraska and South Dakota, was removed because of a potential
dispute between the borrower and a lender, according to a
filing today with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. </p>
<p>The debt, called the Perkins Retail Portfolio, was
originated by Jefferies Group Inc., according to deal documents
obtained by Bloomberg News. C-III Capital Partners, the servicer
overseeing the mortgage, was seeking additional information from
the borrower about the properties while the $1.1 billion
commercial-mortgage backed securities offering was being
marketed, according to a Nov. 5 statement on C-III''s website. </p>
<p>This is one of the first instances that we are aware of
that a loan was pulled out of CMBS deal after pricing, said
Richard Hill, a debt analyst at Morgan Stanley in New York.
That deal priced at a significant concession to another deal
priced that same day, so investors were already concerned about
the credit quality. </p>
<p>A top-ranked portion of the transaction maturing in 10
years was sold to yield 108 basis points more than the benchmark
swap rate, compared with 96 basis points on similar debt sold by
JPMorgan Chase  Co., according to data compiled by Bloomberg. A
basis point is 0.01 percentage point. </p>
<h2>Incorrect Statements'' </h2>
<p>Michael DuVally, a spokesman for Goldman Sachs, and Richard
Khaleel of Jefferies declined to comment. </p>
<p>The Perkins loan wasn''t the only mortgage that raised red
flags. In a supplement distributed to bond buyers prior to the
pricing, the underwriters disclosed additional information about
a $3.8 million loan linked to manufactured housing in Virginia,
noting that the loan documents were being modified because the
borrower failed to disclose a guilty plea in 1989 arising from
incorrect statements submitted to lenders. </p>
<p>Sales of bonds linked to everything from strip malls to
skyscrapers are poised to double to $70 billion this year as
investors chase riskier assets with the Federal Reserve
suppressing interest rates for almost five years, according to
Credit Suisse Group AG. </p>
<p>Moody''s Investors Service is increasing the amount of
credit protection required to obtain investment-grade rankings
on the debt as loans get risker, the New York-based rating
company said in an Oct. 28 report. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Rubin" date="Nov 13, 2013 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-13/jpmorgan-settlement-truth-in-advertising-sought-on-taxes.html"><headline>JPMorgan Settlement Truth in Advertising Sought on Taxes</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>An aspect of U.S. tax law is being criticized by some lawmakers and consumer groups concerned that it may be worth billions of dollars for JPMorgan Chase  Co in negotiations with the Department of Justice. </p> <p>An agreement between the government and the bank over mortgage-bond sales that''s silent on taxes would let the company take a deduction and shave 35 percent off any settlement cost publicized in headlines. That would, for example, turn an announced settlement of $10 billion into one for $6.5 billion. </p> <p>It shouldn''t have hidden subsidies or sweeteners in the settlement, said Francisco Enriquez, a tax and budget associate at the U.S. Public Interest Research Group, which says it operates as a counter to big banks. If the DOJ is in the end going to look for a $6.5 billion price tag, then that''s what they should say. </p> <p>Tax implications are a complicated part of settlement talks between companies and the U.S. government. Companies focused on after-tax costs negotiate with government agencies that may be more concerned about how big a payment they can claim to have extracted than about how much money ends up in the Treasury. </p> <p>At dinner parties, a billion sounds better than $700 million, even if a billion is tax deductible and $700 million is not, said Gregg Polsky, a law professor at the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill who has studied the taxation of penalties and damage payments. </p> <p>Brian Fallon, a DOJ spokesman, declined to comment because the talks are continuing on resolving multiple legal issues surrounding the mortgage-bond sales. Also declining to comment was Brian Marchiony, a spokesman for the New York-based bank. </p> <h2>Fines, Restitution </h2> <p>U.S. tax law places payments to government agencies into two categories: fines and penalties, which are not deductible, and compensatory damages and restitution, which can be deducted as business expenses. </p> <p>If a settlement agreement is silent on taxes, a company is free to claim a deduction against the 35 percent federal corporate income tax and state income taxes. </p> <p>The Internal Revenue Service may challenge the deduction, a path that can lead to litigation over whether payments were deductible restitution or non-deductible penalties. </p> <p>Some government settlement accords include clauses where companies agree not to take deductions. For example, the agreement this month between the Justice Department and SAC Capital Advisors LP prevented the hedge fund from deducting any of the $1.8 billion payment in that settlement and a related case with the Securities and Exchange Commission. </p> <p>JPMorgan''s $5.1 billion settlement on Oct. 25 with the Federal Housing Finance Agency included no clause limiting tax deductions. </p> <h2>Pretty Clear'' </h2> <p>Absent such an agreement, I think it''s pretty clear that virtually all of the payment will be deductible, said Robert Willens, a New York-based tax and accounting consultant. </p> <p>U.S. lawmakers including Representative Peter Welch, a Vermont Democrat, want the bank to forgo a tax deduction. </p> <p>It was the taxpayer who initially funded the bailout of Wall Street, Welch wrote on Oct. 30 to Jamie Dimon, the bank''s chairman and chief executive officer. It was the taxpayer who continues to endure the consequences of the worst recession since the Great Depression. The taxpayer should not, therefore, be required to contribute a nickel towards the fines imposed for conduct that got America into this mess in the first place. </p> <h2>Grassley, Reed </h2> <p>Senator Charles Grassley, an Iowa Republican, and Senator Jack Reed, a Rhode Island Democrat, introduced legislation this month that would require the government and companies to reach advance agreements on how settlements will be taxed. </p> <p>A 2007 version of the measure was estimated to generate $263 million in government revenue over 10 years, according to Jill Gerber, a spokeswoman for Grassley. </p> <p>Cases with punitive and compensatory components are complicated by the differing goals of those involved in the negotiations, Polsky said. </p> <p>The defendant cares about the after-tax dollars, he said. The IRS cares about the after-tax dollars. The regulatory agency that''s settling the case, they don''t seem to care about the after-tax amount. </p> <p>Enriquez said settlement deductibility is a systemic issue that amounts to a loophole, letting companies deduct payments that are really being made to avoid formal fines. </p> <h2>Quite Angry'' </h2> <p>Wrongdoing should not constitute a tax writeoff and wrongdoing shouldn''t be subsidized by the American people, he said. People are just generally quite angry and rightfully so that JPMorgan could get a massive $3.5 billion tax deduction for their suffering. </p> <p>Willens said lawmakers have become more aware of the deductibility of settlements, making it possible that the JPMorgan agreement could include clauses on taxes to make the real cost more closely match the announced amount. </p> <p>Given the outrage that has been expressed by some about the ability to deduct this, including some pretty influential politicians, I would think there probably would be something in the agreement, he said. </p> <p>The Reed-Grassley bill is S. 1654. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Drew Armstrong" date="Nov 14, 2013  1:09 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-14/pfizer-ditching-blackberry-over-volatile-state-of-maker.html"><headline>Pfizer Ditching BlackBerry, Citing Its Volatile'' State</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE), the world''s biggest
drugmaker, will wean off of BlackBerry (BBRY) Ltd.''s phones, citing
concerns that the mobile technology company might not be around
in the future or may have service interrupted. </p>
<p>Pfizer told employees who use BlackBerry devices to instead
get an Apple Inc. phone or one run on Google Inc.''s Android
operating system. The drugmaker cited Waterloo, Ontario-based
BlackBerry''s declining market share and noted that the company
attempted to sell itself. </p>
<p>In response to declining sales, the company is in a
volatile state, New York-based Pfizer told employees in a memo
obtained by Bloomberg News. We recommend that BlackBerry
clients use their BlackBerry devices and plan to migrate to a
new device at normal contract expiration. </p>
<p>After years of losing customers to Apple''s iPhone and
devices running Android, BlackBerry is struggling to keep
remaining users from defecting. The new BlackBerry 10 operating
system, meant to fuel a comeback, drew a tepid response from
buyers, and the company had to write off almost $1 billion in
unsold inventory last quarter. </p>
<p>Pfizer had 92,000 employees as of its last annual filing,
making it the eighth-biggest employer among U.S. and Western
European-based health-care companies, according to data compiled
by Bloomberg. Contingency plans have been developed in case
BlackBerry shuts down or is unable to provide services, Pfizer
said in the memo. </p>
<p>We never go out in the media and talk about our service
providers, said Joan Campion, a Pfizer spokeswoman. </p>
<p>A $4.7 billion takeover bid for BlackBerry was scrapped
this month, prompting a shakeup at the company. BlackBerry
installed former Sybase Inc. Chief Executive Officer John Chen
as the head of the company and raised $1 billion in convertible
debt to help bolster its disappearing cash. </p>
<p>In a blog post on Nov. 13, Chen tried to reassure customers
that the company is not going anywhere. </p>
<p>We also want our customers to know that BlackBerry has
significant financial strength for the long-haul, he said. I
am confident that we will rebuild BlackBerry for the benefit of
all of our constituencies. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Nov 14, 2013 11:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-14/jpmorgan-twitter-hashtag-trends-against-bank.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s #AskJPM Twitter Hashtag Backfires Against Bank</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co., the target of at least eight Justice Department investigations, was mocked and taunted by Twitter users after asking followers to send questions to an executive using the hashtag #AskJPM. </p> <p>The online forum, which the bank canceled late yesterday, was intended in part to give college students an opportunity to communicate directly with a senior executive, said Brian Marchiony, a spokesman for the New York-based company. </p> <p>#Badidea! Back to the drawing board, the bank posted less than six hours after its original post, which drew more than 6,000 responses from users in that span, according to social media tracking service Topsy. The #AskJPM hashtag had more than 24,000 posts on Twitter as of 10 a.m. New York time, according to Topsy. </p> <p>If you''re in the banking industry with what''s happened over the last five years, it might not be a good idea to go out and solicit comments on social media, said Brad Adgate, a senior vice president at marketing firm Horizon Media Inc. in New York. They are paying all these fines and billions of dollars to the federal government. I question the timing of this. </p> <p>The Snarkpocalypse, as @ReformedBroker dubbed it, started after the company''s official Twitter account posted a call for questions at 1:26 p.m. in New York yesterday for investment bank Vice Chairman James Lee, using #AskJPM. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
A security guard stands next to the Twitter Inc. logo displayed in the lobby of JPMorgan Chase  Co. headquarters in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jim Brunsden" date="Nov 14, 2013  6:24 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-14/jpmorgan-gets-map-to-descend-capital-surcharge-plateau-with-hsbc.html"><headline>JPMorgan Gets Map to Descend FSB Surcharge Plateau With HSBC</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Global regulators this week put
JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) and HSBC Holdings Plc (HSBA) at the pinnacle of a
list of 29 too-big-to-fail banks that face tougher capital rules
than other lenders. The companies were also handed a map to plot
their descent. </p>
<p>For the first time since it started compiling a roster of
lenders whose collapse would threaten the global economy, the
Basel Committee on Banking Supervision also disclosed the
thresholds for how it determined the level of extra capital
requirements that such banks should face. The move will enable
lenders to find ways to move down to a lower surcharge category
or exit the list altogether. </p>
<p>The capital surcharges for globally systemic lenders add an
extra layer of safety beyond beefed-up standards known as Basel
III that emerged in the wake of the 2008 collapse of Lehman
Brothers Holdings Inc. Regulators said the additional buffers
were vital to protect taxpayers and prevent crises from
cascading through the financial system. </p>
<p>I think the Basel committee would be quite happy in this
instance for banks to change their scores by becoming smaller,
less interconnected, less complex, said Patricia Jackson, head
of prudential advisory at Ernst  Young LLP in London. It''s
also a shot across the bows in the sense that if they become
more complex, larger, relative to others they go up the list. </p>




Photographer: Chris Ratcliffe/Bloomberg

<p>
A pedestrian walks past a giant poster advertising business banking services in the window of a HSBC Holdings Plc bank branch in London. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Barinka" date="Nov 14, 2013 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-14/ibm-to-offer-jeopardy-winner-watson-as-cloud-app-tool.html"><headline>IBM to Offer Jeopardy!'' Winner Watson as Cloud App Tool</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>     Nov. 14 (Bloomberg) -- International Business Machines
Corp.''s Watson technology, famous for outsmarting humans on the
game show Jeopardy!, will be offered as a cloud-based tool
to application developers, letting them tap a resource capable
of giving everything from shopping tips to medical advice. </p>
<p>Programmers will be able to access the IBM Watson
Developers Cloud, an online marketplace with resources for
developing apps, use a content store with data from third-party
providers and get help from IBM and contracted professionals,
the Armonk, New York-based company said in a statement today. </p>
<p>There is so much more that can be accomplished by drawing
on the creativity of individuals, organizations, entrepreneurs,
startups and established businesses that truly innovate every
day on their own, said Stephen Gold, vice president of Watson
Solutions, in an interview. Watson can be this ultimate
assistant to help individuals get their questions answered and
their problems solved. </p>
<p>Opening up the Watson platform to outside developers is
IBM''s latest step to commercialize the technology as it tries to
boost revenue from cloud computing amid a decline in its
hardware business. Watson, which can answer questions after
being preloaded with documents and websites, has been deployed
in the health and finance markets since its debut on the
Jeopardy! in 2011. </p>
<h2>App Developers </h2>
<p>Application developers, from startups to established
businesses, can submit their requests to use Watson''s services
on IBM''s website beginning this week, said Lori Bosio, a
spokeswoman for the company. </p>
<p>There are no upfront cost for access and partners who use
the service in their apps will be charged on a metered usage
model, Gold said. He declined to comment on expected sales from
the service. </p>
<p>Three apps developed on the cloud-based platform are
targeted to enter the market early next year, IBM said. </p>
<p>MD Buyline, a company that provides supply-chain services
for hospitals and health-care systems, will introduce its
Hippocrates app to let clinical and financial users make real-time, informed decisions, according to the statement. </p>
<p>Fluid Inc., an e-commerce services company, will offer its
Fluid Expert Personal Shopper app to help consumers with
purchase decisions. Welltok Inc.''s CafeWell Concierge app will
combine users'' input and Watson''s ability to learn to create
personalized health plans catered to an individual''s needs. </p>
<p>The introduction of the Watson cloud service follows six
quarters of declining revenue for IBM, underpinned by slumping
sales in its hardware business. The company said it generated
more than $1 billion in revenue from cloud products and services
in the third quarter. </p>
<p>We really believe in the future opportunity it represents
in a revenue and upside perspective, Gold said of the Watson
cloud service. This is clearly IBM''s most prized possession
that we are opening up to the world. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dan Murtaugh, Lananh Nguyen and Eliot Caroom" date="Nov 15, 2013  9:46 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-15/chevron-refinery-fire-in-mississippi-leaves-one-person-dead.html"><headline>Chevron Refinery Fire in Mississippi Leaves One Person Dead</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX) had a furnace fire in
the cracking 2 area at its Pascagoula refinery in
Mississippi that caused the death of one worker. </p>
<p>The fire occurred at 2 a.m. local time at the 330,000-barrel-a-day plant on Mississippi''s Gulf Coast, Kurt Glaubitz, a
San Ramon, California-based spokesman for the company, said in
an e-mailed statement. </p>
<p>The cracking 2 unit has been shut, Terry Jackson, Jackson
County deputy director of emergency services, said by phone. The
rest of the refinery isn''t shut, he said. </p>
<p>Refinery personnel responded to the fire and secured the
site, Glaubitz said. He wouldn''t say if the fire has been
extinguished, nor whether any portion of the refinery has been
shut down in response. Allison Cook, a Pascagoula-based
spokeswoman for the company, identified the location of the fire
in a message on a community hot line. </p>
<p>The refinery produces 130,000 barrels of gasoline, 68,000
barrels of diesel and 50,000 barrels of jet fuel a day,
according to a company website. It also produces bunker fuel,
liquefied petroleum gases and other products. </p>
<p>The plant processes heavy, high-sulfur crude. In August, it
imported 278,000 barrels of oil a day from Brazil, Canada,
Colombia, Mexico and Venezuela. Two of its shipments from
Colombia were the highest-density crudes imported to the U.S.
that month, according to Energy Information Administration data. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki and Tom Schoenberg" date="Nov 18, 2013  6:57 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-18/jpmorgan-said-to-agree-to-cover-some-wamu-costs-on-mortgage-deal.html"><headline>JPMorgan Said to Agree to Cover WaMu Costs on Mortgage Deal</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) agreed to drop
litigation against the Federal Deposit Insurance Corp. over some
mortgage bonds sold by Washington Mutual Inc., clearing the way
for a $9 billion accord with state and federal officials, two
people briefed on the matter said. </p>
<p>The settlement will be announced tomorrow, said one of the
people, requesting anonymity because the negotiations aren''t
public. JPMorgan, the largest U.S. lender by assets, agreed
today to the terms of $4 billion in consumer relief payments,
the person said. The remaining $5 billion will go toward
penalties and resolving claims. </p>
<p>The bank battled with the FDIC over who should pay some
liabilities from WaMu, the failed Seattle thrift that the agency
placed into receivership in 2008 while selling assets to New
York-based JPMorgan. </p>
<p>The agreement, which is being brokered by the Justice
Department, won''t interfere with JPMorgan''s ability to sue the
FDIC to cover part of a $4 billion settlement last month with
the Federal Housing Finance Agency, two people familiar with the
matter said. </p>
<p>It also won''t prohibit the bank from seeking reimbursement
from the FDIC for claims against WaMu from private investors,
they said. JPMorgan announced a tentative $4.5 billion deal last
week with 21 institutional investors, including Pacific
Investment Management Co., to settle claims that the lender and
its subsidiaries sold faulty mortgage bonds. </p>
<h2>Attorneys General </h2>
<p>The $9 billion settlement, which includes a $2 billion
fine, will end civil investigations by the Justice Department
and the California and New York state attorneys general, as well
as lawsuits by the FDIC and National Credit Union
Administration, people briefed on the talks said. </p>
<p>Andrew Gray, a spokesman for the FDIC, JPMorgan''s Brian Marchiony and Brian Fallon at the Justice Department said they
couldn''t comment because the negotiations are confidential. </p>
<p>The consumer-relief portion of the accord, negotiated over
the weekend by Associate Attorney General Tony West and U.S.
Housing and Urban Development Secretary Shaun Donovan, requires
JPMorgan to hire an independent monitor and provide the entire
$4 billion by the end of 2016, one of the people said. </p>
<p>JPMorgan''s costs include at least $1.5 billion in principal
writedowns for struggling homeowners with federally backed
loans, the person said. Of that, $1.2 billion would be for first
lien principal writedowns. At least $300 million must go toward
forbearance, in which banks shift loan terms to account for a
change in a debtor''s income, the person said. </p>
<h2>Vacant Homes </h2>
<p>An additional $2 billion would fund interest-rate
reductions of existing loans, new loans or loan originations
that JPMorgan would be required to keep in its portfolio, the
person said. The bank also would receive credit for so-called
anti-blight efforts, such as the costs of demolishing vacant
homes and absorbing the mortgages of such properties the bank
has yet to foreclose on, the person said. </p>
<p>If JPMorgan doesn''t provide the entire $4 billion by the
end of 2016 then the bank would be required to pay any leftover
portion to the government or a nonprofit, the person said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Schoenberg" date="Nov 18, 2013  6:19 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-18/jpmorgan-u-s-said-to-announce-13-billion-settlement-tomorrow.html"><headline>JPMorgan, U.S. Said to Announce $13 Billion Settlement Tomorrow</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) and the U.S.
Justice Department will announce tomorrow a $13 billion
settlement to resolve civil probes into the bank''s sale of
mortgage bonds, a person familiar with the matter said. A
portion of the total proposed settlement was resolved earlier
with the Federal Housing Finance Agency. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Nov 18, 2013  3:39 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-18/goldman-said-to-draw-interest-in-metro-warehousing-unit.html"><headline>Goldman Said to Draw Interest in Metro Warehousing Unit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc., which
bought aluminum warehouse firm Metro International Trade
Services LLC in 2010, has received inquiries from potential
buyers after the London Metal Exchange imposed new rules on how
storage facilities operate, a person briefed on the matter said. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs hasn''t engaged in a formal sale process, said
the person, who requested anonymity because the talks are
private and didn''t identify the prospective purchasers. Gary Cohn, president of the New York-based company, told CNBC in July
that it was allowed to own Metro for 10 years and that it would
sell the business at an appropriate time. </p>
<p>The LME, the world''s biggest industrial-metals marketplace,
changed its rules earlier this month to speed up withdrawals
from warehoused stockpiles amid consumer complaints that
prompted scrutiny from U.S. regulators. The changes will affect
depots where waiting times exceed 50 calendar days, a broader
group than the original proposal that pertained to sites where
waits were longer than 100 days. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs received interest from private-equity firms
and international commodity companies in potentially buying
Metro after the rule change eliminated some uncertainty in the
warehouse industry, the person said. The bank, the fifth-biggest
in the U.S. by assets, may not pursue a sale in the near future,
the person said. </p>




Photographer: Jason Alden/Bloomberg

<p>
The London Metal Exchange, the world''s biggest industrial-metals marketplace, changed its rules earlier this month to speed up withdrawals from warehoused stockpiles amid consumer complaints that prompted scrutiny from U.S. regulators. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Stephanie Bodoni" date="Nov 18, 2013  3:35 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-18/microsoft-skype-cleared-of-nsa-data-violations-by-luxembourg.html"><headline>Microsoft, Skype Cleared of NSA Data Violations by Luxembourg</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) and its Skype unit
were cleared of privacy violations related to the U.S. spying
scandal by a Luxembourg regulator that said the companies didn''t
provide widespread data access to the U.S. National Security
Agency. </p>
<p>The Luxembourg data protection regulator''s probe concluded
that the transfer of some data to affiliate companies in the
U.S. appear to take place lawfully under a so-called safe
harbor agreement, according to a statement by the watchdog
today. </p>
<p>The regulator conducted the investigation because the
companies have their European headquarters in the country. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Schoenberg, Dawn Kopecki and Laurie Asseo" date="Nov 19, 2013  5:47 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-19/jpmorgan-settlement-announced-by-u-s-justice-department-1-.html"><headline>JPMorgan Reaches Record $13 Billion Mortgage Settlement</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) will pay a record $13 billion to resolve U.S. Justice Department probes into the bank''s sale of mortgage bonds that officials said helped feed the financial chaos of 2008. </p> <p>The accord settles allegations that JPMorgan, the biggest U.S. lender by assets, misled investors and the public when it sold bonds backed by faulty residential mortgages, according to Justice Department statement today. U.S. and state officials blamed the bank''s actions in the statement for helping to cause the credit crisis, and said the settlement doesn''t shield JPMorgan or its employees from criminal charges. </p> <p>Without a doubt, the conduct uncovered in this investigation helped sow the seeds of the mortgage meltdown, Attorney General Eric Holder said in the statement. JPMorgan was not the only financial institution during this period to knowingly bundle toxic loans and sell them to unsuspecting investors, but that is no excuse for the firm''s behavior. </p> <p>Jamie Dimon, JPMorgan''s chief executive officer, said in a separate statement that the settlement resolves a significant portion of claims tied to mortgage-backed securities issued by the lender and two firms it bought during the credit crisis, Bear Stearns Cos. and Washington Mutual Inc.''s bank unit. The sum is covered by reserves, and JPMorgan is cooperating with the Justice Department''s criminal case, the bank said. </p>




Photographer: Victor J. Blue/Bloomberg

<p>
JPMorgan Chase  Co. still faces probes by the U.S. Justice Department that include its energy-trading business, recruiting practices in Asia and its relationship with convicted Ponzi scheme operator Bernard Madoff. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Cathy Chan" date="Nov 19, 2013  1:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-19/jpmorgan-said-to-exit-everbright-bank-offering-amid-u-s-probes.html"><headline>JPMorgan Said to Quit Everbright Bank Offering Amid Probe</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. ended plans to manage China Everbright Bank Co.''s Hong Kong share sale amid a U.S. investigation into the Wall Street firm''s hiring practices in China, two people with knowledge of the matter said. </p> <p>The U.S. bank told Everbright it would quit the deal, which at $2 billion would be the largest first-time offering by a Chinese lender in Hong Kong since 2009, because the probe delayed an internal approval process, the people said. They asked not to be identified because the matter is confidential. Brian Marchiony, a JPMorgan spokesman, declined to comment. </p> <p>U.S. authorities are examining whether New York-based JPMorgan violated anti-bribery laws by hiring the children and other relatives of well-connected politicians and clients in China so that their family members would steer business to the firm, a person with knowledge of the investigation said in August. JPMorgan said it was cooperating with the probes. </p> <p>The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission in May requested records from JPMorgan concerning Tang Xiaoning, the son of China Everbright Group Chairman Tang Shuangning, the New York Times reported in August, citing a confidential government document. </p> <p>Related News:</p>




Photographer: Victor J. Blue/Bloomberg

<p>
U.S. authorities are examining whether New York-based JPMorgan Chase  Co. violated anti-bribery laws by hiring the children and other relatives of well-connected politicians and clients in China so that their family members would steer business to the firm. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Agnieszka Troszkiewicz" date="Nov 19, 2013  7:10 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-19/jpmorgan-s-henry-bath-profit-fell-to-2-4-million-on-taxes-1-.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Henry Bath Profit Fell to $2.4 Million on Taxes</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Henry Bath  Son Ltd., the
commodities warehouse unit of JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) that it wants
to sell, reported profit of $2.4 million last year as revenue
jumped 24 percent. </p>
<p>Profit dropped from $27.7 million a year earlier due to tax
changes, Liverpool, England-based Henry Bath said in a filing
with the U.K.''s Companies House. Before taxes, profit rose to
$42.57 million from $34.19 million. Revenue rose to $148.96
million from $120.28 million. The company provides storage for
cocoa, coffee and metal stockpiles. </p>
<p>Stock holdings have continued to grow through 2012,
resulting in a positive impact on the group profits, Henry
Bath said in the filing. It had net assets of $311.9 million. </p>
<p>JPMorgan, the biggest U.S. bank, said in July that it plans
to get out of the business of owning and trading physical
commodities. The firm could sell or spin off holdings that
include Henry Bath, as well as stakes in power plants and
traders in materials such as gas and coal. The New York-based
firm has sought $3.3 billion for the division, a person with
direct knowledge of the sale process said last month. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kiel Porter and Sabrina Willmer" date="Nov 19, 2013 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-19/jpmorgan-said-in-talks-to-sell-4-billion-private-equity.html"><headline>JPMorgan May Sell $4 Billion of Private-Equity Stakes</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co., which is planning to break off its buyout unit, is in talks to sell about $4 billion of private-equity stakes to an investor group, said three people familiar with the situation. </p> <p>The potential buyers examining the holdings include Canada Pension Plan Investment Board, Coller Capital Ltd., Lexington Partners, HarbourVest Partners LLC, Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and Ardian, said two of the people. They asked not to be named because the talks are private. </p> <p>The investor group would also provide capital for new deals to One Equity Partners, the private-equity arm of JPMorgan that''s in the process of becoming an independent firm. The business, which used to invest the bank''s own money, will begin raising its next fund from an external group of investors, the bank said in June. JPMorgan joins banks including Credit Suisse Group AG and Citigroup Inc. in cutting back private-equity holdings to focus on its main businesses. </p> <p>Tasha Pelio, a spokeswoman for JPMorgan, declined to comment, as did officials for the investment firms. </p> <p>Citigroup, the third-biggest U.S. lender, agreed in September to sell its emerging-markets private-equity unit to the Rohatyn Group to comply with new curbs on bank investments. Credit Suisse, Switzerland''s second-biggest bank, in February struck a deal to sell its stake in the first fund of Global Infrastructure Partners to Lexington Partners Inc., according to a person with knowledge of the matter. The bank in August agreed to sell its private-equity, infrastructure and real estate investment business to Grosvenor Capital Management LP. </p>




Photographer: Victor J. Blue/Bloomberg

<p>
The JPMorgan Chase  Co. logo is displayed at the company''s offices in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Nov 20, 2013  6:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-20/morgan-stanley-said-in-discussions-to-sell-oil-unit-to-rosneft.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Said in Discussions to Sell Oil Unit to Rosneft</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) is in talks to sell
its global oil business to OAO Rosneft (ROSN), Russia''s largest
petroleum producer, a person briefed on the discussions said. </p>
<p>The talks are in early stages and a deal may not be
reached, said the person, who asked not to be identified because
the matter is private. The bank hasn''t discussed selling its
entire commodities unit to Rosneft and may remain in some oil
derivative businesses even with a sale, the person said. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley Chief Executive Officer James Gorman has
been exploring options for the commodities business for more
than a year as the unit faces lower revenue and scrutiny from
regulators who are reviewing banks'' activities in the sector.
Gorman, 55, also has been trying to shrink the amount of capital
dedicated to the fixed-income and commodity division in his
quest to boost the bank''s return on equity. </p>
<p>Mary Claire Delaney, a spokeswoman for the New York-based
bank, declined to comment, as did a spokeswoman for Moscow-based
Rosneft, who couldn''t be identified due to company policy.
SparkSpread, an online energy publication, reported the talks
Nov. 19. </p>
<p>State-run Rosneft became the world''s largest publicly
traded oil producer by volume after completing the $55 billion
purchase of TNK-BP, Russia''s third-biggest producer, in March.
Rosneft is also boosting its natural gas business by acquiring a
stake in the SeverEnergia venture and assets from OAO Alrosa and
Itera. </p>




Photographer: Alexander Zemlianichenko Jr./Bloomberg

<p>
A Russian orthodox church is seen beyond fuel pumps at a gas station operated by OAO Rosneft, Russia''s biggest oil producer, in Moscow. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bob Van Voris and Susan Decker" date="Nov 20, 2013  5:11 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-20/microsoft-claims-acacia-patent-suits-breach-licensing-pact.html"><headline>Microsoft Claims Acacia Patent Suits Breach Licensing Pact</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp., (MSFT) the world''s largest
software maker, filed a lawsuit today claiming patent-licensing
firm Acacia Research Corp. breached a contract between the two
companies. </p>
<p>The complaint was filed today under seal in federal court
in Manhattan and a public copy wasn''t available. </p>
<p>Acacia, which buys patents to generate a profit from
licensing revenue, filed seven lawsuits last month against
Microsoft in Delaware, Illinois and Texas. In the past, the two
companies have reached agreements, including a 2011 deal over e-mail messaging and one in 2010 over patents for smartphone
technology. </p>
<p>Acacia''s lawsuits are the worst kind of abusive
litigation behavior, attempting to extract payment based on
litigation tactics and not the value of its patents, Microsoft
Deputy General Counsel David Howard said in a statement. </p>
<p>Acacia, which reported $115.5 million in sales for the
first three quarters, doesn''t sue in its own name, though it has
filed hundreds of lawsuits. Instead, it forms a unit to handle a
specific portfolio and then the unit -- named for the technology
it covers -- files the suits. In its annual report, the Newport
Beach, California-based company said it had 143 technology
licensing programs. </p>
<p>The lawsuits filed in October against Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft include one for light-emitting panel assemblies
and another for a way to control the use of licensed software. </p>
<p>Adam Handelsman, a spokesman or Acacia, had no immediate
comment on the suit. </p>
<h2>Troll Suits </h2>
<p>The Government Accountability Office found that 19 percent
of all patent lawsuits filed between 2007 and 2011 were by
companies often derided as trolls, whose sole business is to buy
up patents and then demand royalties. With changes in
legislation that limited the number of defendants in a single
suit, that number increased even more in 2012. </p>
<p>Congress is considering proposals that would limit some
litigation practices by patent-licensing firms. The provisions
being considered include a requirement that patent owners
provide more details about both what the patent covers and how
its infringed, disclose who benefits financially from the
litigation, and make the loser in a case pay the winner''s legal
costs. </p>
<p>The case is Microsoft Corp. v. Acacia Research Corp. (ACTG), 13-cv-8275, U.S. District Court, Southern District of New York
(Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Nov 20, 2013  1:51 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-20/morgan-stanley-said-to-discuss-selling-oil-unit.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Said to Discuss Selling Oil Unit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) is in talks to sell
its global oil business to OAO Rosneft (ROSN), Russia''s largest
petroleum producer, a person briefed on the discussions said. </p>
<p>The talks are in early stages and a deal may not be
reached, said the person, who asked not to be identified because
the matter is private. The bank hasn''t discussed selling its
entire commodities unit to Moscow-based Rosneft and may remain
in some oil derivative businesses even with a sale, the person
said. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley Chief Executive Officer James Gorman has
been exploring options for the commodities business for more
than a year as the unit faces lower revenue and scrutiny from
regulators who are reviewing banks'' activities in the sector.
Gorman, 55, also has been trying to shrink the amount of capital
dedicated to the fixed-income and commodity division in his
quest to boost the bank''s return on equity. </p>
<p>Mary Claire Delaney, a spokeswoman for the New York-based
bank, declined to comment, as did a spokeswoman for Rosneft, who
couldn''t be identified due to company policy. SparkSpread, an
online energy publication, reported the talks yesterday. </p>
<p>State-run Rosneft became the world''s largest publicly
traded oil producer by volume after completing the $55 billion
purchase of TNK-BP, Russia''s third-biggest producer, in March.
Rosneft is also boosting its natural gas business by acquiring a
stake in the SeverEnergia venture and assets from OAO Alrosa and
Itera. </p>




Photographer: Alexander Zemlianichenko Jr./Bloomberg

<p>
State-run Rosneft became the world''s largest publicly traded oil producer by volume after completing the $55 billion purchase of TNK-BP, Russia''s third-biggest producer, in March. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lisa Abramowicz" date="Nov 20, 2013 12:11 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-20/morgan-stanley-hires-corporate-bond-trader-driscoll-from-nomura.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Hires Corporate-Bond Trader Driscoll From Nomura</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) hired Daniel Driscoll
from Nomura Holdings Inc. to trade investment-grade notes for
the fourth-most active manager of the debt in the U.S. </p>
<p>Driscoll, who ran financial-debt trading at Credit Suisse
Group AG in the U.S. before leaving last year, will join Morgan
Stanley''s New York office as a managing director, according to
Mark Lake, a spokesman for the firm. Driscoll didn''t respond to
a message left on his mobile phone seeking comment. </p>
<p>Driscoll worked for Japan''s largest brokerage for about a
year after a decade-long career at Credit Suisse, where he
focused on both investment-grade and high-yield bank bonds. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley, the sixth-biggest U.S. bank by assets, has
managed 9.4 percent of investment-grade bond sales in the U.S.
this year, up from 8.2 percent last year, according to data
compiled by Bloomberg that excludes deals in which banks manage
their own offerings. Companies have sold $1.07 trillion of the
debentures in 2013, 3.9 percent more than what had been issued
by this time in 2012, when a record $1.12 trillion of the debt
was sold, Bloomberg data show. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley ranks behind JPMorgan Chase  Co., Bank of
America Corp. and Citigroup Inc. in bond deals managed. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jeanna Smialek" date="Nov 20, 2013 11:31 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-20/goldman-says-5-5-jobless-best-to-boost-participation.html"><headline>Goldman Says 5.5% Jobless Best to Boost Participation</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The Federal Reserve should lower its jobless-rate threshold for raising interest rates to 5.5 percent if it takes both the unemployment and participation rates into account, keeping its main interest rate lower for longer, according to Goldman Sachs Group Inc. research. </p> <p>The analysis updates a study Goldman Sachs published earlier this month by factoring in the labor force participation rate rather than simply addressing unemployment. </p> <p>Taking into account adverse supply side effects -- by aiming to normalize both the unemployment and participation rates -- strengthens the case for lowering the 6.5 percent unemployment threshold, economists led by Jan Hatzius say in the note written by Sven Jari Stehn and dated Nov. 19. Our small model suggests that the most desirable unemployment threshold in this case would be around 5.5 percent. </p> <p>The study builds on papers presented by Fed officials earlier in November. William English, head of the Division of Monetary Affairs, wrote that the strategy of not raising interest rates if unemployment is above 6.5 percent has provided useful stimulus and suggested an even lower threshold could be effective. David Wilcox, the research and statistics chief, argued for loose policy amid contained inflation expectations and high labor slack, noting that participation appears to have moved noticeably lower. </p> <p>Goldman''s previous analysis, which looked at English''s work, found that a threshold of 6 percent would deliver the best combination of a stronger recovery and modest inflation. The update takes into account the supply side mechanisms of the Wilcox paper, the economists wrote. </p> <p>If the Fed tried to address the entire employment picture by taking into account a measure of the so-called participation gap, the Fed''s policy rate would be on hold until mid-2016, they found. In that case, a 5.5 percent jobless rate threshold is best, the Goldman Sachs economists wrote. </p> <p>Our analysis suggests that taking into account that weak aggregate demand might have adverse effects on labor supply strengthens the case for lowering the 6.5% unemployment threshold, they said in the paper. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrea Tan" date="Nov 20, 2013 11:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-20/goldman-seeks-to-halt-singapore-tycoon-yen-real-lawsuit.html"><headline>Goldman Seeks to Halt Singapore Tycoon Yen-Real Lawsuit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A Goldman Sachs Group Inc. unit asked a court to halt Singapore tycoon Oei Hong Leong''s lawsuit over losses after he was allegedly misled into making leveraged trades that the yen would fall against the Brazilian real. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs International said in a Nov. 6 filing with the Singapore High Court that proceedings should be suspended in favor of private and confidential arbitration. Court papers detailing reasons aren''t publicly accessible. A closed hearing is scheduled for tomorrow. </p> <p>Oei, who in 2009 settled a claim against Citigroup Inc. over S$1 billion ($804 million) in trading losses, accused Goldman Sachs in his Sept. 20 lawsuit of making fraudulent representations that the real was a stable and liquid currency anchored to the U.S. dollar. He''s seeking $31.7 million in trading losses, plus interest. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs will defend Oei''s lawsuit, which is without merit, Hong Kong-based spokesman Edward Naylor said yesterday. </p> <p>Oei will challenge Goldman Sachs''s arbitration bid, his lawyer, Siraj Omar, said. </p> <p>Mr. Oei''s position is that the Singapore court is the proper place to decide the claim, especially since the misrepresentation that he is complaining about occurred in Singapore, Omar said. He sees no basis for moving this to confidential arbitration in London. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
Singapore tycoon Oei Hong Leong has been a Goldman Sachs client since 2001. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hugh Son, Zachary Tracer, Tom Schoenberg and Laurie Asseo" date="Nov 20, 2013  9:39 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-20/jpmorgan-13-billion-mortgage-deal-seen-as-lawsuit-shield.html"><headline>JPMorgan $13 Billion Mortgage Deal Seen as Lawsuit Shield</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s record $13
billion deal to end probes into mortgage-bond sales may save the
bank billions more because of what the agreement lacked: an
explicit admission of wrongdoing. </p>
<p>Employees of JPMorgan and two firms it acquired knew some
of the loans included in bonds didn''t meet underwriting
standards, a fact not shared with buyers of those securities,
the U.S. Justice Department said yesterday in a statement. That
doesn''t mean the company misled investors, said Chief Financial
Officer Marianne Lake, disputing how some state and federal
officials characterized the deal. </p>
<p>JPMorgan, the biggest U.S. bank, sought to end one of the
largest legal uncertainties it faced without providing fodder to
private litigants. The firm is still the subject of Justice
Department probes into its energy-trading business, recruiting
practices in Asia and its relationship with Ponzi scheme
operator Bernard Madoff. </p>
<p>They''ve left themselves some wiggle room to say, No we
didn''t violate the law'', said Peter Henning, a former federal
prosecutor and Securities and Exchange Commission attorney who
teaches law at Wayne State University in Detroit. There is at
least some acknowledgment that there were improprieties, but
exactly what they were remains open, and certainly they can deny
it in any specific case. </p>




Photographer: Peter Foley/Bloomberg

<p>
A man exits a JPMorgan Chase  Co. office in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Charles Stein" date="Nov 20, 2013 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-20/morgan-stanley-wins-as-lynch-pays-up-riskless-return.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Wins as Lynch Pays Up: Riskless Return</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley''s Dennis Lynch looks for small companies he can buy and hold for years as they grow into bigger businesses -- a search that has led to investments from Pandora Media Inc. to Twitter Inc. Sometimes he is willing to pay prices that look expensive by traditional measures. </p> <p>Lynch''s picks made the $2.2 billion Morgan Stanley Institutional Fund Inc. - Small Company Growth Portfolio the top performer among U.S. stock funds over the past year on a risk-adjusted basis, according to the BLOOMBERG RISKLESS RETURN RANKING. The fund surged 69 percent in the year ended Nov. 18 for the highest absolute return among 686 equity funds with at least $1 billion in assets, helping to offset above-average volatility. </p> <p>Lynch, who invested in Facebook Inc. and Twitter when they were still private companies, said companies in their early stages with room to grow can command multiples of earnings and cash flow far above the norm for established firms. The Morgan Stanley fund has invested in Internet radio station Pandora and real estate data provider Zillow Inc., which sell for estimated price-to-earnings multiples of more than 900. The trick is to compare the current price to what businesses could earn five years into the future, assuming they realize their potential, Lynch said. </p> <p>It may look like you are paying a lot at the time, but if a company has a large enough potential you may look back and find you got in at a cheap entry point, Lynch said in a telephone interview from New York, where he is based. </p> <p>The stocks in the Morgan Stanley fund trade at an average of 113 times earnings and a price-to-cash flow ratio of 26, compared with 49 and 18 for the Russell 2000 Growth Index, a benchmark for small-capitalization growth-oriented companies, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p> <h2>Pandora, Zillow </h2> <p>Shares of Oakland, California-based Pandora sell at an estimated 958 times earnings, and Seattle-based Zillow trades at an estimated price-to-earnings multiple of about 2029, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. Pandora and Zillow shares have more than tripled in the year ended Nov. 19. </p> <p>Bloomberg''s risk-adjusted return is calculated by dividing total return by volatility or the degree of daily price-swing variation, giving a measure of income per unit risk. The returns aren''t annualized. </p> <p>Morgan Stanley''s small-cap fund produced a risk-adjusted return of 4.6 percent in the year ended Nov. 18. Its volatility was 15.1, compared with 13.5 for the peer group. Lynch said he doesn''t target low volatility, citing Warren Buffett''s saying that large, lumpy returns beat smaller, smoother gains. </p> <h2>Stomach-Churning'' </h2> <p>While acknowledging Lynch''s strong long-term returns, Janet Yang, an analyst for Chicago-based Morningstar Inc., wrote in a note last month that shareholders have had to endure some stomach-churning periods of performance to get there. </p> <p>The fund lost 42 percent in 2008, trailing 60 percent of peers, and 9.1 percent in 2011, behind 91 percent of rivals, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. The fund gained 28 percent on an annualized basis over past five years to beat 89 percent of peers, and returned 9.8 percent when adjusted for volatility over the same stretch, the data show. </p> <p>The $4.6 billion Primecap Odyssey Aggressive Growth Fund gained an adjusted 4.2 percent over the past year, with the second-highest total return and above-average volatility. The $1.2 billion Teton Westwood Mighty Mites Fund, which ranked third, combined higher-than-average returns with lower-than average volatility. </p> <h2>Growth Team </h2> <p>Lynch, 43, runs the growth team at New York-based Morgan Stanley Investment Management, a 17-member group within the bank''s money-management unit that oversees $30.3 billion in stocks of all market values. Lynch''s group also runs Morgan Stanley Institutional Fund Trust-Mid Cap Growth Portfolio, which beat 87 percent of peers over the past five years and the Morgan Stanley Focus Growth Fund, which invests in large-cap stocks and beat 98 percent of rivals over the same period, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p> <p>Morgan Stanley''s small-company growth fund owns less than half as many stocks as the typical small cap growth fund and has lower fund turnover, trading its stocks about one-fourth as often as peers, Morningstar data show. </p> <p>Lynch''s largest holding as of Sept. 30, Corporate Executive Board Co., has been in the portfolio for more than a decade. The firm, which sells research on best practices to large companies, has many of the qualities Lynch looks for in his investments: it dominates a niche market, it can grow at a good pace over time and has what he considers a sustainable competitive edge. In this case, that advantage is the relationship Arlington, Virginia-based Corporate Executive Board has built up with Fortune 500 companies over time. </p> <h2>Spinoff Strategy </h2> <p>That is a powerful network effect you couldn''t easily duplicate, said Lynch. </p> <p>Corporate Executive Board and Lynch''s second-largest holding, Advisory Board Co., a Washington-based company that provides similar research to the health-care industry, were both spinoffs of the same private company. Lynch calls spinoffs a good place to go fishing, because they aren''t always well-scrutinized by other investors. </p> <p>The biggest contributor to the fund''s performance over the past year, according to data compiled by Bloomberg, is another company that was split of from a bigger company: Fiesta Restaurant Group Inc. Fiesta, which is based in Addison, Texas, broke off in 2012 from a company that owned Burger King Worldwide Inc. franchises. </p> <h2>Pollo Tropical </h2> <p>Fiesta has two restaurant chains, one of which, Pollo Tropical, has the potential to grow much larger, said Lynch. Fiesta shares have more than tripled in the past year. The stock sells for a price-to-earnings ratio of 87, compared with a ratio of 34 for the Russell 2000 Growth Index. </p> <p>Lynch isn''t concerned. Investors, he said, are often put off by the high prices commanded by early-stage retailers and restaurants without appreciating how big the companies can become down the road. Chipotle Mexican Grill Inc., throughout its history, has sold at higher price-to-earnings ratios than rivals, he said. </p> <p>Knowing what we know today it probably should have traded at multiples so high they would have seemed absurd at the time, said Lynch. </p> <p>Chipotle shares have climbed about 13-fold in the past five years. The stock currently trades at a multiple of 54 times earnings. </p> <h2>Avoiding Biotechnology </h2> <p>The Morgan Stanley fund has a heavier concentration of consumer discretionary and information-technology stocks than its benchmark index, data compiled by Bloomberg show. Lynch said the many Internet stocks in the portfolio shouldn''t be thought of as a bet on a particularly industry. The firms have different business models and compete in different businesses. </p> <p>What they share is that they use the Internet to disrupt industries, said Lynch. </p> <p>Lynch''s funds invested in Facebook of Menlo Park, California, and in San Francisco-based Twitter when they were still private companies, according to Morningstar''s Yang. Facebook has gained 74 percent this year; Twitter has gained 61 percent since going public this month. </p> <p>The small-cap fund has fewer health-care stocks than the benchmark index and very few early-stage biotechnology firms, said Lynch. While he is comfortable owning volatile stocks, biotech shares represent a different sort of risk. </p> <p>Biotech is tricky, he said. We don''t like the fact that in one day the business can change and you may have to take a significant loss. </p> <p>Lynch said he doesn''t invest based on any particular view of the economy or the stock market, reasoning that trying to add value that way won''t work. </p> <p>What we try to do is identify companies in which we have confidence, regardless of what happens to the economy, he said. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Schoenberg" date="Nov 21, 2013  4:36 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-21/jpmorgan-deal-offers-turning-point-for-attorney-general-holder.html"><headline>JPMorgan Deal Offers Turning Point for Eric Holder</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The Justice Department''s $13 billion
mortgage securities settlement with JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) is a
record and also a rarity -- Attorney General Eric Holder''s first
big win against a bank at the heart of 2008''s financial crisis. </p>
<p>For Holder, the part of the deal announced this week that
requires the bank to pay $9 billion to resolve allegations it
knowingly sold bad mortgage securities is a potential turning
point after a tenure studded with controversy. </p>
<p>Several more announcements are on the way to bring
financial institutions to account, Holder has said. </p>
<p>You have to wait until we are finished with all the work
that we will do, Holder said in an interview. When we get to
that point you will see that we have taken the mandate that we
were given seriously, that we held people accountable, that we
held institutions accountable. </p>
<p>The JPMorgan deal has its critics. Some say it''s too tough
on the bank after the government called it in to take over Bear
Stearns Cos. and Washington Mutual Bank when they failed. Others
say Holder hasn''t gone far enough, because he hasn''t brought
criminal charges against bankers. Several lawmakers and others
have faulted the deal for leaving open the possibility that the
bank could write off a portion of the penalties, essentially
passing some of the burden to taxpayers. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
Attorney General Eric Holder said, You have to wait until we are finished with all the work that we will do, Holder said in an interview. When we get to that point you will see that we have taken the mandate that we were given seriously, that we held people accountable, that we held institutions accountable. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Nov 21, 2013  4:13 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-21/goldman-sachs-says-currency-unit-didn-t-post-third-quarter-loss.html"><headline>Goldman Says Currency Unit Didn''t Post Third-Quarter Loss</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc., the Wall
Street firm with the biggest revenue decline last quarter, said
its currency trading business didn''t incur a loss in the period
as the bank sought to clarify a figure in a regulatory filing. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs did not suffer a loss in our currencies
business in the third quarter, Michael DuVally, a spokesman
for the New York-based bank, said today in an e-mailed
statement. Gains or losses in one product type frequently
offset gains or losses in other product types. </p>
<p>Reuters reported earlier today that the bank posted more
than $1 billion in market-making losses on currency products in
the third quarter, citing U.S. Securities and Exchange
Commission and Federal Reserve filings. Goldman Sachs said in
its quarterly SEC filing on Nov. 7 that the figure isn''t 
representative of how it manages the business. </p>
<p>The filing discloses market-making revenue from different
products. Each product''s revenue can include gains or losses
that are booked in another business, such as a commodity deal
that''s hedged with currency swaps. The figure also excludes
trading commissions and net interest income. </p>
<h2>Mortgages, Commodities </h2>
<p>Earlier this year, the SEC asked Goldman Sachs to disclose
how much products such as mortgages and commodities contribute
to its trading revenue to give investors more clarity on how the
firm makes most of its money. The SEC completed its review after
the firm responded that it would give more qualitative
disclosure and already had provided the market-making figures
by product. </p>




Photographer: Jin Lee/Bloomberg

<p>
Goldman Sachs did not suffer a loss in our currencies business in the third quarter, Michael DuVally, a spokesman for the New York-based bank, said today in an e-mailed statement. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Phoebe Sedgman" date="Nov 21, 2013  8:58 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-21/goldman-predicts-significant-losses-for-gold-iron-ore-in-2014.html"><headline>Goldman Sees at Least 15% Losses for Gold, Iron Ore</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Gold, iron ore, soybeans and copper will probably drop at least 15 percent next year as commodities face increased downside risks even as economic growth in the U.S. accelerates, according to Goldman Sachs Group Inc. </p> <p>The risks are strongest for iron ore and follow increases in supplies, analysts including Jeffrey Currie wrote in a report yesterday that identified the New York-based bank''s top 10 market themes for the coming year. Price pressures will mostly become visible later in 2014, the analysts wrote, forecasting that bullion, copper and soybeans will decline to the lowest levels since 2010. </p> <p>Commodities tracked by the Standard  Poor''s GSCI Index lost 4.7 percent this year, led by corn as supplies surged, and precious metals on expectations the Federal Reserve will taper stimulus. Goldman described the forecast losses for iron ore, gold, soybeans and copper as significant, and said that they could help weaken currencies in producing countries, including the Australian dollar and South African rand. </p> <p>Last year, we pointed to the ongoing shift in our commodity views, ultimately towards downside price risk, the analysts including Currie wrote. The impact of supply responses to the period of extraordinary price pressure continues to flow through the system. </p>




Photographer: Guenter Schiffmann/Bloomberg

<p>
Gold bars weighing one kilogram each sit on a table in the vault of gold vendor ProAurum in Munich. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Adam Ewing" date="Nov 21, 2013  4:21 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-21/microsoft-to-take-over-nokia-s-landmark-headquarters.html"><headline>Microsoft to Take Over Nokia''s Landmark Headquarters</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. will take over Nokia
Oyj (NOK1V)''s glass-walled headquarters, one of Finland''s best-known
buildings, once the software giant''s deal to buy the Finnish
company''s mobile-phone business is completed. </p>
<p>Nokia will move to a location further away from central
Helsinki, to a campus where its network-equipment business is
based, James Etheridge, a spokesman for the Finnish company,
said today in an e-mailed statement. </p>
<p>Microsoft gains occupancy of a landmark complex whose
construction in the 1990s symbolized Nokia''s rise into Finland''s
first major global corporation. The building, just outside
Helsinki in Espoo, is by the shore and offers expansive views to
the Baltic Sea from its meeting rooms. It is situated on a busy
highway between Finland''s two biggest cities and is seen by tens
of thousands of commuters every day. </p>
<p>The Karaportti campus, where Nokia will move, is further
inland in Espoo and resembles more of a traditional industrial
estate. </p>
<p>Nokia''s shareholders agreed this week to sell its device
unit to Microsoft in a 5.44 billion-euro ($7.3 billion) deal.
The majority of workers in the current head office, which Nokia
sold last year and leased back to cut costs, work for the unit
to be acquired by Microsoft. Nokia is renovating a building at
the Karaportti campus for its future use, Etheridge said. </p>




Photographer: Henrik Kettunen/Bloomberg

<p>
Microsoft gains occupancy of a landmark complex whose construction in the 1990s symbolized Nokia''s rise into Finland''s first major global corporation. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Terje Langeland and Marco Lui" date="Nov 21, 2013 12:23 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-21/cocaine-worth-4-8-billion-yen-found-on-japan-beach-asahi.html"><headline>Cocaine Worth 4.8 Billion Yen Found on Japan Beach, Asahi</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Four backpacks stuffed with cocaine
worth 4.8 billion yen ($48 million) were found on a beach in
Japan, the biggest amount ever discovered in the country, local
media reported. </p>
<p>The backpacks, containing 80 kilograms (176 pounds) of the
drug wrapped in waterproof tape, were found by local residents
in Yokosuka city on Nov. 19, the Asahi newspaper reported,
citing local police. The find is the biggest by value in Japan,
public broadcaster NHK said. </p>
<p>Yokosuka, home to a U.S. Navy base, is about 50 kilometers
(31 miles) south of Tokyo. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri" date="Nov 22, 2013  4:58 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-22/disney-s-pixar-said-to-cut-about-60-jobs-after-film-delay.html"><headline>Pixar Cutting Less Than 5% of Jobs After Film Is Delayed</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS)''s Pixar studio is
eliminating jobs after deciding to delay next year''s theatrical
release The Good Dinosaur. </p>
<p>The cuts amount to less than 5 percent of Pixar''s 1,200
employees, according to a person with knowledge of the matter
who wasn''t authorized to speak publicly and requested anonymity.
That''s fewer than than 60 positions. </p>
<p>We are constantly re-evaluating the creative and business
needs of our studio, Emeryville, California-based Pixar said
in a statement, without providing specific numbers. With the
release date change of The Good Dinosaur,'' we have realigned
our production and support priorities, which includes a small
reduction in our staffing. </p>
<p>The decision to delay The Good Dinosaur for 18 months
left the animation studio that produced Toy Story and
Cars without an annual release for the first time since
2005. Disney announced the later date in September and said in
October it would close a Vancouver facility. </p>
<p>The Good Dinosaur, about a 70-foot-tall teenage
Apatosaurus that befriends a young boy, was pushed back to Nov.
25, 2015, Disney said at the time. </p>
<p>Disney, based in Burbank, California, rose 0.4 percent to
$70.20 at 4 p.m. in New York, an all-time closing high. The
stock has gained 41 percent this year. </p>
<p>Pixar''s most-recent release, Monsters University, has
grossed $743.4 million worldwide since its June debut, according
to BoxOfficeMojo.com. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matt Townsend" date="Nov 22, 2013  4:25 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-22/disney-s-doc-mcstuffins-challenges-dora-on-toy-wishlists.html"><headline>Disney''s Doc McStuffins Challenges Dora on Holiday Lists</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Jennifer Chandler-Saunders buys Doc McStuffins toys because the Walt Disney Co. (DIS) character teaches her two-year-old daughter to care for others. </p> <p>My daughter fell in love with Doc right away, said Chandler-Saunders, who nabbed a $35 Doc McStuffins medical kit from Toys R Us Inc. after the toy topped her daughter''s Christmas list. </p> <p>Dottie Doc McStuffins, a six-year-old aspiring physician who treats her toys with help from her dragon and snowman friends, is making most-popular lists this season. The doll is already flying off store shelves, say retailers, which sell about $10 billion worth of toys in the fourth quarter or about half the annual total, according to researcher NPD. </p> <p>Based on Doc McStuffins, Disney Junior channel''s animated hit show, the dolls are vying with toys inspired by Viacom Inc. (VIAB)''s Dora The Explorer character, long the undisputed queen of the toddler set. For parents like Chandler-Saunders, Doc''s skin color enhances the appeal. </p> <p>I''m Caucasian, and the doll is black, so it''s kind of cool kids can look up to someone of another race, said the 35-year-old mother of two, who runs her own insurance agency in Jetersville, Virginia. </p> <p>Doc McStuffins''s rapid ascent since debuting last year is something of a departure for an industry that has a tendency to reboot old brands. Exhibit A: Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles, which debuted in the 1980s and was revived last year as a line of toys and a Nickelodeon series, is a top pick for boys this year, according to hot-toy lists. Another familiar friend is Hasbro Inc. (HAS)''s Big Hugs Elmo, the latest incarnation of the fuzzy Sesame Street character, which industry analysts predict also will be a top seller this holiday-shopping season. </p> <h2>Insufficient Inventory </h2> <p>Last year, McStuffins''s popularity took some retailers by surprise, leaving them with insufficient inventory, said Jim Silver, editor-in-chief of toy review website Time to Play. The shortage prompted moms to hit websites such as EBay Inc. (EBAY) where they spent double the toy''s $10 retail price, he said. </p> <p>Disney''s stock rose 0.4 percent to $70.20 at the close in New York. The shares have gained 41 percent this year, while the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index has advanced 27 percent. </p> <p>This year retailers are prepared. Disney''s top four U.S. retail accounts, Wal-Mart Stores Inc. (WMT), Target Corp., Toys R Us and Sears Holdings Corp. (SHLD)''s Kmart, have on average quadrupled the shelf space given to McStuffins from last holidays, said J.D. Edwards, senior vice president of licensing for Disney Consumer Products. </p> <h2>Quick Greenlight </h2> <p>Doc McStuffins appeals to a wide range of demographics, said Jennifer Dominiquini, Sears chief marketing officer for fitness, sporting goods and toys. It addresses that human need for nurturing. It''s a perfect recipe for success. </p> <p>When Disney executives were pitched Doc McStuffins in 2008, they greenlighted the show quickly because it introduced the concept of nurturing to children''s television. </p> <p>It was almost like one of those duh why didn''t we think of this before'' moments, said Nancy Kanter, executive vice president of original programming and general manager of Disney Junior Worldwide. </p> <p>The company made one key switch: changing the family''s race from white to black. </p> <h2>Diverse Brand </h2> <p>It''s important to us that the brand and the content represents the world as kids live it and see it and that is a world that''s very diverse, Kanter said. Just the notion that for some kids this will look exactly like their families and for others it will look like what they see in their neighborhoods. </p> <p>This year, Disney added a range of accessories, including clothes, bedding and even Doc McStuffins Band-Aids from Johnson  Johnson. The company is also releasing toys aimed at boys, including a blue rather than pink check-up kit because the show''s viewers are almost evenly split between boys and girls. </p> <p>The brand''s growth helped more than double retail sales of Disney Junior products to $1.8 billion in the fiscal year ended Sept. 28, Edwards said. He declined to give specific data for Doc McStuffins. Success in the toy division is important to Disney because the unit generates high-margin sales on characters already created by other businesses. Consumer products accounted for 10 percent of profit in the most recent fiscal year, while making up 7.9 percent of total company sales. </p> <h2>Toy Fads </h2> <p>Hot holiday toys come and go. That''s why toymakers rush to add bells and whistles to keep kids interested. In September, for example, Viacom released the Dora Sizzling Surprises Kitchen and Spin  Skate Dora and Boots. </p> <p>Ten years running Dora remains a beloved property and is doing very well for us this holiday, said Dan Martinsen, a spokesman for Viacom''s Nickelodeon networks. Dora continues to be a trailblazer and has a long, bright future ahead of her. </p> <p>For now, Doc''s race and her TV family''s reversal of gender roles -- mom is a doctor; dad stays home -- has strong appeal for some parents, said Laurie Schacht, chief executive officer of The Toy Book, a trade publication. </p> <p>It makes it more real, and more interesting, she said. Whether we''re talking about color or women, everyone has come a long way, and it''s nice to see that in our kids . </p> <p>Such distinctions are beside the point for toddlers, who relate to the story and character -- not what makes adults feel good, said Nancy Zwiers, a former marketing executive for Mattel Inc. Parents'' discomfort with sexy Bratz fashion dolls didn''t prevent MGA Entertainment Co. from building a billion-dollar business. The Barbie brand hasn''t suffered from complaints that the doll''s unrealistic proportions may hurt girls'' self-esteem. </p> <h2>Emotional Choices </h2> <p>We adults like to overlay our perspective on things, and that''s not the way kids make choices, said Zwiers, who now does brand consulting for toy and entertainment companies, including Disney. Kids are making choices emotionally. </p> <p>Doc McStuffins, who once soothed a bubble bottle character''s stomach ache after it was accidentally filled with paste instead of soap, is seen as a role model. </p> <p>She teaches manners and how to be respectful and how to be nice toward others, said Chandler-Saunders. That''s hard to teach children. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chris Dolmetsch" date="Nov 22, 2013  4:16 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-22/jpmorgan-says-mbia-didn-t-read-report-insurer-says-was-altered.html"><headline>JPMorgan Says MBIA Didn''t Read Report Insurer Says Was Altered</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>MBIA Inc. (MBI) didn''t even read a report
the bond insurer says was altered to hide deficiencies in a
$1.16 billion pool of mortgages until a week after it agreed to
insure the loans, attorneys for JPMorgan Chase  Co. told a New
York state judge. </p>
<p>Lawyers for JPMorgan asked state Supreme Court Justice Alan
D. Scheinkman in White Plains to throw out a lawsuit filed
against the bank by MBIA last year accusing its Bear Stearns
unit of inducing the insurer to back the pool by removing
information from a report showing underwriting and compliance
problems with the loans in the pool. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Catarina Saraiva" date="Nov 22, 2013  1:03 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-22/goldman-sachs-cuts-argentina-2013-2014-gdp-forecasts-table-.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Cuts Argentina 2013, 2014 GDP Forecasts</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The following table shows Goldman Sach''s
Latin America economic forecasts as of Nov. 22, compared to their forecasts
as of Nov. 1.        </p>

==============================================================================
                        -Forecast-    --Change--     -Forecast-    --Change--
                       2013   2014    2013   2014    2013   2014   2013   2014
==============================================================================
                        ---Annual Average GDP---     ---Annual Average CPI---
Argentina              5.1%   1.7%   -0.2%  -0.2%   10.7%  16.8%     --   3.8%
Brazil                 2.6%   2.3%      --     --    5.8%   5.8%   0.1%  -0.1%
Chile                  4.2%   4.2%      --   0.1%    2.2%   2.9%  -0.3%     --
Colombia               4.1%   4.7%      --  -0.1%    2.4%   3.0%  -0.4%     --
Mexico                 1.2%   3.3%    0.1%     --    3.4%   3.8%   2.3%   0.5%
Peru                   5.0%   5.4%   -0.3%  -0.6%    3.0%   2.8%   0.5%   0.3%
Venezuela              1.2%  -1.3%   -0.5%  -3.8%   59.7%  64.6%   8.9%  30.9%
==============================================================================
SOURCE: Goldman Sachs Latin America Economic Analyst''

]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Nov 22, 2013 11:56 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-22/goldman-sachs-said-to-seek-buyer-for-uranium-unit.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Said to Seek Buyer for Uranium Unit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) put its
uranium trading unit up for sale as prices for the radioactive
metal fall and regulatory scrutiny of banks'' commodity
activities increases, a person briefed on the matter said. </p>
<p>The person asked not to be identified because the decision
hasn''t been made public. SparkSpread, an online energy
publication, reported the move earlier today. </p>
<p>Prices for uranium have declined since Japan''s Fukushima
nuclear disaster, which eroded demand for the metal as nations
shuttered reactors. Banks from JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) to UBS AG
have cut their price outlooks for next year as the radiation
leaks fan speculation that the restart of Japan''s idled plants
will take longer than expected. </p>
<p>The Federal Reserve is reviewing companies including
Goldman Sachs as U.S. lawmakers and regulators raise concerns
that banks might abuse their various roles in physical
commodities markets for their own benefit, or that the
businesses pose risks to the firms'' financial stability. </p>
<p>The bank received inquiries from potential buyers for its
aluminum warehousing company, Metro International Trade Services
LLC, a person briefed on the matter said this week. New York-based Goldman Sachs bought Metro as a merchant banking
investment in 2010 and must sell it by 2020. </p>




Photographer: Vladimir Weiss/Bloomberg

<p>
Prices for uranium have declined since Japan''s Fukushima nuclear disaster, which eroded demand for the metal as nations shuttered reactors. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Carroll" date="Nov 22, 2013 11:50 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-22/chevron-says-north-sea-discovery-won-t-pay-to-develop.html"><headline>Chevron Says North Sea Discovery Won''t Pay to Develop</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX), the world''s second-largest non-state energy company by market value, said its
Rosebank oil discovery off the coast of Scotland would be
unprofitable to bring into production at this time. </p>
<p>Chevron plans to continue evaluating the 240 million-barrel
field along with partners OMV AG (OMV) and Dong Energy A/S for ways to
improve the project''s potential returns, the San Ramon,
California-based company said in an e-mailed statement today. A
final decision on whether to proceed will be made next year,
according to the statement. </p>
<p>Rosebank''s unprofitability is a blow to U.K and Norwegian
efforts to halt the slide in North Sea oil output as fields
first drilled in the 1970s and 1980s near the end of their
productive lifespans. Dropping North Sea supplies are expected
to drive a 15 percent decline in European crude and gas liquids
production by 2018, the Organization of Petroleum Exporting
Countries said in its annual world outlook on Nov. 7. </p>
<p>Rosebank does not currently offer an economic value
proposition that justifies proceeding with an investment of this
magnitude, Chevron said in the statement. </p>
<p>Chevron and its partners hired South Korea''s Hyundai Heavy
Industries (009540) Co. Ltd. in April to construct a $1.9 billion
platform that could offload crude directly to tankers, Hyundai
said in a Nov. 15 slide presentation. The vessel would have
capacity to draw 100,000 barrels of oil and 190 million standard
cubic feet of gas daily from the seafloor. </p>
<p>Chevron hasn''t disclosed any cost estimates for the total
development. Rosebank is located 80 miles (130 kilometers)
northwest of the Shetland Islands and 3,700 feet (1,130 meters)
beneath the sea surface. </p>
<p>Chevron discovered Rosebank in 2004 and owns a 40 percent
stake. OMV owns 50 percent and Dong holds a 10 percent interest. </p>
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. is the largest oil company by market
value, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Cliff Edwards" date="Nov 23, 2013 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-23/microsoft-says-initial-xbox-one-sales-exceed-1-million.html"><headline>Microsoft Says Initial Xbox One Sales Exceed 1 Million</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. said it sold more than 1 million Xbox One video-game consoles in less than a day after the new machine went on sale in 13 countries. </p> <p>The tally surpassed first-day sales for the predecessor Xbox 360 and set a record for Microsoft, the Redmond, Washington-based company said yesterday in a statement. The Xbox One went on sale in Australia, Austria, Brazil, Canada, France, Germany, Ireland, Italy, Mexico, New Zealand, Spain, the U.K. and U.S. after the company cut eight countries from the initial sales list, citing production issues. </p> <p>Sony Corp. said on Nov. 17 that it sold more than 1 million PlayStation 4 consoles in North America in the first day of release, topping initial sales for the predecessor PlayStation 3 in 2006. The PS4 goes on sale Nov. 29 in 30 countries in Europe and Latin America, followed by Japan on Feb. 22. </p> <p>The two companies are competing for the attention of gamers and trying to revive a console market that shrank 32 percent to $13.3 billion from 2008 to 2012, according to market researcher NPD Group. Both are offering machines with upgraded graphics and more entertainment tie-ins. The Xbox One sells for $499, while the PlayStation 4 is offered for $399. </p>




Photographer: Victor J. Blue/Bloomberg

<p>
Best Buy Co. employees unload Xbox consoles during the Microsoft Corp. midnight launch event in New York, Nov. 21, 2013. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chris Dolmetsch and Christie Smythe" date="Nov 26, 2013  3:35 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-26/chevron-claims-trial-showed-proof-of-fraud-in-ecuador.html"><headline>Chevron Claims Trial Showed Proof of Fraud in Ecuador</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX) asked a federal judge
in New York to find that a racketeering plot was behind a
multibillion-dollar pollution verdict against the company handed
down by an Ecuadorean court. </p>
<p>Closing arguments began today in Manhattan after six weeks
of trial in which the company claimed lawyers for the plaintiffs
in the Ecuador environmental case bribed judges and drafted much
of the actual ruling. Steven Donziger, a New York attorney
accused of leading the scheme, has denied allegations of
wrongdoing and maintained the judgment is valid. </p>
<p>Randy Mastro, a lawyer for Chevron, the second-largest U.S.
energy company, argued to U.S. District Judge Lewis Kaplan that
the evidence showed the pollution ruling was a fraud. </p>
<p>One thing has always been certain: this judgment was
ghostwritten by these plaintiffs, Mastro told Kaplan today. </p>
<p>Mastro said strings of words from Donziger''s e-mails
and sequences of numbers from an internal database that appear
verbatim in the judgment show the plaintiffs'' influence. </p>
<p>This is like not even fingerprints, Mastro said. This
is like 10 fingers, both palms. Their internal work product
shows up word for word in the document because they wrote it
themselves. </p>
<h2>Toxic Waste </h2>
<p>Donziger and a team of other lawyers won the $19 billion
judgment in 2011 on behalf of Ecuadorean rainforest villagers
who claimed Texaco, later bought by Chevron, dumped billions of
gallons of drilling-generated toxic waste from the 1960s through
the early 1990s. The award was cut in half on Nov. 12 by the
Ecuadorean National Court of Justice, the nation''s highest
tribunal. </p>
<p>Richard Friedman, an attorney representing Donziger, said
many of Donziger''s statements from e-mails and documents have
been taken out of context. The case is bigger than Donziger and
the thousands of Ecuadoreans who will be affected by the ruling,
Friedman said. </p>
<p>They''ll be looking to see if American courts will follow
their own rules of law, Friedman said. They''ll be looking to
see if there are special exceptions, special rules for large
American corporations. What he''s accomplished by legitimate, yet
noisy, boisterous, unconventional ways, has caused people around
the world to look with fresh eyes at how our corporations treat
the Third World. </p>
<h2>Lead Adviser </h2>
<p>Chevron, based in San Ramon, California, has refused to pay
any of the judgment and is seeking an order from Kaplan barring
Donziger from trying to enforce it. The company claims Texaco
already cleaned up its share of the damage. </p>
<p>Donziger, a Harvard Law School graduate originally from
Jacksonville, Florida, got involved in the Ecuadorean case in
the 1990s and became its lead adviser. He contends that his role
has since diminished and Ecuadorean lawyers are now in charge. </p>
<p>He said in written testimony that the pollution judgment is
a profound historical accomplishment of indigenous and farmer
communities in securing justice for wrongs inflicted upon them
by one of the most powerful corporations on the planet. </p>
<p>If the ruling can be upheld in a country where Chevron has
assets to seize, Donziger stands to collect as much as $600
million, he acknowledged in court on Nov. 18 under questioning
by Mastro. Donziger has also been paid during the litigation,
receiving $150,000 in one year while the lead Ecuadorean lawyer
on the team, Pablo Fajardo, received just $24,000, Mastro said. </p>
<h2>Making Money </h2>
<p>Mastro, the Chevron lawyer, said today that Donziger''s
testimony about his smaller role in the case is contradicted by
the fact that he makes six or seven times more than Fajardo. </p>
<p>In every business I''ve ever been in the boss makes more
money, Mastro told the judge. </p>
<p>To him the ends came to justify the means, the methods
didn''t matter, Mastro said. He set about to make the big
score and set his sights on Chevron. </p>
<p>So far, the team working on behalf of the plaintiffs have
filed enforcement actions in Canada, Brazil and Argentina.
Canada, in particular has a history of giving respect to
foreign judgments and is a country where oil companies have
very substantial assets, Donziger said in an interview with
journalists Nov. 15. Chevron has no physical assets in Ecuador. </p>
<h2>Two Judges </h2>
<p>Two former Ecuadorean judges who handled the pollution case
also testified during the trial: Nicolas Zambrano, who issued
the ruling, and his former colleague Alberto Guerra. </p>
<p>Guerra told the court that he regularly drafted rulings for
Zambrano, who wasn''t as experienced at handling civil cases. He
testified that he and his colleague were promised proceeds from
the judgment to throw the case in the plaintiffs'' favor. </p>
<p>Guerra, now living in the U.S. and receiving $12,000 a
month from Chevron, said he helped write the 188-page judgment
against the company based on materials from the plaintiffs. </p>
<p>Zambrano denied he was bribed. He told the court that while
Guerra regularly helped him draft some rulings, he worked on the
Chevron ruling with help only from an 18-year-old assistant. </p>
<p>Mastro said today in his closing argument that Zambrano
lied on the stand when he denied paying Guerra to help with the
judgment and denied being bribed to write the ruling in favor of
the plaintiffs. </p>
<h2>Weak Judiciary </h2>
<p>He couldn''t admit that he was paid to ghostwrite the
judgment, Mastro said. He admitted too much and he lied way
too much. </p>
<p>Chevron filed its racketeering case against Donziger after
pre-trial information exchanges produced materials that included
hundreds of hours of outtakes from a 2009 documentary on the
Ecuador case called Crude, by filmmaker Joe Berlinger. </p>
<p>Chevron alleged the material showed Donziger discussing
ways to take advantage of Ecuador''s weak judiciary. Donziger
said the outtakes were edited by Chevron and that some of his
statements were taken out of context. </p>
<p>Supporters of Donziger''s efforts include Trudie Styler,
wife of musician Sting, who helped start a project to provide
clean water for the rainforest dwellers. The couple watched
Donziger testify in Manhattan federal court Nov. 18. </p>
<p>The racketeering case is Chevron Corp. v. Donziger, 11-cv-00691, U.S. District Court, Southern District of New York
(Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Nick Taborek" date="Nov 26, 2013  1:06 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-26/goldman-sees-s-p-500-falling-10-next-year-before-rally-to-1-900.html"><headline>Goldman Sees S&amp;amp;P 500 Falling 10% Next Year Before Rally to 1,900</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The Standard  Poor''s 500 Index will
probably fall 10 percent in the next 12 months before rebounding
to end the year at 1,900, according to Goldman Sachs Group Inc. </p>
<p>The 1,900 forecast from the New York-based firm implies
about a 5 percent advance from today''s level. The 25 months
since the SP 500 (SPX)''s last 10 percent drop is the longest stretch
without such a decline since 2007, according to SP. </p>
<p>It will be less smooth sailing, David Kostin, the
bank''s chief U.S. equity strategist, said on Bloomberg
Television''s Market Makers program. The likelihood is we
will have something that will prompt a reduction -- a retreat in
the market. But overall the market should be rising, and that''s
because the U.S. economy will be getting better. </p>
<p>Kostin predicts the SP 500 will reach 2,100 by the end of
2015 and 2,200 by the end of 2016. He said he favors technology,
industrial and consumer discretionary companies because they
will benefit the most from an improving economy. </p>
<p>Economists surveyed by Bloomberg forecast U.S. economic
growth will accelerate to 2.6 percent next year and 3 percent in
2015, compared with a 1.7 percent expansion in 2013. </p>
<p>Investors should buy shares of companies that are
increasing capital spending or repurchasing stock, he said. He''s
also bullish on firms that have above-average operating
leverage, a measure of how well a company can control fixed and
variable costs. </p>
<p>All these themes are about taking advantage of the
economy improving, Kostin said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Maria Levitov" date="Nov 26, 2013 10:41 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-26/goldman-says-buy-china-russia-stocks-on-valuations-to-reforms.html"><headline>Goldman Says Buy China, Russia Stocks on Valuation to Reform</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. recommended
buying Chinese (SHCOMP) and Russian stocks as a pick up in growth in
developed countries and government reforms boost prospects for
the least-expensive emerging markets. </p>
<p>Goldman upgraded equities in the two countries to
overweight, the equivalent of buy, from market weight, saying
Chinese banks and Russian energy companies could experience
modest valuation expansion, according to a report today. The
New York-based bank kept Korea and Mexico at overweight. </p>
<p>The Micex Index (INDEXCF) in Moscow trades at 4.3 times projected 12-month earnings, while the multiple for the Shanghai Composite
Index is 8.6, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. That
compares with 10.5 times for the MSCI Emerging Markets Index.
China, the world''s second-largest economy, and Russia, the
largest global energy exporter, are relatively insulated
from concern about Federal Reserve stimulus tapering, which may
start around March 2014, Goldman said. </p>
<p>Efficiency of capital allocation and the treatment of
minority shareholders are improving, analysts including
Christopher Eoyang said. In Russia, we feel the market is
over-focused on the importance of the price of oil, and
unwilling to credit the effects of various reform programs, the
drive for greater efficiency and a potential increase of
energy exports to Asia, it said. </p>




Photographer: Daniel Acker/Bloomberg

<p>
Goldman Sachs Group Inc. upgraded equities in the two countries to overweight, the equivalent of buy, from market weight, saying Chinese banks and Russian energy companies could experience modest valuation expansion, according to a report today. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Nov 26, 2013 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-26/goldman-currency-trading-definition-shows-disclosure-gap.html"><headline>Goldman Currency-Trading Definition Shows Disclosure Gap</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>What''s the difference between
trading currency products and currency trading? More than $1
billion, according to Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) </p>
<p>The investment bank said last week that it didn''t have a
third-quarter loss in currency trading. That followed a report
by Reuters on Goldman Sachs''s Nov. 7 Securities and Exchange
Commission filing, which shows a $1.32 billion loss from market-making in currency products. </p>
<p>The disconnect stems from the fact that the biggest U.S.
banks don''t provide a revenue breakdown for units that make up
their equity- and fixed-income trading divisions, which reap
more than $70 billion a year. An SEC requirement that banks give
some specifics on those businesses resulted in disclosures that
firms such as Goldman Sachs, which gets more than half its
revenue from trading, said lack meaningful context. </p>
<p>If you''re trying to figure out the profitability of
different lines of business, I don''t know how you effectively do
that, said Edward Siedle, a former SEC attorney and president
of Ocean Ridge, Florida-based Benchmark Financial Services Inc.
The commission needs to be careful not to require a disclosure
scheme that is just as likely to be misleading as it is to be
revealing, </p>




Photographer: Victor J. Blue/Bloomberg

<p>
Pedestrians walk near Goldman Sachs Group Inc.''s headquarters in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore, Corina Pons and Nathan Crooks" date="Nov 27, 2013 10:09 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-27/goldman-to-bofa-pitch-venezuela-deals-to-drum-up-dollars.html"><headline>Goldman to BofA Pitch Venezuela Deals to Drum Up Dollars</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) and Bank of
America Corp. (BAC) are among Wall Street firms that offered deals to
help Venezuela obtain U.S. dollars amid a plunge in the nation''s
foreign reserves. </p>
<p>A swap proposed by Goldman Sachs would provide $1.68
billion in cash and be backed by $1.85 billion of the central
bank''s gold, documents obtained by Bloomberg News show. Bank of
America said it could be an intermediary for $3 billion in
payments to firms seeking U.S. dollars, documents show. Neither
deal has been completed, a government official with direct
knowledge of the matter said, requesting anonymity because the
talks are private. </p>
<p>Dollars are becoming scarce in Venezuela, limiting the
supply of products from medicine to toilet paper in a nation
that imports about three-quarters of goods it consumes. Foreign
reserves dropped 28 percent this year, touching a nine-year low
of $20.7 billion this month, largely because 70 percent of the
assets are in gold. The metal plunged 26 percent in the period. </p>
<p>The fact you have dollar shortages is symptomatic of an
economy that''s completely broken down, Robert Abad, who helps
oversee $53 billion in emerging-market debt at Western Asset
Management Co., said yesterday in a telephone interview from
Pasadena, California. This is something that''s just incredibly
unnecessary, very unfortunate, and the victim of all of this is
the real economy, real people. </p>




Photographer: Juan Barreto/AFP/Getty Images

<p>
Dollars are becoming scarce in Venezuela, limiting the supply of products from medicine to toilet paper in a nation that imports about three-quarters of goods it consumes. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sonia Sirletti and Francesca Cinelli" date="Nov 27, 2013  9:42 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-27/generali-ceo-greco-targets-higher-cost-reduction-lower-debt.html"><headline>Generali Chief Greco Boosts Target for Cost Reductions</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Assicurazioni Generali SpA (G), Europe''s
third-largest insurer, plans to cut an extra 150 million euros
($204 million) of costs by 2015 and reduce debt to boost profit
and strengthen capital. </p>
<p>The company increased its cost savings goal to 750 million
euros by 2015 and will seek reductions of 1 billion euros by
2016, the Trieste-based insurer said today. Standard  Poor''s
put Generali on CreditWatch negative yesterday while the rating
company carries out stress tests. </p>
<p>Generali doesn''t need to raise capital, Chief Executive
Officer Mario Greco said in an interview with Francine Lacqua on
Bloomberg Television before a presentation to investors in
London today. The company is not capitalized enough today, but
we are working to get our target by 2015. </p>
<p>Greco, who took over as CEO last year, is selling non-strategic assets and focusing on the company''s main business.
The insurer is more than half way to its goal of raising 4
billion euros from disposals by 2015, after selling its U.S.
reinsurance unit and Mexican businesses earlier this year.
Generali is also seeking a buyer for its Swiss asset-management
unit, BSI Group. </p>
<p>Things now are clearer and we are coming to a point where
valuations are coming closer to what we expect to get, Greco
said in the interview. </p>
<h2>Restructuring Story </h2>
<p>Generali rose 1.8 percent to 16.89 euros as of 2:45 p.m. in
Milan trading, giving the insurer a market value of 26.3 billion
euros. The stock rallied more than 63 percent since Greco''s
appointment in August 2012, compared with a 48 percent gain in
the Bloomberg Europe 500 Insurance Index. </p>
<p>The update on targets in our view is positive, Michael van Wegen, an analyst at Bank of America Merrill Lynch with a
buy rating on the stock, wrote in a note to clients today. We
continue to see Generali as an attractive restructuring story. </p>
<p>Generali reiterated plans to boost the Solvency I ratio, a
measure of its ability to absorb losses, to more than 160
percent by 2015 from 152 percent at the end of October. That
compares with a third-quarter median ratio of 216 percent for 16
insurance companies in western Europe disclosing the
information, according to Bloomberg Industries data. </p>
<p>The insurer''s workforce of about 80,000 will be cut over
the next few years, Greco said, adding that the reduction will
come from a natural turnover, not forced actions. </p>
<p>The company said it intends to lower its debt-to-leverage
ratio to less than 35 percent by 2015 from 40 percent. </p>
<h2>Too High'' </h2>
<p>Analysts'' estimates for operating profit of 4.5 billion
euros this year are too high, Greco said. </p>
<p>Our operating profit will be higher than last year and a
positive number, Greco said. Analysts will be pleased with
our results by year end, but we will not get as far as 4.5
billion euros. </p>
<p>The CEO said the dividend will increase progressively,
linked to the effort to rebuild capital. </p>
<p>Generali''s third-quarter profit rose 75 percent to 510
million euros as it earned more from its life segment and
property and casualty operations. The company reiterated a
return-on-equity goal of 13 percent in 2015 and said it expects
fourth-quarter earnings in line with previous quarters. </p>
<h2>Higher Returns </h2>
<p>Generali, which has about 80 percent of its investment
portfolio in fixed-income instruments, is seeking higher returns
by diversifying its holdings and reducing cash, Chief Investment
Officer Nikhil Srinivasan said at the presentation to investors
in London. </p>
<p>Srinivasan, who oversees about 500 billion euros of assets
at Generali, is cutting liquidity by 10 billion euros this year.
He also reduced holdings of Italian government bonds to 55.5
billion euros at the end of the third quarter from 58.5 billion
euros in 2012, and plans to trim that amount by an additional
500 million euros in the fourth quarter. </p>
<p>The insurer has internal resources to pay down one-third of
2014 maturing debt of 2.25 billion euros, the company said in a
slide presentation. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass and Carol Hymowitz" date="Nov 28, 2013  3:57 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-11-28/microsoft-board-said-to-lean-to-mulally-nadella-in-ceo-search.html"><headline>Microsoft Said to Lean to Mulally, Nadella in CEO Search</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp.''s board is focusing on Ford Motor Co. Chief Executive Officer Alan Mulally and internal executive Satya Nadella as part of a group of more likely candidates to become the next CEO of the world''s biggest software company, according to people familiar with the matter. </p> <p>While internal candidate Tony Bates and former Nokia Oyj CEO Stephen Elop remain in the mix, they''re currently considered less likely to be offered the job, said the people, who asked not to be identified because the deliberations are private. Preferences remain fluid and other people are being considered and could emerge as front-runners, said one of the people, without identifying any. </p> <p>The board is aiming for a quick replacement for longtime CEO Steve Ballmer, who said in August that he will retire within the next 12 months. The Redmond, Washington-based company has seen its software leadership decline amid a shrinking of the personal-computer market, which was its core business. Microsoft is shifting strategy to focus more on hardware and Internet-based services and away from its software roots as it competes with Apple Inc. and Google Inc. </p> <p>Frank Shaw, a spokesman at Microsoft, declined to comment or to make any executives available yesterday. Susan Sheehan, a spokeswoman for Nokia, which is still Elop''s employer, declined to comment. </p>




Photographer: Peter Foley/Bloomberg

<p>
Alan Mulally, president and chief executive officer of Ford Motor Co. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry></news>