
<news><entry author="By Adriana Brasileiro" date="Jan 07, 2010 10:48 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-01-07/brazil-s-serra-ready-for-election-test-jpmorgan-says-update1-.html"><headline>Brazil&#8217;s Serra Ready for Election Test, JPMorgan Says</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Sao Paulo state Governor Jose Serra,
the likely opposition candidate in Brazil&#8217;s presidential
election, will probably do a better job addressing the country&#8217;s
long-term economic challenges, JPMorgan Chase  Co. said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Much is at stake in terms of long-term planning for the
country now that the stabilization phase is over and Brazil is
entering what appears to be a solid growth phase,&#8221; JPMorgan
said in a report published today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cabinet chief Dilma Rousseff, the candidate favored by
President Luiz Inacio Lula da Silva, would likely boost the
state&#8217;s &#8220;intervention&#8221; in the private sector, JPMorgan said.
Rousseff, 62, is a &#8220;very competitive&#8221; candidate and will
likely rise in the polls as Lula&#8217;s popularity continues to
increase, according to the report. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The race to succeed Lula will be a key driver for Brazil&#8217;s
markets this year after the benchmark Bovespa (IBOV) stock index
rallied 83 percent in 2009 and the real jumped 33 percent
against the U.S. dollar, the biggest gain among the 16 most-traded currencies tracked by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lula&#8217;s government injected 100 billion reais ($57.8
billion) into money markets and offered 75 billion reais in tax
cuts to help Latin America&#8217;s biggest economy emerge from its
recession in the second quarter of 2009, according to data from
BNP Paribas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serra, 67, would focus on solving fiscal challenges such as
eliminating overlapping taxes, allowing for an increase in
investment and a drop in interest rates &#8220;to more mundane
levels,&#8221; JPMorgan economists Emy Shayo Cherman and Fabio Akira
wrote in the report. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lula&#8217;s popularity will boost Rousseff&#8217;s chances as she
becomes the face of the government&#8217;s most important programs: a
plan to create 1 million homes for low-income families, an
infrastructure drive known as Growth Acceleration Program and
offshore drilling for oil, JPMorgan said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Serra will win 37 percent of votes and Rousseff 23 percent
in the first round of voting scheduled for October, according a
Dec. 18 nationwide poll taken by Datafolha. The poll has a
margin of error of plus or minus two percentage points. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By David Reilly" date="Jan 21, 2010  9:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-01-21/goldman-s-escape-route-might-be-the-private-road-david-reilly.html"><headline>Goldman&#8217;s Escape Route Might Be the Private Road: David Reilly</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Duck season? Rabbit season? It&#8217;s
bank season. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the wake of this week&#8217;s Massachusetts Massacre,
President Barack Obama and congressional Democrats may place
banks in their sights as they try to appease populist anger and
come up with some sort of achievement to take into this year&#8217;s
midterm elections. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No wonder Obama suddenly embraced the idea espoused by
former Federal Reserve Chairman Paul Volcker of a Glass-
Steagall-like separation of banking and trading activities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While legislative flesh still has to be put on the proposal
-- and it could easily be watered down -- it marks a big shift
in the administration&#8217;s stance toward banks. It may even signal
that the White House and congressional Democrats are getting the
guts to finally tackle the question of too-big-to-fail firms and
the future shape of Wall Street. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That leaves question marks hanging over the too-big-to-fail
club. JPMorgan Chase  Co., Bank of America Corp., Citigroup
Inc. and Morgan Stanley may all have to consider shedding or
restructuring parts of their business. Who knows? Merrill Lynch
 Co. or Bear Stearns Cos. may get a new lease on life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of all these firms, though, Goldman Sachs Group Inc. may be
in the most danger. The bulls-eye on that firm&#8217;s back is so big
it may have to start thinking about contingency plans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunate Timing &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It didn&#8217;t help that as Obama was detailing his proposals,
Goldman was reporting the most profitable year in its history.
Goldman said net income in 2009 climbed to $13.4 billion,
compared to $2.3 billion in the fiscal year ended November 2008.
Revenue for 2009 of $45.2 billion was double that of the 2008
fiscal year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Underscoring the threat posed by Obama&#8217;s proposal, which he
dubbed the Volcker Rule, Goldman reported that fourth-quarter
revenue from trading and principal investments of $6.4 billion
accounted for two-thirds of overall firm revenue. While other
firms such as JPMorgan have big trading operations, none is of
the same significance to the overall firm as Goldman&#8217;s. Even
Morgan Stanley has over the past year been adding more
traditional banking and brokerage operations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Never mind Goldman&#8217;s last-minute attempt to score some PR
points by bringing down compensation as a percentage of revenue
to about 35 percent. While that had Wall Street tongues wagging,
Main Street will see only that Goldman still paid out $16.2
billion in 2009. That&#8217;s a lot of bonus bucks in an economy with
10 percent unemployment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Private Option &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what is Goldman to do? One possibility: spin off some of
its businesses, say its hedge-fund, private-equity and asset
management operations, while taking the remaining investment-
banking firm private, or vice versa. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Granted, that would be extremely difficult to pull off
given the intertwined nature of the firm&#8217;s many businesses. That
was a point made on yesterday&#8217;s earnings call by Goldman Chief
Financial Officer David Viniar. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viniar also said that Goldman, if need be, could wall off
its proprietary trading business, which is &#8220;not very big in the
context of the firm.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus, regulators may find it tough to draw the line between
proprietary trading -- which is done on a firm&#8217;s own behalf --
and trading done for the benefit of clients. Even Volcker
admitted this during congressional testimony, and the
president&#8217;s proposal noted that any prohibition on trading,
hedge-fund or private-equity activity wouldn&#8217;t extend to
business &#8220;serving customers.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How Big &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#8217;s also questionable if a return to private partnership,
which Goldman was before going public in 1999, would leave a
large-enough capital base to maintain the confidence of trading
partners and wholesale funding markets. And if the firm&#8217;s
capital base were big, a private Goldman would likely still be
subject to the kind of regulatory scrutiny it was seeking to
reduce in the first place. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then again, Goldman&#8217;s own employees may embrace such a move
if it spared them and the firm the kind of public attention and
ridicule that pushed Chief Executive Officer Lloyd Blankfein to
chop compensation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And some investors have already been considering such a
possibility. Back in December, Douglas Kass, general partner of
hedge-fund firm Seabreeze Partners Management Inc., listed
Goldman going private as one of his predictions for 2010. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Noting the presence of Warren Buffett as an investor in
Goldman, Kass predicted on the Web site realmoney.com: &#8220;Sick of
the unrelenting compensation outcry, government jawboning and
associated populist pressures, Warren Buffett teams up with
Goldman Sachs to take the investment firm private. The deal is
completed by year end.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Harsh Spotlight &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The spotlight on Goldman may only grow harsher. While Obama
didn&#8217;t single out any particular firm during his press
conference, investors reading between the lines can find none-
too-subtle hints at Goldman. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;When banks benefit from the safety net that taxpayers
provide, which includes lower cost capital, it is not
appropriate for them to turn around and use that cheap money to
trade for profit,&#8221; the president said. &#8220;And that is especially
true when this kind of trading often puts banks in direct
conflict with their customers&#8217; interests.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That seemed to be a dig at Blankfein, who scrambled at last
week&#8217;s Financial Crisis Inquiry Commission hearing to defend
Goldman&#8217;s trading practices in relation to clients. So too did
Obama&#8217;s reference to &#8220;soaring profits and obscene bonuses.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the past year, banks have managed to blunt many
financial-reform proposals. That may be changing if Democrats
feel they need score a few banking scalps to improve their
November election fortunes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that case, Blankfein may find himself cast in the role
of Elmer Fudd. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(David Reilly is a Bloomberg News columnist. The opinions
expressed are his own.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click on &#8220;Send Comment&#8221; in the sidebar display to send a
letter to the editor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Caroline Baum" date="Jan 25, 2010  9:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-01-25/goldman-parachute-awaits-geithner-to-ease-fall-caroline-baum.html"><headline>Goldman Parachute Awaits Geithner to Ease Fall: Caroline Baum</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Treasury Secretary Timothy Geithner
is scheduled to testify to the House Oversight and Government
Reform Committee tomorrow. The hearing is certain to be good
theater. Whether it reveals good government, or a government
working for the few at the expense of the many, is another
matter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If it turns out Geithner failed to act in the best interest
of taxpayers in the bailout of American International Group,
Inc., he is unworthy of the public trust and should step down. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That thought may have crossed President Barack Obama&#8217;s mind
as well. When Obama proposed new limits on the size and scope of
commercial banks last week, standing at his side was Paul
Volcker, head of the president&#8217;s Economic Advisory Board, whose
height (6 feet 7 inches) belies his diminished influence --until
now. Volcker has long advocated banning commercial banks from
speculating with federally insured deposits, but his voice was
drowned out by the pro-Wall Street sympathies of Geithner and
Larry Summers, another Obama economic adviser. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The House Oversight Committee, chaired by Edolphus Towns, a
Democrat from New York, subpoenaed documents from the Federal
Reserve Bank of New York relating to the AIG bailout in
September 2008, when Geithner was president of the New York Fed.
The Fed turned over about 250,000 pages of documents, some of
which have been leaked to the press. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lawmakers are particularly interested in the decision to
pay AIG&#8217;s counterparties, including Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and
Societe Generale SA, 100 cents on the dollar to cancel, then and
there, the credit default swaps the insurer sold them. They also
want to know why the New York Fed pressured AIG to withhold that
information in its regulatory filings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secrecy&#8217;s Downside &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So do we. Secrecy surrounding the AIG bailout has worked to
compound suspicions the New York Fed did something fishy, that
it found a back-door way to pump money into the banks and, in
the process, hosed the rest of us. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geithner has testified that the Fed&#8217;s hands were tied, that
the bank could not &#8220;selectively default on contractual
obligations without courting collapse.&#8221; If that&#8217;s the case, why
hide the evidence? CDSs are customized, privately negotiated
contracts. We have no idea how they were written. Only the
parties to them do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through a Treasury spokesman, Geithner has said he recused
himself from &#8220;working on issues involving specific companies,
including AIG,&#8221; after his Nov. 24 nomination as Treasury
secretary. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How likely is it Geithner was unaware or uninvolved in the
negotiations? The New York Fed did not respond to multiple
inquiries on the nature of the recusal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Body Language &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;It&#8217;s not necessary to speak words or render a decision to
cause influence,&#8221; says Jacob Frenkel, a former federal
prosecutor and Securities and Exchange Commission enforcement
attorney now in private practice. &#8220;Mere presence can affect the
outcome.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geithner&#8217;s problems pre-date AIG. After Obama nominated him
to the Treasury post, a job that put him atop the Internal
Revenue Service, we learned he cheated on his taxes. He settled
his 2003 and 2004 tax liability after a 2006 IRS audit but
didn&#8217;t pay back taxes for 2001 and 2002 until Obama nominated
him. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obama rushed Geithner&#8217;s confirmation process through the
Senate on the grounds that he was the only man for the job. The
main selling point? In his position at the helm of the New York
Fed since 2003, he was familiar with the crisis story line and
was involved in the various rescue efforts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also fiddled while the biggest banks, most of which are
in the New York Fed&#8217;s district, burned. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Escape Clause &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geithner has been a public servant his whole life, holding
various positions at the Treasury, the International Monetary
Fund and the Fed. Somehow he managed to shed the stigma of tax
scofflaw, but now BOTH Democrats and Republicans in Congress
want blood. His may be just the scalp Obama needs to pacify the
populist outrage, especially since he&#8217;s perceived as being too
cozy with bankers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the loss of the late Ted Kennedy&#8217;s Senate seat in
Massachusetts, Obama is trying out his populist voice. By all
rights, he should sacrifice one of his political advisers, who
seem to have miscalculated the Massachusetts election and
misjudged the public&#8217;s appetite for health-care reform when the
chief concern is jobs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Axing Geithner might be good for president and Treasury
secretary alike. Obama would be seen as an ally of the people.
Geithner would be free to claim his just reward: that plum offer
from Goldman Sachs. The circle would be squared. Obama would
have his man on the inside. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Caroline Baum, author of &#8220;Just What I Said,&#8221; is a
Bloomberg News columnist. The opinions expressed are her own.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click on &#8220;Send Comment&#8221; in sidebar display to send a
letter to the editor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Michael Lewis" date="Jan 28, 2010  9:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-01-28/goldman-trader-shares-three-big-ideas-with-lloyd-michael-lewis.html"><headline>Goldman Trader Shares Three Big Ideas With Lloyd: Michael Lewis</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;     Jan. 29 (Bloomberg) --
To: Lloyd Blankfein
Re: Winning the Public Relations War &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Six months ago, with what I mistakenly took to be your
tacit approval, I attempted to address ordinary Americans,
almost as equals. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They envied and resented our firm; I sought merely to
correct their misunderstandings about Goldman Sachs and send
them on their way, so that they might more briskly resume their
quest for gainful employment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In hindsight, I misjudged their ability to see the reality
of their situation, and of ours. At the time I accepted your
strong suggestion that I never again try to speak directly to
mortals -- or, as you referred to them, &#8220;The Morts.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now our predicament is suddenly more dire. Ordinary
Americans wish to control not just our pay but our core values:
We at Goldman have long stood for the right of every prop group
to trade against its firm&#8217;s customers. If we abdicate that
right, who are we, deep down? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In just the past few days many of us on the Goldman trading
floor have wrestled with that question. We believe that rather
than re-think our core values we should re-think our relations
with the American public. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hence this memo. Your recent non-verbal signals -- your
habit of passing directly behind my trading desk en route to the
elevators, your selection of the urinal adjacent to my own --
convince me that you continue to value my thoughts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it happens, I have recently conducted a thorough study
of the culture of ordinary Americans. Please take the following
ideas in the spirit in which they are intended: a team spirit.
There is no &#8220;I&#8221; in Goldman Sachs, or in me. Nor will there
ever be. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Idea No. 1: Give the Morts a small, perhaps even illusory,
stake in our upside. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have all seen the effects on the hearts and minds of our
government officials and business leaders when they sense that
our prosperity might one day be theirs. In the past year Warren Buffett has gone from being a leading critic of Wall Street to
the greatest defender of Wall Street bailouts. Him we needed to
pay hard cash -- most accept less. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#8217;s perhaps the most curious trait of these ordinary
Americans: you don&#8217;t need to give them any money to lead them to
hope that you might. Take Larry Summers, for instance. We both
know that we would never actually employ even this surprisingly
intelligent Mort in anything but the most humiliatingly
ceremonial role. But he doesn&#8217;t know that -- and thus he has
done so much for us. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ordinary Americans &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously we can never employ large numbers of ordinary
Americans. But if you stop for a moment and think like a Mort
you will realize that we don&#8217;t need to. We need only harness two
more of his many irrational traits: overconfidence, plus a
willingness to ignore the odds -- as evidenced by everything
from his interest in the Lotto, to his belief in what he calls
&#8220;love.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each year, for example, Goldman Sachs might announce a
grand national competition, much like &#8220;American Idol.&#8221;
Finalists will appear before a national television audience to
be judged by a panel of three rather ordinary looking Goldman
executives. On stage they will perform various Wall Street
tricks: negotiating with Tim Geithner, lobbying the Senate
Banking Committee, designing securities that blow up, selling
bonds to Germans, etc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The winner receives a job at Goldman Sachs. Which brings me
to... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big Idea No. 2: Give Morts the illusion that they have been
admitted into our realm, and can now truly see who we are and
what we do. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The winner of our national competition, for instance, might
easily be attached to a small Web-enabled, head-top photographic
device. Thus equipped he would become the eyes and ears of Morts
everywhere. As he stumbles around our offices, attempting to
understand that which is beyond his comprehension, he will no
doubt create what ordinary Americans refer to as &#8220;comedy.&#8221;
Morts love to laugh, to the point where they interpret our most
straightforward remarks as occasions for humor. As we do not
respond to comedy it will not disrupt the flow of our business,
and we can encourage it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me say here that I, like every other Goldman trader,
have admired the lengths to which you have gone to resemble an
ordinary, non-threatening American. Your conscious decision to
forgo muscle definition, along with your persistent
hairlessness, has been nothing less than enlightened public
relations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only So Much &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there is only so much one human being can do, even
when that being is more than human. Our employees along this new
interface with Mort culture should reinforce your subliminal
message. They should be &#8220;normal looking&#8221; and trained to mimic
the Mort&#8217;s strange, emotional responses to external stimuli. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the main purpose of any new personal contact with
individual Morts is to address what is perhaps our biggest
problem: the new belief of ordinary Americans that they now,
finally, understand what we do. That our work should be as
simple as &#8220;facilitating productive enterprise,&#8221; or
&#8220;allocating capital.&#8221; They have lost their former awe; we must
restore it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Notice that they do not begrudge professional basketball
players their vast salaries: they can see that those players are
so unlike themselves as to constitute a different species. As
our differences lie below the surface, they are harder for the
Morts to perceive. Closer proximity to us, and our complexity,
will solve this problem. They will soon weary of trying to
comprehend what we do, and go looking for another outlet for
their personal frustrations. Which brings me to my final
thought... &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big Thought No. 3: Remind the Morts of their more natural
resentments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the moment they mistrust us, perhaps even despise us,
but their feelings toward us are new and thus shallow. They have
had 30 years of training in hating their own government (the
ultimate example of Mort irrationality). We must remind Morts
that we share a common enemy: them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; Michael Lewis, a columnist for Bloomberg News, is the
author of &#8220;Liar&#8217;s Poker,&#8221; &#8220;Moneyball&#8221; and &#8220;The Blind
Side.&#8221;  His next book, &#8220;The Big Short,&#8221; will be published in
March.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click on &#8220;Send Comment&#8221; in the sidebar display to send a
letter to the editor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Nichola Saminather" date="Jan 28, 2010 12:58 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-01-28/westfield-group-shares-gain-after-jpmorgan-upgrades-the-stock.html"><headline>Westfield Group Shares Gain After JPMorgan Upgrades the Stock</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Westfield Group (WDC), the world&#8217;s largest
owner of shopping malls by market value, rose the most in five
months in Sydney trading after JPMorgan Securities Australia Ltd.
upgraded the stock to &#8220;overweight.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Westfield shares jumped 4.1 percent to close at A$12.71 on
the Australian Stock Exchange, the biggest gain since Sept. 7.
The shares have risen 1.4 percent this year, compared with a 4
percent decline in the benchmark SP/ASX 200 Index. (AS51) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JPMorgan analyst Rob Stanton raised the Sydney-based
company from &#8220;neutral,&#8221; and lifted its 12-month price estimate
to A$14.35 from A$12.72, citing strong performance at eight
Australian shopping centers Westfield has slated for
redevelopment in the second half of 2010. The malls&#8217; specialty
sales productivity of 19 percent is higher than the Australian
mall average, Stanton said in a note dated yesterday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;In our tour through these eight assets, we saw what
appears to be strong opportunity to add expansion space,&#8221;
Stanton said. &#8220;The centers were heaving, with no evidence of
vacancy issues, and productivity levels that strongly suggest
pent up demand. We think that there is opportunity at 12 other
Australian centers as well, totaling a further A$3.2 billion
($2.9 billion).&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company&#8217;s new payout ratio policy, expected to provide
A$500 million of cash per year, would help it fund its
redevelopment plans, Stanton said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sales Increase &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Retail sales at Westfield&#8217;s domestic malls rose 5.3 percent
in the 12 months to November, helped by centers with almost 100
percent of available space leased, as the Australian economy
avoided the worst of the global recession. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company has four major projects under way with an
estimated cost of A$3.7 billion, including two in the U.S. and
one each in Australia and the U.K. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With malls in four countries, Westfield has leased almost
97 percent of available space. It has forecast 2009 earnings per
share of 94 Australian cents to 97 Australian cents. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asset values are expected to start rebounding in the first
six months of this year, freeing up funds for redevelopment,
Stanton said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Westfield may sign six new leases this year as Australian
retailers start to expand for the first time since the global
financial crisis, Stanton said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Andy Fixmer" date="Jan 29, 2010 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-01-29/disney-shuts-miramax-indy-studio-weinsteins-led-to-oscar-glory.html"><headline>Disney Shuts Miramax, Indy Studio Weinsteins Led to Oscar Glory</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Walt Disney Co. (DIS), the world&#8217;s biggest
media company, closed its Miramax offices and made plans to
distribute the six remaining pictures from the film studio
founded by brothers Harvey and Bob Weinstein. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The moves were part of a restructuring announced in
October, Burbank, California-based Disney said yesterday in an
e-mailed statement. The unit had offices in New York, London and
Los Angeles. An estimated 80 people lost their jobs, according
to TheWrap.com, which reported the action earlier yesterday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miramax made its name taking art and foreign films and
turning them into hits. It won four Oscars for best picture,
including &#8220;Chicago,&#8221; &#8220;Shakespeare in Love&#8221; and &#8220;The English
Patient.&#8221; The Weinsteins left in 2005. Their new studio has
struggled and was in talks with potential partners last month,
David Glasser, a company executive, said in a Dec. 31 interview. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;I know the movies made on my and my brother Bob&#8217;s watch
will live on,&#8221; Harvey Weinstein, 57, said yesterday in an e-mailed statement.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chief Executive Officer Robert Iger has been restructuring
Disney&#8217;s money-losing film operations since October when he
named Rich Ross chairman, replacing Dick Cook. Ross said in
October Miramax chief Daniel Battsek would leave in January and
has consolidated live-action, animation and home-video. The
company is shrinking film production to focus on family titles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Miramax worked best when it was an independent company
where every single film was nurtured by Harvey Weinstein,&#8221; said
David Davis, managing partner of Santa Monica, California-based
Arpeggio Partners, which advises movie industry investors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;220 Oscar Nominations &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Weinsteins left Disney after clashes with then-Chief
Executive Officer Michael Eisner. It was founded 29 years ago
and named after the Weinsteins&#8217; parents, Miriam and Max, Harvey
Weinstein said. The name still holds sentimental value for the
two filmmakers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;If there is ever an opportunity to make a deal to buy it
back, we would certainly take it and there isn&#8217;t much in the
world that would make our 83-year-old mother happier,&#8221; Harvey
Weinstein said in the statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Disney&#8217;s 1993 acquisition of Miramax until the
Weinsteins left, the studio garnered 220 Oscar nominations for
films including &#8220;Pulp Fiction,&#8221; &#8220;The Aviator&#8221; and &#8220;Life Is
Beautiful,&#8221; according to a 2005 Disney statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Harvey used a portfolio that had about one out of every
10 movies pop out and make the whole company profitable for the
year,&#8221; Davis said in an interview. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fewer Movies &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Miramax released five movies last year that took in a total
of $39.6 million in U.S. box-office sales, according to Box
Office Mojo, a film researcher based in Sherman Oaks,
California. Eight films released in 2008 collected $66.2 million
in U.S. ticket revenue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Chicago&#8221; was Miramax&#8217;s top-grossing movie, collecting
$307 million in worldwide ticket sales following its December
2002 release, according to Box Office Mojo. In addition to best
picture, the movie also produced a best supporting actress award
for Catherine Zeta-Jones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disney gained 3 cents to $29.35 yesterday in New York Stock
Exchange composite trading. The stock advanced 42 percent in
2009. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry></news>