
<news><entry author="By David Evans" date="Nov 09, 2009 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-11-09/pfizer-broke-the-law-by-promoting-drugs-for-unapproved-uses.html"><headline>Pfizer Broke the Law by Promoting Drugs for Unapproved Uses</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Prosecutor Michael Loucks remembers
clearly when lawyers for Pfizer Inc. (PFE), the world&#8217;s largest drug
company, looked across the table and promised it wouldn&#8217;t break
the law again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was January 2004, and the attorneys were negotiating in
a conference room on the ninth floor of the federal courthouse
in Boston, where Loucks was head of the health-care fraud unit
of the U.S. Attorney&#8217;s Office. One of Pfizer&#8217;s units had been
pushing doctors to prescribe an epilepsy drug called Neurontin
for uses the Food and Drug Administration had never approved. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the agreement the lawyers eventually hammered out, the
Pfizer unit, Warner-Lambert, pleaded guilty to two felony counts
of marketing a drug for unapproved uses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New York-based Pfizer agreed to pay $430 million in
criminal fines and civil penalties, and the company&#8217;s lawyers
assured Loucks and three other prosecutors that Pfizer and its
units would stop promoting drugs for unauthorized purposes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What Loucks, who&#8217;s now acting U.S. attorney in Boston,
didn&#8217;t know until years later was that Pfizer managers were
breaking that pledge not to practice so-called off-label
marketing even before the ink was dry on their plea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the morning of Sept. 2, 2009, another Pfizer unit,
Pharmacia  Upjohn, agreed to plead guilty to the same crime.
This time, Pfizer executives had been instructing more than 100
salespeople to promote Bextra, a drug approved only for the
relief of arthritis and menstrual discomfort, for treatment of
acute pains of all kinds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Record High Fine &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For this new felony, Pfizer paid the largest criminal fine
in U.S. history: $1.19 billion. On the same day, it paid $1
billion to settle civil cases involving the off-label promotion
of Bextra and three other drugs with the U.S. and 49 states. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;At the very same time Pfizer was in our office
negotiating and resolving the allegations of criminal conduct in
2004, Pfizer was itself in its other operations violating those
very same laws,&#8221; Loucks, 54, says. &#8220;They&#8217;ve repeatedly
marketed drugs for things they knew they couldn&#8217;t demonstrate
efficacy for. That&#8217;s clearly criminal.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The penalties Pfizer paid this year for promoting Bextra
off-label were the latest chapter in the drug&#8217;s benighted
history. The FDA found Bextra to be so dangerous that Pfizer
took it off the market for all uses in 2005. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Across the U.S., pharmaceutical companies have been
pleading guilty to criminal charges or paying penalties in civil
cases when the U.S. Department of Justice finds that they
deceptively marketed drugs for unapproved uses, putting millions
of people at risk of chest infections, heart attacks, suicidal
impulses or death. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;$7 Billion in Penalties &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since May 2004, Pfizer, Eli Lilly  Co. (LLY), Bristol-Myers
Squibb Co. and four other drug companies have paid a total of $7
billion in fines and penalties. Six of the companies admitted in
court that they marketed medicines for unapproved uses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In September 2007, New York-based Bristol-Myers (BMY) paid $515
million -- without admitting or denying wrongdoing -- to federal
and state governments in a civil lawsuit brought by the Justice
Department. The six other companies pleaded guilty in criminal
cases. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In January 2009, Indianapolis-based Lilly, the largest U.S.
psychiatric drug maker, pleaded guilty and paid $1.42 billion in
fines and penalties to settle charges that it had for at least
four years illegally marketed Zyprexa, a drug approved for the
treatment of schizophrenia, as a remedy for dementia in elderly
patients. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In five company-sponsored clinical trials, 31 people out of
1,184 participants died after taking the drug for dementia --
twice the death rate for those taking a placebo. Those findings
were reported in an October 2005 article in the Journal of the
American Medical Association. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&#8216;Don&#8217;t Respect the Law&#8217; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Marketing departments of many drug companies don&#8217;t
respect any boundaries of professionalism or the law,&#8221; says
Jerry Avorn, a professor at Harvard Medical School in Boston and
author of &#8220;Powerful Medicines: The Benefits, Risks, and Costs
of Prescription Drugs&#8221; (Random House, 2004). &#8220;The Pfizer and
Lilly cases involved the illegal promotion of drugs that have
been shown to cause substantial harm and death to patients.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The widespread off-label promotion of drugs is yet another
manifestation of a health-care system that has become
dysfunctional. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;It&#8217;s an unbearable cost to a system that&#8217;s going broke,&#8221;
says Avorn, who heads the pharmacology economics unit of Brigham
and Women&#8217;s Hospital in Boston. &#8220;We can&#8217;t even afford to pay
for effective, safe therapies.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;10 Million Prescriptions &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About 15 percent of all drug sales in the U.S. are for
unapproved uses without adequate evidence the medicines work,
according to a study by Randall Stafford, a medical professor at
Stanford University in Palo Alto, California. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He estimates that doctors write more than 10 million such
prescriptions each year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As large as the penalties are for drug companies caught
breaking the off-label law, the fines are tiny compared with the
firms&#8217; annual revenues. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The $2.3 billion in fines and penalties Pfizer paid for
marketing Bextra and three other drugs cited in the Sept. 2 plea
agreement for off-label uses amount to just 14 percent of its
$16.8 billion in revenue from selling those medicines from 2001
to 2008. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The total of $2.75 billion Pfizer has paid in off-label
penalties since 2004 is a little more than 1 percent of the
company&#8217;s revenue of $245 billion from 2004 to 2008. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;$36 Billion in Revenue &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lilly already had a criminal conviction for misbranding a
drug when it broke the law again in promoting schizophrenia drug
Zyprexa for off-label uses starting in 1999. The medication
provided Lilly with $36 billion in revenue from 2000 to 2008. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&#8217;s more than 25 times as much as the total penalties
Lilly paid in January. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies regard the risk of multimillion-dollar penalties
as just another cost of doing business, says Lon Schneider, a
professor at the University of Southern California&#8217;s Keck School
of Medicine in Los Angeles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2006, he led a study for the National Institute of
Mental Health of off-label use of drugs, including Zyprexa, for
the treatment of Alzheimer&#8217;s disease. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;There&#8217;s an unwritten business plan,&#8221; he says. &#8220;They&#8217;re
drivers that knowingly speed. If stopped, they pay the fine, and
then they do it again.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Shareholders Unmoved &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schneider has been paid both by Lilly as a consultant and
by plaintiffs suing the company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Big Pharma&#8217;s off-label transgressions didn&#8217;t trigger a rush
for the doors by shareholders. From Jan. 26, when Pfizer
announced that it would pay billions in penalties, to Oct. 12,
Pfizer&#8217;s share price increased 9.3 percent, just shy of the
11.2 percent rise in the Standard  Poor&#8217;s 500 Health Care
Index. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Oct. 21, 2008, when Lilly said it would pay its
penalties, to Oct. 12, the company&#8217;s stock value went up 0.6
percent; the SP index gained 6.9 percent in that time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In pushing off-label use of drugs, companies find ready and
willing partners in physicians. Under the fragmented system of
medical regulation in the U.S., it&#8217;s legal for doctors to
prescribe FDA-approved drugs for any use. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The FDA has no authority over doctors, only over drug
companies, regarding off-label practices. It&#8217;s up to the 50
states to oversee physicians. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;I think the physician community has to take some
ownership responsibility and do their own due diligence beyond
the sales and marketing person,&#8221; says Boston&#8217;s former U.S.
Attorney Michael Sullivan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Off-Label Benefits &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loucks says prosecutors realize that patients can benefit
when doctors use drugs for off-label purposes based on science
and not on false marketing claims. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doctors generally don&#8217;t tell people that they&#8217;re
prescribing drugs pitched to them by pharmaceutical salespeople
for unapproved treatments, says Peter Lurie, deputy medical
director of Public Citizen, a Washington-based public interest
group. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most physicians don&#8217;t keep track of FDA-approved uses of
drugs, says Lurie, a physician who has published articles in
&#8220;The Lancet&#8221; and the &#8220;Journal of the American Medical
Association.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;The great majority of doctors have no idea; they don&#8217;t
even understand the distinction between on- and off-labeling,&#8221;
Lurie says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pharmaceutical companies have showered doctors with cash to
persuade them to use drugs off-label, according to their guilty
pleas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&#8216;Buying Access&#8217; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer&#8217;s marketing program offered doctors up to $1,000 a
day to allow a Pfizer salesperson to spend time with the
physician and his patients, according to a whistle-blower
lawsuit filed by John Kopchinski, who worked as a salesman at
Pfizer from 1992 to 2003. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;By &#8216;pairing up&#8217; with a physician, the sales
representative was able to promote over a period of many hours,
without the usual problems of gaining access to prescribing
physicians,&#8221; Kopchinski says. &#8220;In essence, this amounted to
Pfizer buying access to physicians.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer spokesman Chris Loder says the company stopped what
it calls &#8220;mentorships&#8221; in 2005. He says Pfizer paid doctors
$250 per visit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It used to be legal for companies to promote drugs for any
use in the U.S. Congress banned the practice in 1962. The
catalyst was Thalidomide, a morning sickness drug taken by
pregnant women outside the U.S. that caused severe birth
defects. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Recouping Investments &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1962 law required pharmaceutical companies to prove
their drugs were safe and effective for specific uses. Before
that, a drug company could market an approved medicine for any
illness. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the law is clear, why do drug companies keep breaking
it? The answer lies in economics. Pharmaceutical companies spend
about $1 billion to develop and test a new drug. To recoup their
investment, the companies want doctors to prescribe their drugs
as widely as possible. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer&#8217;s Neurontin is a case in point. The FDA approved the
drug as a supplemental medication in treating epilepsy in 1993.
Pfizer took in $2.27 billion from sales of Neurontin in 2002. A
full 94 percent -- $2.12 billion -- of that revenue came from
off-label use, according to the prosecutors&#8217; 2004 Pfizer
sentencing memo. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer, which bought Wyeth on Oct. 15 for $68 billion, put
itself at the center of illegal off-label drug marketing with an
acquisition frenzy a decade earlier. From 1995 to 2005, Pfizer
purchased more than 20 companies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Guilty Pleas &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2004, companies that are now Pfizer divisions have
pleaded guilty to off-label marketing of two drugs. Pfizer
continued off-label promotions for these medications after
buying the firms, according to Pfizer&#8217;s Sept. 2 guilty plea and
FDA correspondence with Pfizer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer first stepped into an off-label scheme in 1999, when
it offered to buy Morris Plains, New Jersey-based Warner-Lambert
Co. Prosecutors charged that Warner-Lambert marketed Neurontin
off-label between 1995 and 1999. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warner-Lambert admitted doing so for one year in a May 2004
guilty plea for which Pfizer paid $430 million in fines and
penalties. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Neurontin, which was invented by Warner-Lambert, was first
tested in humans in 1987. When the FDA approved it in 1993 to be
used only along with other epilepsy drugs, the agency wrote that
a side effect of the drug can be that it induces depression and
suicidal thoughts in patients. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Whistle-Blower &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of what prosecutors learned about Warner-Lambert&#8217;s
marketing of Neurontin comes from a former employee. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Franklin, who holds a Ph.D. in microbiology from the
University of Rhode Island, left his job as a pediatric
researcher at Harvard University&#8217;s Dana-Farber Cancer Institute
in 1996 to work for the Parke-Davis unit of Warner-Lambert in
Boston. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He says he hoped the salary boost -- to $55,000 annually
from $18,000 -- would help him pay off student loans and better
support his family. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Franklin&#8217;s title at Warner-Lambert was medical liaison. He
says he soon realized his new employer viewed his doctorate as a
badge that would allow him to strike up conversations with
physicians. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Franklin, 48, says his job involved more salesmanship than
science. He told doctors that Neurontin was the best drug for a
dozen off-label uses, including pain relief, bipolar disease and
depression. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&#8216;What I Did Was Wrong&#8217; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Technically, I had responsibility for answering physician
questions about all of Parke-Davis&#8217;s drugs,&#8221; Franklin says.
&#8220;In practice, my real job was to promote Neurontin for off-label indications heavily -- to the exclusion of just about
everything else.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Franklin, whose wife is a lawyer, says he knew such uses of
the drug had no scientific support for effectiveness and safety. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;I was actually undermining their ability to fulfill the
Hippocratic oath,&#8221; Franklin says, referring to a physician&#8217;s
pledge to &#8220;first, do no harm.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Franklin says he was horrified when he learned from a
doctor that a child had a behavioral outburst at school for the
first time after taking Neurontin. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Don&#8217;t we have an obligation to tell physicians about
this?&#8221; Franklin says he asked his manager, Phil Magistro. His
boss tried to reassure him, Franklin says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&#8216;Total Disregard&#8217; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;&#8216;Don&#8217;t worry about this stuff,&#8217;&#8221; he says Magistro told
him. &#8220;&#8216;It can never get back to us.&#8217;&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Franklin was stunned. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;I realized at that moment, looking into his eyes, that
there was an absolute total disregard for the patient,&#8221; he
says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Magistro, who now works at drug marketing adviser Atom
Strategic Consulting LLC in Randolph, New Jersey, didn&#8217;t return
calls seeking comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Franklin saved phone messages from Magistro to his sales
team urging them to market Neurontin for off-label uses,
including pain relief. During one such call, on May 23, 1996, at
5:48 p.m. in Boston, Magistro told his staff, &#8220;You&#8217;re supposed
to be pushing on Neurontin,&#8221; according to a transcript of the
tape filed in federal court. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;When we get out there, we want to kick some ass. We want
to sell Neurontin on pain,&#8221; Magistro said. &#8220;All right?&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Quit the Job &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After working for Warner-Lambert for three months, Franklin
grew concerned about his own liability. He quit the job and
talked with Boston attorney Thomas Greene, who helped him file a
lawsuit against the company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Franklin acted as a whistle-blower, suing on behalf of
taxpayers to recover money the government paid for illegally
promoted drugs. Under federal and state whistle-blower statutes,
he stood to collect as much as 30 percent of any settlement the
company made with the government. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Franklin had to wait four years -- until 2000 -- before the
Justice Department began a criminal investigation. In November
1999, Pfizer made its public offer to buy Warner-Lambert. In
January 2000, a federal grand jury in Boston issued subpoenas to
Warner-Lambert employees to testify about the marketing of
Neurontin. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That March, Warner-Lambert&#8217;s annual report disclosed that
prosecutors were building a criminal case. Undeterred, Pfizer
bought Warner-Lambert in June for $87 billion. It was the third-largest merger in U.S. history. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&#8216;Misleading and in Violation&#8217; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A year after the acquisition, the FDA discovered that
Neurontin was still being marketed off-label. In a letter to
the company on June 29, 2001, the agency wrote that Pfizer&#8217;s
promotion of the drug &#8220;is misleading and in violation of the
Federal Food, Drug and Cosmetics Act.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The agency asked Pfizer to stop such promotions of
Neurontin. The FDA said Pfizer had distributed brochures --
known as &#8220;slim jims&#8221; because they&#8217;re small enough to put in a
jacket pocket -- improperly claiming that the drug could improve
energy levels and memory. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Immediately discontinue the use of this slim jim and any
other promotional material or practices with the same or similar
messages,&#8221; the FDA wrote. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer marketed Neurontin off-label after receiving that
letter, agency records show. For 2001, Pfizer reported revenue
of $1.75 billion from Neurontin sales, making it the company&#8217;s
fourth-largest-selling drug that year, ahead of impotence pill
Viagra, which Neurontin topped for four years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Marketing Violated Rules &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Neurontin sales soared to $2.27 billion in 2002, the FDA
found that Pfizer was improperly claiming that the drug was
useful for a broader range of brain disorders than scientific
evidence had established. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The agency sent a letter dated July 1, 2002, that said the
company&#8217;s marketing practices were in violation of FDA rules. It
asked Pfizer to stop using misleading promotions. Pfizer
reported $2.7 billion in revenue from Neurontin in 2003.
Overall, the drug has provided Pfizer with $12 billion in
revenue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a response to Bloomberg News, Pfizer spokesman Chris
Loder said, &#8220;Regarding the 2001 and 2002 FDA letters, we do not
believe that they were suggestive of any continuing off-label
promotion.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For blowing the whistle on his employer, Franklin collected
$24.6 million under the False Claims Act. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prosecutors Loucks and Sullivan got involved in the case
after Franklin filed his suit, relying on information from
Franklin and their own investigation. Before 2004, prosecutions
for off-label marketing were rare. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&#8216;Everybody Does It&#8217; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Until a couple of these cases became public, companies
were probably saying, &#8216;Everybody does it this way,&#8217;&#8221; Sullivan
says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loucks had a track record in off-label prosecutions. He
gave up private practice at Choate Hall  Stewart LLP in Boston
in 1985 to join the U.S. Attorney&#8217;s Office. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1994, he negotiated a $61 million settlement with Murray
Hill, New Jersey-based C.R. Bard Inc., which pleaded guilty to
promoting off-label use of a heart catheter that led to patient
deaths. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2002, he co-authored, with Carol Lam, &#8220;Prosecuting and
Defending Health Care Fraud Cases&#8221; (BNA Books). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the January 2004 settlement negotiations with Loucks,
Sullivan and two other prosecutors, Pfizer&#8217;s lawyers assured the
U.S. Attorney&#8217;s Office that the company wouldn&#8217;t market drugs
off-label. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&#8216;Those Promises&#8217; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;They asserted that the company understood the rules and
had taken steps to assure corporate compliance with the law,&#8221;
Loucks says. &#8220;We remember those promises.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What Pfizer&#8217;s lawyers didn&#8217;t tell the prosecutors was that
Pfizer was at that moment running an off-label marketing
promotion using more than 100 of its salespeople. They were
pitching Bextra, a Pfizer sales manager admitted when she
pleaded guilty to misbranding a drug on March 30, 2009. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jeff Kindler, who became Pfizer&#8217;s general counsel in 2002,
supervised the lawyers who made the promises to prosecutors. By
2004, Kindler increased the compliance budget 12-fold. He became
chief executive officer in 2006. In Pfizer&#8217;s ethics guide,
he says stories about misbehaving companies and executives
abound. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Pfizer truly stands apart,&#8221; he says. &#8220;I am proud of our
record.&#8221; On Oct. 1, Kindler was elected to the board of the
Federal Reserve Bank of New York. Kindler declined to comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peapack, New Jersey-based Pharmacia  Upjohn Inc. developed
Bextra, which was approved by the FDA only for the treatment of
arthritis and menstrual discomfort in 2001. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Sales Manager Pleads Guilty &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PU and Pfizer had by then already crafted a joint
marketing agreement to sell the drug. In November 2001, Mary
Holloway, a Pfizer regional manager for the Northeastern U.S.,
began illegally training and directing her sales team to market
Bextra for the relief of acute pain, Holloway admitted in a
March 2009 guilty plea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Dec. 4, 2001, Pfizer executives sent Holloway a copy of
a nonpublic letter from the FDA to the company. The agency had
denied Pfizer&#8217;s application to market Bextra for acute pain.
Clinical trials had shown Bextra could cause heart damage and
death. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer bought Pharmacia  Upjohn in April 2003. From 2001
to the end of 2003, PU, first as an independent company and
then as a unit of Pfizer, paid physicians more than $5 million
in cash to lure them to resorts, where salespeople illegally
pitched off-label uses for Bextra, PU admitted in its Sept. 2
guilty plea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&#8216;Golf, Massages&#8217; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Pharmacia paid targeted physicians both airfare and two
to three days&#8217; accommodations at lavish resorts in the Bahamas,
Virgin Islands and across the United States and further
entertained these physicians with golf, massages and other
recreation activities,&#8221; according to prosecutors&#8217; findings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In her guilty plea, Holloway said her team had solicited
hospitals to create protocols to buy Bextra for the unapproved
purpose of acute pain relief. Her representatives didn&#8217;t mention
the increased risk of heart attacks in their marketing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They told doctors that side effects were no worse than
those of a sugar pill, Holloway admitted in her guilty plea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2003, Holloway reported her unit&#8217;s off-label promotions
of Bextra up the corporate ladder at Pfizer, according to a pre-sentencing memo to the judge written by Robert Ullmann,
Holloway&#8217;s attorney. Top managers didn&#8217;t attempt to halt the
illegal conduct, the memo said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Corporate tracked this information, and at no time did it
inform Ms. Holloway that any of the reported protocols were
inappropriate,&#8221; he wrote. &#8220;Instead, the instruction was to get
more protocols.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Blockbuster Status &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of 2004, Bextra reached blockbuster status, with
annual sales of $1.29 billion. Holloway promoted Bextra until
the FDA asked Pfizer in April 2005 to pull it from the market
for all uses, evidence in her case shows. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The agency concluded that the drug increased the risk of
heart attacks, chest infections and strokes in cardiac surgery
patients. In June 2009, Holloway, 47, was sentenced to two years
on probation and fined $75,000. She didn&#8217;t return phone calls
seeking comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ronald Rainero, a Pfizer district sales manager and
employee for more than 20 years, says he was responsible for
promoting Bextra in New York from 2001 to 2005. In September
2007, Rainero, 47, began cooperating with federal prosecutors on
the Bextra case. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hotel Meetings &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He says he met monthly with his fellow managers at a Hilton
hotel in Staten Island, New York, to discuss sales methods of
promoting Bextra off-label. As a whistle-blower, Rainero was
awarded $9.3 million as part of the September settlement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the same time period that Pfizer was marketing Bextra
off-label, the company&#8217;s sales force was promoting another drug,
Zyvox, improperly, Pfizer admitted at the time of its September
plea agreement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zyvox was approved in 2000 by the FDA for treating MRSA-caused pneumonia and skin infections. Raniero told federal
prosecutors that Pfizer began the Zyvox campaign in 2001. The
company admitted to falsely claiming that the drug was better
than other medications for treating MRSA pneumonia. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer told doctors to use Zyvox rather than vancomycin, a
generic antibiotic that cost $18 a day. Pfizer sold Zyvox for
about $150 a day. A table on page 30 of a 35-page fact book
produced by Pfizer for Zyvox says the drug is less effective
than vancomycin for MRSA pneumonia. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&#8216;Misleading Promotion&#8217; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On July 20, 2005, the FDA sent a letter to Hank McKinnell,
then Pfizer&#8217;s CEO, saying, &#8220;Your misleading promotion of Zyvox,
and in particular your unsubstantiated implied claims regarding
its superiority to vancomycin, poses serious health and safety
concerns.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The agency ordered the company to stop the promotion. In
response, Pfizer told the FDA it would stop saying Zyvox was
more effective against MRSA pneumonia than vancomycin. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite its 2005 pledge to the FDA, Pfizer continued to
tell hospitals and doctors that Zyvox would save more lives than
vancomycin, the company admitted in the September settlement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By 2007, the criminal and civil cases against Pfizer, its
employees and its subsidiaries had started to mount. The tally
of drugs cited by federal prosecutors for off-label promotion
reached six by 2009. In April 2007, PU pleaded guilty to a
felony charge of offering a $12 million kickback to a pharmacy
benefit manager. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;$2.2 Billion in Penalties &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer paid a criminal fine of $19.7 million. Thomas
Farina, a Pfizer district sales manager, was convicted in
federal court in March 2009 for destroying records during the
Bextra investigation. Farina, 42, was sentenced to three years
on probation, including six months of home confinement. He
didn&#8217;t return calls seeking comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer itself was called to account on Sept. 2, when it
agreed to pay the $2.2 billion in fines and penalties. PU
pleaded guilty to a felony charge of misbranding Bextra with the
intent to defraud. After the settlement, Pfizer general counsel
Amy Schulman said the company had learned its lesson. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;We regret certain actions we&#8217;ve taken in the past,&#8221; she
said. &#8220;Corporate integrity is an absolute priority for
Pfizer.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One reason drug companies keep breaking the law may be
because prosecutors and judges have been unwilling to use the
ultimate sanction -- a felony conviction that would render a
company&#8217;s drugs ineligible for reimbursement by state health
programs and federal Medicare. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;It&#8217;s potentially a death sentence for a drug company,&#8221;
prosecutor Sullivan says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fig Leaf &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A legal fig leaf allows a parent company to continue to
participate in government programs even after its subsidiary has
pleaded guilty. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer maintains its good standing with such agencies
because its subsidiaries, Warner-Lambert and PU, and not the
corporation itself, entered the guilty pleas to felony charges. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A felony conviction of a pharmaceutical giant could lead to
disaster for shareholders, Loucks says, adding that&#8217;s a step
that may have to be taken for repeat offenders. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;I think it&#8217;s something the trigger will get pulled on,&#8221;
he says from his ninth-floor office in the federal courthouse,
with a sweeping view of Boston Harbor. &#8220;It&#8217;s just a question of
when.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Pfizer&#8217;s Pharmacia sentencing on Oct. 16., U.S. District
Court Judge Douglas Woodlock said companies don&#8217;t appear to take
the law seriously. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;It has become something of a cost of doing business for
some of these corporations, to shed their skin like certain
animals and leave the skin and move on,&#8221; he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Eli Lilly &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lilly&#8217;s rap sheet goes back to 1985. That&#8217;s when the
company pleaded guilty to 25 federal misdemeanor charges related
to its misbranding of Oraflex, an arthritis drug. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lilly stopped selling the drug four months after U.S. sales
began in 1982, following the company&#8217;s failure to tell the FDA
about illnesses and deaths tied to the medication. Lilly paid a
$25,000 fine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twenty years later, in 2005, Lilly paid $36 million in a
guilty plea to one federal misdemeanor for off-label marketing
of Evista, a drug the FDA had approved for bone strengthening. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1997, the agency had rejected Lilly&#8217;s application to
market the drug to reduce the risk of breast cancer. Yet
beginning the next year, Lilly adopted an Evista marketing plan
that included a seminar with doctors designed to appeal to
women&#8217;s breast cancer concerns, Lilly admitted in its 2005
guilty plea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2007, the FDA approved Evista for preventing breast
cancer in two limited groups. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Back in Court &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In January 2009, Lilly was back in federal court.
Prosecutors in Philadelphia accused the company of earning
hundreds of millions of dollars by illegally promoting its
schizophrenia drug Zyprexa for the unapproved treatment of
dementia from 1999 to at least 2003. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2001, Lilly&#8217;s senior management decided not to seek FDA
approval for Zyprexa to treat dementia because of what they
viewed as mixed results in clinical trials and safety risks,
according to admissions by Lilly in its 2009 guilty plea. In its
marketing, Lilly promoted the drug as effective. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zyprexa has been Lilly&#8217;s best-selling drug for the past
decade. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Eli Lilly undertook this illegal off-label promotion for
its own financial gain despite the potential risk to patients&#8217;
health and lives,&#8221; prosecutors wrote in their sentencing memo. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lilly Chairman and CEO John Lechleiter said after the
settlement that the company was devoted to acting responsibly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&#8216;Deeply Regret&#8217; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;We deeply regret the past actions covered by the
misdemeanor plea,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Doing the right thing is
nonnegotiable at Lilly.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a written response to questions from Bloomberg News,
Lilly said, &#8220;Lilly entered into a very narrow guilty plea. Even
though the company disagrees with and does not admit to the
allegations, Lilly agreed to settle the dispute.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lilly paid $1.42 billion for a fine and penalties in the
January settlement with federal and state governments. That
included the largest criminal fine in U.S. history -- until
Pfizer pleaded guilty in September. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Justice Department could have charged Lilly with a
felony. Prosecutors decided that it wouldn&#8217;t be fair to innocent
Lilly employees, shareholders and pensioners to potentially shut
down the company, according to the sentencing memo. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&#8216;All the Factors&#8217; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;The government considered all the factors in its
decision,&#8221; prosecutors wrote. &#8220;Those factors included other
persons not proven personally culpable.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Federal regulators have detected a similar pattern of
dishonesty by other pharmaceutical firms. Schering-Plough Corp.
drug salesmen pitched off-label uses of a cancer drug called
Temodar at the American Society of Clinical Oncology&#8217;s annual
conference in San Francisco in May 2001. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schering-Plough representatives said Temodar compared
favorably to a placebo in clinical trials for the off-label uses
and was approved by the FDA for first-line use in treating brain
tumors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An FDA employee attending the conference took note. The
next month, the FDA accused Schering of lying. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There had been no such clinical trials and the agency had
not approved Temodar as the salespeople had claimed, the FDA
said in a June 28, 2001, letter to Mary Jane Nehring, Schering&#8217;s
senior director of marketed products. The agency ordered the
company to immediately cease illegal promotion of Temodar. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kenilworth, New Jersey-based Schering-Plough was quick to
respond. On July 12, 2001, it wrote back to the FDA, assuring
regulators that the San Francisco activity was an isolated
incident. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&#8216;Certainly Inconsistent&#8217; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;It was certainly inconsistent with the direction provided
by the home office,&#8221; the drug company wrote, according to
prosecutor&#8217;s records. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The FDA told Schering-Plough three weeks later that it had
closed its investigation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schering-Plough didn&#8217;t stop pitching the drug for
unapproved uses. At the direction of top management, Schering
ordered widespread off-label marketing of Temodar and Intron A,
another cancer drug, until December 2003, the company admitted
in an August 2006 guilty plea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schering, which agreed in March to be acquired by Merck 
Co., earned a pre-tax profit of $124.2 million from the illegal
sales after promising the FDA in 2001 it would stop marketing
for off-label uses, the company admitted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schering-Plough pleaded guilty in August 2006 to conspiring
to make false statements to the FDA. The company agreed to pay
$435 million to settle the case. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&#8216;Upsetting to Me&#8217; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;U.S. District Court Judge Patti Saris, who had presided
over the Neurontin whistle-blower case before the Pfizer probe,
accepted Schering&#8217;s plea in her Boston courtroom in January
2007. She expressed dismay with the drug industry. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;It&#8217;s been upsetting to me how many of the big
pharmaceutical companies have engaged in what I view as clearly
illegal behavior in terms of off-label marketing,&#8221; she said.
&#8220;It almost seems as if the pharmaceutical companies said &#8216;Yeah,
yeah, yeah&#8217; to the FDA and then went and did it anyway.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brent Saunders, a Schering-Plough senior vice president,
said after the settlement that his company had made great
progress in putting integrity at the center of its work. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;With this agreement, we are putting issues from the past
behind us,&#8221; he said. Schering declined to comment further. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As prosecutors continue to uncover patterns of deceit in
off-label marketing by pharmaceutical companies, millions of
patients across the nation remain in the dark. Doctors often
choose the medications based on dishonest marketing by drug
company salesmen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&#8216;A Morass&#8217; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;It&#8217;s a morass of undifferentiated information out
there,&#8221; Public Citizen&#8217;s Lurie says. &#8220;And the doctors, let
alone patients, aren&#8217;t able to distinguish the good from the
bad.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing all people should do, Lurie says, is ask whether
their prescriptions are for FDA-approved uses, and if not,
whether strong evidence supports using the drug, particularly if
it can be dangerous. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Loucks says that putting an end to the criminal off-label
schemes by the pharmaceutical industry is more difficult. As
drugmakers repeatedly plead guilty, they&#8217;ve shown they&#8217;re
willing to pay hundreds of millions of dollars in fines as a
cost of generating billions in revenue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best hope, Loucks says, is that drug companies actually
honor the promises they keep making -- and keep breaking -- to
obey the law of the land. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By David Wethe and Edward Klump" date="Nov 17, 2009  1:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-11-17/devon-seen-finding-ample-demand-as-exxon-eni-chase-oil-assets.html"><headline>Devon Seen Finding Ample Demand as Exxon, Eni Chase Oil Assets</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Devon Energy Corp. (DVN), the biggest
independent oil and gas producer in the U.S., has plenty of
company in seeking to sell billions of dollars in energy assets.
It may also find plenty of suitors eager to bid. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oklahoma City-based Devon said yesterday that it will sell
its Gulf of Mexico and overseas holdings, raising as much as
$7.5 billion to cut debt and fund onshore projects in the U.S.
and Canada. The plan follows an announcement by ConocoPhillips
to sell $10 billion in assets and a West Africa sale by Kosmos
Energy LLC valued at an estimated $4 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A spate of divestitures won&#8217;t satiate buyers as producers
such as Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) and Royal Dutch Shell (RDSA) Plc seek to
boost reserves, bankers said. There have been $132.7 billion in
oil and gas acquisitions in 2009, the lowest total for this time
of year since 2003, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;There aren&#8217;t that many assets out there,&#8221; said Cameron Smith, head of the Rodman Energy Group in New York. &#8220;This could
be an indication that the flood of assets that the buy side has
been looking for may be beginning.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smith said the Devon fields shouldn&#8217;t depress prices for
oil and natural-gas properties; rather, the sales may help
establish values in a market that&#8217;s had too few transactions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Devon said its sales should be done next year and will
include stakes in deepwater Gulf of Mexico projects and holdings
in Brazil&#8217;s prolific Campos Basin, the South China Sea and the
Caspian Sea. Sales should be done next year, the company said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Deepwater Players &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;They will be selling decent assets that have long lead
times and negative cash flows in the interim,&#8221; said John E. Olson, who manages about $50 million, including oil stocks, at
Houston Energy Partners. &#8220;That will have value to some of the
deepwater players.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prospective buyers include BP (BP/) Plc, Shell, Irving, Texas-based Exxon Mobil and Statoil ASA (STL), Olson said. State-controlled
producers in China and Brazil also may bid, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Devon received inquiries from major oil companies about its
Campos Basin stake, Chief Executive Officer Larry Nichols told
investors yesterday on a conference call. London-based BP,
Devon&#8217;s partner in a Gulf of Mexico discovery known as Kaskida,
announced yesterday that a second well drilled 5 miles to the
west of an earlier well found oil. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Devon&#8217;s assets are high-quality assets,&#8221; said Stephen Trauber, global head of energy investing at UBS AG. &#8220;For high-quality assets, I don&#8217;t think there are ever too many assets in
the marketplace.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Total, Eni &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Total SA (FP), Italy&#8217;s Eni SpA (ENI), and Melbourne-based BHP Billiton
Ltd. (BHP) are among potential buyers for some of Devon&#8217;s properties,
Trauber said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Maybe BP and Shell will look, but they&#8217;ve got a lot of
their own projects to work on, so it&#8217;s probably not them,&#8221;
Trauber said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Houston-based Apache (APA) Corp. could be a buyer, said Leo Mariani, an analyst at RBC Capital Markets in Austin, Texas.
&#8220;I&#8217;m sure they&#8217;re approaching folks as we speak about assets
out there,&#8221; he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apache doesn&#8217;t comment on specific acquisition
opportunities, said Bill Mintz, a company spokesman. &#8220;We&#8217;ve
said we&#8217;re always looking,&#8221; Mintz said. &#8220;We look at lots of
opportunities.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Access to Reserves &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bill Tanner, a spokesman for The Hague-based Shell,
declined to comment on the company&#8217;s potential interest in any
of Devon&#8217;s holdings, as did Daren Beaudo of BP, Rob Young of
Exxon Mobil, Kjersti Torgersen of Norway&#8217;s Statoil and Ruban
Yogarajah of BHP Billiton. Phenelope Semavoine, a spokeswoman
for France&#8217;s Total, and Erika Mandraffino of Eni didn&#8217;t
immediately respond to messages seeking comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Major oil producers such as Shell and Exxon Mobil have
limited places to invest after countries such as Venezuela
reduced foreign access to reserves, said James Halloran, a
consultant at Financial America Securities in Cleveland. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Closely held Kosmos, based in Dallas, said last month that
it agreed to sell its Ghana assets to Exxon Mobil. Ghana&#8217;s state
oil company said it plans to buy Kosmos&#8217;s stake in the offshore
Jubilee field. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Halloran and Mark Gilman, an analyst at Benchmark Co. in
New York, said there&#8217;s little or no overlap between the type of
properties that Devon is selling and those that ConocoPhillips (COP)
will likely unload. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;I don&#8217;t think the people who are looking at their assets
are going to say, &#8216;We&#8217;re either going to buy from Devon or we&#8217;re
going to buy from Conoco,&#8217;&#8221; Halloran said. &#8220;It&#8217;s not like two
guys that own houses side by side on a street trying to sell
their houses.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Mark Gilbert" date="Nov 18, 2009  8:59 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-11-18/goldman-s-500-million-is-day-late-dollar-short-mark-gilbert.html"><headline>Goldman&#8217;s $500 Million Is Day Late, Dollar Short: Mark Gilbert</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;So now we know the value Goldman
Sachs Group Inc. places on salving its conscience for screwing
up what Chief Executive Officer Lloyd Blankfein called &#8220;God&#8217;s
work.&#8221; It seems that $500 million is all it takes to compensate
the world for Goldman&#8217;s role in creating the credit crunch. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman said yesterday it&#8217;s setting up a &#8220;10,000 Small
Businesses Initiative.&#8221; It will shell out $200 million to
educational institutions to help guide business owners, with a
further $300 million invested for lending and philanthropy aimed
at community development groups. Billionaire investor Warren Buffett, whose Berkshire Hathaway Inc. is the largest Goldman
shareholder, is joining the initiative. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#8217;s another way of looking at this sudden burst of
supposed generosity. Goldman has $16.7 billion stashed in its
bonus pot from the record profit earned in the first nine months
of the year, which works out at $527,192 per staffer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That means those 10,000 small businesses the securities
firm says it wants to help are worth the equivalent of about
1,000 Goldman employees. Alternatively, a Goldmanite&#8217;s average
contribution to society is pitched at the equivalent of 10 small
enterprises, based on that bonus-versus-charity calculation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;False Gods &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even at the Stakhanovite work rates the firm legendarily
squeezes out of its staff, that&#8217;s quite a stretch. The idea that
one banker is worth 10 businesses is the kind of math that got
us into this mess, with finance falsely elevated until it became
an end in itself, rather than a means to providing services to
the real economy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The public isn&#8217;t likely to fall for this charade. The
financial community has already spent too many years parading
its charitable contributions to help divert attention from its
risk-taking adventures. Tax-deductible gestures are no longer
sufficient to comfort those who have seen their pension pots
devastated by the credit crisis; even with this year&#8217;s rallies,
the total value of the major global stock exchanges is still a
bit less than $45 trillion, down from a peak of almost $62
trillion at the end of 2007, before the subprime meltdown
wrecked the global economy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Potentially more valuable than the charity fig-leaf is the
apology Blankfein made yesterday. &#8220;We participated in things
that were clearly wrong and have reason to regret,&#8221; Blankfein,
55, said at a conference in New York hosted by a magazine called
Directorship. It would be nice to think that banking chiefs
truly -- albeit very belatedly -- recognize that their reckless
propagation of alchemical securities must never be repeated. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fawning Adoration &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blankfein&#8217;s apology might ring truer, however, if he hadn&#8217;t
been named CEO of the year by the magazine whose conference he
was gracing with his presence. The fawning adoration for the
multimillionaires who run the banking industry has only been
diminished, not destroyed, by the damage their actions wrought. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If he worked for anyone other than Goldman Sachs, Blankfein
would probably be out of a job by now. His remark earlier this
month to the Sunday Times magazine that bankers are &#8220;doing
God&#8217;s work&#8221; is the kind of indiscretion that loses you the key
to the executive bathroom at most public companies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter how many charitable donations it makes, Goldman
will struggle to shake off the moniker bestowed on it by Matt
Taibbi in Rolling Stone magazine earlier this year. Taibbi
described the firm as &#8220;a great vampire squid wrapped around the
face of humanity, relentlessly jamming its blood funnel into
anything that smells like money.&#8221; Goldman and its peers need to
practice humility and contriteness for an extended period,
rather than seeking image-buffing headlines with token gestures. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Mark Gilbert is the London bureau chief and a columnist
for Bloomberg News. The opinions expressed are his own.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click on &#8220;Send Comment&#8221; in the sidebar display to send a
letter to the editor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Sarah McDonald and Yusuke Miyazawa" date="Nov 19, 2009  1:22 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-11-19/citigroup-goldman-sachs-hybrids-face-cut-by-moody-s-update3-.html"><headline>Citigroup, Goldman Sachs Hybrids Face Cut by Moody&#8217;s</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Debt sold by Citigroup Inc. (C), Goldman
Sachs Group Inc. (GS) and JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) is among the $450
billion of securities that Moody&#8217;s Investors Service (MCO) said it may
downgrade. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some 775 hybrid and subordinated notes sold by 170 &#8220;bank
families&#8221; in 36 countries are on review after Moody&#8217;s altered
assumptions used in ratings, the risk assessor said yesterday in
a statement. Aflac Inc., a Columbus, Georgia-based health
insurer which had almost 20 percent of its investment portfolio
in perpetual securities as of Sept. 30, fell $1.31, or 2.9
percent, to $43.63 at 1:20 p.m. in New York Stock Exchange
composite trading, it&#8217;s biggest drop since Oct. 30. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;The key concern is whether the ratings downgrades trigger
investment mandate breaches which could force investors to
sell,&#8221; said Ben Byrne, a credit analyst at Nomura Australia
Ltd. in Sydney. &#8220;We think the majority of the selling has
already occurred, given that hybrids have been trading at prices
significantly lower than their current ratings suggest are
appropriate.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Half the hybrids may have their ratings lowered by three to
four grades, 40 percent may be cut by one or two grades and the
rest may be lowered five steps or more, New York-based Moody&#8217;s
said. &lt;/p&gt;




Photographer: Jeremy Bales/Bloomberg

&lt;p&gt;
The headquarters building of Citigroup Inc. stands at 399 Park Avenue in New York, on Sept. 15, 2009. Close
&lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Christine Harper" date="Nov 25, 2009  1:15 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-11-25/goldman-sachs-hires-christoffersen-after-two-years-update1-.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Hires Christoffersen After Two Years</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), the most
profitable securities firm in Wall Street history, hired back
Kasper Christoffersen almost two years after he left to join a
hedge fund in London. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christoffersen, 36, starts Dec. 1 in London as a managing
director and co-head of the European investment-grade syndicate
group with Ian Gilday, said Michael DuVally, a spokesman for
Goldman Sachs in New York. Gilday will continue running the
European high-yield and loan capital markets syndicate division. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christoffersen, a Danish national, ran European government
bond trading at Goldman Sachs before leaving in early 2008 for
Autonomy Capital Research LLP, a hedge-fund firm founded in 2003
by former Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. trader Robert Gibbins. A
year ago, Autonomy halted withdrawals from its $1.2 billion
flagship Autonomy Capital Fund after slumping about 40 percent
in the year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Goldman Sachs, Christoffersen and Gilday, who are both
based in London, will report to Jim Esposito, the New York-based
global head of investment-grade and municipal financing, and to
Francois Xavier de Mallmann, who runs the European financing
group from London, DuVally said. Goldman Sachs&#8217;s financing group
operates as a joint venture between the investment banking and
sales and trading departments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;James Garvey &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;James Garvey, who ran the European debt capital markets
business at Goldman Sachs, left the firm earlier this year. He
joined Lloyds Banking Group Plc (LLOY) in September as head of its
capital markets and advisory unit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman Sachs ranks 14th among underwriters of debt from
European issuers this year, down from 13th in 2008, according to
data compiled by Bloomberg. The firm&#8217;s debt underwriting
business globally made $795 million in revenue in the first nine
months of 2009, down from $989 million in the first three
quarters of fiscal 2008. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Christoffersen&#8217;s appointment was reported earlier today by
Financial News. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Roger Neill" date="Nov 27, 2009  1:12 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-11-27/dsg-cut-to-sell-from-neutral-at-goldman-sachs.html"><headline>DSG Cut to &#8216;Sell&#8217; From &#8216;Neutral&#8217; at Goldman Sachs</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;DSG International Plc, the U.K.&#8217;s
largest consumer-electronics retailer, was cut to &#8220;sell&#8221; from
&#8220;neutral&#8221; at Goldman Sachs Group Inc., which cited &#8220;weak
supply chain positioning and a high and fixed cost base.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Alice Schroeder" date="Dec 03, 2009  1:57 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-12-03/arming-goldman-sachs-with-pistols-alice-schroeder-correct-.html"><headline>Arming Goldman Sachs With Pistols: Alice Schroeder</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;(Corrects second paragraph of story published Dec. 1 to say
the New York Police Department believes some bankers may have
received handgun permits.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;I just wrote my first reference for
a gun permit,&#8221; said a friend, who told me of swearing to the
good character of a Goldman Sachs Group Inc. banker who applied
to the local police for a permit to buy a pistol. The banker had
told this friend of mine that senior Goldman people have loaded
up on firearms and are now equipped to defend themselves if
there is a populist uprising against the bank. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I called Goldman Sachs spokesman Lucas van Praag to ask
whether it&#8217;s true that Goldman partners feel they need handguns
to protect themselves from the angry proletariat. He didn&#8217;t call
me back. The New York Police Department has told me that &#8220;as a
preliminary matter, it appears that some of the records you
requested may be in the possession of this department&#8221; after I
asked for information on approved handgun permits for bankers.
The NYPD also said it will be a while before it can name names. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we wait, Goldman has wrapped itself in the flag of
Warren Buffett, with whom it will jointly donate $500 million,
part of an effort to burnish its image -- and gain new Goldman
clients. Goldman Sachs Chief Executive Officer Lloyd Blankfein
also reversed himself after having previously called Goldman&#8217;s
greed &#8220;God&#8217;s work&#8221; and apologized earlier this month for
having participated in things that were &#8220;clearly wrong.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Has it really come to this? Imagine what emotions must be
billowing through the halls of Goldman Sachs to provoke the firm
into an apology. Talk that Goldman bankers might have armed
themselves in self-defense would sound ludicrous, were it not so
apt a metaphor for the way that the most successful people on
Wall Street have become a target for public rage. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pistol Ready &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Common sense tells you a handgun is probably not even all
that useful. Suppose an intruder sneaks past the doorman or
jumps the security fence at night. By the time you pull the
pistol out of your wife&#8217;s jewelry safe, find the ammunition, and
load your weapon, Fifi the Pomeranian has already been taken
hostage and the gun won&#8217;t do you any good. As for carrying a
loaded pistol when you venture outside, dream on. Concealed gun
permits are almost impossible for ordinary citizens to obtain in
New York or nearby states. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, a little humility and contrition are
probably the better route. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until a couple of weeks ago, that was obvious to everyone
but Goldman, a firm famous for both prescience and arrogance. In
a display of both, Blankfein began to raise his personal-
security threat level early in the financial crisis. He keeps a
summer home near the Hamptons, where unrestricted public access
would put him at risk if the angry mobs rose up and marched to
the East End of Long Island. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To the Barricades &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He tried to buy a house elsewhere without attracting
attention as the financial crisis unfolded in 2007, a move that
was foiled by the New York Post. Then, Blankfein got permission
from the local authorities to install a security gate at his
house two months before Bear Stearns Cos. collapsed. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the kind of foresight that Goldman Sachs is justly
famous for. Blankfein somehow anticipated the persecution
complex his fellow bankers would soon suffer. Surely, though,
this man who can afford to surround himself with a private army
of security guards isn&#8217;t sleeping with the key to a gun safe
under his pillow. The thought is just too bizarre to be true. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So maybe other senior people at Goldman Sachs have gone out
and bought guns, and they know something. But what? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Henry Paulson, U.S. Treasury secretary during the bailout
and a former Goldman Sachs CEO, let it slip during testimony to
Congress last summer when he explained why it was so critical to
bail out Goldman Sachs, and -- oh yes -- the other banks. People
&#8220;were unhappy with the big discrepancies in wealth, but they at
least believed in the system and in some form of market-driven
capitalism. But if we had a complete meltdown, it could lead to
people questioning the basis of the system.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Torn Curtain &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There you have it. The bailout was meant to keep the
curtain drawn on the way the rich make money, not from the free
market, but from the lack of one. Goldman Sachs blew its cover
when the firm&#8217;s revenue from trading reached a record $27
billion in the first nine months of this year, and a public that
was writhing in financial agony caught on that the profits
earned on taxpayer capital were going to pay employee bonuses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This slip-up let the other bailed-out banks happily hand
off public blame to Goldman, which is unpopular among its peers
because it always seems to win at everyone&#8217;s expense. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plenty of Wall Streeters worry about the big discrepancies
in wealth, and think the rise of a financial industry-led
plutocracy is unjust. That doesn&#8217;t mean any of them plan to move
into a double-wide mobile home as a show of solidarity with the
little people, though. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cool Hand Lloyd &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, talk of Goldman and guns plays right into the way Wall-
Streeters like to think of themselves. Even those who were
bailed out believe they are tough, macho Clint Eastwoods of the
financial frontier, protecting the fistful of dollars in one
hand with the Glock in the other. The last thing they want is to
be so reasonably paid that the peasants have no interest in
lynching them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if the proles really do appear brandishing pitchforks
at the doors of Park Avenue and the gates of Round Hill Road,
you can be sure that the Goldman guys and their families will be
holed up in their safe rooms with their firearms. If nothing
else, that pistol permit might go part way toward explaining why
they won&#8217;t be standing outside with the rest of the crowd, broke
and humiliated, saying, &#8220;Damn, I was on the wrong side of a
trade with Goldman again.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Alice Schroeder, author of &#8220;The Snowball: Warren Buffett
and the Business of Life&#8221; and a former managing director at
Morgan Stanley, is a Bloomberg News columnist. The opinions
expressed are her own.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Click on &#8220;Send Comment&#8221; in the sidebar display to send a
letter to the editor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry></news>