
<news><entry author="By Charles Mead" date="May 06, 2013  5:34 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-06/general-motors-financial-plans-to-sell-2-billion-of-senior-debt.html"><headline>Ford Joins General Motors Raising $3.5 Billion With Bond Sales</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Lending units of General Motors Co. (GM)
and Ford Motor Co. (F), the two largest U.S. automakers, are selling
$3.5 billion of bonds. </p>
<p>General Motors Financial intends to issue $2 billion of
senior notes in its first debt offering in almost nine months to
help fund its purchase of Ally Financial Inc.''s international
operations and to repay debt, the company said today in a
regulatory filing. </p>
<p>Ford Motor Credit today sold $1 billion of 1.7 percent,
three-year notes that yield 140 basis points more than similarly
dated Treasuries and $500 million of floating-rate securities
with the same maturity that pay 125 basis points more than the
London interbank offered rate, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Libor, the rate at which banks say they can borrow in
dollars from each other, was set at 0.275 percent today. </p>
<p>The GM debt will probably be issued in three-, five- and
10-year portions and may be sold May 8, according to a person
familiar with that offering who asked not to be identified
because terms aren''t set. Proceeds will be used to finance a
portion of its $4.2 billion deal for Ally (ALLY)''s operations in Europe
and Latin America, to repay an inter-company loan and to fund
working capital. </p>
<h2>Formerly GMAC </h2>
<p>Ally, formerly known as GMAC Inc., was owned by GM until
2006, when the automaker sold 51 percent to Cerberus Capital
Management LP. GMAC almost collapsed under the weight of bad
subprime mortgages during the financial crisis. </p>
<p>GM last issued new bonds in August with a $1 billion sale
of 4.75 percent securities due 2017, Bloomberg data show. </p>
<p>The GM finance unit''s $500 million of 6.75 percent debt due
June 2018 traded May 2 at 114.5 cents on the dollar to yield
3.59 percent, or 294.7 basis points more than Treasuries,
according to Trace, the bond-price reporting system of the
Financial Industry Regulatory Authority. Those bonds are rated
Ba3 by Moody''s Investors Service and an equivalent BB- at
Standard  Poor''s. </p>
<p>Ford''s offering may be used for the purchase of
receivables, for loans and for retiring debt, the unit said
today in a filing. The company is rated Baa3 by Moody''s, the
lowest level of investment grade, and BB+ by SP, the highest
category of speculative grade. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Spillane" date="May 06, 2013 11:25 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-06/microsoft-takes-on-blackberry-to-android-for-south-africa-growth.html"><headline>Microsoft Takes On BlackBerry, Android in South Africa</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), trying to find growth
markets for its mobile products, is projecting that rising
demand in South Africa will help it pass BlackBerry and Android
and pave the way for further gains on the continent. </p>
<p>The company, working with hardware partners such as Nokia
Oyj (NOK1V) and HTC Corp. (2498), plans to become South Africa''s No. 1
smartphone provider by 2016, Gustavo Fuchs, who runs its Windows
Phone business in Africa and Middle East, said in an interview.
The company plans models across a range of prices to lure users
in the continent''s biggest economy, where the average household
income is about $13,500 a year. </p>
<p>Africa will be the fastest-growing market by wireless
subscribers over the next five years, according to consulting
firm A.T. Kearney. Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft is
seeking areas of growth for its mobile business, which lags far
behind Apple Inc. (AAPL) and Google Inc.''s Android that combined
account for about 90 percent of the global smartphone market. </p>
<p>With a low-smartphone-penetration market, Windows Phone
has a bigger chance to be the first smartphone for users,
Fuchs said in a phone interview from Johannesburg. The
smartphone snowball effect has started. </p>




Photographer: Simon Dawson/Bloomberg

<p>
Microsoft Corp.''s share has grown rapidly recently, and the company now has 10 percent of the market, helped by the introduction of the new Windows Phone 8 software in November. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ben Bain and Jonathan Levin" date="May 06, 2013  6:32 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-06/coca-cola-femsa-inbursa-gbm-grupo-famsa-mexico-bond-alert.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Femsa, Inbursa, GBM, Grupo Famsa: Mexico Bond Alert</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Coca-Cola Femsa SAB, Grupo Financiero
Inbursa SAB, Corporativo GBM SAB and Grupo Famsa SAB are among
issuers that plan to sell bonds in Mexico''s debt markets. </p>
<p>COCA-COLA FEMSA SAB: (KOFL) Latin America''s largest bottler of the
soft drink plans to sell as much as 7.5 billion pesos ($620
million) in fixed-rate bonds due in 10 years as part of a
program to raise as much as 20 billion pesos through debt
offerings. Units of Banco Bilbao Vizcaya Argentaria, HSBC
Holdings Plc and Citigroup Inc. are helping manage sale that is
expected to be on May 22. (Added May 6) </p>
<p>GRUPO FINANCIERO INBURSA SAB: (GFINBURO) The financial unit controlled
by the billionaire Carlos Slim plans to sell as much as 6
billion pesos in debt due in three years. The planned offering
is part of a program to raise as much as 30 billion pesos
through debt sales. Units of Inbursa, Banco Bilbao Vizcaya
Argentaria, Grupo Financiero Banorte SAB and HSBC are helping
manage sale. (Added May 6) </p>
<p>KIMBERLY-CLARK DE MEXICO SAB: The consumer-goods company
plans to sell bonds including floating-rate securities due in
five years and fixed-rate bonds due in 10 years as part of a
program to raise as much as 16 billion pesos through debt
offerings. Units of Citigroup and Bank of America Corp. are
arranging the sale. (Added April 29) </p>
<p>COMISION FEDERAL DE ELECTRICIDAD: The state-owned utility''s
chief financial officer, Francisco Santoyo, said in an interview
that the company may sell 10 billion pesos in local currency
bonds. (Added April 22) </p>
<p>CORPORATIVO GBM SAB (GBMO): The brokerage said in a filing with
the stock exchange that it plans to issue fixed-rate bonds due
in five years and worth as much as 200 million pesos as part of
a program to sell as much as 3.5 billion pesos in long-term
debt. The sale is planned for this week and is being managed by
GBM. (Added April 15) </p>
<p>FOVISSSTE: The mortgage administrator said in a filing with
the stock exchange that it plans to issue bonds as part of a
program worth as much as 17 billion pesos. Banorte, HSBC, Corp.
Actinver SAB and the local unit of Banco Bilbao Vizcaya
Argentaria are managing the deal. (Added April 8) </p>
<p>GRUPO FAMSA SAB: The retailer said in a filing with the
stock exchange that it plans to sell as much as 250 million
pesos of bonds under a program to raise as much as 2 billion
pesos. Banorte is coordinating the sale, according to the
filing. (Added March 25) </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Selcuk Gokoluk and Benjamin Harvey" date="May 06, 2013  4:40 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-06/jpmorgan-commerzbank-pondering-turkey-bond-yield-bottom.html"><headline>JPMorgan, Commerzbank Pondering Turkey Bond Yield Bottom</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Banks from JPMorgan Chase  Co. to
Morgan Stanley and Commerzbank AG are weighing the outlook for
Turkey''s two-year note yield after it fell below 5 percent for
the first time amid fading inflation concern. </p>
<p>Two-year yields will drop to 4 percent, according to Tatha Ghose at Commerzbank, Germany''s second-biggest lender. Morgan
Stanley says the current low rate isn''t justified, while Turk
Ekonomi Bankasi AS (TEBNK) predicts yields won''t fall further. The yield
sank to as low as 4.96 percent on May 3 before rising to 5.14
percent, trimming the drop in the past year to 419 basis points,
the most among 17 emerging markets tracked by Bloomberg and more
than twice the slide for Polish notes, the next largest decline. </p>
<p>Turkish inflation slowed more than economists estimated to
a two-year low in April, giving the central bank room to reduce
interest rates. Even with the drop in yields, Turkey still
offers the fifth-highest rate in emerging markets as policy
makers globally rely on stimulus measures to revive growth. </p>
<p>We may test towards 4.5 percent, Yarkin Cebeci, an
economist at JPMorgan in Istanbul, said in e-mailed comments on
May 3. Sounds unbelievable, but this is the reality. Given
ample global liquidity, a strong domestic story, low
inflationary pressures and a dovish central bank, bond yields
could fall further. </p>
<h2>Negative Yields </h2>
<p>Swiss, Germany and Finnish two-year yields trade near zero
while Australia''s 2.51 percent rate is the highest among 22
developed countries, according to data compiled by Bloomberg at
the end of last week. </p>
<p>India cut interest rates for a third straight meeting on
May 3, a day after the European Central Bank lowered its main
rate to a record 0.5 percent. ECB President Mario Draghi said
last week that policy makers had an open mind on reducing
their so-called deposit rate below the current level of zero for
the first time. </p>
<p>The lira weakened for a fourth day, sliding 0.1 percent to
1.7956 per dollar at 11:15 a.m. in Istanbul today. The currency
has depreciated 0.7 percent this year. The two-year note yield
fell three basis points to 5.11 percent. </p>
<p>Moody''s Investors Service rekindled expectations of a
rating upgrade on April 11 when it praised Turkey''s peace talks
with the Kurdistan Workers'' Party in an effort to end a conflict
that began in 1984. </p>
<h2>Upgrade Story'' </h2>
<p>Turkey has a rating upgrade story and funds in the system
are also cheap and abundant, said Ali Cakiroglu, a strategist
at HSBC Asset Management in Istanbul. If this euphoria
continues, we can see the benchmark bond yields reach 4.8-4.9
percent. </p>
<p>Fitch Ratings lifted Turkey to investment-grade status in
November, the economy''s first such ranking in 18 years. Moody''s
and Standard  Poor''s rate Turkey one level below investment
grade. Investors who borrowed in U.S. dollars and bought Turkish
lira debt earned 5.4 percent over the past year, according to
data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Turkey''s economy grew 2.2 percent last year, the slowest
pace since a recession in 2009, and down from 8.8 percent in
2011. The economy needs to grow at least 6 percent a year to
meet its goal of becoming one of the world''s top 10 economies by
the 2023 centennial of the Turkish Republic, Economy Minister
Zafer Caglayan said April 1. </p>
<p>The extra yield investors demand to hold Turkey''s dollar
bonds rather than U.S. Treasuries fell one basis point, or 0.01
percentage point, to 185 today, compared with an average 269
basis points for emerging markets, JPMorgan''s EMBI Global
Diversified index showed. </p>
<h2>No Logic </h2>
<p>I don''t think there is a clear logic behind yields
anywhere in emerging markets these days, Tevfik Aksoy, chief
economist for emerging Europe, the Middle East and Africa at
Morgan Stanley in London, said in e-mailed comments on May 3.
As long as investors get a tiny amount of carry, they will
pile in. </p>
<p>Turkey''s central bank reduced all three of its main
interest rates last month, citing an increase of capital
inflows. The Monetary Policy Committee is next scheduled to meet
May 16. </p>
<p>Yields on Turkey''s two-year notes may fall to 4 percent and
then stay there through year-end, while rates on longer-maturity
debt rise, according to Ghose, Commerzbank''s senior emerging-
market economist in London. </p>
<p>Inflation and overheating worries are disappearing around
the world and won''t be back for three years, Ghose wrote in e-
mailed comments. I would be much more bullish for two-year
bonds. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Edward Klump" date="May 07, 2013  7:38 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-07/exxon-starting-development-of-4-billion-gulf-of-mexico-field.html"><headline>Exxon Starting Development of $4 Billion Gulf of Mexico Field</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM), the largest U.S.
oil company, said it will invest more than $4 billion in the
development of its Julia oil field in the Gulf of Mexico. </p>
<p>Oil production is expected to start in 2016 from the field,
which was discovered in 2007, Irving, Texas-based Exxon said in
a statement today. The resource in place is estimated to be
almost 6 billion barrels, Exxon said. </p>
<p>The Julia unit was the subject of a 2011 Exxon lawsuit
against the U.S. over the government''s decision to cancel the
offshore leases because Exxon hadn''t proceeded quickly enough
with development. The litigation was later settled, allowing the
company to develop this very large, but technically
challenging, resource as quickly as possible using a phased
approach, Patrick McGinn, an Exxon spokesman, said in January
2012. </p>
<p>An initial phase of the project is designed for daily
output of 34,000 barrels of oil, the company said in today''s
statement. It will have tie-backs to a production facility
operated by Chevron Corp. (CVX) Exxon and Statoil ASA (STL) both have a 50
percent stake in the Julia unit. </p>
<p>Julia is one of the first large oil discoveries in the
ultra-deepwater frontier of the Gulf of Mexico, Neil Duffin,
president of Exxon''s development company, said in the statement.
This resource is located more than 30,000 feet below the
ocean''s surface. Enhanced technologies will be deployed to
ensure the safe and environmentally responsible development of
this important energy resource. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David M. Levitt" date="May 07, 2013  6:42 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-07/jpmorgan-said-to-agree-to-acquire-tower-for-650-million.html"><headline>JPMorgan Said to Agree to Acquire Tower for $650 Million</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s asset-
management unit agreed to buy the 31-story tower at 425
Lexington Ave. in midtown Manhattan for about $650 million, a
person with knowledge of the plans said. </p>
<p>A contract to acquire the 750,000-square-foot (70,000-
square-meter) building is likely to be completed soon, said the
person, who asked not to be identified because the talks are
private. It''s one of two Manhattan towers being marketed by
Houston-based developer Hines, along with 499 Park Ave.,
designed by I.M. Pei. </p>
<p>New York commercial-property transactions are forecast to
climb this year as investors globally see Manhattan as a safe
place to buy real estate. Brokerage Cushman  Wakefield last
month projected sales of $14.6 billion for the first half of
2013, up from $10.8 billion a year earlier. </p>
<p>Alyson Leiter, a Hines spokeswoman, said the company had no
comment on the planned sale of 425 Lexington. Douglas Harmon,
senior managing director at Eastdil Secured, who''s marketing the
building, and Darin Oduyoye, a spokesman for New York-based
JPMorgan, also declined to comment. </p>
<p>Law firm Simpson Thacher  Bartlett LLP, the tower''s
primary tenant, with 595,000 square feet on 26 floors, renewed
its lease through 2033, Hines said last month. </p>
<p>Hines bought the glass tower, completed in 1987, for $346
million in 2003, according to Real Capital Analytics Inc., a New
York-based property-research firm. The building is on the east
side of Lexington between East 43rd and 44th streets, just north
of the Chrysler Building. </p>
<p>The JPMorgan agreement was reported by Crain''s New York
Business on its website earlier today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Patricia Hurtado" date="May 07, 2013  5:11 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-07/chevron-ceo-can-t-avoid-questioning-in-ecuador-fraud-case.html"><headline>Chevron CEO Can''t Avoid Questioning in Ecuador Fraud Case</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX) lost a bid to stop Chief
Executive Officer John Watson from being questioned by the
attorney the company is suing over claims he committed fraud to
win a $19 billion verdict in a pollution case in Ecuador. </p>
<p>U.S. Magistrate Judge James Francis in Manhattan today
ruled that Watson''s experience in leading the 2001 Chevron-
Texaco merger is likely to have given him personal knowledge
of the environmental issues underlying the Ecuador litigation. </p>
<p>Francis also overruled San Ramon, California-based
Chevron''s objection to a deposition of vice president and
general counsel Edward Scott by defendant Steven Donziger, who
is accused in the racketeering lawsuit of improperly influencing
a court expert whose findings were used by the Ecuador judge in
the environmental damage case in the Amazon. </p>
<p>Kent Robertson, a spokesman for the company, didn''t
immediately respond to a phone call seeking comment on the
ruling. </p>
<p>Donziger has denied wrongdoing and plaintiffs in the
Ecuadorian case have said the oil company is attacking him to
avoid responsibility for the damages. </p>
<p>The racketeering case is Chevron v. Donziger, 11-00691,
U.S. District Court, District of New York (Manhattan). The case
in Ecuador is Aquinda v. Chevron, 002-2003, Superior Court of
Nueva Loja, Lago Agrio, Ecuador. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="May 07, 2013  4:10 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-07/microsoft-sells-100-million-windows-8-licenses-preparing-update.html"><headline>Microsoft Readies Windows Update as PC Sales Slump</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) is preparing an update for Windows 8 as new licensing figures indicate the new operating system isn''t fueling enough demand to reverse a slump in personal-computer sales. </p> <p>The 100 million Windows 8 licenses sold since the software''s debut in October are in the general ballpark with the previous version during a similar period, Tami Reller, chief financial officer of the Windows division, said in an interview last week. </p> <p>Microsoft completely overhauled its flagship operating system to make it more appealing to users amid a shift to mobile, touch-based computing. Still, Windows 8 has failed to reignite the ailing personal-computer market, where shipments plummeted by their largest margin on record in the latest quarter, according to market-research firm IDC. While Microsoft said it''s planning to update Windows 8 to address customer feedback, updates won''t quickly turn the PC industry around. </p> <p>The changes will help some but there are some serious challenges that the PC industry is facing that I''m not sure can be easily fixed, said Bob O''Donnell, an analyst at IDC who is based in San Mateo, California. </p> <p>O''Donnell also questioned whether the licensing milestone accurately reflects the number of operating systems in use. </p>




Photographer: Stuart Isett/Bloomberg

<p>
Microsoft completely overhauled Windows to make it more appealing to users amid a shift to mobile, touch-based computing. Still, Windows 8 has failed to reignite the ailing personal-computer market. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="May 07, 2013  2:28 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-07/jpmorgan-should-split-chairman-and-ceo-roles-glass-lewis-says.html"><headline>JPMorgan Should Replace Most of Board, Glass Lewis Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the biggest U.S. bank, should oust most of its board and split Jamie Dimon''s dual roles as chairman and chief executive officer, shareholder advisory firm Glass Lewis  Co. said. </p> <p>Stockholders should replace six of the board''s 11 directors at the bank''s annual meeting May 21 and approve a proposal to name an independent chairman, Glass Lewis said today in a report. </p> <p>Calls for Dimon, 57, to relinquish the chairmanship have mounted since last May, when New York-based JPMorgan disclosed risk-control lapses in its chief investment office on credit-derivative bets that fueled a $6.2 billion trading loss and sparked regulatory probes. Institutional Shareholder Services on May 3 also urged a vote in favor of splitting Dimon''s roles and removing three directors. </p> <p>Investigations by the company and lawmakers have revealed questionable risk-management practices at both the senior management and board levels, Glass Lewis wrote in the report. Shareholders should be concerned that company management was allowed to build a massive exposure to credit derivatives, switch risk models and undervalue its losses without triggering a review by the board. </p> <p>Glass Lewis said shareholders should vote against James A. Bell, former chief financial officer at Boeing Co.; Crandall C. Bowles, chairman of Springs Industries Inc.; David M. Cote, CEO of Honeywell International Inc. (HON); James S. Crown, president of Henry Crown  Co.; Ellen V. Futter, president of the American Museum of Natural History; and Laban P. Jackson, CEO of Clear Creek Properties Inc. </p>




Photographer: Chris Ratcliffe/Bloomberg

<p>
Calls for JPMorgan Chase  Co. Chairman Jamie Dimon to relinquish the chairmanship have mounted since last May, when New York-based JPMorgan disclosed risk-control lapses in its chief investment office on credit-derivative bets that fueled a $6.2 billion trading loss and sparked regulatory probes. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Stefania Bianchi and Ambereen Choudhury" date="May 07, 2013  5:21 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-07/jpmorgan-said-to-plan-commodity-trader-job-cuts-in-london-dubai.html"><headline>JPMorgan Said to Plan Commodity Trader Job Cuts in London, Dubai</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the biggest U.S.
bank, told about 10 traders in its commodity business that their
jobs may be eliminated, according to two people with knowledge
of the situation. </p>
<p>The bank may dismiss or relocate seven in London and one in
Dubai, said the people, asking not to be identified because the
matter is private. A second Dubai-based trader will be relocated
to London, the people said. Patrick Burton, a spokesman for the
bank in the U.K. capital, declined to comment. </p>
<p>JPMorgan had the second-biggest revenue from commodities
after Goldman Sachs Group Inc. last year, analytics company
Coalition said in March. New York-based JPMorgan has commodity
bankers based in 12 countries, according to its website, though
it doesn''t disclose how many commodity traders it has globally. </p>
<p>Commodities revenue at the 10 largest banks slumped 24
percent last year to $6 billion amid low volatility and reduced
client activity, according to a Feb. 15 Coalition report.
Increasing concerns about regulation and capital sensitivity
also led banks to re-examine commodity strategies, it said. </p>
<h2>Low Volatility </h2>
<p>The Standard  Poor''s GSCI Spot Index of raw materials
climbed less than 0.3 percent in 2012, the worst performance in
four years. The gauge''s 100-day historic volatility fell to as
low as 14.1 percent in May, from as much as 23.8 percent in
January 2012, data compiled by Bloomberg show. </p>
<p>JP Morgan said in February it will eliminate as many as
19,000 jobs in mortgages and community banking through 2014 as
it trims expenses. This year, the bank''s headcount will shrink
by about 4,000 people, mainly through attrition, while some
employees are redeployed to other areas, said Kristin Lemkau, a
spokeswoman, said at the time. </p>
<p>The bank''s first-quarter profit rose 33 percent to a record
last month as the bank shrank expenses by 16 percent. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki and Brian Wingfield" date="May 08, 2013  7:43 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-08/jpmorgan-received-wells-type-notice-from-ferc-in-energy-probe.html"><headline>JPMorgan Says Energy Watchdog May Seek to Punish Units, Workers</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the biggest U.S.
bank, was warned by federal energy-market regulators that its
personnel and two subsidiaries may face claims stemming from a
probe into bidding practices. </p>
<p>Federal Energy Regulatory Commission staff told JPMorgan in
March they may recommend the agency bring an enforcement case,
the New York-based company said yesterday in a regulatory
filing. Claims may include alleged violations of FERC rules
and the rules of certain independent system operators, the
lender said, without elaborating on the allegations. </p>
<p>The FERC has stepped up scrutiny of corporations as it
wields policing powers that were expanded in the wake of Enron
Corp.''s 2001 collapse. Agency investigators may seek to hold
JPMorgan traders and commodities-unit chief Blythe Masters
individually liable, the New York Times reported last week,
citing a 70-page document the watchdog sent the bank in March. </p>
<p>The case focuses on eight schemes adopted by traders in
Houston between September 2010 and June 2011, according to the
newspaper. Traders offered energy at prices calculated to
falsely appear attractive, prompting state authorities in
California and Michigan to make about $83 million in
excessive payments to JPMorgan, the Times cited
investigators as saying. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
The JPMorgan Chase  Co. logo is seen through trees at the company''s offices in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Charles Mead" date="May 08, 2013  5:30 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-08/jpmorgan-raises-2-billion-with-five-year-bonds-at-lower-cost.html"><headline>JPMorgan Leads Companies Borrowing $15.6 Billion With Bonds</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) was among
borrowers including State Street Corp. and Statoil ASA (STL) selling
at least $15.6 billion of bonds in the U.S. today. </p>
<p>The biggest U.S. bank issued $2 billion of 1.625 percent,
five-year notes at narrower relative yields than those on
similar-maturity debt sold four months ago, according to data
compiled by Bloomberg. A spread of 92 basis points more than
similar-maturity Treasuries compares with an extra yield of 103
basis points for $1.25 billion of 1.8 percent, five-year
debentures that New York-based JPMorgan sold Jan. 17. </p>
<p>Statoil, the largest Norwegian energy company, sold $3
billion of debt in a four-part offering that included $900
million of 2.65 percent bonds due 2024 that pay 90 basis points
more than Treasuries, $850 million of 30-year, 3.95 percent debt
with an extra yield of 95 basis points, $750 million of 1.15
percent notes maturing 2018 that pay 45 more than benchmarks and
$500 million of similar-maturity, floating-rate bonds that yield
29 basis points more than the London interbank offered rate. </p>
<p>State Street, the third-largest custody bank, sold $1
billion of 3.1 percent, 10-year bonds that yield 135 basis
points more than Treasuries and $500 million of 1.35 percent
debt due 2018 with a spread of 62.5, Bloomberg data show. </p>
<p>Other issuers today included Warren Buffett''s Berkshire
Hathaway Inc. (BRK/A), HSBC Holdings Plc and Brinker International Inc. (EAT),
the owner of the Chili''s and Maggiano''s dining chains. Libor (US0003M),
the rate at which banks say they can borrow in dollars from each
other, was set at 0.275 percent today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Nina Mehta" date="May 08, 2013  1:47 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-08/morgan-stanley-overhauls-equity-technology-to-shave-milliseconds.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Overhauls Equity Systems to Cut Microseconds</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) has overhauled its
trading infrastructure for U.S. equities to keep pace with a
marketplace in which millionths of a second count. </p>
<p>The bank modernized its technology for stock trading to
save fractions of a millisecond and is now moving clients onto
the new platform, Bill Neuberger, global co-head of Morgan
Stanley Electronic Trading at the New York-based company, said
by phone. A millisecond is a thousandth of a second and a
microsecond is a millionth. When carrying out buy or sell orders
for customers, the changes will enable the bank to get 99
percent of the shares available on exchanges at a specific
price, up from the high 80s two years ago, he said. </p>
<p>Faster computers and regulatory changes aimed at spurring
competition among exchanges have increased the speed at which
stocks change hands over the last 15 years. High-frequency
trading, which relies on fast access to changing data, now
accounts for more than half of U.S. stock volume. Neuberger and
Andrew Silverman, who run Morgan Stanley Electronic Trading,
oversaw the firm''s 18-month project. </p>
<p>As markets continued to evolve, the importance of speed
and smart coordination became more and more prominent,
Neuberger said. Trading fundamentally changed. We needed to
think about it at the level of microseconds as opposed to
milliseconds in the previous world and that involved rethinking
how our trading systems operate. </p>
<p>The technology overhaul is unprecedented for Morgan
Stanley, said Neuberger, who has worked at the bank for 24 years
including eight in information technology where he wrote
software code. The firm typically made changes to its equities
technology at a more gradual pace, he said. He declined to say
how much the bank spent on the project. </p>
<h2>Daily Volume </h2>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s equities trading unit accounts for more
than 11 percent of average daily volume in the U.S., up from
less than 10 percent two years ago, Neuberger said. Neuberger,
who said he expects the upgrade to increase market share, and
Silverman are responsible for the trading technology systems
across Morgan Stanley''s entire equities division including the
electronic unit. </p>
<p>The overhaul and focus on low-latency trading, or buying
and selling with a minimum of delay, comes as banks face
decreased profitability from stock trading following a decline
in U.S. volume for three years in a row. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s equities trading revenue was $1.59 billion
in the first quarter, a 19 percent drop from a year earlier,
excluding accounting charges. The business, headed by Ted Pick,
produced the second-most revenue among global investment banks
last year, trailing only Goldman Sachs Group Inc. </p>
<h2>Largest Broker </h2>
<p>The firm has been the largest broker by volume traded on
the Nasdaq Stock Market in the exchange''s listed companies every
month since at least June, according to data from Nasdaq OMX
Group Inc. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley plans to buy the remaining 35 percent of a
brokerage joint venture from Citigroup Inc. this year, giving it
full ownership of a wealth management division with $1.79
trillion in client assets. Chief Executive Officer James Gorman
said earlier this year that his firm will get a revenue benefit
since it no longer has to give Citigroup a portion of retail
trading orders. </p>
<p>The bank introduced the new trading infrastructure
internally in recent weeks and is shifting clients onto it,
according to Silverman, who was head of U.S. algorithmic trading
at Goldman Sachs before joining Morgan Stanley in 2006. The firm
will shift its U.S. options client business to the new
technology by mid-year, futures and European trading by the end
of the year and Asia in 2014, he said. </p>
<h2>Market Data </h2>
<p>The overhaul encompasses trading-related systems and
technology including how market data from 13 stock exchanges is
processed, algorithms that execute orders, Morgan Stanley''s dark
pools and so-called smart routers, or software that decides
which venue should receive the smaller pieces of a larger order
and for how many shares. It also includes hardware, the way
Morgan Stanley connects to exchanges and how it uses its main
data center for equities trading in Weehawken, New Jersey. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley has three dark pools: MS Pool, Trajectory
Cross and MS Retail Pool. The retail venue was introduced about
two years ago. </p>
<p>Reducing latency, increasing automation and maintaining
proper risk measurements are major objectives of financial
firms, Anthony Dostellio, Chicago-based managing partner at
Objective Paradigm Inc., a technology recruiting firm
specializing in financial services, said by phone. More
organizations are facing a greater emphasis on getting data,
analyzing data and reacting to data. </p>
<h2>IT Spending </h2>
<p>Spending by banks and brokers for U.S. equity trading IT
infrastructure is projected to be $2.09 billion this year, down
from $2.27 billion in 2012, according to Bob Iati, partner and
global head of consulting at New York-based research firm Tabb
Group LLC. The costs include market data, feed handlers, high-speed messaging, data centers and networking. </p>
<p>As markets moved to more automated processes from exchanges
centered on human traders over the last decade, brokers
developed algorithms or electronic execution strategies to buy
and sell bigger orders over a period of time without
exacerbating price moves. Programs employed by brokers and their
clients usually take liquidity by trading against bids and
offers that have been placed on exchanges and dozens of
alternative venues. </p>
<p>You want to hit a bid but it''s made up of 13 different
bids, Silverman said, referring to orders spread across stock
exchanges. The ability to maximize the capture of that
liquidity was declining. </p>
<h2>Canceling Quotes </h2>
<p>High-frequency traders may see incoming orders take
liquidity in a stock at several exchanges and cancel their bids
or offers on other venues. While firms including market makers
usually quote on many platforms because they don''t know which
venues investors or brokers will use, they don''t want to get
more executions than they expect. Their place in the queue of
orders awaiting execution at a certain price also differs across
venues, giving them an incentive to quote in multiple places. </p>
<p>For investors and brokers, that poses a problem, Silverman
said. They see quotes available across exchanges and are
frustrated when they try to trade with them and the bids or
offers vanish or only fewer shares are available. </p>
<p>In today''s market, liquidity is fleeting, Silverman
said. </p>
<p>The problem of market makers canceling quotes at better
prices isn''t new and occurred when trading was handled by
individuals manually entering bids and offers on their computer
screens. Some brokers in recent years have timed when their
algorithms send trade requests seeking to access buy and sell
orders at different exchanges to try to reach as many quotes as
possible at the same time. </p>
<h2>Hit Rate </h2>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s average hit rate of about 99 percent means
that if 10,000 shares are available at a specified price, the
bank could take all but 100. </p>
<p>The firm changed its smart router as part of the overhaul.
Decisions about how to handle orders now incorporate real-time
learning algorithms that evolve as they get new information from
trading orders, improving the ability to get more shares by
selecting venues where trades are more likely, Neuberger said. </p>
<p>The data center is where the smart router''s brain sits,
with smaller order-handling systems co-located at exchanges or
other venues, Neuberger said. Dark fiber is used to send orders
rapidly between the Weehawken building and other sites, he said. </p>
<h2>Keeping Up </h2>
<p>Infrastructure at a bank isn''t a commodity, David B.
Weiss, a senior analyst at Boston-based research firm Aite Group
LLC, said by phone. It''s part of their business. They''ve all
got to keep up with the Joneses. </p>
<p>Banks employ systems engineers and software engineers and
individuals with advanced degrees in computer science,
electrical engineering, math and physics to build and manage
trading systems, Dostellio said. The smartest and most versatile
are also pursued by high-frequency trading firms, gaming
companies, corporations that make consumer products sold online
and social-media firms, he said. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s electronic trading group worked in the
past with application developers to construct execution
algorithms and smart routers. Trading executives decided how
they wanted the algorithms to behave and developers built them. </p>
<p>For the project the bank brought so-called enterprise
infrastructure specialists into the discussion with developers
for the first time, Neuberger said. These are engineers focused
on hardware, network switches and operating systems. The
involvement of both groups ensured that the hardware and
software were integrated to trim microseconds, he said. </p>
<h2>Servicing Brokers </h2>
<p>The changes will also benefit Morgan Stanley''s business of
servicing other brokers, Silverman said. The bank, like its
rivals, handles some trading services for small and mid-size
brokers. The new technology will let it process more orders, he
said. Morgan Stanley has more than 275 broker-dealer clients
globally and expects that number to increase with the new
infrastructure, he said. </p>
<p>The bank maintained two separate equities trading
technology infrastructures during the overhaul. Doing so doubled
the computer-coding work to prepare for regulatory changes such
as the so-called limit-up/limit-down system that curbs trading
in individual stocks when prices move rapidly and ordinary
technical updates to systems. </p>
<p>We''re betting a lot in a resource-constrained environment
that this will be a big selling point for us globally,
Neuberger said. The decay due to the changing market
environment and latency issues is so fast that what you had four
years ago -- it gets old. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Leising" date="May 08, 2013  9:44 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-08/jpmorgan-said-to-name-erik-bisso-to-run-cio-in-north-america.html"><headline>JPMorgan Said to Name Erik Bisso to Run CIO in North America</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) has named Erik Bisso to run the bank''s chief investment office for North
America, according to an internal memo sent today. </p>
<p>Bisso ran agency mortgage-backed securities pass-through
trading for the New York-based bank, according to the memo, a
copy of which was obtained by Bloomberg News. Bill Anast will
join JPMorgan in August to replace Bisso in that role, a person
familiar with the matter said. Anast previously ran the agency
collateralized-mortgage obligation business at Barclays Plc. (BARC) </p>
<p>Bisso''s move demonstrates our ongoing commitment to
developing senior talent and encouraging mobility across the
firm, Matt Cherwin, head of securitized products, and Craig Delany, who runs the global chief investment office, wrote in
the memo. </p>
<p>Bisso will replace Irene Tse, the former head of the chief
investment office in North America, who left the bank last year
to start a hedge fund, people familiar with the plan said at the
time. </p>
<p>Liz Seymour, a spokeswoman for JPMorgan and Brandon
Ashcraft of Barclays declined to comment. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="May 08, 2013 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-08/morgan-stanley-expands-debt-purchases-as-brokerage-adds-deposits.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Expands Debt Purchases as Brokerage Adds Deposits</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) is expanding the types
of debt it buys as deposits increase with the purchase of its
brokerage venture and interest rates remain near record lows. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley added $677 million of collateralized debt
obligations to its available-for-sale portfolio in the first
quarter and increased its corporate bond holdings to $3.53
billion, according to a regulatory filing yesterday. The
portfolio was invested solely in government and agency debt and
U.S.-backed student loans at the end of 2011. </p>
<p>The available-for-sale portfolio grew 27 percent to $41
billion in the 12 months through March as the firm gained
investable deposits by acquiring more of the brokerage from
Citigroup Inc. (C) Morgan Stanley will get an additional $60 billion
over time after buying the rest of the venture this year, and
Chief Executive Officer James Gorman has sought to build the
lending business to produce better returns from those funds. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley owned $29.1 billion of U.S. Treasury and
agency debt on March 31, down from $30 billion a year earlier.
The portfolio had $2.17 billion of auto loan asset-backed
securities, up from $237 million, and almost six times the
amount of corporate bonds it had in March 2012. </p>
<p>The portfolio still contained less credit risk than that of
larger banks. While Treasury and agency securities accounted for
71 percent of Morgan Stanley''s available-for-sale book, they
comprised only 3.2 percent of Wells Fargo  Co.''s and 3.3
percent of JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s at year-end. </p>
<h2>Warned Fed </h2>
<p>Gorman, 54, was on a council of bankers that warned the
Federal Reserve in February of the potential harm of low
interest rates to U.S. financial institutions even as they
endorsed the central bank''s record stimulus. </p>
<p>The margin pressures that the low-rate environment has
put on financial institutions, coupled with dramatically
increased compliance and other infrastructure costs, have caused
many to seek higher returns by accepting greater interest-rate
or credit risk, the bankers said on Feb. 8, following a
Federal Open Market Committee meeting on Jan. 29-30. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley had $211 million of net unrealized gains in
its portfolio as of March 31, according to the filing. That''s
down from $257 million at the end of 2012. </p>
<p>The bank increased both consumer and residential real
estate loans in its brokerage business by at least $300 million
in the quarter from the end of last year, according to the
filing. About 5 percent of Morgan Stanley wealth-management
clients have a loan with the bank, compared with an average of
10 percent for competitors, Gorman said in a January
presentation. </p>
<p>Total loans were $47.1 billion, up from $46.4 billion at
the end of 2012. The bank had a $129 million allowance for loan
losses, which covered $26.5 billion of loans held for
investment. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri and Andy Fixmer" date="May 09, 2013  4:26 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-09/disney-said-to-tell-advertisers-of-live-abc-app-in-mobile-push.html"><headline>Disney Telling Advertisers of Live ABC App in Mobile Push</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS)''s ABC network, staking
a claim to growth in online video ads, will brief advertisers
next week on a service providing live shows on mobile phones and
tablets, people with knowledge of the plan said. </p>
<p>Watch ABC, a first-of-its-kind application from a
broadcaster, will stream live and archived shows to pay-TV
subscribers, said the people, who sought anonymity because the
plans aren''t public. It could be released near the new TV season
in September, they said. </p>
<p>With online video ad sales growing faster than network TV
revenue, Disney and other programmers such as News Corp.''s Fox
are developing ways to let audiences watch away from home on
smartphones and products such as Apple Inc.''s iPad. The move
pits entertainment companies against Google Inc. (GOOG)''s YouTube and
Facebook Inc. (FB) for an ad market that Morgan Stanley (MS) predicts will
grow 18 percent to $2.73 billion this year. </p>
<p>While the audience online is still small, it''s growing
fast and represents one of the biggest opportunities for the
media companies, Ben Swinburne, a Morgan Stanley analyst in
New York, said in an interview. </p>
<p>As with Watch ESPN, the mobile TV service offered by
Burbank, California-based Disney''s sports channel, Watch ABC
represents a potential new revenue source. The network will
outline the product to advertisers in New York next week during
upfront sales presentations for the September 2013 TV season. </p>




Photographer: Jonathan Alcorn/Bloomberg

<p>
Walt Disney Co.''s ABC network''s step marks the biggest effort yet by a broadcaster to capture the nation''s 101 million pay-TV subscribers while they''re away from the living-room set and more apt to be posting on Facebook or watching a YouTube video. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Carroll" date="May 09, 2013  4:20 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-09/exxon-to-build-10-billion-u-s-lng-export-plant-with-qatar-1-.html"><headline>Exxon to Build $10 Billion U.S. LNG Export Plant With Qatar</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM), the largest energy
company by market value, signed an agreement with Qatar
Petroleum International to move forward with construction of a
$10 billion natural gas export terminal in Texas. </p>
<p>The project will involve installing liquefaction equipment
at an existing import facility in Sabine Pass, Texas, according
to an e-mailed statement today from Golden Pass Products LLC, a
subsidiary formed by the two companies. It won permission last
year to export the fuel to nations with free-trade agreements
with the U.S. and is awaiting approval to send the fuel to all
other countries. </p>
<p>Exxon, based in Irving, Texas, and state-owned Qatar
Petroleum plan to ship as much as 15.6 million metric tons of
gas annually from the Golden Pass facility, according to the
statement. A boom in U.S. production has spurred several
proposals to export the fuel, which is cooled to liquid form at
-260 degrees Fahrenheit (-162 Celsius) to reduce volume and
allow for transportation by ship. </p>
<p>This agreement sets out a highly competitive commercial
blueprint for Golden Pass Products, with a commitment that
builds on the unique combined strengths of QPI and Exxon Mobil
through the the global downstream LNG value chain, Bill
Collins, president of Golden Pass, said in the statement. </p>
<p>Exxon has been expanding its worldwide gas portfolio with
acquisitions such as the 2010 purchase of XTO Energy in the U.S.
and investments in projects that include the A$52 billion ($52
billion) Gorgon LNG complex in Australia. Gas accounted for half
of Exxon''s global production during the first three months of
this year. </p>
<p>U.S. liquefied natural gas import facilities have been
operating below capacity as a glut of domestic gas from shale
formations erased demand for foreign supplies. The import
terminal at Golden Pass began operations in 2010. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Zajac and Tom Schoenberg" date="May 09, 2013  2:07 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-09/chevron-wins-suit-against-u-s-over-california-oil-field.html"><headline>Chevron Wins Suit Against U.S. Over California Oil Field</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX) is entitled to
unspecified damages against the federal government in a contract
dispute over oil deposits in California worth $37 billion, the
U.S. Court of Claims ruled. </p>
<p>The Department of Energy repeatedly and materially
violated two agreements governing determination of equity
interests in oil and gas deposits located in the Elk Hills
Reserve of California, Judge Susan Braden in Washington wrote in
a 90-page ruling. </p>
<p>Chevron is entitled to be compensated for damages, in an
amount to be determined, including sanctions for DOE and the
government''s bad faith'' conduct and abusive discovery
tactics, Braden wrote in the ruling made public yesterday. </p>
<p>Chevron filed the suit in 2004 after failing to agree on
the exact split of its joint holdings in the Elk Hills facility
with the Energy Department. The company and the government
operated the field together for more than 50 years, and had
agreed to proceed with the sale of the government''s stake to
Occidental Petroleum Corp. (OXY) while they worked out the holdings. </p>
<p>Steven Thai, an Energy Department spokesman, referred calls
for comment to the Justice Department. Allison Price, a Justice
Department spokeswoman, didn''t immediately respond to an e-mail
message seeking comment. Donald Campbell, a spokesman for San
Ramon, California-based Chevron, didn''t immediately respond to
an e-mail message seeking comment on the ruling. </p>
<h2>Elk Hills </h2>
<p>The Elk Hills Field, located near Bakersfield, California,
encompasses more than 47,000 acres and includes more than 1,000
wells, a 47-megawatt power plant and two units that process gas.
The government''s share in the field of about 78 percent, which
is still being disputed by Chevron, is estimated to hold
reserves equal to about 1 billion barrels of oil. </p>
<p>Occidental Petroleum bought the government''s stake in Elk
Hills, one of the largest remaining oil fields outside Alaska,
for $3.65 billion in 1997. That''s about $3.65 for each barrel of
oil-equivalent it contains. Chevron and Occidental are not
operating the oil and gas field together. </p>
<p>The sale of the interest in Elk Hills reserve, set aside in
the early 1900s for emergency military use by the U.S. Navy, was
the largest government asset sale ever at the time. </p>
<p>In her ruling, Braden ordered the government to reimburse
Chevron for 42 percent of its legal fees for two years,
beginning in February 2007, as a sanction for bad faith
litigation tactics involving the production of documents. </p>
<p>The case is Chevron USA Inc. v. U.S., 04-1365, U.S. Court
of Federal Claims (Washington). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Charles Mead" date="May 09, 2013 10:08 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-09/general-motors-financial-bonds-rise-after-2-5-billion-offering.html"><headline>General Motors Financial Bonds Rise After $2.5 Billion Offering</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Bonds of General Motors Co. (GM)''s lending
unit rose after the company issued more debt than it had
previously forecast with a $2.5 billion offering. </p>
<p>General Motors Financial''s $750 million of 4.25 percent
notes due May 2023, which the unit issued at par, traded at 103
cents on the dollar to yield 3.89 percent at 8:54 a.m. in New
York, according to Trace, the bond-price reporting system of the
Financial Industry Regulatory Authority. </p>
<p>The company also sold $750 million of 3.25 percent debt due
2018 and $1 billion of 2.75 percent securities maturing 2016 in
an offering originally marketed at $2 billion. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore and Liam Vaughan" date="May 09, 2013  6:10 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-09/goldman-sachs-traders-lost-money-on-two-days-in-first-quarter.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Traders Lost Money on Two Days in First Quarter</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), which
generated about half its revenue from trading last quarter,
posted losses from that business on two days in the first three
months of 2013, compared with one day a year earlier. </p>
<p>The bank''s traders made more than $100 million on 17 days
in the quarter ended March 31, compared with 24 days in the
year-earlier period, the New York-based company said in a
regulatory filing today. </p>
<p>The bank generated $5.22 billion from its trading division
in the first quarter of 2013, excluding accounting charges, a 12
percent declined from the year-earlier period. About $230
million of that revenue came from a reinsurance business the
firm sold a majority stake in this month. </p>
<p>Clients were more active really in the first month of the
quarter and then it slowed down a bit in March, Chief
Financial Officer Harvey Schwartz said last month. As issues
started to come back more on to front screens as it relates to
issues in Europe, clients obviously pulled back toward the end
of the quarter. </p>
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. and Bank of America Corp. (BAC) had perfect
trading records in the first quarter, making money on every day
of the period, while Morgan Stanley posted losses in eight
sessions. Citigroup Inc. doesn''t disclose money-losing days. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
Pedestrians pass in front of 200 West Street, which houses the headquarters of Goldman Sachs Group Inc., in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lynn Doan" date="May 10, 2013  7:27 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-10/jpmorgan-may-be-evading-power-trading-ban-with-swaps-iso-says.html"><headline>JPMorgan May Evade Power-Trading Ban With Swaps, ISO Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) unit suspended
from market-based power trading in California may be evading the
ban through swap agreements with EDF Group and Cargill Inc.
subsidiaries, the state''s grid operator said. </p>
<p>EDF Trading North America LLC signed a swap agreement with
J.P. Morgan Ventures Energy Corp.''s BE CA LLC unit for energy
from units at three power plants in California for the six
months that the JPMorgan subsidiary is banned from trading, the
California Independent System Operator Corp. said in a filing to
federal regulators yesterday. Cargill Power Markets LLC has also
acquired control of units at two plants through a swap contract,
the filing shows. </p>
<p>The units covered by the EDF and Cargill contracts
together comprise the total capacity previously controlled by
JPMVEC and BE CA LLC in California, Cal ISO said in the filing
with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission. There is
precedent for firms using swap contracts to secure a portion of
the profit stream from a unit, while masking the identity of a
party that has some level of control over the bidding. </p>
<p>JPMorgan, the biggest U.S. bank, was warned by FERC in
March that its personnel and two subsidiaries may face claims
stemming from a probe into bidding practices. FERC revoked J.P.
Morgan Ventures'' right to trade power at market-based rates in
California for six months starting in April, saying the firm
provided misleading information to the ISO. </p>
<h2>Internal E-Mails </h2>
<p>FERC said in September it had initiated a proceeding
against the energy trading unit focused on whether JPMorgan''s
energy division met its obligations to give documents to the
ISO. J.P. Morgan Ventures Energy allegedly made bids that
resulted in at least $73 million in improper payments to the
generators, according to FERC. </p>
<p>The investigation came to light when the commission went to
court seeking internal e-mails from JPMorgan. </p>
<p>FERC has stepped up scrutiny of corporations as it wields
policing powers that were expanded in the wake of Enron Corp.''s
2001 collapse. The agency has announced since January 2011 at
least 13 separate investigations of possible market
manipulation, including probes of energy-trading units at
Barclays Plc (BARC) and JPMorgan Chase  Co. </p>
<p>Through contracts with EDF and Cargill, JPMorgan could be
bringing in profits during its suspension beyond those
contemplated by FERC in its order, Cal ISO said. The operator
recommended broad changes that would capture any situation in
which a market participant structured transactions to evade
its suspension of market-based rate authority. </p>
<p>Jennifer Zuccarelli, a JPMorgan spokeswoman in New York,
declined to comment on the California ISO filing, saying the
company is still reviewing it. </p>
<h2>Deal Approved </h2>
<p>California utility regulators approved a deal yesterday
under which BE CA LLC would give Edison International (EIX)''s Southern
California Edison unit all of its rights to energy from power-plant units in California beginning Oct. 1, when JPMorgan''s
trading suspension ends. </p>
<p>The tolling arrangement, which runs through May 2018,
covers power from 12 natural gas-fired units at the Alamitos,
Huntington Beach and Redondo Beach power plants in the Los
Angeles Basin area with a total capacity of 3,690 megawatts, the
resolution approved by the California Public Utilities
Commission yesterday shows. </p>
<p>BE CA previously resold some tolling and resource adequacy
rights from the units to Edison, the filing shows. </p>
<p>In a separate proceeding today, FERC granted an April 10
request from J.P. Morgan Ventures for rehearing on how it''ll
manage electricity sales in power markets outside California
during its six-month suspension and gave the company 15 days to
file more information. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="May 10, 2013  2:46 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-10/jpmorgan-directors-oppose-splitting-dimon-s-role-as-disruptive-.html"><headline>JPMorgan Directors Oppose Splitting Dimon''s Role as Disruptive''</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s leading
directors urged shareholders to reject calls for Chief Executive
Officer Jamie Dimon to relinquish his dual role as chairman and
chief executive officer, saying it could be disruptive and
against the best interests of investors. </p>
<p>An inflexible approach to the question of whether one
person can serve as both chairman and CEO is not the right
answer, according to a letter today sent to shareholders of
the New York-based company. It was signed by former Exxon Mobil
Corp. Chairman and CEO Lee R. Raymond, who serves as the board''s
presiding director, and former Johnson  Johnson Chairman and
CEO William C. Weldon, who heads the panel''s corporate
governance and nominating committee. </p>
<p>Proxy advisers at Glass Lewis  Co. and Institutional
Shareholder Services have told investors to vote for a separate
chairman and oust some directors. Calls for Dimon, 57, to
relinquish the chairmanship have mounted since last May, when
JPMorgan disclosed lapses in risk controls at its chief
investment office in the so-called London Whale episode that led
to at least $6.2 billion in losses on derivatives. </p>
<p>JPMorgan is the biggest U.S. bank by assets and deposits. </p>
<p>ISS on May 3 urged a vote in favor of splitting Dimon''s
roles and removing three directors. Glass Lewis urged
shareholders May 7 to oust three members of the four-person risk
committee as well as all three audit committee members following
internal and congressional investigations that revealed
questionable risk-management practices at both the senior
management and board levels. </p>
<p>The board''s current structure provides appropriate
accountability to our shareholders and counterbalance to the
combined CEO/Chair role, according to Raymond and Weldon. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Rick Green" date="May 10, 2013  2:08 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-10/jpmorgan-directors-say-splitting-dimon-s-job-could-be-disruptive.html"><headline>JPMorgan Directors Say Splitting Dimon''s Job Could Be Disruptive</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co., the biggest
U.S. lender, opposed splitting Jamie Dimon''s roles of chairman
and chief executive officer because the change could be
disruptive. </p>
<p>The board is made up of directors who are all independent
other than Dimon and is led by a strong presiding director,
according to a letter sent today by two directors to
stockholders of the New York-based company. The structure
provides appropriate accountability to our shareholders and
counterbalance to the combined CEO/Chair role, according to
the letter. </p>
<p>The letter was written by former Exxon Mobil Corp. Chairman
and CEO Lee R. Raymond, the board''s presiding director, and
former Johnson  Johnson Chairman and CEO William C. Weldon, the
chairman of JPMorgan''s corporate governance and nominating
committee. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Brian Wingfield and David Biller" date="May 10, 2013  1:19 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-10/morgan-stanley-joins-u-s-trip-targeting-brazil-boom.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Joins U.S. Trip Targeting Brazil Boom</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The Obama administration is setting
out to help exporters get in on Brazil''s building boom even as
it spars with the region''s biggest economy over high tariffs,
rules favoring local companies and monetary policies. </p>
<p>Brazil will be the focus of a U.S. trade mission for 20
companies including Morgan Stanley, CNH Global (CNH) NV, Textron
Inc. (TXT)''s Cessna Aircraft Co. and OSI Systems Inc. (OSIS)''s Rapiscan,
which makes airport screening devices. The delegation also will
visit Colombia and Panama, where commercial investment is on the
rise. </p>
<p>They''re going to be spending big bucks on their
infrastructure improvement, Deputy Commerce Secretary Rebecca Blank, who has led the agency for 11 months, said in a phone
interview. The May 12-18 mission is her first as agency head. </p>
<p>The U.S. last year exported $43.7 billion in goods to
Brazil, a 68 percent increase since 2009, when President Barack Obama took office and the global economic crisis depressed
global exports. U.S. merchandise sent to Colombia increased 73
percent, to $16.4 billion, and to Panama jumped 131 percent, to
$9.9 billion, during the same period. </p>
<p>The administration of President Barack Obama in September
threatened to retaliate against Brazil for what it called
protectionist tariff increases on goods including steel,
plastics and machinery. The Latin American nation has accused
industrialized nations of waging a currency war to weaken its
exchange rates and thus boost exports. U.S. support for cotton
farmers and Brazilian policies to favor local manufacturers also
have heightened trade tensions between the nations. </p>




Photographer: Jonathan Alcorn/Bloomberg

<p>
People enter a Textron Inc. Cessna business jet at Santa Monica Municipal airport. Brazil will be the focus of a U.S. trade mission for 20 companies including Morgan Stanley, CNH Global N.V., Textron Inc.''s Cessna Aircraft Co. and OSI Systems Inc.''s Rapiscan, which makes airport screening devices. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christine Harper and Serena Saitto" date="May 10, 2013 12:28 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-10/morgan-stanley-hires-collins-for-investment-banking-operations.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Hires Collins for Investment-Banking Operations</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley re-hired John Collins,
a mergers-and-acquisitions banker who left the firm three years
ago to join Moelis  Co., for a newly created role as global
operations officer for the investment-banking division. </p>
<p>Collins, 45, will start the job in New York in early July,
according to Mark Lake, a spokesman for the New York-based bank.
He will report to Mark Eichorn and Franck Petitgas, the global
co-heads of investment banking. </p>
<p>Collins first joined Morgan Stanley in 1990 as an analyst
in the firm''s real-estate banking group and spent most of his
career in the mergers-and-acquisitions department, where he was
promoted to managing director in 2004, according to Lake. He
left to join Moelis in April 2010. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s investment-banking division generated $945
million in first-quarter revenue, up 11 percent from a year
earlier, the company reported last month. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sonia Sirletti and Francesca Cinelli" date="May 10, 2013  1:41 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-10/generali-profit-unexpectedly-rises-as-non-life-income-climbs.html"><headline>Generali Profit Unexpectedly Rises as Non-Life Income Climbs</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Assicurazioni Generali SpA (UCG), Italy''s
biggest insurer, said first-quarter profit rose 6.3 percent as
earnings at its non-life insurance business increased. </p>
<p>Net income in the three months to March climbed to 603
million euros ($787 million) from 567 million euros a year
earlier, the Trieste, Italy-based company said in a statement
today. That beat the 561.4 million-euro average estimate of 10
analysts surveyed by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Mario Greco is seeking to boost
profit at Generali and increase capital by cutting costs,
disposing of non-strategic assets and targeting faster-growing
emerging markets. The company, which targets 4 billion euros in
revenue from disposals by 2015, is selling its U.S. life-reinsurance business and Swiss asset-management unit BSI Group
as part of a plan approved in January. </p>
<p>Generali still is an attractive investment case for
investors comfortable with exposure to Italy, Michael van Wegen and Jelena Bjelanovic, analysts at Bank of America Merrill
Lynch, wrote last week. We expect the company to make steady
progress to improve the solvency ratio over the next few years,
driven by earnings and divestments, they said. </p>
<p>Generali reiterated today that it expects an improvement in
its total operating result in 2013, forecasting a reduction in
life premiums and an increase in non-life. </p>
<h2>Income Climbs </h2>
<p>Operating income rose 8 percent in the first quarter from a
year earlier to 1.33 billion euros as income at the non-life
business rose 27 percent to 520 million euros. Operating income
at the life business declined 2.6 percent to 797 million euros. </p>
<p>In this quarter we have recorded our best operating
result of the last four years, thanks to an excellent PC
performance and a solid life business, Greco said. We are
making good progress in implementing the planned measures to
turn around our business. </p>
<p>The solvency ratio, a measure of an insurer''s capacity to
absorb losses, dropped to 138 percent on March 30 from 145
percent at the start of the year. The ratio climbed to 145
percent as of April 30, Generali said. The first-quarter reading
was hurt by the purchase of a 25 percent stake in the eastern
Europe venture from private-equity firm PPF Group NV. </p>
<p>Spending on claims and other costs as a percentage of
premiums, known as the combined ratio, improved to 93.6 percent
in the first quarter from 95.4 percent a year earlier. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joel Rosenblatt" date="May 10, 2013 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-10/jpmorgan-accused-by-harris-of-illegal-collection-lawsuits.html"><headline>JPMorgan Accused by Harris of Illegal Collection Lawsuits</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) was sued by
California over claims that the biggest U.S. credit-card lender
pursued lawsuits against defaulted borrowers based on
insufficient evidence. </p>
<p>From January 2008 to April 2011, JPMorgan filed more than
100,000 debt-collection lawsuits in California, taking illegal
shortcuts to obtain judgments against consumers, Harris claims
in the lawsuit filed yesterday in state court in Los Angeles. </p>
<p>The bank couldn''t have won the judgments so quickly if it
had complied with minimum consumer protections under state law,
according to the complaint. Harris said in a statement yesterday
that the suit was filed to end widespread, illegal robo-signing of court filings without the review of relevant files
or bank records. </p>
<p>Chase abused the judicial process and engaged in serious
misconduct against California credit-card borrowers, Harris
said in the statement. The lawsuit seeks to hold Chase
accountable for systematically using illegal tactics to flood
California''s courts with specious lawsuits against consumers. </p>
<p>Kristin Lemkau, a spokeswoman for New York-based JPMorgan,
didn''t immediately  yesterday to phone and e-mail messages
seeking comment on the lawsuit. </p>
<p>According to the complaint, based on alleged violations of
California''s unfair competition law, JPMorgan sent letters to
consumers demanding payment of a balance due, claiming they may
be liable for attorney''s fees, and threatening to garnish income
and place liens on property. </p>
<p>The correspondence is signed by a lawyer, though no lawyer
reviewed the consumer''s file to determine whether the claims and
amounts due are correct, according to the suit. </p>
<p>The case is California v. JPMorgan Chase, BC508466,
California Superior Court for the County of Los Angeles. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jef Feeley" date="May 13, 2013  7:16 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-13/morgans-hotel-board-faced-burkle-deal-threats-judge-told.html"><headline>Morgans Hotel Board Faced Burkle Deal Threats, Judge Told</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgans Hotel Group Co. (MHGC) board members
faced threats by billionaire Ron Burkle to harm the hotel chain
if they didn''t back his acquisition of several of Morgans''s
businesses, a lawyer for one of the company''s directors said. </p>
<p>Burkle, whose Yucaipa Cos. is swapping $230 million in
notes and preferred stock for ownership of Morgans''s Delano
South Beach Hotel in Miami and a restaurant company,
threatened to crater some of the hotel company''s other deals
if directors didn''t accept his buyout bid and offer to backstop
a $100 million recapitalization effort, A. Thompson Bayliss, an
attorney for a Morgans board member opposing the deal, told a
judge today. Burkle also serves on the hotel chain''s board. </p>
<p>What we have here is business terrorism by Mr. Burkle,
Bayliss told Delaware Chancery Court Judge Travis Laster at a
hearing in Wilmington today. </p>
<p>Jason Taubman Kalisman, a Morgans director and a founding
member of its largest shareholder, OTK Associates, sued his
fellow board members last month over their decision to back the
Yucaipa deal and the $100 million rights offering to current
investors. OTK owns about 14 percent of New York-based Morgans''s
shares, according to court filings. </p>
<h2>Proxy Fight </h2>
<p>OTK began a proxy fight earlier this year, saying it''s
seeking to overhaul Morgans''s board and return the company to
profitability. The 13-hotel chain has lost money in every
quarter since 2007, according to data compiled by Bloomberg.
Kalisman wants Laster to bar the swap and recapitalization from
proceeding until after the July 10 shareholder vote. </p>
<p>Last month, Morgans officials agreed to postpone the rights
offering until May 16 so Laster could consider Kalisman''s
complaints about the deal. OTK and Kalisman accused Morgans''s
current directors of rushing to complete the offering before the
company''s annual shareholder meeting, originally scheduled for
May 15, to avoid losing their seats as a result of the proxy
vote. </p>
<p>Lawyers for the Morgans board and Burkle argued today the
swap and recapitalization deals are best interests of the hotel
company''s investors and shouldn''t be enjoined. </p>
<h2>Rhetoric, Innuendo'' </h2>
<p>An injunction could lead to the breakup of this deal,
Raymond DiCamillo, a lawyer for company directors, told Laster. </p>
<p>Kalisman''s lawyers are relying on rhetoric and innuendo
to raise question about Burkle''s negotiations with his Morgans
board colleagues over the swap and the recapitalization, Bruce
Silverstein, the billionaire''s lawyer, said during the hearing. </p>
<p>Silverstein added that Burkle isn''t seeking to gain control
of the hotel chain in the $230 million deal, which includes the
billionaire''s holdings in Morgans preferred shares and
convertible notes. Burkle also will retire warrants and assume
an $18 million promissory note as part of the deal. </p>
<p>Frank Quintero, a spokesman for Los Angeles-based Yucaipa,
didn''t immediately return a call seeking comment on Bayliss''s
claims the billionaire threatened to disrupt Morgans''s operation
if his board colleagues didn''t support his acquisition bid. </p>
<h2>Various Threats'' </h2>
<p>Kalisman contends in court filings the company''s plan to
sell $100 million in stock to existing shareholders at $6 a
share could mean Burkle winds up with as much as 32 percent of
Morgans''s shares if the rights aren''t exercised in full. He also
objects to the sale of the Miami hotel and the Light Group, a
restaurant company, to the billionaire in exchange for Morgans
notes and preferred shares. </p>
<p>As part of his negotiations over the deal, Burkle liked
to use various threats to try to intimidate his colleagues on
Morgans board, Kalisman''s lawyers said in court filings. </p>
<p>Burkle repeatedly threatened to litigate to pressure
Morgans officials into a deal, according to a filing unsealed
just before today''s hearing. The billionaire also threatened to
scuttle deals aimed at having Morgans executives operate hotels
in Moscow and Las Vegas, Kalisman''s lawyers said. </p>
<p>Kalisman contends Burkle''s supporters on Morgans board
failed to seriously consider competing bids for the hotel and
food-and-beverage company. </p>
<p>Even though he was a Morgans director and a member of the
board group responsible for evaluating such transactions, his
colleagues weren''t forthright about the rights offering''s
details and didn''t give him reasonable notice that the deal
would be considered, Bayliss argued today. </p>
<p>The Morgans chain features boutique hotels such as the
Mondarian SoHo in New York, the Clift Hotel in San Francisco and
the Delano Marrakech in Morocco. </p>
<p>The case is Kalisman v. Friedman, 8447, Delaware Chancery
Court (Wilmington). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="May 13, 2013  6:59 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-13/goldman-shareholders-should-oppose-pay-plan-glass-lewis-says.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Investors Should Oppose Pay Plan, Glass Lewis Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc (GS). shareholders should vote against the bank''s executive-pay plan, proxy-advisory firm Glass Lewis  Co. said, while ISS Proxy Advisory Services USA supported the program. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs has been deficient in linking compensation to company performance, Glass Lewis said yesterday in a report, which also opposed the re-election of compensation committee Chairman James A. Johnson. ISS said in a May 8 report that shareholders should vote for Johnson at the New York-based bank''s May 23 annual meeting. </p> <p>Chief Executive Officer Lloyd C. Blankfein, 58, received $21 million for last year, his highest annual compensation package since 2007. Goldman Sachs shares climbed 41 percent in 2012, leaving them 24 percent below the level at which they ended 2010. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs doesn''t have specific measures to help set annual pay for top executives, Glass Lewis said in the report, which gave the firm a D grade in linking pay to performance. ISS said the increase in executive pay for 2012 reflected stronger company performance. </p> <p>While the bank has topped peers in earnings-per-share growth and return on equity, it has trailed in total shareholder return, according to Glass Lewis''s analysis. Glass Lewis recommended last year that shareholders back the pay plan in an advisory vote, and the measure was approved with 94 percent support. </p>




Photographer: Victor J. Blue/Bloomberg

<p>
Pedestrians walk in front of the entrance to Goldman Sachs Group Inc.''s headquarters in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Carter Dougherty" date="May 13, 2013  3:37 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-13/jpmorgan-says-it-faces-enforcement-on-consumer-practices.html"><headline>JPMorgan Says It Faces Enforcement on Consumer Practices</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM),  the biggest
U.S. bank by assets, said it will face enforcement action from
federal regulators over its collection practices and add-on
products commonly appended to credit cards. </p>
<p>The company said in a May 8 regulatory filing that it
expects that its banking supervisors will in the future continue
to take more formal enforcement actions against the firm,
instead of issuing informal supervisory actions or criticisms. </p>
<p>The U.S. Consumer Financial Protection Bureau is conducting
an industrywide review of credit card add-on products, which can
include debt cancellation and identity theft services. New York-based JPMorgan cited an identity theft product in its filing. </p>
<p>Banks including JPMorgan and Bank of America Corp. stopped
offering such add-on products entirely in the face of regulatory
scrutiny. The bureau''s first enforcement action was against
Capital One Financial Corp. (COF), which paid about $210 million in
restitution and penalties over the products. </p>
<p>Paul Hartwick, a JPMorgan spokesman, said the bank had no
comment on the filing. </p>
<p>JPMorgan, the biggest U.S. bank by assets and deposits, is
facing regulatory inquiries on its trading practices and conduct
in the energy business. Shareholders are also considering at
their May 21 meeting whether to separate the chairman and chief
executive officer role, both currently held by Jamie Dimon. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="May 13, 2013 10:51 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-13/jpmorgan-stock-would-decline-10-if-dimon-leaves-bank-mayo-says.html"><headline>JPMorgan Stock Would Decline 10% If Dimon Leaves Bank, Mayo Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) shares would
probably fall by about 10 percent if Chief Executive Officer
Jamie Dimon leaves the company, Mike Mayo, an analyst at CSLA
Ltd., said today in a research note to clients. </p>
<p>The lender''s market value would likely drop by about $20
billion if shareholders vote on May 21 to strip Dimon of his
chairman role and he leaves as some analysts predict, Mayo said. </p>
<p>The stock would suffer because the New York-based bank has
no obvious successor to Dimon, 57, who is top-ranked among large
bank CEOs, Mayo said. </p>
<p>JPMorgan declined 0.2 percent to $48.85 at 10:42 a.m. in
New York. The shares have gained 11 percent this year, compared
with the 14 percent advance of the 24-company KBW Bank Index. (BKX) </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Pratik Parija and Pooja Thakur" date="May 13, 2013  7:23 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-13/jpmorgan-backed-developer-says-slump-to-reverse-corporate-india.html"><headline>JPMorgan-Backed Developer Says Slump to Reverse: Corporate India</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Parsvnath Developers Ltd. (PARSV), an Indian
builder that counts JPMorgan Chase  Co. among project
investors, says sales growth is rebounding after four quarters
of declines, as rate cuts this year help revive the economy. </p>
<p>The real-estate company, which has 190 million square feet
of land, is introducing new plans for buyers to sweeten offers
and aggressively selling units to double sales this quarter
as demand picks up in the world''s second-most populous country,
Chairman Pradeep Jain said in an interview. Quarterly group
revenue of Parsvnath slid an average 26 percent in 2012,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>The overall economic situation isn''t very great but is
recovering, Jain said in New Delhi, where Parsvnath is based.
End-user demand is good, particularly in Delhi and surrounding
areas. You can see growth in sales from the current quarter. </p>
<p>India''s central bank has lowered borrowing costs three
times in 2013, kindling optimism the property market will snap
out of a slowdown that propelled unsold homes to a record in the
final quarter of last year. Growth in the $1.8 trillion economy,
Asia''s third biggest, is set to accelerate from an estimated 5
percent in the 12 months ended March 31, the least in a decade,
according to government estimates. </p>
<h2>Share Slump </h2>
<p>Shares of Parsvnath have dropped 37 percent in the past
year, making it the worst performing stock in the SP BSE India
Realty Index. DLF Ltd. (DLFU), India''s biggest developer whose market
value of 403 billion rupees ($7.4 billion) is 26 times that of
Jain''s company, has gained 24 percent in the period. The
benchmark SP BSE Sensex index has climbed 21 percent. </p>
<p>JPMorgan''s private-equity unit had paid 2.6 billion rupees
in December, 2010 for a 22 percent stake at Parsvnath''s La
Tropicana residential project in the nation''s capital, according
to Jain, while Sun-Apollo Ventures LLC and Red Fort Capital are
other funds that have invested in its other projects. </p>
<p>Parsvnath has introduced a plan that allows buyers to pay
25 percent of the property''s cost on booking, and the rest while
taking possession with no extra cost built in and no loans
involved. The offer, which Jain said will lure buyers and boost
profit, is for four commercial and 16 residential projects
across India. </p>
<p>It''s a very risky move for a developer, especially if it
is a falling property market, said Parikshit Kandpal, a
Mumbai-based analyst at Karvy Stock Broking Ltd. The risk is
entirely on the developer as there''s no customer''s bank loan to
back up the sale. </p>
<h2>Most Expensive </h2>
<p>Home prices in Mumbai, India''s most expensive real estate
market, rose to a record high of 11,626 rupees a square foot in
the quarter ended March 31, according to data from Liases Foras
Real Estate Rating  Research Pvt., driven by speculation demand
will pick up. In the capital region, where Parsvnath operates,
prices have risen 21 percent since June 30. </p>
<p>In the previous quarter, the stock of unsold homes at new
residential projects climbed to a record, as rising prices
crimped affordability in the nation''s biggest cities, according
to Pankaj Kapoor, founder of property research company Liases.
Total unsold inventory of residential stock in the six major
cities tracked by Liases Foras climbed to 100 million square
feet (9.3 million square meters), the highest since 2009. </p>
<p>Interest rates, which are still near a two-year high, and a
cultural aversion to debt account for India''s relatively low
home-loan penetration rates. Home loan debt of $104 billion is
equal to 8 percent of gross domestic product compared with 20
percent in China and 77 percent in the U.S., according to data
compiled by Housing Development Finance Corp. (HDFC) </p>
<h2>Worst Is Over </h2>
<p>Indian mortgage rates, at 10 percent on average, are among
the highest in Asia. That compares with about 2 percent in Hong
Kong, 6.5 percent in China, and 6 percent in South Korea,
according to Credit Suisse Group AG. </p>
<p>The worst for the industry is over, Jain said separately on
May 9, adding the environment is changing for the better.
Prices may increase as much as 18 percent annually, he said. </p>
<p>Real-estate stocks in India are looking more attractive as
borrowing costs decline and demand for homes support property
prices, according to CLSA Asia-Pacific Markets. The 11-member
SP BSE India Realty Index has rebounded 9 percent from a five-month low reached on April 9. It is still 18 percent lower than
its 21-month high reached on Jan. 18. </p>
<p>Residential volumes continued to hold up in the first
quarter of 2013, Mahesh Nandurkar and Abhinav Sinha, Mumbai-based analysts at CLSA, wrote in a note to clients on April 17.
With residential volumes holding well and chances of interest-rate cuts increasing, property stocks are offering attractive
entry points. </p>
<h2>Rate Cuts </h2>
<p>Bank of America Merrill Lynch predicts the Reserve Bank of
India will extend its rate reductions with four more for a total
of 1 percentage point through the end of March. Governor Duvvuri Subbarao lowered the benchmark repurchase rate in March and May,
both times signaling there''s little space for further cuts. </p>
<p>Sales volumes have picked up in some markets with signs of
an economic revival and a rebound in stocks, according to
Karvy''s Kandpal. Finance Minister Palaniappan Chidambaram last
month predicted growth of as much as 6.7 percent in the year
that started April 1, from an estimated 5 percent in the
previous 12 months. </p>
<p>Over the earlier part of the past 12 months, many issues
with the sector caused a massive underperformance of listed
realty stock, Kandpal wrote in a research note last month.
There''s been a marked shift during the latter part of the last
six months. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Brian Chappatta" date="May 13, 2013 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-13/morgan-keegan-denies-fraud-in-offering-defaulted-moberly-bonds.html"><headline>Morgan Keegan Denies Fraud in Offering Defaulted Moberly Bonds</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Keegan  Co. is seeking to
dismiss a petition that claims the underwriter made fraudulent
statements when offering $39 million of now-defaulted municipal
bonds for an artificial-sweetener plant in Moberly, Missouri. </p>
<p>Missouri Secretary of State Jason Kander last month issued
a cease-and-desist order against Memphis-based Morgan Keegan for
fraud and dishonest and unethical practices in selling debt
for Mamtek U.S. to build the factory. Morgan Keegan denied those
claims in a May 3 filing with Kander''s office. </p>
<p>Kander seeks excessive, punitive, non-remedial,
cumulative, objectively unreasonable, arbitrary, capricious,
disproportionate, unwarranted, unsupported and unsupportable
sanctions, penalties and relief that fair-minded, objective and
unbiased jurists operating a fair and unbiased tribunal would
never impose, Morgan Keegan said in the filing. </p>
<p>The battle between Kander and Morgan Keegan is the latest
in Moberly, a city of 14,000 that became one of the cautionary
tales of localities issuing debt for economic-development
projects in the $3.7 trillion municipal market. The Moberly
Industrial Development Authority, which sold the bonds in July
2010, was downgraded 13 levels by Standard  Poor''s to CC, or
junk, from A- in September 2011. SP cut the agency two more
steps to D, its lowest, after a payment default in March 2012. </p>
<p>Without Morgan Keegan''s involvement, this failed
investment would not have cost Missouri investors more than $6.5
million, Kander said in an April 4 statement. Companies have
a duty to disclose the risks of stocks and bonds before their
clients invest. </p>
<h2>Three Weeks </h2>
<p>Morgan Keegan was a unit of Regions Financial Corp. (RF) when it
served as underwriter for the Moberly bonds. It was since sold
to Raymond James Financial Inc. Jana Strange, a spokeswoman for
St. Petersburg, Florida-based Raymond James, declined to comment
on Kander''s order. </p>
<p>The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission and Texas are
also investigating Morgan Keegan for violating securities laws,
according to a May 8 filing from Regions Financial. </p>
<p>Moberly officials gave Mamtek Chairman and Chief Executive
Officer Bruce Cole initial approval for the $39 million of munis
within three weeks of his arrival in town. In September, the SEC
charged Cole with fraud and he was arrested. </p>
<p>Morgan Keegan misrepresented that Mamtek had a facility in
China that was producing sucralose when the bonds were offered
in 2010, according to Kander''s petition. He also said the
company misled investors when stating bond payments were backed
by Mamtek''s patents, when the company had none. </p>
<p>Many problems existed with the offering, and if Morgan
Keegan had done its due diligence and investigated the
feasibility of Mamtek''s business plan, we would not be in this
situation, Kander said. </p>
<p>The Moberly agency''s defaulted debt maturing in 2024 traded
on Feb. 14 at an average yield of 62 percent, or 8.56 cents on
the dollar, data compiled by Bloomberg show. That''s up from an
average yield of 33 percent when the securities last traded on
Dec. 11. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Pablo Gonzalez" date="May 14, 2013  6:17 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-14/chevron-ypf-to-sign-1-5-billion-deal-to-develop-shale-in-july.html"><headline>Chevron, YPF to Sign $1.5 Billion Deal to Develop Shale in July</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX) will become the first
major oil company to partner with YPF SA to develop shale oil
and a final deal is expected in July, YPF said. </p>
<p>Miguel Galuccio, chief executive officer of YPF, and Ali Moshiri, Chevron''s head of Latin America, Middle East and
Africa, visited the Patagonia shale formation today and met with
Neuquen''s governor Jorge Sapag, according to an e-mailed
statement today from the Buenos Aires-based company. </p>
<p>Jim Craig, a spokesman for San Ramon, California-based
Chevron, didn''t immediately replied to a call and an e-mail
seeking comment. </p>
<p>Moshiri, who in December signed with Galuccio an exclusive
right to negotiate final terms for YPF to transfer a 50 percent
interest in Loma de la Lata Norte and Loma Campana, was
surprised with the advanced state of YPF exploration
projects, according to the statement. The fields for the $1.5
billion joint venture comprise an area of 290 square kilometers
(180 miles) in southwestern Argentina. </p>
<p>Along with Chevron, we will constitute the first joint
venture to develop shale, Galuccio said. </p>
<p>YPF is pumping 7,000 barrels a day, according to the e-mailed press release. Vaca Muerta, which means dead cow in
Spanish, holds at least 23 billion barrels of oil equivalent,
according to a report by independent auditor Ryder Scott
released in February 2012 by YPF. Argentina holds the world''s
third-largest shale gas reserves, according to US Energy
Administration data. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jef Feeley" date="May 14, 2013  5:23 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-14/morgans-hotel-group-burkle-deal-can-t-proceed-judge-says.html"><headline>Morgans Hotel Group Burkle Deal Can''t Proceed, Judge Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgans Hotel Group Co. (MHGC) can''t sell
billionaire Ron Burkle two of its businesses and begin a $100
million recapitalization plan because directors didn''t properly
approve the actions, a judge ruled. </p>
<p>Delaware Chancery Court Judge Travis Laster today barred
Morgans from going forward with the deal, which would allow
Burkle''s Yucaipa Cos. to swap $230 million in notes and
preferred stock for ownership of Morgans''s Delano South Beach
Hotel in Miami and a restaurant company. Laster found Morgans
directors'' process for approving the transactions was flawed. </p>
<p>These were transactions that had major consequences for
the company and involved the sale of its crown jewel, Laster
said in a conference call with attorneys for the company, Burkle
and a dissident Morgans director who sued to challenge the deal. </p>
<p>Jason Taubman Kalisman, the company director and a founding
member of its largest shareholder, OTK Associates, sued his
fellow board members last month over their decision to back the
Yucaipa deal and the $100 million rights offering to current
investors. OTK owns about 14 percent of New York-based Morgans''s
shares, according to court filings. </p>
<p>OTK opened a proxy fight this year, saying it''s seeking to
overhaul Morgans''s board and return the company to
profitability. The chain, which includes 13 boutique hotels, has
lost money in every quarter since 2007, according to data
compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<h2>June Meeting </h2>
<p>OTK and Kalisman accused Morgans''s current directors of
rushing to complete the offering and the Burkle swap before the
company''s annual shareholder meeting, originally scheduled for
May 15, to avoid losing their seats in the proxy vote. The board
had pushed the vote back to July 10. </p>
<p>Laster ordered Morgans officials to hold the annual meeting
tomorrow as originally planned. Still, the judge said directors
can open the meeting as a procedural matter and then vote to
postpone it. That would give company executives time to provide
proper notice about the meeting and the proxy vote, the judge
said. Only investors who held Morgans stock as of March 22 can
cast ballots, he noted. </p>
<p>Morgans officials have rescheduled the company''s annual
meeting for June 14 in the wake of Laster''s ruling, Lex Suvanto,
a spokesman for Morgans Hotel at Abernathy McGregor in New York,
said in an e-mailed statement. Frank Quintero, a spokesman for
Los Angeles-based Yucaipa, didn''t immediately return calls for
comment. </p>
<h2>Record Date'' </h2>
<p>OTK officials said they were pleased Laster ordered Morgans
executives to limit voting to investors who owned shares as of
March 22. They accused the company and Burkle of seeking to
change the so-called record date for who could cast ballots in
the proxy vote to help block the push to oust the board. </p>
<p>Laster''s ruling also allows for a trial on the
recapitalization plan, which OTK believes is not in the best
interests of shareholders, Nathaniel Garnick, a spokesman for
OTK at Sard Verbinnen  Co. in New York, said in a e-mailed
statement. </p>
<p>Morgans closed unchanged at $6.14 in Nasdaq trading today.
The hotel chain''s stock rose more than 1.2 percent after Laster
announced his ruling. The shares have climbed 29 percent over
the past 12 months. </p>
<p>Kalisman complained that Burkle, who serves on Morgans''s
board, improperly swayed his colleagues to support his
acquisition bid and backing for the rights offering so that he
could exert control over the hotel chain. </p>
<h2>Various Threats'' </h2>
<p>The billionaire liked to use various threats to try to
intimidate his colleagues on the board, Kalisman''s lawyers
said in court filings. For example, Burkle threatened to scuttle
deals aimed at having Morgans executives operate hotels in
Moscow and Las Vegas, Kalisman''s lawyers said. </p>
<p>Burkle''s warnings and inducements to fellow directors,
which included rides on his private jet, provided incentives for
the board to dismiss competing bids for the hotel and food-and-beverage company, Kalisman contended. </p>
<p>He said that because of his opposition to the Burkle deal
his fellow directors withheld information and kept him in the
dark about the recapitalization plan''s details until the board
met to give it final approval in March. </p>
<p>After hearing arguments in the case, Laster found Burkle
and other Morgans board members pushed to complete the
recapitalization effort in March as part of the board''s response
to OTK''s proxy challenge. </p>
<h2>Rights Offering </h2>
<p>The judge also found Kalisman''s colleagues misled him about
the progress of the rights offering transaction and didn''t
provide proper notice about a meeting to give the plan final
approval. </p>
<p>Morgans'' board is expected to reconsider the
recapitalization plan and the Burke acquisitions in the coming
days, Morgans spokesman Suvanto said in his statement. </p>
<p>The Morgans chain features boutique hotels such as the
Mondrian SoHo in New York, the Clift Hotel in San Francisco and
the Delano Marrakech in Morocco. </p>
<p>The case is Kalisman v. Friedman, 8447, Delaware Chancery
Court (Wilmington). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andy Fixmer" date="May 14, 2013  4:05 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-14/disney-s-abc-adds-avengers-tv-show-to-female-skewing-schedule.html"><headline>Disney''s ABC Adds Avengers'' Show to Female-Skewing Schedule</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS)''s ABC network, ranked
last among the TV viewers that advertisers target, will add five
comedies and seven dramas to its schedule, including a show
based on the secret agency from Marvel''s Avengers. </p>
<p>Marvel''s Agents of S.H.I.E.L.D., from producer Joss Whedon, will air on Tuesdays at 8 p.m., ABC said today in an e-mailed statement. The network and other broadcasters are showing
their new lineups to advertisers this week in an annual event
known as the upfronts. (See schedule below) </p>
<p>The action series marks an effort by the network to draw
more young male viewers, an elusive group on broadcast TV, to a
schedule that skews more toward women with Grey''s Anatomy
and Nashville. It''s also leveraging the highly successful
films based on Marvel superheroes, such as Iron Man. Including a
reality series, ABC unveiled 13 new programs. </p>
<p>That should work better at getting younger male
viewers, said Brad Adgate, director of research at New York
advertising company Horizon Media Inc. The network has very
little live sports, which has hindered its ability to become a
destination for male viewers. </p>
<p>About 65 percent of ABC''s viewers are female, Adgate said,
citing Nielsen data. The average age of ABC''s viewers is about
53, second oldest to CBS, he said. </p>
<p>Disney, also owner of ESPN, gained 0.2 percent to $67.47 at
the close in New York. Shares of the Burbank, California-based
company have climbed 36 percent this year, compared with 16
percent for the Standard  Poor''s 500 index. </p>
<h2>Upscale Women </h2>
<p>In S.H.I.E.L.D, Clark Gregg reprises the role of Agent
Phil Coulson from the Marvel films. He assembles a group of
agents who protect the public from strange occurrences around
the world. The timeslot would pit the show against CBS (CBS)''s
NCIS, the most-watched drama on television. </p>
<p>Our job is to be inclusive, Paul Lee, president of the
ABC Entertainment Group, told reporters on a conference call.
We are a big, broad network that does over deliver on upscale
audience and does over deliver on upscale women. </p>
<p>With the new season, Dancing with the Stars will air
its performance and results shows in a single two-hour block on
Mondays. On Tuesdays, starting with S.H.I.E.L.D., ABC plans
all new programs. Networks regularly schedule new shows after a
well-established program to draw viewers. That practice is
changing due to DVRs, Lee said. </p>
<p>Lead-in does matter and it is important, Lee said. It
is at times compromised by huge DVR viewing from the previous
show. We put on shows and started off with shows we knew we
loved and that we would get behind and market. </p>
<h2>Women''s Empowerment </h2>
<p>With Once Upon a Time in Wonderland, a spinoff of
Once Upon a Time, ABC creates an all-drama Thursday night
that includes Grey''s Anatomy and Scandal. </p>
<p>In Wonderland, set in Victorian England, Sophie Lowe
plays Alice telling stories of a strange new land on the other
side of a rabbit hole. The network built a night of women''s
empowerment, Lee said. </p>
<p>Other dramas to be added this year will include Lucky 7
on Tuesdays and Betrayal on Sundays. ABC''s four September
comedies include The Goldbergs, Trophy Wife, Back in
the Game, and Super Fun Night, the network said. </p>
<p>ABC ordered a reality series called The Quest, from the
producers of The Lord of the Rings movies and The Amazing
Race TV show, according to the statement. In the show, 12
contestants face challenges in a fantasy world with mythical
creatures. </p>
<p>The network also ordered Toy Story of Terror, a
Halloween special from Disney''s Pixar animation studio. </p>
<h2>New Lineups </h2>
<p>ABC ranks last in the 18-to-49-year-old demographic group
that marketers target, with that audience down 9.1 percent for
the season through May 12, Nielsen data show. The network is
second in total viewers behind CBS, averaging 7.8 million
viewers a night, down 6.5 percent from a year earlier. </p>
<p>U.S. TV networks are introducing new shows ahead of
meetings with their biggest advertisers to obtain commitments
and set ad rates for the TV season that begins in September. </p>
<p>NBC, which announced its schedule on May 12, picked up
three dramas and three comedies, including The Michael J. Fox
Show. News Corp. (NWSA)''s Fox said yesterday it will add nine
programs, including the comedy Dads from Seth MacFarlane and
the drama Almost Human from Star Trek producer J.J. Abrams. CBS plans to announce its new shows tomorrow. </p>
<p>Ad spending on network television is projected to decline 2
percent this year to $16.9 billion, and total TV advertising,
including cable networks, will increase 2.8 percent to $63.9
billion, slowing from 7.1 percent in 2012, according to
ZenithOptimedia, Publicis Groupe SA (PUB)''s research division. </p>

                  ABC''s Fall Prime-Time Schedule

MONDAY:
    8:00 p.m.     Dancing with the Stars
   10:00 p.m.     Castle

TUESDAY:
    8:00 p.m.    Marvel''s Agents of S.H.I.E.L.D. (New)
    9:00 p.m.    The Goldbergs (New)
    9:30 p.m.    Trophy Wife (New)
   10:00 p.m.    Lucky 7 (New)

WEDNESDAY:
    8:00 p.m.    The Middle
    8:30 p.m.    Back in the Game (New)
    9:00 p.m.    Modern Family
    9:30 p.m.    Super Fun Night (New)
   10:00 p.m.    Nashville

THURSDAY:
    8:00 p.m.    Once Upon a Time in Wonderland (New)
    9:00 p.m.    Grey''s Anatomy
   10:00 p.m.    Scandal

FRIDAY:
    8:00 p.m.    Last Man Standing
    8:30 p.m.    The Neighbors
    9:00 p.m.    Shark Tank
   10:00 p.m.    20/20

SATURDAY:
    8:00 p.m.    Saturday Night College Football

SUNDAY:
    7:00 p.m.    America''s Funniest Home Videos
    8:00 p.m.    Once Upon a Time
    9:00 p.m.    Revenge
   10:00 p.m.    Betrayal (New)

<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kevin Dugan" date="May 14, 2013  3:58 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-14/goldman-sachs-sells-second-largest-callable-step-up-note-of-2013.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Sells Second-Largest Callable Step-Up Note of 2013</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) sold $31
million of 15-year callable step-up notes, the second-largest
such offering in the U.S. this year. </p>
<p>The securities, issued May 8, yield 3.25 percent for the
first eight years, then increase five more times to 7.5 percent
for the last year, according to a prospectus filed with the U.S.
Securities and Exchange Commission. The New York bank and
Incapital LLC distributed the notes for a 3.24 percent fee. </p>
<p>The bank has the option to call the notes quarterly
starting Nov. 13, according to the prospectus. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs sold $42 million of 15-year callable step-up
notes in two related offerings on Feb. 19 and 25, the biggest
such deal this year. The securities yield 3.5 percent annually
for the first eight years, then increase four times to 7.5
percent during the last six months, according to a prospectus
filed with the SEC. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs has issued the most rate-tied notes in the
U.S. this year, $418.9 million, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. The bank was also No. 1 for all of 2012, selling
$1.14 billion of the securities. </p>
<p>Tiffany Galvin, a company spokeswoman, declined to comment. </p>
<p>Banks create structured notes by packaging debt with
derivatives to offer customized bets to retail investors while
earning fees and raising money. Derivatives are contracts whose
value is derived from stocks, bonds, commodities and currencies,
or events such as changes in interest rates or the weather. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David McLaughlin and Chris Dolmetsch" date="May 14, 2013 12:59 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-14/goldman-sachs-wins-dismissal-of-abacus-cdo-suit-on-appeal.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Wins Dismissal of Abacus CDO Suit on Appeal</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) won
dismissal of bond insurer ACA Financial Guaranty Corp.''s fraud
lawsuit over a collateralized debt obligation known as Abacus. </p>
<p>A New York state appeals court in Manhattan today ordered
the complaint against Goldman Sachs dismissed, overturning a
lower-court ruling that had allowed the case to proceed. </p>
<p>ACA claimed that New York-based Goldman Sachs and hedge-fund firm Paulson  Co. conspired to induce ACA to provide
financial guaranty insurance for the Abacus transaction and
deceived the insurer into believing Paulson was a long investor
when in fact it was taking a short position. </p>
<p>The appeals court said ACA could have uncovered Paulson''s
actual position, but apparently chose not to. </p>
<p>Plaintiff should have questioned defendant or the non-party hedge fund, the court said. Such an inquiry would have
likely informed plaintiff that the nonparty hedge fund was
taking a short rather than a long equity position. </p>
<p>ACA added New York-based Paulson as a defendant in the
lawsuit this year. A court has yet to rule on the hedge fund''s
motion to dismiss. </p>
<p>Marc Kasowitz, an attorney for New York-based ACA, said his
client may ask the divided appellate panel to reconsider the
decision and would pursue an appeal to the state''s highest court
in Albany. </p>
<h2>Two-Judge Dissent'' </h2>
<p>As the two-judge dissent makes clear, the three-judge
majority''s line of reasoning neither comports with the factual
record nor the law on this issue, Kasowitz said. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs in July 2010 won court approval of a
$550 million settlement with the U.S. Securities and Exchange
Commission over claims that it misled investors in the Abacus
CDO. Goldman Sachs failed to disclose Paulson''s role in
selecting underlying securities or that Paulson had taken a
short position against the CDO, according to the SEC. </p>
<p>The bank didn''t admit or deny wrongdoing in the SEC
settlement. It acknowledged that it made a mistake and that
marketing materials for the instruments had incomplete
information, the agency said at the time. </p>
<p>The case is ACA Financial Guaranty Corp. v. Goldman Sachs 
Co., 650027-2011, New York State Supreme Court (Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christine Harper" date="May 14, 2013 11:09 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-14/jpmorgan-markets-revenue-beating-year-ago-quarter-cavanagh-says.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Cavanagh Says Quarter''s Markets Revenue Is Rising</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s revenue from
its markets businesses, which include trading of bonds and
equities, is about 10 percent to 15 percent greater so far this
quarter than the year-earlier period, a senior executive said. </p>
<p>Michael Cavanagh, co-head of JPMorgan''s corporate and
investment bank, made the remark at a conference in New York
hosted by UBS AG (UBSN), according to a transcript. </p>
<p>Revenue from markets businesses are running about 10
percent to 15 percent higher than the second quarter of 2012,
he said. The revenue is still down a bit from the typically
strong first quarter that we just had. </p>
<p>Wall Street banks'' trading units usually generate their
greatest profits in the first quarter, in part because
corporations raise more debt at the beginning of the year,
stoking fixed-income operations. A jump in second-quarter
trading earnings from a year earlier would mark a turnaround for
JPMorgan after revenue from that business slipped 5.4 percent in
2013''s first three months. </p>
<p>JPMorgan, the largest U.S. bank by assets, rose 1.4 percent
to $50.38 at 11:08 a.m. in New York. The stock has climbed 15
percent so far this year, compared with a 16 percent advance in
the 24-company KBW Bank Index. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="May 14, 2013 10:06 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-14/morgan-stanley-shareholders-approve-pay-after-bonus-cut.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Shareholders Approve Pay After Bonus Cut</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) shareholders backed
the bank''s executive-compensation package after the board cut
Chief Executive Officer James Gorman''s pay by 7 percent and
deferred bonuses for top managers. </p>
<p>Investors voted about 86 percent in favor of the policy in
a non-binding resolution, down from about 95 percent last year,
according to a preliminary tally today at the company''s annual
meeting in Purchase, New York. They also elected the bank''s 14
board members, including new director Thomas Glocer, the former
CEO of Thomson Reuters Corp. (TRI) </p>
<p>Gorman''s compensation fell to $9.75 million for 2012, and
was 40 percent below target based on the firm''s performance, New
York-based Morgan Stanley said in a March filing. Total
shareholder return, including appreciation and dividends, was 28
percent in 2012, below the 36 percent median of the bank''s nine
largest peers, said the company, which owns the world''s biggest
brokerage. </p>
<p>Proxy advisory firm Glass Lewis  Co. recommended voting
against the plan, saying Morgan Stanley paid better than peers
while performing worse. ISS Proxy Services USA on April 30 said
Gorman''s pay cut was aligned with performance and advised voting
for the proposal. </p>
<p>Gorman, 54, got no cash bonus for 2012 and 38 percent of
his pay was tied to specific future performance measures, up
from 18 percent for 2011, Morgan Stanley said in the March
filing urging shareholders to vote for the plan. The firm''s
other named officers also got no cash bonus and had at least 34
percent of their pay tied to future performance. </p>
<p>Bloomberg LP, the parent company of Bloomberg News,
competes with Thomson Reuters in providing financial news and
information. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Stephanie Bodoni" date="May 14, 2013  7:33 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-14/visa-europe-offers-to-cap-credit-card-fees-to-settle-eu-probe.html"><headline>Visa Europe Offers to Cap Credit-Card Fees to End EU Probe</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Visa Europe Ltd. plans to
significantly reduce the fees it sets for processing cross-border credit-card payments in a bid to allay European Union
competition concerns, the bloc''s antitrust watchdog said. </p>
<p>Visa Europe''s offer would bring its fees in line with those
of its main competitor MasterCard Inc. (MA), the European Commission
said today. The operator of the EU''s largest payment-card
network also committed to overhaul its rules so that banks will
be able to apply a reduced cross-border interbank fee when they
compete for clients cross-border. </p>
<p>It will put at the same level the fees that are used by
MasterCard and by Visa and this will allow cheaper use of cards
that are a payment system used in almost half of our total
payments in the EU, Joaquin Almunia, the EU''s antitrust
commissioner, said in a video statement. Visa Europe''s offer
will mean the two big credit and debit card companies can''t
use their market position to have extra profits. </p>
<p>Visa Europe proposed to reduce by 40 percent to 60 percent
its so-called interbank fees for credit-card payments to a level
of 0.3 percent of the value of the transaction for cross-border
and domestic transactions, the commission said. The remedies
would last for four years. Visa Europe was sent a formal
complaint over the levies last year. </p>
<h2>Market Test </h2>
<p>Almunia said antitrust officials will carry out a so-called
market test with industry groups before deciding to make the
commitments legally binding. </p>
<p>Merchants will now be able to benefit from centralizing
their acquiring in one place, which will bring benefits to the
European economy as a whole, said Ruth Milligan, senior
adviser on payments at EuroCommerce, a group representing EU
retailers including Carrefour SA (CA) and Ikea Group. Acquiring banks
are those that process card payments on behalf of shops and
traders. </p>
<p>We have long argued that the card scheme''s rule on cross-border acquiring were wholly contrary to single market
principles and are delighted to see them go, said Milligan. </p>
<p>MasterCard in 2009 in a settlement with the Brussels-based EU regulator agreed to similar fee changes to avoid a
daily penalty of as much as 3.5 percent of sales. MasterCard is
appealing that decision at the EU courts in Luxembourg. Last
month, the EU said it is probing MasterCard''s bank fees on
foreign card payments such as when tourists go shopping in the
27-nation bloc. </p>
<h2>Inflate Costs </h2>
<p>Visa Europe''s so-called multilateral interchange fees
harm competition between acquiring banks, inflate the cost of
payment card acceptance for merchants and ultimately increase
consumer prices, the commission said today. </p>
<p>An earlier probe into Visa Europe''s fees for debit-card
payments made outside a user''s home country was settled in 2011.
The company split from Visa Inc. (V) before the U.S. card company''s
initial public offering in early 2008. </p>
<p>Today''s outcome is the result of constructive dialogue
between Visa Europe and the European Commission and is in line
with the level of 0.3 percent established in the industry,
Peter Ayliffe, Visa Europe''s chief executive officer, said in an
e-mailed statement. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bloomberg News" date="May 14, 2013 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-14/ibm-taps-china-s-engineers-to-develop-linux-software.html"><headline>IBM Taps China''s Engineers to Develop Linux Software</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines Corp. (IBM) opened a center today for computing systems in Beijing to help customers and outside software engineers develop business applications for the open-source Linux operating system. </p> <p>The facility will aid creation of programs for big data, cloud, mobile and social-business computing and represents a sizable investment, Colin Parris, general manager of IBM Power Systems, said in an interview. He declined to say how much the company spent or how many workers were employed. </p> <p>IBM Chief Executive Officer Ginni Rometty is focusing on profitable businesses including data analysis and cloud computing to maintain growth. She has said services that help customers mine troves of information to make better decisions are the company''s biggest priority. </p> <p>China is an environment in which you have some of the largest challenges, Parris said by phone from Beijing. If you solve those adequately in China, what you have is a capability to deliver that solution around the world. </p> <p>The Beijing center is the company''s first to focus on Linux applications for IBM''s Power Systems-brand servers, Parris said. The center will collaborate with Linux distributors Red Hat Inc. (RHT) and Attachmate Group''s SUSE, he said. </p>




Photographer: Sean Gallup/Getty Images

<p>
The new IBM facility will aid creation of programs for big data, loud, mobile and social-business computing and represents a izable investment, Colin Parris, general manager of IBM Power ystems, said in an interview. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Eliot Caroom" date="May 15, 2013  6:42 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-15/exxon-pegasus-pipeline-shutdown-kept-in-place-by-u-s-regulator.html"><headline>Exxon Pegasus Pipeline Shutdown Kept in Place by U.S. Regulator</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Restrictions on Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM)''s
Pegasus crude oil pipeline, shut since March 29 after a spill,
remain in place after the company requested changes in a hearing
held on May 2, according to a filing from federal regulators. </p>
<p>Exxon told the U.S. Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety
Administration that a 211-mile (340-kilometer) southern section
of the pipeline presented less risk because it was constructed
more recently than the northern leg that spilled about 5,000
barrels of oil near Mayflower, Arkansas. </p>
<p>The regulators pointed out at the hearing that the newer
section, built in 1954, and had a seam failure during a prior
hydrostatic test, according to a decision from Jeffrey Wiese,
associate administrator for pipeline safety. The corrective
action order preventing the line''s restart was kept in place,
with modifications to future limitations on pressure. </p>
<p>On April 30, Exxon found a second leak on Pegasus in
Doniphan, Missouri. The shutdown of the line, which delivers
about 96,000 barrels a day to Gulf Coast refineries from Patoka,
Illinois, helped back up oil supplies in the central U.S. Exxon
hasn''t provided a timeline for restarting Pegasus or filed a
plan with federal regulators to return it to service. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christie Smythe" date="May 15, 2013  3:35 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-15/visa-mastercard-swipe-deal-draws-little-rock-objection.html"><headline>Visa, MasterCard Swipe Deal Draws Little Rock Objection</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Little Rock, Arkansas, objected to a
multibillion-dollar settlement of a price-fixing case against
Visa Inc. (V) and MasterCard Inc. (MA) over the fees charged to merchants
to process credit-card transactions. </p>
<p>The settlement doesn''t address potential future fixing of
the so-called interchange or swipe fees and contains
unacceptable obligations, City Manager Bruce T. Moore said
in a filing today in federal court in Brooklyn, New York, where
the agreement is under review. </p>
<p>The proposed $7.25 billion settlement, estimated to be the
largest-ever U.S. antitrust accord, has drawn criticism from
trade associations and retailers, which contend that it grants
the card companies too much leeway to raise rates in the future. </p>
<p>Bentonville, Arkansas-based Wal-Mart Stores Inc. (WMT), the
world''s largest retailer, said in a statement in July that it
was disappointed in the settlement and would encourage
merchants to reject the deal. </p>
<p>Little Rock, the state capital and home to department-store
chain Dillard''s Inc. (DDS), said it was protesting the settlement in
its capacity as a potential member of a class that has accepted
Visa and MasterCard credit-card payments. </p>
<p>Separately, the city of Oakland, California, also filed an
objection to the settlement today. The city, which also accepts
credit-card payments, said the accord explicitly permits Visa
and MasterCard to continue to fix interchange fees for their
banks, forcing consumers to pay higher prices. </p>
<h2>Higher Prices </h2>
<p>Interchange fees on credit card transactions result in
higher prices for Oakland''s residents, and amount to a hidden
and regressive tax on goods and services, the city said in its
objection, filed by attorney Jeffrey Shinder, who is also
representing several trade associations that oppose the deal. </p>
<p>Hundreds of objections have been filed since U.S. District
Judge John Gleeson gave a preliminary sign-off to the deal in
November, including many from smaller retailers and merchants. </p>
<p>Large retailers including Target Corp. (TGT) and Home Depot Inc. (HD)
have also spoken out against the accord. </p>
<p>Last month, Gleeson ordered that corrections be made to
websites established by groups opposing the settlement,
including Merchantsobject.com, which directed business owners to
pages where they could submit objections electronically. The
judge said that the sites were misleading and failed to
prominently display a link to a court-approved website,
paymentcardsettlement.com. </p>
<h2>Consider Remedies </h2>
<p>At a follow-up hearing earlier this month, Gleeson said he
would consider remedies for merchants that dropped out of the
settlement, leaving them unable to receive payments for damages,
based on what he described as misleading information on the
sites. </p>
<p>The settlement was unveiled in July after about seven years
of litigation. A hearing on final approval of the deal, which
would cover merchants throughout the U.S., is scheduled for
Sept. 12. </p>
<p>The case is In re Payment Card Interchange Fee and Merchant
Discount Antitrust Litigation, 05-md-01720, U.S. District Court,
Eastern District of New York (Brooklyn). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sabrina Willmer" date="May 15, 2013 11:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-15/generali-said-to-seek-sale-of-private-equity-funds.html"><headline>Generali Said to Seek Sale of Private Equity Funds</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Assicurazioni Generali SpA (G), Italy''s
biggest insurer, is seeking to sell a portfolio of private-equity fund stakes valued at almost 500 million euros ($648.3
million), according to three people familiar with the matter. </p>
<p>Generali, based in Trieste, Italy, is talking to buyers
itself rather than using an agent, said the people, who asked
not to be identified because the process is private. Generali''s
portfolio is mostly made up of stakes funds that invest in
leveraged buyouts, according to the people. </p>
<p>Insurance companies and financial institutions have been
selling stakes in private-equity funds on the secondary market
as new regulations make it more costly to hold illiquid assets.
Generali sold about $400 million in private-equity fund stakes
in June to New York-based firm Lexington Partners Inc., said a
person familiar with the matter. </p>
<p>A Generali spokesman declined to comment. </p>
<p>Financial institutions including insurance companies made
up 24 percent of sellers in the secondary market last year and
29 percent of the transaction value, according to a report by
Cogent Partners, an advisory firm based in New York. In March,
French insurer AXA SA (CS) agreed to sell its private-equity unit AXA
Private Equity to senior management, AXA Group and outside
investors. French insurer Groupama SA agreed to sell Groupama
Private Equity to ACG Group in January as part of an effort to
get rid of assets that are not central to its business. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Amy Thomson" date="May 15, 2013 10:45 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-15/microsoft-predicts-eurovision-yup-you-heard-that-right-the-winner-will-be-denmark.html"><headline>Microsoft Predicts Eurovision (Yup, you heard that right). The Winner Will Be Denmark</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>To win Eurovision, the annual pan-European song contest that launched the careers of Abba and Celine Dion, you''ve got to have style, a killer song and enough charm to convince judges from rival countries to vote for you. For the 2013 finals, aired across the region this weekend, the odds are on Denmark, according to Microsoft.</p><p>What does a big tech company -- that''s a big tech company that didn''t invent iTunes, by the way (remember the Zune? Didn''t think so) -- know about a kitschy European songfest? Microsoft Research economist David Rothschild has a project called PredictWise that sifts through zillions of data points scooped up from the Internet to predict outcomes of various public events like Eurovision, the Academy Awards, and elections.</p><p>PredictWise used its "big data" aggregation to correctly predict the U.S. Presidential election results for every state except Florida. And it got 19 out of 24 categories correct in the 2013 Oscars.</p><p>Its Eurovision predictions take odds from gambling sites such as PaddyPower and Betfair, as well as Youtube views and mentions in social media, Rothschild says. Those, he said on his blog, are predictors of the votes of judges drawn from the dozens of countries competing.</p><p>This method works "particularly well for Eurovision, firstly, because the markets are extremely robust, and secondly, because the collective wisdom of the users includes the unique politics of the Eurovision voting blocs," Rothschild wrote on his blog. "This means that an American like me -- with detailed knowledge of markets, but little  knowledge of Eurovision -- can make meaningful predictions."</p><p>His prediction, as of the time this blog was published: Denmark''s Emmelie de Forest, singing "Only Teardrops," has a 50 percent chance of winning. Norway and Ukraine are next with 9.8 percent and 8.4 percent odds respectively. The odds are sure to keep changing until Saturday, when some 125 million viewers will tune in for the Eurovision finals in Malmo, Sweden. </p><p>Last year, Sweden won in Baku, Azerbaijan, with "Euphoria" by Loreen, followed by a gang of Russian grandmothers called Buranovskiye Babushki, who got a standing ovation for the dance song, "Party for Everybody."</p><p>Great Britain has just a 0.9 percent chance of finishing first, according to Rothschild''s data. That won''t sit well with Britons, who grumble that without a win since 1997 ("Love Shine a Light," by Katrina and the Waves), the contest must be rigged against them.</p><p>To end the drought, the country is putting forward Bonnie Tyler, a veteran Welsh hitmaker who topped the charts with "It''s a Heartache," "Total Eclipse of the Heart" and "Holding Out for a Hero" in the ''70s and ''80s. She''ll ask viewers -- and more important, judges -- to "believe in things that your eyes can''t see" with her song "Believe in Me." </p><p>If they don''t? Well, let''s just say the Brits will always have the Beatles.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By John Glover" date="May 15, 2013 10:19 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-15/jpmorgan-asset-plans-u-k-s-first-convertible-investment-trust.html"><headline>JPMorgan Asset Plans U.K.''s First Convertible Investment Trust</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Asset Management, the money
management unit of the biggest U.S. bank by assets, said it''s
starting the U.K.''s first investment trust dedicated to global
convertible bonds. </p>
<p>The JPMorgan Global Convertibles Income Fund will be set up
as a closed-end fund, which has a fixed number of shares,
targeting a 4.5 percent yield through dividend income and
capital growth, according to Antony Vallee, the unit''s London-based head of convertible bonds. The closed-end structure will
add flexibility to the investment strategy by avoiding the need
to hold cash and the most liquid securities to meet potential
withdrawals, he said. </p>
<p>Convertible debt combines a bond with an option to buy a
preset amount of stock, allowing lenders to share in gains from
the growth or revival of borrowers while offering the same
protection of capital as a traditional bond. New issuance, which
soared to more than $10 billion in the first quarter, a record
for the period in Europe, stalled in recent weeks as improving
economic indicators in some regions encourage chief financial
officers and other managers to view their stock as undervalued. </p>
<p>Few CFOs in the world are happy to issue convertibles
because of the dilution, Vallee said at a  presentation
today. Right now they''re looking at the U.S. and Japan and
expecting that equities will go up. When companies need some
money they will come back. </p>
<p>The new fund plans to raise at least 100 million pounds
($152 million) and its size is capped at 300 million pounds. The
directors plan to prevent its value falling to a discount of
more than 5 percent to net asset value by buying back stock
where necessary. </p>
<p>The shares of the investment trust are expected to start
trading by the middle of next month, according to the term
sheet. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kit Chellel and Nicholas Dunbar" date="May 15, 2013 10:17 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-15/jpmorgan-sues-portugal-owned-companies-to-enforce-metro-swaps.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sues Portugal-Owned Companies to Enforce Swaps</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) sued state-owned
Portuguese companies running the Lisbon and Oporto metro rail
services, as well as the country''s strategic oil reserves, to
enforce derivative contracts worth at least 455 million euros
($587 million). </p>
<p>JPMorgan filed the lawsuits in London on April 26, the same
day Portugal made a deal with other banks to reduce its 3
billion-euro exposure to derivatives entered into by state-owned
firms. The government failed to reach an agreement with JPMorgan
and Banco Santander SA''s Portuguese unit, and said it would sue
to defend its interests. </p>
<p>We were forced to take protective measures in the English
courts following the April announcement by Portugal, JPMorgan
spokesman Brian Marchiony said in an e-mail. The New York-based
bank remains open to negotiations and the contracts aren''t in
default, he said. </p>
<p>Banks are turning to U.K. courts to resolve swaps disputes
with local governments and state-owned companies that say they
lost money on complex derivatives. More than half a dozen
Italian municipalities are embroiled in legal disputes with
investment banks in London. </p>
<p>Maria Luis Albuquerque, Portugal''s secretary of state for
treasury and finance, described the country''s hedging contracts
as toxic with elevated risks, when she announced the
April deal. An official at Portugal''s finance ministry declined
to comment. </p>
<h2>Santander Suits </h2>
<p>Santander''s Portugal-based unit also sued the Oporto and
Lisbon metro and bus companies in London on May 10. Peter
Greiff, a Santander spokesman in Madrid, didn''t immediately
return a phone call seeking comment. </p>
<p>Metropolitano de Lisboa had at least 455 million euros of
swap contracts with the JPMorgan at the end of 2011, as measured
by notional value, according to the company''s annual report. The
disclosed JPMorgan contracts had a negative value of 221 million
euros, Metropolitano de Lisboa said. </p>
<p>JPMorgan''s Marchiony said in an e-mailed statement the
figures weren''t accurate and declined to comment further. A
Metro de Lisboa spokesman declined to comment beyond the
company''s filings. </p>
<p>Metro Porto had 120 million euros of outstanding loans with
JPMorgan at the end of 2011 according to its annual report,
which didn''t disclose details of derivatives held with the bank.
The Strategic Oil Reserve Fund didn''t disclose details of its
derivative counterparties. </p>
<p>The cases are: JP Morgan Securities PLC v. Metropolitano de
Lisboa EP, High Court of Justice, Queen''s Bench Division,
Commercial Court, 13-607; JP Morgan Chase Bank NA v. Entidade
Gestora De Reservas Estrategicas De Produtos, High Court of
Justice, Queen''s Bench Division, Commercial Court, 13-606; and
JP Morgan Chase Bank NA  Anr v. Metro Do Porto SA, High Court
of Justice, Queen''s Bench Division, Commercial Court, 13-603. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bloomberg News" date="May 15, 2013  2:44 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-15/jpmorgan-sees-yuan-band-widening-within-3-months-after-safe-rule.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sees Yuan Band Widening in 3 Months After SAFE Rule</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. said China may
widen the yuan''s trading band in the next three months after the
foreign-exchange regulator announced rules to deter speculative
funds from betting on appreciation. </p>
<p>The State Administration of Foreign Exchange said May 5 it
would put in measures to increase monitoring of cross-border
trade flows and ordered banks to adjust currency positions so
that dollar loans are kept at a certain proportion to deposits.
Patrick Wu, head of yuan trading at JPMorgan, the largest U.S.
bank by assets, said the move may be part of preparations to
broaden the band. </p>
<p>If SAFE widened the band without the new measure, it
would trigger more speculation, Wu said in an interview
yesterday in Shanghai. However, if they introduce the measure,
it would be more helpful to push down the yuan''s spot level and
give SAFE more room to widen the band because corporates and
banks will have to reduce short-dollar positions. </p>
<p>The government has pledged to allow more flexibility in the
exchange rate and promote freer movement of capital in and out
of the country for investment purposes. China''s State Council,
or cabinet, signaled May 6 it will propose plans this year for
yuan capital-account convertibility. The central bank last
widened the band in April 2012, to 1 percent from 0.5 percent. </p>
<h2>Yuan Outlook </h2>
<p>The People''s Bank of China sets a daily reference rate
against the dollar around 9:15 a.m. in Shanghai. The yuan has
been within 0.1 percent of the upper limit on most days since
October. The fixing was weakened 0.06 percent to 6.2070 today.
Wu said the reference rate may strengthen to 6.10 by year-end. </p>
<p>There will be fewer speculative foreign-exchange trades
in the onshore market because banks have limitations in making
loans for corporates to go long on the yuan and short on
dollars, said Wu. The whole outlook for the yuan still
remains unchanged. </p>
<p>The yuan weakened 0.06 percent to 6.1462 per dollar as of
2:22 p.m. in Shanghai, according to the China Foreign Exchange
Trade System. It touched 6.1307 on May 9, the strongest level
since the government unified official and market exchange rates
at the end of 1993. A long position is a bet that a currency
will appreciate while a short position anticipates a decline. </p>
<p>China''s currency has appreciated 1.5 percent in the last
three months, the third-best performance among 24 emerging-market currencies tracked by Bloomberg after the Mexican peso
and Malaysia''s ringgit. </p>
<h2>Around June </h2>
<p>Widening of the band is likely in June or shortly after,
Credit Agricole CIB strategist Dariusz Kowalczyk wrote in a
research note on May 7. With the new foreign-exchange position
limits for banks, policy makers were likely trying to reduce
speculative capital and prepare ground for foreign-exchange
regime relaxation, Hong Kong-based Kowalczyk said. </p>
<p>The band may be expanded around June, before the U.S.-China
Strategic Economic Dialogue in Washington during the week of
July 8-12, Bank of America Merrill Lynch strategist Christy Tan
in Singapore wrote in a report on April 24. The PBOC may widen
the band against the dollar to 1.5 percent or 2 percent, while
1.5 percent is more likely, Tan said. </p>
<p>China is testing the yuan''s exchange-rate equilibrium and
may soon double its trading band, Shanghai Securities News
reported May 13, citing people it didn''t identify. </p>
<p>A widening is likely in the near future, People''s Bank
of China Deputy Governor Yi Gang said in April. China will push
ahead with opening its capital account because current economic
conditions are favorable, Yi said. </p>
<p>One-year implied volatility in the onshore yuan, a measure
of exchange-rate swings used to price options, rose nine basis
points, or 0.09 percentage point, to 2.43 percent, according to
data compiled by Bloomberg. That''s the highest since Jan. 15. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="May 15, 2013 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-15/morgan-stanley-share-target-lifted-by-mayo-on-ceo-s-plan.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Share Target Lifted by Mayo on CEO''s Plan</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Michael Mayo, an analyst at CLSA
Ltd., raised his share-price estimate on Morgan Stanley to $36
after Chief Executive Officer James Gorman said the firm may
reach his profitability target next year. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley shares can rally almost 50 percent, Mayo
said yesterday in a note to investors, raising the price
estimate from $30. Reaching Gorman''s target of 10 percent return
on equity implies earnings per share of $3 for 2014, higher than
the average estimate of $2.50, Mayo wrote. </p>
<p>Gorman, 54, laid out a plan in January to double return on
equity, a measure of how well the New York-based firm reinvests
earnings, from 5 percent in 2012, without assigning a date to
the goal. He said at yesterday''s annual shareholder meeting, in
response to a question from Mayo, that the target can be reached
next year if regulators allow Morgan Stanley (MS) to return
reasonable amounts of capital to shareholders through
buybacks and dividends. </p>
<p>The new explicit time frame for consolidated ROE allows
investors to keep the pressure on, Mayo wrote. Gorman and
Morgan Stanley board members Robert Kidder and Erskine Bowles
were on the same page about the importance of ROE at the
meeting, Mayo said. </p>
<p>Mayo raised his Morgan Stanley rating on July 19 to
outperform, after having it at underperform for at least three
years, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. He upgraded the
firm to buy in September and maintained that rating yesterday. </p>
<p>The shares, which climbed 2.5 percent to $24.27 yesterday
in New York, have advanced 83 percent since July 19. </p>
<p>Gorman''s plan to boost ROE involves cutting $1.6 billion of
costs in the next two years, reducing capital used by the firm''s
fixed-income trading business and boosting the pretax margin at
the wealth-management division. </p>
<p>We''re now in a position where we have excess capital;
however, returning that to shareholders is dependent upon our
regulators granting that desire to return it, Gorman said
yesterday. But we expect, with reasonable capital returns,
that we will deliver those goals in 2014. That''s been our
expectation. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Laurence Arnold" date="May 16, 2013  7:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-16/walter-o-brien-bb-t-equities-chief-who-mentored-dies-at-46-1-.html"><headline>Walter O''Brien, BB&amp;amp;T Equities Chief Who Was Mentor, Dies at 46</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walter J. O''Brien III, head of equity sales and trading at BBT Corp. (BBT) and a mentor to finance-minded graduates of his alma mater, the University of Richmond in Virginia, has died. He was 46. </p> <p>He died on May 10 at his home in Richmond, his wife, Debra, said yesterday in an interview. The cause was colon cancer, which was diagnosed in February 2012. </p> <p>Known as Joe, O''Brien held jobs on Wall Street at Smith Barney and Citicorp Inc. before joining Scott  Stringfellow Inc., a regional brokerage, investment banking and financial services firm in Richmond that billed itself as the U.S. South''s oldest continuous member of the New York Stock Exchange. BBT, North Carolina''s second-biggest bank after Bank of America Corp., bought Scott  Stringfellow in 1999. </p> <p>BBT, based in Winston-Salem, promoted O''Brien to senior vice president of capital markets in 2002. He rose to managing director. </p> <p>A member of the Executive Advisory Council of the University of Richmond''s Robins School of Business, O''Brien took many students under his wing, according to an article in the university''s alumni magazine. </p> <p>It told of an MBA candidate, Grant Garcia, who drove to BBT''s offices in downtown Richmond, sometimes before dawn, to sit at O''Brien''s desk learning the markets, a relationship they continued for almost two years. </p> <h2>Leg Up'' </h2> <p>Garcia, 29, now works in securitized product sales at Credit Suisse Securities in New York. He said yesterday in an interview that his unpaid experience with O''Brien was valuable and gave him a leg up in a tough job market. When Garcia graduated from Robins in 2009, he landed a job at Bank of America''s Merrill Lynch brokerage unit, then moved to the U.S. unit of Zurich-based Credit Suisse Group AG. </p> <p>He really changed my life, Garcia said. He gave me the foundation during a really hard period of time in the economy. His door was always open. Every time he came to New York we''d go out for a drink or for dinner. </p> <p>In an e-mail to the Robins community, Dean Nancy A. Bagranoff wrote, Joe showed great courage as he dealt with his illness. He will be much missed by us all. </p> <p>Walter Joseph O''Brien III was born on Nov. 26, 1966, in London to Nancy Malmuth and Walter J. O''Brien Jr. He was raised in Chicago and New York. His father was president of J. Walter Thompson, then the world''s largest advertising agency, and later ran two other firms, according to a biography for a Richmond non-profit group where he serves on the board. </p> <p>In 1985, the son graduated from the Hotchkiss School in Lakeville, Connecticut, and in 1989 earned an economics degree from Richmond. </p> <p>O''Brien was a senior vice president at Citicorp when he left New York for Scott  Stringfellow. </p> <p>Survivors include his wife, Debra, a graduate of New York University''s Stern School of Business and adjunct associate professor of information systems at Richmond; a son, Connor, 13; a daughter, Caitlin, 10; his parents and stepmother, Margaret O''Brien. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Cliff Edwards" date="May 16, 2013  6:38 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-16/microsoft-tops-u-s-retail-game-console-sales-with-xbox.html"><headline>Microsoft Tops U.S. Retail Game Console Sales With Xbox</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) said U.S. retailers
sold 130,000 Xbox 360 game consoles in April, helping it retain
the top-selling spot for the 28th straight month. </p>
<p>April spending on all Xbox products, including the console,
Kinect motion-sensing peripheral and software, totaled $208
million, Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft said today in an e-mail, citing NPD Group Inc. data. Microsoft sold 236,000
consoles a year ago. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Brian Louis" date="May 16, 2013  5:40 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-16/general-growth-sells-stake-in-las-vegas-shopping-mall.html"><headline>General Growth Sells Stake in Las Vegas Shopping Mall</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>General Growth Properties Inc. (GGP) sold
half its interest in the Grand Canal Shoppes, including the
Shoppes at the Palazzo, in Las Vegas for net proceeds of $410
million as part of a new joint venture with TIAA-CREF. </p>
<p>The 774,000-square-foot (72,000-square-meter) mall in the
Venetian and the Palazzo hotel-and-casino complex on the Las
Vegas Strip is 99 percent leased, the partners said today in a
statement. General Growth, based in Chicago, said it will
continue to handle management and leasing of the property, which
generates more than $1,000 of sales per square foot. </p>
<p>The investment boosts New York-based TIAA-CREF''s real
estate holdings as demand for luxury-mall space climbs. At
regional centers, which typically include department stores,
vacancies fell to 8.3 percent in the first quarter from 9
percent a year earlier, and rents rose to $39.46 a square foot
from $39, research firm Reis Inc. (REIS) said on April 4. </p>
<p>Tenants at Grand Canal include Sephora, Swarovski, Banana
Republic, Kenneth Cole, Godiva Chocolatier and the Art of
Shaving, according to General Growth''s website. </p>
<p>TIAA-CREF, the provider of retirement accounts for teachers
and non-profit organizations, had $520 billion of assets under
management as of the end of March, according to the statement.
General Growth is the biggest U.S. mall owner after
Indianapolis-based Simon Property Group Inc. (SPG) </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Martin" date="May 16, 2013  4:26 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-16/goldman-sachs-to-finance-500-million-in-solarcity-roofs.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs to Finance $500 Million for SolarCity Roofs</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> SolarCity Corp. (SCTY), a solar-energy
developer chaired by billionaire Elon Musk, won financing from
Goldman Sachs (GS) Group Inc. for more than $500 million in rooftop
solar systems that the company will complete this year. </p>
<p>The lease-financing agreement will help SolarCity build
about 110 megawatts of solar power systems with little or no up-front cost for homeowners and businesses, San Mateo, California-based SolarCity said today in a statement. </p>
<p>The deal is the largest single financing agreement for
rooftop systems in the U.S. and will raise awareness of the
quality of the solar-lease asset class, SolarCity Chief
Executive Officer Lyndon Rive said in a telephone interview. </p>
<p>We hope it sends a signal that solar is a stable and
reliable asset to invest in, Rive said in an interview.
These aren''t luxury yachts we''re talking about, it''s your
energy, and the default rates are lower than mortgages. </p>
<p>During the first quarter, SolarCity said it invested $138.2
million in solar systems as demand for rooftop panels from
homeowners and businesses surged. </p>
<p>For New York-based Goldman Sachs, the SolarCity agreement
will help reach the Wall Street bank''s goal of financing $40
billion in renewable energy during the next decade, said Stuart Bernstein, global head of clean technology. </p>
<p>SolarCity''s range of distributed solar solutions
targeting a wider customer base will help us move toward a low
carbon energy future, Bernstein said in the statement. </p>
<p>The financing agreement also allows SolarCity to extend
credit to homeowners with lower credit scores, Rive said. </p>
<p>When we started you needed a FICO score of 720 or
higher, Rive said. Now it''s more like 680 and I suspect in
the near term we''ll be at 650. </p>
<p>SolarCity climbed 11 percent to $35.69 at the close in New
York. The shares have quadrupled since the initial offering in
December. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christie Smythe" date="May 16, 2013  2:45 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-16/morgan-stanley-sued-over-retirement-plan-deal-with-ing.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Sued Over Retirement Plan Deal With ING</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) was sued by a
Birmingham, Alabama, medical center over claims the bank
received improper payments from ING Life Insurance and Annuity
Co. in exchange for referral of retirement-investment business. </p>
<p>The bank placed retirement plans with so-called alliance
partners, including ING, and received additional compensation
from them based on the assets invested, according to the suit
filed today in federal court in Manhattan. The compensation
amounted to a pay-to-play fee, prohibited by U.S. law,
according to the suit brought by Skin Pathology Associates Inc. </p>
<p>The alliance partner program is structured to take
advantage of a conflict of interest Morgan Stanley has
created, the skin-testing center said in the complaint. </p>
<p>The Skin Pathology alleged it hired New York-based Morgan
Stanley, the sixth-largest institutional broker in the U.S., as
a broker for the retirement plan that was placed with ING. The
center is seeking damages on behalf itself and other companies
subject to Morgan Stanley''s alliance partner program. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley spokesman Akhilesh Raina declined to comment
on the lawsuit. Dana Ripley, a spokesman for ING, said he
couldn''t immediately comment. </p>
<p>The case is Skin Pathology Associates Inc. v. Morgan Stanley
 Co., 13-cv-3299, U.S. District Court, Southern District of New
York (Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Pablo Gonzalez" date="May 16, 2013  1:50 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-16/chevron-says-shale-to-help-make-argentina-energy-independent-2-.html"><headline>Chevron Says Shale to Help Make Argentina Energy Independent</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX), the second-biggest
U.S. oil company, said it''s preparing an investment that will
help make the country energy independent by developing what
could be the world''s second-largest shale oil reservoir. </p>
<p>Some people think China is the second-largest shale
oil, Ali Moshiri, Chevron''s head of Latin America, Middle East
and Africa, told reporters yesterday in Buenos Aires. I
believe after the U.S., Vaca Muerta holds the largest shale oil
in terms of reserves, he said, referring to a formation in
southwestern Argentina that translates to Dead Cow. </p>
<p>Moshiri spoke along with Miguel Galuccio, chief executive
of state-owned YPF SA, after signing a contract establishing
terms for a definitive agreement that will start with a $1.5
billion investment and may reach as much as $15 billion. The San
Ramon, California-based company first agreed to the partnership
in December. </p>
<p>Now it is the time for finalizing details as there are no
significant commercial issues between the two companies,
Moshiri said. </p>
<p>Both executives declined to provide details of production
targets and capital expenditures. The final accord may be
completed as early as July as two teams of six members each are
writing the fiscal terms and other covenants, they said. </p>
<p>YPF gained 1.7 percent to 121 pesos at 2:45 p.m. in Buenos
Aires. The stock earlier rose as much as 8.3 percent to 128.90.
Chevron added 0.07 percent to $123.09 in New York. </p>
<h2>Frozen Assets </h2>
<p>Once we sign the deal, we will immediately allocate a
large sum of money to take the investment to the next level,
Moshiri said. We are going to provide whatever YPF asks to
reach the target. </p>
<p>Moshiri said Chevron is spending $150 million a year even
while an embargo linked to an Ecuadorean lawsuit froze 40
percent of its accounts in Argentina. The lawsuit against
Chevron stems from a $19 billion award for pollution in Ecuador. </p>
<p>Chevron will continue reinvesting all the money it makes
in Argentina, Moshiri said, declining to elaborate how the
company will avoid having its funds seized. At the end of the
day the right decision will be made by the people in Argentina,
the government and the judiciary system. </p>
<p>Argentine President Cristina Fernandez de Kirchner''s
government seized a 51 percent YPF stake from Spain''s Repsol SA (REP)
in April 2012 to stem fuel imports that doubled to $9.4 billion
in 2011 and are expected to rise to as much as $15 billion this
year. </p>
<h2>Repsol Lawsuit </h2>
<p>Another legal dispute threatening the agreement is a suit
filed in November in Madrid by Repsol against the U.S. company.
The Repsol lawsuit is an issue between shareholders, Galuccio
said. There is a lot of goodwill from both sides to reach an
agreement, nevertheless, as YPF CEO I couldn''t comment
further, he said. </p>
<p>Repsol is open to a negotiation that includes liquid
assets as compensation, Kristian Rix, a spokesman for the
Madrid-based company, said today by telephone from Madrid. </p>
<p>Galuccio and Moshiri said they would only discuss the
future of Vaca Muerta now that YPF has cut well costs in half to
$7.5 million apiece. On May 14, the two executives visited YPF''s
shale operations, which has 35 operating rigs and is expecting
to receive four more this week. </p>
<p>YPF said it''s pumping 7,000 barrels of oil a day, up from
4,000 in January. Vaca Muerta may hold at least 23 billion
barrels of oil equivalent, according to a report by independent
auditor Ryder Scott released in February 2012 by YPF. Argentina
holds the world''s third-largest shale gas reserves, according to
U.S. Energy Information Administration data. </p>
<p>If you look at Vaca Muerta in the future, in 30, 40
years, you will be looking at a factory drilling operation,
Galuccio said. We are working on industrializing the process
as that will be the key for Argentina to develop those resources
we have on the ground. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David Welch" date="May 16, 2013  1:22 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-16/jpmorgan-names-cristerna-ventresca-as-global-m-a-co-heads.html"><headline>JPMorgan Names Ventresca, Cristerna as Global M&amp;amp;A Co-Heads</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co., the largest
U.S. bank by assets, named Chris Ventresca and Hernan Cristerna
as co-heads of global mergers and acquisitions. </p>
<p>Ventresca, 46, previously was JPMorgan''s head of North
American MA, while Cristerna, 48, oversaw MA for Europe,
Middle East and Africa, according to a memo obtained today by
Bloomberg News. They will report to Jeff Urwin, global head of
investment banking. Tasha Pelio, a spokeswoman for New York-based JPMorgan, confirmed the memo''s contents. </p>
<p>JPMorgan, led by Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon, is
overhauling top management on its MA team. Ventresca and
Cristerna will have global responsibilities, with each
overseeing their former regions, Pelio said. They will share
responsibility for deals in Asia, she said. </p>
<p>Combining global MA under two leaders streamlines the
bank''s decision-making, Ventresca said in a phone interview. </p>
<p>We can move more quickly with common leadership,
Ventresca said. When an opportunity arises, we can put the
right advisory resources in place. </p>
<p>Until February, Ventresca shared oversight of North
American MA with Jim Woolery, 44, who left the company that
month to become deputy chairman at corporate law firm Cadwalader
Wickersham  Taft LLP. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
Pedestrians pass in front of the JP Morgan Chase  Co. headquarters in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jeremy Hodges" date="May 16, 2013  5:09 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-16/goldman-sachs-tax-deal-didn-t-break-u-k-law-judge-rules.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Tax Deal Didn''t Break U.K. Law, Judge Rules</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)''s deal with
the U.K. government that may have saved the investment bank as
much as 20 million pounds ($30.6 million) on its taxes didn''t
break any laws, a judge ruled. </p>
<p>Her Majesty''s Revenue  Customs''s decision to reduce the
New York-based bank''s tax bill was properly conducted, a judge
in London ruled today. Still, Judge Andrew Nicol criticized tax
officials who considered the potential embarrassment to
Chancellor of the Exchequer George Osborne if a deal with
Goldman Sachs wasn''t completed. </p>
<p>The settlement with Goldman Sachs was not a glorious
episode in the history of the Revenue, Nicol said in his
written ruling. </p>
<p>The U.K. government has pledged to clamp down on tax-avoidance schemes following widespread media and public anger
caused by the amount of corporation tax the likes of Google
Inc., Starbucks Corp. (SBUX) and Amazon.com Inc. pay in the country.
Lawmakers said in a report last month that increased
transparency about companies'' tax affairs would build pressure
on multinational businesses to pay a fair share. </p>
<p>UK Uncut Legal Action, an advocacy group that lobbies for
alternatives to government spending cuts, said HMRC reached the
agreement with Goldman Sachs on the day Osborne announced a
bankers'' code to counter tax avoidance. An HMRC executive said
in an e-mail cited by UK Uncut that he was concerned the bank
might drop out of the code if the deal was scuttled. </p>




Photographer: Jason Alden/Bloomberg

<p>
Pedestrians pass the main entrance to the Goldman Sachs offices in London. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jun Yang" date="May 16, 2013  1:39 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-16/jpmorgan-leads-surge-in-indonesia-tied-note-sales-to-3-year-high.html"><headline>JPMorgan Leads Surge in Indonesia-Tied Note Sales to 3-Year High</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Issuance of structured notes tied to
Indonesia''s sovereign debt surged to the most in three years,
led by JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), as investors seek to capitalize on
the second-highest yields among major Asian economies. </p>
<p>Sales of notes linked to Indonesian government bonds jumped
to the equivalent of $519.7 million this year through May 14, 89
percent higher than the same period of 2012, according to data
compiled by Bloomberg. The volume is the highest since 2010 and
90 percent of the products were issued by JPMorgan, which rose
to No. 1 after being ranked eighth last year, the data show. </p>
<p>Overseas investors pumped a net 18 trillion rupiah ($1.8
billion) into local-currency sovereign notes in April, pushing
holdings to a record 299 trillion rupiah, according to the
finance ministry data. The country''s 10-year bonds yielded 5.55
percent yesterday, the highest behind Indian debt among 14 Asia-Pacific countries tracked by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>For foreign investors, Indonesia offers high yield, but
the risk is controllable, said Nurul Eti Nurbaeti, head of
treasury research at PT Bank Negara Indonesia in Jakarta. </p>
<p>JPMorgan on May 6 issued the largest notes tied to
Indonesia this year in a 1.93 trillion rupiah offering. The 20-year securities, issued at a 4.4 percent premium, both pay a
6.625 percent annual coupon and are redeemed in U.S. dollars.
The U.S. currency gained against the rupiah for two consecutive
years through 2012. </p>
<h2>Long-Term Investments </h2>
<p>Polly Leung, a spokeswoman at JPMorgan in Hong Kong,
declined to comment on the notes. Standard Chartered Plc (STAN) and
Deutsche Bank AG (DBK) have also issued the securities this year,
according to Bloomberg data. </p>
<p>More than two-thirds of the products sold this year have
maturities of 10 years or longer, Bloomberg data show. Such
tenors are popular among pension funds and other foreign
institutional buyers, as they tend to seek long-term
investments, Nurbaeti said. </p>
<p>Indonesia on May 14 kept interest rates unchanged for a
15th consecutive time as predicted. The central bank won''t
resist raising rates if needed, Assistant Governor Hendar said
May 8. </p>
<p>Standard  Poor''s cut its rating outlook on Indonesia''s
debt to stable from positive this month, citing slow progress in
improving infrastructure, regulatory uncertainty and
bureaucratic obstacles. The agency ranks the country at its
highest junk level, while Fitch Ratings Ltd. and Moody''s
Investors Service restored Indonesia to investment grades in
December 2011 and January 2012. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Prashant Gopal and Jef Feeley" date="May 17, 2013  4:31 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-17/morgans-surges-after-disclosure-of-spurned-takeover-offer.html"><headline>Morgans Surges After Disclosure of Spurned Takeover Offer</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgans Hotel Group Co. (MHGC) said it
received a $7.50-a-share takeover offer from a large
international hotel company late last year that it rejected as
too low. The stock rose to the highest in a year and half. </p>
<p>Yucaipa Cos., which has a stake in Morgans through
preferred shares and stock warrants, said in a regulatory filing
earlier today the New York-based hotelier should disclose an
offer it received. Morgans, in a statement after the filing,
said the $7.50 bid was turned down because the price was not
sufficiently attractive. Lex Suvanto, a spokesman for Morgans
at Abernathy MacGregor Group, wouldn''t name the company that
made the offer. </p>
<p>The Morgans board responded that it was not interested at
the proposed price, but that it might entertain a proposal at a
significantly higher price, the company said in its statement.
A similar proposal was received by the company from the same
party at the same price in February 2013 and the company''s
position on the proposal was unchanged. </p>
<p>Morgans Hotel shares rose 13 percent to $6.97 at the close
in New York. It was the stock''s biggest gain and highest price
since October 2011. </p>
<p>A Delaware Chancery Court judge ruled on May 14 that
Morgans can''t sell two of its businesses to billionaire Ron Burkle''s Yucaipa and begin a $100 million recapitalization plan
because directors didn''t properly approve the actions. </p>
<p>Jason Taubman Kalisman, a company director and founding
member of its largest common-stock holder, OTK Associates LLC,
sued his fellow board members last month over their decision to
back the Yucaipa deal. </p>
<h2>Proxy Fight </h2>
<p>OTK opened a proxy fight this year, saying it''s seeking to
overhaul Morgans''s board and return the company to
profitability. The chain, which includes 13 boutique hotels, has
lost money in every quarter since 2007, according to data
compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Kalisman and OTK officials contend Morgans executives
sought to ram through a deal with Burkle calling for the
billionaire to swap his $230 million investment in the chain''s
notes and preferred shares for Morgans''s Delano South Beach
Hotel in Miami and a restaurant company. Burkle also would
retire warrants and assume an $18 million promissory note as
part of the deal. </p>
<p>Burkle also agreed to backstop the $100 million rights
offering without charging a fee as part of the acquisition.
Burkle, who serves on the the Morgans board, could end up with
32 percent of the company''s shares should no other investors
participate in the offering. </p>
<h2>Deal Barred </h2>
<p>Three days ago, Judge Travis Laster barred the deal and the
recapitalization from proceeding because Morgans''s directors
didn''t properly approve them. Company officials said directors
will reconsider the transactions. The board also faces a proxy
vote at the company''s June 14 meeting. </p>
<p>During a hearing on Kalisman''s challenge to the deals, the
dissident director''s lawyers cited the board''s rejection of the
$7.50-a-share bid as evidence it improperly favored Burkle''s
acquisition offer for the hotel and food-and-beverage company. </p>
<p>In its filing today, Yucaipa said it would honor the
agreement to buy the businesses, and urged Morgans to invite OTK
officials to help backstop the rights offering. Yucaipa also
said it wouldn''t object should Morgans cut the recapitalization
to $75 million. </p>
<p>The Morgans chain features boutique hotels such as the
Mondrian SoHo in New York, the Clift Hotel in San Francisco and
the Delano Marrakech in Morocco. </p>
<p>The case is Kalisman v. Friedman, 8447, Delaware Chancery
Court (Wilmington). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri" date="May 17, 2013 12:31 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-17/disney-s-iron-man-3-tops-1-billion-worldwide.html"><headline>Disney''s Iron Man 3'' Tops $1 Billion Worldwide</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney''s Co.''s super-hero movie
Iron Man 3 passed $1 billion in worldwide ticket sales, the
company said today in an e-mailed statement. </p>
<p>The film from Disney''s Marvel unit had grossed $302 million
domestically through yesterday, its 14th day of release, and
$699 million overseas in 23 days of showings, the company said.
The biggest international market was China with $104 million
in sales. </p>
<p>Disney, the world''s largest entertainment company, has cut
back on the number of films it releases to focus on ones with
global appeal and the potential to be parlayed into other
businesses. This week the Burbank, California-based firm
announced that a Marvel''s Agents of S.H.I.E.L.D. television
show, based on its comic book characters, would debut on the
company''s ABC network. </p>
<p>Disney shares fell less than 1 percent to $65.96 at 12:14
p.m. in New York. The stock is up 34 percent this year through
yesterday, while the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index has added 16
percent. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass and Cliff Edwards" date="May 20, 2013  4:55 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-20/microsoft-updates-xbox-as-apple-to-facebook-gain-in-games.html"><headline>Microsoft Updates Xbox as Apple to Facebook Gain in Games</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp (MSFT) (MSFT). is revamping the Xbox to fend off a breed of competitors ranging from Apple Inc (AAPL) (AAPL). to Facebook Inc. (FB) Those companies were nowhere in gaming when the software maker debuted its last version five years ago. </p> <p>Now these newcomers -- along with the likes of Google Inc. (GOOG) and Amazon.com Inc. (AMZN) -- are posing a threat by introducing their own software and devices that let consumers access an array of games and entertainment on smartphones, computers and home electronics. </p> <p>Where once Microsoft''s Xbox had only to contend with Sony Corp. (SNE)''s PlayStation and Nintendo Co.''s Wii, there''s now a plethora of devices boasting robust graphics and computing power, capable of downloading games from the Internet and connecting TVs in the living room to gadgets throughout the house. That''s putting pressure on Microsoft to make the new Xbox -- to be unveiled tomorrow at an event in Redmond, Washington -- capable of delivering more programming, entertainment and services, moving it further beyond the gaming realm. </p> <p>This has to last them in the living room for four to 10 years, said Brian Blau, an analyst at Gartner Inc. in San Francisco. They have to think about what''s coming in five years and compete against the two generations of tablets which will come out during that time. </p>




Photographer: David Paul Morris/Bloomberg

<p>
Attendees play with Microsoft Corp.s Xbox 360 game console during the Consumer Electronics Show in Las Vegas. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lisa Abramowicz" date="May 20, 2013 10:57 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-20/jpmorgan-barclays-boost-forecasts-on-junk-bond-returns-for-2013.html"><headline>JPMorgan, Barclays Boost Forecasts on Junk-Bond Returns for 2013</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) and Barclays Plc
are lifting their forecasts for U.S. junk-bond returns as this
year''s rally exceeds the expectations of top-rated credit
strategists. </p>
<p>Barclays analysts predict high-yield bonds may gain 8
percent in 2013, as much as four percentage points more than
their original expectation, wrote strategists led by Jeffrey Meli and Bradley Rogoff in a May 17 report. JPMorgan sees
modest upside risk to our original full-year return forecast
of 7 to 8 percent for U.S. high yield and now expects gains of
as much as 10 percent, according to strategists led by Jan
Loeys. </p>
<p>Speculative-grade bonds have posted average annual returns
of 21 percent since 2008 as the Federal Reserve pumped more than
$2.5 trillion into the financial system to galvanize economic
growth. Junk notes have gained 5.3 percent this year, almost the
same as in the similar period of 2012, according to Bank of
America Merrill Lynch index data, and exceeding the 3.1 percent
full-year 2013 prediction in December by Morgan Stanley (MS)
strategists led by Adam Richmond. </p>
<p>Junk debt''s value is still higher than fixed-income
alternatives given low defaults and volatility, wrote JPMorgan
strategists in a May 17 global asset allocation report. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
A man speaks on his mobile phone in front of JPMorgan Chase  Co. offices in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lyubov Pronina" date="May 20, 2013  7:54 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-20/jpmorgan-sees-earnings-drag-for-major-emerging-stock-markets.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sees Earnings Drag for Major Emerging Stock Markets</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Emerging-market stocks face
fundamental headwinds as 2013 earnings revisions for most major
country sectors are negative and growth in the four biggest
economies is disappointing, according to JPMorgan Chase  Co. </p>
<p>We remain concerned that earnings-per-share forecasts
will continue to fall, Adrian Mowat, Hong Kong-based chief
Asia and emerging-market strategist at JPMorgan, wrote in a
report dated May 18. While growth in gross domestic product is
low, earnings per share are estimated to rise 16 percent
this year after falling 4 percent in 2012, he said. </p>
<p>The year-to-date performance for emerging equities relative
to the U.S. is the worst since 1995 and the worst on record
against the world, Mowat said. </p>
<p>The MSCI Emerging Markets Index rose 0.2 percent at 12:30
p.m. in London, trimming this year''s decline to 0.7 percent.
MSCI BRIC Index of equities from Brazil, Russia, India and China
has dropped 1.1 percent this year. That compares with a 13
percent increase in the MSCI World Index of developed-country
stocks and 17 percent jump in the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index. </p>
<p>JPMorgan has an underweight allocation for Russia, China,
South Africa, Korea, Taiwan and Colombia, a recommendation to
hold less than benchmark indexes. It''s overweight Turkey, India,
Mexico, Indonesia, Malaysia, Thailand, the
Philippines and Peru, according to the report. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Shigeru Sato" date="May 20, 2013  1:36 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-20/goldman-sachs-eyes-japan-renewable-energy-investments.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Eyes Japan Renewable Energy Investments</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) plans to
invest as much as 50 billion yen ($487 million) in renewable
energy projects in Japan in the next five years, tapping demand
for electricity produced from solar and wind-power generators. </p>
<p>The Wall Street firm also plans to take as much as 250
billion yen of bank loans and project-financing over the same
period to move ahead with projects that would cost a total of
300 billion yen, Hiroko Matsumoto, a Tokyo-based spokeswoman for
Goldman, said by telephone. The Nikkei newspaper reported the
plan earlier today. </p>
<p>Japan began offering incentives in July through feed-in
tariffs to encourage renewables after the Fukushima nuclear-plant crisis stemming from the March 11, 2011 earthquake and
tsunami. Japan has been forced to slash its reliance on atomic
power generation since Fukushima. </p>
<p>We believe that we can leverage our global expertise in
investing in renewable energy in places such as the U.S. and
India, to help expand Japan''s renewable power capabilities,
Ankur Sahu, co-head of the merchant banking division in the
Asia-Pacific, said by e-mail. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs formed the Japan Renewable Energy Co. unit in
August to plan, design and operate power plants run on sun,
wind, fuel cells and biomass fuels, it said on its website. </p>
<h2>Investor Attraction </h2>
<p>Renewable energy has attracted interest from investors
ranging from billionaire Masayoshi Son''s Softbank Corp. (9984) and
financial-services company Orix Corp. (8591) to the country''s biggest
banks led by Mizuho Financial Group Inc. (8411) </p>
<p>Japan will probably become the largest solar market in the
world after China this year, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Commercial and utility-scale projects will boost solar
installations to a range of 6.1 gigawatts to 9.4 gigawatts in
2013, exceeding an earlier forecast of 3.2 gigawatts to 4
gigawatts, Bloomberg New Energy Finance said in April. </p>
<p>Companies that stand to benefit include Kyocera Corp. (6971),
Sharp Corp. and Suntech Power Japan Corp., all of which make and
sell solar panels for residential and industrial use. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christine Harper, Christopher Condon and Charles Stein" date="May 20, 2013 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-20/jpmorgan-holders-led-by-chairmen-ceos-to-vote-on-dimon.html"><headline>JPMorgan Holders Led by Chairmen-CEOs to Vote on Dimon</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>As JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s Jamie Dimon prepares for a vote tomorrow on whether he should keep his chairman and chief executive officer titles, he may take comfort knowing most of his biggest shareholders are led by men with the same dual role. </p> <p>Seven of JPMorgan''s 10 largest owners -- including top five BlackRock Inc. (BLK), Vanguard Group Inc., State Street Corp. (STT), Wellington Management Co. and FMR LLC -- are run by CEOs who are also chairmen. The top 10 hold a combined 29.5 percent of New York-based JPMorgan''s stock, data compiled by Bloomberg show. </p> <p>People just like him are going to vote on this, said Erik Gordon, a business and law professor at the University of Michigan in Ann Arbor. If you''ve told your own board that the best structure for the sake of the company is to combine the roles, then how do you turn around and say, But that''s not true for JPMorgan?'' </p> <p>Of JPMorgan''s top 10 shareholders, only Baltimore-based T. Rowe Price, the seventh-biggest with a 2.15 percent stake, has commented publicly on Dimon''s role. Brian Rogers -- T. Rowe Price''s chairman and chief investment officer, and not the CEO - - said in a May 16 statement that I fully support the combined chairman and CEO role at JPMorgan under the superb leadership of Jamie Dimon. </p>




Photographer: Chris Ratcliffe/Bloomberg

<p>
Since JPMorgan Chase  Co. Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon took over at the start of 2006, JPMorgan has climbed 32 percent, the best performance in the KBW Bank Index of 24 U.S. lenders. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri" date="May 21, 2013  5:16 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-21/disney-s-espn-trims-fewer-than-400-jobs-amid-companywide-cuts.html"><headline>Disney''s ESPN Trims Fewer Than 400 Jobs Amid Company Cuts</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS)''s ESPN sports
television division fired several hundred workers today, part of
a companywide drive to improve profitability. </p>
<p>The firings number fewer than 400 and include unfilled
positions, according to a person with knowledge of the situation
who wasn''t authorized to speak publicly and asked not to be
named. ESPN, based in Bristol, Connecticut, announced the cuts
in an e-mailed statement. </p>
<p>We are implementing changes across the company to enhance
our continued growth while smartly managing costs, ESPN said
in the statement. While difficult, we are confident that it
will make us more competitive, innovative and productive. </p>
<p>The cuts amount to less than 6 percent of ESPN''s 7,000
employees worldwide. Disney, the world''s largest entertainment
company, has made an ongoing review of costs a crucial part of
its strategy, along with growth at its parks, media networks and
consumer products unit, to increase profit margins. </p>
<p>The company eliminated 150 jobs from its film studio in
April and shut down video-game development in Austin, Texas, and
at the recently acquired Lucasfilm Ltd., as part of broad
efficiency effort this year. The company said May 7 that fiscal
second-quarter profit rose 32 percent to $1.51 billion. </p>
<p>The cuts were previously reported by the sports news
website Deadspin.com. </p>
<p>Disney, based in Burbank, California, fell 0.4 percent to
$65.83 at the close in New York. The stock has risen 32 percent
this year, compared with 17 percent for the Standard  Poor''s
500 Index. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass and Cliff Edwards" date="May 21, 2013  4:53 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-21/microsoft-unveils-new-xbox-in-widening-home-entertainment-battle.html"><headline>Microsoft Unveils New Xbox in Bid to Lead Home Entertainment</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) (MSFT) unveiled its first new Xbox in almost eight years, seeking to position the console at the center of games and home entertainment against a growing roster of competitors that includes Apple Inc. (AAPL) (AAPL) to Facebook Inc. (FB) </p> <p>The device is called Xbox One, Don Mattrick, president of Microsoft''s Interactive Entertainment division, said today in Redmond, Washington, where he unveiled the product. The player, set to go on sale later this year, will use voice commands and motion sensing to recognize users and let them switch seamlessly between games, live TV and Skype video calling. </p> <p>Microsoft, the top seller in U.S. consoles for more than two years, faces fresh competition from Sony Corp. (6758)''s PlayStation 4, also set for release near year-end, and Nintendo Co. (7974)''s Wii U, introduced last November. It must fend off Apple, Facebook (FB), Google Inc. (GOOG) and Amazon.com Inc. (AMZN), which all now offer an array of entertainment services, software and products. </p> <p>The new machine marks the first time Microsoft has not introduced a console that is first and foremost about gaming, said Ben Bajarin, an analyst at Creative Strategies Inc. Exclusive content deals could help the company sell more players even as the traditional game audience fragments onto mobile devices, he said. </p> <p>To underscore the broader approach, Microsoft said it will produce a live-action TV show based on its best-selling Halo alien shooting game. Director Steven Spielberg, famous for films such as the Indiana Jones series and Jaws, will have a role in the production, the company said, without providing details. </p> <h2>Fantasy Football </h2> <p>Microsoft also struck a deal with the National Football League, letting the company develop applications like fantasy football games for use on the Xbox and mobile devices. The NFL will give players and coaches Microsoft products such as the Surface tablet for use on-field. </p> <p>Team Xbox is on a new mission: design and build an all-in-one system to light up a new generation of games, TV and entertainment, Mattrick said. It''s the one system you''re going to use and love every day, the place where your games and entertainment come alive. </p> <p>The company calls the new features intelligent TV. Prices won''t be revealed today, according to David Dennis, a spokesman. Games from the current model, which sells for $180 at Amazon.com, won''t work on the new Xbox, Dennis said. The company will allow trade-ins and resales of games for the new player. </p> <h2>Kinect Included </h2> <p>The Kinect controller will be included with each Xbox, the company said, allowing Microsoft and developers to create products around the device''s motion, voice and visual recognition capabilities. The Kinect will recognize users and show them a customized TV guide and a dashboard with the last five things they''ve done on the device. </p> <p>Kinect has been improved to operate better in low light, the company said. It uses a custom chip developed in Microsoft''s Mountain View, California, office and employs technology the company calls time of flight that works by tracking the speed of photons bouncing off the user to a sensor. </p> <p>The new machine is black and horizontally oriented. It is eight to 10 times more powerful than the Xbox 360 and will run on an 8-core system-on-a-chip processor from Advanced Micro Devices Inc (AMD). The Xbox One will include 8 gigabytes of random access memory and a Blu-ray disc player, the company said. </p> <p>Microsoft fell 0.7 percent to $34.85 at the close in New York. The stock has risen 30 percent this year, compared with a 17 percent gain for the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index. </p> <h2>Mobile Market </h2> <p>Shifts in the market, especially in mobile, are pressuring Microsoft to make the new Xbox capable of delivering more entertainment and services, moving further from video games. </p> <p>U.S. retail sales of packaged video games fell 21 percent last year to $8.9 billion, according to researcher NPD Group, while revenue from games downloaded to computers and mobile devices rose 16 percent to $5.9 billion. </p> <p>This has to last them in the living room for four to 10 years, said Brian Blau, an analyst at Gartner Inc. in San Francisco. They have to think about what''s coming in five years and compete against the two generations of tablets which will come out during that time. </p> <p>Activision Blizzard Inc. (ATVI), the largest U.S. game producer, provided a first look at Call of Duty: Ghosts, the next version of its top-selling game franchise. Downloadable content for the game will be available on Xbox first. </p> <h2>Fresh Titles </h2> <p>Microsoft also announced a strategic partnership with Electronic Arts Inc. (EA), the second-largest U.S. video-game maker. The Redwood City, California-based game publisher will supply exclusive content from its soccer, football, basketball and fighting titles next year, Andrew Wilson, executive vice president of EA Sports, said at the briefing. </p> <p>Microsoft said it plans to offer 15 exclusive games in the first year, including eight completely new titles. </p> <p>The Xbox is one of Microsoft''s better-performing businesses. Sales in the entertainment and devices unit, including Xbox, rose 56 percent in the quarter that ended March 31. Operating income totaled $342 million, compared with a loss a year earlier. </p> <p>In fiscal 2012, the entertainment unit saw sales increase 7.6 percent, while revenue in Microsoft''s Windows division dropped 3.4 percent. </p> <p>Industry leadership is no guarantee of future success. In November 2005, when Microsoft took the wraps off the Xbox 360, Sony led in console sales, only to came up short with the PlayStation 3 after Nintendo''s Wii upended the market with a motion-activated controller. </p> <h2>U.S. Sales </h2> <p>Nintendo has sold 41.2 million of its first-generation Wii players in the U.S., compared with 39 million Xbox 360 consoles and 24.2 million Sony PlayStation 3s, according to NPD Group Inc., the Port Washington, New York-based researcher. </p> <p>This time Xbox comes in with 28 months of market-leading sales in the U.S., according to NPD, outgunning Sony and the Wii-U, which is selling below Nintendo''s projections. Microsoft has sold 76 million Xbox 360 consoles worldwide and has 46 million subscribers to the Xbox Live online service. </p> <p>Worldwide the video game industry generated hardware and software sales of $37.4 billion last year, according to Gartner. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="May 21, 2013 11:59 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-21/jpmorgan-shareholders-reject-ceo-chairman-split-in-win-for-dimon.html"><headline>JPMorgan Shareholders Reject CEO-Chairman Split in Win for Dimon</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) Chief Executive
Officer Jamie Dimon won shareholder support to remain chairman,
surviving a campaign to split the roles after a record trading
loss at the biggest U.S. bank. </p>
<p>The proposal to divide Dimon''s duties won 32.2 percent of
the votes, down from 40 percent last year, the bank said today
at its annual meeting in Tampa, Florida. Dimon, 57, had told
some investors he might quit if the non-binding measure passed,
according to a person with knowledge of the conversation, who
requested anonymity because the discussion was private. </p>
<p>The vote to back Dimon, who guided JPMorgan to three
straight years of record profit, is a defeat for investors who
say companies need the balance of a separate chairman and CEO.
While Dimon can keep both jobs, the vote may spur JPMorgan''s
directors to tighten how they oversee the company after
last year''s $6.2 billion London Whale trading loss and
identify a future successor. </p>
<p>JPMorgan changes after this annual meeting season, even
if all the votes go in the direction JPMorgan wanted, Michael Mayo, an analyst at CLSA Ltd., told Bloomberg Television''s Erik
Schatzker in Tampa today. The bank could give more authority to
lead director Lee R. Raymond, the former chairman and CEO of
Exxon Mobil Corp., or split Dimon''s roles after he leaves, a
person with knowledge of the matter said. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
Jamie Dimon, chief executive officer of JPMorgan Chase  Co. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Laura Marcinek" date="May 21, 2013 11:44 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-21/jpmorgan-top-director-says-stay-tuned-on-risk-panel-change-1-.html"><headline>JPMorgan Top Director Says Stay Tuned'' on Risk Panel Change</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s risk committee
could undergo changes in its membership, said Lee R. Raymond,
the bank''s lead director. </p>
<p>In terms of the composition of the risk committee, you
should stay tuned, Raymond said today at the firm''s annual
meeting in Tampa, Florida. He was responding to a question from
Mike Mayo, an analyst at CLSA Ltd., on why the board didn''t
overhaul the committee following last year''s risk-management
failures in the chief investment office. </p>
<p>Shareholders are scheduled to vote on three members of the
risk committee, including Ellen Futter, 63, David Cote, 60, and
James Crown, 59. Futter, president of the American Museum of
Natural History in New York, wasn''t able to attend the
shareholder meeting, Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon said. </p>
<p>A majority of preliminary ballots supported the three risk-committee members, according to the New York Times. Among them,
Futter received the least support, the newspaper said. </p>
<p>Futter didn''t immediately respond to phone and e-mail
messages seeking comment. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bloomberg News" date="May 21, 2013 10:13 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-21/goldman-said-to-seek-icbc-exit-with-1-1-billion-sale.html"><headline>Goldman Said to Seek ICBC Exit With $1.1 Billion Sale</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) ended a
seven-year investment in Industrial  Commercial Bank of China
Ltd. by selling a $1.1 billion stake in the world''s largest
lender by market value, a person familiar with the matter said. </p>
<p>The U.S. bank sold 1.58 billion shares in ICBC at HK$5.50
each, the person said, asking not to be identified as the
information is private. That''s a 2.5 percent discount to ICBC''s
closing price yesterday in Hong Kong trading. The Beijing-based
bank closed 2.1 percent lower at HK$5.52 today, paring its gain
for the past year to 19 percent. Singapore''s state-owned Temasek
Holdings Private Ltd. bought 280 million ICBC shares, increasing
its stake to 7.04 percent, according to disclosures posted the
Hong Kong stock exchange website. </p>
<p>The Wall Street firm joins Citigroup Inc. (C) and Bank of
America Corp. in cutting holdings in China as new capital rules
known as Basel III make it more expensive to hold minority
stakes in banks. Goldman Sachs has reaped about $12 billion in
sales proceeds and dividends from its $2.58 billion investment
in ICBC, calculations by Macquarie Capital Securities Ltd. show. </p>
<p>Many foreign banks are facing capital shortages with the
new Basel requirement, so I''m not surprised that they dumped
holdings in Chinese banks on which they''ve already made massive
returns, said Chen Xingyu, a Shanghai-based analyst at Phillip
Securities Group. The exit strategy has been on the table for
these foreign investors since the very beginning because they
know these aren''t real strategic investments. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs and client funds offloaded ICBC shares at
least five times before the latest transaction after first
investing in ICBC in 2006. Connie Ling, a spokeswoman for New
York-based Goldman Sachs in Hong Kong, declined to comment today
on the latest sale. </p>
<h2>Capital Deductions </h2>
<p>New rules set by the Basel Committee on Banking Supervision
require punitive capital deductions for holding minority
investments in other financial institutions. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs'' Tier 1 common ratio was about 12.7 percent
under Basel I and an estimated 9 percent under Basel III, Chief
Financial Officer Harvey Schwartz said last month. </p>
<p>Citigroup sold its entire stake in Shanghai Pudong
Development Bank in March 2012, nine years after buying it, for
an after-tax gain of $349 million. Bank of America sold 10.4
billion shares of China Construction Bank Corp. in November 2011
for a profit of about $1.8 billion, its fourth sale, leaving it
with a 1 percent stake. </p>
<p>ICBC last month reported a 12 percent increase in first-quarter profit, defying a sluggish domestic economy to boost
lending. The world''s most profitable lender extended 461 billion
yuan ($75 billion) of new loans in the first quarter, 25 percent
more than in the same period a year earlier. </p>
<h2>Low Valuations </h2>
<p>The bank and its closest local rivals are trading near
record-low valuations on concern that profit growth may slow as
loans sour and the government deregulates interest rates. ICBC
trades at about six times estimated 2013 earnings, down from a
high of 21 times in early 2008, data compiled by Bloomberg show. </p>
<p>It''s good timing for Goldman to sell its stake in ICBC,
said Rainy Yuan, an analyst in Shanghai at Masterlink Securities
Corp. Valuations of Chinese banks will remain low as China''s
interest-rate liberalization is a long-term trend which will
hurt lenders'' profits. </p>
<p>Credit-rating companies have also warned that China isn''t
reducing risks from local-government debt and credit expansion
fast enough. China''s shadow banking system -- which includes
private lending, trust loans, and credit from non-bank
institutions -- poses systemic risks to the nation''s financial
industry after expanding by more than 67 percent over the past
two years, Moody''s Investors Service said earlier this month. </p>
<h2>Soured Loans </h2>
<p>Chinese banks'' nonperforming loans increased for a sixth
straight quarter, the longest streak in at least nine years, to
526.5 billion yuan as of March 31, regulatory data show. </p>
<p>We believe NPL figures greatly understate the potential
scope of the problem of poor quality loans, Carson Block, the
short seller who runs Muddy Waters LLC, said in an e-mailed
reply to queries. Our concerns implicate loans throughout the
economy -- both public and private sector. </p>
<p>Block said this month that he''s betting against the debt of
Standard Chartered Plc (STAN), in part because an economic slowdown in
China will lead to considerable stress at the U.K. lender,
which gets two-thirds of profit from Asia. </p>
<p>Global financial firms including Temasek Holdings Pte
invested $33 billion in Chinese lenders from 2001 to 2009,
according to the regulator. They still own at least $45 billion
of stakes in local banks, data compiled by Bloomberg show. </p>
<p>Since acquiring the stake in ICBC in 2006, Goldman Sachs
has recorded $3.47 billion in net gains on the position,
according to company filings through the first quarter of 2013. </p>
<p>As of March, Goldman Sachs had a $1.11 billion position in
ICBC on its own balance sheet, down from $2.08 billion at the
end of December because of a sale in January, according to the
firm''s 10-Q filing with the Securities and Exchange Commission. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Charles Stein" date="May 21, 2013  9:34 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-21/morgan-creek-to-buy-fund-business-of-signet-capital.html"><headline>Morgan Creek to Buy Fund Business of Signet Capital</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Creek Capital Management LLC,
a money manager that helps clients invest across asset classes
in the style of endowments, agreed to acquire the alternative-funds business of Signet Capital Management Ltd. </p>
<p>Signet, whose alternative-funds unit has $700 million in
assets, specializes in global fixed income and has offices in
London and Lausanne, Switzerland. The firm''s senior management
team, including founder Robert Marquardt and Chief Executive
Officer Serge Umansky, will join Morgan Creek, the Chapel Hill,
North Carolina-based manager said today in a statement. </p>
<p>This agreement represents a major achievement in our
overall strategy to expand our global footprint, Mark W. Yusko, Morgan Creek''s chief investment officer, said in the
statement. </p>
<p>Morgan Creek invests in a range of categories including
equities, fixed income, hedge funds, private equity, real estate
and venture capital. The transaction is expected to close in the
second quarter, according to the statement. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore and Christine Harper" date="May 22, 2013  7:40 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-22/morgan-stanley-names-heaney-rooney-to-lead-fixed-income-unit.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Fixed-Income Veteran deRegt Leaves for New Firm</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Ken deRegt, a Morgan Stanley (MS) veteran
called on to revamp risk-management and the fixed-income trading
business after returning in February 2008, is leaving again to
join investment firm Canarsie Capital Group. </p>
<p>DeRegt, 57, will be succeeded by Michael Heaney, 49, and
Robert Rooney as global co-heads of fixed-income sales and
trading, according to a staff memo from Colm Kelleher, who
oversees investment banking and trading for Morgan Stanley.
Kelleher and Chief Executive Officer James Gorman sent a
separate memo about deRegt''s departure. </p>
<p>He proved invaluable in steering the firm through the
financial crisis of 2008 and its aftermath, Gorman and
Kelleher wrote. Our fixed-income business is more stable,
focused and better aligned with the rest of the firm than it has
been in some time, due in large part to Ken and his team. </p>
<p>DeRegt will become a partner at Canarsie Capital, which
will be a Morgan Stanley client, according to the memo from
Gorman and Kelleher. DeRegt''s son works at Canarsie, a firm that
was started in January, according to a person familiar with the
matter who asked not to be identified because he wasn''t
authorized to comment publicly. Attempts to contact Canarsie
Capital''s office and employees weren''t successful. </p>
<p>Heaney, global head of credit sales and trading at Morgan
Stanley, and Rooney, who runs fixed-income sales and trading in
Europe, take over a business that''s paring risk-weighted assets
and seeking to boost its share of revenue among the largest
fixed-income traders to 8 percent, from 6 percent in 2010. </p>
<h2>Stalled Progress </h2>
<p>Progress toward that goal has stalled. Morgan Stanley''s
market share of fixed-income trading revenue among the nine
largest global investment banks exceeded 8 percent in the year
ended March 2012, data compiled by Bloomberg show. In the next
12 months, that figure dropped to less than 6 percent, excluding
accounting charges. The division''s risk-weighted assets fell to
$253 billion in the first quarter from a peak of about $500
billion. </p>
<p>Ken deRegt''s departure will certainly cause investors to
wonder how much market share of fixed-income and commodities
trading Morgan Stanley can recapture while simultaneously
reducing the regulatory risk-weighted assets of the business,
said David Hilder, an analyst at Drexel Hamilton LLC in New
York, who recommends buying Morgan Stanley stock. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s bond-trading revenue fell 42 percent in
the first quarter, contributing to the biggest drop in total
trading revenue among the largest U.S. banks. </p>
<p>Given that Michael and Rob worked closely under Ken, I am
confident that they will continue to deliver on the rebuilding
of our fixed-income franchise, Kelleher said in the memo. </p>
<h2>Called Back </h2>
<p>DeRegt, who first joined Morgan Stanley in 1981, had served
as global head of fixed income for three years when he left in
2000 to work at an investment firm. He was called back in
February 2008 by John Mack, Morgan Stanley''s then-CEO, to help
the company recover from a $9.4 billion writedown and quarterly
loss that Mack described as embarrassing. In January 2011,
the firm tapped deRegt to replace Jack DiMaio as global head of
fixed-income sales and trading. </p>
<p>Rooney, who has been global head of fixed-income client
coverage in addition to running Europe fixed-income since 2009,
joined Morgan Stanley in 1990 and relocated to London in 1993.
Heaney, who also has run global credit since 2009, joined the
firm in 1986 in credit research and moved into corporate bond
trading in 1990, according to the memo. </p>
<p>Gorman, 54, who succeeded Mack as CEO in 2010 and added the
chairman title last year, has vowed to raise profitability at
the firm, owner of the world''s biggest brokerage. His plan to
double return on equity from last year''s 5 percent includes
cutting $1.6 billion of costs in the next two years, reducing
capital used by the fixed-income trading business and boosting
pretax margin at the wealth-management division. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Nussbaum and Drew Armstrong" date="May 22, 2013  4:05 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-22/pfizer-to-sell-rest-of-zoetis-animal-health-stock-to-investors.html"><headline>Pfizer to Split Off Rest of Zoetis Animal Health Business</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE), the world''s largest
drugmaker, is offering investors a share exchange to reduce its
80.2 percent stake in Zoetis Inc. (ZTS), the animal-health business
that the company spun off almost four months ago. </p>
<p>Pfizer shareholders will have the option of swapping their
shares for Zoetis stock in a tax-free transaction, New York-based Pfizer said in a statement today. If the exchange is fully
subscribed, Pfizer will no longer have a controlling interest,
leaving Madison, New Jersey-based Zoetis fully independent. </p>
<p>The exchange would end the latest stage of Pfizer Chief
Executive Officer Ian Read''s plans to slim down the company and
concentrate on producing new drugs. Pfizer agreed in April 2012
to sell its baby food unit to Nestle SA (NESN), the world''s biggest
food maker, for $11.9 billion. Zoetis shares have risen 29
percent since trading started in February after an initial
public offering. </p>
<p>The proceeds from the IPO plus the Pfizer share reduction
from this exchange will more than offset the lost income from
Zoetis, Mark Schoenebaum, an analyst with International
Strategy  Investment Group LLC in New York said in a note to
clients. The timing was sooner than expected, and a positive for
Pfizer because it should add to earnings next year, he said. </p>




Photographer: Peter Foley/Bloomberg

<p>
Pfizer Inc. shareholders will have the option of swapping their shares for Zoetis Inc. stock in a tax-free transaction, New York-based Pfizer said in a statement today. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="May 22, 2013  2:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-22/jpmorgan-seen-waiting-on-board-changes-after-stay-tuned-remark.html"><headline>JPMorgan Seen Waiting on Board Changes After Stay Tuned'' Remark</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s board, whose
top director told investors yesterday to stay tuned for
changes to its risk committee, isn''t likely to add new members
immediately, according to two people with knowledge of the
board''s thinking. </p>
<p>The board isn''t seeking to replace current members and may
take months to make any additions, the people said, asking not
to be named because the talks are private. Lead director Lee R. Raymond, 74, wants to strengthen the New York-based firm''s board
by adding executives with more experience in finance and
accounting after some shareholder groups opposed re-electing as
many as six risk- and audit-committee members, the people said. </p>
<p>The 11-member board doesn''t see a need to rush additions to
those two panels after shareholders voted yesterday in favor of
every member and increased support for Jamie Dimon''s dual roles
as chairman and chief executive officer, the people said. Three
of the risk committee''s four members received less than 60
percent support from shareholders. </p>
<p>In terms of the composition of the risk committee, you
should stay tuned, Raymond told investors yesterday at the
annual investor meeting in Tampa, Florida, shortly before the
preliminary voting results were made public. Kristin Lemkau, a
spokeswoman for the bank, declined to comment on the board''s
plans. </p>




Photographer: Victor J. Blue/Bloomberg

<p>
Pedestrians walk by the offices of JPMorgan Chase  Co. in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bloomberg News" date="May 22, 2013 12:57 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-22/microsoft-to-add-several-thousand-workers-in-china-ballmer-says.html"><headline>Microsoft to Add Several Thousand Workers in China, Ballmer Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), the largest software
maker, will hire several thousand workers in China to support
new cloud computing services and smartphones using its Windows
operating system, Chief Executive Officer Steve Ballmer said. </p>
<p>The workforce expansion, from a current base of 4,000
staff, will take place during the next year, Ballmer said
yesterday at a press conference in Shanghai that was streamed
live on the Internet. He didn''t provide a specific number for
new workers. </p>
<p>China has become the fastest growing market for the
company''s smartphone operating system, Ballmer said. The
Redmond, Washington-based company will start a public preview of
its Windows Azure service in the country next month, making
Microsoft the first multinational to offer public cloud
computing in the nation. </p>
<p>I visited China last about one year ago in May and it is
remarkable to me how much has changed, Ballmer, 57, said. At
Microsoft this is an incredibly exciting time. </p>
<p>Microsoft is counting on Azure and Internet-based business
programs to bolster growth as a global personal-computer slump
erodes demand for its software installed on desktop machines.
Shipments of PCs dropped 13.9 percent in the first three months
of this year, the steepest quarterly decline ever, International
Data Corp. reported last month. </p>




Photographer: Nelson Ching/Bloomberg

<p>
Microsoft Corp.''s China headquarters stands in Beijing. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sabrina Willmer" date="May 22, 2013 11:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-22/morgan-stanley-said-to-seek-4-billion-for-infrastructure.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Said to Seek $4 Billion for Infrastructure</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS)''s infrastructure
investment unit plans to seek $4 billion for a second global
fund, according to two people with knowledge of the matter. </p>
<p>At that size, the new pool from Morgan Stanley
Infrastructure Partners would be the same size as the prior
vehicle from 2008, which originally targeted $2.5 billion. The
New York-based bank plans to officially start raising money in
the coming weeks, said one of the people asking not to be named
because the plans haven''t been made public. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley, the biggest financial brokerage, is among a
number of firms targeting billions of dollars globally for
investments related to public works. Toronto-based Brookfield
Asset Management Inc. (BAM/A) is seeking $5 billion for a private
infrastructure fund, according to a March agenda from New Mexico
State Investment Council. As of the end of the first quarter,
144 unlisted infrastructure funds were trying to gather $93
billion in capital, according to data from London-based research
firm Preqin Ltd. </p>
<p>Matt Burkhard, a spokesman at Morgan Stanley, declined to
comment on the company''s fundraising plans. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley Infrastructure, which has teams in North
America, Europe and Asia, invests in assets that provide public
goods and services in sectors such as transportation,
communications, energy and utilities, according to its website. </p>




Photographer: Victor J. Blue/Bloomberg

<p>
Morgan Stanley, the biggest financial brokerage, is among a number of firms targeting billions of dollars globally for investments related to public works. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="May 23, 2013  6:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-23/goldman-sachs-shareholders-approve-executive-pay-plan.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Shareholders Approve Executive-Pay Plan</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) investors voted to approve pay packages of top managers after Chief Executive Officer Lloyd C. Blankfein''s total awards climbed 73 percent. </p> <p>The compensation plan was approved with 87 percent support in the non-binding vote, according to a tally disclosed in a regulatory filing today after the firm''s annual meeting in Salt Lake City. All of the bank''s directors were elected, including former Chief Financial Officer David Viniar, who joined the board in January. </p> <p>Blankfein, 58, was awarded $21 million for his performance in 2012, and received a $5 million long-term incentive. That was up from $12 million and a $3 million long-term award a year earlier. Shares of the New York-based bank climbed 41 percent in 2012, the most in three years, still leaving them 24 percent below their price at the end of 2010. </p> <p>Proxy-advisory firm Glass Lewis  Co. said earlier this month that shareholders should oppose the bank''s executive-pay plan. Goldman Sachs has been deficient in linking compensation to company performance, Glass Lewis said. ISS Proxy Advisory Services USA supported the compensation program and said the increase in executive pay for 2012 reflected stronger company results. </p> <p>Shareholders rejected four measures proposed by investors and opposed by the board, according to the tallies, which include abstentions. </p> <h2>Maximize Value </h2> <p>One requested that the board hire an investment bank to explore options for maximizing shareholder value, including a merger or sale of the company. It received 1.3 percent of the vote, according to data in the filing. </p> <p>Two others would have required the bank to disclose the amount it spends on lobbying and to set up a committee to assess its policies on human rights. Those measures received 5.6 percent and 3.5 percent support, respectively. </p> <p>Another would give shareholders the ability to nominate their own selections for the board. It got support from 5.2 percent of the votes. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs held the meeting for the first time at its offices in Salt Lake City, the bank''s second-largest U.S. location. The bank has shifted more of its staff to what it calls high-value locations in an effort to cut costs. About 22 percent of Goldman Sachs employees work in such places, which also include Dallas and Singapore, up from 10 percent in 2007, Blankfein said in November. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="May 23, 2013  6:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-23/goldman-sachs-committed-to-china-after-icbc-sale-blankfein-says.html"><headline>Goldman Committed to China After ICBC Sale, CEO Blankfein Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) Chief
Executive Officer Lloyd C. Blankfein said his company is
committed to growing in China even after it ended a seven-year
investment in Industrial  Commercial Bank of China Ltd. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs this week sold a $1.1 billion stake in ICBC,
the world''s largest lender by market value, a person familiar
with the matter said. The firm reaped about $12 billion in sales
proceeds and dividends from its $2.58 billion investment in
ICBC, calculations by Macquarie Capital Securities Ltd. show. </p>
<p>ICBC is not the key to our interest in China, or the big
reflection of it, Blankfein, 58, said in a Bloomberg
Television interview with Erik Schatzker. We''re investing in
China because China -- I was going to say it''s the future, but
it''s a big part of the present as well. </p>
<p>Blankfein said earlier this month that this will probably
be China''s century, even if it struggles in certain years.
China''s economic growth slowed to 7.7 percent in the first
quarter, and a report yesterday showed manufacturing is
contracting in May for the first time in seven months. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs served as a quasi-strategic partner for
ICBC as the Chinese government took its banking industry public,
Blankfein said in the interview. </p>




Photographer: George Frey/Bloomberg

<p>
Lloyd Blankfein, chairman and chief executive officer of Goldman Sachs Group Inc. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jody Shenn" date="May 23, 2013  3:20 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-23/jpmorgan-to-sell-bonds-backed-by-443-million-of-mortgages-1-.html"><headline>JPMorgan to Sell Bonds Backed by $443 Million of Mortgages</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan (JPM) Chase  Co. is planning its
second sale of U.S. home-loan securities without government
backing since the financial crisis the debt helped to trigger. </p>
<p>The bonds will be backed by $443 million of high-quality so-called jumbo mortgages, according to statements e-mailed today by Kroll Bond Rating Agency and DBRS Ltd., which
expect to grant top grades to most of the notes. Jennifer Zuccarelli, a JPMorgan spokeswoman, declined to immediately
comment. </p>
<p>The deal, like a $616.3 million transaction in March by the
New York-based bank, contains relatively weak contractual
promises that lenders or the issuer will repurchase loans that
fail to match their promised quality, DBRS said. Sellers have
begun taking different approaches to those terms as issuance in
the so-called non-agency mortgage-bond market revives. </p>
<p>Still, the representations and warranties framework in
this transaction does show some improvements from JPMorgan''s
last deal, including how fraud is defined, DBRS analysts
including Claire J. Mezzanotte and Quincy Tang said in the
statement. </p>
<p>DBRS and Kroll said that they took the weaker provisions
into account in assigning grades to the securities. Fitch
Ratings, which will also rate most of the notes, said in a
report that it was not asked to rank a $13.7 million slice
granted AAA ratings by those two firms. The risk of
the debt means it deserves an AA grade, two levels lower, Fitch
said. </p>
<h2>Slow Acceleration </h2>
<p>Issuance of non-agency bonds has been tied to about $6
billion of new loans this year, increasing from about $3.5
billion in all of 2012, according to data compiled by Bloomberg.
Barclays Plc analysts said in a May 21 report that the expansion
will be slow to accelerate and maintained a 2013 forecast of $12
billion to $15 billion. Sales peaked at about $1.2 trillion in
each of 2005 and 2006. </p>
<p>The relative yields buyers demand on the bonds have been
widening as issuance increases and amid investor concern that
government-backed housing debt offered better value and that the
mortgages will prepay slower than expected if interest rates
rise or faster if they fall. </p>
<p>A May 17 offering by Redwood Trust Inc. (RWT) included $299
million of top-rated bonds that priced to yield 2.82 percent, or
1.90 percentage points more than benchmark swap rates. That
compared with spreads of 1.75 percentage points on similar
securities sold last month by the Mill Valley, California-based
firm and as low as 0.97 percentage point in January. </p>
<p>Jumbo home loans are larger than allowed in government-supported programs, currently as much as $729,750 for single-family properties in high-cost areas. For Fannie Mae and Freddie
Mac loans with the lowest costs for borrowers using 20 percent
down payments, limits range from $417,000 to $625,500. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Frier" date="May 23, 2013  3:11 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-23/ibm-cfo-forecasts-8-profit-jump-for-second-quarter.html"><headline>IBM CFO Forecasts 8% Profit Jump for Second Quarter</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines Corp. (IBM)
Chief Financial Officer Mark Loughridge predicted earnings this
quarter will rise 8 percent from a year earlier, in line with
estimates. </p>
<p>The forecast suggests that profit will rise to about $3.79
a share in the period, excluding some items, up from $3.51 a
year earlier. That matches the average analyst prediction,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Loughridge repeated his view that the Armonk, New York-based company''s growth in the second half of the year would be
stronger, with double-digit performance in the fourth
quarter. </p>
<p>He was speaking at the Barclays Global Technology, Media
and Telecommunications Conference in New York. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Justin Doom" date="May 23, 2013 12:35 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-23/ibm-waterfund-index-expands-with-uganda-as-first-african-nation.html"><headline>IBM-Waterfund Index Expands With Uganda as First African Nation</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines Corp. (IBM)
and Waterfund LLC, a risk-management provider, agreed to add
Uganda to their global Water Cost Index, the first African
member of the investing tool the companies announced in January. </p>
<p>The agreement with Uganda''s Ministry of Water and
Environment will let IBM collect data to calculate the cost of
producing water, in dollars per cubic meter, said Peter Williams, chief technology officer of Big Green Innovations at
IBM. </p>
<p>Global water use has grown at more than twice the rate of
population increase over the last century, according to the
United Nations. A growing number of nations are turning to the
private sector to build and maintain water networks, and
information such as the water index may facilitate investment,
Williams said. </p>
<p>The primary purpose is to enable more capital investment
in a sector that desperately needs it, Williams said today in
an interview from Uganda. This is not a price index -- it''s a
cost index. The price that you charge for water is an entirely
different decision than the cost of getting it there in the
first place. </p>
<p>The first version of the index will be released next month
with information from about a half-dozen nations, he said. The
goal is to build it out to 25 percent of the world''s GDP. The
index will also include countries in Asia and the Americas. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="May 23, 2013 11:45 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-23/goldman-sachs-links-bonuses-to-protecting-firm-reputation.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Links Bonuses to Protecting Firm Reputation</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) linked
bonuses and promotions to employees'' success in protecting the
firm''s reputation and put new restrictions on some client
transactions to avoid a repeat of the damage to its standing in
the wake of the financial crisis. </p>
<p>A new-activity committee will evaluate and approve
suitability when clients undertake transactions that carry new
risks, New York-based Goldman Sachs said today in a report. When
setting year-end pay, the firm is reviewing employees'' efforts
to protect its reputation and win clients'' trust, according to
the report. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs, which is holding its annual shareholders''
meeting today in Salt Lake City, created a business-standards
committee in May 2010 as it faced a lawsuit from the Securities
and Exchange Commission over a mortgage-related security called
Abacus 2007-AC1. The firm settled that suit by agreeing to pay
$550 million, and said it made a mistake in omitting disclosures
to investors in the product. </p>
<p>If an Abacus transaction came today, it would encounter a
completely different framework of processes, practices,
procedures, transaction approval and review than what we had
before, said J. Michael Evans, a Goldman Sachs partner who led
the business-standards committee with E. Gerald Corrigan. It
might have the same name, but it would look a lot different. </p>




Photographer: David Paul Morris/Bloomberg

<p>
Lloyd Blankfein, chairman and chief executive officer of Goldman Sachs Group Inc. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki and Laura Marcinek" date="May 23, 2013 10:47 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-23/jpmorgan-promotes-barry-sommers-to-oversee-chase-consumer-bank.html"><headline>JPMorgan Names Sommers for Consumer Bank as McInerney Joins Visa</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the largest
U.S. lender, named Barry Sommers chief executive officer of its
consumer bank, replacing Ryan McInerney, who''s leaving to become
president of Visa Inc. (V) </p>
<p>Sommers will continue overseeing Chase Wealth Management
and reporting to Gordon Smith, CEO of consumer and community
banking, the New York-based company said today in a statement.
McInerney will be responsible for Foster City, California-based
Visa''s global client organization, product management and new
solutions group, according to a separate statement. </p>
<p>JPMorgan CEO Jamie Dimon shook up the consumer bank''s top
management two years ago, removing former retail chief Charlie Scharf from his position and ousting former mortgage head David
Lowman after the lender came under fire for abusive foreclosure
practices, which it spent more than $8.6 billion to settle.
Scharf left to become CEO of Visa, the world''s largest
electronic-payments network, in November. </p>
<p>Barry and Ryan have been close partners and friends for
several years, and we expect a seamless transition as we bring
these businesses under Barry''s leadership, Smith said in the
statement. </p>
<p>McInerney succeeds John Partridge, who retired as Visa''s
president in March. Partridge, 63, who is staying with the
company to work on special projects, will receive a base salary
of $50,000 a month and be paid $562,000 in November as a pro-rated bonus for his work this year as president, according to a
filing last month. </p>
<p>McInerney worked at JPMorgan for eight years and was head
of the consumer bank since 2009, according to JPMorgan''s
statement. Sommers joined Bear Stearns Cos. in 1996 and came to
JPMorgan when it acquired the firm in 2008, according to the
statement. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ben Moshinsky" date="May 23, 2013  7:20 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-23/jpmorgan-fined-4-5-million-for-wealth-management-failings.html"><headline>JPMorgan Fined $4.5 Million for Wealth Management Failings</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The U.K. markets regulator fined a
JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) unit 3 million pounds ($4.5 million) for
failing to keep up-to-date records of clients and lacking risk
and compliance controls. </p>
<p>Senior management at JPMorgan International Bank didn''t
have sufficient information and oversight tools to correct
the problem in its wealth management business for two years, the
London-based Financial Conduct Authority said in an e-mailed
statement today. </p>
<p>Customers of wealth managers should be able to expect the
firm to keep complete, up-to-date client records so that they
can give the right advice, Tracey McDermott, director of
enforcement and financial crime at the FCA, said. In this case
the firm did not have complete records, nor did its management
have the information they needed to recognize this. </p>
<p>The regulator said that the bank''s computer-based record
system didn''t hold sufficient information and that its
suitability reports didn''t have adequate statements about client
needs. </p>
<p>We have fully cooperated with the FCA and have enhanced
our procedures to ensure that they are compliant with regulatory
requirements, the bank said in an e-mailed statement. As the
FCA has noted in its press release, there has been no detriment
to customers identified to date. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lu Wang" date="May 24, 2013  4:46 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-24/goldman-sachs-buyback-orders-reach-highest-level-of-year.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Buyback Orders Reach Highest Level of Year</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Investors trying to explain the
resilience of American equities during a global selloff may want
to consider the pace that companies are repurchasing shares. </p>
<p>About 79 percent of buyback orders at Goldman Sachs Group
Inc.''s corporate trading desk were active yesterday, the most
this year, according to a note to clients obtained by Bloomberg
News. Companies stepped up purchases as the Standard  Poor''s
500 Index fell as much as 3 percent from an intraday record
reached May 22. </p>
<p>The buybacks may have limited losses in American equities
after shares in Japan fell the most in two years and stock
markets from London to Paris and Frankfurt saw declines of more
than 2 percent. The SP 500 closed yesterday down 0.3 percent,
trimming gains to 16 percent in 2013. </p>
<p>The overall buy-the-dip mentality is very, very
prevalent, Jim Welsh, who helps oversee $6 billion at Forward
Management LLC in San Francisco, said in a phone interview.
When you have corporate buybacks, it''s kind of like a support
underneath the market. </p>
<p>The SP 500 slipped 0.1 percent to 1,649.60 at 4 p.m. in
New York, paring losses after falling as much as 0.8 percent. </p>
<h2>$275 Billion </h2>
<p>Companies authorize buybacks and carry them out from time
to time through brokerages as a way to reduce outstanding stock
and increase per-share earnings. U.S. firms have announced about
$275 billion of repurchases this quarter, the highest total in
more than five years, Jeffrey Kleintop, chief market strategist
at LPL Financial Holdings Inc. (LPLA), wrote in a report this week. </p>
<p>Aflac Inc. (AFL), the largest provider of supplemental health
insurance, plans to buy back $600 million in stock this year,
Chief Executive Officer Dan Amos said at a presentation to
investors this week. </p>
<p>Merck  Co., the second-biggest U.S. drugmaker, reached a
deal to repurchase $5 billion of its shares from Goldman Sachs
as part of a buyback program announced earlier this month,
according to a statement on May 21. </p>
<p>A lot of these corporate buybacks are on autopilots, in
other words, the board authorized X amount of purchases and
these will be done over many months, Forward''s Welsh said.
Whether or not it''s to the discretion of Goldman or the
investment bank, I don''t know. I do believe the amount of stock
buybacks have definitely been helpful to the overall market. </p>
<p>The Nasdaq Buyback Achievers Index, which consists of
companies that repurchased at least 5 percent of their shares in
the previous 12 months, has tripled since March 2009. That
compares with the 144 percent gain in the SP 500. </p>
<p>Shares in the SP 500 are trading at about 15 times
estimates for 2013 earnings, above the five-year average of
about 13 times, according to a May 20 note from David Kostin,
the chief U.S. equity strategist at Goldman Sachs in New York. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Grant Smith" date="May 24, 2013  7:17 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-24/goldman-advises-selling-wti-oil-buying-brent-for-december-2014.html"><headline>Goldman Advises Selling WTI Oil, Buying Brent for December 2014</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) recommended
selling West Texas Intermediate crude and buying North Sea Brent
contracts for December 2014 as supplies accumulate on the U.S.
Gulf Coast. </p>
<p>The discount on WTI for delivery in December 2014 against
the equivalent Brent contract has narrowed to $8.38 a barrel
from $10.11 a month ago. The spread should widen as pipelines
carrying crude out of the U.S. storage hub in Cushing, Oklahoma,
cause a build-up on the Gulf Coast that would lower the price of
WTI versus the European benchmark, Goldman said. </p>
<p>If an oversupply of light, sweet crude in the U.S. Gulf
coast becomes a problem as soon as third quarter 2013, it should
be an even bigger problem in 2014, analysts Jeffrey Currie and
Stefan Wieler in New York said in a report today. </p>
<p>The discount on front-month WTI against Brent, at $8.44 a
barrel today, is still set to narrow toward $5 in the third
quarter as new pipeline capacity to move oil out of Cushing
causes stockpiles there to decline substantially, Goldman
said. Booming U.S. production expanded the discount on WTI to
more than $28 a barrel in October, 2011. </p>
<p>Refinery maintenance and reduced pipeline flows are
putting a drag on a more meaningful decline of Cushing
inventories, according to the report. Supplies at Cushing
increased by 0.9 percent to 50.2 million barrels in the week to
May 17, according to the Energy Department. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jason Corcoran" date="May 24, 2013  6:49 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-24/jpmorgan-is-hired-by-russia-to-promote-sovereign-credit-rating.html"><headline>JPMorgan Is Hired by Russia to Promote Sovereign Credit Rating</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Russia''s Finance Ministry hired
JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) the biggest U.S. lender, to help boost the
country''s standing among credit-rating companies. </p>
<p>JPMorgan was chosen after beating proposals from other
investment banks, the ministry said in a statement on its
website, without naming the other firms. Natalia Shchetinina, a
JPMorgan spokeswoman in Moscow, declined to comment. </p>
<p>Russia has long complained of bias by the three U.S. rating
companies that dominate the industry. President Vladimir Putin
said in 2011 the rankings given to Russia were an outrage
that increased borrowing costs for domestic companies and the
government. The country has more than earned an upgrade,
Deputy Finance Minister Sergei Storchak said in June. </p>
<p>The world''s largest energy exporter last had its debt score
changed by one of the three U.S. companies in February 2009,
when Fitch Ratings cut it one level to BBB, three steps below A
and two above junk. That came three months after Standard 
Poor''s did the same. Moody''s Investors Service has held Russia
at Baa1, the third-lowest investment grade, since July 2008. </p>
<p>SP and Moody''s have said Russia''s reliance on oil revenue,
which makes the budget vulnerable to swings in commodity prices,
outweighs the low level of sovereign debt. Russia plans to
follow last year''s sale of $7 billion in euro bonds with another
offering of the same amount in 2013. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. said in February it had been hired
by the government to burnish Russia''s image overseas and attract
institutional investors. The New York-based bank signed a three-year agreement with the Economy Ministry and the Russian Direct
Investment Fund to advise on issues such as communicating
government decisions and setting up meetings with investors,
according to Sergei Arsenyev, Goldman Sachs''s managing director
of investment banking in Moscow. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs and New York-based JPMorgan are on a list of
23 foreign and domestic banks selected to advise Russia on its 1
trillion-ruble ($33 billion) privatization program. Last year
both American investment banks helped advise OAO Sberbank,
Russia''s largest lender, on a $5.2 billion equity sale. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jose Orozco" date="May 27, 2013  5:35 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-27/chevron-lends-venezuelan-oil-venture-2-billion-for-output-boost.html"><headline>Chevron Lends Venezuelan Oil Venture $2 Billion for Output Boost</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Petroleos de Venezuela SA, the
country''s state-owned oil producer, signed a $2 billion
financing agreement with San Ramon, California-based Chevron
Corp. (CVX) to increase output at their Petroboscan oil joint venture. </p>
<p>The loan''s interest rate is the London Interbank Offered
Rate plus 4.5 percentage points, Oil Minister Rafael Ramirez
told reporters in Caracas today. The money will be handled
directly by Petroboscan and will help boost daily output to
127,000 barrels from 107,000 barrels, he said. </p>
<p>The loan has a very low rate because it''s a corporate
loan from Chevron to its joint venture and is tied to increased
production, said Ramirez, who signed the credit along with Ali Moshiri, Chevron''s head of Latin America, Middle East and
Africa. That way we obligate ourselves and our partner to
focus on increasing production. </p>
<p>Venezuela, which channels oil earnings into social programs
and regional fuel subsidies, is seeking financing from foreign
partners to tap more of the world''s largest oil reserves. The
state-owned producer reached an agreement with China on terms of
a $4 billion loan on May 15 for the Sinovensa joint venture with
China National Petroleum Corp. Ramirez said today he''ll sign the
financing agreement in Beijing this week. </p>
<p>The minister said May 3 that PDVSA would invest $15.4
billion in exploration and production this year and that its
partners must meet production targets or risk having projects
disbanded. Ramirez said last month that PDVSA would ask its
partners to finance at least $8 billion of a $25 billion
investment program. </p>
<p>Venezuela is producing 830,000 barrels a day in western oil
fields, Ramirez said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Victoria Stilwell" date="May 28, 2013  5:47 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-28/pfizer-planning-benchmark-bonds-in-first-u-s-offering-since-09.html"><headline>Pfizer Issues $4 Billion of Debt in First U.S. Sale Since 2009</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE) sold $4 billion of bonds
in its first dollar-denominated offering in more than four
years. </p>
<p>The world''s largest drugmaker issued $1 billion of 1.5
percent, five-year securities to yield 50 basis points more than
similar-maturity Treasuries and an equal portion of 3 percent,
10-year debt with a relative yield of 87.5 basis points,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Pfizer also sold $750 million of 0.9 percent notes due
January 2017 paying a spread of 45 and an equal amount of 4.3
percent, 30-year debt that pays 100, Bloomberg data show. A $500
million portion of five-year, floating-rate debt yields 30 basis
points more than the three-month London interbank offered rate. </p>
<p>The issue will be used to repay the company''s 1.85 billion
euros of 3.625 percent bonds due June 3, according to a
regulatory filing. Proceeds may also be used to repay a portion
of Pfizer''s $750 million of 4.5 percent debentures and $1.75
billion of 5.5 percent securities, both maturing in February
2014, the company said in the filing. Other funds may be used
for investments or to pay down part of its $1.75 billion of
commercial paper. </p>
<p>Pfizer last sold dollar-denominated debt in March 2009,
when the New-York based pharmaceutical manufacturer issued $13.5
billion of securities in five parts. That offering included
$3.25 billion of 6.2 percent, 10-year notes that were priced to
yield 325 basis points more than similar-maturity Treasuries.
Those bonds traded at 124.9 cents on the dollar on May 22 to
yield 1.67 percent, or 78.5 basis points more than benchmarks,
according to Trace, the bond-price reporting system of the
Financial Industry Regulatory Authority. </p>
<p>The new notes are rated A1 by Moody''s Investors Service,
the credit grader said in a statement today. Citigroup Inc.,
Credit Suisse Group AG, Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and Royal Bank
of Scotland Group Plc managed the offering, according to a
regulatory filing by Pfizer. </p>
<p>Libor, the rate at which banks say they can borrow in
dollars from each other, was set at 0.273 percent today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Rick Green" date="May 28, 2013  3:57 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-28/jpmorgan-names-treasury-s-kingsley-mortgage-co-general-counsel.html"><headline>JPMorgan Names Treasury''s Kingsley Mortgage Co-General Counsel</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co., the biggest
U.S. lender, named former U.S. Treasury Department official
Darius Kingsley as co-general counsel of mortgage banking. </p>
<p>Kingsley was the agency''s chief of the homeownership
preservation office and had been senior counsel for the Office
of Financial Stability, the New York-based lender said today in
a statement. He will share duties with Denise DesRosiers, who
served as deputy general counsel of mortgage banking. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="May 28, 2013 12:18 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-28/jpmorgan-hires-travis-machen-to-run-financial-institutions-group.html"><headline>JPMorgan Hires Travis Machen to Run Financial Institutions Group</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) hired Travis Machen from Morgan Stanley to run corporate banking for hedge
funds, money managers and other mid-sized financial firms. </p>
<p>Machen, 37, was co-head of Morgan Stanley''s North American
banks group in the investment-bank division, New York-based
JPMorgan said today in a statement. He''ll be in charge of
JPMorgan''s financial institutions group within its commercial
bank, which serves clients with $50 million to $25 billion in
assets, the company said. </p>
<p>Machen''s experience will be essential to effectively
address the rapidly changing regulatory environment that
continues to affect this industry, Rob Holmes, head of
JPMorgan corporate client banking, said in the statement. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Nadja Brandt" date="May 29, 2013  7:39 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-29/morgans-hotel-board-votes-to-eliminate-poison-pill-plan.html"><headline>Morgans Hotel Board Votes to Eliminate Poison-Pill Plan</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgans Hotel Group Co. (MHGC), the hotelier
embroiled in a legal dispute with its largest investor, said its
board voted to end a poison-pill plan and instated a new policy
requiring shareholder approval of any future rights plan. </p>
<p>The change will require investors to endorse any new
stockholder-rights plan within a year of its implementation, the
New York-based company said today in a statement. The vote will
end the current rights plan by Oct. 3, two years before it was
scheduled to expire, Morgans said. </p>
<p>The decision to terminate the plan early and establish a
new policy reflects our ongoing commitment to good corporate
governance practices and responsiveness to our stockholders,
Chief Executive Officer Michael Gross said in the statement. </p>
<p>Poison pills are used to discourage takeover bids by making
companies less attractive to potential buyers. Earlier this
month, Morgans said it received a $7.50-a-share takeover offer
from a large international hotel company late last year that
it rejected as too low. Morgans''s stock rose to a year-and-a-half high the day the offer was disclosed. </p>
<p>Jason Taubman Kalisman, a company director and founding
member of its largest common-stock holder, OTK Associates LLC,
sued his fellow board members last month over their decision to
back a deal with billionaire Ron Burkle''s Yucaipa Cos. OTK
opened a proxy fight this year, saying it''s seeking to overhaul
Morgans''s board and return the company to profitability. The
chain, which includes 13 boutique hotels, has lost money in
every quarter since 2007, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. </p>
<p>A Delaware Chancery Court judge ruled on May 14 that
Morgans, a boutique hotel chain that includes such properties as
the Mondrian SoHo in New York and the Clift Hotel in San
Francisco, can''t sell two of its businesses to Yucaipa and begin
a $100 million recapitalization plan because directors didn''t
properly approve the actions. Yucaipa has a stake in Morgans
through preferred shares and stock warrants. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Carroll" date="May 29, 2013  1:48 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-29/exxon-renews-u-s-gulf-of-mexico-exploration-for-oil.html"><headline>Exxon Renews U.S. Gulf of Mexico Exploration For Oil</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM), the world''s
largest energy company by market value, is boosting exploration
for oil in the U.S. Gulf of Mexico five years after dismissing
the region as too costly. </p>
<p>Technological breakthroughs in seismic imaging have enabled
Exxon''s geologists and engineers to more thoroughly assess
subsea crude deposits that previously eluded them in the deepest
parts of the Gulf, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer Rex Tillerson said in a meeting with reporters in Dallas today. </p>
<p>We''ve re-entered in a very active way the Gulf of
Mexico, Tillerson said. His comments followed the Irving,
Texas-based company''s annual shareholders meeting. </p>
<p>In March 2008, Tillerson said the discoveries being made in
the Gulf weren''t large enough to justify the costs of erecting
production platforms and installing pipelines. Energy explorers
needed to cobble together individual discoveries to make
pumping oil and natural gas to the surface profitable, he said
at the time. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Stephanie Bodoni" date="May 29, 2013  9:27 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-29/microsoft-skype-merger-approval-was-careless-cisco-tells-court.html"><headline>Microsoft-Skype Merger Approval Was Careless, Cisco Tells Court</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Cisco Systems Inc. (CSCO) challenged
European Union regulators'' approval of Microsoft Corp. (MSFT)''s 2011
takeover of Skype Technologies SA, telling judges the deal
created so many competition concerns there should have been an
in-depth probe. </p>
<p>Microsoft should never have been allowed to buy its way
to monopoly in the market for communications that combine
instant messaging, voice and video calls, Cisco told the EU
General Court in Luxembourg today. Cisco wants the court to rule
whether the EU was able to conclude beyond a reasonable doubt
that the merger didn''t trigger competition problems, without an
in-depth examination. </p>
<p>This was a very serious case and there were many factors
to show that there could be serious harm for consumers,
Alfonso Lamadrid, a lawyer for Cisco told the court today. The
commission brushed off these concerns. Its assessment was, with
all due respect, careless. </p>
<p>Microsoft won unconditional approval from the EU in October
2011 to buy Skype, the world''s most popular international
calling service, for $8.5 billion. EU regulators said the deal
wouldn''t harm competition because the market was growing and
they faced numerous players, including Google. </p>
<p>The commission used flawed reasoning that conflicted
with its approach in previous cases, said Cisco, the largest
maker of computer-networking equipment. The combination of the
companies would give them a combined market share of 80 percent
to 90 percent in the market for video calls on Microsoft''s
Windows-based computers. </p>
<h2>Eliminate Incentive </h2>
<p>It would reinforce the new company''s dominant position
and eliminate any incentive to offer interoperability with
other products, Cisco said, according to a court summary of the
San Jose, California based company''s written arguments. </p>
<p>The market share hasn''t put off other participants,
such as Viber Media Inc., from entering the market, said
Nicholas Khan, a lawyer for the commission. </p>
<p>Cisco pretends to seek interoperability, but what it
actually seeks is that it wants Microsoft to change its
products, Georg Berrisch, a lawyer for Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft, told the three-judge panel. Microsoft bought
Skype to expand its offerings on the consumer market. </p>
<p>Luis Ortiz Blanco, another lawyer for Cisco, said the EU
failed to show that users will be able to easily switch from one
platform to another. The commission failed to understand that
people communicate in interconnected groups and as such would be
less willing to switch. </p>
<p>If you can already reach everybody on Skype, why should
you switch to different applications, said Ortiz Blanco. </p>
<p>The case is: T-79/12, Cisco Systems and Messagenet v.
Commission. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Victoria Slind-Flor" date="May 29, 2013 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-29/microsoft-louboutin-maasai-arbitron-intellectual-property.html"><headline>Microsoft, Louboutin, Maasai, Arbitron: Intellectual Property</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), the world''s largest
software company, is seeking a patent on a technology that
rewards viewers for watching commercials. </p>
<p>Application 20130125161, published in the database of the
U.S. Patent and Trademark Office May 16, covers a method of
increasing interactive viewing by tying achievement to specific
content. Viewers who meet certain set goals will receive an
award, which may be physical or virtual, according to the
application. </p>
<p>In some situations, the award may be tied to an avatar,
Microsoft said. Such awards could include the avatar itself, new
vehicles for the avatar, new homes for the avatar, virtual money
to purchase different avatar items, including clothes for the
avatar. </p>
<p>Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft applied for this patent
in November 2011. </p>
<p>For more patent news, click here. </p>
<h2>Trademark </h2>
<h2>Louboutin Sues California Company Over Knockoff Red Shoe Soles </h2>
<p>Christian Louboutin Sarl, the Paris-based maker of shoes
that sell for as much as $6,400 per pair, sued a California shoe
distributor for trademark infringement and is seeking more than
$2 million in damages. </p>
<p>Alba Footwear LLC of City of Industry, California, is
accused of importing shoes that infringe Louboutin''s red-sole
trademark. </p>
<p>Investigators for Louboutin have bought Alba-supplied shoes
that featured red soles, according to court papers. </p>
<p>The French shoe company asked the federal court in
Manhattan to order Alba and its co-defendants'' to halt their
acts of infringement. Additionally, Louboutin is seeking an
order for the recall and destruction of infringing products and
promotional materials and for awards of money damages, attorney
fees and litigation costs. </p>
<p>Alba didn''t respond immediately to an e-mailed request for
comment on the lawsuit. </p>
<p>The case is Christian Louboutin SAS v. Alba Footwear LLC,
1:13-cv-03536-PAC, U.S. District Court, Southern District of New
York (Manhattan). </p>
<h2>Maasai Tribe May Seek Trademark Protection for Name, Images </h2>
<p>Africa''s Maasai tribe may consider seeking protection for
its intellectual property by registering trademarks, the BBC
reported. </p>
<p>Light Years IP, a Washington-based non-profit that works on
IP issues with producers in developing countries, told the BBC
that if the Maasai brand were owned by a corporation, it might
be worth more than $10 million a year. </p>
<p>About 80 companies worldwide use either the Maasai name or
an image of the tribe, including LVMH Moet Hennessy Louis
Vuitton SA (MC), which uses it for a line of beach towels, hats,
scarves and duffle bags, and Jaguar Land Rover Automotive Plc''s
Land Rover unit, which uses the term for a series of accessories
for its vehicles, the BBC reported. </p>
<p>For more trademark news, click here. </p>
<h2>Copyright </h2>
<h2>Arbitron Sues Saga for Unauthorized Use of Audience Rating Data </h2>
<p>Arbitron Inc., the media and marketing research firm, sued
Saga Communications Inc. (SGA) for allegedly making unauthorized use
of Arbitron''s audience estimates. </p>
<p>Saga, based in Gross Pointe Farms, Michigan, is accused of
using the audience estimates without permission, beginning in
September 2010, according to the complaint filed May 23 in
federal court in Wilmington, Delaware. Saga owns and operates
radio and television stations. </p>
<p>Arbitron, of Columbia, Maryland, accuses Saga of using the
data for a variety of purposes, including setting advertising
rates for its radio stations, and making programming decisions. </p>
<p>These ratings were also factored into a formula used to
determine employee compensation, Arbitron said. This was such a
common practice, Arbitron claims, that employees'' bonuses were
known as Arbitron bonuses, based on how well a particular
radio program fared in Arbitron audience estimates. </p>
<p>Arbitron is asking the court for awards of damages of at
least $150,000 per act of infringement, in addition to attorney
fees and litigation costs. The company also asked for extra
damages aimed at punishing Saga for its actions. </p>
<p>Saga didn''t respond immediately to an e-mailed request for
comment on the complaint. </p>
<p>The case is Arbitron Inc. (ARB), v. Saga Communications Inc.,
1:13-cv-00923-UNA, U.S. District Court, District of Delaware
(Wilmington). </p>
<h2>Taiwan''s Music Industry Seeks Blockage of Infringing Websites </h2>
<p>Taiwan''s Recording Industry Foundation, a music-industry
trade group, is calling for amendments to that nation''s
copyright laws, the Taipei Times reported. </p>
<p>The industry favors legislation enabling the blocking of
foreign websites that infringe, according to the newspaper. </p>
<p>Taiwan''s Intellectual Property Office said it will ask
Internet services providers to block access to domain names and
Internet protocol addresses that infringe, the Times reported. </p>
<p>Cheng Kuo-wei, who heads the Association of Digital Culture
Taiwan''s Department of Media and International Cooperation
cautioned that what he deemed excessive expansion of IP rights
could obstruct chill the development of culture-oriented
business, according to the Times. </p>
<p>For more copyright news, click here. </p>
<h2>Trade Secrets/Industrial Espionage </h2>
<h2>U.K. Court Approves Extradition in Industrial Spying Case </h2>
<p>A U.K. court ordered extradition of an Indian citizen
accused of industrial espionage under India''s Official Secrets
Act, the Times of India reported. </p>
<p>Ravi Shankaran, who was accused of leaking confidential
military information to arms dealers, has argued that the
evidence against him was fabricated and that the lengthy delays
in the Indian judicial system would violate his human rights,
according to the newspaper. </p>
<p>Lawyers for Shankaran said they will appeal the extradition
ruling from the Westminster''s Magistrate Court in London, the
Times reported. </p>
<p>India''s Central Bureau of Investigation, which began
investigating the case in 2006, sent a two-member team to London
to assist authorities at the extradition trial, according to the
Times. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore, Mary Childs and Erik Schatzker" date="May 30, 2013  7:01 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-30/morgan-stanley-cutting-correlation-unit-added-50-billion.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Cutting Correlation Unit Added $50 Billion</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) was shrinking its derivatives business to cut risk under new banking rules when three deals came along that it couldn''t resist. </p> <p>The bank bought credit-correlation positions with a notional value of more than $50 billion over the past three years, including a portfolio sold by Credit Suisse Group AG in 2012, four people with knowledge of the transactions said. The trades helped boost Morgan Stanley''s fixed-income revenue, the lowest among the biggest Wall Street firms, at the same time they swelled the balance sheet with risky assets. Such large acquisitions have since been halted, two other people said. </p> <p>Global banks are shrinking or shutting correlation units, which make bets on the degree to which companies will default at the same time, as new regulations force them to hold more equity against the positions. Morgan Stanley''s moves highlight the challenges confronting Chief Executive Officer James Gorman, 54, as he seeks to meet long-term strategic goals while satisfying demands to show short-term revenue gains. </p> <p>They recognize that this credit-trading part of the business is going to be uneconomic under new capital rules, said Brad Hintz, an analyst at Sanford C. Bernstein  Co. in New York and a former Morgan Stanley treasurer. So you work these positions off and, unfortunately, it brings your revenue down. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
Morgan Stanley began winding down its credit-correlation book in 2008 after losing more than $9 billion on structured fixed-income bets a year earlier and as regulators debated new capital rules. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri" date="May 30, 2013  4:41 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-30/disney-falls-after-rasulo-tempers-expectations-for-quarter-1-.html"><headline>Disney Falls After Rasulo Tempers Expectations for Quarter</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS) fell the most in more
than a month after Chief Financial Officer Jay Rasulo tempered
expectations for the current quarter, citing film marketing
costs and tough comparisons with a year earlier. </p>
<p>Shares of Disney, based in Burbank, California, declined
2.4 percent to $64.65 at the close in New York, the most since
April 15. The stock has gained 30 percent this year. </p>
<p>Rasulo, speaking at a Nomura Securities investor
conference, said he was reiterating and elaborating on comments
made earlier this month that the company''s film studio and theme
parks would be up against tough year-over-year comparisons in
the current fiscal third quarter. </p>
<p>When I''m looking at estimates across the Street, maybe I
wasn''t clear or they weren''t properly reflected, Rasulo said. </p>
<p>Disney will incur significant marketing costs for The
Lone Ranger this quarter, while revenue from the film won''t
start to flow until July 3, after the period ends, he said.
Iron Man 3, while collecting about $1.2 billion at the
worldwide box office, will fall short of Marvel''s The
Avengers from last year, he said. </p>
<p>Those items will lower operating income at the film unit by
about $150 million from a year earlier, Rasulo said. In
addition, cable-sports channel ESPN will recognize about $75
million less in deferred revenue for the period than a year ago,
he said. </p>
<h2>Less Easter </h2>
<p>Theme-park results will reflect one less week of Easter
holiday traffic, compared with the same period last year, Rasulo
said. The company won''t get the same earnings boost from the new
cruise ship Fantasy as it did a year earlier because the ship
has now been operating for more than a year. </p>
<p>Analysts predict Disney will earn $1.05 a share this
quarter excluding items, the average of 29 estimates compiled by
Bloomberg. They forecast sales of $11.8 billion. </p>
<p>Rasulo said the company''s acquisition strategy is focused
on film franchises that lead to business for other Disney units.
The 2006 purchase of the Pixar animation studio led to the
Cars movies, which translated into toys and theme-park
attractions. Marvel Entertainment brought Iron Man 3 and
The Avengers, which is now being spun off into a television
show. </p>
<p>This is how we like to allocate our capital, he said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="May 30, 2013 12:49 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-30/microsoft-restores-start-button-adds-search-to-windows.html"><headline>Microsoft Updates Windows Software After Complaints</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) is restoring some old
Windows features and rolling out new ones in a bid to reignite
interest in its flagship operating system, after customers
complained about the software''s usability. </p>
<p>Windows 8 debuted in October for tablets and personal
computers with a tile-based layout for selecting programs,
replacing a desktop design that let users start programs from a
button. An update later this year will restore the start button,
while adding search capabilities and other features, said Jensen
Harris, director of program management for Windows. </p>
<p>Microsoft, which redesigned its main product to appeal to
users switching to mobile, touch-based computing, has failed to
jump-start growth in the ailing PC market with Windows 8. While
tweaking designs and adding features will help, Microsoft needs
more applications running on Windows and a greater variety of
low-cost machines to stem the defection of consumers to tablets. </p>
<p>I''m not sure this helps them restore demand by itself,
said Wes Miller, an analyst at Kirkland, Washington-based
Directions on Microsoft. Bringing people back to Windows is a
question of apps and a device-cost question -- right now you
have to pay a premium price in general. </p>
<p>The update will let users set their machines to run the
previous desktop design as a default, rather than the new tiled
layout, Harris said. Windows 8.1 will also offer greater
flexibility to tweak the start screen''s tiles, he said. </p>
<p>Microsoft, based in Redmond, Washington, said it will
release a test version of the Windows update on June 26. The
company will ship the final product later this year as a free
update for Windows 8 customers, the company said. </p>
<h2>Interim Upgrade </h2>
<p>Users who are unfamiliar with the new design of Windows 8
had complained about the removal of the start button and menu,
and that Windows 8 machines only booted up to the new tiled
design. </p>
<p>In the update, the start button is visible when users touch
or move a mouse at the screen''s bottom-left corner. Previously,
Microsoft had a small image in that corner which also brought up
the start screen. The latest changes to Windows represent a move
forward rather than a retrenchment, said Antoine Leblond, vice
president of Windows program management. </p>
<p>This is anything but a U-turn, Leblond said in an
interview. There''s no question that our view is this modern
world is the future, and we want more apps developed on this
part of the platform. </p>
<h2>New Features </h2>
<p>While Windows 8 allowed users to run two programs side by
side, the update will add the ability to adjust how much of the
screen is given to each one. For larger displays, the software
will let users open as many as four applications at once. </p>
<p>The new software, code-named Blue, adds new search features
that return a wider variety of types of results. A search for
Marilyn Monroe lists her page in Windows 8''s Wikipedia app,
songs in various music apps, movie clips in other apps, as well
as web results. </p>
<p>The lock screen for Windows 8.1 will feature a slide show
of photos, and users will be able to answer Skype Web-based
calls without unlocking the machine. The automatically updating
tiles come in new sizes, from a small one to fit more apps on
the screen to a very large format that can show several recent
e-mails or appointments. </p>
<h2>PC Slump </h2>
<p>The changes are being introduced as Microsoft faces a
second straight year of shrinking PC shipments, according to
IDC. While tablet shipments are projected to climb 59 percent
this year and outpace PCs in 2015, sales of Surface, the
Microsoft''s tablet computer featuring Windows 8, are off to a
slow start, falling short of predictions, people familiar with
the matter said in March. </p>
<p>One issue, particularly for tablet customers, has been the
lack of applications for Windows 8, compared with more than
350,000 apps for Apple Inc. (AAPL)''s iPad. Windows now has about 79,000
apps, according to MetroStore Scanner, a website that tracks how
many apps are in the Windows store. Microsoft has added a new
health and fitness program, as well as a recipe one that can be
controlled with gestures to enable users who are cooking to keep
dirty fingers off the screen. </p>
<p>While the Windows 8 update is a concession by Microsoft
that the new operating system may have turned off some
customers, the software maker isn''t backing away from its new
design, Miller said. </p>
<p>That''s not giving in -- that''s just changing it to be
more usable, Miller of Directions on Microsoft said. People
need to realize Microsoft isn''t just going back to the way
Windows 7 was. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chris Dolmetsch" date="May 30, 2013 11:43 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-30/jpmorgan-chicago-based-funds-settle-mortgage-bond-suit.html"><headline>JPMorgan, Chicago-Based Funds Settle Mortgage Bond Suit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) and a Chicago-based group of funds agreed to settle a lawsuit in which the
funds claimed JPMorgan gave faulty information involving
residential mortgage-backed securities. </p>
<p>AMF Funds sued JPMorgan in New York State Supreme Court in
Manhattan in February 2012, accusing the bank of making
material representations and omissions on underwriting
standards used to make mortgage loans pooled into $515.6 million
of securities purchased from May 2003 to May 2007. </p>
<p>The two sides have reached an agreement in principle to
settle the suit, according to letters filed by both sides in the
past week. Watertown Savings Bank, a Massachusetts lender and
former shareholder of AMF Funds, has asked to intervene in the
case, which both sides oppose. </p>
<p>AMF Funds, managed by Shay Assets Management Inc., had
about $590 million in assets under management in 2011, according
to its website. Mark Arisohn, an attorney with Labaton Sucharow
LLP representing the funds, and Darrell S. Cafasso, a lawyer
with Sullivan  Cromwell LLP for JPMorgan, didn''t immediately
return telephone calls seeking comment on the letters. </p>
<p>Pools of home loans securitized into bonds were a central
part of the housing bubble that helped send the U.S. into the
biggest recession since the 1930s. The housing market collapsed,
and the crisis swept up lenders and investment banks as the
market for the securities evaporated. </p>
<p>The case is Asset Management Fund v. JPMorgan Chase  Co.,
650320/2012, New York State Supreme Court, New York County
(Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="May 31, 2013  3:26 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-31/morgan-stanley-s-hadden-suspended-from-cme-trading-for-10-days.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley''s Hadden Barred From CME Trading for 10 Days</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS)''s head of interest-rates trading, Glenn Hadden, was suspended from accessing all
CME Group Inc. trading floors for 10 days to resolve claims tied
to his 2008 transactions in Treasury futures. </p>
<p>The sanctions, including an $80,000 fine, stem from
Hadden''s handling of trades while at Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS),
according to a statement today from the Chicago Board of Trade.
New York-based Goldman Sachs also was fined $875,000 for failing
to supervise employees, the CBOT said. </p>
<p>The CBOT''s business conduct committee found that Hadden
didn''t liquidate a large position in Treasury futures in an
orderly manner required by the exchange''s rules. Hadden made
orders in the final minute prior to expiration of a 10-year
futures contract on Dec. 19, 2008, and the price rose in the
process, according to the panel''s findings. </p>
<p>This matter arose from standard risk management
procedures for Treasury note futures contracts, James Benjamin, Hadden''s attorney at Akin, Gump, Strauss, Hauer  Feld
LLP, said in an e-mailed statement. Although Mr. Hadden acted
in good faith and attempted to follow a textbook approach, he
had difficulty liquidating the futures position in an orderly
manner in light of stressed and illiquid market conditions. </p>
<p>Hadden and Goldman Sachs didn''t admit or deny violations in
settling. The suspension starts on July 15, according to the
CBOT''s statement. </p>
<h2>Trading Head </h2>
<p>Mark Lake, a spokesman for New York-based Morgan Stanley,
said Hadden remains the firm''s head of global rates. </p>
<p>We''re pleased to have resolved this matter, said
Michael DuVally, a Goldman Sachs spokesman. </p>
<p>Hadden worked at Goldman Sachs from 1996 through 2010,
according to his employment record with the Financial Industry
Regulatory Authority. He rose to head of U.S. government-bond
trading at Goldman Sachs and was named a partner in 2008. Morgan
Stanley hired him in 2011 to turn around its interest-rates
business. </p>
<p>Interest-rates trading involves buying and selling products
including U.S. Treasury notes and bonds, other government debt,
inflation-linked securities and interest-rate derivatives. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Agnieszka Troszkiewicz" date="May 31, 2013 12:53 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-31/goldman-s-metro-delists-last-three-lme-warehouses-in-johor-1-.html"><headline>Goldman''s Metro Delists Last Three LME Warehouses in Johor</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Metro International Trade Services
(U.K.) Ltd., asked to remove three warehouses approved by the
London Metal Exchange in Johor, Malaysia, according to an LME
notice to members today. </p>
<p>The warehouses are Metro''s last three at the location,
according to a list of approved warehouses on the LME website
dated May 23. Johor is the largest location for LME copper with
204,500 tons, out of a total of 608,450 tons. The company, owned
by Goldman Sachs Group Inc., delisted two other warehouses at
Johor, according to an LME notice on May 16. </p>
<p>Metro still has 10 warehouses in Port Klang, Malaysia,
according to the list. Pacorini Metals, owned by Glencore
Xstrata Plc, has 12 LME-approved storage facilities in Johor,
the LME data show. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Scott Rose" date="May 31, 2013 11:03 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-05-31/goldman-sachs-among-22-candidates-on-russia-eurobond-list.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Among 22 Candidates on Russia Eurobond List</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Russia selected 22 banks as possible
organizers of its first Eurobond sale in more than a year, the
government said. </p>
<p>The list to manage a planned $7 billion offering has four
domestic lenders and 18 foreign banks including Goldman Sachs
Group Inc., JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) and Deutsche Bank AG (DBK), according
to a government decree published today and dated May 28. </p>
<p>The release indicates the government overcame a dispute
between the economy and finance ministries over how to pick
banks to organize the sale, which left Russia unable to tap the
market when yields fell to record lows earlier this year. The
world''s largest energy exporter sold $7 billion of bonds in
March 2012, including 30-year debt, in what was the largest
emerging-market sovereign issue since 2009. </p>
<p>The decree gives the Finance Ministry the right to select
from among the approved organizers for bond issues this year on
international capital markets. Deputy Finance Minister Sergei Storchak said May 16 the government was considering Deutsche
Bank and Citigroup Inc. (C), while Sberbank CIB, VTB Capital and OAO
Gazprombank were also candidates. There will be rotation
from the managers picked last year, according to Storchak. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry></news>