
<news><entry author="By John Dorfman" date="Feb 02, 2009 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-02-02/pfizer-nikon-may-benefit-from-the-stimulus-plan-john-dorfman.html"><headline>Pfizer, Nikon May Benefit From the Stimulus Plan: John Dorfman</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Stocks of road builders and
construction companies were jolted last week when the $819
billion stimulus plan passed by the House of Representatives
proved to have only $30 billion designated for roadways, bridges
and tunnels. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many investors had expected more money for such
infrastructure projects. Shares in Granite Construction Inc. (GVA), a
road construction company based in Watsonville, California, have
fallen to $36.45 from more than $44 in early January. They had
risen 23 percent in November and December in anticipation of the
stimulus package. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If not road builders, then which stocks will be the major
beneficiaries of the stimulus plan now working its way through
Congress? The dimensions of the plan are huge -- $819 billion in
the House version and about $900 billion in the Senate version --
and the bills are complex. Final details aren&#8217;t yet known. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both plans stick closely to the blueprint provided to
Congress by President Barack Obama. He has met with Congressional
leaders to rally support; so far he has it from most Democrats
but not from Republicans. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are six stocks I believe could benefit from the
stimulus package: Pfizer Inc., Nikon Corp. (7731), Jos. A. Bank (JOSB)
Clothiers, Inc, Garmin (GRMN) Ltd., Lincoln Electric (LECO) Holdings Inc. and
Parker Hannifin (PH) Corp. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Healthcare Emphasis &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The House bill includes $81 billion for Medicaid, a program
that pays for healthcare for poor people. There is also $30
billion to extend the Cobra health-care program for people who
lose their health insurance when they lose a job. These funds
could expand the market for pharmaceuticals. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While several pharma stocks are appealing, I&#8217;m especially
partial to Pfizer, the world&#8217;s largest drugmaker, based in New
York. It sells for six times earnings and currently yields 8
percent a year in dividends. In a thorny market like the current
one, that dividend yield is especially welcome. Pfizer (PFE) last week
agreed to buy Wyeth for more than $68 billion; I think the
proposed acquisition makes sense. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The administration&#8217;s plan includes about $275 million in tax
relief for consumers and businesses. About a third of that total
takes the form of tax cuts for families earning as much as
$150,000 or individuals making up to $75,000. Families would be
eligible for a tax credit of as much as $1,000; individuals would
get one of up to $500. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Consumer Spending &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can picture some people using the savings to buy a nice
camera. That would redound to the benefit of Nikon The Tokyo-based company is best known for high-quality cameras; it also
makes microscopes and other instruments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nikon (NINOY) stock, traded in the U.S. as an American depositary
receipt, sells for seven times earnings and yields 2.6 percent in
dividends. Its balance sheet is strong, with debt only 24 percent
of stockholders&#8217; equity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consumers might take their tax credit and buy some new
clothes. And someone who was recently laid off may want to spend
money on a new suit for job interviews. This could work to the
benefit of Jos. A. Bank, a Hampstead, Maryland-based retailer
selling classic men&#8217;s clothing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jos. A. Bank pays no dividend, and its stock sells for 10
times earnings. The company has recorded a profit 11 years
running, and the streak should go to 12 when results are reported
for the fiscal year ended Jan. 31, 2009. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Garmin&#8217;s Gains &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more potential beneficiary in the consumer realm is
Garmin, the largest U.S. maker of car-navigation devices. Garmin
had a 59 percent market share in the U.S. as of mid-2008, and a
19 percent share in Europe as of 2007. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competition and the recession have forced Garmin to cut
prices. Garmin shares fetch a mere five times earnings, and the
stock yields 4 percent in dividends. The Cayman Islands-based
company is debt-free. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stimulus package also includes provisions designed to
make it easier for businesses to invest in new equipment. These
provisions might benefit Lincoln Electric of Cleveland, the
world&#8217;s largest maker of welding equipment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, it looked as if Lincoln might be imperiled
by lawsuits alleging that use of its welding equipment could
produce symptoms similar to those of Parkinson&#8217;s Disease.
However, the company prevailed in the vast majority those
lawsuits. Of some 15,000 cases filed, about 12,000 have been
dismissed. Lincoln has lost in four cases, three of which are
being appealed. Lincoln Electric shares trade for seven times
earnings, and the stock yields 2.4 percent in dividends. Debt is
admirably low at 11 percent of equity. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another potential beneficiary of the proposed liberalized
tax treatment of new-equipment purchases is Parker Hannifin, also
of Cleveland. It is the world&#8217;s largest manufacturer of hydraulic
equipment. On Jan. 28 the company announced it had won a contract
worth as much as $2.5 billion to make jet engine parts for Rolls
Royce. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Parker Hannifin&#8217;s other products include systems for
regulating fluid flow, fluid purification and assembly line
processes. The stock sells for seven times earnings and yields
2.5 percent in dividends. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclosure note: I own shares of Pfizer and Lincoln Electric
personally and for clients. I don&#8217;t currently own the other
stocks mentioned in this column. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(John Dorfman, chairman of Thunderstorm Capital in Boston,
is a Bloomberg News columnist. The opinions expressed are his
own. His firm or clients may own or trade securities discussed in
this column.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Angela Macdonald-Smith" date="Feb 17, 2009  1:27 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-02-17/sp-ausnet-cut-to-hold-by-goldman-jbwere-on-bushfire-update1-.html"><headline>SP AusNet Cut to &#8216;Hold&#8217; by Goldman JBWere on Bushfire</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;SP AusNet, the Australian power
distributor majority owned by Singapore Power Ltd., was cut to
&#8220;hold&#8221; from &#8220;buy&#8221; by Goldman Sachs JBWere Pty, which cited
its potential liability for two bushfires in Victoria. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;We cannot recommend buying SP AusNet given the
unquantifiable nature of this risk,&#8221; Goldman Sachs JBWere said
in a Feb. 16 report. Should SP AusNet&#8217;s liability amount to A$100
million ($65 million), the company may have to either reduce its
dividend or take on more debt, it said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A writ was filed yesterday by Slidders Lawyers in the
Supreme Court of Victoria, on behalf of landowners and residents
who suffered losses in bushfires this month, alleging Melbourne-based SP AusNet allowed faulty power lines to catch fire. The
utility is blamed for causing fires at Kilmore and Beechworth,
according to the court documents. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Melbourne-based SP AusNet said it believes the claim &#8220;is
premature and inappropriate&#8221; given the establishment of a Royal
Commission to examine the bushfire crisis. The company will
&#8220;vigorously defend the claim,&#8221; it said in a statement today to
the Australian Stock Exchange. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SP AusNet fell 5.3 percent to 99 cents in Sydney trading,
the lowest close for four weeks. Its Singapore shares dropped 3.9
percent to 99 Singapore cents. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;We think SP AusNet&#8217;s strong operational focus suggests it
should have proper maintenance schedules in place, which should
in our view help to address the allegations,&#8221; Merrill Lynch  Co.
said in a separate Feb. 16 report. Merrill retained its &#8220;buy&#8221;
recommendation on the stock. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Liability Insurance &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company&#8217;s legal liability has been capped at A$100
million under a 1995 agreement between the former state
government and private utility operators, the Sunday Age
newspaper reported Feb. 15. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SP AusNet said it has liability insurance that provides
cover for bushfires and is reviewed annually. The cover &#8220;is
arranged with local and global insurers, many of which specialize
in the insurance requirements of the utility industry,&#8221; it said
in the statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The death toll from the Feb. 7-8 bushfires that destroyed
four major towns and dozens of hamlets around the state stands at
189. The fires razed more than 1,800 houses and left 7,000 people
homeless, according to Victoria&#8217;s Country Fire Authority. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry></news>