
<news><entry author="By Tim Culpan" date="Aug 18, 2008  3:37 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-08-18/microsoft-under-antitrust-probe-in-taiwan-over-vista-update1-.html"><headline>Microsoft Under Antitrust Probe in Taiwan Over Vista</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), the world''s largest
software maker, is being probed by Taiwan''s Fair Trade Commission
after an activist group filed a complaint saying consumers are
being forced to buy its Windows Vista operating system. </p>
<p>''''We have received the complaint and are now conducting our
own investigation, which may last around six months,'''' Chou Ya-shu, the antitrust regulator''s spokeswoman, said in a telephone
interview today. Microsoft can face fines of as much as NT$25
million ($796,000) and be ordered to halt illicit practices if
found guilty of fair-trade breaches, she said. </p>
<p>Sophia Chang, a spokeswoman for Microsoft in Taipei, denied
the company forces people to buy Vista and declined to comment
further on the case. </p>
<p>Microsoft should be fined for using its monopoly to force
consumers to adopt Vista after the company ended sales of Windows
XP in June, Taiwan''s Consumer Foundation, a non-profit group,
said in its complaint posted on its Web site on Aug. 15. </p>
<p>Microsoft, based in Redmond, Washington, stopped selling XP
individually and pre-installing the operating system in most
computers in June to spur Vista sales. Vista, which was released
for consumers in January last year, requires more memory capacity
and greater processing power than XP. </p>
<p>''''It would be a very unusual and creative interpretation of
antitrust law to say that a company is obliged to keep selling a
product,'''' said Brendon Carr, an attorney who advises
multinational companies on antitrust issues at the law firm Hwang
Mok Park in Seoul. </p>
<h2>Demand For XP </h2>
<p>The Consumer Foundation said its research showed 56 percent
of consumers buying a computer with Vista would reinstall XP,
while 67 percent oppose Microsoft ending the sale of the earlier
operating system. Windows XP remains available preinstalled in
some low-cost computers such as Acer Inc. (2353)''s Aspire One laptop. </p>
<p>Under Taiwan''s Fair Trade Act, a company may not ''''use
incentives or other devious means to induce a business to alter a
consumer''s shopping choices,'''' the foundation said in the
statement. </p>
<p>''''The Fair Trade Commission should fine Microsoft a large
enough amount that would strip away its profits from selling
Vista,'''' the foundation said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Flavia Krause-Jackson and Francesca Cinelli" date="Aug 20, 2008  2:27 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-08-20/generali-eni-fiat-finmeccanica-stm-italian-equity-preview.html"><headline>Generali, Eni, Fiat, Finmeccanica, STM: Italian Equity Preview</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The following companies may have
unusual price changes in Italy. Stock symbols are in parentheses
and share prices are from the last close. </p>
<p>Italy''s SP/MIB Index declined 610, or 2.1 percent, to
28,257 in Milan. </p>
<p>Assicurazioni Generali SpA (G) : European insurance
companies including Generali are looking for small to medium-sized
acquisitions in emerging markets as they face sluggish premium
growth at home, the Wall Street Journal reported. Italy''s biggest
insurer, fell 39 cents, or 1.7 percent, to 22.51 euros. </p>
<p>Eni SpA (ENI) : The oil company''s Taranto refinery was left
undamaged by a fire in an industrial area on the outskirts of the
city, according to local police. The refinery can process 110,000
barrels of oil a day, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. The
shares fell 30 cents, or 1.3 percent, to 21.36 euros. </p>
<p>Fiat SpA (ISP) : Merrill Lynch downgraded the stock to
''''underperform'''' from ''''buy.'''' Fiat, Italy''s largest manufacturer,
shed 44.5 cents, or 3.8 percent, to 11.37 euros. </p>
<p>Finmeccanica SpA (FNC) : Italy''s biggest defense company won
the Italian antitrust regulator''s approval for its purchase of an
11 percent stake in Eurotech SpA, a maker of mini computers. The
watchdog posted the ruling on its Web site. Finmeccanica said in
May it was planning to buy 11.1 percent of Eurotech for 18.1
million euros ($27 million). The shares fell 38 cents, or 2.1
percent, to 17.95 euros. </p>
<p>STMicroelectronics NV (STM) : Europe''s largest semiconductor
maker and Ericsson AB, the world''s largest maker of wireless
networks, plan to set up a joint venture for wireless applications
that will employ almost 8,000 people. STMicro declined 28.3 cents,
or 3.4 percent, to 8.1 euros. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry></news>