
<news><entry author="By Hugh Son and Dakin Campbell" date="Aug 04, 2014  3:22 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-04/jpmorgan-s-top-retail-banking-lawyer-biben-said-to-depart.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Top Retail Banking Lawyer Biben Said to Depart</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Matthew Biben, general counsel for
JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s retail-banking operations, has left after
three years at the firm, a person with knowledge of the move
said. </p>
<p>Jill Centella, global litigation head for the New York-based lender, was named acting general counsel for consumer and
community banking in June, said the person, who requested
anonymity because the information hasn''t been made public.
JPMorgan is the largest U.S. bank by assets. </p>
<p>Biben managed more than 425 lawyers and helped negotiate
JPMorgan''s share of the industry''s $25 billion foreclosure
settlement in 2012, according to his LinkedIn profile. The
firm''s retail division had $21.9 billion in revenue in the first
six months of 2014, the most of the bank''s four main businesses,
according to a financial statement. </p>
<p>Joe Evangelisti, a spokesman for JPMorgan, declined to
comment. Biben didn''t immediately return a telephone message or
e-mail seeking comment. </p>
<p>Biben earlier spent 12 years working for the government,
including the U.S. Attorney''s Office for the Southern District
of New York and the New York County District Attorney''s Office,
according to his profile. He graduated from Cornell University
in 1989 and the University of Pennsylvania Law School in 1992. </p>
<p>He joined Bank of New York Mellon Corp. as a deputy general
counsel in 2004 and was hired by JPMorgan in 2011 as its lead
lawyer for mortgage banking. In 2012, he was promoted to oversee
the legal department for all of the firm''s retail businesses
including credit cards, auto financing and consumer and business
banking. Gordon Smith, 55, heads the consumer bank. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Gabrielle Coppola" date="Aug 04, 2014  6:11 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-04/mobileye-record-ipo-defeats-global-selloff-as-shares-soar.html"><headline>Mobileye Record IPO Defeats Global Selloff as Shares Soar</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Mobileye NV (MBLY), which makes software to
avoid car accidents, overcame the worst global stock-market
selloff in almost five months to raise $890 million last week, a
record for an Israeli company going public in the U.S. </p>
<p>The shares soared 48 percent to $37 in New York on their
first day of trading on Aug. 1 after the company and existing
shareholders sold 35.6 million shares for $25 each, according to
a Mobileye statement. That was above the high end of the $21 to
$23 marketed range. </p>
<p>The Jerusalem-based company weathered the biggest rout in
global equities since March and a weekly drop of 1.8 percent in
the Bloomberg Israel-US Equity Index. Mobileye commanded more
money from investors while only three of four Israeli
biotechnology firms completed planned initial public offerings
last week, with all either downsizing or pricing below their
target range. </p>
<p>Some of these IPOs which are in special industries are
trading in their own world, Josef Schuster, the founder of
IPOX Schuster LLC in Chicago, said by phone Aug. 1. In the
last week or two you have seen some of the IPO stocks really
trading independently of the market. </p>
<p>Sharron Silvers, a New York-based spokeswoman for Mobileye,
declined via e-mail to comment on the trading. </p>
<p>The company, which counts luxury electric-carmaker Tesla
Motors Inc. as a customer, posted 2013 net income of $19.9
million following two years of losses, according to the
prospectus. Revenue in 2013 was $81.2 million, more than double
the figure from 2012. </p>
<h2>Revenue Growth </h2>
<p>Mobileye rallied after boosting its deal because investors
see it as a high-growth technology company with proven sales
within the auto industry, said Brian Krawez, who oversees $3
billion at Scotts Valley, California-based Scharf Investments
LLC. </p>
<p>A lot of tech companies that don''t make a lot of money
such as Mobileye and Tesla that have high revenue growth, tend
to get really high valuations, Krawez said by phone Aug. 1.
To justify this valuation, the company has to hit a huge home
run. </p>
<p>The MSCI All-Country World Index slid 2.4 percent last week
as Mobileye completed its stock offering. Stocks tumbled after
companies from Exxon Mobil Corp. to Samsung Electronics Co.
reported results that disappointed investors, Argentina
defaulted and Banco Espirito Santo SA in Portugal was ordered to
raise capital. </p>
<p>Israel''s TA-25 benchmark slipped 0.4 percent in the five
days ended July 31 as fighting between Israel and Hamas
continued. The gauge gained 0.4 percent to 1,398.35 at 1:10 p.m.
in Tel Aviv today. </p>
<h2>Biotech IPOs </h2>
<p>Mapi Pharma Ltd. (MAPI), which makes treatments for multiple
sclerosis, postponed plans to raise $18 million in an IPO last
week, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. Vascular
Biogenics Ltd., which develops cancer drugs, raised $64.8
million, selling 5.4 million shares for $12 a share, below the
marketed price range of $13 to $15, according to a regulatory
filing. MacroCure Ltd. and Bio Blast Pharma Ltd. also raised
less than planned. </p>
<p>There''s a difference between a hot market where you can
do anything, and a smart market that says, is there a catalyst
behind this, is there an unmet medical need? Jason Kolbert, an
analyst at Maxim Group LLC in New York, said by phone Aug. 1.
The market is beginning to differentiate between just
anything, which is where we were in January to March, to
selective. </p>
<p>Mobileye''s IPO was the 10th-largest in the U.S. this year
and surpassed Partner Communication Ltd.''s share sale of $525
million in October 1999 to become the biggest by an Israeli
company in the U.S. </p>
<h2>Mobileye Founders </h2>
<p>Founded by Hebrew University professor Amnon Shashua and
Ziv Aviram 15 years ago, Mobileye makes a chip and a system that
alert drivers to pedestrians and unintended lane departures. The
company''s products will help enable hands-free driving on the
highway by 2016, according to the filing. </p>
<p>As of March 31, Mobileye''s technology was installed in
about 3.3 million cars made by manufacturers from Honda Motor
Co. to Tesla, the company estimates. Mobileye''s software is
distributed through auto-parts suppliers such as TRW Automotive
Holdings Corp. (TRW) and Delphi Automotive Plc. </p>
<p>The record deal size represents a new wave of Israeli
startups that are turning down strategic partnerships and
acquisition offers to grow independently, said Adam Fisher, a
partner in the Herzliya, Israel-based office of Bessemer Venture
Partners. </p>
<p>The companies we back seem to be more ambitious than ever
before, much bigger markets, they don''t sell out as early,
Fisher, who isn''t an investor in Mobileye, said by phone on July
28. It''s a new breed of Israeli tech that''s different from the
tech of the 90''s. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Gabrielle Coppola" date="Aug 04, 2014  6:11 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-04/mobileye-record-ipo-defeats-global-selloff-as-shares-soar.html"><headline>Mobileye Record IPO Defeats Global Selloff as Shares Soar</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Mobileye NV (MBLY), which makes software to
avoid car accidents, overcame the worst global stock-market
selloff in almost five months to raise $890 million last week, a
record for an Israeli company going public in the U.S. </p>
<p>The shares soared 48 percent to $37 in New York on their
first day of trading on Aug. 1 after the company and existing
shareholders sold 35.6 million shares for $25 each, according to
a Mobileye statement. That was above the high end of the $21 to
$23 marketed range. </p>
<p>The Jerusalem-based company weathered the biggest rout in
global equities since March and a weekly drop of 1.8 percent in
the Bloomberg Israel-US Equity Index. Mobileye commanded more
money from investors while only three of four Israeli
biotechnology firms completed planned initial public offerings
last week, with all either downsizing or pricing below their
target range. </p>
<p>Some of these IPOs which are in special industries are
trading in their own world, Josef Schuster, the founder of
IPOX Schuster LLC in Chicago, said by phone Aug. 1. In the
last week or two you have seen some of the IPO stocks really
trading independently of the market. </p>
<p>Sharron Silvers, a New York-based spokeswoman for Mobileye,
declined via e-mail to comment on the trading. </p>
<p>The company, which counts luxury electric-carmaker Tesla
Motors Inc. as a customer, posted 2013 net income of $19.9
million following two years of losses, according to the
prospectus. Revenue in 2013 was $81.2 million, more than double
the figure from 2012. </p>
<h2>Revenue Growth </h2>
<p>Mobileye rallied after boosting its deal because investors
see it as a high-growth technology company with proven sales
within the auto industry, said Brian Krawez, who oversees $3
billion at Scotts Valley, California-based Scharf Investments
LLC. </p>
<p>A lot of tech companies that don''t make a lot of money
such as Mobileye and Tesla that have high revenue growth, tend
to get really high valuations, Krawez said by phone Aug. 1.
To justify this valuation, the company has to hit a huge home
run. </p>
<p>The MSCI All-Country World Index slid 2.4 percent last week
as Mobileye completed its stock offering. Stocks tumbled after
companies from Exxon Mobil Corp. to Samsung Electronics Co.
reported results that disappointed investors, Argentina
defaulted and Banco Espirito Santo SA in Portugal was ordered to
raise capital. </p>
<p>Israel''s TA-25 benchmark slipped 0.4 percent in the five
days ended July 31 as fighting between Israel and Hamas
continued. The gauge gained 0.4 percent to 1,398.35 at 1:10 p.m.
in Tel Aviv today. </p>
<h2>Biotech IPOs </h2>
<p>Mapi Pharma Ltd. (MAPI), which makes treatments for multiple
sclerosis, postponed plans to raise $18 million in an IPO last
week, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. Vascular
Biogenics Ltd., which develops cancer drugs, raised $64.8
million, selling 5.4 million shares for $12 a share, below the
marketed price range of $13 to $15, according to a regulatory
filing. MacroCure Ltd. and Bio Blast Pharma Ltd. also raised
less than planned. </p>
<p>There''s a difference between a hot market where you can
do anything, and a smart market that says, is there a catalyst
behind this, is there an unmet medical need? Jason Kolbert, an
analyst at Maxim Group LLC in New York, said by phone Aug. 1.
The market is beginning to differentiate between just
anything, which is where we were in January to March, to
selective. </p>
<p>Mobileye''s IPO was the 10th-largest in the U.S. this year
and surpassed Partner Communication Ltd.''s share sale of $525
million in October 1999 to become the biggest by an Israeli
company in the U.S. </p>
<h2>Mobileye Founders </h2>
<p>Founded by Hebrew University professor Amnon Shashua and
Ziv Aviram 15 years ago, Mobileye makes a chip and a system that
alert drivers to pedestrians and unintended lane departures. The
company''s products will help enable hands-free driving on the
highway by 2016, according to the filing. </p>
<p>As of March 31, Mobileye''s technology was installed in
about 3.3 million cars made by manufacturers from Honda Motor
Co. to Tesla, the company estimates. Mobileye''s software is
distributed through auto-parts suppliers such as TRW Automotive
Holdings Corp. (TRW) and Delphi Automotive Plc. </p>
<p>The record deal size represents a new wave of Israeli
startups that are turning down strategic partnerships and
acquisition offers to grow independently, said Adam Fisher, a
partner in the Herzliya, Israel-based office of Bessemer Venture
Partners. </p>
<p>The companies we back seem to be more ambitious than ever
before, much bigger markets, they don''t sell out as early,
Fisher, who isn''t an investor in Mobileye, said by phone on July
28. It''s a new breed of Israeli tech that''s different from the
tech of the 90''s. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christine Harper" date="Aug 04, 2014  3:59 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-04/goldman-sachs-hires-former-barclays-m-a-head-paul-parker.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Hires Former Barclays M&amp;amp;A Head Paul Parker</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), this year''s
top-ranked takeover adviser, hired Paul Parker to be a co-chairman of its mergers and acquisitions group less than three
months after he left Barclays Plc. (BARC) </p>
<p>Parker, 51, served as global head of finance at London-based Barclays before being named to run the worldwide mergers
and acquisitions in October. He decided to leave in May after a
reorganization of the bank that prompted the departure of Hugh
Skip McGee, who ran the business in the Americas. </p>
<p>At Goldman Sachs, Parker will be co-chairman of the MA
group with Tim Ingrassia and Jack Levy, Michael DuVally, a
spokesman for the New York-based firm, said yesterday. The post
is a senior position dealing directly with clients. Gregg Lemkau
and Gene Sykes are the group''s global heads, running the
business. </p>
<p>Banks have been hiring in corporate finance amid a 71
percent surge in MA to $2.6 trillion this year, according to
data compiled by Bloomberg. Goldman Sachs, JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)
and Citigroup Inc. saw their combined revenue from investment
banking rise 6.7 percent to $9.17 billion in the first half of
2014, led by gains in equity underwriting and advising on
mergers. </p>
<p>Parker joined Barclays through the British bank''s purchase
of Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. North American operations out
of bankruptcy in September 2008 after talks to acquire all of
the New York-based firm collapsed. </p>




Photographer: Jin Lee/Bloomberg

<p>
Paul Parker, former head of Barclays mergers unit. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kiel Porter, Marcus Bensasson and Aaron Kirchfeld" date="Aug 05, 2014  7:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-05/goldman-deutsche-bank-said-near-deal-for-buyout-firm.html"><headline>Goldman, Deutsche Bank Said Near Deal for Buyout Firm</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The private-equity units of Goldman
Sachs Group Inc. (GS) and Deutsche Bank AG (DBK) are nearing an agreement
to purchase the buyout arm of National Bank of Greece SA,
according to two people with knowledge of the matter. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs Asset Management and DB Private Equity are in
talks to pay Greece''s largest lender about 300 million pounds
($506 million) for NBGI Private Equity Ltd., about a third less
than the bank originally invested, said the people, who asked
not to be identified because they weren''t authorized to speak
publicly. </p>
<p>NBGI''s management, headed by Chairman and Chief Executive
Officer Pavlos Stellakis, is in negotiations to remain with the
London-based unit after the deal is completed, though no final
decision has been made, two of the people said. The business has
underperformed similar buyout firms, with 10 of its 11 funds
projected to lose about 25 euros for every 100 euros invested,
according to an April document outlining the sale seen by
Bloomberg News. </p>
<p>We''re in the final stage, but there hasn''t been any
decision, Dimitris Spyropoulos, a spokesman for Athens-based
National Bank, said yesterday. Spokesmen for Goldman Sachs,
Deutsche Bank and NBGI all declined to comment. </p>
<p>National Bank, majority owned by Greek taxpayers after a
8.5 billion-euro bailout last year, is selling assets to boost
capital before European stress tests. </p>
<p>Stellakis has presided over the buyout arm for more than a
decade and received a $3.8 million bonus in 2009 -- the same
year National Bank got its first state rescue. He has properties
in London, New York and the south of France, and has had luxury
cars including a Bentley and two Porsches, Bloomberg previously
reported. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri" date="Aug 05, 2014  6:39 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-05/disney-profit-tops-estimates-as-hit-films-spark-studio.html"><headline>Disney Profit Tops Estimates as Hit Films Spark Studio</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS), becoming as well
known for Marvel superheroes as for Mickey Mouse, posted third-quarter profit that beat analysts'' estimates, fueled by box-office hits. </p>
<p>Net income rose to $2.25 billion, or $1.28 a share, from
$1.85 billion, or $1.01, a year earlier, Burbank, California-based Disney said today in a statement. That beat the $1.16-a-share average of 28 analysts'' estimates compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Disney, the world''s largest entertainment company, had two
big films for the quarter that ended June 30, with Marvel''s
Captain America: The Winter Soldier and Maleficent,
according to Box Office Mojo. Guardians of the Galaxy, also
from Marvel, opened last weekend with $94.3 million in domestic
cinemas, the best ever for an August release. </p>
<p>People said it came out of nowhere because those
characters were not well known, Iger said of the latest film.
The title was not well known, but the Marvel brand has become
something that, at least in the consumer''s eyes, really means
something and should be trusted. </p>
<p>Revenue grew 7.7 percent to $12.5 billion, surpassing the
$12.1 billion estimate, Disney said. </p>
<h2>Frozen'' DVDs </h2>
<p>Operating income at the film studio more than doubled to
$411 million, the biggest gain among the company''s five
divisions. Frozen, the hit 2013 movie, continued to deliver
profit in home entertainment and international cinemas. </p>




Source: Disney via AP Photo

<p>
Angelina Jolie in a scene from "Maleficent," Walt Disney Co.''s live-action twist on the animated classic Sleeping Beauty. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Aug 05, 2014  2:09 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-05/microsoft-names-johnson-head-of-business-development.html"><headline>Microsoft Names Johnson Head of Business Development</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) named Qualcomm Inc.
executive Peggy Johnson to be head of business development, as
Chief Executive Officer Satya Nadella continues to shift the
software company''s management ranks. </p>
<p>Johnson served as executive vice president of Qualcomm
Technologies and president of global market development. At
Microsoft, she will oversee business deals and partnerships with
important customers, equipment makers and publishers, the
company said in a statement today. Johnson replaces Tony Bates,
who left in March when Nadella shuffled management just weeks
after taking on the CEO role. Johnson joins Nadella''s senior
leadership team. </p>
<p>The business development role is a key one at Microsoft.
The Redmond, Washington-based company needs to smooth over
relationships with existing hardware partners and recruit new
ones as it integrates Nokia Oyj''s handset unit and copes with
the poor adoption of its Windows operating system on handsets
and tablets. Nadella is also ramping up efforts to offer
Microsoft''s applications and services on rival operating systems
and is trying to work more closely with rivals like
Salesforce.com Inc. </p>
<p>Since Bates left, Microsoft Executive Vice President for
Advanced Strategy Eric Rudder had been overseeing business
development on an interim basis. Rudder will focus on technology
initiatives for devices and services across the company. </p>
<p>Johnson, who will start Sept. 1, has a degree in electrical
engineering and spent 24 years at Qualcomm. She oversaw both the
company''s global marketing organization and its Qualcomm Labs
incubator. According to her new Microsoft bio, she will be
relocating to the Seattle area with her husband and youngest of
three children, four dogs and one goldfish. </p>
<p>Bates, who was passed over for the CEO job, has since
joined wearable-camera maker GoPro Inc. as president. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jaime Myslik and Duane D. Stanford" date="Aug 05, 2014  1:17 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-05/coca-cola-to-invest-5-billion-in-africa-with-partners.html"><headline>Coca-Cola to Invest $5 Billion in Africa With Partners</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Coca-Cola Co. (K), the world''s largest
beverage company, plans to invest $5 billion with its bottling
partners in Africa over the next six years, to create new
manufacturing capacity, sustainability initiatives and jobs. </p>
<p>The new expenditure will raise investment in the region to
$17 billion from 2010 to 2020, the Atlanta-based company said in
a statement. The company also announced the initiative at the
U.S.-Africa Business Forum, which is taking place in Washington
today. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Muhtar Kent is expanding in Africa
to capitalize on a growing middle class with more money to spend
on high-end soft drinks and juices. Nigeria and Kenya, among the
major economies in the region, consume fewer than 50 servings of
Coke''s beverages per person each year, compared with the 745
servings per individual consumed in Mexico. </p>
<p>Even as we see tremendous growth potential in Africa, we
know that the strength and sustainability of our business are
tied directly to the strength and sustainability of the African
communities we proudly serve, Kent said in the statement. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola is increasingly relying on overseas markets to
maintain growth as it contends with sluggish demand for drinks
such as juice and Diet Coke in North America. </p>
<p>The new investment will also be channeled into Coca-Cola''s
cooling and distribution equipment and production, its supply
chain across the continent, as well as supporting programs for
safe water access, sustainable sourcing and the economic
empowerment of women, the company said. </p>
<p>Kent also announced that the Coca-Cola Africa Foundation
will expand its Replenish Africa Initiative to reach an
additional four million African people through 2020. The
program, which works with public and private partners, supports
clean water access and sanitation initiatives across the region.
The new target is in addition to an existing goal of reaching
two million people by 2015. </p>
<p>Today''s U.S.-Africa Business Forum is hosted by Bloomberg
Philanthropies and the U.S. Commerce Department. Bloomberg
Philanthropies is led by Michael Bloomberg, the founder and
majority owner of Bloomberg LP, the parent of Bloomberg News. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jason Corcoran" date="Aug 05, 2014  7:48 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-05/jpmorgan-s-emerging-markets-equities-banker-mcculloch-quits.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Emerging Markets Equities Banker McCulloch Quits</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Gordon McCulloch resigned as a
managing director of JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s European emerging
markets equity unit after more than four years at the U.S. bank. </p>
<p>McCulloch, a Russia specialist, departed last month after
joining JPMorgan in January 2010 from Moscow brokerage
Renaissance Capital, where he was deputy chief executive
officer. He was previously managing director at Goldman Sachs
Group Inc. (G) in Russia. </p>
<p>I will be back in a role in due course, London-based
McCulloch said in an e-mailed response to questions. I am
taking some time out with the family now. </p>
<p>Kate Haywood, a spokeswoman for JPMorgan in London,
declined to comment by e-mail. </p>
<p>JPMorgan''s Russia''s equities head Vladimir Bril and the
equity sales head Alexey Kaminsky departed last month amid a
round of job cuts, people with knowledge of the matter have
said. The bank, which opened a representative office in Moscow
in 1973, cut some jobs in equity trading and equity research in
the Russian capital, said a third person. McCulloch said his
departure wasn''t related to Moscow job cuts. </p>
<p>Equity and debt markets have seized up for Russian issuers
since the annexation of Crimea earlier this year led to
sanctions from the U.S. and the European Union against companies
and Vladimir Putin''s inner circle. </p>
<p>U.S. investment banks in Moscow, led by JPMorgan, Citigroup
Inc. and Morgan Stanley (MS), earned $54 million in fees from
advising on mergers and underwriting in the year to July 27,
down 56 percent from a year earlier, according to data compiled
by Freeman  Co., a New York-based consulting firm. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Karen Gullo" date="Aug 06, 2014  5:34 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-06/jpmorgan-wins-dismissal-of-los-angeles-bias-lending-case.html"><headline>JPMorgan Wins Dismissal of Los Angeles Bias Lending Case</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. won dismissal of
claims by Los Angeles accusing the bank''s Washington Mutual unit
of targeting minority borrowers with predatory loans, while a
judge said the allegations could be refiled against the parent
company. </p>
<p>U.S. District Judge Otis Wright in Los Angeles ruled that
while claims related to Washington Mutual Inc. were barred, the
city could revise the lawsuit to focus on Chase''s lending
practices during and after JPMorgan bought WaMu in 2008. The
city lumped Chase and WaMu loan information together in the
original complaint and has 21 days to refile the lawsuit
focusing on non-WaMu loans, Wright said. </p>
<p>The lawsuit is one of at least four filed by Los Angeles
against banks for allegedly flooding minority neighborhoods with
subprime mortgages even when residents qualified for better
terms. The city alleged the subprime loans drove up the number
of foreclosures in the city. Wells Fargo  Co. (WFC) lost a court bid
in May to dismiss a similar case brought by Los Angeles. </p>
<p>Los Angeles and other cities have explored legal means to
hold banks accountable for urban blight in the wake of the 2008
collapse of the U.S. housing market and financial crisis.
Homeowners in Los Angeles lost about $78.8 billion in home value
as the result of 200,000 foreclosures from 2008 through 2012,
the city said last year, citing a report by Alliance of
Californians for Community Empowerment and the California
Reinvestment Coalition. The lost property tax revenue to the
city has been $481 million, according to the complaints. </p>
<p>We are pleased with this decision, and we will continue
to carry out our strong commitment to Los Angeles residents,
Suzanne Ryan, a spokeswoman for New York-based JPMorgan, said in
an e-mail. </p>
<p>Frank Mateljan, a spokesman for Los Angeles City Attorney
Michael Feuer, said the city is weighing whether to appeal the
ruling. </p>
<p>In the meantime we are aggressively pursuing our claims
against JPMorgan Chase, he said by phone. </p>
<p>The case is City of Los Angeles v. JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM),
14-cv-04168, U.S. District Court, Central District of California
(Los Angeles). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri" date="Aug 06, 2014  5:06 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-06/disney-profit-tops-estimates-as-hit-films-spark-studio.html"><headline>Disney Profit Tops Estimates as Hit Films Spark Studio</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS), becoming as famous for Marvel superheroes as for Mickey Mouse, posted third-quarter profit that beat analysts'' estimates, fueled by box-office hits. </p> <p>Net income rose to $2.25 billion, or $1.28 a share, from $1.85 billion, or $1.01, a year earlier, Burbank, California-based Disney said yesterday in a statement. That beat the $1.16-a-share average of 28 analysts'' estimates compiled by Bloomberg. </p> <p>Disney, the world''s largest entertainment company, had two of the biggest films for the quarter that ended June 30, with Marvel''s Captain America: The Winter Soldier and Maleficent, according to Box Office Mojo. Guardians of the Galaxy, also from Marvel, opened last weekend with $94.3 million in U.S. and Canadian theaters, the best ever for an August release. </p> <p>People said it came out of nowhere because those characters were not well known, Chief Executive Officer Bob Iger said of the latest film, in an interview with Bloomberg Television yesterday. The title was not well known, but the Marvel brand has become something that, at least in the consumer''s eyes, really means something and should be trusted. </p> <p>Revenue increased 7.7 percent to $12.5 billion, surpassing the $12.1 billion estimate, Disney said. </p> <h2>Frozen'' DVDs </h2> <p>Operating income at the film studio more than doubled to $411 million, the biggest gain among the company''s five divisions. Frozen, the hit 2013 movie, continued to deliver profit in home video and international theaters. </p> <p>Disney''s consumer products unit, which also benefits from Marvel-themed products, posted a 25 percent rise in profit to $273 million, while revenue grew 16 percent. </p> <p>The acquisitions of Marvel in 2009 and Lucasfilm in 2012 has brought to Disney new material to attract teenage boys to its films, as well as characters for its toys, TV networks and theme parks. The film studio is well positioned for at least the next five years, Iger said. </p> <p>The results were strong across most of Disney''s businesses, according to Kannan Venkateshwar, an analyst with Barclays Plc. </p> <p>While the media networks business was roughly in line with our estimates, the company''s parks, studio, consumer products and even interactive businesses showed strength, Venkateshwar wrote in a research note. </p> <h2>Theme Parks </h2> <p>Disney gets the bulk of its profit from its TV division. Operating income at the unit, which includes ESPN, ABC and the Disney Channel, was little changed at $2.3 billion, as sports programming costs increased. While ABC earnings increased, profit at the much larger cable operation fell 7 percent because of higher costs at ESPN, the sale of a U.K. unit at ESPN and the shift in the timing of some revenue. </p> <p>Profit at Disney''s parks increased 23 percent to $848 million, with attendance and guest spending up at its domestic resorts. The company raised daily admission prices at its Magic Kingdom park in Orlando, Florida, twice in the past year, to $99 from $89, and benefited from the later Easter holiday, which pulled business into the quarter. Disney also is in the second year of introducing electronic wristbands that make purchases easier in the parks. </p> <p>The interactive unit, which makes video games, reported a profit of $29 million, compared with a year-earlier loss, fueled by sales of the company''s Infinity gaming system. </p> <p>Disney''s shares fell 0.2 percent to $86.59 at the close in New York today, giving them a gain this year of 13 percent. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Aug 06, 2014  4:39 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-06/goldman-sachs-promotes-bash-polley-to-newly-created-role.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Promotes Bash-Polley to Newly Created Role</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc., which gets
the largest share of revenue from trading among U.S. banks,
promoted sales executive Stacy Bash-Polley to expand its
relationships with those clients. </p>
<p>Bash-Polley, 45, will take on a newly created role as head
of client relationship management and strategy in the Americas,
according to an internal memo obtained by Bloomberg News.
Tiffany Galvin, a spokeswoman for the New York-based firm,
confirmed the memo''s contents. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Lloyd C. Blankfein, 59, has been
trying to win market share from rivals that are pulling back
from trading businesses amid revenue declines and higher capital
requirements. Goldman Sachs''s trading revenue fell 12 percent in
the first half of the year, the fifth consecutive first-half
decline. </p>
<p>Bash-Polley is currently head of sales for all U.S.
interest-rate, currency, mortgage and emerging-market products.
In her new role, she''ll oversee the firm''s institutional client
group, which is run by Valentino Carlotti, and will report to
Tom Cornacchia, 51, global head of fixed-income, currency and
commodity sales, and Paul Russo, the co-head of the firm''s
equities-trading business. </p>
<p>She currently manages the bank''s trading relationship with
BlackRock Inc. (BLK), the world''s largest asset manager. Richie Prager, head of trading and liquidity strategies at New York-based BlackRock, credits her with changing the interaction
between the two firms from transactional to a more strategic
bond. </p>




Photographer: Craig Barritt/Getty Images

<p>
Stacy Bash-Polley attends the Randall''s Island Park Alliance Fielding Dreams 2013 Gala at the American Museum of Natural History in New York, on March 12, 2013. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Barinka" date="Aug 06, 2014  2:03 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-06/ibm-apple-app-deal-for-businesses-hits-snag-as-china-spurns-ipad.html"><headline>IBM-Apple App Deal for Businesses Hits Snag as China Spurns IPad</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines Corp. (IBM)''s goal to dominate the business application market through a partnership with former rival Apple Inc. (AAPL) has hit a snag where IBM has faced challenges before: China. </p> <p>China''s government excluded Apple products such as iPads and iPad Minis from the list of products that can be bought with public money because of security concerns, according to government officials familiar with the matter. That means the business-software apps IBM is building for those tablets may face hurdles reaching the burgeoning Chinese corporate market. </p> <p>The Chinese government has been excluding U.S. technology companies from publicly-funded purchases and reviewed reliance on foreign products as tensions escalate between the countries over claims of hacking and cyberspying. The move against Apple products could deter the potential corporate customers that IBM is counting on to expand its mobile business. </p> <p>The large businesses in China tend to buy where the government leads, Frank Gillett, an analyst at Forrester Research Inc., said in an interview. There''s a point of national pride here. I would expect that pattern to continue. </p> <p>Lia Davis, a spokeswoman for Armonk, New York-based IBM, declined to comment on the Chinese government''s move. Kristin Huguet, a spokeswoman for Cupertino, California-based Apple, declined to comment. </p>




Photographer: Tomohiro Ohsumi/Bloomberg

<p>
China represents an important market for IBM''s handheld device business, especially after announcing a partnership with Apple last month to develop iPhone and iPad-centric software. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jasmine Ng" date="Aug 06, 2014  7:43 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-06/goldman-sees-iron-ore-rout-extending-as-supply-growth-quickens.html"><headline>Goldman Sees Iron Ore Rout in 2015 as Supply Growth Quickens</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Iron ore will extend a drop through
2015 when an increase in seaborne supply that''s spurred a global
glut is set to accelerate, said Goldman Sachs Group Inc. </p>
<p>While the expansion in supply will probably moderate in the
second half of 2014, the trend rate of growth in seaborne
cargoes exceeds demand by a ratio of three to one, the bank said
in a report dated today. Goldman kept its forecast for the
steelmaking raw material at an average of $80 a metric ton in
2015 from $106 this year. </p>
<p>Prices have tumbled 29 percent in 2014 as companies from
Rio Tinto Group to BHP Billiton Ltd. (BHP) increased output, betting
higher volumes will more than offset falling prices. Deutsche
Bank AG and Morgan Stanley see lower rates through 2016.
Fortescue Metals Group Ltd. has said it''s completed a $9.2
billion expansion to boost annual output to 155 million tons. </p>
<p>The shift to oversupply started barely six months ago and
the adjustment phase is far from over, said Goldman analysts
Christian Lelong and Amber Cai. Seaborne supply is set to
accelerate again in 2015 while Chinese steel production growth
slows further. </p>
<p>Ore with 62 percent content delivered to Tianjin increased
0.4 percent to $95.90 a dry ton today, according to data from
The Steel Index Ltd. Prices entered a bear market in March and
dropped to $89 on June 16, the lowest level since September
2012. China buys 67 percent of global seaborne supply. </p>
<h2>Labor Dispute </h2>
<p>While mining companies plan to boost shipments, a labor
dispute over leave and wages threatens to disrupt cargoes at
Australia''s Port Hedland, the world''s largest bulk terminal.
Tugboat engineers intend to strike for four hours each on Aug.
9, Aug. 11 and Aug. 13, says Teekay Shipping (Australia) Pty,
which is contracted by BHP Billiton Ltd. to tow vessels. </p>
<p>The action would mean that half of the day''s shipping is
lost, Ian Roper, a Singapore-based analyst at CLSA Ltd., said
by phone, estimating the strike would disrupt about 2.2 million
tons of supply. That''s not a great amount. Fundamental wise,
there''s still an awful lot of supply. </p>
<p>Fortescue and BHP estimate such a disruption may cost users
about $93 million a day. Port Hedland shipments made up 55
percent of Australia''s total ore exports last year and about a
quarter of global seaborne trade, Bloomberg calculations based
on Bureau of Resources and Energy Economics data show. Iron ore
is the country''s biggest export earner. </p>
<h2>High Tide </h2>
<p>Given the short duration of the stoppages and the glut, the
strike will probably not materially impact the seaborne market
or prices, Morgan Stanley said in a report today. If conducted
at high tide, each four-hour stoppage could affect as much as
500,000 tons, or 1.5 percent of monthly volumes, analysts
including Joel Crane said. </p>
<p>The outlook from Goldman contrasts with the view from
Westpac Banking Corp.''s senior economist Justin Smirk, who said
prices will rally and peak at $123 in the second quarter. </p>
<p>We are likely to see softer near-term growth in ore
supply overall as Chinese and other sources of ore moderate
production, Smirk wrote in a report today. Any near-term
upside surprise in demand will be a positive for prices. </p>
<p>Iron ore rose in July for a second straight month on
speculation that China''s demand for imports was improving,
helping to absorb a global surplus as local supplies in the
largest buyer are displaced. </p>
<p>Sanford C. Bernstein Ltd. predicted a dramatic recovery in
prices in second half, saying that it''s now cheaper for steel
mills in China to buy seaborne supply rather than domestic
material. Citigroup Inc. said in June prices will rebound as the
daily closure of mines supplying high-cost output in China
boosts demand for seaborne shipments. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Takahiko Hyuga" date="Aug 06, 2014  3:23 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-06/morgan-stanley-tops-deutsche-bank-with-most-japan-profit.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Tops Deutsche Bank With Most Japan Profit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley beat Deutsche Bank (DBK) AG
to become the most profitable foreign securities firm in Japan
last fiscal year as the country''s stock-market rally boosted
brokerage commissions and underwriting fees. </p>
<p>The U.S. firm''s Japanese unit reported net income of 30.6
billion yen ($298 million) in the year ended March as revenue
jumped 20 percent from a year earlier to 127.2 billion yen, the
highest among 11 global banks operating in the country,
regulatory filings show. Deutsche Bank''s Japan profit surged
more than four times to 30.3 billion yen, driven by structured-product sales and cost cuts. </p>
<p>Combined revenue at the 11 foreign firms rose 23 percent as
overseas investors flocked to Japanese stocks after Prime
Minister Shinzo Abe pledged to revive the economy with stimulus
measures and deregulation. At the same time, the rally wasn''t
enough to persuade the banks to add employees, with staff levels
falling 6.4 percent to the lowest in at least three years,
according to the filings. </p>
<p>Foreign brokerages reaped the benefits of Abenomics last
year, thanks to overseas hedge funds that aggressively bought
Japan stocks, said Katsunobu Komizo, president of Tokyo-based
Executive Search Partners Co., Japan''s biggest banking
recruitment firm. </p>
<p>Despite posting higher revenue, Morgan Stanley (MS)''s net income
from Japan fell 7.8 percent in the fiscal year as personnel
costs rose and it moved into new headquarters in Tokyo. </p>
<h2>Higher Revenue </h2>
<p>Combined revenue climbed to 719.3 billion yen, according to
the filings from Bank of America Corp., Barclays Plc, BNP
Paribas SA, Citigroup Inc. (C), Credit Suisse Group AG, Deutsche
Bank, Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), Morgan
Stanley, Royal Bank of Scotland Group Plc and UBS AG. (UBSN) Total net
income more than tripled to 98 billion yen. </p>
<p>The banks'' headcount fell by 428 to 6,258, the statements
to the Financial Services Agency showed. New York-based Morgan
Stanley was the only firm to increase staff, boosting the number
by five to 680. </p>
<p>Komizo said global firms in Tokyo focused on reducing
senior banker and management positions last year to shed a
costly top-heavy structure. They are now seeking to add junior
staff for investment banking, including mergers advice, he said. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley, which operates in Japan through ventures
with its largest shareholder, Mitsubishi UFJ Financial Group
Inc. (8306), was ranked second among managers of Japanese share sales
in the year ended March, trailing only Nomura Holdings Inc.
after arranging transactions including the global initial public
offering of Suntory Beverage  Food Ltd. (2587) Morgan Stanley was the
top adviser of Japanese mergers and acquisitions. </p>
<h2>Bearing Fruit </h2>
<p>The alliance with Mitsubishi UFJ continues to bear
fruit, Jonathan Kindred, chief executive officer of Morgan
Stanley MUFG Securities Co., said in an e-mailed statement. As
Japanese corporations and institutional investors become more
globally minded, we see substantial opportunities to serve our
clients as well as grow our businesses. </p>
<p>Revenue at Frankfurt-based Deutsche Bank''s Japan brokerage
climbed 21 percent to 93.9 billion yen, the second highest of
the 11 firms. Operating expenses including personnel costs fell
8.1 percent, its filing showed. Sales in both fixed income and
equities businesses were strong, the unit said in a statement. </p>
<p>We see increasingly strong interest from Japanese
institutional investors in foreign assets, Makoto Kuwahara,
CEO of Deutsche Securities Inc., said in an e-mailed statement. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs''s Japan unit posted a 9 percent increase in
revenue to 84.7 billion yen, its filing showed. Net income more
than doubled to 9.8 billion yen. </p>
<h2>Investment Banking </h2>
<p>Bank of America''s revenue advanced 37 percent to 71.9
billion yen. Net income dropped 84 percent to 7.3 billion yen
after the sale of a stake in a private bank bolstered the
previous year''s earnings. </p>
<p>Foreign investors who traded through brokerages accounted
for 58 percent of transactions on the Tokyo Stock Exchange last
year, according to the bourse. While the Nikkei 225 (NKY) Stock
Average jumped 57 percent to a six-year high in 2013, it has
since lost about 7 percent as investors grow wary that Abe''s
economic agenda will deliver a sustainable recovery. </p>
<p>Investment banking remains promising for foreign firms as
Japanese companies look to expand abroad, said Komizo at
Executive Search Partners. Japan stock and bond sales rose last
fiscal year, while MA fell, data compiled by Bloomberg show. </p>
<p>There''s more room for activity to increase, Komizo
said. Companies need the expertise of foreign firms to help
them make global acquisitions and raise funds. </p>


Revenue (Billions of yen)    3/2014   3/2013   % Change
=======================================================
Morgan Stanley               127.2    106.2    19.8
Deutsche Bank                 93.9     77.9    20.5
Goldman Sachs                 84.7     77.7     9.0
Bank of America               71.9     52.6    36.7
JPMorgan                      71.6     52      37.7
Barclays                      71.2     57.1    24.7
BNP Paribas                   58.3     39.8    46.5
Credit Suisse                 52.4     37.5    39.7
Citigroup                     39.9     48     -16.9
UBS                           35.2     23      53.0
RBS                           13       11.4    14.0
-------------------------------------------------------
Total                        719.3    583.2    23.3


Net Income (Billions of yen) 3/2014   3/2013   % Change
=======================================================
Morgan Stanley                30.6     33.2    -7.8
Deutsche Bank                 30.3      6.4   373.4
JPMorgan                      13.5      4.7   187.2
Credit Suisse                 10.1     -3.2    n.a.
Goldman Sachs                  9.8      4.2   133.3
Barclays                       9.5      5.8    63.8
Bank of America                7.3     44.8   -83.7
BNP Paribas                    0.3     -8.2    n.a.
Citigroup                     -3.5      1      n.a.
UBS                           -4.2    -55.9   -92.5
RBS                           -5.7     -3.2    78.1
-------------------------------------------------------
Total                         98.0     29.6   231.2


Employees                    3/2014   3/2013   % Change
=======================================================
Bank of America                810     842     -3.8
JPMorgan                       793     820     -3.3
Goldman Sachs                  731     766     -4.6
Morgan Stanley                 680     675      0.7
Citigroup                      620     648     -4.3
Barclays                       616     645     -4.5
Deutsche Bank                  556     630    -11.7
UBS                            503     638    -21.2
Credit Suisse                  439     466     -5.8
BNP Paribas                    399     414     -3.6
RBS                            111     142    -21.8
-------------------------------------------------------
Total                        6,258   6,686     -6.4

<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Eduard Gismatullin and Stephen Bierman" date="Aug 08, 2014  7:01 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-08/exxon-to-start-drilling-arctic-exploration-well-with-rosneft.html"><headline>Exxon to Start Drilling Arctic Exploration Well With Rosneft</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) and OAO Rosneft (ROSN),
the world''s largest publicly traded oil companies by output,
will start drilling a $700 million well in the Arctic Ocean
today, undeterred by the crisis in U.S.-Russian relations. </p>
<p>Vladimir Putin, Rosneft Chief Executive Officer Igor Sechin, who''s subject to U.S. sanctions, and Exxon''s Russia head
Glenn Waller will bless the start of Russia''s northernmost well,
the government said yesterday. It''s the first step in a quest
for new oil resources to help maintain oil production near a
post-Soviet high of more than 10 million barrels a day. </p>
<p>The European Union imposed a third round of sanctions last
week, restricting the export of equipment used for offshore oil
production to Russia after its relations with Europe and the
U.S. deteriorated to the lowest point since the Cold War over
the conflict in Ukraine. That hasn''t stopped Exxon because the
contract to hire the rig was signed before the measures were
announced. </p>
<p>In the area of oil, the sanctions are more symbolic
perhaps at this stage, but if they remain in place for a long
period then they will have some significant consequences, said
John Lough, a London-based associate fellow at Chatham House, a
London-based foreign policy research group. </p>
<p>The partners plan to drill the Universitetskaya prospect
after more than two years of planning. Exxon, where output fell
to a five-year low in the second quarter, isn''t the only western
oil company involved. BP Plc, the U.K.''s second-largest oil
company by value, has an interest through its 20 percent stake
in Rosneft. </p>
<h2>West Alpha </h2>
<p>Universitetskaya is the first of as many as 40 offshore
wells Rosneft plans by 2018 to test the potential of the
unexplored the Arctic Ocean. The geological structure targeted
by the drilling is roughly the size of the city of Moscow and
may contain as many as 9 billion barrels of oil, according to a
presentation on Rosneft''s website. </p>
<p>The West Alpha rig, leased by Exxon from Bermuda-based
Seadrill Ltd. (SDRL), is currently in the Kara Sea about 72 miles off
the coast of Novaya Zemlya, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Drilling will take about 70 days, a period that should be
sufficient to assess the reserves of any discovery, Rosneft''s
head of offshore, Zeljko Runje, said on a call with analysts
last week. The area is relatively free of icebergs, meaning work
is ready to start, he said. </p>
<p>Tensions with Russia will make companies pay more attention
to risk, said Richard Mallinson, an analyst at Energy Aspects
Ltd. in London. </p>
<h2>Ecologically Sensitive'' </h2>
<p>In addition to the political background, drilling in the
Arctic Ocean is controversial because campaigners say it
threatens a unique ecosystem. </p>
<p>The West Alpha platform is fast becoming the most
controversial oil rig in the world, Gustavo Ampugnani, an
Arctic campaigner at Greenpeace, said in an e-mailed statement.
The companies'' plan to drill in the ecologically sensitive
Arctic is nothing less than absurd. </p>
<p>The Exxon-Rosneft cooperation also includes a $300 million
investment in Russian shale pilot projects, which now risk being
suspended, Rosneft Chairman Alexander Nekipelov said on July 29.
The partners have also invested in a new platform this year to
expand oil production at the Sakhalin-1 project in Russia''s Far
East. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Aug 08, 2014  4:08 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-08/jpmorgan-s-fund-choices-for-clients-said-under-sec-review.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Fund Choices for Clients Said Under SEC Review</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The Securities and Exchange
Commission is reviewing whether conflicts of interest led
JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) to sell certain investment products to
individual clients, according to a person briefed on the matter. </p>
<p>The review is at an early stage, said the person, who asked
to remain anonymous because the inquiry isn''t public. The Wall
Street Journal, in a report on the review earlier today, said
the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency has conducted a
similar probe into whether JPMorgan inappropriately steered
private-banking clients into its own products. </p>
<p>Banks can capture a greater portion of fees by having
clients invest in their own products. In some cases, they can
also offer better-than-average performance. New York-based
JPMorgan said in February that 80 percent of its fixed-income
assets under management and 81 percent of its equity assets were
in funds that were in the top 40 percent of peers over the
previous 10 years. </p>
<p>We manage a variety of portfolios based on a client''s
investment objectives, and the mix of solutions varies, is
dynamic and transparent, said Darin Oduyoye, a JPMorgan
spokesman. Our clients have countless options in selecting
financial providers. They come to JPMorgan because of our long-term investments track record and the depth and breadth of our
platform. </p>
<p>Kevin Callahan, a spokesman for the SEC, couldn''t be
immediately reached for comment. Bryan Hubbard, an OCC
spokesman, declined to comment. </p>
<h2>Unit Performance </h2>
<p>Private banking, which caters to wealthy individual
clients, generated more than half of JPMorgan''s $5.73 billion in
asset-management revenue in the first six months of this year.
The unit accounted for $383 billion in assets under management,
or 22 percent of the division''s $1.7 trillion total. </p>
<p>JPMorgan''s asset-management business, led by Mary Callahan Erdoes, generated $993 million of net income in the first half
of 2014, the lowest among the largest U.S. bank''s four major
divisions. The unit''s 22 percent return on equity was the
highest of the four. </p>
<p>JPMorgan set aside $669 million for legal expenses in the
second quarter. The lender agreed to pay $23 billion in
penalties and settlements last year, leading to its first
quarterly loss under Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ian King and Alex Barinka" date="Aug 08, 2014 12:16 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-08/ibm-chip-inspired-by-human-brain-can-sense-images-cut-energy.html"><headline>IBM Chip Inspired by Human Brain Can Sense Images, Cut Energy</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>IBM''s engineers have come up with a way computer chips can think more like humans. </p> <p>International Business Machines Corp. (IBM) said it''s produced a chip that more closely replicates the way the human brain operates than traditional processors do. The new architecture is better at tasks like image recognition in video data -- which could be a new way to help computers sense movement. On top of that, the chip uses less energy than traditional designs. </p> <p>If the design eventually turns into a product, it could help the processor industry, which is searching for new ways to make its products run computers faster. It''s increasingly turning to new methods of trying to perform multiple tasks at the same time, since traditional designs that simply counted faster have led to overheating. </p> <p>IBM said that traditional computer science, which uses linear logic to process data, is inefficient. Processors basically perform one operation at a time, then react to the result of the previous calculation. The computer chip IBM has developed, described in a paper in the journal Science, has 1 million programmable neurons based on 5.4 billion transistors. Its neurosynaptic cores can each compute and communicate in parallel, rather than in a row. </p> <p>IBM''s statement on the chip design didn''t contain information about when the technology would go into commercial production or go on sale. </p> <p>The company''s labs are so renowned in the industry that titans like Samsung use its technology for their production. That reputation in research hasn''t translated to a leadership position in the chip business, which is dominated by Intel Corp. </p> <h2>Balancing Needs </h2> <p>IBM has had to balance two distinct needs when it comes to its semiconductor business: having control over chip design to make its hardware products better and more efficient, though wanting to get the money-losing manufacturing unit off its books. The division loses as much as $1.5 billion a year, a person familiar with the matter said in June. </p> <p>The company was willing to pay Globalfoundries Inc. about $1 billion to take the chip-manufacturing unit of its hands -- an offer that was turned down for being $1 billion too short, a person familiar with the talks said this month. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Stephen Bierman and Eduard Gismatullin" date="Aug 08, 2014 10:02 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-08/exxon-drilling-russian-arctic-shows-sanction-lack-bite.html"><headline>Exxon Drilling Russian Arctic Shows Sanction Lack Bite</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Sanctions, what sanctions? </p> <p>Exxon Mobil Corp. will start drilling a $700 million well in the Arctic Ocean tomorrow, Russia''s government said, showing that for all the talk of action against Vladimir Putin''s oil industry, the largest U.S. energy company is undeterred. </p> <p>As Russia''s relations with Europe and the U.S. deteriorated to the lowest point since the Cold war over the conflict in Ukraine, the European Union imposed a third round of sanctions last week, restricting the export of equipment used for offshore oil production. That doesn''t affect Exxon''s plans because the contract to hire the rig was signed before the measures were announced. </p> <p>Developing the Arctic is vital for Russia, where energy provides half the state''s revenue, to maintain oil production near a post-Soviet high of more than 10 million barrels a day. For Exxon, where output fell to a five-year low in the second quarter, a discovery would offer a vital new source of crude. </p> <p>The well is very important, it''s probably one of the most interesting wells in the global oil industry for many years, James Henderson, a senior research fellow at the Oxford Institute for Energy Studies, said in a phone interview. </p> <p>After more than two years'' planning Exxon and its partner OAO Rosneft, Russia''s state oil producer, will start drilling the Universitetskaya prospect tomorrow, the Kremlin said in a statement today. Putin will give the signal to start Russia''s northernmost well accompanied by Rosneft Chief Executive Igor Sechin, who''s subject to U.S. sanctions himself, and Exxon Mobil Russia head Glenn Waller. </p>




Photographer: Andrey Rudakov/Bloomberg

<p>
President Vladimir Putin will give the signal to start Russia''s northernmost well accompanied by Rosneft Chief Executive Igor Sechin, seen here, who''s subject to U.S. sanctions himself, and Exxon Mobil Russia head Glenn Waller. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Stephen Bierman" date="Aug 08, 2014  5:16 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-08/exxon-to-start-exploration-well-in-russian-arctic-sea-tomorrow.html"><headline>Exxon to Start Exploration Well in Russian Arctic Sea Tomorrow</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. and its Russian
partner OAO Rosneft will start exploration drilling in Russia''s
Kara Sea tomorrow, undeterred by souring relations between the
U.S. and Russia. </p>
<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin will give the command to
begin drilling at the Universitetskaya structure tomorrow, the
Kremlin said in an e-mailed statement today. Irving, Texas-based
Exxon and Rosneft will drill using the West Alpha rig and work
will continue through October, according to the statement. </p>
<p>Relations between Russia and the U.S. have reached their
lowest point since the Cold War after Russia annexed the Crimea
and the downing of a passenger plane over war-torn Eastern
Ukraine. </p>
<p>BP Plc (BP/) is the largest shareholder in Rosneft after the
Russian state with an almost 20 percent stake in the company. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Devin Banerjee" date="Aug 11, 2014  4:43 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-11/jpmorgan-to-sell-50-of-buyout-portfolio-to-alpinvest-lexington.html"><headline>JPMorgan to Sell 50% of Buyout Portfolio to Two Buyers</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), which last
year said its private-equity unit would become independent,
agreed to sell half of its $4.5 billion in buyout holdings to
Carlyle Group LP (CG)''s AlpInvest Partners BV and Lexington Partners
Inc. </p>
<p>Dealmakers at One Equity Partners LLC will form OEP Capital
Advisors LP, an investment firm independent from New York-based
JPMorgan, when the transaction is completed, which is expected
by year-end, according to a statement today. OEP will manage the
rest of the portfolio, JPMorgan said. Financial terms of the
agreement weren''t disclosed. </p>
<p>Wall Street firms are unloading parts of their businesses
as regulations require that they bolster capital and reduce
investments made with their own money. JPMorgan, whose Chief
Executive Officer Jamie Dimon said in December he''s pruning
divisions the bank doesn''t need, last month agreed to sell about
$1.3 billion of loans and securities to Bain Capital LLC''s
Sankaty Advisors LLC. </p>
<p>The sale of One Equity Partners'' holdings isn''t expected to
have a material impact on JPMorgan''s earnings, the company said
in the statement. </p>
<p>Lexington, based in New York, raised $7 billion in 2011 for
a fund to buy stakes in buyout funds, a practice known as
secondary private-equity investing. AlpInvest, a Dutch manager
of funds-of-funds and secondary stakes with $52 billion in
assets under management, is a unit of Washington-based Carlyle,
the second-largest manager of investment alternatives to stocks
and bonds. </p>




Photographer: Jason Alden/Bloomberg

<p>
Jamie Dimon, chief executive officer of JPMorgan Chase  Co. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Aug 11, 2014  1:14 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-11/jpmorgan-said-to-consider-moving-site-of-nyc-headquarters.html"><headline>JPMorgan Considers Moving Site of NYC Headquarters</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the biggest U.S. bank, is considering moving its headquarters within New York as the company has fewer employees in the nation''s largest city, according to a person briefed on the discussions. </p> <p>The potential plans, which include taking office space in Manhattan developments at the World Trade Center or Hudson Yards, are in early stages and no decision is imminent, said the person, who asked not to be identified because the talks are private. JPMorgan has moved back-office jobs to New Jersey, Delaware and Florida to cut expenses, the person said. </p> <p>Banks, under pressure to boost returns, have been seeking lower-cost locations for employees who don''t interact directly with clients. JPMorgan is examining its property holdings in New York, where it had 11.4 million square feet (1.1 million square meters) at the end of 2013, including 1.3 million at its 270 Park Ave. headquarters. </p> <p>JPMorgan sold its 60-story skyscraper at 1 Chase Manhattan Plaza last year to Shanghai-based Fosun International Ltd., and began moving 2,000 employees to offices in Brooklyn''s MetroTech Center this year. JPMorgan owns the Park Avenue building as well as the former headquarters of Bear Stearns Cos. at 383 Madison Ave., which it acquired in 2008. </p>




Photographer: Ron Antonelli/Bloomberg

<p>
People stand inside the lobby of the JPMorgan Chase  Co. headquarters building in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Julia Verlaine" date="Aug 12, 2014 10:22 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-12/jpmorgan-appoints-bischoff-as-chairman-of-europe-arm.html"><headline>JPMorgan Appoints Bischoff as Chairman of Europe Arm</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) appointed Win Bischoff chairman of its main legal entity in Europe, the Middle
East, and Africa as British regulators press banks to bolster
oversight of their operations. </p>
<p>Bischoff will replace Tom Hoppe in January 2015 if approved
by the board, according to a memo from Daniel Pinto, 51, head of
the global corporate and investment bank and chief executive
officer of Europe, Middle East and Africa. The 73 year-old will
first serve as a director as well as an independent adviser of
the London branch''s oversight committee. </p>
<p>The decision to appoint Bischoff comes at a time when
British regulators are seeking to restore confidence in a
industry that has been hit by a series of scandals ranging from
rigging benchmark interest rates to foreign exchange. JPMorgan
agreed to accords valued at $23 billion in 2013 to resolve
probes into mortgage-bond sales, claims it failed to stop
Bernard Madoff''s Ponzi scheme and faulty oversight of a U.K.-
based trader known as the London Whale. </p>
<p>The non-executive directors of JPMorgan Securities are
central to our firm''s international governance, providing an
independent perspective and input to the overall way we run our
business, Pinto said in the memo. </p>




Photographer: Chris Ratcliffe/Bloomberg

<p>
JPMorgan Chase  Co. appointed Win Bischoff chairman of its main legal entity in Europe, the Middle East, and Africa. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bloomberg News" date="Aug 12, 2014 10:09 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-12/morgan-stanley-says-hong-kong-shanghai-stock-gaps-to-end.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Says Hong Kong-Shanghai Stock Gaps to End</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The days of paying different prices
for the same stock in Hong Kong and Shanghai are numbered,
according to Morgan Stanley. </p>
<p>Valuation gaps between dual-listed shares will disappear as
an exchange link between the two cities leads to the creation of
a one-China market, Jonathan Garner, the head of Asia and
emerging-market strategy at Morgan Stanley, said in a Bloomberg
Television interview in Hong Kong today. Yuan-denominated A
shares on the mainland are valued at a discount of about 7
percent versus Hong Kong counterparts, known as H shares,
according to the Hang Seng China AH Premium Index. </p>
<p>We''re looking for A-H stock price convergence, Garner
said. Over time, the gaps will effectively come down to
zero, he said. </p>
<p>While the Shanghai Composite Index (SHCOMP) has rebounded 11 percent
since mid-March on speculation government stimulus will revive
growth in the world''s second-largest economy, the gauge has
lagged behind a 20 percent surge in the Hang Seng China
Enterprises Index (HSCEI) of H shares. The planned tie-up, scheduled to
start around October, will give foreign investors unprecedented
access to the mainland market while opening a route for wealthy
Chinese investors to buy Hong Kong stocks. </p>
<p>Trading rules for A shares through the exchange link needs
to be more similar to Hong Kong for investors to be interested,
the city''s brokers told Shanghai bourse executives at a meeting
today, said Martin Sin, an assistant to lawmaker Christopher
Cheung, who represents securities firms. Hong Kong brokers want
day trading of A shares when the link starts, he said. </p>
<h2>Bourses Link </h2>
<p>The Shanghai Composite dropped 0.1 percent to close at
2,221.60 today, while the Hang Seng China index added 0.2
percent. The Hang Seng China AH Premium Index slid 1 percent to
92.32, signaling a widening gap between dual-listed stocks. </p>
<p>The $5.5 billion iShares China Large-Cap ETF, which tracks
Hong Kong-listed securities, slipped 0.4 percent to $40.86 at
9:51 a.m. in New York. </p>
<p>The Shanghai measure jumped to an eight-month high
yesterday as a report showed inflation was subdued last month,
giving policy makers more scope to ease policy. Data tomorrow
will probably show industrial output growth in July kept pace
with June''s 9.2 percent gain, which was the biggest for a single
month since December, while growth in fixed-asset investment
excluding rural households picked up to 17.4 percent in the
first seven months, according to Bloomberg News surveys. </p>
<p>Valuation gaps between the two exchanges reached the widest
since 2006 on July 23 as mainland investors exited the stock
market and international money managers awaited details of the
exchange tie-up. </p>
<h2>HSBC, AIA </h2>
<p>A survey conducted by CLSA Asia-Pacific Markets of 401
mainland investors showed 77 percent of them aren''t interested
in investing in Hong Kong stocks through the link. The biggest
obstacle is the minimum account requirement of 500,000 yuan
($81,222), CLSA analysts David Murphy and Lei Chen wrote in a
report dated yesterday. </p>
<p>Nearly half of them say the threshold is too high, the
analysts wrote. If there were no funding threshold, the share
of potential investors could expand to over 90 percent. </p>
<p>While the system won''t be perfect, the exchanges are
pushing forward because the tie-up will help open up China''s
markets and boost Hong Kong''s role as a global financial hub,
Charles Li, the chief executive officer of Hong Kong Exchanges 
Clearing Ltd., wrote in a blog posting this week. </p>
<p>HSBC Holdings Plc (HSBA) and billionaire Li Ka-Shing''s Cheung Kong
Holdings Ltd. (1) are two Hong Kong-traded companies attractive to
mainland investors, CLSA and Morgan Stanley (MS) said. Cheung Kong
and HSBC, Europe''s biggest bank by market value, along with AIA
Group Ltd. (1299), the second-largest Asia-based insurer, offer very
interesting geographic exposure that you can''t get onshore,
Garner said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Aug 12, 2014 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-12/morgan-stanley-s-tirupattur-to-lead-debt-research-in-u-s-.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley''s Tirupattur to Lead Debt Research in U.S.</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS), owner of the world''s
biggest brokerage, promoted Vishwanath Tirupattur to a newly
created post leading U.S. fixed-income research. </p>
<p>Tirupattur, 52, will continue in his role as global head of
securitized products strategy, Neil McLeish, global head of
fixed-income research, wrote in an internal memo obtained by
Bloomberg News. Lauren Bellmare, a spokeswoman for the New York-based company, confirmed the memo''s contents. </p>
<p>Research that''s seen as superior can lure clients to trade
with a firm, a potential boost to Morgan Stanley''s plan to focus
on high-volume flow trading that uses less capital. The bank
generated $2.67 billion in fixed-income trading revenue in the
first six months of the year, about half that of competitors
such as Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and Bank of America Corp. </p>
<p>Tirupattur joined Morgan Stanley in 2004, after working at
insurer Chubb Corp., according to Financial Industry Regulatory
Authority records. He wrote in a note last week that a recent
slump in the U.S. high-yield market may lead to lower prices for
mezzanine tranches of collateralized loan obligations. </p>
<p>Matt Hornbach, who leads research of rates products, Sivan Mahadevan, who heads corporate credit, and Rashique Rahman,
leader of foreign exchange and emerging markets, will report to
Tirupattur in addition to reporting to McLeish, according to the
memo. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Harris and Neil Weinberg" date="Aug 13, 2014  3:48 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-13/jpmorgan-chase-accused-of-self-dealing-in-managing-church-trust.html"><headline>JPMorgan Accused of Self-Dealing in Managing Church Trust</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) was sued for
fraud, self-dealing and mismanagement of trust accounts
established for an Indianapolis church endowed by the
descendants of drug company founder Eli Lilly. </p>
<p>The Christ Church Cathedral sued JPMorgan today in
Indianapolis federal court, claiming it selected unsuitable and
poorly-performing investments to further its own financial
interests. The Episcopal church founded in 1837 accused the
world''s fourth-biggest bank by asset value of breaching state
and federal securities laws. </p>
<p>The bank caused the church trusts to lose approximately
$13 million in value as a result of JPMorgan''s decisions to
purchase over 177 different investment products, mostly from
itself, using church funds, between July 2004 and December
2013, the plaintiffs said in the complaint. </p>
<p>The congregation seeks unspecified compensatory and
punitive damages. The lawsuit comes five days after a Bloomberg
News report that the Securities and Exchange Commission is
reviewing whether conflicts of interest led JPMorgan to sell
certain investment products to individual clients, according to
a person briefed on the matter. </p>
<h2>Guided Architecture </h2>
<p>Banks can capture a greater portion of fees by having
clients invest in their own products. The Christ Church
Cathedral alleged JPMorgan employed a guided architecture
platform through which it selected products based on their
profitability to the bank. </p>
<p>Kristen Chambers, a spokeswoman for the New York-based
bank, declined to comment on the church lawsuit. </p>
<p>JPMorgan put between 68 percent and 85 percent of the
church''s assets into its own products, including private equity
funds, structured notes and hedge funds, according to the
complaint. </p>
<p>Christ Church claims JPMorgan made more money on some of
the financial products it bought for the church, even as the
trusts bore all of the risk. During one seven-year stretch
ending in 2013, according to the complaint, the trusts, which
were worth as much as $39.2 million, declined to $31.6 million,
according to the filing. </p>
<p>At the same time, JPMorgan''s holdings increased by $1.4
trillion and its net revenue more than doubled, the church
claimed. </p>
<p>The case is Rector, Wardens and Vestrymen of the Christ
Church Cathedral of Indianapolis v. JPMorgan Chase  Co., 14-cv-01331, U.S. District Court, Southern District of Indiana
(Indianapolis). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ben Elgin" date="Aug 13, 2014  1:30 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-13/chevron-puts-hawaiian-solar-projects-on-ice.html"><headline>Chevron Puts Hawaiian Solar Projects on Ice</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>     Aug. 13 (Bloomberg Businessweek) -- Chevron has taken
another step away from its renewable-energy efforts, putting a
pair of solar projects at its Kapolei refinery in West Oahu,
Hawaii, on indefinite hold. </p>
<p>The tabled projects, first reported earlier this week by
Pacific Business News, include a farm of solar panels that would
have spanned almost five acres, supplying as much as 1 megawatt
of electricity to the local utility. Chevron also shelved a
demonstration solar thermal project, which would have covered
about 15 acres and used mirrors to generate steam to help power
the Hawaii refinery. </p>
<p>In recent months, Chevron, the second-biggest oil company in
the U.S., has quietly been pulling back from renewable-energy
endeavors, despite a long-promoted commitment to develop what its
corporate website calls newer, cleaner ways to power the world. </p>
<p>In May, Bloomberg Businessweek reported that Chevron
shuttered a business unit that had surpassed internal profit
targets by helping to launch large-scale solar and geothermal
power projects. In June, we wrote about the sale of its key
renewable-energy subsidiary, Chevron Energy Solutions, to Oaktree
Capital Management. </p>
<p>Each of the Hawaii projects would have reduced carbon
dioxide emissions by about 5,000 tons and contributed to Hawaii''s
goal of generating 70 percent of its energy from renewable
sources by 2030, according to Chevron''s filings with the state. </p>
<p>Instead, they''re being put on hold as the oil company
focuses its resources on other projects, such as its $54 billion
liquefied natural gas plant in Australia, a company spokesman
told Pacific Business News . </p>
<p>Reached by e-mail, Chevron spokesman Kent Robertson
confirmed that the company has put its Hawaiian solar plants on
hold. </p>
<p>Chevron''s pullback on renewables has come amid increasing
concern that climate change and carbon constraints threaten
fossil-fuel companies. Many organizations, including the
International Energy Agency, estimate that as much as two-thirds
of fossil-fuel reserves will need to remain unburned if the world
is to avoid the most severe consequences of climate change.</p>
<p></p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lyubov Pronina and Natasha Doff" date="Aug 13, 2014  7:29 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-13/morgan-stanley-sees-bond-rout-propelling-buybacks-russia-credit.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Sees Russian Bond Rout Propelling Buybacks</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Russian companies are set to seize
on sliding asset prices to buy back their bonds, helping stem
the third-biggest rout in emerging markets, according to Morgan
Stanley and Erste Sparinvest. </p>
<p>Steelmaker OAO Severstal and Far East Shipping Co., whose
cash piles both amount to 1.1 times short-term debt obligations,
are among companies with an incentive to buy back bonds,
Morgan Stanley said in a report two days ago. Corporate notes
slid 5 percent since new U.S. penalties limited access of some
Russian companies to dollar funding on July 16, the most after
Ukraine and Venezuela among more than 50 countries in the
Bloomberg USD Emerging Market Corporate Bond Index. (BEMC) </p>
<p>European Union sanctions late last month further curbed
appetite for Russian assets amid a worsening of the crisis in
Ukraine, leaving companies grappling for new funding sources.
Severstal, which in May repurchased $288 million of two
Eurobonds, is considering using about $1 billion of proceeds
from an asset sale to lower debt, including possibly a buyback,
Chief Executive Officer Alexey Mordashov said on July 30. </p>
<p>It could put a very strong floor in the market, Peter Varga, who manages $750 million in emerging-market corporate
bonds at Erste Sparinvest in Vienna, said by e-mail yesterday.
It''s basically a good option to buy back bonds trading at a
discount. </p>
<h2>Bond Selloff </h2>
<p>Severstal''s $750 million of securities due in October 2022
slid as much as 4.37 cents from July 16 to a three-month low of
94.50 cents on Aug. 7, sending the yield up to 6.79 percent. The
2018 debt of Far East Shipping lost 14.9 cents to 67.5 cents in
the period. </p>
<p>There will be some cash-rich, non-sanctioned corporates
using this opportunity to buy back debt, thus providing some
support for Russian corporate credit, Morgan Stanley said in its
research note. </p>
<p>The press office for Far East Shipping declined to comment
in e-mailed responses to questions from Bloomberg News.
Severstal''s press service declined to comment. </p>
<p>Buybacks will help companies lower debt and boost
accounting gains, particularly if they expect the conflict in
Ukraine will get resolved, Lutz Roehmeyer, who helps manage
about $1.1 billion of emerging-market assets at Landesbank
Berlin Investment GmbH, said by e-mail yesterday. </p>
<h2>No Visibility'' </h2>
<p>In the market rout that followed President Vladimir Putin''s
annexation of Ukraine''s Crimea peninsula in March, companies
including Severstal turned the slump in asset prices to their
advantage by repurchasing debt. </p>
<p>While companies may benefit in the short term, a prolonged
standoff poses risks, according to Roehmeyer and Dorothea Froehlich, a Zurich-based money manager at MainFirst Schweiz AG. </p>
<p>Russia retaliated last week against sanctions with a food-import ban on products from the U.S., EU, Australia, Canada and
Norway. Tension escalated yesterday as Ukraine blocked a Russian
aid convoy from crossing into its territory. </p>
<p>There is no visibility on how long the standoff with the
West will continue, Froehlich, who helps oversee $750 million
in emerging-market assets, including Russian corporate bonds,
said by e-mail yesterday. In such an environment, you don''t
want to spend cash. You hoard it. </p>
<p>OAO Gazprom Neft, which was listed in Morgan Stanley''s
note, sees no benefit from buying back bonds, Chief Financial
Officer Alexey Yankevich said on a conference call yesterday.
OAO Phosagro, another company cited in the report, doesn''t plan
to buy back Eurobonds, the company''s press service said
yesterday. The fertilizer producer''s bonds due in February 2018
fell 4.1 cents on the dollar this month to 94.8 cents by 3:22
p.m. in Moscow. </p>
<p>It''s basically a good option to buy back bonds for
companies with surplus funds, or those having low indebtedness
with good cash flow and with good access to financing, Varga of
Erste Sparinvest said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael P. Regan" date="Aug 14, 2014  1:08 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-14/goldman-expertise-can-t-help-momentum-funds-gain-momentum.html"><headline>Goldman Expertise Can''t Help Momentum Funds Gain Momentum</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>There are simple exchange-traded
fund strategies (buy gold) and more-ambitious exchange-traded fund strategies (dynamically allocate across a basket
of assets based on historical price momentum and volatility.) </p>
<p>ALPS Distributors Inc. offers simple ETFs like the U.S. Oil
Fund (strategy: buy oil, basically) as well as the more-ambitious varieties, such as those of the dynamically allocating
persuasion. Except investors weren''t allocating funds to those
ambitious ETFs in a dynamic fashion, even though they were
advertised as a way to gain access to Goldman Sachs''
expertise. As a result ALPS is euthanizing them. </p>
<p>So here is their obituary: The ALPS/GS Momentum Builder
Index ETF series, an ambitious group of securities that
attempted to outsmart the market by licensing Goldman Sachs
Group Inc. strategies based on historical price momentum,
volatility and correlation, died this month after a lifelong
battle with investor disinterest. They were less than 2 years
old. </p>
<p>None of the four ETFs has more than about $3.4 million in
assets. While not all of them performed terribly, neither did
they perform, uh, dynamically. Which is kind of sad, really, if
you believe in old-fashioned notions like the powers of math and
that the biggest brains on Wall Street can outfox the mailman
who puts his whole 401(k) into the Vanguard 500 Index Fund. </p>
<h2>Wet Screens </h2>
<p>Now, some may shake their fists in the air and curse at a
market perceived to be hypnotized into marching in a straight
line by the magic wand of the Federal Reserve. And maybe that''s
a fair reaction, but at the end of it all you''re left with is
tired fist and maybe some spittle on three or four of your
computer screens. </p>
<p>Anyway, here''s what the back of the baseball cards would
look like for the Goldman-inspired funds (for comparison, note
that the SP 500 -- arguably not the best benchmark to compare
each of these to, but let''s do it anyway --  has returned about
40 percent including dividends since these ETFs started trading
in December 2012): </p>
<p>*The ALPS/GS Risk-Adjusted Return U.S. Large Cap Index ETF (GSRA)
did the best since inception, returning 38 percent, less than
the 41 percent gain in the Russell 1000 Index from which it
picks its stocks. Selection criteria included average analyst
price estimates adjusted by volatility, with sectors showing
lower anticipated risk getting a higher allocation. Its expense
ratio is 0.55 percent, compared with 0.15 percent for the
iShares Russell 1000 ETF. Top holdings: Pharmacyclics Inc.,
Cameron International Corp., Biomarin Pharmaceutical Inc. and
Madison Square Garden Co. (Goldman''s risk modelers are,
presumably, not Knicks fans.) </p>
<h2>Baseball Cards </h2>
<p>*The ALPS/GS Momentum Builder Multi-Asset Index ETF (GSMA)
returned 9.5 percent since inception and had an expense ratio of
0.68 percent. This is an ETF squared since it only holds
four other ETFs tracking real-estate, emerging markets stocks,
Treasuries maturing in more than 20 years and Latin American
equities. </p>
<p>*The ALPS/GS Momentum Builder Growth Markets Equities and
U.S. Treasuries Index ETF. This baseball card will not be a
collector''s item: the fund has returned negative 11 percent
since inception. It holds ETFs tracking stocks in India, Brazil,
Turkey and Indonesia and just a dash (0.2 percent) of long-maturity Treasuries. </p>
<p>*The ALPS/GS Momentum Builder Asia ex-Japan and U.S.
Treasuries Index ETF lost 2.7 percent on a total-return basis
since inception. </p>
<p>On consideration of current market conditions, as well as
prospects for growth in the funds'' assets, the board determined
that it was in the best interests of the funds and their
shareholders to liquidate the funds'' shares, ALPS said
yesterday in statement. </p>
<p>For sure, the ALPS/GS offerings aren''t the only momentum
funds struggling to catch lightning in a bottle from past high-flying stocks. The $12.4 million SPDR SP 1500 Momentum Tilt ETF (MMTM)
has returned 42 percent since its inception in 2012, which is
pretty sweet but not as sweet as the almost 44 percent return
for the SP 1500 itself. Neither have the $313 million iShares
MSCI USA Momentum Index ETF or the AQR Momentum Fund blown the
doors off large, mid and small-cap benchmarks since their
inceptions. </p>
<p>The 16 U.S. momentum ETFs have a total of $3.7 billion in
assets yet have only taken in $57 million this year, according
to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>The lesson to take away, if it''s not obvious by now, is
that catching lightning in a ETF jar is not easy no matter how
dynamically you allocate. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Gavin Finch" date="Aug 14, 2014 12:05 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-14/goldman-sachs-said-to-hire-eu-bank-specialist-from-u-k-treasury.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Said to Hire EU Bank Specialist From U.K. Treasury</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) hired
European financial policy specialist Martina Garcia from the
U.K. Treasury, according to a person with knowledge of the move. </p>
<p>Garcia will become the firm''s only Brussels-based employee
when she starts in September, said the person, who declined to
be identified because the appointment has not been made public.
Garcia is currently a deputy director in the Treasury''s
financial services group with responsibility for developing
policy on European Union banking reform and financial stability. </p>
<p>The European Commission and European Council are based in
Brussels, making it the main center for originating and
discussing financial rules in the 28-nation bloc. The EU
agencies are in the process of overhauling banking and
securities markets rules, from derivatives trading to bonuses
and capital requirements, in a series of reforms that began in
2010 after the crisis. </p>
<p>Garcia will report to Martine Doyon, the bank''s head of
government affairs for Europe, the Middle East and Africa, said
the person. Doyon also joined Goldman Sachs from a public role,
leaving Britain''s Financial Services Authority in 2011 to head
the bank''s EU government affairs department. </p>
<p>Officials for the Treasury and Goldman Sachs declined to
comment. Garcia didn''t return a call to her office. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ellen Rosen" date="Aug 14, 2014  8:29 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-14/jpmorgan-barclays-s-p-argentina-amazon-compliance.html"><headline>JPMorgan, Barclays, S&amp;amp;P, Argentina, Amazon: Compliance</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>An Indianapolis church sued JPMorgan
Chase  Co. (JPM), accusing the bank of fraud, self-dealing and
mismanagement of its trust accounts. </p>
<p>The Christ Church Cathedral claimed the world''s fourth-biggest bank selected unsuitable and poorly performing
investments to further its own financial interests and, as a
result, breached both state and federal securities laws. </p>
<p>The bank caused the church trusts to lose approximately
$13 million in value as a result of JPMorgan''s decisions to
purchase over 177 different investment products, mostly from
itself, using church funds, from July 2004 to December 2013,
the plaintiffs said in the complaint filed yesterday. </p>
<p>The trusts were endowed by the descendants of drug company
founder Eli Lilly. </p>
<p>The lawsuit came five days after Bloomberg News, citing a
person briefed on the matter who asked to remain anonymous,
reported that the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission is
reviewing whether conflicts of interest led JPMorgan to sell
certain investment products to individual clients. </p>
<p>Kristen Chambers, a spokeswoman for the New York-based
bank, declined to comment on the church lawsuit. </p>
<p>The case is Rector, Wardens and Vestrymen of the Christ
Church Cathedral of Indianapolis v. JPMorgan Chase  Co., 14-cv-01331, U.S. District Court, Southern District of Indiana
(Indianapolis). </p>
<p>For more, click here. </p>
<h2>Compliance Action </h2>
<h2>U.S. Banks Said to Get Enforcement Letters in FX-Rigging Probes </h2>
<p>Banks including JPMorgan Chase  Co., Citigroup Inc. (C) and
Morgan Stanley (MS) have been notified that regulators are preparing
enforcement actions on currency rigging, people familiar with
the investigation said. </p>
<p>Talks are progressing between banks, the U.S. Federal
Reserve and the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency to
settle investigations into alleged manipulation of foreign-exchange markets, according to two people who asked not to be
identified because the discussions are private. Some firms have
received so-called 15-day letters outlining the agencies''
findings and warning that enforcement actions are likely, the
people said. </p>
<p>Enforcement actions can range from cease-and-desist orders
to fines to banning bankers from the industry. The letters
typically detail the investigators'' findings and give recipients
about 15 days to offer a written defense. Such notices usually
open a final stage of settlement negotiations. </p>
<p>U.S. regulators are coordinating with the U.K.''s Financial
Conduct Authority to settle some of the probes by November,
according to two people. The FCA is in settlement talks with
firms including Barclays Plc, Citigroup, HSBC Holdings Plc,
JPMorgan, Royal Bank of Scotland Group Plc (RBS) and UBS AG. It
scheduled meetings with some banks for as soon as next month to
discuss penalties, the people said. </p>
<p>A few investigations are taking longer, and talks with
firms such as Bank of America Corp. and HSBC haven''t progressed
as far, according to some of the people. </p>
<p>For more, click here. </p>
<h2>Corinthian Subpoenaed for Records on Student Outcomes, Debt </h2>
<p>Corinthian Colleges Inc. (COCO), the for-profit chain in the
process of selling or shutting its campuses, received a federal
grand jury subpoena seeking records on student-loan defaults and
job placement. </p>
<p>The Aug. 8 subpoena also seeks information on graduation
rates, the transferability of student credits and marketing
materials, according to a regulatory filing yesterday. </p>
<p>Corinthian, which served about 72,000 students as of last
month when it agreed to a government plan to shut down or sell
its 107 campuses, is facing allegations in multiple states of
falsifying job placement and marketing data. The Santa Ana,
California-based company is evaluating the subpoena and intends
to cooperate fully with the request, according to the filing. </p>
<p>Corinthian''s downfall accelerated in June when the U.S.
Education Department imposed a 21-day waiting period for it to
draw on the federal student aid that accounts for almost all its
revenue. </p>
<p>There can be no assurance that the company will be able
to obtain any such additional needed liquidity on a timely
basis, on terms acceptable to it, or at all, Corinthian said
in yesterday''s filing. </p>
<h2>Barclays Seen Facing $2 Billion More in 2014 Conduct Charges </h2>
<p>Barclays Plc (BARC) faces costs of as much as 1.2 billion pounds
($2 billion) for its alleged rigging of currency markets, lying
to clients about its U.S. dark pool and mis-selling interest-rate swaps, Sanford C. Bernstein Ltd. said. </p>
<p>The U.K.''s second-largest lender may incur a 700 million-pound charge to settle a foreign-exchange probe with regulators
and a further 200 million pounds relating to a U.S.
investigation into its private-trading venue, Chirantan Barua,
an analyst at Bernstein in London, said in a note yesterday. The
bank might reach settlements by the end of 2014, he said. </p>
<p>Barclays is part of a group of banks in talks with the
U.K.''s Financial Conduct Authority to reach a settlement in the
currency-rigging probe, while fighting a U.S. lawsuit accusing
it of falsifying marketing materials to hide the presence of
high-frequency traders in its dark pool. </p>
<p>The scandals are undermining Chief Executive Officer Antony
Jenkins''s attempts to reform the culture of a bank after it was
fined 290 million pounds in 2012 for rigging the Libor benchmark
interest rate. </p>
<p>London-based Barclays may also set aside 300 million pounds
in the second half to compensate customers improperly sold
interest-rate hedging products, Barua estimates. The bank didn''t
make further provisions for redress in the first half. </p>
<p>Other British lenders are also struggling with rising
provisions for misconduct. Royal Bank of Scotland Group Plc,
Britain''s largest state-owned lender, may face as much as 1
billion pounds in charges to settle the allegations of currency
market manipulation, Barua wrote in an separate Aug. 11 report. </p>
<p>For more, click here. </p>
<h2>Lawsuit News </h2>
<h2>SP Accuses U.S. of Withholding Documents in Fraud Lawsuit </h2>
<p>The U.S. is withholding documents that might show the
government sued Standard  Poor''s for fraud in retaliation for
downgrading the country''s debt, the ratings company said in a
court filing this week. </p>
<p>In April, a federal judge ruled that SP could seek
potential evidence from the Justice Department. Since then, the
government has turned over documents with redactions ranging
from the omission of a single word on a page to multiple pages,
SP said in court documents filed Aug. 12 seeking to compel
production. </p>
<p>The case is U.S. v. McGraw-Hill Cos., 13-cv-00779, U.S.
District Court, Central District of California (Santa Ana). </p>
<p>For more, click here. </p>
<h2>Paul Singer Gets OK to Follow Argentina Money Trail to Nevada </h2>
<p>Billionaire Paul Singer, the hedge fund founder seeking to
collect on more than $1.5 billion in judgments over Argentina''s
defaulted bonds, may search Nevada for some of that money, a
judge ruled. </p>
<p>Singer asked a Las Vegas court in April to order 123
companies in Nevada to turn over information about assets
belonging to Argentine businessman Lazaro Baez, who is accused
in that country of embezzling $65 million from government
contracts. U.S. Magistrate Judge Cam Ferenbach in Reno granted
that request Aug. 11, ruling that Singer''s hedge fund was
attempting to execute a valid judgment against Argentina. </p>
<p>There is no doubt that the 123 companies are shell
corporations, Ferenbach said in an order. Similarly, there
is no doubt that shell corporations are routinely formed to
commit fraud. </p>
<p>Singer''s decade-long quest to recoup on investments in
Argentina''s debt peaked last month when the country went into
default for the second time in 13 years after talks broke down
with some creditors. Singer leads a group of hedge funds owed
more than $1.5 billion from the country''s 2001 default. A
federal judge in New York barred Argentina from paying on
restructured debt until it satisfies Singer''s group. </p>
<p>In his order, Ferenbach wrote that Argentina''s failure so
far to satisfy judgments won by Singer''s NML Capital has caused
the company to travel the globe in search of property owned by
Argentina. </p>
<p>The case is NML Capital Ltd. v. Argentina, 14-00492, U.S.
District Court, District of Nevada (Las Vegas). </p>
<p>For more, click here. </p>
<h2>Interviews </h2>
<h2>Amazon''s Prices Seen Holding Regulators at Bay in Hachette Spat </h2>
<p>Amazon.com Inc. (AMZN)''s treatment of customers means more to U.S.
antitrust authorities than how the largest Web retailer
pressures publishers and movie studios. </p>
<p>Typically it''s seen as a good thing for a retailer to
pressure suppliers to trim prices, as that can lead to better
deals for shoppers, David Balto, a former policy director at the
Federal Trade Commission, said in an interview with Bloomberg
News. </p>
<p>The antitrust cops clearly would be on Amazon''s
doorstep if it was also pushing those suppliers to charge
competing retailers more, he said. Successfully going after
Amazon at this stage would be breaking new territory under the
antitrust laws. </p>
<p>That hasn''t damped debate about the tactics Chief Executive
Officer Jeff Bezos is using against Hachette Book Group, Walt
Disney Co. and film studio Warner Bros. The question is whether
he''s pushing Amazon toward the same monopolistic territory that
tripped up Microsoft Corp., Standard Oil and ATT Inc. </p>
<p>They are getting very close to the line, said Joseph
Tabacco, a former senior trial lawyer at the Justice Department
who has worked on federal monopoly and price-fixing cases
against mining, electronics and pharmaceutical companies. </p>
<p>A phone call left at Seattle-based Amazon''s press office
wasn''t immediately returned. </p>
<p>Amazon, the world''s largest Web retailer, commands 60
percent of the U.S. e-book sales, a market that is projected to
jump almost sevenfold to $8.6 billion as demand for paper books
falls, according to Forrester Research Inc. </p>
<p>For more, click here. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Barinka and David McLaughlin" date="Aug 15, 2014  6:37 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-15/ibm-gets-u-s-approval-for-sale-of-server-business-to-lenovo.html"><headline>IBM Obtains U.S. Approval for Sale of Server Business to Lenovo</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM) cleared a U.S. national-security review for the sale of
its low-end server business to China''s Lenovo Group Ltd. (992),
letting the $2.3 billion transaction go forward even amid
tensions between the two nations. </p>
<p>The conclusion of the review by the Committee on Foreign
Investment in the U.S., or Cfius, is good news for both IBM
and Lenovo, and for our customers and employees, Armonk, New
York-based IBM said yesterday in a statement. While Cfius placed
some conditions on the deal, they don''t significantly affect the
business, and terms of the transaction didn''t change as result,
a person with knowledge of the matter said, without specifying
the conditions. </p>
<p>The sale drew scrutiny because of disputes between China
and the U.S., the world''s two largest economies, over
cyberintrusions. By completing the deal, IBM can jettison a less
profitable business to focus on growing areas, such as cloud
computing and data analytics, while giving Lenovo a bigger piece
of the global computing-hardware market. </p>
<p>This is part of IBM''s process moving away from hardware
manufacturing to a more service-oriented product line and more
profitable product lines, Ivan Feinseth, chief investment
officer at Tigress Financial Partners LLC, said in an interview.
They are trying to change the direction they are going. He
has a neutral rating on IBM stock. </p>
<p>Spokesmen for IBM and Lenovo declined to comment on whether
the Cfius clearance included any requirements or concessions.
Holly Shulman, a spokeswoman for the Treasury Department, which
leads Cfius, declined to comment. </p>
<h2>Essentially Commodities </h2>
<p>The IBM servers, known as x86 for the type of chips they
use, link computers on corporate networks and are essentially
commodities in the information technology world, Christopher Padilla, IBM''s vice president for governmental programs, said in
January. Most of IBM''s x86 servers are made in Shenzhen, China,
he said. </p>
<p>The clearance of the national-security review may also bode
well for Lenovo''s separate $2.91 billion purchase of Google
Inc.''s Motorola Mobility unit. </p>
<p>We continue to work through a number of regulatory and
business processes to ensure an effective and timely closure on
both deals, Lenovo, which has its headquarters in Beijing and
Morrisville, North Carolina, said in a statement. We remain on
track to close both deals by the end of the year. </p>
<h2>Maintenance Continues </h2>
<p>U.S. agencies, including the Defense Department and the
Department of Homeland Security, buy the IBM servers, according
to Bloomberg Intelligence. The companies were able to head off a
lot of government concerns on the x86 deal because IBM has
agreed to continue maintenance on existing servers for five
years, said the person with knowledge of the matter, who asked
not to be identified because the process was private. </p>
<p>The Cfius review took 150 days to complete, with the
companies forced to resubmit the transaction after an initial
75-day investigation expired, the person said. Cfius asked
hundreds of questions during the probe, primarily focusing on
maintenance of installed IBM servers and Lenovo''s access to
them, while also paying heed to heightened concern and scrutiny
about any Chinese transaction in the U.S. technology sector, the
person said. </p>
<p>Cfius examines acquisitions of U.S. companies by foreign
investors to determine the effects on national security. The
U.S. on May 19 accused five Chinese military officials of
stealing trade secrets and other information from American
companies. </p>
<h2>More Examination </h2>
<p>Lenovo was successful in getting Cfius approval in 2005 for
an earlier deal, in which the Chinese company acquired IBM''s
personal-computer unit for $1.25 billion. </p>
<p>Cfius examined more than double the number of transactions
by Chinese investors in 2012 than it did the previous year,
making them the most scrutinized foreign buyers of American
assets ahead of the U.K., according to the committee''s most
recent report to Congress. </p>
<p>Lenovo had agreed to pay a fee more than double the typical
size should it fail to acquire IBM''s low-end server unit, people
familiar with the matter said in January. The breakup charge of
about $200 million, according to one of the people, highlights
the risk the Chinese company has chosen to bear for its largest-ever purchase. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Brendan Coffey" date="Aug 15, 2014  4:15 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-15/coca-cola-s-stake-buy-makes-monster-founders-billionaires.html"><headline>Coca-Cola''s Stake Buy Makes Monster Founders Billionaires</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Rodney Sacks and Hilton Schlosberg wanted to get into the packaging business. Frustrated in their attempt to find a company to buy, the partners took a tip from an investment banker and purchased debt-laden soda maker Hansen Natural Corp. in 1992. </p> <p>Two decades, a name change and a whole lot of caffeine later, the partners have emerged as billionaires as their company, Monster Beverage Corp. (MNST), agreed to sell a 17 percent stake to Coca-Cola Co. (KO) yesterday for $2.15 billion. The stock jumped 30 percent to $93.49 at 4:15 p.m. today in New York. </p> <p>The deal gives Coca-Cola greater exposure to the energy drinks market, one of the fastest-growing segments in the beverage industry, having doubled in sales since 2007, according to Euromonitor International Ltd. The carbonated soft drinks category, which includes offerings from PepsiCo Inc. (PEP) and Coca-Cola, expanded just 0.3 percent in 2013. </p> <p>If you look across mature beverage categories, it''s impossible to find someone with a growth rate that does not let up like Monster Beverage''s, said Jeffrey Klineman, editor of trade publication BevNet. </p> <p>The company''s main product, Monster Energy, has sold more than 10 billion units since its introduction in 1997. It has almost four times the amount of caffeine as Coke, according to the website Caffeine Informer. </p>




Photographer: Patrick T. Fallon/Bloomberg

<p>
Monster has 34.3 percent share of the energy drink market to Red Bull''s 33.9 percent, according to a Monster presentation to investors in January. Last year, Monster started a protein drink, Muscle Monster. In a nod to its natural soda roots, it introduced a kale flavored Hansen-brand soda earlier this year. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jiyeun Lee and Kyung-Jin Kim" date="Aug 17, 2014 11:41 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-17/jpmorgan-s-lee-sees-won-rising-to-pre-lehman-levels-on-surplus.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sees Won Rising to Pre-Lehman Levels on Surplus</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>South Korea''s record current-account
surplus will boost the won to levels prior to the 2008 global
credit crisis, JPMorgan Chase  Co.''s Seoul branch manager said. </p>
<p>The won will climb past 1,000 per dollar as local equities
attract inflows, Managing Director Lee Sung Hee said in an Aug.
14 interview, without specifying a timeframe. The U.S. bank''s
Singapore-based strategist Daniel Hui predicts a 1.8 percent
gain to 1,000 by end-December. The median estimate in a
Bloomberg survey of 31 analysts is for a 0.7 percent decline to
1,025 in the same period. </p>
<p>The currency has advanced 3.1 percent this year as global
funds pumped $27.7 billion into South Korean bonds and stocks.
The central bank last month raised its 2014 forecast for the
current-account excess to an unprecedented $84 billion from $68
billion. The Bank of Korea''s decision last week to lower
borrowing costs in support of the government''s efforts to revive
economic growth won''t deter capital inflows, Lee said. </p>
<p>It would be difficult for the won to weaken given a
current-account surplus of this size, Lee, who is also
JPMorgan''s head of global emerging markets in Korea, said in his
office in Seoul. Gains in the stock market will spur inflows,
adding appreciation pressure on the won. </p>
<p>The won rose 0.3 percent from Aug. 14 to 1,017.75 per
dollar as of 12:19 p.m. in Seoul, according to prices from local
banks. Korean financial markets were closed for a public holiday
on Aug. 15. The currency rallied 0.8 percent on Aug. 14, the
most since April, as the central bank cut its key interest rate. </p>
<h2>Currency Forecasts </h2>
<p>The nation''s currency last traded at 1,000 per dollar in
July 2008, before Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. filed for
bankruptcy, triggering a crisis in global credit markets. </p>
<p>Hui, the JPMorgan strategist, predicts that after reaching
1,000 by September, the won will remain at that level through
the end of 2014 before climbing to 995 by March and to 985 in
June. The median forecasts in the Bloomberg survey are for the
currency to reach 1,020 in the first quarter of 2015 and 1,017
in the second. </p>
<p>South Korea''s finance ministry unveiled a 11.7 trillion won
($11.5 billion) spending program on July 24 after cutting its
2014 growth forecast to 3.7 percent from 3.9 percent. The
ministry plans to encourage companies to boost dividend payouts. </p>
<p>One of the government''s policy goals is to raise the
wealth effect by boosting prices of asset such as equities,
JPMorgan''s Lee said. </p>
<p>The benchmark Kospi (KOSPI) index of shares gained 2.7 percent this
quarter, more than the 1.5 percent increase in the MSCI Asia
Pacific Index of regional equities. </p>
<h2>Stimulus Measures </h2>
<p>The central bank reduced its key interest rate from 2.5
percent to 2.25 percent on Aug. 14, the first cut since May
2013. The move will help boost the effectiveness of the
government''s stimulus, Governor Lee Ju Yeol said the same day. </p>
<p>The fiscal spending package, along with the central bank''s
policy easing, will encourage foreign inflows by supporting
growth and boosting equities, Morgan Stanley strategists
including Geoffrey Kendrick in Hong Kong wrote in an Aug. 14
report. </p>
<p>Lower borrowing costs won''t discourage overseas bond
investors as central banks and sovereign wealth funds tend to
focus on long-term economic fundamentals, according to the
report. Global central banks accounted for 42 percent of foreign
investment in South Korean bonds as of end-2013, data from the
finance ministry show. </p>
<h2>Volatility Seen </h2>
<p>While the won will appreciate over the long term, the
currency may face increased volatility due to geopolitical
tension in Ukraine and slower economic growth in Europe,
according to JPMorgan''s Lee. </p>
<p>One-month implied volatility in the won, a gauge of
expected swings in the exchange rate used to price options, has
risen 125 basis points, or 1.25 percentage points, this quarter
to 5.90 percent today. </p>
<p>A certain amount of foreign-exchange volatility can be
beneficial to traders and companies, Lee said. Too little
volatility tends to lead to overreactions by investors if the
exchange rate moves beyond a certain range. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alan Katz, Jesse Drucker and Irina Reznik" date="Aug 18, 2014 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-18/morgan-stanley-enabled-rosneft-as-no-1-until-crimea-grab.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Enabled Rosneft as No. 1 Until Crimea Grab</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Long before the Ukraine crisis ruptured U.S.-Russian relations, Vladimir Putin and his right-hand man, Igor Sechin, hosted then-Morgan Stanley Chief Executive Officer John Mack at an exclusive reception at Putin''s Novo-Ogaryovo estate outside Moscow. </p> <p>According to the Kremlin, Putin thanked Mack and a few other foreign bankers at the October 2006 gathering for leading the $10 billion initial public offering of OAO Rosneft, the state-controlled oil giant headed by Sechin. He then chatted with the bankers for an hour in a formal meeting room. </p> <p>Putin and Sechin have a lot more to thank Morgan Stanley for. The American investment bank helped transform state-owned Rosneft from a business the Russian government failed to sell three times in 1998 into the world''s biggest publicly traded oil producer by output. Morgan Stanley played a key role in saving it from being acquired, and Rosneft hired three consecutive chief financial officers from the bank. In 2013, Putin approved Mack''s appointment to Rosneft''s board. </p> <p>Since the Soviet Union broke up a quarter-century ago, Russia has become so closely entwined with the global economy that doing anything to unwind those ties -- or successfully impose sanctions for misbehavior -- is proving difficult for the U.S. and its allies, and awkward for western businesses that embraced Putin''s Russia. With Sechin and his oil company both under U.S. sanctions, a look at the courtship, marriage, and now separation between Morgan Stanley and Rosneft is a telling microcosm of this turnabout. </p>




Photographer: Alexei Druzhinin/RIA Novosti via Bloomberg

<p>
Vladimir Putin, left, greets then-Morgan Stanley Chief Executive Officer John Mack, right, at the Eighth International Investment Forum in Sochi, on Friday, Sept. 18, 2009. In 2013, Putin personally approved Mack''s appointment to the Rosneft board, which paid $580,000 a year. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Isabel Reynolds" date="Aug 19, 2014 11:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-19/goldman-lauds-japan-defense-shares-on-abe-push-chart-of-the-day.html"><headline>Japan Defense Shares Beats National Benchmark as Abe Beefs Up Military: Chart</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Defense-related shares in Japan beat the national benchmark and U.S. peers since Prime Minister Shinzo Abe came to power and embarked on a policy to strengthen the military and lower barriers to arms exports. </p> <p>The CHART OF THE DAY tracks defense gauges for Japanese, American and European equities and counterpart geographic benchmarks normalized from Dec. 14, 2012, just before Abe led an election victory, through Aug. 18. Goldman Sachs''s new Japan defense measure of 20 companies was the biggest gainer at 72 percent, with the Topix index next at 60 percent. In each pairing, the aerospace-military group beat the broader index, which also included the Standard  Poor''s 500 and FTSE Eurotop 100. </p> <p>Since we expect the defense theme to become a long-term secular theme in the Japanese market, we see scope for improved relative performance ahead for related stocks, Goldman Sachs analysts led by Chief Japan Equity Strategist Kathy Matsui said last week in a research note to unveil the gauge. Mitsubishi Heavy Industries Ltd., Kawasaki Heavy Industries Ltd. and Toshiba Corp. are among the component stocks. </p> <p>Boosting Japan''s military capabilities has been one of the focuses of the Abe government, amid a territorial dispute with an increasingly assertive China. In 2013 Abe increased the defense budget for the first time in 11 years, and this year relaxed an effective ban on defense exports. Even with the changes, defense spending will account for less than 1 percent of gross domestic product, compared with 4 percent in the U.S. and 1.3 percent in China, according to estimates by Japan''s Ministry of Defense. </p>




Photographer: Yuriko Nakao/Bloomb

<p>
National Defense Academy of Japan (NDA) cadets dismantle and reassemble rifles during a class at the NDA campus in Yokosuka, Kanagawa Prefecture, Japan. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jeremy Hodges" date="Aug 19, 2014  8:53 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-19/goldman-sachs-drops-bid-to-throw-out-libyan-wealth-fund-suit.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Drops Bid to End Libyan Wealth Fund Suit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) abandoned
its bid to get a U.K. court to throw out a $1 billion lawsuit by
the Libyan Investment Authority that alleged the New York-based
bank made about $350 million selling it investments that turned
out to be worthless. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs had asked a London judge in April to decide
that the case didn''t have a realistic chance of success and to
issue a so-called summary judgment dismissing the suit, the
sovereign wealth fund said in a statement today. The bank has
withdrawn the request, LIA said. </p>
<p>The application was misconceived and issued purely for
tactical reasons, including a desire to delay the determination
of the LIA''s claims, the fund said. </p>
<p>Libya''s sovereign wealth fund is one of dozens of small
companies and government agencies that have sued lenders over
deals the investors claim were too complicated to understand. It
also sued Societe Generale SA (GLE) in a $1.5 billion lawsuit, saying
that the French bank paid about $58 million to a friend of the
Qaddafi family to secure investments. </p>
<p>We continue to believe this case is entirely without
merit and intend to contest it vigorously as it moves through
the legal process, Goldman Sachs said in an e-mailed
statement. </p>
<p>A London court hearing is scheduled to take place in early
October, the fund said. </p>
<p>The case is: The Libyan Investment Authority v. Goldman
Sachs International, case no. 14-310, High Court of Justice,
Chancery Division. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lisa Abramowicz and Michael J. Moore" date="Aug 20, 2014  4:49 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-20/goldman-sachs-credit-sales-co-head-shaffer-to-leave-at-year-end.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Credit Sales Co-Head Shaffer to Leave</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>John Shaffer, a former Penn State
University quarterback who''s spent more than two decades on Wall
Street, is departing Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) as co-head of New
York credit sales. </p>
<p>Shaffer, 49, will leave at the end of the year after
joining in 2007 as a managing director, according to an internal
memo obtained by Bloomberg News and confirmed by Tiffany Galvin,
a Goldman Sachs spokeswoman. </p>
<p>Avanish Bhavsar, head of cross-asset sales, and Jon Meltzer, who''s now co-head of investment-grade, high-yield and
municipal bond sales, will become co-heads of U.S. credit sales,
according to another internal memo. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs has shuffled its sales leadership as trading
revenue fell 12 percent in the first half of the year, the fifth
consecutive first-half decline. The New York-based firm this
month named Stacy Bash-Polley, 45, to lead management of its
client relationships across trading. </p>
<p>Meltzer and Bhavsar, who will also continue to oversee
cross-asset sales, will report to Tom Cornacchia, 51, global co-head of sales for fixed-income, currency and commodities.
Salespeople typically call on trading clients to pitch products
and ideas and help manage orders. </p>
<h2>National Championship </h2>
<p>Shaffer, who previously worked at Merrill Lynch  Co. for
17 years, was known to customers and traders partly because of
his background as a football player for Penn State. In 1986, he
quarterbacked the team to a 12-0 season, winning the national
championship with a 14-10 victory over the University of Miami
in the Fiesta Bowl in January 1987. </p>
<p>He said that playing on the team under Joe Paterno was
tougher than working on Wall Street, according to an October
2011 article. </p>
<p>That pressure, that competition I tried to replicate on
Wall Street, but I just couldn''t, he said at the time. </p>
<p>He joined Goldman Sachs as head of the high-yield and
distressed sales group and was named to his current role in
2012, according to one of the memos. </p>
<p>In 2010, Shaffer was promoted to partner, Goldman Sachs''s
highest rank, in a nod to its history as a private partnership
before going public in 1999. Meltzer and Bhavsar were also named
partners four years ago. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs is the fourth-most active underwriter of U.S.
corporate bonds this year, up from fifth last year, according to
data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>(An earlier version of this story corrected the spelling of
Merrill Lynch.) </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Aug 20, 2014 11:18 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-20/goldman-sachs-said-to-raise-junior-staff-salaries-20-.html"><headline>Goldman Said to Boost Salaries for Junior Staff About 20%</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), which cut the portion of revenue set aside for pay the past two years, will increase 2015 salaries for junior employees in the U.S. by about 20 percent, according to a person briefed on the decision. </p> <p>The raises will apply to employees in all divisions with the title of analyst, typically recent college graduates, said the person, who asked not to be identified speaking on personnel matters. The increase won''t affect bonuses, which are based on the firm''s and employees'' performance. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs and other Wall Street firms have been cutting hours and attempting to improve working conditions for junior bankers as the companies seek to prevent defections to competitors such as private-equity funds. Investment banks including Credit Suisse Group AG and Bank of America Corp. have encouraged analysts to take time off on weekends. </p> <p>Related:</p>
Millennial Bankers Get Raises as Firms Fight Defections
Hedge-Fund Director Bonuses Drop 94% as Returns Decline
BofA Joins Goldman Raising Salaries for Junior Bankers
<p>Morgan Stanley is raising salaries for associates and vice presidents in its investment-banking and underwriting units worldwide by about 25 percent, a person briefed on the matter said last month. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs''s salary increase will bring some first-year analysts'' annual base pay to about $85,000, the person said. Such employees typically are paid $70,000 to $90,000 in salary, with bonuses bringing total compensation to as much as $140,000, according to New York-based consultant Johnson Associates Inc. The junior-banker title doesn''t refer to research analysts who recommend stocks to investors. </p> <h2>Weekend Work </h2> <p>Andrew Williams, a Goldman Sachs spokesman, declined to comment. The New York Post reported on the pay increases earlier today. </p> <p>In 2012, Goldman Sachs decided to stop offering two-year contracts to investment-banking analysts, instead making them full-time employees from the start. Last year, it discouraged them from working weekends and pledged to hire more junior workers to prevent overloading. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs set aside 37 percent of revenue for pay last year, down from 38 percent in 2012 and 42 percent in 2011. The ratio was 43 percent in the first half of 2014, the same as a year earlier. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dalia Fahmy" date="Aug 20, 2014  6:09 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-20/goldman-goldentree-to-acquire-144-u-k-travelodge-hotels.html"><headline>Goldman, Goldentree to Acquire 144 U.K. Travelodge Hotels</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), Goldentree
Asset Management LP and Avenue Capital Group LLC, which acquired
Travelodge Hotels Ltd. in a debt restructuring in 2012, agreed
to buy 144 U.K. hotels leased to the company. </p>
<p>The hotels, located in London and southeast England, are
owned by Lloyds Banking Group Plc (LLOY), Prestbury Investment Holdings
Ltd., West Coast Capital and Aldersgate Investments, Travelodge
said in an e-mail today. The deal is valued at about 500 million
pounds ($830 million), the London-based Times reported today
without saying where it got the information. A spokeswoman for
closely held Travelodge wouldn''t comment on the price. </p>
<p>Travelodge is adding properties and renovating its
buildings in an effort to improve profitability. A group of
creditors comprising Goldman Sachs, Avenue Capital and
GoldenTree took ownership of the company in 2012 from Dubai
International Capital in a debt-for-equity swap. </p>
<p>We are well on our way to building a new Travelodge,
Chief Executive Officer Peter Gowers said in the e-mail. In
the past 18 months we have invested 57 million pounds in
modernizing our hotels, helping us attract more business
customers. </p>
<p>The budget-hotel chain, based in Thame, England, operates
500 hotels and 38,000 rooms in the U.K., Ireland and Spain,
according to its website. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David Fickling" date="Aug 20, 2014  3:36 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-20/coca-cola-amatil-flags-drop-in-full-year-earnings-as-costs-rise.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Amatil Flags Earnings Drop as Costs Rise</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Coca-Cola Amatil Ltd. (CCL) flagged a
second consecutive drop in full-year earnings amid weak consumer
confidence and rising costs in Indonesia. Its shares fell the
most in more than two months. </p>
<p>Earnings before interest and tax fell 12 percent from a
year earlier to A$317 million ($295 million) in the six months
ended June 30, Australia''s largest beverage company said in a
regulatory statement today. Net income fell 16 percent to its
lowest first-half level in three years. </p>
<p>Declining profits add to pressure on new Managing Director
Alison Watkins, who''s reviewing the company''s businesses and
considering new products. She faces domestic price competition
as Asahi Group Holdings Ltd. sells Pepsi as much as 33 percent
cheaper than Coke. Annual net income last year hit a 21-year low
due to a A$404 million writedown at its packaged-foods unit. </p>
<p>Amatil needs to make considerable price investments, to
cut its differential over Pepsi, Michael Simotas, an analyst at
Deutsche Bank AG in Sydney, wrote in an Aug. 6 note to clients.
The increasing negativity toward sugar and the resultant
reduction in consumption remains a key concern. </p>
<p>The shares declined 2.1 percent to A$9.54 at the close of
trading in Sydney, the sharpest fall since June 5. The stock has
slumped 21 percent this year, compared to a 5.3 percent
improvement in the benchmark SP/ASX 200 index. </p>
<p>Full-year earnings will be materially below those
during the 12 months ended December, with revenue falling in its
alcoholic drinks unit and competition and costs hitting its
Indonesian business. The company is trying to cut A$100 million
of costs over the next three years, it said today. </p>
<h2>Low-Calorie Drinks </h2>
<p>Sydney-based Coca-Cola Amatil will offer more low and no-calorie drinks in future as a result of a strategic review
announced after Watkins took over its top job. </p>
<p>As a business we have been slow to adapt to these changes
in market conditions and shifting consumer trends, she said in
today''s statement. </p>
<p>Net income in the period was A$182 million, compared with
the A$173 million average of three analysts'' estimates compiled
by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ari Natter" date="Aug 21, 2014  3:12 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-21/microsoft-leaves-lobbying-group-alec-amid-split-over-renewables.html"><headline>Microsoft Leaves Lobbying Group ALEC Amid Split Over Renewables</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Bloomberg BNA -- Microsoft Corp. has left the American Legislative Exchange Council because of concerns about the lobbying group''s opposition to renewable energy, a coalition of activist investor groups said.</p><p>The Sustainability Group and Walden Asset Management, asset management companies that describe themselves as focused on sustainable investing, said Microsoft confirmed in e-mails that it''s no longer a part of ALEC after the groups pressed the company to abandon it.</p><p>Microsoft is a leader on carbon issuesin 2012, it committed to becoming carbon neutral, and is one of the largest corporate purchasers of renewable energy, the Boston-based groups said in a news release. Thus, we believe that its affiliation with ALEC, which is actively fighting policies that promote renewable energy, was incongruous. In addition, there were numerous other ALEC actions that conflicted directly with Microsoft''s values.</p><p>Arlington, Va.-based ALEC has drafted model legislation for use in state legislatures to roll back renewable fuel standards across the country. Its members include ExxonMobil Corp., Peabody Energy Inc., American Electric Power Co. and Koch Industries Inc., according to the Checks and Balances Project, a nonprofit watchdog group that supports the use of clean energy.</p><p>In response to a request for comment, Microsoft told Bloomberg BNA: In 2014, Microsoft decided to no longer participate in the American Legislative Exchange Council (ALEC) Communications and Technology Task Force. Our trade association memberships are determined annually on a case by case basis and are based on a number of factors, including evolving policy priorities, business needs and available budgets.</p><h2>Question of Budget Cuts</h2><p>Bill Meierling, a spokesman for ALEC, said Microsoft left the organization July 16 for budgetary reasons and not as a result of the group''s positions on renewable energy.</p><p>They left because of budget cuts. They are rearranging their government relations here in D.C., Meierling said in an interview with Bloomberg BNA. This is groups opposed to ALEC up to their old tricks.</p><p>Microsoft announced July 17 it planned to eliminate as many as 18,000 jobs, the largest round of cuts in its history, Bloomberg News reported.</p><p>The Sustainability Group, along with Walden Asset Management, said in a joint news release Aug. 19 that they began pressing Redmond, Wash.-based Microsoft to leave ALEC in 2013.</p><p>According the groups, Microsoft, which had been a member of ALEC''s Communications and Technology Task Force, sent an e-mail on July 14 that said, We are no longer members of ALEC and do not provide the organization with financial support of any kind.</p><h2>E-Mail Called Part of Ongoing Dialogue</h2><p>In an interview, Timothy Smith, Walden Asset Management''s senior vice president and director of environmental social and governance shareowner engagement, said the e-mails, which the group sent to investors last month, were part of an ongoing dialogue Walden had been having with Microsoft.</p><p>It was an ongoing debate inside the company, Walden said of the company''s participation in ALEC.</p><p>Walden, which manages $8 billion in assets, considers Microsoft one of its major holdings, Smith said.</p><p>ALEC approved model legislation for the 2013 legislative session designed to be used to repeal states'' renewable portfolio standards and wrote a new version for 2014.</p><p>The standards, which exist in 29 states, have been credited with being one of the largest drivers of renewable energy generation in the U.S. and are expected to drive more than 40,000 megawatts of renewable electricity generation by 2015, according to the Energy Department.</p><p>According to the Environmental Protection Agency, 50 percentor more than 1.3 billion kilowatt hoursof the power used by Microsoft annually comes from renewable energy sources, including biogas, biomass, solar and wind. That makes it No. 3 on the EPA''s list of top companies that voluntarily use renewables.</p><h2>Called Example to Others</h2><p>Microsoft has demonstrated a commitment in recent years to clean energy and climate action by introducing an internal carbon fee and purchasing large amounts of wind energy to power two of its data centersall actions which run contrary to ALEC''s goal of killing the clean energy economy, Greenpeace Senior IT Policy Analyst Gary Cook said in a statement.</p><p>Google, Facebook, eBay, Yahoo, Yelp and other technology companies that are currently still ALEC members would do well to learn from Microsoft''s leadership, Cook said.</p><p>Other major corporations that have left ALEC include Coca-Cola, General Motors, Bank of America and Procter  Gamble, according to Common Cause, a Washington group that has challenged ALEC''s status as a nonprofit organization.</p><p>According to Common Cause, the exodus began in 2011 after public exposure related to the group''s development of proposals to block renewable energy, as well as other issues such as restrictive voter ID requirements, anti-union measures and Stand Your Ground gun bills.</p><h2>Consumers Should Decide Energy Choices</h2><p>Meierling said ALEC continues to grow and isn''t opposed to renewable energy specifically. Rather, Meierling said, the group believes consumers, not mandates, should decide consumer energy choices.For more about Bloomberg BNA, click here.</p><p>Visit www.bloomberg.com/sustainability for the latest from Bloomberg News about energy, natural resources and global business</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Subhadip Sircar, Anurag Joshi and Shikhar Balwani" date="Aug 21, 2014  6:21 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-21/jpmorgan-said-to-have-led-record-buying-of-india-bonds-yesterday.html"><headline>JPMorgan Said to Have Led Record Buying of India Bonds Yesterday</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. bought about
$2.4 billion of Indian government bonds yesterday, leading
record purchases by international banks, according to three
fixed-income dealers in Mumbai. </p>
<p>Foreign lenders acquired a net 148 billion rupees ($2.4
billion) of sovereign debt yesterday, the most in Clearing Corp.
of India Ltd. data going back to 2006. JPMorgan may have
purchased the notes on behalf of institutional clients, the
dealers said, asking not to be identified as the information
isn''t public. Mollica Senapati, a spokeswoman in Mumbai for the
U.S. bank, declined to comment on the matter in an e-mailed
response to questions. </p>
<p>Global funds pumped in an unprecedented $13.8 billion into
local government and corporate bonds in 2014 as India''s success
in reining in inflation and stabilizing the rupee added to
optimism the nation''s new government will spur economic growth.
JPMorgan''s purchases made up about 90 percent of the $2.76
billion pumped in by overseas money managers yesterday, exchange
data show. </p>
<p>The purchases represent a significant amount for the bond
markets, said Anindya Das Gupta, Mumbai-based treasurer at
Barclays Plc. A stable currency, easing inflation and the
fiscal intent of the government are helping to boost the global
appetite for Indian bonds. </p>
<p>The yield on the benchmark 8.4 percent sovereign securities
due July 2024 dropped five basis points, or 0.05 percentage
point, yesterday to 8.48 percent, the lowest level this month.
That''s the biggest decline in a week. </p>
<h2>Rupee, Inflation </h2>
<p>The rupee has rebounded 13 percent from a record low of
68.845 per dollar reached a year ago, the world''s best-performing currency in the period, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. Consumer-price inflation in India slowed to 7.96
percent in July from as much as 11.2 percent in November. </p>
<p>Finance Minister Arun Jaitley aims to reduce the budget
deficit to 4.1 percent of gross domestic product, which would be
the least since 2008, in the year through March 2015, according
to official estimates released last month. </p>
<p>JPMorgan''s bond purchases were executed across different
maturities in the afternoon trading session, the dealers said.
All other categories of investors, including public and private
banks, mutual funds and primary dealers, were net sellers of the
securities yesterday, the Clearing Corp. data show. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Aug 22, 2014  7:52 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-22/goldman-sachs-partners-ownership-at-lowest-since-2010.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Partners'' Ownership at Lowest Since 2010</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) partners
cut their ownership of the firm to the lowest level since 2010
by exercising options dating from the financial crisis, as the
total reaped this year from such awards nears $400 million. </p>
<p>The partners owned 8.52 percent of the New York-based
company''s shares on Aug. 13, down from 9.45 percent in May,
according to a regulatory filing today. Individuals exercised
options from July 16 to Aug. 12 that yielded $107 million after
covering the cost of the options and some tax withholding, the
filing shows. </p>
<p>The conversions bring the total netted by partners this
year from the 2008 options to about $390 million, as the
employees benefited from a doubling in the firm''s stock price
since the financial crisis. The options vested over three years
ended in January 2012, and shares gained through such awards
couldn''t be sold until this year. </p>
<p>In December 2008, Goldman Sachs granted 36 million options
in an effort to give top performers an incentive to stay after
the bank reduced compensation expense by almost half during the
credit crunch. More than 34 million of those options were still
outstanding at the end of 2013. The partners have exercised
almost 9 million of the options this year, according to filings. </p>
<p>The awards were granted at an exercise price of $78.78. The
shares closed this week at $175.47 in New York, after climbing
more than 38 percent each of the past two years. The partners
also sold $77.4 million of shares unrelated to the options,
according to the filing. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael P. Regan" date="Aug 22, 2014 11:37 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-22/goldman-data-show-hedge-funds-can-t-find-way-out-of-mall.html"><headline>Goldman Data Show Hedge Funds Can''t Find Way Out of Mall</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Hedge-fund managers, it turns out,
are really like a bunch of grown-up mall rats. </p>
<p>That''s the conclusion one could draw from Goldman Sachs
Group Inc.''s report on trends in the alternative-investment
industry. Managers continue to allocate about 20 percent of
assets to shares in companies dependent on discretionary
consumer spending. In the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index, their
weighting is only 12 percent. </p>
<p>That group of 85 stocks, from Walt Disney Co. to Nike Inc.
and Yum! Brands Inc., was up 2.4 percent this year compared with
an almost 8 percent gain in the SP 500 as of yesterday. As a
result, many hedge-fund managers, like teenagers who spent too
much time in the mall, are bringing home some lousy report
cards. The industry has returned 1 percent so far this year,
according to Goldman''s Aug. 20 report. </p>
<p>Consistent large allocations to retail and media stocks
in the consumer discretionary sector have been headwinds to
returns, Goldman strategists including Ben Snider and David Kostin wrote. </p>
<p>The smaller dispersion of returns within the group isn''t
helping matters, Goldman notes. There was a 94 percentage point
gap between the SP 500''s best performing consumer-discretionary
stock this year (Under Armour Inc.) and the worst (Coach Inc.)
as of today''s open. That sounds like a lot, but not really when
you compare it with the 217 percentage points that separated the
top winner from the loser at this time of year in 2013. </p>
<h2>First, Worst </h2>
<p>Still the current dispersion, second only to energy shares
among the 10 main SP 500 groups, makes it easy to see why this
is a tough group to quit. And, obviously, not everyone''s a bull,
especially after government data showed consumer spending
stalled in July. </p>
<p>Another report from research firm Markit this week showed
demand to borrow shares of retailers in the SP 500 has climbed
to a one-year high. As the back-to-school season kicks into full
gear, Abercrombie  Fitch Co., Kohl''s Corp. and Five Below Inc.
are among retail stocks showing increases in short interest,
according to Markit. </p>
<p>Goldman serves as sort of a Jane Goodall to hedge-fund
managers, journeying deep into the Excel jungles to learn more
about these exotic creatures and report back to us on their
mysterious ways. The additions and deletions to their indexes of
most-important longs and shorts shows where the action has been
in the consumer space. </p>
<h2>Longs, Shorts </h2>
<p>Dollar General Corp. and DirecTV were added to their basket
of very-important longs, while News Corp. and Constellation
Brands Inc. were dropped. In the very important short basket,
Keurig Green Mountain Inc. and Home Depot Inc. were added, while
DirecTV, Kohl''s and McDonald''s Corp. were dropped. </p>
<p>Perusing the full list, it''s clear that hedge-fund managers
are scattered out across the entire mall, rather than clustered
at a few stores. </p>
<p>Anyway, one theory for their 20 percent weighting in
consumer discretionary could be that hedge fund managers are
wisely getting in front of a pickup in spending and subsequent
rally in the shares. Another theory could be that one is not in
the best position to gauge retail traffic trends if they''re able
to take a helicopter to the mall. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Aug 26, 2014 11:28 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-26/goldman-partners-bott-shalett-depart-ahead-of-new-class.html"><headline>Goldman Partners Bott, Shalett Depart Ahead of New Class</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)''s list of
so-called partners dropped to 409, the lowest in almost two
years as the firm is set to name a new class at the end of this
year. </p>
<p>Alison Bott, 58, who ran human capital management in Asia,
and Lisa Shalett, 48, who led the firm''s brand marketing and
digital strategy, were absent from a list of partners included
in an Aug. 22 filing. The pair retired earlier this year and
will become advisory directors, according to a person briefed on
the matter, who asked not to be identified speaking on personnel
matters. </p>
<p>Cyril Cottu, who worked in currency sales, also dropped
from the list. Cottu remains with the firm, said the person. </p>
<p>Partner is the firm''s highest rank, a nod to its history as
a private partnership before going public in 1999. Such
employees typically receive a $900,000 salary and share in a
special bonus pool. The bank''s partnership committee, led by
Vice Chairman Michael Sherwood, selects an additional class
every other year, including 70 new members in 2012. </p>
<p>The number of partners will fall further before the new
class is added. Executives including Canada head Jack Curtin,
63, and John Shaffer, who ran credit sales in New York, have
announced their intentions to leave at the end of the year. </p>
<p>Shalett worked at Goldman Sachs since 1995, including roles
in equity sales and as chief operating officer of compliance,
legal and internal audit, according to her LinkedIn profile. </p>
<p>Cottu didn''t immediately respond to an e-mail seeking
comment, while Shalett didn''t answer phone calls to her listed
number. Attempts to locate a phone number or e-mail address for
Bott were unsuccessful. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Victoria Slind-Flor" date="Aug 26, 2014  6:43 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-26/disney-rovio-ikea-paltrow-sirius-xm-intellectual-property.html"><headline>Rovio, Ikea, Paltrow, Sirius: Intellectual Property</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The Walt Disney Co. (DIS), operator of the
Disneyland and Walt Disney World amusement parks, is seeking
patents on the use of drones in its parks for entertainment
purposes. </p>
<p>According to three patent applications published Aug. 21 in
the database of the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office, the
company would use unmanned aerial vehicles to project streams of
colored light, to support flexible projection screens, or to
support and manipulate articulated marionettes in the air. </p>
<p>The drones would follow predetermined flight paths and
would have a local controller operating them through a series of
points defined by the flight plan. </p>
<p>The applications are 20140231590, 20140233099 and
20140236388. Burbank, California''s Disney applied for all three
in February 2013. </p>
<p>For more patent news, click here. </p>
<h2>Trademark </h2>
<h2>Rovio Fails to Derail Angry Bite'' Trademarks in Singapore </h2>
<p>Rovio Entertainment Oy, maker of the Angry Birds video
game, failed in its challenge to a trademark used in Singapore
by a Malaysian maker of snack food, MediaCorp''s ChannelNewsAsia
website reported. </p>
<p>The Espoo, Finland-based game creator claimed that Kimanis
Food Industries SDN BHD''s Angry Bite mark was too similar to
Angry Birds and would confuse the public, according to
ChannelNewsAsia. </p>
<p>Singapore''s registrar of trademarks said that in addition
to the absence of visual or conceptual similarity between the
marks, purchasers of Angry Bite products are self-selected and
likely to exercise care as they select the items they are
buying, ChannelNewsAsia reported. </p>
<h2>Ikea Wins Dismissal of Trademark Suit by Website Operators </h2>
<p>Ikea of Sweden AB, the Swedish home-furnishings company,
persuaded a federal court in Virginia to dismiss a trademark
case brought by the operators of a website at which people can
comment about Ikea products. </p>
<p>Ikeafans Inc. of Colonial Beach, Virginia, brought the suit
May 20, seeking a declaration it wasn''t infringing the Swedish
company''s trademarks. The Virginia company said it has operated
the www.ikeafans.com website since 2005, and over the years
enjoyed a symbiotic relationship with the giant home furnishings
company. </p>
<p>After what Ikeafans said was years of collaboration and
cross-marketing Ikea said in January 2012 it couldn''t continue
to use the name, according to court papers. Ikeafans then sued
in federal court in Alexandria, Virginia. </p>
<p>U.S. District Judge Anthony J. Trenga dismissed Ikea on
Aug. 22 as the defendant in the case. He noted that the Ikeafans
website does carry ads for home furnishing companies that
compete with Ikea. </p>
<p>The case is Ikeafans Inc. v. Ikea U.S. Inc., 1:14-cv-00584,
U.S. District Court, Eastern District of Virginia (Alexandria). </p>
<p>Gwyneth Paltrow''s Goop Sued for Infringing Diet Detective'' Mark </p>
<p>Goop Inc., the website promoting a high-end lifestyle and
owned by actress Gwyneth Paltrow, was sued for trademark
infringement by the author of a work on diets and fitness. </p>
<p>In the New York federal court suit, Charles Platkin of New
York claims that Goop has infringed his trademark The Diet
Detective, which he registered with the U.S. Patent and
Trademark Office in 2007. He said Goop used Diet Detective
without license or permission beginning July 18. </p>
<p>Goop didn''t respond immediately to an e-mailed request for
comment. </p>
<p>The case is Platkin v. Goop Inc., 1:14-cv-06676, U.S.
District Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). </p>
<p>For more trademark news, click here. </p>
<h2>Copyright </h2>
<h2>Sirius Says It Didn''t Infringe Marketing Firm''s Flyer Design </h2>
<p>Sirius XM Holdings Inc. (SIRI), the satellite radio broadcaster,
denied claims in a copyright suit brought by a direct marketing
agency. </p>
<p>Chapman Cubine Adams  Hussy Inc. filed the suit in
Alexandria, Virginia, June 25, claiming that the New York-based
broadcast company infringed a design the agency used for direct-mail marketing. </p>
<p>In its response, Sirius denied it had misappropriated the
Arlington, Virginia-based marketing company''s UrgentGram
design and said it was investigating allegations it had access
to the design. The broadcaster said the allegedly infringed
design was functional, not original and in the public domain. </p>
<p>The case is Chapman Cubine Adams  Hussy Inc. v. Sirius XM
Holdings Inc., 1:14-cv-00807, U.S. District Court, Eastern
District of Virginia (Alexandria). </p>
<p>For more copyright news, click here. </p>
<h2>Trade Secrets </h2>
<h2>Ozburn-Hessey Logistics Trade Secrets Case Against 721 Fails </h2>
<p>Ozburn-Hessey Logistics LLC''s trade-secret misappropriation
claims against 10 former employees and the rival shipping
logistics company they started was dismissed by a federal judge
in Philadelphia. </p>
<p>The company filed the suit in February 2012, claiming that
the ex-employees who left to form 721 Logistics LLC in Lester,
Pennsylvania, took trade secrets and were conspiring to compete
unfairly with their former employer. </p>
<p>Ozburn-Hessey, based in Brentwood, Tennessee, said the
purloined proprietary information included client names, product
and service marketing techniques, customer pricing and discount
structures, and sales volumes and purchase patterns of the
company''s customers. </p>
<p>U.S. District Judge Felipe Restrepo dismissed the case,
saying Ozburn-Hessey''s trade-secret claims didn''t qualify as
such under Pennsylvania law. </p>
<p>There is no basis in Pennsylvania law for affording
trade-secret protection to a compilation'' that exists only in
the collective consciousness, he wrote. </p>
<p>He also dismissed the unfair-competition, breach-of-contract and conspiracy claims. The judge did reject the
defendants'' bid for attorney fees, saying they failed to state a
cause for which they could be claimed. </p>
<p>The case is Ozburn-Hessey Logistics LLC v. 721 Logistics
LLC, 12-cv-00864, U.S. District Court, Eastern District of
Pennsylvania (Philadelphia). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Raymond Colitt" date="Aug 27, 2014  4:57 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-27/goldman-joins-nomura-in-saying-silva-becoming-favorite.html"><headline>Goldman Joins Nomura in Saying Silva Becoming Favorite</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Marina Silva''s performance in the
campaign''s first televised presidential debate helped establish
trust among voters and investors, reinforcing her status as the
front-runner in Brazil''s election, analysts from Goldman Sachs
Group Inc. to Nomura Holdings Inc. said. </p>
<p>The former environment minister showed in the debate aired
last night on Bandeirantes TV that she would be reliable and
not extreme in the changes she proposes, Tony Volpon, head of
emerging markets research for the Americas at Nomura, said by
phone from New York. It makes her the odds-on favorite to win
the election. </p>
<p>Silva, who captured the support of Brazilians dissatisfied
with the political establishment and deteriorating growth when
she entered the race, now is capturing enough backing from her
competitors to beat President Dilma Rousseff in a runoff, two
polls published this week show. Equities rallied on speculation
Silva would do a better job managing the economy than Rousseff. </p>
<p>Silva has 43.7 percent support in a possible Oct. 26 second
round vote versus 37.8 percent for the incumbent, according to
an Aug. 21-24 MDA survey published today, which has a margin of
error of plus or minus 2.2 percentage points. </p>
<p>She has 45 percent of voters'' support, against 36 percent
for Rousseff,  according to an Aug. 23-25 Ibope poll published
yesterday. While both polls show Rousseff leading in the first
round, she doesn''t have the support needed to avert a runoff. </p>
<h2>Stocks Rally </h2>
<p>The Ibovespa stock exchange index rose 1.9 percent at 5:50
p.m. local time today and the real appreciated 0.6 percent to
2.2477 per U.S. dollar, the biggest increase among emerging
market currencies after the South African rand and Turkish lira. </p>
<p>Silva criticized Rousseff''s handling of the economy last
night, saying the incumbent has failed on pledges to slow
inflation and is poised to turn over the country in worse shape
than she found it. </p>
<p>She handled the debate well, Alberto Ramos, chief Latin
America economist at Goldman Sachs, said in a phone interview
when asked about Silva. Based on the polls, it''s her election
to lose. </p>
<p>Before the debate, Eurasia Group wrote in a note that the
challenge for Silva will be to transition from being a protest
vote candidate to someone voters are willing and able to trust
to govern. The political risk consulting firm wrote today the
candidate last night took a positive step toward
establishing her reputation as a credible leader. </p>
<h2>Confident, Prepared </h2>
<p>Silva was confident and prepared in going after Rousseff on
slowing growth while fielding questions on how she would forge a
majority in Congress, said Andre Cesar, director at public
policy and business strategy consulting company Prospectiva. </p>
<p>Silva said she could tap support from rival parties to form
a majority. She said she would select for her government some of
the country''s best politicians who have been forced onto the
sidelines by the ruling Workers'' Party and candidate Aecio Neves''s Brazilian Social Democracy Party. </p>
<p>She passed the first test, Cesar said. </p>
<p>Silva''s campaign team has pledged to slow inflation to 3
percent from 6.5 percent last month by the end of 2018, support
formal autonomy for the central bank and undo fiscal policies
that led to a sovereign debt rating downgrade this year. On the
social front, she says she would expand the government program
that transfers money to poor families, known as Bolsa Familia. </p>
<h2>Faster Inflation </h2>
<p>When Rousseff said that her policies have shielded the poor
and workers from the effects of an international economic
crisis, Silva retorted that faster inflation has undermined
confidence and purchasing power. </p>
<p>Silva would support inflation control, the floating
exchange rate and cut government spending, Luciano Rostagno,
chief strategist at Banco Mizuho do Brazil in Sao Paulo, said in
a phone interview. That is positive. </p>
<p>In the debate, Neves showcased his experience as the former
governor of Brazil''s second-most populous state, saying in a
reference to Silva that voters shouldn''t choose a president
whose proposals are unclear. </p>
<p>Brazil also can''t put up with new adventures, with
improvisation, said Neves, who is running third in polls. </p>
<p>She responded that voters were tired of the dominance of
her two rivals'' parties, which have ruled Brazil for 20 years. </p>
<p>We will respect the gains that were made in other
governments, she said. But we will correct the mistakes. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Stephanie Baker" date="Aug 28, 2014  6:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-28/goldman-new-madrid-landlord-as-investors-return-to-spain.html"><headline>Goldman New Madrid Landlord as Investors Return to Spain</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Marcelino Calvo Sanchez and his wife, Maria Luisa, had never heard of Goldman Sachs Group Inc. until last year, when the global investment bank bought the four-building housing estate where they live in Vallecas, on the southern outskirts of Madrid. Marcelino, a 71-year-old retired truck driver, isn''t impressed by his new landlord. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs picked up the 289-unit complex in August 2013 as part of its purchase of 3,000 low-income apartments from the regional government of Madrid for 201 million euros ($269 million). With the sale, some subsidies for tenants disappeared, and, according to Sanchez, a small problem with squatters has become a larger one. </p> <p>We don''t want to live with squatters, Sanchez says. This has become a business -- it''s not a social program anymore. </p> <p>That''s exactly right, Bloomberg Markets will report in its October issue. Though the housing estate looks like one of the last places in the world smart-money Goldman Sachs bankers would bet on -- glass doors are shattered, broken mailboxes hang open, and graffiti mars the courtyard walls -- this is where Goldman has touched down in the Spanish real estate market. Blackstone Group LP, the world''s largest alternative-asset manager, bought a similar low-income-housing portfolio from the city of Madrid in July 2013 for 125 million euros. </p>




Photographer: Ricardo Labougle/Bloomberg Markets

<p>
This building in Madrid''s Vallecas neighborhood  is part of a 125 million euro portfolio of low-income housing purchased in 2013 by Blackstone Group LP. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lisa Abramowicz" date="Aug 28, 2014 11:58 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-28/jpmorgan-s-380-billion-man-won-t-let-bubble-get-him-down.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s $380 Billion Man Won''t Let Bubble Get Him Down</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>All those bond investors fretting
about a bubble will probably be right eventually. In the
meantime, they may want to think about buying some junk debt. </p>
<p>That''s how Bob Michele, who oversees $380 billion as
JPMorgan Asset Management''s chief investment officer for fixed
income, is approaching the market. Just because yields on
speculative-grade debt are falling toward the lowest ever,
that''s not a good enough reason to avoid it, he said. </p>
<p>Ultimately there will be a bubble, Michele said in a
Bloomberg Television interview on Aug. 26. As for now, he said,
there''s only so long that you''re going to sit in cash earning
a zero percent return in the U.S., perhaps a negative yield in
Europe, before you go back into some form of bonds. </p>
<p>Michele isn''t alone in seeing value in junk bonds despite
Federal Reserve Chair Janet Yellen''s suggestion that the market
has gotten frothy. While high-yield notes in the U.S. posted a
1.3 percent loss last month, their first in almost a year,
they''ve bounced right back with a 1.5 percent gain in August,
Bank of America Merrill Lynch index data show. </p>
<p>The reason yields are so low is because of the Fed''s easy
money policies, which are ongoing (even if a little scaled
back). </p>
<p>So why leave now when the party''s still good? </p>
<h2>Not Much Upside </h2>
<p>It''s understandable why investors would be wary of plunging
into less-creditworthy debt right now. Junk-rated bonds are
yielding 5.9 percent as measured by Bank of America Merrill
Lynch index data. That''s about 0.2 percentage point from the
all-time low, meaning potential returns are significantly less
than the historic average. </p>
<p>While mutual-fund investors yanked a record $7.1 billion
from the debt in the week ended Aug. 6, they''ve since had a
change of heart, plowing $2.9 billion back into the funds in the
two weeks since, according to data provider Lipper. </p>
<p>Everybody has been lulled into this comforting notion
that between a Goldilocks economy, not lifting off but not
collapsing, and the Fed being the market''s best friend, it''s OK
to leverage every risk factor, Mohamed El-Erian, former chief
executive officer of Pacific Investment Management Co. and
Bloomberg View columnist, said in an interview last week. </p>
<p>Everybody''s in the same trade, he said. If sentiment
changes, there''s no shock absorber in the system. </p>
<p>Call it a game of chicken, where investors wait as long as
they can before slipping out just before everybody else runs for
the exits. Or perhaps another case of don''t fight the Fed, which
has pledged to keep benchmark rates low for a prolonged period. </p>
<p>Typically you see bubbles at the end of Fed tightening,
when the Fed has withdrawn liquidity from the system, Michele
said. </p>
<p>That''s not happening yet. So for now, game on. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hugh Son" date="Aug 28, 2014  8:53 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-28/jpmorgan-boosts-defenses-against-hackers-after-attack.html"><headline>JPMorgan Boosts Customer Data Protections After Attack</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co., the biggest U.S. bank, said it increased defenses against computer hackers after an attack against the industry this month. </p> <p>The lender is working with U.S. authorities to determine the scope of the assault and is taking additional steps to safeguard confidential information, Patricia Wexler, a spokeswoman for the New York-based bank, said today in an e-mail, declining to give specific examples. JPMorgan will contact any customers that might have been affected, Wexler said, adding that the firm hasn''t seen unusual fraud levels. </p> <p>Related:</p>

Graphic: Data Breaches in the U.S.

Russian Hackers Said to Loot Gigabytes of Big Bank Data
<p>JPMorgan was among at least five banks targeted in the coordinated attack on financial institutions in recent weeks, a U.S. official said yesterday. The assault led to the theft of customer data that could be used to drain accounts, according to another person briefed by U.S. law enforcement. Both asked not to be identified because U.S. probes are continuing. </p> <p>Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon, 58, has warned shareholders in annual letters that hackers'' efforts to breach the bank''s computers were growing more frequent, sophisticated and dangerous. The firm expected to boost yearly spending on cybersecurity to about $250 million by the end of 2014, with 1,000 workers dedicated to the effort, he wrote in April. </p>




Photographer: Jason Alden/Bloomberg

<p>
JPMorgan Chase  Co. Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon. Dimon, 58, has warned shareholders in annual letters that hackers'' efforts to breach the bank''s computers were growing more frequent, sophisticated and dangerous. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Barinka" date="Aug 28, 2014 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-28/ibm-s-watson-goes-from-jeopardy-player-to-scientist-used-by-j-j.html"><headline>IBM''s Watson Goes From Jeopardy Player to Scientist Used by J&amp;amp;J</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM) wants you to know that its Watson technology can do more
than win Jeopardy! -- it can now help accelerate scientific
research and discoveries. </p>
<p>IBM, in a peer-reviewed paper with Baylor College of
Medicine, used the Watson Discovery Advisor technology to map
connections within troves of scientific research. The ability to
point scientists toward new hypotheses and patterns in data is
also being used by Johnson  Johnson (JNJ) to help develop medicines
and find additional uses for existing drugs, IBM said in a
statement. </p>
<p>Since the Jeopardy! win in 2011 proved Watson can
answer questions and analyze data in natural human language, IBM
has been trying to commercialize the technology by showing how
it can be applied to customer service and financial planning. As
declining demand for IBM''s hardware has led to nine straight
quarters of falling sales, the company has turned to data
analytics tools like Watson as a new source of growth. </p>
<p>We''ve gone from co-creating with these early partners to
creating a commercial offering, John Gordon, vice president of
IBM''s Watson Group, said in a phone interview, referring to
Baylor and JJ. In the past we''ve talked about how Watson can
help people find answers to things that are known. We are
shifting to really helping innovators investigate the great
problems of our time. </p>
<p>IBM has been marketing different uses for Watson since the
company spent about $1 billion to create a new business unit
around the tool. Financial-services firm USAA said last month it
will use Watson on its website to answer military customers''
questions about transitioning back to civilian life -- the first
wide-scale test with consumers. </p>
<h2>70,000 Articles </h2>
<p>Watson''s new science applications identify potentially
unknown points of interest about a topic, instead of only
finding direct answers to specific questions. </p>
<p>Baylor used the tool to analyze the abstracts of 70,000
scientific articles on a specific cancer-related protein to
predict other compounds that may interact with it. Using
frequent words to rank and map relationships, the researchers
identified six proteins to investigate, more than the one that
scientists typically discover in a year. </p>
<p>Johnson  Johnson, whose Chief Executive Officer Alex Gorsky will join IBM''s board next week, will use Watson to
analyze drug data to potentially allow researchers to more
quickly ask questions about the effectiveness and side effects
of medical treatments. </p>
<p>This points them to the next great idea, Gordon said.
It''s kind of Watson becoming a scientist. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Rupert Rowling" date="Aug 29, 2014 12:37 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-29/morgan-stanley-extends-diesel-buying-spree-amid-stockpile-surge.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Extends Diesel-Buying Spree Amid Supply Surge</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley extended purchases of
diesel in Europe to a 43rd day amid the region''s biggest
stockpiles in more than two years. </p>
<p>The bank bought 77 percent of the 807,450 metric tons that
traded on the diesel barge market in July and August in a
pricing window operated by Platts, a unit of McGraw Hill
Financial Inc. (MHFI), brokers'' data compiled by Bloomberg show. The
bank purchased every day since July 1, including 18,700 tons
today. </p>
<p>While Germans will buy diesel and gasoil for heating this
winter, the European country''s supplies will be replenished by a
glut in Amsterdam, Rotterdam and Antwerp where the fuels are
traded, according to Olivier Jakob, the managing director of
Petromatrix GmbH, a consulting firm in Zug, Switzerland. Prices
are in a pattern called contango that means later-month costs
exceed immediate ones. That can create an incentive for traders
to buy and store. </p>
<p>The curve is attractive to storage, so if you have the
flexibility and the empty tanks then it makes sense to be
stockpiling now, Robert Campbell, head of oil products
research at Energy Aspects Ltd., said by phone from New York
Aug. 27. Despite the contango there is an unwillingness on the
part of end-consumers to buy much, so end-user storage is not
that high but ARA levels are. </p>
<p>Campbell spoke in general terms and declined to speculate
specifically on Morgan Stanley (MS)''s reasons for the trades. Hugh Fraser, a London-based spokesman for the bank, declined to
comment. </p>
<h2>Heating Oil Glut </h2>
<p>Combined inventories of diesel and heating oil in
independent storage in Antwerp-Rotterdam-Amsterdam, Europe''s
oil-trading center, are at their highest since March 2012,
according to PJK International BV. Heating oil storage tanks at
commercial premises in Germany are 37.7 percent full, the second
highest for this time of year since Ipsos Loyalty GmbH began
recording levels in 2011. Diesel and gasoil have become
increasingly interchangeable in Europe because of the sulfur
limits imposed on the heating fuel, according to Jakob. </p>
<p>The price of diesel barges in northwest Europe has dropped
by $51 a ton, or 5.5 percent, since the start of July to $880.25
a ton yesterday, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>ICE gasoil futures, against which European diesel is
priced, are trading $10 a ton higher for January than September. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrea Wong" date="Aug 29, 2014 11:08 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-29/goldman-sachs-says-euro-to-sink-to-parity-by-the-end-of-2017.html"><headline>Goldman Euro Parity Call Shows Growth Crisis Draghi Confronts</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc.''s forecast
for the euro to weaken to parity with the dollar comes as the
region confronts escalating deflation and the risk that some of
its biggest member states are falling back to recession. </p>
<p>Robin Brooks, the New York-based chief currency strategist,
cut his six-month forecast today to $1.25 from $1.34, saying the
European Central Bank will need to ease monetary policy further
to counter falling inflation expectations. The 18-nation
currency will weaken to parity by the end of 2017, he said.
Goldman isn''t alone in cutting its outlook -- JPMorgan Chase 
Co. also reduced its forecast today to $1.26 from $1.28 by the
end of June 2015. </p>
<p>The ECB will ease more, I don''t know what easing that
will be, but that the direction of policy is pretty clear,
Brooks said in a telephone interview. People had doubts
whether the ECB is going to take low inflation seriously, those
expectations are being updated. </p>
<p>The euro had staged a 16 percent rally after ECB President
Mario Draghi said he''ll do whatever it takes to save the
currency in July 2012. Since reaching the high for the year on
May 8, the euro has slumped 4.9 percent in the face of the
weakest inflation in almost five years, a recession in Italy and
zero growth in France. </p>
<p>Goldman cut the three-month estimate to $1.29 from $1.35
and the one-year forecast to $1.20 from $1.30. That''s one of the
most bearish views among banks surveyed by Bloomberg, with the
median forecast of $1.31 by the end of the year and $1.30 by the
end of the first quarter. </p>
<h2>Inflation Gauge </h2>
<p>The euro has slumped for seven consecutive weeks, the
longest stretch in more than a decade. The shared currency was
little changed at $1.3184 at 10:46 a.m. in New York. </p>
<p>Draghi last week pushed the central bank closer to
quantitative easing by singling out the five-year, five-year
inflation break-even rate, his preferred gauge of inflation
expectations, sliding below 2 percent. Draghi previously said
that a worsening of the medium-term inflation outlook would
provide a reason for broad-based asset purchases. ECB officials
meet Sept. 4. </p>
<p>In contrast, the U.S. is moving closer toward raising
interest rates. The Federal Reserve has kept the benchmark rate
at a record-low zero to 0.25 percent since December 2008, while
futures traders saw about a 56 percent chance the central bank
will start raising rates by July 2015, according to data
compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>The July Federal Open Market Committee meeting showed
policy makers discussed the possibility that jobs gains may lead
them to increase rates sooner than anticipated. </p>
<p>The longer-term forecast to parity is a pure view that
growth in the U.S. will outperform that that of the euro-zone,
Brooks said. In terms of our euro forecast, we''re clearly
signaling growth will be better in the U.S. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jordan Robertson and Michael Riley" date="Aug 29, 2014  8:54 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-29/jpmorgan-hack-said-to-span-months-via-multiple-flaws.html"><headline>JPMorgan Hackers Came In the Front Door -- in June. Two Months of Mayhem</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Hackers burrowed into the databanks of JPMorgan Chase  Co. and deftly dodged one of the world''s largest arrays of sophisticated detection systems for months. </p> <p>The attack, an outline of which was provided by two people familiar with the firm''s investigation, started in June at the digital equivalent of JPMorgan''s front door, exploiting an overlooked flaw in one of the bank''s websites. From there, it quickly developed into any security team''s worst nightmare. </p> <p>The hackers unleashed malicious programs that had been designed to penetrate the corporate network of JPMorgan -- the largest U.S. bank, which had vowed two months before the attack began to spend a quarter-billion dollars a year on cybersecurity. With sophisticated tools, the intruders reached deep into the bank''s infrastructure, silently siphoning off gigabytes of information, including customer-account data, until mid-August. </p> <p>Related:</p>

Graphic: Data Breaches in the U.S.

JPMorgan Boosts Customer Data Protections After Attack
<p>Only then did a JPMorgan team conducting a routine scan trigger an alarm. They discovered a breach, now being traced and evaluated, which investigators believe originated in Russia. </p> <p>Securing the Net</p><p>Evidence of advanced planning and the access to elaborate resources, as well as information provided by the FBI, led some members of the bank''s security team to tell outside consultants that they believed the hackers had been aided by the hidden hand of the Russian government, possibly as retribution for U.S.- imposed sanctions. </p>




Photographer: Marcio Jose Sanchez/AP Photo

<p>
A global map tracks computer virus activity at the McAfee headquarters in Santa Clara, California, in this July 3, 2013 file photo. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jason Corcoran" date="Aug 29, 2014  8:38 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-08-29/jpmorgan-sees-lehman-moment-if-ukraine-deteriorates.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sees Lehman Moment'' for Russia If Ukraine Deteriorates</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Russia''s equity markets may face a Lehman moment if the Ukraine conflict deteriorates further, according to Alexander Kantarovich, head of research for JPMorgan Chase  Co. in Moscow. </p> <p>With the significant deterioration in the Ukrainian situation, markets may treat this as a Lehman-style shock, Kantarovich wrote in an e-mailed report today. Revisiting the post-Lehman lows would imply downside of 50 percent from an index perspective. </p> <p>Russia''s ruble-denominated Micex Index has fallen 6.6 percent this year. The stock gauge posted the worst monthly drop in July since 2012 as the U.S. and the European Union escalated sanctions targeting Russia''s $2 trillion economy after the downing of a passenger jet on July 17 over Ukrainian territory controlled by pro-Russian insurgents. </p> <p>Related:</p>
Next U.S. Bank Bailout Could Come After a Cyber-Terror Attack
U.K. Wants EU to Block Russia From SWIFT Banking Network
Ukraine Invasion Claims Wipe Out Russia Bondholder Gains
<p>The Micex lost 67 percent in 2008, the biggest decline among benchmarks in the 30 largest stock markets, as Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc.''s collapse triggered a global recession and foreign banks cut credit. It rebounded by 120 percent in 2009, data compiled by Bloomberg show. </p> <p>Kantarovich sees significant differences between the situation now and the 2008-2009 crisis because oil prices, Russia''s chief export, are holding up and an economic contraction may not be that deep. </p>




Photographer: Alexander Khudoteply/AFP via Getty Images

<p>
The stock gauge posted the worst monthly drop in July since 2012 as the U.S. and the European Union escalated sanctions targeting Russia''s $2 trillion economy after the downing of Malaysia Airlines passenger jet MH17 on July 17 over Ukrainian territory controlled by pro-Russian insurgents. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry></news>