
<news><entry author="By Jason Webb" date="Feb 06, 2011  5:21 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-06/pfizer-s-closing-of-research-office-will-hurt-u-k-times-says.html"><headline>Pfizer''s Closing of Research Office Will Hurt U.K., Times Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Pfizer Inc.''s decision to close a
U.K. research office will damage the country''s standing in
research, the Sunday Times reported, citing an interview with
Simon Campbell, a retired scientist who helped Pfizer develop
the impotence drug Viagra. </p>
<p>Scientists employed at the office in Sandwich, England,
will struggle to find new jobs, Campbell said, according to
Times. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Edward Klump" date="Feb 07, 2011  4:11 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-07/chevron-to-pay-atlas-holders-10-cents-more-a-share-after-closing.html"><headline>Chevron to Pay Atlas Holders 10 Cents More a Share</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Chevron Corp., the second-largest
U.S. oil company, will pay holders of Atlas Energy Inc. an
additional 10 cents a share to settle litigation when its $3.59
billion purchase of the natural-gas producer is completed. </p>
<p>The settlement follows Atlas shareholder lawsuits that
alleged company directors breached fiduciary duties by agreeing
to an inadequate merger price and using an unfair process,
according to a filing with the U.S. Securities and Exchange
Commission today. The defendants denied any violations of their
duties. </p>
<p> Reliance Industries Ltd., which has a joint venture with
Atlas, has said it should''ve been given a chance to top
Chevron''s Nov. 9 offer. The company, based in Mumbai, sent a
Jan. 10 letter to the board calling itself the most natural
and obvious partner to buy Atlas. </p>
<p>The additional 10 cents a share doesn''t really move the
needle too much, said Fadel Gheit, an analyst at Oppenheimer 
Co. in New York who has a market perform on Chevron and owns
shares of the company. There will be no white knight. It''s a
done deal. </p>
<p>Chevron''s cash-and-stock bid valued the company at $43.34 a
share, a 37 percent premium to the closing price a day before it
was announced. The additional 10 cents would add about $7.8
million to the overall deal value. </p>
<p>Certain shareholders are excluded from the 10 cents,
including Vice Chairman Jonathan Cohen and Chief Executive
Officer Edward Cohen. </p>
<p>Atlas rose 4 cents to $45.86 at 4 p.m. on the Nasdaq Stock
Market. Chevron rose 55 cents to $97.66 in New York Stock
Exchange composite trading. </p>
<p> Exxon Mobil Corp. is the largest U.S. oil company. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Blanche Gatt" date="Feb 07, 2011 10:55 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-07/jpmorgan-s-highbridge-plans-standalone-credit-fund-ft-reports.html"><headline>Highbridge to Start Standalone Credit Fund, FT Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> JPMorgan Chase  Co.''s $27-billion
hedge fund, Highbridge Capital Management, is preparing to start
a new standalone credit fund and has recruited Serge Adam to
head its public credit platform, the Financial Times reported. </p>
<p>Adam, previously the head of Sandell Asset Management''s
credit fund, will head the public credit platform under Scott Kapnick, head of Highbridge''s principal strategies unit, the
newspaper said. </p>
<p>Adam will share responsibility for managing the Highbridge
Principal Strategies public credit business with HPS Managing
Director Purnima Puri, the company later said in a statement. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Adria Cimino" date="Feb 07, 2011  7:31 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-07/jpmorgan-advises-buying-european-stocks-favors-mining-energy.html"><headline>JPMorgan Advises Buying European Stocks; Favors Mining, Energy</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. advised
investors to buy European stocks on any weakness, saying the
economic cycle and earnings continue to support shares. </p>
<p>Many are arguing for a correction given that the market
appears overbought and the sentiment is seen as overly
bullish, Mislav Matejka, head of European equity strategy,
wrote in a note today. We believe risk-reward for stocks
remains compelling. </p>
<p>Insurers, miners, technology companies, energy producers
and carmakers are JPMorgan''s top picks. The firm is
cautious on defensive shares including utilities,
drugmakers, food producers and telecommunications operators. </p>
<p>The Stoxx 600 Europe Index has surged 24 percent since its
12-month low in May 2010 on optimism that the U.S. economy is
improving and as European governments bailed out Greece and
Ireland. </p>
<p>European stocks continue to be valued at less than the
historic average multiple of their earnings for the next 12
months. Central banks will keep interest rates at record lows,
JPMorgan wrote, and investors will allocate more of their assets
to equities, supporting share prices. </p>
<p>Equities appear attractively valued versus other asset
classes, are underowned and have posted resilient performance
over the past two years, which usually leads to inflows
starting, Matejka wrote. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Catherine Airlie" date="Feb 07, 2011  5:17 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-07/exxon-mobil-releases-coke-at-baytown-refinery-nrc-filing-shows.html"><headline>Exxon Mobil Releases Coke at Baytown Refinery, NRC Filing Shows</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Exxon Mobil Corp. released 100 pounds
of coke at its Baytown, Texas, refinery while loading a barge,
causing a spill heading north on the Houston ship canal,
according to a filing with the National Response Center. </p>
<p>U.S. refineries must notify the response center if they
release hazardous substances in excess of reportable quantities,
according to the Comprehensive Environmental Response,
Compensation and Liability Act, commonly known as Superfund. </p>
<p>Bloomberg News couldn''t immediately verify that the
information in the NRC filing was accurate. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sonia Sirletti and Jason Corcoran" date="Feb 07, 2011  3:59 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-07/generali-said-to-be-interested-in-stake-in-vtb-group-update1-.html"><headline>Generali Said to Be Interested in Stake in VTB Group</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Assicurazioni Generali SpA may buy
about 1 percent of VTB Group, Russia''s second-largest lender,
for about $300 million, said a person with knowledge of the
situation. </p>
<p>Italy''s biggest insurer expressed its interest in buying
the stock through a planned share sale of a 10 percent stake of
the bank owned by the Russian government, said the person, who
asked not be identified because the talks are private. </p>
<p>Russia will start the sale of its 10 percent stake in VTB
today, an official in the government''s press service said on
Feb. 4. The government hired Deutsche Bank AG, Merrill Lynch and
VTB Capital for the sale and doesn''t intend to sell another
stake in the Moscow-based lender for at least three months after
the deal is completed, the official said. </p>
<p>A Generali official at the company''s Trieste headquarters
declined to comment. A VTB spokesman in Moscow said the outcome
of the presentation to investors may be known by Feb. 11,
declining to comment on Generali''s bid. Generali may become a
strategic investor in the company, newspaper Vedomosti reported
today, citing two unidentified people working on the matter. </p>
<p> Russia boosted its stake in the bank to 85.5 percent from
77.5 percent in September 2009 by acquiring shares for 180
billion rubles ($6 billion) as part of a program to stabilize
the financial industry. VTB President Andrei Kostin said Oct. 1
that the lender definitely planned to conclude the sale of a
10 percent government stake by mid-2011. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Marthe Fourcade" date="Feb 07, 2011  3:05 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-07/pfizer-to-buy-ferrosan-consumer-health-business-from-altor-equity-partners.html"><headline>Pfizer to Buy Ferrosan Consumer-Health Business From Altor Equity Partners</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Pfizer Inc. agreed to buy the
consumer healthcare business of Denmark''s Ferrosan for an
undisclosed price, gaining a Nordic seller of skin products and
omega 3 nutritional supplements, it said in a statement today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jef Feeley and Phil Milford" date="Feb 08, 2011  6:44 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-08/pfizer-liable-for-1-68-million-in-prempro-damages-appeals-court-rules.html"><headline>Pfizer Told to Pay $10 Million Over Prempro Verdict</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Pfizer Inc. must pay more than
$10 million in damages to an Arkansas woman who blamed her
cancer on the company''s Prempro menopause drug, after an appeals
court reinstated a jury verdict. </p>
<p>A Pennsylvania appeals court yesterday overturned a judge''s
ruling that Pfizer''s Wyeth unit deserved a new trial in
connection with Mary Daniel''s claim that Prempro caused her
breast cancer. A Philadelphia jury in 2007 awarded Daniel and
her family $1.5 million in compensatory damages and $8.6 million
in punitives on her claim, according to Esther Berezofsky, one
of the family''s lawyers. </p>
<p>The appellate judges concluded no fraud on the court took
place here and a new trial should not have been granted,
according to the 55-page decision from the Superior Court of Pennsylvania. </p>
<p>Officials of New York-based Pfizer said they were
disappointed with the decision and considering their legal
options. Pfizer, the world''s largest drugmaker, completed its
$68 billion purchase of Wyeth in 2009. </p>
<p>The company disputes the fairness of the previous trial
and the appropriateness of the jury''s verdict, Christopher Loder, a Pfizer spokesman, said today in an e-mailed statement. </p>
<p>Annual sales of Wyeth''s hormone-replacement drugs once
topped $2 billion before the Women''s Health Initiative study,
sponsored by the U.S. National Institutes of Health, suggested
that women on the therapy had a 24 percent higher risk of breast
cancer. </p>
<p>Jury Trials </p>
<p>Until 1995, many menopausal women combined Premarin,
Wyeth''s estrogen-based drug, with progestin-laden Provera, made
by Pfizer''s Upjohn unit, to relieve their symptoms. Wyeth
combined the two hormones in its Prempro pill. </p>
<p>Pfizer''s Wyeth and Upjohn units have now lost eight of the
15 Prempro cases decided by juries since trials began in 2006.
The drugmaker got some of those verdicts thrown out after trial
or had the awards reduced. </p>
<p>It resolved some of the verdicts through settlements, while
other decisions are on appeal. Wyeth also has won dismissals of
more than 3,000 cases before trial, according to court filings. </p>
<p>Evidence in Daniel''s case showed that she took Prempro for
about 16 months starting in December 1999 and was diagnosed with breast cancer in July 2001. </p>
<p>A Philadelphia Common Pleas Court jury found that Prempro
was a factual cause of Daniel''s cancer and awarded her $1
million in compensatory damages. The panel also awarded Daniel''s
husband, Tom, $500,000 in damages. </p>
<p>Sealed Verdict </p>
<p>Jurors also handed down $8.6 million in punitive damages,
Berezofsky said. The judge in the case sealed that verdict
because another Prempro trial was ongoing in the same
courthouse. Berezofsky made the punitive damage award public
today after the appeals court ruling. </p>
<p>The trial judge in the case threw out both verdicts and
gave Wyeth a new trial because of questions about the testimony
of one of the plaintiffs'' expert witnesses. </p>
<p>The appeals court found the trial judge erred in
questioning the testimony and ordered the verdicts reinstated.
The ruling means an additional $2.4 million in pre- and post-
judgment interest will be added the award, Berezofsky said. </p>
<p>Pfizer rose 12 cents to $19.16 at 4:15 p.m. in New York
Stock Exchange composite trading. The shares have climbed 9.4
percent this year. </p>
<p>The case is Mary Daniel v. Wyeth Pharmaceuticals Inc., No.
2626 EDA 2007, Superior Court of Philadelphia (Philadelphia). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ronald Grover" date="Feb 08, 2011  4:35 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-08/disney-net-beats-analysts-estimates-on-gains-at-parks-espn-shares-rise.html"><headline>Disney Net Beats Analysts'' Estimates on Gains at Parks, ESPN; Shares Rise</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Walt Disney Co., the world''s biggest
theme-park company, reported first-quarter profit that beat
analysts'' estimates after an increase in attendance at its
resorts and advertising sales growth at ESPN. The shares rose. </p>
<p>Net income rose to $1.3 billion, or 68 cents a share, from
$844 million, or 44 cents, a year earlier, Burbank, California-
based Disney said today in a statement. Profit beat the 56-cent
average of 23 analysts'' estimates compiled by Bloomberg. Sales
rose 10 percent to $10.7 billion, also topping estimates. </p>
<p>The recovering economy drove attendance gains at Disney
theme parks and advertising growth at cable networks led by
ESPN. Anthony DiClemente, an analyst at Barclays Capital in New
York, predicted 3 percent higher attendance at parks in Orlando,
Florida. Analysts on average projected sales of $10.5 billion. </p>
<p>Their strength was across the board, said Michael Morris, an analyst with Davenport  Co. in Richmond, Virginia,
who recommends the stock. They were ahead of my expectations
and that of the Street on nearly every front. </p>
<p>Theme-park income increased 25 percent to $468 million as
revenue expanded 8 percent to $2.87 billion. Earnings at
Disney''s TV operations gained 47 percent to $1.07 billion,
boosted by gains at ESPN, which aired two newly acquired college
bowl games in the quarter. </p>
<p>Disney''s cable revenue gained 16 percent to $3.07 billion,
led by higher fees and advertising sales at ESPN and the Disney
Channel. Profit increased 42 percent to $771 million. </p>
<p>The company''s ABC broadcast unit boosted revenue 4 percent
to $1.58 billion as Disney''s local TV stations increased
advertising sales. Profit increased 64 percent to $295 million
after ESPN took over the Rose Bowl telecast and ABC reduced its
news and daytime production cost. </p>
<p>Disney rose 3.4 percent to $42.60 in extended trading. The
shares added 24 cents to $41.18 at 4 p.m. in New York Stock
Exchange composite trading and have advanced 9.8 percent this
year. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Paul Burkhardt" date="Feb 08, 2011  3:12 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-08/exxon-baytown-says-mont-belvieu-fire-impact-limited-update1-.html"><headline>Mont Belvieu Fire Has Limited Impact'' on Exxon Baytown Complex</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>     Feb. 8 (Bloomberg) - Exxon Mobil Corp.''s Baytown
petrochemical complex is experiencing a limited impact to
operations from a fire at Enterprise Product Partners LP''s Mont
Belvieu natural gas liquids processing facility, according to
Neely Nelson, a spokeswoman for the Baytown plant. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joao Oliveira" date="Feb 08, 2011  2:36 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-08/jpmorgan-s-one-equity-plans-to-invest-500-million-in-brazil.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Fund May Invest $500 Million in Brazil</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>One Equity Partners LLC, the buyout
arm of JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), plans to invest $500 million in
Brazilian companies over the next two years, Veronica Allende Serra, a private-equity consultant, said by telephone yesterday. </p>
<p>One Equity is in talks to invest in eight industrial,
consumer-goods and energy companies, said Allende Serra, a
partner at Pacific Investimentos, which represents One Equity in
the South American country. She declined to name potential
acquisition targets. </p>
<p>Brazil was named by the board as one of three priority
investment markets for the firm, alongside Asia and Eastern
Europe, Allende Serra said. Our focus is on companies with
good management, which need capital to grow organically or by
acquisitions. </p>
<p>The fastest growth in more than two decades in Brazil last
year helped fuel 482 mergers and acquisitions totaling $146.4
billion, the highest volume of deals in at least 12 years,
according to Bloomberg data. Gross domestic product probably
grew 7.3 percent in 2010, according to the central bank''s
quarterly inflation report, published Dec. 22. </p>
<p>Mergers and acquisitions in Brazil by foreign and local
companies will reach record volumes this year, Luiz Leonardo Cantidiano, former head of Brazil''s securities regulator, said
in an interview on Jan 27. Private equity company Advent
International Corp. has $2 billion for acquisitions in Brazil,
partner Patrice Etlin said in a Feb. 1 interview. </p>
<p>Serra, the daughter of former Sao Paulo governor Jose
Serra, said One Equity is looking for deals involving a minimum
investment of $100 million. The private equity fund was created
in 2001 and has $8 billion of liquidity, the executive said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joel Rosenblatt" date="Feb 08, 2011  2:20 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-08/disney-news-corp-time-warner-sue-hotfile-com-over-infringement-claims.html"><headline>Movie Studios Sue Hotfile.com Over Infringement Claims</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A Walt Disney Co. unit and four other
movie studios sued the operators of Hotfile.com for copyright
infringement, claiming the website facilitates the theft of
motion pictures and television content. </p>
<p>News Corp.''s Twentieth Century Fox Film Corp., Universal
City Studios Productions LLLP, Sony Corp.''s Columbia Pictures
Industries Inc. and Time Warner Inc.''s Warner Bros.
Entertainment Inc. joined Disney in the suit, according to a
complaint filed today in federal court in Miami. </p>
<p>Hotfile is a commercial online hub for distributing
popular entertainment content without authorization, including
hundreds of thousands of copies of the plaintiffs'' copyrighted
works, according to the complaint. </p>
<p>Users of Hotfile pay a monthly fee to download content,
including movies playing in theaters, from the company''s
computer servers, the studios said in their complaint. Hotfile
is operated by Anton Titov, who is also a named defendant,
according to the filing. </p>
<p>Titov and a Hotfile representative didn''t immediately
return an e-mail message seeking comment. </p>
<p>The Motion Picture Association of America Inc. today
announced the suit in an e-mailed statement. </p>
<p>The case is Disney Enterprises Inc. v. Hotfile Corp.,
11-20427, U.S. District Court, Southern District of Florida
(Miami). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Barbara Powell" date="Feb 08, 2011  1:06 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-08/exxon-says-baton-rouge-turnaround-includes-catalytic-cracker.html"><headline>Exxon Says Baton Rouge Work Includes Catalytic Cracker</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Exxon Mobil Corp.''s refinery in Baton
Rouge, Louisiana, is performing maintenance on a fluid catalytic
cracker and associated units that will last several weeks, Kevin Allexon, a company spokesman, said in an e-mail. </p>
<p>Allexon, based in Fairfax, Virginia, said the refinery
began the turnaround on Feb. 5. </p>
<p>Catalytic crackers are the main gasoline-making units at a
refinery. The Baton Rouge plant, second-largest in the U.S.
after Exxon''s refinery in Baytown, Texas, has a fluid catalytic
cracking capacity of 243,000 barrels a day, according to the
U.S. Energy Department''s Energy Information Administration. </p>
<p>The EIA''s 2010 refinery capacity report does not say how
many catalytic crackers are at the Baton Rouge plant, and
Allexon said he had no further details to share. </p>
<p>The Baton Rouge refinery processes domestic crudes from Louisiana, Texas, Mississippi and Alaska, according to the
company''s website. It also imports crude from Mexico, the North
Sea, West Africa, South America, Central America and the Arabian
Gulf. </p>
<p>The plant can process 525,000 barrels of oil a day,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sapna Maheshwari and Rachel Layne" date="Feb 08, 2011 12:43 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-08/general-electric-capital-to-sell-benchmark-subordinated-notes.html"><headline>GE Capital Plans Subordinated Debt Ahead of Fed Rules</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> General Electric Co.''s finance arm is
marketing $2 billion of subordinated debt for the first time
since 2005 as it prepares to be regulated by the Federal
Reserve. </p>
<p>The notes from General Electric Capital Corp. are expected
to be counted as so-called Tier 2 capital, said Russell Wilkerson, a company spokesman. The 10-year debt may yield 162.5
basis points more than similar-maturity Treasuries, said a
person familiar with the transaction. </p>
<p>GE Capital, which will be overseen by the Fed under the
Dodd-Frank regulatory overhaul set to take effect in July, plans
to raise $25 billion to $30 billion of long-term securities this
year. The unit boosted its estimated Tier 1 capital ratio, a
measure of the ability to absorb potential losses, to 8.9
percent in the fourth quarter from 7.5 percent a year earlier,
according to a presentation last month to investors. </p>
<p>What we''re seeing is the company getting its ducks in
order for its capital ratios for when it becomes regulated by
the Fed, said Adam Steer, a senior analyst in New York at
research firm CreditSights Inc. They have no need outside of
this for subordinated debt. It''s a result of Dodd-Frank. </p>
<p>The unit of Fairfield, Connecticut-based GE expects the
sale to further strengthen our total risk based-capital,
providing further flexibility in capital allocation decisions,
Wilkerson said. </p>
<p>Attractive Environment'' </p>
<p>Tier 1 capital includes securities such as common stock
while Tier 2 incorporates a broader range of securities that are
used if an institution becomes insolvent. </p>
<p>GE Capital issued $6 billion of senior unsecured bonds on
Jan. 4 in the biggest corporate debt offering in 11 months,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. The company has raised
about $8 billion toward its 2011 goal, Wilkerson said. </p>
<p>We believe this is an attractive environment in which to
issue, and there will be strong demand from investors for this
type of transaction, he said. </p>
<p> GE Capital''s January sale included $2 billion of 4.625
percent, 10-year debt that priced at 99.62 cents on the dollar
to yield 135 basis points more than similar-maturity Treasuries,
Bloomberg data show. </p>
<p>The notes traded yesterday at 98.5 cents on the dollar to
yield 4.8 percent, or a 116.8 basis-point spread, according to
Trace, the bond price reporting system of the Financial Industry
Regulatory Authority. </p>
<p>Capital as Cheap'' </p>
<p>The offering suggests that GE views Tier 2 capital or
subordinated capital as cheap, said Guy LeBas, chief fixed-
income strategist and economist at Janney Montgomery Scott LLC
in Philadelphia. Given the demand for cash in the marketplace
right now, I think the notes will be received pretty positively,
especially since they''ll yield above the senior debt. </p>
<p>Today''s notes are expected to be rated Aa3 by Moody''s
Investors Service and AA by Standard  Poor''s, said the person
familiar with the offering, who declined to be identified
because terms aren''t set. </p>
<p>The bonds will rank pari passu with the company''s existing
subordinated notes including euro-denominated portions of debt
due 2035 and securities maturing in 2037, the person said. </p>
<p> Barclays Capital, Citigroup Inc. and Goldman Sachs Group
Inc. are managing the sale, the person said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Yee Kai Pin" date="Feb 08, 2011  8:42 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-08/jpmorgan-says-bullish-crude-oil-investors-should-consider-taking-profit.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sees Oil Notable Correction'' as Unrest Eases</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Oil investors should consider selling
existing bullish positions because prices may decline this week
without fresh political tension in North Africa and the Middle
East, according to JPMorgan Chase  Co. </p>
<p> New York crude futures surged to the highest since October
2008 on Jan. 31, with London''s Brent trading above $100 a
barrel, on concern Egyptian unrest would disrupt supplies from
the Middle East and unsettle the region''s stability. Signs that
protests are easing mean the market may be set for a notable
correction, the bank said in a report yesterday. Hedge funds
raised bullish bets on oil by the most in eight weeks, according
to the U.S. Commodity Futures Trading Commission. </p>
<p>This week will be characterized by a drift down in crude
prices on days where either no new tensions arise or where
political progress is perceived, JPMorgan analysts led by New
York-based Lawrence Eagles said in the report. Investors
should therefore consider taking profits on all or a portion of
their remaining long positions. </p>
<p>Oil fell to the lowest in more than a week today as China
raised key interest rates for the third time since October,
spurring bets that fuel demand may be curtailed in the
world''s biggest energy user. Futures for March delivery on the New York Mercantile Exchange fell as much as 1.8 percent to
$85.88 a barrel while Brent crude dropped as low as $97.53. </p>
<p>Egypt Progress'' </p>
<p>Prices in New York slid 5 percent in the five days through
yesterday as demonstrations against Egyptian President Hosni Mubarak subsided and the government met with opposition leaders. </p>
<p>Hedge funds and other large speculators boosted net-long
positions on oil, or wagers on rising prices, by 17 percent in
the seven days ended Feb. 1, CFTC data show. </p>
<p>U.S. President Barack Obama yesterday said Egypt is
making progress in negotiations with the opposition. About
3.5 percent of global oil output moves through Egypt via the
Suez Canal and the Suez-Mediterranean Pipeline, according to
Bloomberg calculations using data from the Energy Department. </p>
<p>Crude may remain volatile because geopolitical risks in
Algeria, Yemen and Jordan haven''t subsided, JPMorgan said.
Opposition groups in Algeria, a member of the Organization of
Petroleum Exporting Countries, planned protests in Algiers on
Feb. 12. </p>
<p>The risks of a more substantive price shock in the months
ahead remain in place, the JPMorgan analysts said. We would
look to add call option length. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. on Jan. 31 said Brent crude is
vulnerable to a temporary price drop as anti-government
violence won''t spread to the Middle East. Brent futures in
London reached $100 a barrel that day for the first time since
October 2008 and traded near $99 today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Gavin Finch, Bryan Keogh and Charles Penty" date="Feb 08, 2011  5:51 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-08/goldman-sachs-turns-bullish-on-stocks-in-european-banks-bond-market-shuns.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Turns Bullish on Stocks in European Banks Bond Market Shuns</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. is telling
investors to buy European bank stocks for the first time in more
than 16 months. Bond buyers are taking the opposite view on
concern that policy makers will fail to staunch the debt crisis. </p>
<p>Banks in Spain, Italy and Greece have led the Bloomberg
Europe Banks and Financial Services Index 16 percent higher
since November. While shares of Spain''s Banco Santander SA
rallied 23 percent and Italy''s UniCredit SpA jumped 25 percent,
both lenders had to offer investors record premiums over
government debt when they sold covered bonds in the same period. </p>
<p>Equity investors are betting political leaders will bridge
their differences over the mandate of the European Financial
Stability Facility and stop the region''s debt crisis from
spreading. Bond buyers are skeptical that the talks will succeed
and concerned banks may be forced to accept losses on the more
than $2 trillion of loans and other assets they have in Greece,
Ireland, Italy, Portugal and Spain. Analysts say that while
equity investors may be right in the short term, they risk
ignoring a jump in funding costs that will erode future profit. </p>
<p>The fundamental split here is about whether policy
measures in Spain and the rest of Europe are going to work in
halting the crisis -- or not, said Huw van Steenis, a banking
analyst at Morgan Stanley in London. </p>
<p>Especially Attractive'' </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs equity strategists, including Peter Oppenheimer and Sharon Bell, turned bullish on European lenders
last week, saying anxiety about the debt crisis will ease,
driving down banks'' funding costs. The analysts, citing a
narrowing of sovereign spreads in the peripheral eurozone,
said in a Feb. 3 note that bank stocks were among the cheapest
and the trade-off between their growth prospects and earnings
in the next few years looks especially attractive. </p>
<p>UBS AG, Switzerland''s biggest bank, today posted a 7
percent increase in fourth-quarter profit. Deutsche Bank AG last
week reiterated its target to double pretax profit at its
operating units to 10 billion euros ($13.6 billion) this year
from 2009 levels as the Frankfurt-based company posted a gain in
fourth-quarter earnings at its investment bank. Santander,
Spain''s biggest bank, reported fourth-quarter profit on Feb. 3
that beat analysts'' estimates. Chairman Emilio Botin told
reporters that the worst of the crisis is behind us. </p>
<p>Bank stocks are benefiting as investors ride the positive
earnings story for short-term gains, said Suki Mann, senior
credit strategist at Societe Generale SA in London. Funding
levels are still very high for the banks, he said. Credit''s
where the smart money is. </p>
<p>More Uncertainty'' </p>
<p>That point was echoed by Alexander Plenk, a Munich-based
analyst at UniCredit. </p>
<p>Equity investors are typically more focused on the short
term than credit investors, and the really horrible news seems
to have ended, Plenk said. Credit investors tend to take
more of a medium to long-term view, where there is much more
uncertainty. </p>
<p>European banks have more at stake in Spain than in Greece
and Ireland combined, with total claims exceeding $716 billion
at the end of September, according to the Bank for International
Settlements. Europe''s lenders hold more than $902 billion of
loans and other assets in Italy, including sovereign debt, and
$216 billion in Portugal, according to BIS data. </p>
<p>Financial firms in southern Europe are paying some of the
highest costs ever to borrow relative to government debt. An
increase in funding costs erodes bank profit by narrowing the
net interest margin, or the difference between what a bank earns
from lending and pays for funding. </p>
<p>Covered Bonds </p>
<p>Lenders in Spain and Italy are offering record amounts of
covered bonds because investors are wary of buying unsecured
debt that could be subject to so-called bail-ins being discussed
by regulators that would convert it into equity when triggers
are breached. Investors are forcing banks to pay more in
interest on the securities, which are typically backed by
mortgages or public-sector loans, are getting costlier for banks
to sell as supply outstrips demand. </p>
<p>Santander, which hasn''t sold a senior unsecured bond this
year, issued 1 billion euros of five-year covered bonds on Jan.
5 at a spread of 287 basis points, almost three times what it
paid in March last year. UniCredit, Italy''s largest lender, sold
1.25 billion euros of 12-year covered debt on Feb. 1 at a record
spread of 210 basis points. Four months ago, the Milan-based
bank sold seven-year covered notes at 154 basis points. A basis
point is one-hundredth of a percent. </p>
<p>Intesa, BBVA </p>
<p> Intesa Sanpaolo SpA, Italy''s second-biggest bank, based in
Turin, paid a record spread of 208 basis points to sell 10-year
covered bonds on Jan. 14, compared with a spread of 148 basis
points at a five-year debt sale less than three months earlier. Banco Bilbao Vizcaya Argentaria SA, Spain''s No. 2 lender, sold
1.5 billion euros of three-year covered notes on Jan. 4 at a
record spread of 310 basis points. </p>
<p>U.S. banks by contrast are selling debt from three-year
floating-rate notes to 30-year bonds as the cost to protect the
securities from default declines amid signs the economy is
improving. Borrowing costs for U.S. lenders are near the lowest
in nine months relative to the debt of industrial companies. </p>
<p>No banks in Portugal, Italy, Ireland, Greece or Spain have
sold debt in dollars since September. German, Swiss and British
lenders, including Deutsche Bank and London-based HSBC Holdings
Plc, aren''t paying as much to borrow as southern European banks
and are finding overseas investors willing to buy their debt. </p>
<p> Credit Suisse Group AG, Switzerland''s second-biggest
lender, raised $2.18 billion this year in the U.S., including a
sale of three-year notes that paid a spread of 128 basis points
over Treasuries. HSBC, Europe''s biggest bank, sold 750 million
euros of four-year notes at a spread of 127 basis points on Jan.
24, two weeks after a $4 billion offering, Bloomberg data show. </p>
<p>Pretty Dire'' </p>
<p>Funding costs for Banco Santander, Intesa, UniCredit and
BBVA have declined from record highs this month, helped by a
wider rally in bank bonds. Spreads on senior euro-denominated
bank debt narrowed 32 basis points to 169 basis points last week
since reaching a six-month peak on Jan. 11, Barclays Capital''s
Euro Aggregate Banking Senior Index shows. BBVA raised 2 billion
euros in a five-year covered note sale on Feb. 2 at a spread of
242 basis points. That''s still more than three times as much as
the lender paid about a year ago to sell similar securities. </p>
<p>Nothing material has changed over the past two or three
weeks, even though there has been improved sentiment in the
stock markets, said John Anderson, who manages about 500
million pounds ($805 million) in European bonds as head of
credit at Gartmore Investment Management Ltd. in London. The
macro situation is still pretty dire in countries like Spain,
and if they can''t grow, they can''t reduce their deficit. </p>
<p>Capital Rules </p>
<p>European Union officials are trying to bolster confidence
in the 27-nation bloc''s financial industry by forcing banks to
hold more capital in reserve against future losses and to
undergo stress tests to show they can withstand a recession. </p>
<p>Group of 20 leaders in November endorsed rules drawn up by
the Basel Committee on Banking Supervision that will more than
triple the highest-quality capital, such as shareholders''
equity, that lenders must hold to cushion against losses.
European regulators, preparing a second round of stress tests in
the first half of this year, have pledged to toughen the exams. </p>
<p>The cost of protecting European senior financial debt from
default has surged 32 percent in the past four months. The
Markit iTraxx Financial Index of 25 banks and insurers increased
39 basis points to 162.5 basis points, which means it costs
162,500 euros annually to insure 10 million euros of the debt
for five years, according to data provider CMA. </p>
<p>Prices for credit-default swaps linked to the bonds of New
York investment banks, including Goldman Sachs and Morgan
Stanley, traded at levels that approached those of junk bonds in
March 2007, before the global financial crisis and as shares in
those firms were rallying. </p>
<p>Unlimited Cash </p>
<p>European banks are also charging more to lend to each
other. The rate at which European firms say they will lend euros
to other banks for three months, known as Euribor, reached a 19-
month high on Feb. 4 on concern that the European Central Bank
may withdraw emergency cash supplies to lenders in April. </p>
<p>The ECB said in December it would lend unlimited cash at
its weekly, monthly and three-month refinancing operations until
April to alleviate banks'' funding pressures and spur lending.
The ECB offers the unlimited cash at 1 percent, the same as its
benchmark, record-low interest rate. European banks are still
dependent on the emergency funding: 371 lenders sought 213.7
billion euros in seven-day funds on Feb. 2, the most this year,
according to the ECB. </p>
<p>Comprehensive'' Package </p>
<p>EU leaders meeting in Brussels Feb. 4 reiterated a March 25
deadline to reach what German Chancellor Angela Merkel called a
comprehensive package to address the crisis. The measures
may include stiffer sanctions against budget deficits higher
than 3 percent of gross domestic product, lower interest rates
on loans and allowing the 440 billion-euro stability fund to buy
debt directly from member states. </p>
<p>Merkel, forced into underwriting a 110 billion-euro rescue
of Greece last year, has toned down her insistence that
government bondholders accept losses in future bailouts. In
November, as the EU and International Monetary Fund bailed out
Ireland, she called the euro''s condition exceptionally
serious. Two months later, she said she''d back whatever is
needed to support the euro. </p>
<p>That''s helped Europe''s benchmark Stoxx 50 index gain 9
percent this year. Credit-default swaps tied to Spanish government bonds fell about 36 percent since Jan. 10, CMA prices
show, indicating an improvement in the perception of credit
quality. The swaps are at 230 basis points. Contracts on Italy
fell about 33 percent to 172 basis points, CMA prices show. </p>
<p>Some of the frantic activity we have seen in the last few
weeks has died down, said Julian Chillingworth, who helps
manage about 15 billion pounds of shares at Rathbone Brothers
Plc in London. Whether or not the European debt crisis is over
is debatable. There''s still a long way to go. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Janet Ong" date="Feb 08, 2011  2:42 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-08/walton-advanced-january-sales-rise-20-14-table-8110-tt.html"><headline>WALTON ADVANCED January Sales Rise 20.14% (Table) : 8110 TT</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>WALTON ADVANCED said unconsolidated sales
in January rose 20.14% to NT$660,891,000 from NT$550,095,000,
according to a statement filed to the Taiwan Stock Exchange. </p>
<p>(Figures are in thousands of New Taiwan dollars) </p>
<p>================================================================= </p>
<p>1/2011           1/2010
Sales            660,891          550,095    
YOY%              20.14%  </p>
<p>-----------------Year-to-date-----------------
Sales            660,891          550,095    
YOY%              20.14% 
=================================================================
 </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Janet Ong" date="Feb 08, 2011  1:20 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-08/general-plastic-january-sales-rise-1-47-table-6128-tt.html"><headline>GENERAL PLASTIC January Sales Rise 1.47% (Table) : 6128 TT</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>GENERAL PLASTIC said unconsolidated sales
in January rose 1.47% to NT$123,669,000 from NT$121,872,000,
according to a statement filed to the Taiwan Stock Exchange. </p>
<p>(Figures are in thousands of New Taiwan dollars) </p>
<p>================================================================= </p>
<p>1/2011           1/2010
Sales            123,669          121,872    
YOY%              1.47%   </p>
<p>-----------------Year-to-date-----------------
Sales            123,669          121,872    
YOY%              1.47%  
=================================================================
 </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hui-yong Yu" date="Feb 09, 2011  6:19 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-09/morgan-stanley-starwood-said-to-team-on-bid-for-centro-assets.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley, Starwood Capital Said to Bid for Centro U.S. Mall Assets</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Morgan Stanley''s global real estate
fund is teaming with Barry Sternlicht''s Starwood Capital Group
LLC to bid for U.S. shopping centers being sold by Australia''s Centro Properties Group, a person briefed on the plans said. </p>
<p>Centro said on Dec. 22 it had received several expressions
of interest. Blackstone Group LP made a preliminary bid for some
assets, a person with knowledge of the offer said in December.
Centro, based in Melbourne, ceded control to its bankers at the
end of 2008 and put its assets up for sale after an acquisition
spree in the U.S. backfired as the credit markets seized up. </p>
<p>The person briefed on Morgan Stanley and Starwood''s plans
asked not to be identified because the information is private. </p>
<p>Mark Lake, a spokesman for Morgan Stanley in New York, and Tom Johnson, a spokesman for Greenwich, Connecticut-based
Starwood Capital, declined to comment. Stacy Slater, a New York-
based spokeswoman for Centro, also declined to comment. </p>
<p>The Wall Street Journal reported Morgan Stanley and
Starwood''s interest on Feb. 8. Blackstone and a consortium led
by Lend Lease Group and NRDC Equity Partners also may submit
formal offers by Feb. 24, the newspaper said. The bids were
close to the $8 billion of debt on the U.S. properties and the
$9.5 billion book value of the malls, according to the Journal. </p>
<p>An NRDC spokeswoman declined to comment on the report. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley last June raised $4.7 billion for a new
global real estate fund, less than half its target before the
financial crisis. The company has reported gains in its real
estate funds during the past four quarters as the commercial property market began to recover. </p>
<p>Share Decline </p>
<p>Centro shares fell A$0.01 to A$0.15 yesterday in Sydney
trading, and have declined 35 percent in the past year. They
reached a peak closing price of A$10.02 in May 2007. </p>
<p>The company has about 600 properties in the U.S., which it
leases to tenants including TJX Cos., the owner of T.J. Maxx,
Marshalls and HomeGoods stores; and Kroger Co., the largest U.S.
grocery store chain. The U.S. properties were 88.3 percent
leased in the year through June 30, compared with 88.7 percent a
year earlier, according to Centro''s annual report. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Randall" date="Feb 09, 2011  5:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-09/pfizer-novartis-drugs-fight-rare-pancreatic-malignancies-in-studies.html"><headline>Pfizer, Novartis Drugs Fight Rare Pancreatic Tumors in Studies</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Cancer drugs made by Pfizer Inc. and Novartis AG helped combat a rare form of pancreatic tumor, the
type diagnosed in Apple Inc.''s Steve Jobs in 2004, reports in a
medical journal confirmed today. </p>
<p>Pfizer''s Sutent and Novartis''s Afinitor, both used to treat
kidney cancer, more than doubled the time that patients lived
without their pancreatic neuroendocrine tumors spreading,
according to company-funded research reported today in the New
England Journal of Medicine. Data from the studies were
previously presented at medical meetings and submitted to
regulators for marketing approval, according to the companies. </p>
<p>Pancreatic neuroendocrine tumors make up about 1.4 percent
of the 40,000 people a year who are diagnosed with pancreatic
cancer. Patients have few treatment options and die an average
of three years from diagnosis, according to a 2007 study. The
new treatments may prolong survival, while adding side effects,
including diarrhea, vomiting and infections. Jobs, 55, chief
executive officer of Cupertino, California-based Apple, told
employees on Jan. 17 he was taking his third medical leave. </p>
<p>These studies provide optimism, said Robert T. Jenson
and Gianfranco Delle Fave, doctors at the National Institute of
Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases, in Bethesda, Maryland, in an editorial that accompanied the studies. Both
drugs are effective at improving disease-free survival, even in
patients in whom other treatments have failed, and thus offer
effective therapies where there were none before. </p>
<p>European Clearance </p>
<p>Both companies have applied to regulators in the U.S. and
the European Union. Pfizer won European approval in December to
market Sutent for pancreatic tumors. Pfizer also has clearance
to sell Sutent for gastrointestinal stromal tumors. </p>
<p>In the Sutent study, patients lived without progression of
their advanced pancreatic neuroendocrine tumors for a median
time of 11.4 months compared with 5.5 months for patients taking
a placebo, according to authors led by Eric Raymond of the University of Paris. </p>
<p>Those taking Sutent lived longer, and the study was halted
early because it would have been unethical to continue giving
any patients a placebo instead of the medicine, Pfizer said in
March 2009. </p>
<p>Afinitor from Basel, Switzerland-based Novartis kept
advanced pancreatic neuroendocrine tumors at bay for 11 months
compared with 4.6 months for patients on a placebo. The study
failed to prove that the drug extended overall survival,
possibly because patients on the placebo were allowed to switch
to Afinitor once their disease progressed, wrote authors led by
J.C. Yao of the University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center in
Houston. </p>
<p>Unanswered Questions </p>
<p>The studies leave unanswered questions, according to
today''s editorial. Doctors don''t know how long patients should
take the medicines. If one drug fails, it''s unclear whether
switching to the other would help. Doctors also don''t know
whether it''s safe or effective to give the drugs in combination
with other treatments, including radiation and surgery, and
whether long-term side effects will limit the usefulness of the
treatments. </p>
<p>Apple CEO Jobs took a leave of absence in 2004 after
saying he had a neuroendocrine tumor. He left again in 2009 for
a liver transplant, sometimes done when the cancer spreads. He
didn''t say on Jan. 17 why he was taking the third medical leave. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Linda Sandler" date="Feb 09, 2011  4:47 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-09/jpmorgan-chase-asks-judge-to-move-madoff-case-from-u-s-bankruptcy-court.html"><headline>JPMorgan Seeks Jury Trial in $6.4 Billion Madoff Case</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> JPMorgan Chase  Co., sued by the
trustee for Bernard Madoff''s defunct firm for $6.4 billion for
allegedly aiding the con man''s fraud, asked a judge to remove
the case from bankruptcy court because it raises novel and
unsettled questions beyond the court''s scope and expertise. </p>
<p>In a lawsuit unsealed last week, Madoff trustee Irving Picard accused JPMorgan of actively assisting Madoff''s crimes to
protect earnings from his bank accounts, in the process
violating federal banking law. The earnings were wholly
immaterial and the allegations about law-breaking were not
the domain of bankruptcy law, JPMorgan said yesterday. </p>
<p>Picard was appointed to liquidate the Madoff brokerage
firm, JPMorgan said in a filing in U.S. Bankruptcy Court in Manhattan. Instead, he is mostly pursuing non-bankruptcy claims
on behalf of Madoff''s customers, the bank said. </p>
<p>The trustee is trying to pursue an enormous backdoor
class action to recoup damages incurred by individuals and
entities other than the firm to which he is the appointed
successor, said JPMorgan, the second-biggest U.S. bank. </p>
<p>Addressing a U.S. District Court in Manhattan, the New
York-based bank said it has a right to a jury trial by law in an
appropriate federal court. Picard falsely accused the bank
of complicity in the largest securities fraud in U.S. history,
JPMorgan said. </p>
<p>Madoff opened accounts with JPMorgan or banks it bought in
1986, depositing customer investments and transferring money out
of the accounts, the bank said in the filling. Its fees were
$597,000 in the six years before Madoff''s 2008 bankruptcy, it
said, citing Picard. JPMorgan earned less than $3.5 million in
interest by loaning $145 million to Madoff''s firm in 2005 and
2006, the bank said. </p>
<p>Starting in 2006, JPMorgan invested about $338 million in
four Madoff feeder funds, whose assets were managed by Madoff.
The investments were a hedge for financial products tied to
Madoff''s reported returns, it said. JPMorgan redeemed
$276 million of its original investments in the funds after
buying Bear Stearns in 2008, losing the rest when the Ponzi
scheme was revealed, it said. </p>
<p>Picard wants to recoup the money redeemed, the loan
payments, interest and fees, in addition to $5.4 billion in
damages, allegedly the amount lost by Madoff customers in the
four years through December 2008, JPMorgan said. To get the
damages, he used theories of aiding and abetting fraud and
breach of fiduciary duty, as well as a theory of fraud on
regulators, it said. </p>
<p>The Madoff trustee''s suit against JPMorgan is very
aggressive, bankruptcy lawyer Harvey Miller told Bloomberg
Television today. He is pushing the envelope to the limit. </p>
<p>Aiding and Abetting'' </p>
<p>According to a statement by Picard last week, JPMorgan had
a decades-long role as Madoff''s primary banker, aiding and
abetting the fraud. While the bank was warned Madoff may have
been running a Ponzi scheme and had a palpable concern that
Madoff was a fraud for years, it wasn''t until October 2008
that it reported Madoff to government officials, the trustee''s
lawyers said in the statement. </p>
<p>The banks'' executives didn''t restrict the Madoff firm''s
bank account even though it was being used to launder money
from the Ponzi scheme, they said. </p>
<p>In response, JPMorgan said Picard''s interpretation of
banking law would impose broad investigative duties on banks
that do not exist. </p>
<p>While federal banking laws do provide broad guidelines
for detecting money laundering, the guidelines have rarely been
interpreted by the courts, it said. </p>
<p>Picard asserted a novel claim that JPMorgan committed a
fraud on regulators including the U.S. Securities and Exchange
Commission and the Federal Reserve by not alerting them to
Madoff''s crimes, it said. </p>
<p>Array'' of Statutes </p>
<p>The bank''s relationships with its regulators are governed
by an array of federal statutes and regulations, none of which
creates an express private right of action against banks for
fraud on the regulator, it said. </p>
<p>Picard would have to prove in the correct federal court
that he had a right to pursue a claim of fraud on regulators, it
said. </p>
<p>Kevin McCue, a Picard spokesman, didn''t respond to an
e-mail seeking comment on the JPMorgan filing. </p>
<p>JPMorgan is leading a charge in legal maneuver to slow
trustees, St. John''s University business professor Anthony Michael Sabino said in an e-mailed statement. He predicted
JPMorgan and others fighting Picard would lose the fight, saying
Picard had a right under bankruptcy law to bring lawsuits to
recover money for Madoff customers. </p>
<p>The Madoff liquidation case is Securities Investor
Protection Corp. v. Bernard L. Madoff Investment Securities
Inc., 08-01789, U.S. Bankruptcy Court, Southern District of New
York (Manhattan). The adversary case is Picard v. JPMorgan Chase
 Co., 10-AP-4932, U.S. Bankruptcy Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Feb 09, 2011  4:23 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-09/microsoft-s-bing-engineering-chief-nadella-named-to-lead-server-division.html"><headline>Microsoft''s Bing Engineering Chief Nadella Named to Lead Server Division</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Microsoft Corp. said Satya Nadella,
an engineering manager in its Internet business, is becoming
president of the server division, part of an effort to put more
people with a technology background in top jobs. </p>
<p>Nadella, 43, will oversee strategy, engineering, marketing
and product development for the company''s server, tools and
cloud-computing efforts, Microsoft said today in a statement. He
replaces Bob Muglia, whose departure was announced last month. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Steve Ballmer is making executive
changes to inject more engineering experience into the senior
levels of product divisions. He''s contending with criticism from
the board and investors that Microsoft is falling behind in
smartphones and tablet computers. Ballmer also is trying to
capitalize on a shift to cloud software, which is stored online. </p>
<p>Nadella, a 19-year Microsoft veteran, served as a senior
vice president overseeing engineering and technical strategy for
the Bing search engine, MSN websites and Internet advertising.
Those products run on one of the biggest cloud-based systems in
the world, giving Nadella experience in that field. </p>
<p>In another change, Amitabh Srivastava, a server unit senior
vice president who oversaw the company''s Windows Server and
Windows Azure cloud-computing products, is leaving the company.
He will be replaced by Bill Laing for now, Nadella said in a
message on Microsoft''s website. </p>




Photographer: David Paul Morris/Bloomberg

<p>
Satya Nadella, an engineering manager in Microsoft''s Internet business, is becoming
president of the server division. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ronald Grover" date="Feb 09, 2011  4:16 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-09/disney-rises-to-record-high-after-profit-revenue-top-analysts-estimates.html"><headline>Disney Rises to Record High After Profit, Revenue Top Analysts'' Estimates</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Walt Disney Co., the world''s biggest
theme-park company, rose to a record high in New York after
first-quarter sales and profit topped analysts'' estimates. </p>
<p>Disney, based in Burbank, California, advanced $2.18, or
5.3 percent, to $43.36 at 4 p.m. in New York Stock Exchange
composite trading. The old closing high of $43.05 was set in
April 2000. </p>
<p>The recovering economy drove attendance gains at Disney
theme parks and advertising growth at cable networks led by
ESPN. Anthony DiClemente, an analyst at Barclays Capital in New
York, predicted 3 percent higher attendance at parks in Orlando,
Florida. Analysts on average projected sales of $10.5 billion.
Income from Disney''s studio and consumer products also rose. </p>
<p>The earnings beat was broad-based and resolute as
operating income surpassed estimates in all segments, most
notably at the cable networks, Michael Nathanson, an analyst
at Nomura Securities International Inc., said today in a note to
investors. He recommends investors buy the stock </p>
<p>First-quarter net income rose to $1.3 billion, or 68 cents
a share, from $844 million, or 44 cents, a year earlier, Disney
said yesterday in a statement. Profit beat the 56-cent average
of 23 analysts'' estimates compiled by Bloomberg. Sales rose 10
percent to $10.7 billion, also topping estimates. </p>
<p>Theme-park income increased 25 percent to $468 million as
revenue expanded 8 percent to $2.87 billion. Attendance at
domestic parks rose 2 percent from a year earlier, while per-
capita guest spending increased 8 percent, Chief Financial
Officer Jay Rasulo said yesterday on a call. </p>
<p>Park Bookings </p>
<p>Bookings for this quarter are running 3 percent ahead of a
year earlier, Rasulo said. </p>
<p>Earnings at Disney''s TV operations gained 47 percent to
$1.07 billion, boosted by gains at ESPN, which aired two newly
acquired college bowl games in the quarter. </p>
<p>Disney''s cable revenue gained 16 percent to $3.07 billion,
led by higher fees and advertising sales at ESPN and the Disney
Channel. Profit increased 42 percent to $771 million. </p>
<p>The company''s ABC broadcast unit boosted revenue 4 percent
to $1.58 billion as Disney''s local TV stations increased
advertising sales. Profit increased 64 percent to $295 million
after ESPN took over the Rose Bowl telecast and ABC reduced its
news and daytime production cost. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Duane Stanford" date="Feb 09, 2011  4:13 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-09/coca-cola-fourth-quarter-earnings-more-than-triple-on-one-time-cash-gain.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Net More Than Triples on Acquisition Gain</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Coca-Cola Co., the world''s largest
soft-drink maker, said fourth-quarter profit more than tripled
after a one-time non-cash gain related to the acquisition of its
North American bottling operations. </p>
<p>Net income advanced to $5.77 billion, or $2.46 a share, the
Atlanta-based company said today in a statement. Excluding some
items, profit was 72 cents, matching the average of estimates
compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola, led by Chief Executive Officer Muhtar Kent, now
controls 90 percent of its North America beverage distribution
following a deal last year with its largest bottler. The company
boosted volume sales in the U.S. and Canada by 8 percent for the
quarter, the third consecutive quarterly increase. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola advanced 28 cents to $63.15 at 4:01 p.m. in New
York Stock Exchange composite trading. The shares have fallen 4
percent this year, compared with a 1.4 percent slide for rival
PepsiCo Inc. </p>
<p>Global sales by drink volume grew 6 percent, helped by a 5
percent gain in Latin America and a 2 percent increase in Europe. Volume in the Eurasia  Africa unit jumped 14 percent. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola will put a lot of effort into dairy drinks in
conjunction with its growing juice business, Chief Executive
Officer Muhtar Kent also said today in an interview. PepsiCo
Inc. recently purchased a controlling stake in Russia-based
Wimm-Bill-Dann to expand more into dairy-based beverages. Coca-
Cola''s Minute Maid unit already sells a dairy and juice drink in China called Pulpy Super Milky. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola recorded a $5 billion one-time, non-cash gain for
the 33 percent stake in Coca-Cola Enterprises Inc. it traded in
the purchase of the bottler''s North American operations. </p>
<p>Sales rose 40 percent to $10.5 billion, helped by the new
distribution. Analysts on average estimated $10.2 billion,
according to a Bloomberg survey. </p>
<p>Net income in the fourth quarter of 2009 was $1.54 billion,
or 66 cents a share. </p>
<p>Purchase, New York-based PepsiCo, the second-biggest soft-
drink company, is scheduled to report earnings tomorrow. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christine Harper" date="Feb 09, 2011 10:45 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-09/goldman-sachs-says-it-bought-too-many-illiquid-assets-pre-financial-crisis.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Says It Bought Too Many Illiquid Assets Before 2008 Crisis</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Goldman Sachs Group Inc., the fifth-
biggest U.S. bank, purchased too many hard-to-sell assets 
before the financial crisis in 2008, Chief Financial
Officer David A. Viniar said. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs was buying more illiquid assets than we
probably should have, Viniar, 55, said today at a conference
in Miami hosted by Credit Suisse Group AG, his eighth
consecutive appearance at the annual event. It was a good
lesson learned. </p>
<p>Less liquid assets increased at a 39 percent compound
annual growth rate between the start of 2005 and the start of
2008, compared with 24 percent growth in liquid assets,
according to a slide Viniar included in his presentation. Since
the first quarter of 2008, the firm has reduced holdings of such
investments at an 18 percent compound annual rate, while liquid
assets are down 9 percent. </p>
<p>The assets included mortgage-backed and other asset-backed
securities, loans, high-yield debt, emerging-market stocks and
bonds and investments in funds and private equity, the slide
showed. They totaled $172 billion in the first quarter of 2008,
or 14 percent of the firm''s balance sheet, up from $65 billion,
or 11 percent, three years earlier. </p>
<p>After posting record profit in 2009, Goldman Sachs reported
a 38 percent drop in net income for 2010 as revenue from
underwriting and trading slumped. Viniar said he expects revenue
to rebound from fixed-income, currencies and commodities
trading, the firm''s largest division, known as FICC. </p>
<p>You''ll see FICC start to improve, he said. </p>
<p>Principal Strategies </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs closed a proprietary-trading unit called
Goldman Sachs Principal Strategies last year in response to new
financial regulations, known as the Volcker rule, that puts
limits on banks'' trading for their own account. Viniar has said
the company is waiting to see how the final rules are written to
determine if they will have to close other units. </p>
<p>Whatever effects there have been, you''ve seen already,
Viniar said today. We don''t see that big of an effect from the
Volcker rule on our revenues. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs shares, which closed yesterday at $168.55,
fell 0.4 percent in 2010 after doubling in 2009. They reached a
peak of $247.92 in October 2007 and closed as low as $52 in
November 2008. </p>
<p>The firm, which paid $550 million last year to settle a
U.S. regulator''s fraud suit, published a set of new business
standards last month after a committee of employees completed an
eight-month review of the company''s practices. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Manuel Baigorri" date="Feb 09, 2011  3:39 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-09/general-de-alquiler-jumps-to-highest-in-5-months-on-debt-accord.html"><headline>General de Alquiler Jumps to Highest in 5 Months on Debt Accord</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> General de Alquiler de Maquinaria SA,
a Spanish construction-machinery rental provider, rose to its
highest price in Madrid trading in five months after reaching an
agreement to delay debt repayments. </p>
<p>The Madrid-based company jumped 8.2 percent to 2.25 euros
as of 9:30 a.m., the stock''s highest price in five months, after
soaring as much as 12 percent. The stock has gained 49 percent
this year, valuing the company at 102.9 million euros ($140
million). </p>
<p>General de Alquiler reached an agreement with lenders to
delay the repayment of 118 million euros of debt coming due in
2011 and 2012, the company said in a regulatory filing late
yesterday. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Frances Schwartzkopff" date="Feb 09, 2011  2:37 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-09/jp-politikens-hus-eyes-rival-berlingske-media-borsen-says.html"><headline>JP/Politikens Hus Eyes Rival Berlingske Media, Borsen Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Danish newspaper publisher
JP/Politikens Hus would be interested in acquiring rival
Berlingske Media if owner Mecom Group Plc were to consider
selling the group, Borsen reported, citing Lars Munch,
JP/Politikens'' managing director. </p>
<p>JP/Politikens Hus is debt-free with considerable liquidity
and therefore ready for an acquisition, the Copenhagen-based
Borsen said, citing Munch.         </p>
<p>Click here for web link </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Edward Klump" date="Feb 10, 2011  4:26 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-10/exxon-mobil-seeks-partners-for-polish-shale-gas-concessions.html"><headline>Exxon Seeks Partners for Polish Shale-Gas Concessions</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Exxon Mobil Corp., the largest U.S.
oil company, is seeking partners for four concessions in the
Podlasie natural-gas shale basin in Poland. </p>
<p>The company owns the concessions and will retain its role
as operator, according to a posting on a Schlumberger Ltd.-
operated website today. A concession is a grant from a
government to allow exploration for petroleum. </p>
<p>Exxon said the area covers about 1 million gross acres. An
exploration well in the Minsk Mazowiecki concession scheduled
for this month is intended to help evaluate the gas potential,
the company said. Exxon said a seismic survey has been acquired
on the Wolomin concession. The other sections are known as
Legionowo and Wodynie-Lukow. </p>
<p>Exxon and Chevron Corp. are looking to tap Poland''s
unconventional gas reservoirs, which can require fracturing of
rock formations to help gas flow. Poland last year called on the
European Union to give more weight to shale gas in its energy
policy to reduce the reliance on imports. </p>
<p>Exxon''s posting shows the company is seeking offers to buy
as much as 49 percent of its equity in the areas, with
preference given to offers with full corporate approval. An
online data room is set to open Feb. 16 and close April 13.
Offer submissions are due on April 15. </p>
<p>The company continually reviews assets and their
contributions to operating needs and financial objectives,
Patrick McGinn, an Exxon spokesman, said today in an e-mail. </p>
<p>This does not indicate any shift in Exxon Mobil''s
interest in Polish shale gas opportunities, McGinn said. We
are continuing to evaluate the hydrocarbon resource potential in
Poland. </p>
<p>Exxon rose 65 cents to $83.20 as of 4 p.m. in New York
Stock Exchange composite trading. Exxon is based in Irving, Texas. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Wendy Leung and Billy Chan" date="Feb 10, 2011 11:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-10/disney-s-buzz-lightyear-battles-sharks-in-hong-kong-park-contest.html"><headline>Disney''s Buzz Lightyear Battles Sharks in Hong Kong Park Contest</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>For 15 minutes, 11-year-old Lily Li
stared through a glass panel at hammerhead sharks and bluefin
tuna in Hong Kong''s newest attraction, Aqua City. </p>
<p>It''s like a dream, said Li, from China''s Guangdong
province, who crowded with her mother and about 50 others at the
window, the width of a basketball court, on the packed Jan. 27
opening day. </p>
<p>The egg-shaped building, with nightly water shows, is part
of a HK$5.5 billion ($707 million) redevelopment by government-
owned Ocean Park to profit from a jump in mainland Chinese
visitors. The revamp adds pressure on Walt Disney Co.''s Hong
Kong Disneyland, which has trailed Ocean Park since its 2005
opening, has yet to make a profit, and is spending HK$3.6
billion on its own expansion, including Toy Story Land. </p>
<p>Home-grown theme parks like Ocean Park have proven that
they can compete with a big global corporation like Disney,
said Jonathan Galaviz, managing director of Galaviz  Co., a
tourism industry economist. As consumer disposal income
increases in Asia, the first place that Asian consumers will
spend that money on is travel, tourism, and fun experiences. </p>
<p>The tussle between Hong Kong Disneyland, which lost $92
million last year, and Ocean Park underscores the importance of
tourism in Asia, with countries and cities including Singapore
and Thailand getting as much as 16 percent of gross domestic
product from visitors, according to an October report by HSBC
Holdings Plc. Hong Kong, known for its dim sum restaurants and
luxury brand shops, tops the list of the 14 places HSBC surveyed. </p>
<p>Tickets Sold Out </p>
<p>Ocean Park sold all its admission tickets for Feb. 5 to
Feb. 7, with attendances during the Chinese New Year holidays,
started last week, up as much as 50 percent from a year ago,
spokeswoman Una Lau said. Disneyland''s two hotels were almost
fully-booked and attendances rose almost 10 percent for the
period, spokesman B.C. Lo said, declining to give specific
figures. </p>
<p>Mainland Chinese tourists, the only group of visitors to
increase spending in Hong Kong between 2008 and 2009, are
expected to more than double global spending to $110 billion by
2015, according to HSBC. The Chinese made about 54 million
outbound visits last year, the official Xinhua News Agency said
on Jan. 11, citing the nation''s tourism academy. That''s more
than the number of people living in South Korea or Spain. </p>
<p>We''re doing a lot of pre-arrival promotions in China,
Andrew Kam, managing director of Hong Kong Disneyland said in an
interview. We need to make sure they must come when they are
in Hong Kong. </p>
<p>Narrow Losses </p>
<p>The park, which cut its annual loss to HK$718 million from
HK$1.3 billion a year earlier, is marketing in secondary Chinese
cities including Jiangsu, Ningbo, Wenzhou and Shaoxing, Kam said.
It may soon introduce a HK$450 multi-day pass for Guangdong
visitors, he said. </p>
<p> Walt Disney''s profit in the three months ended Jan. 1
jumped 54 percent to $1.3 billion on higher theme-park
attendance and advertising sales growth at ESPN. The parks in
Paris and Hong Kong saw higher spending, the company said Feb. 8,
without providing specific numbers. </p>
<p>Mainland arrivals spend huge sums of money on shopping,
and they are the big drivers for Hong Kong retail sales, said
Paul Tang, a Hong Kong-based economist at Bank of East Asia Ltd.,
Chinese spending will not come down but keep going up. </p>
<p>Chinese visitors to Hong Kong jumped 26.3 percent last year. </p>
<p>Record Visitors </p>
<p>Attendances at Disneyland rose 13 percent to 5.2 million
for the fiscal year ended Oct. 2, with mainland visitors
increasing 32 percent, according to the company. That''s behind
the record 5.4 million paid visitors last year at 34-year old
Ocean Park, which houses pandas An An and Jia Jia. </p>
<p>Ocean Park has grown even in the midst of all other
developments, Chief Executive Officer Tom Mehrmann said in an
interview. In 2004, there were 15 theme parks in Asia excluding India, and by last year there were 35, he said. He expects
visitors from China to rise as much as 15 percent this year. </p>
<p>Every city is working hard on promoting their tourism,
said Joseph Tung, executive director of Hong Kong''s Travel
Industry Council. Fierce competition is unavoidable. </p>
<p> Genting Singapore Plc opened its Universal Studios theme
park last year, with attractions based on the Jurassic Park
movies and science-fiction television series Battlestar
Galactica. </p>
<p>Fifty million Chinese traveled abroad last year, so they
can easily fly to Singapore, the U.S. or other markets that are
fun, said Shaun Rein, Shanghai-based managing director of
China Market Research Group. </p>
<p> Shanghai Competition </p>
<p>Walt Disney and state-owned Shanghai Shendi Group Co. plan
to jointly open the first Disneyland Park in China in Shanghai.
The Shanghai government is spending 40 billion yuan on
infrastructure for the park, expected to open in 2015, in the
city''s Pudong area, according to the Shanghai Daily. </p>
<p>We''ll probably go to Shanghai Disneyland instead of
coming to Hong Kong in the future because the commute from
Beijing is shorter, said Zhang Wensheng, 40, who went to the
Hong Kong park for the first time last week with his six-year-
old son. I heard the park in Shanghai will be much bigger in
size too. </p>
<p>Hong Kong Disneyland, 47-percent owned by Burbank,
California-based Walt Disney, will fight back later this year
with the unveiling of Toy Story Land, based on the exploits
of toy spaceman Buzz Lightyear and his cowboy friend Woody. The
latest film in the series was nominated for an Academy Award for
Best Picture. Disney is hiring musician Danny Elfman to compose
music for another attraction Mystic Point, which along with
Grizzly Gulch will be ready by 2014. </p>
<p>Too Few Rides </p>
<p>The expansion may address tourist complaints that the
smallest of the Disney theme parks needs more rides, said China
Market Research''s Rein. Hong Kong Disneyland has fewer hotel
rooms than counterparts in Paris and Tokyo. </p>
<p>Disneyland seems a bit small and it feels like a waste of
time, said Ge Lin, 36, a visitor from Guizhou who prefers
Ocean Park because of the pandas and marine attractions. </p>
<p>Disneyland''s Kam said the expansions will help. The park is
also planning to lure more visitors from other parts of Asia
with an Indian restaurant and looking at introducing Halal food
to cater to Muslims, he said. </p>
<p>For now, he''s relying on Chinese tourists like Susan Liu,
who bought her family of four to Hong Kong from China for the
first time last month. They stayed in Disneyland''s hotel,
spending 7,000 yuan ($1,063) as the children acquired Mickey
Mouse bags full of princess outfits and toy cars. </p>
<p>We came here because of Disney, said Liu, 33, as she
watched her 8-year old daughter dash around in a Tinkerbell
dress. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ellen Rosen" date="Feb 10, 2011  8:20 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-10/jpmorgan-credit-ratings-volcker-rule-compliance.html"><headline>JPMorgan, Credit Ratings, Volcker Rule: Compliance</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> JPMorgan Chase  Co., sued by the
trustee for Bernard Madoff''s defunct firm for $6.4 billion for
allegedly aiding the con man''s fraud, asked a judge to remove
the case from bankruptcy court because it raises novel and
unsettled questions beyond the court''s scope and expertise. </p>
<p>In a lawsuit unsealed last week, Madoff trustee Irving
Picard accused JPMorgan of actively assisting Madoff''s crimes to
protect earnings from his bank accounts, in the process
violating federal banking law. The earnings were wholly
immaterial and the allegations about law-breaking were not
the domain of bankruptcy law, JPMorgan said yesterday. </p>
<p>Picard was appointed to liquidate the Madoff brokerage
firm, JPMorgan said in a filing in U.S. Bankruptcy Court in
Manhattan. Instead, he is mostly pursuing non-bankruptcy claims
on behalf of Madoff''s customers, the bank said. </p>
<p>The trustee is trying to pursue an enormous backdoor
class action to recoup damages incurred by individuals and
entities other than the firm to which he is the appointed
successor, said JPMorgan, the second-biggest U.S. bank. </p>
<p>Picard falsely accused the bank of complicity in the
largest securities fraud in U.S. history, JPMorgan said. The New
York-based bank said it has a right to a jury trial by law in an
appropriate federal court. </p>
<p>The Madoff trustee''s suit against JPMorgan is very
aggressive, bankruptcy lawyer Harvey Miller told Bloomberg
Television yesterday. He is pushing the envelope to the
limit. </p>
<p>According to a statement by Picard last week, JPMorgan had
a decades-long role as Madoff''s primary banker, aiding and
abetting the fraud. While the bank was warned Madoff may have
been running a Ponzi scheme and had a palpable concern that
Madoff was a fraud for years, it was not until October 2008
that it reported Madoff to government officials, the trustee''s
lawyers said in the statement. </p>
<p>The banks'' executives didn''t restrict the Madoff firm''s
bank account, even though it was being used to launder money
from the Ponzi scheme, they said. </p>
<p>In response, JPMorgan said Picard''s interpretation of
banking law would impose broad investigative duties on banks
that do not exist. </p>
<p>While federal banking laws do provide broad guidelines
for detecting money laundering, the guidelines have rarely been
interpreted by the courts, it said. </p>
<p>Picard asserted a novel claim that JPMorgan committed a
fraud on regulators including the U.S. Securities and Exchange
Commission and the Federal Reserve by not alerting them to
Madoff''s crimes, it said. </p>
<p>The Madoff liquidation case is Securities Investor
Protection Corp. v. Bernard L. Madoff Investment Securities
Inc., 08-01789, U.S. Bankruptcy Court, Southern District of New
York (Manhattan). The adversary case is Picard v. JPMorgan Chase
 Co., 10-AP-4932, U.S. Bankruptcy Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). </p>
<p>Compliance Action </p>
<p>U.K. Government, Banks Seal Bonus, Disclosure Accord </p>
<p>Chancellor of the Exchequer George Osborne yesterday
announced an agreement by Britain''s biggest banks -- Lloyds
Banking Group Plc, Barclays Plc, HSBC Holdings Plc and Royal
Bank of Scotland Group Plc -- to lower compensation from last
year''s levels. Under the agreement, the banks will disclose the
remuneration details of their five most-senior employees below
board level, without naming the individuals. The announcement
came a day after the chancellor raised tax on the industry by
800 million pounds ($1.3 billion). </p>
<p>Britain needs to move from retribution to recovery,
Osborne told the House of Commons in London. The banks will
lend more money, especially to small businesses, pay more taxes
and pay smaller bonuses, be more transparent about bonuses they
do pay and make a greater contribution to our regional
economy. </p>
<p>The deal follows two months of talks during which ministers
have wrangled with bank chiefs over demands for lower bonuses as
the government raises taxes and reduces spending to narrow a
record budget deficit. Barclays Chief Executive Officer Robert
Diamond said Jan. 11 the time for apologies and remorse from
banks following the financial crisis was over. Britain''s bankers
learn the size of their bonuses this month and next. Following
the negotiations, known as Project Merlin, Lloyds, HSBC, RBS,
Barclays and Banco Santander U.K. also agreed to make loans of
about 190 billion pounds to companies to help bolster the
economic recovery, Osborne said. </p>
<p>The banks are the clear winners here, said Ralph Silva,
a strategist at London-based Silva Research Network, which
provides research to financial companies. The banks had
already said they were going to increase lending to businesses
and that was to be expected given that the economy is
recovering. Coupled with that the salary disclosures are pretty
pointless as we aren''t going to know what the star traders
earn. </p>
<p>The agreement was criticized as having no real effect. Andrew Tyrie, the Conservative head of Parliament''s cross-party
Treasury Committee, said little progress had been made on
bonuses in the accord. </p>
<p>Without further transparency on bonuses we will never
know whether banks are fueling risks and mistakes for which one
day we may have to pay as a result of the way they misallocate
risk, Tyrie told lawmakers. </p>
<p>Ed Balls, who speaks for the opposition Labour Party on
financial affairs, said the agreement is vague, toothless and
not a substitute for proper competition. </p>
<p>The agreement is the latest occasion that RBS and Lloyds
have accepted the need to show restraint on bonuses, with both
banks first making the pledge in 2009. The state has majority
stakes in the two lenders after the previous Labour government
provided about 1 trillion pounds in bailouts and guarantees to
support the financial system. </p>
<p>For more, click here. </p>
<p>Fed Confirms Banks Would Have 2 Years to Adapt to Volcker Rule </p>
<p>The Federal Reserve confirmed yesterday that banks would
generally have two years to comply with the Volcker Rule, which
bars bank holding companies from trading for their own accounts,
once its provisions become effective. </p>
<p>The Fed yesterday announced approval of a final rule to
implement the provisions of the Volcker Rule. It said in a
statement that the final rule is substantially similar to a
proposal published in November. The Volcker Rule hasn''t yet been
completed. </p>
<p>SEC Seeks Comment on Cutting Credit-Rating References </p>
<p>The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission is proposing to
replace references to credit ratings in forms used to register
securities. </p>
<p>SEC commissioners voted 5-0 yesterday to seek comment on a
rule that would remove credit ratings from a list of criteria
that could qualify issuers for expedited sale of non-convertible
securities. Ratings would be replaced by a new test tied to the
amount of debt an issuer has sold in the preceding three years. </p>
<p>The global community has continued to express concern
with credit-rating reliance being embedded into regulatory
frameworks, SEC Chairman Mary Schapiro said in a statement.
We believe that having issued $1 billion of registered non-
convertible securities over the prior three years would
generally correspond with a wide following in the marketplace. </p>
<p>The Dodd-Frank Act requires federal regulators including
the SEC to replace references to credit ratings in their rules
by July 21. The regulatory overhaul enacted last year calls on
agencies to replace the reference with an appropriate new
standard for measuring creditworthiness. </p>
<p>Lawmakers took aim at credit-rating companies after firms
including Moody''s Corp. and McGraw-Hill Cos.'' Standard  Poor''s
unit gave top rankings to subprime mortgage bonds whose collapse
sparked the worst financial crisis since the Great Depression. </p>
<p>The Financial Crisis Inquiry Commission, assigned by
Congress to find the causes of the meltdown, said in its final
report last month that poor performance by credit-rating firms
was a significant contributor to the collapse. </p>
<p>The SEC is seeking comment through March 28 on the proposed
rule, which would also remove credit ratings from other agency
documents related to the short-form registrations. The proposal
is the first of a series of steps the SEC is taking under the
Dodd-Frank requirement to remove all references to ratings. </p>
<p>SEC Commissioner Troy Paredes, one of two Republicans on
the panel, said he would be keenly interested in comments on
the number of firms that might be inconvenienced by the change. </p>
<p>The rules could hinder capital formation by making it
more difficult for some public companies to use the streamline
registration form, said Bradley J. Bondi, a law partner at
Cadwalader, Wickersham  Taft LLP in Washington, in an e-mail. </p>
<p>It will be important for any affected companies to
comment on the SEC''s proposed changes, said Bondi, who
investigated credit-rating firms for the FCIC. </p>
<p>An SEC staff study, however, found that fewer than 5
percent of issuers from 2006 through 2008 would have been
prevented from using short-form registration if the proposed
rule had been in place. </p>
<p>SEC Said to Probe Insider Trading Through Exchange-Traded Funds </p>
<p>The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission is
investigating whether exchange-traded funds are being used to
hide insider trading, a person with knowledge of the probe said. </p>
<p>The funds, which usually track an index and trade like
stocks, enable buyers to bet on price changes without trading
futures. An investor with non-public information about a company
may be able to hide illegal orders by trading in a fund that
includes that stock instead of buying or selling the equity
directly, the person said. </p>
<p>The number of exchange-traded funds has surged since they
were created in 1993, widening investors'' access to different
assets, including commodities. The SEC has said it is using
data-driven techniques to find patterns of insider trading and
market manipulation. </p>
<p>The probe was previously reported by the Financial Times. </p>
<p>Bank of England, Finance Regulator Propose Bank Auditor Rules </p>
<p>The Bank of England and the Financial Services Authority
proposed rules that would require auditors to share information
with regulators. </p>
<p>The rules would apply to auditors when they are dealing
with firms regulated by the FSA and require the external
auditors of certain firms to have formal meetings with the
regulator, the FSA said in a statement today. </p>
<p>This increased coordination will enhance the ability of
the FSA to scrutinize specific accounting practices and related
judgments in order to understand fully their implications and to
highlight emerging problems, the FSA said in the statement. </p>
<p>The London-based regulator said last year that bank
auditors must pay more attention to possible management bias in
the banking industry after accounting firms failed to uncover
problems before the financial crisis. Investors lost confidence
in banks'' financial reporting during the early stages of the
credit crunch because they didn''t reflect the reality of
emerging problems, the FSA said. </p>
<p>The FSA and the Financial Reporting Council, which
regulates accounting firms, said in a separate statement that
they reached an agreement to share more information to improve
oversight of audits at finance firms. </p>
<p>There are concerns some auditors may not be exercising
sufficient professional skepticism in their approach to the
audit of key areas of management judgment, said Richard
Thorpe, the FSA''s accounting and auditing section leader. The
FSA relies on audited financial information to meet its
regulatory objectives and it is imperative that we have
confidence in the information provided. </p>
<p>The Bank of England will oversee prudential regulation by
the end of 2012 in an overhaul of the current regulatory
structure. The FSA will be replaced by an independent Consumer
Protection and Markets Authority. </p>
<p>Compliance Policy </p>
<p>Senators Urge Regulators to Move Cautiously on Derivatives Rules </p>
<p>A bipartisan group of U.S. senators urged regulators
implementing derivatives measures under the Dodd-Frank Act to
move cautiously so the rules can be completed without
unintended consequences. </p>
<p>The senators, in a Feb. 8 letter signed by 13 members of
the Senate Banking and Agriculture committees, warned Treasury
Secretary Timothy F. Geithner, Federal Reserve Chairman Ben S.
Bernanke and two other top officials against overly
prescriptive rules that might push market participants abroad.
If the major overhaul of our derivatives market is implemented
hastily, agency rulemakings could have negative effects on our
economy at a time when we can least afford it, the lawmakers
said in the letter signed by three Democrats and 10 Republicans
including Senator Mike Johanns of Nebraska, who serves on both
the Banking and Agriculture committees. </p>
<p>The Securities and Exchange Commission and the Commodity
Futures Trading Commission are leading efforts to regulate the
$583 trillion over-the-counter derivatives market after largely
unregulated trades helped fuel the credit crisis. SEC Chairman
Mary Schapiro and CFTC Chairman Gary Gensler also were sent
copies of the letter. </p>
<p>The lawmakers urged regulators to exempt end-users --
non-financial firms that use derivatives to hedge business risk
-- from margin requirements stipulated by Dodd-Frank. Failing to
do so would blatantly disregard the law''s intent, they said. </p>
<p>Swaps and other derivatives are financial instruments whose
value is based on an underlying security or benchmark, such as a
stock option. Companies may use them to hedge risks and other
investors employ them to bet on markets. </p>
<p>The letter was signed by Republican Senators Pat Roberts of
Kansas, Thad Cochran of Mississippi, Ron Johnson of Wisconsin,
David Vitter of Louisiana, Mike Crapo of Idaho, Kay Bailey
Hutchison of Texas, Roger Wicker of Mississippi, John Boozman of
Arkansas and Jerry Moran of Kansas as well as Johanns. Democrats
Max Baucus of Montana, Herb Kohl of Wisconsin and Jon Tester of
Montana also signed the letter. </p>
<p>Republican Threat to Cut SEC Funding May Delay Fiduciary Rules </p>
<p>Republicans in the U.S. Congress may withhold funds from
the Securities and Exchange Commission, delaying a new standard
for brokers and registered investment advisers, said
Representative Barney Frank. </p>
<p>The SEC''s potential budget shortfall will have the effect
of either delaying or slowing down at best fiduciary
rulemaking, Frank of Massachusetts, the senior Democrat on the
Financial Services Committee, said in a telephone interview. The
agency was asked by Congress to look at the effectiveness of
existing rules governing brokers and investment advisers as part
of the Dodd-Frank financial services overhaul law enacted July
21. </p>
<p>Without money for staff to help implement a common standard
and follow up on complaints, the SEC won''t be able to enforce
it, said Frank, a coauthor of the legislation. The SEC, which
can make the rules without additional Congressional approval,
recommended in a staff report delivered to Congress Jan. 21 that
brokers and registered investment advisers who give personalized
investment advice follow a uniform fiduciary standard. </p>
<p>Broker-dealers currently are held to a suitability standard
that calls for advice that meets their clients'' needs when a
product is sold, instead of the fiduciary duty followed by
registered investment advisers to put their clients'' best
interests first. Rulemaking is scheduled for between April and
July, according to the SEC''s website. </p>
<p>A dramatic spending increase to fund the SEC and CFTC, as
envisioned by the authors of the Dodd-Frank legislation, would
further the mindset that our nation''s problems can be solved
with more spending, not more efficiency, Representative Scott Garrett, chairman of the Financial Services subcommittee that
oversees the SEC, said Jan. 25 in a statement. </p>
<p>For more, click here. </p>
<p>Wells Fargo Says Fiduciary Standard May Narrow Customer Choice </p>
<p> Wells Fargo  Co.''s head of brokerage operations said banks
may reduce the number of investment products offered to
customers if regulators impose a fiduciary standard on brokers. </p>
<p>The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission''s proposal for
a common fiduciary standard for brokers and registered advisers
may increase the need for due diligence from banks and advisers,
Senior Executive Vice President David Carroll said yesterday at
a Miami investor conference. </p>
<p>The SEC''s plan would make all brokers and registered
investment advisers who provide personalized investment advice
adhere to a common standard when dealing with clients. Broker-
dealers currently must ensure only that an investment product
and accompanying advice is suitable for their clients'' needs. A
fiduciary duty would mean putting clients'' best interests first,
which might require passing up choices with bigger commissions. </p>
<p>It''s going to cause the investment menu to narrow,
Carroll said. We won''t have 6,000 mutual funds in our network
probably two years from now like we do today. </p>
<p>Wells Fargo, with $1.2 trillion in client assets and based
in San Francisco, is the third-largest among U.S. brokerages,
behind Morgan Stanley Smith Barney and Bank of America Corp.''s
Merrill Lynch. </p>
<p>The process of developing the standard is moving along the
way Wells Fargo would like because it''s being developed by
regulators and not by congressional staff, he said. </p>
<p>We have been driving our brokerage business toward a
fiduciary model starting back in 2004, Carroll said. So
we''re pretty pleased with where this is headed. </p>
<p>For more, click here. </p>
<p>Courts </p>
<p>Freeman Told Judge Inside Tips Came From Taiwan </p>
<p>Former SAC Capital Advisors LP portfolio manager Noah
Freeman told a judge this week that his illegal inside tips came
from sources in California, New York, Texas and Taiwan,
according to a court transcript. </p>
<p>Freeman, 35, pleaded guilty on Feb. 7 and agreed to
cooperate with Manhattan federal prosecutors in their probe of
insider trading by hedge funds. A transcript of his guilty plea,
which was initially under seal, was made public today. </p>
<p>In his plea, Freeman said he worked at two hedge funds
between 2005 and 2010, which he didn''t identify, and on several
occasions paid insiders for detailed financial information
including revenues and, on some occasions, gross margins and
earnings per share. </p>
<p>Some of the people with whom I -- from whom I received
information were based in other states including California, New
York and Texas, and others were abroad including in Taiwan,
Freeman said, according to the transcript. </p>
<p>The case is U.S. v. Barai, 11-mag-00332, U.S. District
Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). </p>
<p>Activision Blizzard Loses EU Court Challenge to Antitrust Fine </p>
<p>An Activision Blizzard Inc. unit lost a bid to have the
European Union''s highest court reduce an antitrust fine levied
on a cartel involving Nintendo Co. </p>
<p>The European Court of Justice, the 27-nation EU''s top
tribunal, today dismissed the appeal, ruling that the documents
EU regulators had relied on constituted sufficient evidence of
the existence of an agreement between Activision Blizzard and
Nintendo which was contrary to EU law. </p>
<p>The European Commission, the EU antitrust agency, fined
Nintendo and seven distributors 167.8 million euros ($228.9
million) for colluding between 1991 and 1998 to raise prices of
games and consoles. Nintendo won an appeal to the EU''s second-
highest court in 2009 cutting its fine by 20 percent to 119.2
million euros from 149.1 million euros. </p>
<p>The Belgian unit of Germany''s CD-Contact Data GmbH, which
has since become Activision Blizzard Germany, was the only
company in the cartel to appeal its fine to the EU''s top court.
The lower EU court in 2009 halved its 1 million euro-fine to
500,000 euros because of the company''s passive role. CD-
Contact became Nintendo''s importer for Belgium in 1997,
according to the commission. </p>
<p>The case is C-260/09 P, Activision Blizzard Germany
(anciennement CD-Contact Data) v European Commission. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Rudy Ruitenberg" date="Feb 10, 2011  5:17 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-10/goldman-advises-keeping-soybean-cotton-corn-bets-update1-.html"><headline>Goldman Advises Keeping Soybean, Cotton, Corn Bets</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Investors should maintain bets on
higher prices for soybeans, cotton and corn, Goldman Sachs Group
Inc. said after the U.S. Department of Agriculture lowered
stockpile estimates. </p>
<p>The bank''s crop outlook is unchanged after the USDA
released new projections yesterday, analyst Damien Courvalin
wrote in an e-mailed report. The USDA cut its forecasts for
inventories before this year''s harvests and said world supplies
of crops including corn, wheat and soybeans will slump 2.2
percent. </p>
<p>Shrinking stockpiles have pushed up food costs, helping to
spark protests and riots across North Africa and the Middle
East. World food prices climbed to a record in January, the United Nations said on Feb. 3. </p>
<p>U.S. corn planting will likely climb to the detriment of
soybeans this year, as corn margins will likely remain most
appealing to U.S. farmers in February, Courvalin wrote.
Acreage competition will keep crop-price correlation
elevated. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs kept its recommendation to hold long
positions in Chicago March-delivery corn futures and November-
delivery soybeans, as well as New York-traded December-delivery
cotton futures, the report shows. </p>
<p>Soybeans, Cotton </p>
<p>The bank forecasts soybean prices will rise to $16 a bushel
in the next three months, while the six- and 12-month target
price is $15.75. </p>
<p>While soybeans may underperform corn in the near term, we
continue to expect further price strength in 2011, as a loss of
U.S. acreage would create high risks of another deficit in 2011-
12, Courvalin wrote. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs forecasts cotton prices in three months'' time
at $1.50 a pound, with a six- and 12-month forecast of $1.25. </p>
<p>Inventory levels remain critically low, the analyst
wrote. The large deficit and strong emerging-market demand
require significantly higher new-crop prices to secure
sufficient U.S. acreage. </p>
<p>Corn may rise to $7.15 a bushel in the three-month period
before falling to $6.75 later in the year, according to Goldman
Sachs. Wheat prices may drop to $7.75 a bushel within three
months before sliding further to $7.50, the report shows. </p>
<p>Ethanol Demand </p>
<p>We continue to expect further upside in corn prices on
continued strong U.S. ethanol demand, Courvalin wrote. We
believe wheat inventories remain sufficient to absorb the 2010-
11 supply shortfall and view wheat prices as too elevated
relative to corn and soybeans. </p>
<p>Stockpiling in the face of food inflation and social unrest
is likely to continue to support milling-wheat prices, creating
upside risk to the three-month price forecast, according to
the analyst. </p>
<p>March-delivery corn last traded at $6.96 a bushel on the
Chicago Board of Trade and November-delivery soybeans were at
$13.97 a bushel. Cotton for December delivery was at $1.27 a
pound on ICE Futures U.S. in New York. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Janet Ong" date="Feb 10, 2011  4:20 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-10/mobiletron-elect-january-sales-rise-43-63-table-1533-tt.html"><headline>MOBILETRON ELECT January Sales Rise 43.63% (Table) : 1533 TT</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>MOBILETRON ELECT said unconsolidated sales
in January rose 43.63% to NT$142,845,000 from NT$99,453,000,
according to a statement filed to the Taiwan Stock Exchange. </p>
<p>(Figures are in thousands of New Taiwan dollars) </p>
<p>================================================================= </p>
<p>1/2011           1/2010
Sales            142,845           99,453    
YOY%              43.63%  </p>
<p>-----------------Year-to-date-----------------
Sales            142,845           99,453    
YOY%              43.63% 
=================================================================
 </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Janet Ong" date="Feb 10, 2011  3:49 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-10/general-biologic-january-sales-fall-12-66-table-4117-tt.html"><headline>GENERAL BIOLOGIC January Sales Fall 12.66% (Table) : 4117 TT</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>GENERAL BIOLOGIC said unconsolidated sales
in January fell 12.66% to NT$8,215,000 from NT$9,406,000,
according to a statement filed to the Taiwan Stock Exchange. </p>
<p>(Figures are in thousands of New Taiwan dollars) </p>
<p>================================================================= </p>
<p>1/2011           1/2010
Sales             8,215            9,406     
YOY%             -12.66%  </p>
<p>-----------------Year-to-date-----------------
Sales             8,215            9,406     
YOY%             -12.66% 
=================================================================
 </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Janet Ong" date="Feb 10, 2011  2:26 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-10/walton-chaintech-january-sales-fall-22-46-table-2425-tt.html"><headline>WALTON CHAINTECH January Sales Fall 22.46% (Table) : 2425 TT</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>WALTON CHAINTECH said unconsolidated sales
in January fell 22.46% to NT$178,709,000 from NT$230,488,000,
according to a statement filed to the Taiwan Stock Exchange. </p>
<p>(Figures are in thousands of New Taiwan dollars) </p>
<p>================================================================= </p>
<p>1/2011           1/2010
Sales            178,709          230,488    
YOY%             -22.46%  </p>
<p>-----------------Year-to-date-----------------
Sales            178,709          230,488    
YOY%             -22.46% 
=================================================================
 </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Inyoung Hwang" date="Feb 11, 2011  3:31 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-11/coca-cola-abbott-t-rowe-price-may-boost-dividends-next-week.html"><headline>Coca-Cola, Abbott, T. Rowe Price May Boost Dividends Next Week</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Coca-Cola Co., Abbott Laboratories
and T. Rowe Price Group Inc. are among 12 Standard  Poor''s 500
Index companies that may boost their dividends next week,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola, the world''s largest soft-drink maker, may raise
its quarterly payout to 48 cents from 44 cents, according to
Bloomberg estimates that factor in earnings and options prices.
Drugmaker Abbott may increase its dividend to 48 cents from 44
cents, while T. Rowe may declare a payout of 30 cents, up from
27 cents. </p>
<p>Two-thirds of dividend-paying companies in the U.S. equity
benchmark will return more money to owners this year after the
biggest dividend decline in dollar value on record in 2009,
according to Howard Silverblatt, senior index analyst at SP. </p>
<p>The companies are holding a near-record amount of cash
after earnings topped estimates for seven straight quarters. As
of Dec. 31, cash on balance sheets totaled $3.33 trillion, 12.6
percent of assets, according to Ned Davis Research Inc. in Venice, Florida. Cash peaked in the third quarter at $3.46
trillion, 13.1 percent of assets, according to Ned Davis. </p>
<p>Other companies projected to increase dividends this week,
in cents: </p>

COMPANY                       PAYOUT         PROJECTION
Sempra Energy                 39             50
Genuine Parts Co.             41             42
Public Service                34.25          35.25
Enterprise Group Inc.
PGE Corp.                    45.5           49
EOG Resources Inc.            15.5           16.5
Sherwin-Williams Co.          36             37
Colgate-Palmolive Co.         53             57
Sealed Air Corp.              13             14
Ventas Inc.                   53.5           55

<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Feb 11, 2011 11:43 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-11/jpmorgan-chase-names-bisignano-to-run-home-loans-as-losses-erode-earnings.html"><headline>JPMorgan Taps Bisignano to Oversee Home Lending</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> JPMorgan Chase  Co., the second-
largest U.S. bank by assets, named Chief Administrative Officer
Frank Bisignano to oversee mortgage lending as home-loan losses
erode the company''s earnings. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon and Charlie Scharf, the
CEO of Retail Financial Services, told employees in an e-mail
today that David Lowman, the unit''s CEO who joined JPMorgan from Citigroup Inc. in 2006, will report to Bisignano, effective
immediately. </p>
<p>As you know, our home lending business has gone through a
period of enormous challenge and change, the e-mail said. </p>
<p>Bisignano takes over the unit as it struggles with the
worst housing decline since the Great Depression and soured
mortgage investments inherited from the 2008 acquisitions of
Washington Mutual Inc. and Bear Stearns Cos. Bank of America
Corp., the biggest U.S. lender, split its mortgage unit this
month and put Terry Laughlin in charge of cleaning up bad loans. </p>
<p>Bisignano, 51, retains most of his administrative
responsibilities, including overseeing technology, real estate,
procurement and security. He joined JPMorgan in 2005 from
Citigroup where he headed its global transactions services
business and was a member of Citigroup''s management committee.
The Brooklyn native serves on the boards or is a trustee of New
York-based nonprofit groups including The National September 11
Memorial  Museum and St. Patrick''s Cathedral. </p>
<p>Last month, Bisignano received 115,164 shares of restricted
stock worth $5 million and 76,924 stock options for his
performance last year, according to securities filings. His full
compensation wasn''t disclosed. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Feb 11, 2011  9:43 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-11/jpmorgan-chief-dimon-calls-fannie-freddie-biggest-disasters-of-all-time-.html"><headline>Dimon Calls Fannie, Freddie Biggest Disasters'' Ever</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> JPMorgan Chase  Co. Chief Executive
Officer Jamie Dimon said government-sponsored mortgage companies
Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac were the biggest disasters of all
time and a leading cause of the U.S. financial crisis. </p>
<p>That one was an accident waiting to happen, Dimon said
in an Oct. 20, 2010, interview with the Financial Crisis Inquiry
Commission. The congressional panel yesterday released audio
files of interviews gathered during its 18-month investigation
into the causes of the crisis. </p>
<p>U.S. Treasury Secretary Timothy F. Geithner recommended
gradually winding down Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac in a proposal
sent to Congress today. The Obama administration is trying to
end taxpayer support for the companies and wean the $11 trillion
mortgage market from its dependence on the government.
Washington-based Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac, in McLean, Virginia, have taken more than $150 billion in federal aid since
regulators seized their operations in September 2008. </p>
<p>We all knew about it, we all worried about it, no one did
anything about it, Dimon, 54, told investigators. New York-
based JPMorgan is the second-biggest U.S. lender by assets
behind Bank of America Corp. </p>
<p>Subprime Lending </p>
<p>Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac, which were privately owned by
shareholders, received federal tax breaks and other subsidies to
help fulfill their public mission to bolster the U.S. housing
market. Dimon said they financed risky loans like subprime
mortgages that helped drive more than $1.9 trillion in
writedowns at financial institutions across the world. </p>
<p>Dimon said lax lending standards across the industry and
excessive leverage and risk-taking by banks helped cause the
crisis. </p>
<p>You kind of got sucked into this whole sense of security
because there were no losses, Dimon said. I would also say
people lied. There was more and more of that in a frothy
market. </p>
<p>The report delivered today by Geithner and Housing and
Urban Development Secretary Shaun Donovan presents three
approaches for a future housing finance system. It calls on the
government to shrink and ultimately wind down Fannie Mae and
Freddie Mac, which regulators said were insolvent after the two
suffered record losses from investments in subprime and other
risky home loans. </p>
<p>Winding Down </p>
<p>This is a plan for fundamental reform -- to wind down the
GSEs, strengthen consumer protection and preserve access to
affordable housing for people who need it, Geithner said in a
statement accompanying the report. The report also pledges
ongoing U.S. government support to make sure Fannie and Freddie
can make good on their debt payments and mortgage guarantees.
The companies don''t lend directly to consumers. Instead, they
buy mortgages from private lenders, package them into securities
and guarantee timely loan payments to investors who buy the
mortgage bonds. </p>
<p>Together, Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac accounted for
67 percent of the mortgage bonds issued in the third quarter of
last year, according to U.S. government data. Government
mortgage bond insurer Ginnie Mae accounted for 29 percent,
leaving about 4 percent to private lenders. </p>
<p>President Barack Obama''s plan doesn''t endorse a particular
option or offer legislation. All three proposals seek to end
taxpayer support for Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By James Attwood" date="Feb 11, 2011  7:04 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-11/jpmorgan-may-start-chilean-brokerage-mid-year-mercurio-reports.html"><headline>JPMorgan May Start Chilean Brokerage Mid-Year, Mercurio Reports</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. probably will
be ready to begin brokerage operations in Chile by the end of
the first half of this year after receiving regulatory approval
last month, newspaper El Mercurio reported, citing the firm''s
country head Vicente Monge. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Anuchit Nguyen" date="Feb 11, 2011  4:48 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-11/electricity-generating-kim-eng-siam-city-thai-equity-preview.html"><headline>Thailand Stocks: Electricity Generating, Inoue Rubber, Kim Eng</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Shares of the following companies
had unusual moves in Thailand trading. Stock symbols are in
parentheses and prices are as of 4:30 p.m. close in Bangkok. </p>
<p>The SET Index rose 0.48, or 0.1 percent, to 949.57. The
gauge has declined 3.6 percent this week, the biggest weekly
drop since the week to May 28. </p>
<p> Electricity Generating Pcl (EGCO TB), Thailand''s smallest
publicly traded power producer by market value, fell 0.5 percent
to 103 baht. The company said profit in 2010 declined 14 percent
to 6.79 billion baht ($220 million), or 12.90 baht a share. </p>
<p>Inoue Rubber (Thailand) Pcl (IRC TB), a Thai maker of
motorcycle tires, dropped 2.4 percent to 12.4 baht, the lowest
close since Dec. 22. Net income for the three months ended Dec.
31 declined 52 percent to 50.4 million baht. </p>
<p>Kim Eng Securities (Thailand) Pcl (KEST TB), the country''s
largest stock brokerage, gained 4.2 percent to 15 baht, the
steepest increase since Oct. 1. The company will pay a final
dividend of 1.18 baht a share for its 2010 earnings. That was an
increase from a payout of 1 baht a share in the same period last
year. The company also plans to sell as much as 2 billion baht
of bonds, it said in a regulatory filing. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By James Kraus" date="Feb 11, 2011  3:17 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-11/goldman-michigan-reach-auction-rate-settlement-free-press-says.html"><headline>Goldman, Michigan Reach Auction Rate Settlement, Free Press Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and Michigan reached a settlement over auction rate securities, the Detroit Free Press reported, citing Ken Ross, commissioner of
the state''s Office of Financial and Insurance Regulation. </p>
<p>As part of the settlement, Goldman agreed to pay as much as
$32 million to any Michigan customer who purchased the
securities through the bank, and $91,000 to state agencies, the
newspaper reported. </p>
<p>Click here for web link </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Aydan Eksin" date="Feb 11, 2011  2:41 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-11/coca-cola-icecek-halkbank-teb-turkey-equity-market-preview.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Icecek, Halkbank, TEB: Turkey Equity Market Preview</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The following stocks may be active
in Turkey. Symbols are in parentheses and prices are from the
last close. </p>
<p>Turkey''s benchmark ISE National 100 index fell 1,148.08, or
1.8 percent, to 64,421.53 yesterday. </p>
<p> Coca-Cola Icecek AS (CCOLA TI): The company which bottles
Coke beverages in Turkey, reported fourth-quarter net income of
147.5 million liras ($92 million) in a preliminary filing for
tax purposes only, according to a statement to the Istanbul
Stock Exchange today. It will report full earnings for 2010 to
the bourse later this month. Coca-Cola Icecek dropped 40 kurus,
or 2.1 percent, to 18.95 liras. </p>
<p> Turk Ekonomi Bankasi AS (TEBNK TI): The Turkish bank part-
owned by BNP Paribas SA of France, said profit last year rose 43
percent to 300.3 million liras ($188 million), according to a
statement to the bourse after the market closed yesterday. TEB,
as the bank is known, was expected to earn 236.4 million liras,
according to the average estimate in a Bloomberg survey of 14
analysts. TEB rose 2 kurus, or 1 percent, to 2.02 liras. </p>
<p> Turkiye Halk Bankasi AS (HALKB TI): The state-run Turkish
bank''s profit last year rose 23 percent to 2.01 billion liras
($1.3 billion), it said in a press release distributed to
reporters in Istanbul today. The profit matched an average
estimate of 28 analysts in a Bloomberg survey. Halkbank declined
40 kurus, or 3.1 percent, to 12.35 liras. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Max Abelson" date="Feb 11, 2011 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-11/goldman-sachs-former-chief-whitehead-calls-nyse-s-planned-sale-an-insult-.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Former Chief Whitehead Says NYSE Deal An Insult''</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>John C. Whitehead isn''t celebrating
the 219-year-old New York Stock Exchange''s plan to be acquired
by Germany''s 18-year-old Deutsche Boerse AG. </p>
<p>I think it''s a terrible idea and I hope it can be
stopped, Whitehead, the 88-year-old former co-chairman of Goldman Sachs Group Inc., said in an interview yesterday. It
would be an insult to New York City, and New York State, and
indeed to all America. </p>
<p>The erstwhile U.S. deputy secretary of state, NYSE director
and Lower Manhattan Development Corp. chairman said his
experience gives him the credibility to speak out against the
potential takeover. </p>
<p>I speak out rarely, and this is one time when I can''t
hold myself back, he said, adding that the exchange is an
important symbol of American capitalism and of New York
City''s status as a global financial center. I think of it as a
holy institution, he said. </p>
<p>Whitehead, whose autobiography A Life in Leadership
chronicles his command of a landing craft at Omaha Beach on D-
Day, said his opposition has nothing to do with his World War II
experiences. I''d be anti- any other country buying the New
York Stock Exchange, he said. It''s not that it''s German. </p>
<p>Whitehead, who joined Goldman Sachs in 1947, said he
remembers visiting the exchange in his early days at the firm. </p>




Photographer: Marko Georgiev/Bloomberg

<p>
John Whitehead, former co-chairman of Goldman Sachs, seen here in 2008. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Wayne" date="Feb 13, 2011 10:33 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-13/jpmorgan-is-lending-aggressively-to-businesses-dimon-says.html"><headline>JPMorgan Is Lending Aggressively'' to Businesses, Dimon Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The idea that banks slowed lending
during the U.S. recession is a huge misconception, JPMorgan
Chase  Co. Chairman and Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon
said. </p>
<p>Any lending slowdown was a result of reduced demand for
capital from businesses and consumers, Dimon said in a Jan. 27
interview broadcast today on CNN''s Fareed Zakaria GPS. Dimon
said his bank loaned $1.4 trillion to corporations and
individuals worldwide in 2010, up pretty substantially from
2009. </p>
<p>We are lending aggressively to corporate, to middle
market, he said. If you talk to most economists, there is a
demand issue. A lot of people don''t need the money. </p>
<p>Dimon said the banking industry in the U.S. is far less
concentrated than in Europe or Asia, and that JPMorgan could
fail without putting the nation''s financial system at risk. The
nation should create a process Dimon called minimally damaging
bankruptcy for big, dumb banks to unwind troubled institutions
such as Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. </p>
<p>Dimon defended his bank''s lobbying against President Barack Obama''s financial regulation overhaul. </p>
<p>We fought the parts of the reform we thought were
irrational, he said. JPMorgan supports oversight
committees for the financial system, clearing houses for
trading in derivatives, and better consumer protection, he
said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Campbell" date="Feb 14, 2011  1:33 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-14/microsoft-s-ballmer-sees-windows-phone-update-in-early-march.html"><headline>Microsoft''s Ballmer Sees Windows Phone Update in March</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Microsoft Corp. will release the
first Windows Phone 7 update in early March, Chief Executive
Officer Steve Ballmer said. </p>
<p>The operating system, which got a boost last week after Nokia Oyj said the platform would be its primary mobile-phone
software, will get features this year such as Internet Explorer
9, Twitter and multitasking capabilities, Ballmer said today at
the Mobile World Congress in Barcelona, Spain. </p>
<p>Increasingly, consumers, developers and mobile operators
won''t just choose a phone, they''re really choosing a platform,
he said. </p>
<p>Microsoft is pulling out all the stops to reverse market
share declines in its mobile-phone software as smartphone sales
are estimated by analysts to pass personal computers in the next
two years. The deal with Nokia, the world''s biggest maker of
handsets, is a bet the two companies together can challenge Apple Inc. and Google Inc. </p>
<p>Nokia Chief Executive Officer Stephen Elop, a former
president of Microsoft''s business unit, said his company will
get billions in benefits from the partnership. Andy Lees,
president of Microsoft''s mobile division, declined to tell
analysts exactly how much Microsoft will pay. The agreement
involves the transfer of revenue from search, advertising,
geographic-location services and royalty payments, he said. </p>
<p>Microsoft released a complete overhaul to its mobile
operating system last year. Called Windows Phone 7, 2 million
copies of the program were shipped in its first quarter on the
market, a number analysts termed disappointing. </p>
<p>Brand Awareness </p>
<p>Microsoft said last month that customer satisfaction for
the product is at 93 percent and brand awareness jumped 22
points to 66 percent since the release. The Redmond, Washington-
based company is now trying to add features and get the product
in the hands of as many customers as possible. </p>
<p>Microsoft''s share of the smartphone operating-system market
declined to 2.8 percent in the third quarter, from 7.9 percent a
year earlier, according to Gartner Inc. The share of Google''s
Android platform rose to 25.5 percent from 3.5 percent, while
Apple''s iOS share declined to 16.7 percent from 17.1 percent. </p>
<p>Phones with the new Microsoft software went on sale Oct. 21
in Europe and Nov. 8 in the U.S. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Vivek Shankar" date="Feb 15, 2011  5:25 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-15/goldman-sachs-shutting-down-global-macro-trading-desk-wsj-says.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Shutting Down Global Macro Trading Desk, WSJ Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Goldman Sachs Group Inc. is shutting
down its Global Macro Proprietary Trading desk to comply with
the Dodd-Frank law''s Volcker rule, the Wall Street Journal
reported, citing an unidentified person familiar with the
matter. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Feb 15, 2011  2:56 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-15/jpmorgan-posts-perfect-trading-record-for-three-quarters-of-2010.html"><headline>JPMorgan Established a Perfect Trading Record for Three Quarters of 2010</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> JPMorgan Chase  Co. racked up a
perfect trading record for the second half of last year, making
money every day after accomplishing the same feat in the first
three months of the year. </p>
<p>Traders at the New York-based bank made an average of
$76 million a day last year, down from $84 million in 2009,
according to an investor presentation today at the bank''s New
York headquarters. The investment bank lost money on eight days
last year, all in the second quarter. </p>
<p>We don''t expect that to be repeated, said Jes Staley,
chief executive officer of the investment bank. I imagine I''ll
be up here next year and you''ll see a number higher than eight,
but I think it underscores how well we''ve been managing our
business. </p>
<p>By comparison, JPMorgan had 42 days of losses in 2009, 97
in 2008, 46 in 2007, 33 in 2006 and 52 in 2005, according to the
presentation. JPMorgan''s average daily trading revenue was
$21 million in 2008, $39 million in 2007, $47 million in 2006
and $37 million in 2005, according to the data. </p>
<p>Banks have relied on trading profit to make up for weak
earnings or losses tied to consumer banking. Charlotte, North
Carolina-based Bank of America Corp., which hasn''t reported its
fourth-quarter trading results yet, also posted perfect trading
records in the first and third quarters. Traders at Goldman
Sachs Group Inc. and Citigroup Inc. also made money every single
day in the first quarter. </p>
<p>U.S. Role </p>
<p>The perfect trading results are rare and were primarily
driven by the Federal Reserve''s programs buying mortgage bonds
and U.S. Treasury securities. That''s driven trading volumes
higher, boosted asset values and provided backup liquidity in
the markets, analysts say. </p>
<p>It gives traders a buyer of last resort and confidence
that they have an outlet if some goes wrong, said Paul Miller,
a former examiner for the Federal Reserve Bank of Philadelphia
and analyst at FBR Capital Markets in Arlington, Virginia. He
said the strategy keeps bears on the sidelines in the fixed-
income markets. The results are driven by the Fed, not really
any expertise of any trading desk. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael Buteau" date="Feb 15, 2011 12:54 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-15/mobile-phone-use-by-fans-at-golf-tournaments-is-approved-by-u-s-pga-tour.html"><headline>Mobile Phone Use by Fans at Golf Tournaments Is Approved by U.S. PGA Tour</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Fans at U.S. PGA Tour events will be
allowed to carry mobile devices and use them in select areas
during tournaments, beginning at next month''s Honda Classic. </p>
<p>The world''s top professional golf circuit tested the use of
mobile devices by fans at five events late in the 2010 season
and early this year to determine the impact phones and other
hand-held equipment might have on the competition. </p>
<p>Under the new policy, fans will be allowed to carry such
devices on the course with the volume set to silent. Phone calls
can be made or received in designated areas throughout the
course, such as concession stands, according to a Tour statement. </p>
<p>We understand that mobile devices are an important part
of everyday life. said Andy Pazder, the Tour''s chief of
operations. We anticipate our fans will be respectful of the
policy and as a result the integrity of our competitions will
not be compromised. </p>
<p>Fans can receive and send data messages while on the course,
provided it''s done away from the playing area. No video
recording will be permitted at any time, and photography won''t
be allowed during official rounds. </p>
<p>The policy will be implemented on a tournament-by-
tournament basis. The Masters Tournament, U.S. Open, British
Open and PGA Championship -- golf''s four major tournaments --are
run by bodies other than the PGA Tour and will have their own
policies. Currently, mobile devices aren''t permitted during the
majors. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Paul Burkhardt" date="Feb 15, 2011 12:28 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-15/chevron-briefly-shut-natural-gas-lines-at-henry-hub-facility.html"><headline>Chevron Briefly Shut Natural Gas Lines at Henry Hub</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Chevron Corp. said it shut pipelines
at its Henry Hub gas separation station in Texas as a precaution
during a grass fire in the area. </p>
<p>Gas interconnects were down for just a little while and
restarted after the fire was out, Mickey Driver, a spokesman for
the company, said in an e-mail. The cause of the blaze is under
investigation. </p>
<p>The fire did not impact or threaten any CPL equipment and
was extinguished by the Henry Volunteer Fire Department at
4:30 p.m. local time yesterday, Driver said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Feb 15, 2011 10:29 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-15/jpmorgan-in-nod-to-whitney-says-its-diversified-muni-holdings-limit-risk.html"><headline>JPMorgan, With a Nod to Meredith Whitney, Calls Muni Holdings Diversified</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> JPMorgan Chase  Co.''s municipal
bond holdings are diversified enough to handle a likely increase
in defaults, according to the firm''s head of commercial banking. </p>
<p>We are not worried about our portfolio, despite what I do
think is going to be an increase on a national basis on
defaults, said Todd Maclin, chief executive officer of
JPMorgan''s commercial bank, during a presentation today for
investors in the New York-based company. </p>
<p>Among the audience was Meredith Whitney, the independent
analyst who stirred controversy by predicting municipal defaults
will total hundreds of billions of dollars. Maclin presented
data on how JPMorgan''s $9.7 billion municipal portfolio is split
up to allay investor concern. </p>
<p>About 26 percent is concentrated in local government bonds,
22 percent is invested in primary and secondary education,
14 percent is in state governments and the rest is split among
higher education, utilities, airports and other investments,
according to Maclin''s presentation. </p>
<p>I put this chart together for you, girlfriend, he told
Whitney, drawing laughter from the audience and the analyst. She
declined to comment in an interview. JPMorgan ranks second by
assets among U.S. lenders after Bank of America Corp. </p>
<p>Whitney, a banking analyst and chief executive officer of
Meredith Whitney Advisory Group, predicted on Dec. 19 during
CBS Corp.''s 60 Minutes that states'' fiscal stress would
spark 50 to 100 sizable defaults. </p>
<p>Her analysis drew criticism from investors and state
officials. California Treasurer Bill Lockyer called the
prediction apocalyptic arm-waving. The National League of
Cities'' research director cited her stunning lack of
understanding. William H. Gross, who runs the world''s
biggest bond fund at Pacific Investment Management Co., said he
doesn''t subscribe to her theory. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ashley Lutz" date="Feb 15, 2011  9:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-15/coca-cola-enterprises-may-issue-300-million-of-10-5-year-notes.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Enterprises May Issue $300 Million of 10.5-Year Notes</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Coca-Cola Enterprises Inc. plans to
issue $300 million of 10.5-year notes as soon as today,
according to a person familiar with the transaction, who
declined to be identified because terms aren''t set. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By James Pressley" date="Feb 16, 2011  5:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-16/goldman-doing-god-s-work-helps-chinese-oligarchs-tighten-grip-books.html"><headline>China''s Oligarchs Tighten Grip, With Assist From Goldman: Books</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>To hear analysts talk, Industrial 
Commercial Bank of China Ltd. is one sizzling stock. Of 43
recommendations on its Hong Kong shares, 88 percent advise
buy or outperform. Not a sell in sight. </p>
<p>What does a share in China''s largest bank represent,
though? Not ownership, let alone control. The government holds
some 70 percent of Industrial  Commercial, and its executives
obey Communist Party bosses, as Carl E. Walter and Fraser J.T. Howie show in their sobering book, Red Capitalism. </p>
<p>Set aside, for a moment, the vapid chatter about the
Chinese miracle. Forget that clever clogs at Goldman Sachs
Group Inc. invested in the bank before it went public. </p>
<p>Recall instead the $42 billion that investors poured into
Industrial  Commercial and two other state banks in initial
public offerings. What happened to that money? It cascaded right
into the state''s coffers as dividends, the authors say. Call it
free cash flow with Chinese characteristics. </p>
<p>Why wouldn''t international investors keep the cash in the
first place? they ask. The question is especially worth asking
now that China has surpassed Japan as the world''s second-largest
economy. </p>
<p>Walter and Howie have lived in China for 25 years and
worked at banks including JPMorgan Chase  Co. and Morgan
Stanley. They recognize that the country''s economic resurgence
and opening to the world have lifted more than 300 million
people out of poverty. They also understand that China''s Party
bosses still control the economy, thanks partly to the
ministrations of Goldman Sachs and other banks, they say. </p>




Source: Wiley via Bloomberg

<p>
The cover jacket of "Red Capitalism," by Carl L. Walter and Fraser J.T. Howie. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Feb 16, 2011  4:40 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-16/microsoft-phone-sees-boost-in-app-developer-activity-after-deal-with-nokia.html"><headline>Microsoft Phone Sees Boost in App Activity After Nokia Deal</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Microsoft Corp.''s Windows Phone 7
operating system has lured an increasing number of application
developers since the software maker announced a partnership with Nokia Oyj last week, according to analytics firm Flurry Inc. </p>
<p>In the four days after the Feb. 11 deal, 4 percent of new
app projects started were for Windows Phone, compared with 1
percent in the previous four days, according to data from
Flurry, which tracks mobile games and programs. </p>
<p>New projects for Windows Phone passed Research In Motion
Ltd.''s BlackBerry and now rank third behind new apps for Apple
Inc.''s iOS and Google Inc.''s Android, Flurry said. Redmond,
Washington-based Microsoft, which agreed last week to have its
Windows Phone software power Nokia handsets, is working to turn
around market-share losses to Apple and Google. A wide variety
of applications is critical to attracting mobile-phone users. </p>
<p>Apple''s software for the iPhone was the platform for 69
percent of apps started in the 4 days after Feb. 11. Android had
25 percent. BlackBerry was fourth with 2 percent. </p>
<p>Flurry predicts most developers will build apps for three
operating systems, meaning RIM and Microsoft are likely to
compete for the No. 3 spot, Peter Farago, vice president of
marketing at Flurry, said in an e-mail. </p>
<p>International Appeal </p>
<p>Crowdbeacon, maker of an app that lets users ask questions
about nearby businesses, is now planning to release a Windows
Phone 7 version, lured by Nokia''s international position, said
Robert Boyle, the company''s chief executive officer. </p>
<p>The Crowdbeacon program, which lets customers ask things
like where to get a haircut nearby in the next 45 minutes, now
is focused on the U.S. A planned international expansion means
Nokia customers are a key audience, Boyle said. </p>
<p>We weren''t even considering it before, he said of
Windows Phone 7. It just lags behind in users in the U.S. The
Nokia deal changed that. The Crowdbeacon app was released a
week ago for Apple''s iOS. </p>
<p>The reported surge in interest in Windows Phone comes on
top of an increase that started showing up early last week as
speculation about the deal mounted, Flurry reported in a Feb. 11
posting on its Web site. </p>
<p>Microsoft, the largest software maker, rose 6 cents to
$27.02 at 4 p.m. New York time on the Nasdaq Stock Market. The
shares had dropped 3.4 percent this year before today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Feb 16, 2011  3:04 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-16/jpmorgan-consolidates-trading-platforms-to-cut-costs-3-000-jobs-by-2014.html"><headline>JPMorgan Consolidates Trading Platforms to Cut Costs, 3,000 Jobs by 2014</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> JPMorgan Chase  Co.''s investment
bank has reduced trading costs for foreign exchange and other
transactions from about 75 cents per trade to around 10 cents by
consolidating some trading systems. </p>
<p>The overhaul began about two years ago, Jes Staley, the
unit''s chief investment officer, said during an investor meeting
at the company''s New York headquarters yesterday. JPMorgan has
cut its trading systems from 10 platforms to five with plans for
just two systems by 2014, he said. </p>
<p>When the project is complete, the costs to process a trade
should fall to five cents, with some of that savings being
passed on to clients, Staley said. </p>
<p>Just think of the importance of having a foreign exchange
desk, whether you are in Sao Paulo, Brazil or Tokyo, Japan or
Berlin, Germany, you''re on the exact same system, so you have
the exact same pricing and deal with clients in the exact same
way. The impact is extraordinary, Staley said. Once we get
the consolidation, then we get to innovate and to make the
overall system that much more efficient. </p>
<p>The lender, which processes about 68 million foreign
exchange trades a year, will be able to eliminate 3,000 jobs of
employees who manually process trades by the end of 2014, Staley
said. Those people may move to other functions within the bank,
said Jennifer Zuccarelli, a company spokeswoman. </p>
<p>The new system, which will cost about $500 million over the
five-year program, will save the company about $300 million with
a broader impact of $1 billion a year once it''s in place,
Staley said. The new platform will enable JPMorgan to execute
trades faster and to get products to the market quicker. </p>
<p>The real impact though is on the revenue side, he said,
comparing the new systems with game-changers like the cellular
telephone for consumers and iPad for institutional clients. If
we can get innovative like that, I think our revenue impact will
be even more significant. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By William Pesek" date="Feb 16, 2011  3:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-16/goldman-s-picks-can-t-beat-7-club-on-sexiness-william-pesek.html"><headline>Goldman''s Picks Can''t Beat 7% Club'' on Sexiness: William Pesek</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Is anyone else a bit BRIC-ed out? </p>
<p>Hey, I completely get the importance of Brazil, Russia,
India and China as emerging powers, growth engines and, perhaps,
role models. Yet ever since Goldman Sachs Group Inc. squeezed
the indispensable four into an acronym, we seem to have lost
sight of a wider constellation of hugely promising economies. </p>
<p>Even Jim O''Neill, coiner of Goldman''s now-ubiquitous BRICs,
says investors ought to concentrate on a broader basket of
growth economies as Brazilian, Russian, Indian and Chinese
stocks gyrate. It really is time to dispense with this BRICs
hype and focus on a more useful yardstick: the 7 Percent
Club. </p>
<p>This concept comes courtesy of Standard Chartered Plc. It''s
a fluid list of economies that achieve that rate of growth
consistently over an extended period -- and, of course, it
includes China and India. More importantly, the nature of the
grouping has the power to exert a much-needed peer-pressure
dynamic in Asia, the world''s fastest-growth region. </p>
<p>It''s an incentive for countries like Bangladesh, Cambodia, Indonesia, Mongolia and Vietnam on the cusp of membership to try
harder. It''s also a reminder to investors that focusing only on
the biggest, sexiest emerging powers isn''t always best. </p>
<p>Imagine for a moment a utopia in which theoretically any
economy, regardless of population and mix of natural resources
can join the 7 percent crowd. All John Calverley, Standard
Chartered''s global head of macroeconomic research, has done is
create a simple criteria for entry. Club members can enter and
leave depending on their macroeconomic performance. </p>
<p>Cult of GDP </p>
<p>Sure there are caveats here. One is the Cult of GDP. In Asia, GDP stands less for gross domestic product than gross
domestic problem. Leaders work to mask challenges with big
headline growth rates. They are just as much about advertising
as they are a diversion. Racy data distract investors from the
cracks undermining economies and give politicians room to step
before the cameras and say we''re moving forward. </p>
<p>What matters is that growth reaches those who most need it.
So it''s not just a matter of growing faster, but the quality of
that growth. By focusing on growth alone without democratizing
its benefits, governments risk Egypt-like backlashes. </p>
<p>Another is environmental. Were Britain''s Prince Charles to
read this argument, he might be tempted to toss his morning tea
at the computer screen. In a recent piece in the Times, of London, the prince made an impassioned and logical call for
decoupling economic growth from increased consumption in such
a way that both the well-being of nature''s ecology and our own
economic needs benefit simultaneously. </p>
<p>Growing Faster </p>
<p>Yet high-income nations tend to do a better job of growing
sustainably than poorer ones. It''s also more likely that
developing nations will be far more enthusiastic about boosting
growth than reducing carbon emissions. So, for better or worse,
this issue of growing faster is what it is. </p>
<p>The argument is a simple one. Economies growing 7 percent
annually double in size every decade and more than quadruple in
a generation. After three decades of growing at such rates, an
economy can be twice as large as one achieving 5 percent.
Calverley points to the experience of China, Hong Kong,
Indonesia, Japan, Malaysia, Singapore, South Korea and Thailand
over the last half century. </p>
<p>Investors are learning to differentiate between Asian
economies doing the right things and those walking in place.
Indonesia and the Philippines are as good an example as any.
Long-term investment is pouring into Indonesia as the government
tries to improve infrastructure, reduce corruption and narrow
the rich-poor divide. </p>
<p>Perception Problems </p>
<p>Markets are less enamored of the Philippines. There remains
a perception of timidity in Manila at a time when policy makers
need to reform an economic system that''s been neglected for
decades. Also, the nation''s key export has become its people.
Remittances account for more than 10 percent of the Philippine
economy. Not a good sign. </p>
<p>The Philippines, by the way, is actually growing faster
than Indonesia -- 7.1 percent year-over-year and 6.9 percent,
respectively. And yet Indonesia gets the headlines and the
kudos. The reason: It''s widely perceived to offer greater
potential than the Philippines. </p>
<p>That gets us back to Goldman''s BRICs. Russia''s GDP is more
than double Indonesia''s and yet it''s often seen as a less
promising business opportunity. Russia is a proud BRIC member;
Indonesia is left wondering what gives. Some offer a similar
argument about Brazil. While it has performed masterfully over
the last decade, are the structural changes needed to bring
Brazil to the next level feasible? Only time will tell. </p>
<p>All this leaves the specter of upstarts out-BRIC-ing the
BRICs. </p>
<p>Chatter about adding another I for Indonesia (BRIICs,
anyone?) or a K for Korea (BRICKs) or a T for Turkey
(BRICTs) is good sport. It just doesn''t get us closer to knowing
where to invest and in which sectors. </p>
<p>It''s time to think bigger. Let''s toss aside alphabet-soup
groupings parading as insights and missing the bigger picture
about emerging markets. The 7 Percent Club may be a good place
to start. </p>
<p>(William Pesek is a Bloomberg News columnist. The opinions
expressed are his own.) </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alan Purkiss" date="Feb 16, 2011  7:26 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-16/jpmorgan-plans-to-cut-number-of-trading-platforms-ft-reports.html"><headline>JPMorgan Plans to Cut Number of Trading Platforms, FT Reports</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> JPMorgan Chase  Co. set out
yesterday a $500 million plan to consolidate its trading
platforms around the world, a step that could save $300 million
a year, the Financial Times reported, citing Jes Staley, who
heads the company''s investment banking unit. </p>
<p>Staley said at the bank''s annual investor day that as many
as 3,000 employees might be eliminated or redeployed, and total
savings might be more than $1 billion, because of lower costs
and increased efficiency, the newspaper said. </p>
<p>The project began two years ago, in which time the number
of trading systems has fallen from 10 to five, and the aim is to
have just two by 2014, the FT said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Stephen Morris" date="Feb 16, 2011  5:59 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-16/morgan-crucible-jumps-most-in-year-on-ceramics-demand-forecast.html"><headline>Morgan Crucible Jumps Most in Year on Ceramics Demand, Forecast</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Crucible Co., a provider of
body armor to the U.K. Ministry of Defence, rose the most in a
year after saying it aims to double underlying pretax profit by
2013 and as net income soared on demand for ceramic products. </p>
<p>Morgan Crucible surged as much as 8.1 percent and was up
6.9 percent at 295.7 pence as of 10:56 a.m. in London trading.
The stock has risen 83 percent in the past year, giving the
company a market value of 807 million pounds ($1.3 billion). </p>
<p>The ceramics division had a particularly strong
performance in emerging markets, places like China, India and Brazil, Chief Executive Officer Mark Robertshaw said in a
telephone interview. The macro trends in those countries will
create higher levels of growth than in the Western world,
particularly in the petrochemical, power-generation and
infrastructure-building sectors, he said. </p>
<p>Morgan Crucible aims to double underlying pretax profit by
2013 through organic growth supported by acquisitions, the
Windsor, England-based company said today in an e-mailed
statement. It also aims to achieve mid-teen underlying
operating profit margins, and improve its return on operating
capital employed from 25.4 percent to more than 35 percent by
2013. </p>
<p>Morgan Crucible''s full-year 2010 results were slightly
ahead of consensus and RBS expectations, Royal Bank of
Scotland analyst Andrew Douglas, who has a buy rating on the
stock, wrote in a report today. The more attractive potential
upside comes over the longer term, where management targets
appear significantly higher than we are currently forecasting. </p>
<p>Bolt-on Acquisitions </p>
<p>Morgan Crucible may make acquisitions in the health-care
market and the renewable energy sector where it sees its highest
growth potential, Robertshaw said. </p>
<p>For bolt-on type acquisitions, where our focus will be,
we''ll be looking at the 10 to 60 million-pound range, the CEO
said. </p>
<p>Last month, the company announced the acquisition of
Changsha Hairong New Materials Co., a Chinese company that makes
graphite components for lithium-ion batteries used in electric
vehicles. The purchase price was about 6 million pounds in cash.
It is part of Morgan Crucible''s expansion in the renewable
energy sector, Robertshaw said. </p>
<p>Morgan Crucible''s full-year net income rose to 42.5 million
pounds, or 15 pence a share, from 19 million pounds, or 6.8
pence, according to the statement. </p>
<p>A recovery in the aerospace and general industrial sectors
helped boost revenue more than 21 percent in technical ceramics,
the company said. Growth in the South American market,
particularly the Brazilian petrochemical sector, contributed to
a 14 percent increase in thermal ceramics revenue. </p>
<p>The dividend for the year ending Jan. 2 climbed to 7.7
pence a share from 7 pence. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Feb 17, 2011  4:41 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-17/morgan-stanley-names-paul-wirth-deputy-finance-chief-amid-new-regulations.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Names Paul Wirth Deputy Chief Financial Officer</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Morgan Stanley, the world''s top
merger adviser, promoted Finance Director Paul Wirth to be
deputy chief financial officer. </p>
<p>Wirth, 53, will report to CFO Ruth Porat in his new role,
according to an internal memo obtained today by Bloomberg News.
Mark Lake, a spokesman for the New York-based firm, confirmed
the contents of the memo. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley, owner of the world''s largest brokerage, is
shifting how it allocates resources to its businesses as banks
face higher capital requirements, Chief Executive Officer James Gorman said this month. The firm will likely have a Tier 1
common equity ratio of 8 percent to 10 percent under so-called
Basel III by the end of 2012, Porat said in January. </p>
<p>In light of the growing number of strategic initiatives
and regulatory mandates that lie ahead, Paul will provide valued
leadership, Porat wrote in the memo. </p>
<p>Wirth previously worked at Credit Suisse Group AG and
Deloitte  Touche LLP. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ronald Grover" date="Feb 17, 2011  4:35 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-17/disney-abc-station-owners-agree-to-share-fees-from-pay-tv.html"><headline>Disney, ABC Station Owners Agree to Share Pay-TV Fees</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Walt Disney Co., owner of the ABC
network, said it reached an agreement with some affiliate
stations to collect a share of the retransmission fees they
obtain from pay-TV systems. </p>
<p>The agreement, along with accords Disney-owned stations
have reached with pay TV operators, covers 64 percent of the
U.S., Anne Sweeney, president of the Disney/ABC Television
Group, said at an investor meeting today. Stations may pay a
license fee to Disney or share fees they collect from cable and
satellite TV systems, she said. Other terms weren''t disclosed. </p>
<p>The agreement advances Disney''s effort to receive so-called
retransmission fees from pay-TV carriers for signals that are
available free over the air. The company announced such an
agreement today with Verizon Communications Inc.''s FiOS pay-TV
service and has similar accords with Cablevision Systems Corp.,
the New York-area cable company, and Time Warner Cable Inc. </p>
<p>The Verizon accord is part of a larger deal that gives FiOS
subscribers online access to Disney''s ESPN cable programs along
with traditional pay TV viewing of the ABC Family, Disney and
Disney Junior cable channels, the companies said in a statement.
Terms weren''t disclosed. </p>
<p>The agreement with Verizon covering the cable channels and
ESPN online was announced in October. Starting today, Verizon''s
3.3 million FiOS customers have access to ESPN, ESPN2, ESPNU and
ESPN Buzzer Beater, which provides live clips of college
basketball games through personal computers and mobile devices. </p>
<p>Interactive Cuts </p>
<p>Disney, based in Burbank, California, closed unchanged at
$43.70 at 4 p.m. in New York Stock Exchange composite trading.
The shares have risen 17 percent this year, the second-highest
gain among stocks in the Dow Jones Industrial Average. Verizon,
based in New York, gained 20 cents to $36.37. </p>
<p>The company also said it plans to cut operating expenses at
its money-losing interactive division by 25 percent by 2012. </p>
<p>The reductions are part of a drive to achieve profitability
at the division by 2013, John Pleasants and James Pitaro, co-
heads of the interactive business, told investors at the meeting
in Anaheim, California. </p>
<p>The division, which posted a loss of $234 million for all
of fiscal 2010, plans to reduce spending on video games for
consoles by 50 percent over the next few years. </p>
<p>In July, the company agreed to buy Playdom Inc. for $563.2
million, acquiring the second-biggest maker of games played on
Facebook Inc. and MySpace websites, and completed the purchase
of Tapulous Inc., a developer of music-related video games for
Apple Inc. products. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tim Catts" date="Feb 17, 2011  2:53 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-17/jpmorgan-sells-3-billion-of-3-45-notes-due-2016-correct-.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sells $3 Billion of 3.45% Notes Due 2016</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>(Corrects coupon in headline, second paragraph.) </p>
<p> JPMorgan Chase  Co. sold $3 billion
of five-year debt, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>The 3.45 percent notes yield 120 basis points more than
similar-maturity Treasuries, Bloomberg data show. A basis point
is 0.01 percentage point. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christian Wienberg" date="Feb 17, 2011  7:22 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-17/goldman-eqt-plan-ipo-of-iss-biggest-in-denmark-in-16-years.html"><headline>Goldman, EQT Plan $2.42 Billion Initial Public Offering for Denmark''s ISS</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Capital Partners and
EQT Partners AB will sell shares of ISS Holding A/S, the world''s
largest cleaning-service provider, in what may be Denmark''s
biggest initial public offering in more than 16 years. </p>
<p>The IPO will consist mostly of new shares and will raise
gross proceeds of about 13.3 billion kroner ($2.42 billion)
which will be used to reduce the company''s debt, the Copenhagen-
based company said today in a statement. </p>
<p>There''s an appetite for IPOs in the market now, there''s
liquidity, Chief Executive Officer Jeff Gravenhorst said in a
phone interview today. </p>
<p>The offering would be Denmark''s biggest since the
government in 1994 sold a stake in Copenhagen-based phone
company TDC A/S for $3 billion and would exceed last year''s $1.7
billion IPO of Pandora A/S, a Glostrup-based maker of jewelry. </p>
<p>EQT and Goldman Sachs, which acquired ISS for 21.9 billion
kroner in 2005, said in August they were considering a sale of
the company and hired bankers to review their options. ISS has
an enterprise value of as much as 49 billion kroner, Jyske Bank
A/S said in December. Because the owners haven''t decided how
many shares to sell, it isn''t possible to estimate the company''s
value from the planned IPO proceeds, Gravenhorst said. </p>
<p>Reduce Gearing </p>
<p>We couldn''t go to the stock exchange without doing
something to reduce our gearing at the same time, Gravenhorst
said. The IPO will take place on the Copenhagen exchange in
not too long, he said. </p>
<p>ISS said net debt amounted to 30.6 billion kroner at the
end of last year, according to today''s earnings report. ISS
reported a 7.3 percent advance in 2010 sales to 74.1 billion
kroner while its net loss shrank three-fold to 532 million
kroner. Earnings before interest, tax, depreciation and
amortization jumped 21 percent to a record 5 billion kroner. </p>
<p>EQT and Goldman are staying on board for a while, but in
the long run they''ll probably dispose of all their shares,
Martin Bo Hansen, a corporate bond analyst at Jyske Bank said by
phone today. He said he will now review his December ISS
valuation estimate of 47 billion kroner to 49 billion kroner
based on today''s earnings report. </p>
<p>Biggest Acquisition </p>
<p>Apax Partners LLP dropped a 6.4 billion-euro ($8.7 billion)
bid for ISS last month, according to two people familiar with
the talks. That would have been the biggest acquisition by a
European private equity firm since the credit crisis. </p>
<p>ISS, operating in more than 50 countries with more than
500,000 workers, provides cleaning, catering, security and call-
center services. It has mainly grown through acquisitions of
more than 600 companies in the past decade, making it the Nordic
region''s most acquisitive company. </p>
<p>The cost of insuring the senior debt of ISS Global fell 31
basis points to 198, the lowest level since December 2007,
according to CMA. Credit-default swaps linked to the holding
company''s subordinated debt dropped 65 basis points to 183. </p>
<p>A basis point on a credit-default swap protecting 10
million euros of debt from default for five years is equivalent
to 1,000 euros a year. Swaps pay the buyer face value in
exchange for the underlying securities or the cash equivalent
should a borrower fail to adhere to its debt agreements. </p>
<p> Goldman Sachs Group Inc., Morgan Stanley, Citigroup Inc.,
Deutsche Bank AG, HSBC Holdings Plc and Nordea Bank AB will
manage the IPO. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David McLaughlin" date="Feb 18, 2011  5:26 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-18/jpmorgan-says-it-was-tricked-into-keeping-lehman-s-goat-poo-collateral.html"><headline>JPMorgan Says It Was Tricked Into Keeping Lehman''s `Goat Poo'' Collateral</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc.
tricked JPMorgan Chase  Co. into holding onto collateral that
the bankrupt investment firm internally described as goat poo,
according to a court filing by JPMorgan. </p>
<p>JPMorgan was stuck with Lehman''s worst securities backing
$25 billion of loans as Lehman was sold to Barclays Plc in
September 2008, JPMorgan said in its filing yesterday in U.S.
Bankruptcy Court in Manhattan. Lehman described the collateral
as toxic crap and goat poo to be scattered in other
people''s backyards, JPMorgan said. </p>
<p>Only later was JPMorgan able to determine that the
position in which it unexpectedly found itself was the result of
collusion and deception by Lehman and Barclays, JPMorgan said. </p>
<p>The accusations appeared in amended counterclaims against
Lehman in its lawsuit against JPMorgan. Both companies are based
in New York. </p>
<p>Lehman accuses JPMorgan of siphoning billions of dollars
from Lehman, leading to it collapse in September 2008. London-
based Barclays bought Lehman''s broker-dealer unit after Lehman''s
bankruptcy filing. </p>
<p>Kimberly Macleod, a spokeswoman for Lehman, and Mark Lane,
a spokesman for Barclays, both declined to comment. </p>
<p>The case is Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. v. JPMorgan Chase
Bank NA, 10-03266, U.S. Bankruptcy Court, Southern District of
New York (Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Feb 18, 2011  1:16 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-18/goldman-sachs-may-repay-buffett-buy-back-10-of-common-stock-nomura-says.html"><headline>Goldman May Repay Buffett, Buy Back 10% of Shares, Schorr Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Goldman Sachs Group Inc. will likely
repay the $5 billion investment from Warren Buffett''s Berkshire
Hathaway Inc. and may buy back as many as 10 percent of its
outstanding shares over the next two years, according to Glenn Schorr, an analyst at Nomura Holdings Inc. </p>
<p>Repurchasing the preferred shares from Berkshire would
increase annual earnings per share at the New York-based firm by
about 85 cents, Schorr said today in a note to investors. A
5 percent reduction in shares outstanding would add about
$1 a share to earnings, he wrote. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs is awaiting results of a stress test that the Federal Reserve is using to determine whether the largest U.S.
banks can begin returning capital to shareholders through
dividends and share repurchases. The firm has an estimated
Tier 1 common ratio of about 8 percent under the so-called Basel
III capital rules, Schorr wrote. </p>
<p>We think Goldman will be part of the small group of U.S.
banks allowed to return capital at the end of 1Q11 and we
believe the firm is clearly able to effectively manage its
capital base given its strong starting point, Schorr wrote.
Goldman''s shares outstanding could be reduced by 10 percent
over the next two years (and we may be on the conservative
side). That would boost earnings per share and returns on
equity, he wrote. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs is likely to invest in its emerging markets
businesses and technology improvements before returning capital
to shareholders, Schorr wrote. </p>
<p>Capital Impact </p>
<p>The repayment could reduce the firm''s tier 1 common equity
ratio by about 0.4 percentage points and reduce book value by
about $3 a share, Schorr wrote. Those effects would likely be
offset by the first-quarter earnings, he wrote. </p>
<p> David Wells, a Goldman Sachs spokesman, declined to
comment. The bank is considering repaying the Berkshire
investment, needing approval from the Federal Reserve to do so,
a person familiar with the plans said in October. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs turned to Buffett, the second-richest
American and a cult figure in the investing world, to shore up
the investment bank''s capital and restore market confidence
after its stock tumbled and borrowing costs spiked following the
Sept. 15, 2008, collapse of Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. News
of Berkshire''s investment also helped Goldman Sachs raise
$5.75 billion from a stock offering a day later. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Cecile Vannucci" date="Feb 22, 2011  4:54 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-22/walter-investment-put-options-trades-rise-to-13-month-high-1-.html"><headline>Walter Investment Put-Options Trades Rise to 13-Month High</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Walter Investment Management Corp.
call volume jumped to its highest level since December 2009,
with most of the trading concentrated in contracts that have a
strike price 5.6 percent below today''s close. </p>
<p>More than 3,500 puts to sell the mortgage real estate
investment trust changed hands today, 20 times the four-week
average and 47 times the number of calls to buy. The most-traded
contracts were the March $17.50 puts, which accounted for almost
all put volume and rose 33 percent to 20 cents. Ninety percent
of those puts were exchanged at the ask price, indicating that
buyers initiated most of the transactions. Tampa, Florida-based
Walter Investment declined 2.9 percent to $18.53. </p>
<p>The REIT is expected to report a 30 cent profit per share
excluding some items next week, according to the average of
three analyst estimates from a Bloomberg survey. Walter
Investment was created in 2009 through a merger of the company,
which was spun off from coal producer Walter Industries Inc.,
and Hanover Capital Mortgage Holdings Inc. </p>
<p>Walter Investment''s implied volatility, the key gauge of
option prices, for at-the-money options expiring in 30 days rose
to 24.43 from 20.76 Feb. 18. </p>
<p>Calls give the right to buy 100 shares of a security for a
certain amount, the strike price, by a set date. Puts convey the
right to sell. Investors use options to guard against
fluctuations in the price of securities they own, speculate on
share-price moves or bet that volatility, or stock swings, will
rise or fall. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Nicole Ostrow" date="Feb 22, 2011  4:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-22/mobile-phone-use-found-to-boost-brain-cell-activity-in-areas-near-antenna.html"><headline>Mobile-Phone Use Found to Boost Brain-Cell Activity in Areas Near Antenna</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Using a mobile phone for 50 minutes
stirs brain metabolism, although the health consequences are
unknown and need to be studied further, U.S. researchers said. </p>
<p>When mobile phones were on and held against the ear, brain
glucose metabolism, a marker of brain cell activity, was about 7
percent higher in areas closest to the antenna than when phones
were off, a study in today''s Journal of the American Medical
Association found. The study, the first to show the effects of
mobile-phone use on brain metabolism, was done by researchers
from the National Institutes of Health in Bethesda, Maryland,
and Brookhaven National Laboratory in Upton, New York. </p>
<p>Studies, including a report last year from the World Health
Organization''s International Agency for Research on Cancer, have
produced conflicting results over the health dangers of mobile
phones, particularly their link to cancer. Today''s finding shows
that human brain metabolism is sensitive to the effects of
radiofrequency-electromagnetic fields, a form of radiation, from
mobile phones. </p>
<p>We need to investigate this carefully so that we can send
a clear-cut message that is as unequivocal as possible, said
Nora Volkow, director of the National Institutes of Health''s
National Institute on Drug Abuse, in a Feb. 18 telephone
interview. We don''t know the clinical significance. In
principle, increasing brain glucose metabolism is not a bad
thing. You don''t need to stop using your cell phones. If you are
concerned, use a wire ear piece or use your speaker phone
mode. </p>
<p>There were almost 293 million wireless accounts in the U.S.
as of June 2010, according to CTIA-The Wireless Association, a
Washington-based trade group that represents carriers, phone
makers and suppliers. The number of U.S. households that only
have wireless phones was about 25 percent, the group said. </p>
<p>Industry Response </p>
<p>The peer-reviewed scientific evidence has overwhelmingly
indicated that wireless devices, within the limits established
by the FCC, do not pose a public health risk or cause any
adverse health effects, John Walls, vice president of public
affairs for CTIA, said in a Feb. 18 e-mail. The leading global
health organizations such as the American Cancer Society,
National Cancer Institute, World Health Organization and the
U.S. Food and Drug Administration all have concurred that
wireless devices are not a public health risk. </p>
<p>The researchers from the National Institutes of Health and
Brookhaven National Laboratory included 47 people in the study.
They placed mobile phones on the right and left ears of
participants and then measured brain glucose metabolism once
when the phone on the right side was on but muted for 50 minutes
and a second time when both cell phones were off. After 50
minutes, the patients had their brain activity measured using a
positron emission tomography, or PET, scan. </p>
<p>Affected Brain Regions </p>
<p>Researchers found that only the regions closest to the
antenna, the orbitofrontal cortex and the temporal pole, saw a
rise in brain metabolism when the mobile phone was on. The
orbitofrontal cortex plays a role in decision making and reward
and punishment, and the temporal pole is involved in social and
emotional processes. </p>
<p>Henry Lai, who wrote an accompanying editorial in the
journal with Lennart Hardell from University Hospital in Orebro, Sweden, said the results of today''s study add to information
about the possible effects of emissions from wireless phones on
the brain. </p>
<p>It is an intriguing discovery and it certainly adds to
the concern that cell phone use is not completely safe, said
Lai, a bioengineering researcher at the University of Washington
in Seattle, in a Feb. 20 e-mail. Before we understand the
impact of the results of this study, people who use cell phones
should limit their exposure to the radiation, particularly to
the head. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Roxana Tiron" date="Feb 22, 2011  3:29 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-22/general-aviation-deliveries-fell-11-4-in-2010-trade-group-says.html"><headline>General Aviation Deliveries Fell 11.4% in 2010, Trade Group Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Deliveries of general aviation
airplanes, not including military aircraft or commercial jets,
declined 11.4 percent last year, as traditional private
customers struggled to obtain credit and shipments have yet to
catch up to the economic recovery, the General Aviation
Manufacturers Association said today. </p>
<p>The number of airplanes delivered fell for a third
consecutive year, dropping to 2,015 from 2,274 airplanes the
year before, the association said in a statement. The
association represents more than 65 worldwide manufacturers of
airplanes, engines and related equipment. </p>
<p>Industry billings increased to $19.7 billion from $19.5
billion the year before. Last year was the third best year
ever for total industry billings due to deliveries of long-
range, large-cabin aircraft, the association said. </p>
<p>Our industry experienced another challenging year that
required many manufacturers to continue to make careful
decisions about production schedules, employment and product
development, John Rosanvallon, the association''s chairman and
president and chief executive officer of Dassault Aviation SA''s
Dassault Falcon, said in a statement. Despite the pain caused
by the downturn, we are now seeing strong GDP growth on a global
level and corporate profits are up. This bodes well for general
aviation''s future. </p>
<p>Shipments of turboprop airplanes declined the most, by 17.7
percent to 363 planes in 2010, from 441 the year before.
Shipments of piston-engine airplanes fell 7.7 percent to 889
from 963 in 2009. Business jet deliveries dropped to 763 in 2010
from 870 in 2009, a 12.3 percent decline. </p>
<p>-- Editors: Steven Komarow, Bob Drummond </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chris Peterson" date="Feb 22, 2011  5:46 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-22/microsoft-plans-to-add-as-many-as-400-staff-in-china-wsj-says.html"><headline>Microsoft Plans to Add as Many as 400 Staff in China, WSJ Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Microsoft Corp. said it plans to add
as many as 400 staff to its research and development facilities
in China, the Wall Street Journal said, citing Ya-Qing Zhang,
head of the company''s Asia Pacific RD group. </p>
<p>Microsft already has some 3,000 people working in research
in China, the newspaper said.   </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Peter Woodifield" date="Feb 22, 2011  4:27 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-22/morgan-sindall-net-income-drops-9-4-on-charges-revenue-1-.html"><headline>Morgan Sindall Net Income Drops 9.4% on Charges, Revenue</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Morgan Sindall Group Plc, a U.K.
based construction and regeneration company, said profit fell
9.4 percent last year on one-time charges and lower revenue that
resulted from government spending cuts. </p>
<p>Net income dropped to 29.9 million pounds ($48.3 million),
or 69.1 pence a share, from 33 million pounds, or 77.1 pence, in
2009, the London-based company said in a statement today.
Revenue fell 5 percent to 2.1 billion pounds. </p>
<p>We think the private sector is going to pick up some of
the slack from the spending cuts, Chairman John Morgan said in
a telephone interview. It is doing a little better than
expected, there is a little more confidence in the economy. </p>
<p>Morgan Sindall expects the construction market to weaken
for the next three years as the U.K. government cuts spending
plans to deal with a record budget deficit caused by the biggest
recession since World War II. Profit margins will come under
pressure in 2011 as too many companies compete for less
business, Morgan said. </p>
<p>The company''s order book at the start of the year rose 13
percent to 3.6 billion pounds, according to the statement. </p>
<p>Morgan Sindall bought Connaught Plc''s maintenance business
out of administration last year and has since made 800 workers
redundant, he said. The acquisition was transformational for
the company''s Lovell unit, Morgan said. </p>
<p>The fitting-out business would go back this year
because of a shortage of new offices being completed, he said. </p>
<p>The shares fell 1 penny to 715 pence at 8:28 a.m. in London
trading. The stock has risen 30 percent in the past six months. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jeran Wittenstein" date="Feb 23, 2011  6:36 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-23/jpmorgan-plans-up-to-1-22-billion-technology-fund-wsj-reports.html"><headline>JPMorgan Plans Up to $1.22 Billion Technology Fund, WSJ Reports</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> JPMorgan Chase  Co. plans to raise
as much as $1.22 billion for a fund aimed at buying stakes in
private technology companies such as Twitter Inc. and Facebook
Inc., the Wall Street Journal reported, citing a regulatory
filing. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sonia Sirletti" date="Feb 23, 2011  1:43 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-23/generali-says-company-s-equity-holdings-are-managed-by-ceo.html"><headline>Generali Says Company''s Equity Holdings Are Managed by CEO</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Assicurazioni Generali SpA, Italy''s
biggest insurer, said most of the company''s equity investments
aren''t strategic and are managed by its chief executive officer. </p>
<p>None of the company''s equity investments can be considered
a strategic shareholding, with the exception of those that
involve industrial relationships, Trieste, Italy-based
Generali said in a statement distributed by the Italian
Exchange. The CEO will manage them with a view to creating value
for all shareholders, Generali said. </p>
<p>Generali Chairman Cesare Geronzi said in an interview with
the Financial Times on Feb. 16 that the company may consider
investing in Italian banks, comments that contrasted with the
insurer''s position outlined in a business plan presented in
November. Luxottica Group SpA founder Leonardo Del Vecchio
resigned as a Generali director Feb. 21, saying he wasn''t able
to influence strategy at the insurer. </p>
<p>The resignation won''t have any negative consequences on
the effectiveness and efficiency of current governance, the
company said today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Steven Fromm" date="Feb 23, 2011  9:55 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-23/morgan-stanley-may-sell-shanghai-motel-management-wsj-says.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley May Sell Shanghai Motel Management, WSJ Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Morgan Stanley may sell the Shanghai
Motel Management Co. for as much as $1 billion, the Wall Street
Journal reported on its website, citing unidentified people
familiar with the matter. </p>
<p>Shanghai Motel Management operates a chain under the Motel
168 brand. Morgan Stanely bought 20 percent of the company in
2006 for $20 million, the Journal reported. Morgan Stanley now
controls 59 percent of the company, the Journal said.  </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Leela Landress and Yee Kai Pin" date="Feb 24, 2011  5:25 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-24/exxon-mobil-releases-gas-from-beaumont-refinery-nrc-filing-says.html"><headline>Exxon Reports Compressor Trips at Beaumont, Texas, Refinery</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Exxon Mobil Corp., the largest U.S.
oil company, reported a compressor trip and flaring at the
Beaumont, Texas, refinery, according to a filing with the U.S.
National Response Center. </p>
<p>Operations has restarted the compressor and is working to
normalize operations, the company said in another filing with
the Texas Commission on Environmental Quality today. The
compressor trip was associated with a coker unit, the filing
showed. </p>
<p>Production was not impacted, Kevin Allexon, a company
spokesman based in Fairfax, Virginia, said today in an e-mail.
The compressor was restarted, he said. </p>
<p>Flaring associated with the trip began yesterday at about 2
p.m. local time and lasted until almost 8 a.m. today, according
to the filing. </p>
<p>Refinery outages can increase prices for refined products
as refiners turn to spot markets to help them meet supply
contracts. Operational disruptions can also depress prices for
crude oil because less feedstock is needed. </p>
<p>The Irving, Texas-based company had a release of hydrogen
sulfide and sulfur dioxide from a flare stack at the refinery,
according to an earlier filing with the U.S. National Response
Center. </p>
<p>U.S. refineries must notify the National Response Center if
they release hazardous substances in excess of reportable
quantities, according to the Comprehensive Environmental
Response, Compensation and Liability Act, commonly known as
Superfund. </p>
<p>The plant can process 359,100 barrels of crude a day,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Susan Decker" date="Feb 24, 2011  2:18 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-24/microsoft-case-against-tivo-to-be-reviewed-by-u-s-trade-agency.html"><headline>Microsoft Case Against TiVo to Be Reviewed by U.S. Trade Agency</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Microsoft Corp.''s patent-
infringement claims against TiVo Inc. will be investigated by a
U.S. trade agency that has the power to block imports of TiVo''s
television set-top boxes. </p>
<p>The U.S. International Trade Commission said today it would
investigate a complaint filed by Microsoft on Feb. 24.
Microsoft, the world''s biggest software maker, claims that set-
top boxes made by TiVo infringe four of its patents. TiVo, based
in Alviso, California, makes the devices in Mexico, according to
the Microsoft complaint. </p>
<p>The case before the trade agency expands a legal battle
that began more than a year ago when Microsoft challenged TiVo
patents after TiVo sued ATT Inc., a customer of Microsoft, over
the same patents. A separate lawsuit was filed by Redmond,
Washington-based Microsoft claiming that TiVo infringed seven
Microsoft patents. The two sides are in talks to settle the
dispute, Microsoft said last month. </p>
<p>The four patents in the ITC case, which may be completed
within 15 months, relate to program schedules and selection,
controlling the interface, and a way to restrict use of the
digital-video recorder based on a program''s rating. Microsoft
said the technology is used in its Mediaroom software that runs
on competing set-top boxes including ATT''s U-Verse service. </p>
<p>The case is In the Matter of Set-Top Boxes, and Hardware
and Software Components Thereof, 337-761, U.S. International
Trade Commission  Washington). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael Riley" date="Feb 24, 2011  3:26 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-24/exxon-shell-bp-said-to-have-been-hacked-through-chinese-internet-servers.html"><headline>Exxon, Shell, BP Said to Have Been Hacked Through Chinese Internet Servers</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Computer hackers working through
Internet servers in China broke into and stole proprietary
information from the networks of six U.S. and European energy
companies, including Exxon Mobil Corp., Royal Dutch Shell Plc
and BP Plc, according to one of the companies and investigators
who declined to be identified. </p>
<p> McAfee Inc., a cyber-security firm, reported Feb. 10 that
such attacks had resulted in the loss of project-financing
information with regard to oil and gas field bids and
operations. In its report, Santa Clara, California-based
McAfee, assisted by other cyber-security firms, didn''t identify
the energy companies targeted. The attacks, which it dubbed
Night Dragon, originated primarily in China and occurred
during the past three years. </p>
<p>The list of companies hit, none of which disclosed the
attacks in filings with regulators, also includes Marathon Oil
Corp., ConocoPhillips and Baker Hughes Inc., according to the
people who worked on or are familiar with the companies''
investigations and asked not to be identified because of the
confidential nature of the matter. </p>
<p>Chinese hackers broke into the computer network of Baker
Hughes, said Gary Flaharty, spokesman for the Houston-based
provider of advanced drilling technology. Baker Hughes concluded
the incident didn''t need to be disclosed because it wasn''t
material to investors, he said, declining to comment further. </p>
<p>Undetected Access </p>
<p>In some of the cases, hackers had undetected access to
company networks for more than a year, said Greg Hoglund, chief
executive officer of Sacramento, California-based HBGary Inc., a
cyber-security company that investigated some of the security
breaches at oil companies. Hoglund, who was cited by McAfee as a
contributor to its report, declined to identify his clients. </p>
<p>Legal information, information on deals and financial
information are all things that appear to be getting targeted,
Hoglund said, summing up conclusions his firm made from the
types of documents and persons targeted by the hackers. This
is straight up industrial espionage. </p>
<p>Hackers targeted computerized topographical maps worth
millions of dollars that show locations of potential oil
reserves, said Ed Skoudis, whose company, Washington-based
InGuardians Inc., investigated two recent breaches of U.S. oil
companies'' networks. He declined to name his clients or the
origin of the hackers. </p>
<p>Unsophisticated'' Techniques </p>
<p>The McAfee report described the techniques used to get into
the energy company computers as unsophisticated and commonly
used by Chinese hackers. The attacks began in November 2009,
McAfee said. Two cyber investigators familiar with the probes
said the attacks began even earlier -- in 2008 -- and involved
several well-financed groups. The investigators asked not to be
identified because the company investigations are private. </p>
<p>McAfee based the report on information gathered from its
own work on the breaches and from others who were directly
involved in investigating them. The report, produced on the
condition that the affected companies not be identified, was
done to educate the community, said Ian Bain, a McAfee
spokesman. </p>
<p>The thefts of oil company data like those in the McAfee
report match the profile of industrial espionage operations that
have the backing or consent of the Chinese government, said Joel Brenner, former head of U.S. counterintelligence during the Bush
and Obama administrations and now a lawyer with Cooley LLP in Washington. In his former post, one of Brenner''s jobs was
tracking spying efforts against U.S. companies from foreign
countries. </p>
<p>On the Hunt'' </p>
<p>The Chinese are on the hunt for natural resources to fuel
this massive economic leap forward, Brenner said. </p>
<p>Ma Zhaoxu, spokesman for China''s Ministry of Foreign
Affairs, said he had no information about the attacks on the oil
companies when asked about the issue at a regular briefing today. </p>
<p>The Chinese government opposes hacking activities, Ma
said. China falls victim to hacking itself. We will step up
efforts to crack down on hacking crimes. </p>
<p>The thefts might trigger legal liability for companies that
chose not to disclose them to investors, said Blair Nicholas, a
San Diego-based partner at law firm Bernstein Litowitz Berger
and Grossman. </p>
<p>To the extent that there aren''t adequate procedures in
place to protect the companies'' crown jewels and somebody gets
the key to jewelry box, there is certainly potential for
shareholder derivative liability, Nicholas said. </p>
<p>Securities Laws </p>
<p>Investors might also argue they had a right under U.S.
securities laws to be informed of the thefts, which a judge
might construe as a material fact that should have been
disclosed, Nicholas said. </p>
<p>John Roper, a spokesman for Houston-based ConocoPhillips;
Lee Warren, a Marathon Oil spokeswoman at its Houston
headquarters, and Alan Jeffers, a spokesman for Irving, Texas-
based Exxon, said in e-mail messages that their companies don''t
comment on security-related issues. David Nicholas, a spokesman
for London-based BP, and Kim Blomley, a spokesman in London for
Shell, which is based in The Hague, declined to comment. </p>
<p>Jenny Shearer, an FBI spokeswoman in Washington, said she
couldn''t comment on whether the agency was investigating the
attacks. Laura Sweeney, a Justice Department spokeswoman, said
the department can''t comment on a possible investigation. </p>
<p>Hacker Activists </p>
<p>Some aspects of the attacks were disclosed in internal e-
mails made public after a February security breach at HBGary.
The e-mails were stolen from HBGary''s computer network by the
group of hacker activists called Anonymous, which posted them on
the Internet. </p>
<p>I''ve been able to confirm that the same attackers are
conducting coordinated IP thefts against Baker Hughes and Shell
Oil, going after bid data and operational reporting, as well as
projects/plans and related financial information, according to
an e-mail written on Jan. 13 by an independent security
consultant working on the cases. </p>
<p>I reached out to some friends at Conoco and Exxon and
they also experienced similar breaches, the consultant wrote
in the e-mail. This is of course client confidential, he
added under the subject line coordinated Chinese attacks on
oil companies. </p>
<p>In a separate e-mail, an HBGary investigator discussed the
analysis of malware designed to steal data in the computers of a
drilling rig working on a ConocoPhillips project. </p>
<p>Marc Zwillinger, an attorney representing HBGary, declined
to comment on the e-mails'' content. </p>
<p>Stolen E-Mails'' </p>
<p>Those are stolen e-mails and they contain confidential
information relating to clients, Zwillinger said. </p>
<p>The McAfee report, which cites several attacks connected to
the Chinese hacking underground, doesn''t link the Night
Dragon attack directly to the Chinese government. </p>
<p>Analysts who assessed the attacks on energy companies said
the source of the breaches was easier to pinpoint than in
previous hits by Chinese hackers, including an attack against Google Inc. that that company disclosed in January 2010. </p>
<p>The hackers used tools prevalent in China''s underground
hacking forums, the McAfee report said, and they appeared to
work from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m., Beijing time. McAfee traced the
hackers'' command-and-control operations to servers operated by a
company in China''s Heze City in Shandong province. </p>
<p>The owner of the company, Song Zhiyue, said he wasn''t aware
of any hacking taking place from his servers and that he always
seeks to verify the activities of customers who rent server
space from him. </p>
<p>There are so many servers in the world, Song said.
This has nothing to do with me. This is very unfair. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Schneider" date="Feb 24, 2011  1:14 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-24/disney-viacom-lose-bid-to-hold-internet-provider-liable-for-users-piracy.html"><headline>Hollywood Studios Lose Appeal on Australian Piracy Lawsuit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Walt Disney Co. and Viacom Inc.''s Paramount Pictures are among Hollywood''s biggest movie studios
that lost a piracy lawsuit in Australia as an appeals court
upheld a ruling that a local internet provider wasn''t
responsible for customers illegally downloading films. </p>
<p>The Federal Court of Australia Full Court, in a two-one
decision, today upheld Judge Dennis Cowdroy''s Feb. 4, 2010,
verdict that vindicated iiNet Ltd. The studios can appeal the
ruling to the country''s High Court and a notice must be filed
within 28 days, unless an extension is sought. </p>
<p>Village Roadshow Ltd.''s Roadshow Films led the companies
trying to stop iiNet customers from using BitTorrent software to
illegally download copyrighted films, in a precedent-setting
case for all Internet providers in Australia. A ruling in the
studios'' favor would have made all Internet providers liable for
their customers'' conduct. </p>
<p>The evidence supports a conclusion that iiNet
demonstrated a dismissive and, indeed, contumelious, attitude to
the complaints of infringement, Judge Arthur Emmett wrote.
Its conduct did not amount to authorization of the primary
acts of infringement on the part of iiNet users. </p>
<p>iiNet rose 2 percent to A$2.55 at the 4:10 p.m. close of
trading on the Australian Stock Exchange, reversing an earlier
decline of 1.6 percent. The stock has slid 12 percent this year,
compared with a 1.4 percent gain for the SP/ASX 200 index. </p>
<p>Also appealing Cowdroy''s ruling were Time Warner Inc.''s
Warner Bros. Entertainment Inc., Twentieth Century Fox Film
Corp., a unit of News Corp., and 30 other entities who owned or
had exclusive licenses to commercially released films. </p>
<p>Future Lawsuits </p>
<p>Today''s victory for iiNet doesn''t protect Internet
providers from future lawsuits and that they may be found
liable, Emmett said. </p>
<p>It does not necessarily follow from the failure of the
present proceeding that circumstances could not exist whereby
iiNet might in the future be held to have authorized primary
acts of infringement, Emmett wrote. </p>
<p>The case is Roadshow Films Pty. Ltd. v iiNet Ltd.
NSD179/2010, Federal Court of Australia (Sydney.) </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Mathew Carr and Leela Landress" date="Feb 25, 2011  5:26 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-25/exxon-flared-gases-at-joliet-refinery-for-29-hours-filing-says.html"><headline>Exxon Flared Gases at Joliet Refinery for 29 Hours</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Exxon Mobil Corp., the largest U.S.
oil company, flared gases at its Joliet refinery in Channahon, Illinois, for more than 29 hours, according to a filing with
state regulators. </p>
<p>The filing to the Illinois Emergency Management Agency
didn''t say what caused the flaring or why it occurred for so
long before being discovered at 5:20 p.m. local time yesterday. </p>
<p>Operating conditions necessitated flaring, there was no
impact on production, Tricia Simpson, an Illinois-based
company spokeswoman, said in an e-mail today. </p>
<p>Refinery outages can increase prices for refined products
as refiners turn to spot markets to help them meet supply
contracts. Operational disruptions can also depress prices for
crude oil because less feedstock is needed. </p>
<p>The refinery has a processing capacity of 248,000 barrels a
day, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Margot Habiby" date="Feb 25, 2011  4:58 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-25/jpmorgan-raises-2011-brent-oil-forecast-to-104-barrel-from-95.html"><headline>JPMorgan Boosts 2011 Brent Oil Forecast by $9 to $104</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> JPMorgan Chase  Co. boosted its
2011 oil-price forecast for Brent oil by $9 to $104 a barrel,
citing supply shut-ins in Libya. </p>
<p>The $104 forecast assumes that supply problems will be
limited to Libya, that OPEC will supply additional oil and that
demand for precautionary inventories will moderate over time
from their crisis-levels of today, analysts led by Lawrence Eagles in New York said in a note to clients today. </p>
<p>There is a smaller but significant chance prices could
head toward $180 a barrel if the disruptions spread, with the
probability at 5 percent, the report showed. </p>
<p>Brent will likely average $108 a barrel in the first
quarter of the year, a 7.9 percent increase from its quarterly
average to date of $100.08 a barrel, the report said. JPMorgan
also raised its 2012 forecast by $5 to $110. The previous
forecasts were issued on Dec. 2. </p>
<p>Brent crude oil for April settlement rose 78 cents, or 0.7
percent, to $112.14 a barrel on the London-based ICE Futures
Europe exchange. Yesterday, it touched $119.79, the highest
price since Aug. 22, 2008. Brent gained 9.2 percent this week. </p>
<p>JPMorgan also changed its estimates for West Texas
Intermediate in the U.S., increasing the 2011 forecast by $4 to
$97 a barrel and lowering the 2012 outlook by $1 to $103. The
oil will likely average $96 a barrel in the first quarter of
this year, the report showed. Oil has averaged $89.47 so far
this quarter. </p>
<p>Oil for April delivery gained 60 cents, or 0.6 percent, to
settle at $97.88 a barrel on the New York Mercantile Exchange.
Oil touched $103.41 yesterday, the highest intraday price since
Sept. 29, 2008. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Catherine Larkin" date="Feb 25, 2011  4:27 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-25/pfizer-protalix-fail-to-win-fda-approval-of-cerezyme-rival-1-.html"><headline>Protalix Falls After FDA Declines Drug for Gaucher Disease</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Protalix BioTherapeutics Inc. (PLX) fell
the most in two years in New York trading after it failed to win
U.S. approval of a plant-based medicine it''s developing with
Pfizer Inc. (PFE) to treat Gaucher disease. </p>
<p>Protalix, based in Carmiel, Israel, dropped $1.73, or 18
percent, to $7.63 at 4:04 p.m. in New York Stock Exchange
composite trading, the biggest percentage decline since Dec. 1,
2008. Pfizer fell 4 cents to $18.86. </p>
<p>The Food and Drug Administration asked for more data from
two studies and information on testing specifications in the new
drug application for taliglucerase alfa, developed to treat
Gaucher disease, an inherited illness that causes fat build-up
that can lead to lung disease and brain damage, Protalix said
today in a statement. No new trials were requested. The drug
would compete with Genzyme Corp.''s top-selling Cerezyme and
Shire Plc (SHP)''s Vpriv. </p>
<p>We don''t think this is going to be a very long process,
Protalix Chief Executive Officer David Aviezer told analysts and
investors on a conference call today. The company plans to work
closely with Pfizer and request a meeting with the FDA as soon
as possible to determine what needs to be done for approval. </p>
<p>Taliglucerase is the first product for Protalix. The
medicine is designed to replace an enzyme missing in people with
Gaucher disease, a disorder that causes fat to build up in the
liver, spleen, bone marrow and nervous system. </p>
<h2>Rivals'' Sales </h2>
<p>Cerezyme had global sales of $719.6 million last year for
Cambridge, Massachusetts-based Genzyme, a 42 percent decline
from two years ago because of manufacturing issues. Vpriv,
chemically known as velaglucerase alfa, generated sales of $143
million for Dublin-based Shire after being approved by the FDA
in February 2010. </p>
<p>Importantly, it does not appear that the FDA has
significant safety concerns with taliglucerase, said Brian Abrahams, an analyst at Wells Fargo Securities in New York, in a
note to clients today. Rather, given the improving supply of
Genzyme''s Cerezyme and availability of Shire''s velaglucerase,
the agency likely prefers to wait for a more complete dataset
for patients on taliglucerase prior to approval. </p>
<p>Gaucher disease affects about 1 in every 50,000 to 100,000
people and can lead to bone pain, anemia, lung disease or brain
damage, according to the National Human Genome Research
Institute. </p>
<p>Taliglucerase, once approved, may win at least 15 percent
of patients through strong marketing and competitive
pricing, said Ritu Baral, an analyst at Canaccord Genuity in
New York, in a Feb. 22 note to clients. Cerezyme costs more than
$200,000 a year. </p>
<p>Pfizer, the world''s largest drugmaker, paid $60 million for
rights to taliglucerase in November 2009 and promised Protalix
an additional $55 million if the drug passed certain regulatory
hurdles. New York-based Pfizer is entitled to 60 percent of the
drug''s revenue under the licensing agreement. </p>
<p>Sanofi-Aventis SA of Paris said Feb. 16 it would buy
Genzyme for at least $20.1 billion. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Feb 25, 2011  2:33 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-25/jpmorgan-avoids-debt-downgrade-as-profits-increase-standard-poor-s-says.html"><headline>JPMorgan Outlook Improving, Downgrade Less Likely, S&amp;amp;P Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> JPMorgan Chase  Co., the second-
biggest U.S. bank by assets, had its credit outlook upgraded by Standard  Poor''s, which said the lender''s profit is likely to
rise. </p>
<p>The outlook was raised to stable from negative
because the New York-based firm is well-positioned to resume
significant earnings growth as the general economy recovers,
SP said today in a statement. </p>
<p>The credit rater said JPMorgan has a very strong
competitive position and implicit backing for the company''s
debt from the federal government because of the bank''s size and
importance in the global economy. </p>
<p>The stable outlook assumes that JPM''s earnings and
capitalization will continue to strengthen, and that it will
retain a sound funding and liquidity position, SP said. New
York-based SP also warned that JPMorgan''s ratings could fall if
the credit quality of the bank''s lending book deteriorates or if home prices significantly decline. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Feb 25, 2011  2:05 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-25/goldman-sachs-special-situations-group-head-richard-ruzika-plans-to-leave.html"><headline>Goldman''s Special-Situations Chief Ruzika to Leave</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>(Corrects description of SSG founders in the fifth,
sixth paragraphs of story originally published Feb. 25.) </p>
<p> Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)
special situations-group chief Richard Ruzika plans to
leave and will be replaced by Jason Brown. </p>
<p>Ruzika, 51, who has run the unit that invests in
distressed assets since 2007, will retire at the end of
April, Chief Executive Officer Lloyd Blankfein and
President Gary Cohn wrote in a Feb. 17 memo obtained by
Bloomberg News. Brown, who has led the group in Asia since
2007, will remain in Hong Kong, according to a separate
memo. </p>
<p>The group, known as SSG, began in Asia more than a
decade ago before expanding into Europe and the Americas.
While SSG''s overall performance isn''t made public, some of
its one-time gains and losses are included in company
disclosures. The group''s sale of Horizon Wind Energy LLC in
2007 generated about $900 million in gains, and it made
about $500 million in the fourth quarter of 2006 from the
recovery of failed Japanese golf courses that it purchased. </p>
<p> Michael DuVally, a spokesman for New York-based
Goldman Sachs, confirmed the content of the memos. The
moves were reported earlier today by the New York Times. </p>
<p>Peter Briger, who left in 2001 and is now co-chairman
of Fortress Investment Group LLC (FIG), and Edward Mule, now CEO
of Silver Point Capital LP, started the Asia business,
according to three people with knowledge of the group who
declined to be identified because the details haven''t been
disclosed by the bank. </p>
<p>New York Jet </p>
<p>Mark McGoldrick, who left in 2007 to start Mount
Kellett Capital Management LP, became co-head of the global
business with Ralph Rosenberg in 2003, according to a
Goldman Sachs memo at the time, and later led the group
with Stephen McGuinness. Ruzika became co-head with
McGuinness and sole head when McGuinness moved into Goldman
Sachs Asset Management in 2008, according to one of the
people familiar with evolution of the unit. </p>
<p>Ruzika joined Goldman Sachs in 1982 as a silver and
gold trader. He became head of global commodities in 2000
and co-head of global macro trading in 2006. </p>
<p>Ruzika played football at Columbia University and was
signed by the New York Jets in 1981 as a tight end before
he decided he didn''t want to play football and left
training camp, according to a New York Times article at the
time. </p>
<p>Performance Not Public </p>
<p>The firm has never given detailed results of the
special-situations group, which had been included in the
fixed-income, currencies and commodities revenue segment.
Last month, the company changed the way it disclosed
financial information, moving SSG to a new investing and
lending division. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs Chief Financial Officer David Viniar
said last month that there''s a chance some activities in
the firm''s investing and lending segment won''t be allowed
by new regulatory rules. SSG shouldn''t be affected by the
Dodd-Frank Act''s prohibition on proprietary trading because
most of the group is actually a lending business,
Viniar told analysts on Oct. 19. </p>
<p>Regulators are in the process of implementing the
Volcker rule, which was passed as part of Dodd-Frank in
July. The Federal Reserve confirmed this month that banks
would generally have two years to comply after the rule
takes effect. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jody Shenn" date="Feb 25, 2011 12:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-25/morgan-stanley-trader-colin-teichholtz-said-to-join-pine-river-hedge-fund.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Trader Teichholtz Joins Hedge Fund Pine River</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Colin Teichholtz, co-head of liquid
rates trading at Morgan Stanley, is leaving the company to join
hedge fund Pine River Capital Management LP, according to two
people familiar with the move. </p>
<p>Teichholtz, 40, helped lead a group at the New York-based
securities firm that traded Treasuries, interest-rate swaps,
agency debt and government-backed mortgage bonds. He will work
in New York for Minnetonka, Minnesota-based Pine River, said the
people, who declined to comment because the information isn''t
public. Teichholtz declined to comment for this article. </p>
<p>Hedge funds may step up hiring from investment banks after
firms including Goldman Sachs Group Inc., Morgan Stanley and
JPMorgan Chase  Co. cut compensation pools and deferred pay to
appease regulators seeking to reduce risk-taking in the wake of
the financial crisis. Average bonuses among 1,009 U.S.
respondents dropped 5 percent in 2010 from the previous year, a
survey by eFinancialCareers.com released last month showed </p>
<p>Performance at hedge funds climbed 1.7 percent last month,
reaching a two-year high as global stock markets rallied. </p>
<p>Teichholtz, who began at Morgan Stanley in 2003, is joining
a firm whose Nisswa Fixed Income Fund Ltd. ranked No. 7 in
Bloomberg Markets magazine''s 2010 list of 100 best-performing
hedge funds managing $1 billion or more. It returned 27 percent
in the first 10 months of the year, the period covered by the
rankings. </p>
<p>Patrick Clifford, a spokesman for Pine River, said the
company couldn''t comment at this time. Mary Claire Delaney,
a spokeswoman for Morgan Stanley, declined to comment. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley Chief Executive Officer James Gorman has
made changes in the firm''s trading unit after fourth-quarter
revenue from the fixed-income business was less than half that
of its rivals. The company last month replaced fixed-income
trading head Jack DiMaio with Ken deRegt, and hired Glenn Hadden
from rival Goldman Sachs Group Inc. as global head of interest
rates. </p>
<p>Jared Work, a Morgan Stanley trader of 30-year government-
backed mortgage bonds, also left the company this year, said one
of the people. Work declined to comment. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bob Willis" date="Feb 25, 2011  9:46 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-25/jpmorgan-economists-lower-first-quarter-u-s-growth-projection.html"><headline>JPMorgan Economists Lower First-Quarter U.S. Growth Projection</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> JPMorgan Chase  Co. revised down
its first-quarter growth estimate for the U.S. economy to an
annual rate of 3.5 percent from a prior forecast of 4 percent,
according to chief U.S. economist Michael Feroli. </p>
<p>Consumers stumbled a bit to start the year, Feroli
wrote in a note e-mailed to clients today. The recent rise in
energy prices poses a notable headwind. </p>
<p>The economy expanded at a 2.8 percent rate in the fourth
quarter, less than the earlier estimate of 3.2 percent as state
and local government spending declined, the Commerce Department
reported earlier today. Consumer spending grew at a 4.1 percent
rate, compared with a prior estimate of 4.4 percent. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Theo Mullen" date="Feb 26, 2011 10:50 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-26/exxon-mobil-flares-gases-at-refinery-in-baton-rouge-louisiana.html"><headline>Exxon Mobil Flares Gases at Refinery in Baton Rouge, Louisiana</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Exxon Mobil Corp. reported a
flaring event involving sulfur dioxide at its plant complex
in Baton Rouge, Louisiana, according to a regulatory filing. </p>
<p>A company report to the National Response Center showed
Exxon had repaired the source of the flare. </p>
<p>U.S. refineries must notify the National Response Center if
they release hazardous substances in excess of reportable
quantities, according to the Comprehensive Environmental
Response, Compensation and Liability Act, commonly known as
Superfund. </p>
<p>Baton Rouge is 81 miles (130 kilometers) northwest of New
Orleans. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Camilla Hall" date="Feb 26, 2011  3:49 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-26/jpmorgan-says-dubai-support-fund-may-need-2-4-billion-top-up-by-2012.html"><headline>JPMorgan Says Dubai Support Fund May Need $2.4 Billion `Top-up'' By 2012</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Dubai''s financial support fund, set
up to help the emirate''s state-owned companies pay back debt,
may need as much as $2.4 billion extra by 2012 to pay off
maturing liabilities, according to JPMorgan Chase. </p>
<p>We estimate that DFSF''s cash will get exhausted later
this year or early next, and will have to be topped up'' by $1.3
to $2.4 billion over the next two years, Zafar Nazim, a
London-based analyst at JPMorgan Securities Ltd, said in a
report to clients yesterday. We would expect capital markets
to be the primary source of such fund-raising, although some
asset sales cannot be ruled out. </p>
<p>Dubai roiled international markets in 2009 when it
announced plans to delay $24.9 billion in debt of its state-
owned holding company Dubai World. The holding company, which
has interests from real estate to industry, reached an agreement
with more than 70 creditor banks to delay loan payments after
property prices slumped in the emirate and frozen credit markets
prevented it from raising new loans to repay older ones. </p>
<p>Dubai World plans to return $4.4 billion of its loans in
five years and $10 billion in eight years, and pay below-market interest rates over their lifespan as part of its restructuring
plan. The money will be raised by selling assets. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Rebecca Evans" date="Feb 27, 2011  5:30 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-27/jpmorgan-chase-co-in-talks-to-acquire-twitter-stake-ft-says.html"><headline>JPMorgan in Talks to Acquire 10% Twitter Stake for $450 Million, FT Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> JPMorgan Chase  Co. is in talks to
acquire a 10 percent stake in Twitter for $450 million, the
Financial Times reported today citing people familiar with the
plans it didn''t name. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Cecile Vannucci" date="Feb 28, 2011 10:18 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-28/general-dynamics-put-trades-surge-as-investors-bet-on-a-decline.html"><headline>General Dynamics Put Trades Surge to 23-Month High</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>(Corrects put-option volume in second paragraph.) </p>
<p> General Dynamics Corp. put volume
rose to the highest level since March 2009, boosted by bets on a
decline of around 15 percent in the shares by January. </p>
<p>About 5,800 puts to sell the stock changed hands as of 3:40
p.m. in New York, 9 times the four-week average and more than 11
times the number of calls to buy. The most-traded contracts were
the January $65 puts, which accounted for almost two-thirds of
all put volume and rose 6 percent to $3.50. The Falls Church,
Virginia-based defense company gained 0.2 percent to $76.06. </p>
<p>General Dynamics gained 4.8 percent in the past year,
compared with a 27 percent increase in the Standard and Poor''s
500 Industrials Index. The share of Pentagon contract dollars
awarded to General Dynamics, Lockheed Martin Corp., Boeing Co.,
Northrop Grumman Corp. and Raytheon Co. dropped to 24.6 percent
last year from 35.9 percent in 2001, data compiled by Bloomberg
show. </p>
<p>U.S. Defense Secretary Robert M. Gates, who has targeted
$78billion in cuts through 2016 for deficit reduction, on Jan.
6 proposed canceling General Dynamics''s amphibious vehicle for
the U.S. Marine Corps. Ashton Carter, undersecretary of defense
for acquisitions, asked the Navy to have ready by mid-April a
cancellation plan for General Dynamics Corp.''s Expeditionary
Fighting Vehicle program. </p>
<p>General Dynamics'' implied volatility, the key gauge of
option prices, for at-the-money options expiring in 30 days rose
to 20.96 from 20.36 on Feb. 25. </p>
<p>Calls give the right to buy 100 shares of a security for a
certain amount, the strike price, by a set date. Puts convey the
right to sell. Investors use options to guard against
fluctuations in the price of securities they own, speculate on
share-price moves or bet that volatility, or stock swings, will
rise or fall. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael Riley" date="Feb 28, 2011  8:03 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-28/morgan-stanley-network-hacked-in-same-china-based-attacks-that-hit-google.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Attacked by China-Based Hackers Who Hit Google</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Morgan Stanley experienced a very
sensitive break-in to its network by the same China-based
hackers who attacked Google Inc.''s computers more than a year
ago, according to e-mails stolen from a cyber-security company
working for the bank. </p>
<p>The e-mails from the Sacramento, California-based computer
security firm HBGary Inc., which identify the first financial
institution targeted in the series of attacks, said the bank
considered details of the intrusion a closely guarded secret. </p>
<p>They were hit hard by the real Aurora attacks (not the
crap in the news), wrote Phil Wallisch, a senior security
engineer at HBGary, who said he read an internal Morgan Stanley
report detailing the so-called Operation Aurora attacks. </p>
<p>The nickname came from McAfee Inc., a Santa Clara,
California-based cyber-security firm, which said the attacks
occurred for about six months starting in June 2009 and marked
a watershed moment in cyber security. The number of
companies known to be hit in the attacks was initially estimated
at 20 to 30 and now exceeds 200, said Christopher Day, senior
vice president for Terremark Worldwide Inc., which provides information-technology security services. </p>
<p>The HBGary e-mails don''t indicate what information may have
been stolen from Morgan Stanley''s databanks or which of the
world''s largest merger adviser''s multinational operations were
targeted. </p>
<p>They have given me access to a very sensitive report on
their Aurora experience, Wallisch wrote in a May 10 e-mail to
HBGary President Penny Leavy-Hoglund. I will honor their
wishes about not sharing the info with anyone, but the good news
is that I have some great ideas for our final reports. </p>
<p> Sandra Hernandez, a spokeswoman for the New York-based
bank, which unlike Google didn''t disclose the attacks publicly,
declined to comment on them specifically. </p>
<p>Conducting Business'' </p>
<p>Like any other company in our industry we deal with
malware and attempted computer compromises as a matter of
conducting business and work with law enforcement where
appropriate, Hernandez said yesterday by phone. </p>
<p>FBI Deputy Assistant Director Steven Chabinsky said that
hackers have increasingly targeted information related to
mergers and acquisitions, data that can give companies involved
an advantage in negotiations. </p>
<p>Google said in January 2010 after an attack lasting for
months that it was one of 20 major U.S. companies breached by
hackers using China-based servers, an event that McAfee Chief
Technology Officer George Kurtz described as the largest and
most sophisticated cyberattack we have seen in years targeted at
specific corporations. </p>
<p>Politburo Standing Committee'' </p>
<p>U.S. diplomatic cables published by WikiLeaks and citing
high-level Chinese sources later traced direction of the attack
to the Politburo Standing Committee level of China''s
government. </p>
<p> Wang Baodong, a spokesman for the Chinese embassy in
Washington, said cyber-hacking is an international issue and
that many Chinese governmental websites have been attacked. </p>
<p>China''s stand on fighting hacking activities is clear and
consistent, with relevant strict domestic laws and regulations
in place, and is always ready to work with other countries to
jointly strike down on hacking crimes, he said yesterday in an
e-mail. </p>
<p>China''s official news agency last year quoted an
unidentified spokesman from the Ministry of Industry and
Information Technology saying that accusations the government
was behind the attacks were groundless. </p>
<p>Escalating Tensions </p>
<p>The attacks fueled escalating U.S.-China tensions and led
to a call on China by Secretary of State Hillary Clinton to
investigate Google''s claims and make the results public. </p>
<p>The attacks also led Google to stop censoring search
results generated by its Chinese search engine Google.cn. After
months of negotiations with Chinese officials, Google began to
shutter the site last March, redirecting users to the company''s
service in Hong Kong. </p>
<p>Google''s share of revenue generated by the China search
market fell to less than 20 percent in the fourth quarter of
2010 from 31 percent before the closure, according to Analysys
International, a Beijing research firm. This month, China''s
official news agency launched its own Internet search site
called Panguso that will conform to government-specified norms. </p>
<p>Forensic Investigations </p>
<p>Dmitri Alperovitch, McAfee''s vice president of threat
research, said that the company believes the Aurora attacks were
shut down by the hackers as Google began to uncover their
activities near the end of 2009. The company announced on Jan.
12, 2010, that it had been a victim of an attack. </p>
<p>Kevin Mandia, chief executive officer of the cyber-security
firm Mandiant, based in Alexandria, Virginia, said forensic
investigations of the attacks showed that the hackers had
penetrated various company networks over a period lasting more
than a year and had hit some companies multiple times. </p>
<p>Day and Mandia, citing client confidentiality, didn''t
discuss the companies that were victims of the attack. </p>
<p>The HBGary e-mails were stolen from the firm''s computer
network by the group of hacker activists called Anonymous, which
posted them on the Internet as a searchable database. HBGary
confirmed the messages were stolen and declined last week to
comment on their content. </p>
<p>Marc Zwillinger, an attorney for HBGary, didn''t respond to
a phone message seeking comment. Zwillinger has previously
declined to comment on the HBGary e-mails'' content, citing
client confidentiality. </p>
<p>Hired in 2010 </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley hired HBGary in 2010 to address suspected
network breaches by hackers not linked to Operation Aurora who
broke through the company''s Internet security systems. The
hackers successfully implanted software designed to steal
confidential files and internal communications, according to
dozens of HBGary e-mails that detail efforts to plug the holes. </p>
<p>One e-mail, dated June 19, said that the attackers may be
the same ones who had hit a U.K.-based defense contractor and
discusses hacking software called Monkif, which can be used by
intruders to remotely orchestrate a sophisticated form of cyber
attack known as an advanced persistent threat'' or APT. </p>
<p>This Monkif payload may represent APT or play a part in
the APT''s campaign, HBGary Chief Executive Officer Greg
Hoglund wrote to Wallisch. Phil, you might find this of value
given that you are dealing with the same attack over at
Morgan. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Feb 28, 2011  7:05 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-28/jpmorgan-says-it-may-face-enforcement-fines-in-mortgage-servicing-probes.html"><headline>JPMorgan Chase May Face Enforcement Action, Added Costs in Mortgage Probe</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> JPMorgan Chase  Co., the second-
largest U.S. bank by assets, may face enforcement actions, fines
and other added costs stemming from probes of its mortgage-
servicing procedures. </p>
<p>The firm expects to incur additional costs and expenses
in connection with its efforts to correct and enhance its
mortgage foreclosure procedures, the New York-based company
said in its annual filing with the Securities and Exchange
Commission yesterday. JPMorgan said it can''t predict the outcome
of the federal and state investigations or the financial impact. </p>
<p> Bank of America Corp. and Wells Fargo  Co., the largest
and third-largest U.S. banks by assets, said in separate filings
last week they may face fines or enforcement actions from state
and federal law enforcement agencies tied to their foreclosure
practices. The probes may also lead to significant legal
costs, Charlotte, North Carolina-based Bank of America said.
Wells Fargo, based in San Francisco, said in its filing that
penalties are likely. </p>
<p>JPMorgan and its subsidiaries are defending themselves in
more than 10,000 legal proceedings, including government
investigations and civil litigation, the company said. It added
$7.4 billion to its litigation reserves in 2010, up from $161
million in 2009. The bank reduced its legal reserves by $781
million the year before. </p>
<p>Possible Tally </p>
<p>JPMorgan said it''s reasonably possible that legal
proceedings may cause as much as $4.5 billion in additional
losses that aren''t covered by its litigation reserves, which
were not fully disclosed. Such losses may be as low as zero, it
said. </p>
<p>The bank may incur as much as $2 billion in losses beyond
accruals to cover demands that it repurchase faulty mortgages,
such as loans sold to government-sponsored enterprises Fannie
Mae and Freddie Mac. Such losses may also be as low as zero,
JPMorgan said. The estimate is contingent on a further decline
in home prices. </p>
<p>JPMorgan said its cost of repurchasing mortgage loans sold
to the government-sponsored enterprises increased substantially
last year, and there is no assurance that such costs could not
continue to increase substantially in the future. JPMorgan''s
repurchase liability to Fannie Mae, Freddie Mac or private
companies may materially and adversely affect the bank''s
future earnings. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Feb 28, 2011  6:46 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-28/morgan-stanley-faces-probe-on-loans-made-to-military-members.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Faces Probe on Military Members'' Mortgages</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Morgan Stanley, the sixth-biggest
U.S. bank by assets, faces a probe tied to mortgages for members
of the U.S. military. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley has received subpoenas and requests for
information on matters that include the company''s compliance
with the Service Members Civil Relief Act, according to the
New York-based firm''s annual report today to securities
regulators. The subpoenas and requests include those relating to
the purchase, origination and servicing of residential
mortgages, according to the filing. </p>
<p>The Service Members Civil Relief Act provides financial
relief to military personnel on active duty and can delay
foreclosures. JPMorgan Chase  Co., the second-biggest U.S. bank
by assets, said earlier this month it will forgive mortgages of
military families whose homes were improperly seized and revamp
its housing program for service members and veterans. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley is also facing subpoenas and information
requests regarding its due diligence on loans it purchased for
securitization, communications with ratings companies and its
handling of foreclosure-related issues, according to the filing. </p>
<p> Sandra Hernandez, a spokeswoman for the firm, declined to
comment. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Feb 28, 2011  5:46 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-28/morgan-stanley-divested-stake-in-half-built-revel-casino-stake-on-feb-17.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Sold Revel Casino Stake on Feb. 17, Filing Shows</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Morgan Stanley, the sixth-largest
U.S. bank by assets, said it sold its stake in Revel
Entertainment Group LLC, the developer of a half-built casino
resort in Atlantic City, New Jersey. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley sold its stake to an investor group led by
Kevin DeSanctis, chairman and chief executive officer of Revel
Entertainment, according to a filing today with the U.S.
Securities and Exchange Commission. The New York-based bank
didn''t take a pretax loss or gain on the sale, according to the
filing. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley wrote down the value of its stake by about
$1.2 billion last year, recognizing a loss of about 98 percent,
after deciding to sell the holding. The SEC asked Morgan Stanley
to explain why it waited until last year to report the losses,
according to letters released in November. </p>
<p>The sale came on the day Revel said it raised $1.15 billion
to restart construction. The beachfront resort, located at the
northern end of the Atlantic City boardwalk and budgeted at
about $2.4 billion, is expected to open in mid-2012, Revel said
on that day. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley told the SEC in letters last year that
before its decision to sell the stake, it had consolidated Revel
and compared the book value of the investment with undiscounted
cash flows to check whether a charge was warranted. The bank
said it recognized there were impairment indicators before
the first quarter of 2010. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Feb 28, 2011  5:24 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-28/morgan-stanley-says-it-experienced-net-trading-losses-38-days-in-2010.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Reports Trading Losses 38 Days in 2010, Same as Year Before</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Morgan Stanley, the sixth-largest U.S. bank by assets, had trading losses on 38 days in 2010, the
same number as in 2009. </p>
<p>The firm''s trading division lost money on 13 days during
the fourth quarter, according to a filing with the U.S.
Securities and Exchange Commission. New York-based Morgan
Stanley generated more than $100 million on about 25 days in
2010, down from 69 days in 2009. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley had $10.3 billion in sales and trading
revenue for 2010, about half that of rivals Goldman Sachs Group
Inc. and JPMorgan Chase  Co. Excluding charges relating to the
firm''s credit spreads, the bank''s trading revenue fell 22
percent from 2009 to $11.1 billion. Chief Executive Officer James Gorman, 52, has changed management and increased hiring in
the fixed-income trading unit to close the gap. </p>
<p>Bank of America Corp. said last week that it had gains on
90 percent of its trading days in 2010. Citigroup Inc. had 55
days of losses out of 260 trading days in the year, meaning it
had positive revenue on 79 percent of days. JPMorgan said it
lost money on eight trading days in 2010. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Karen Freifeld" date="Feb 28, 2011  3:39 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-28/morgan-stanley-loses-bid-to-dismiss-taiwanese-bank-s-fraud-claims-over-cdo.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Loses Bid to Dismiss Taiwanese Bank''s Fraud Claims Over CDO</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Morgan Stanley lost a bid to dismiss
fraud claims by Taipei-based China Development Industrial Bank,
which seeks to recover losses from an investment tied to U.S.
residential mortgage-backed securities. </p>
<p>The Taiwanese bank claims Morgan Stanley made an investment
linked to U.S. subprime mortgage bonds in mid-2006 and dumped
those losses on CDIB in April 2007 after learning of problems
with the investment. </p>
<p>New York state Supreme Court Justice Melvin L. Schweitzer''s
decision was posted today on the state''s court filing system. </p>
<p>CDIB has alleged in sufficient detail that Morgan Stanley
knew the Supersenior Swap was a highly risky, if not troubled,
investment and also that the ratings process which made it
appear to be safe, or even more secure than a AAA'' rated
security, was deeply flawed, Schweitzer wrote. </p>
<p>Pen Pendleton, a spokesman for Morgan Stanley, declined to
comment on the decision. </p>
<p>CDIB claims it was fraudulently sold a $275 million
interest in what the bank called the STACK 2006-1 Ltd., a hybrid
collateralized debt obligation. CDOs are pools of assets such as
mortgage bonds packaged into new securities. </p>
<p>CDIB said in its lawsuit it had lost $228 million on the
transaction. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley allegedly knew the CDO assets were rated
with models no longer in use and that the CDO assets'' ratings
were likely to be downgraded in the future, according to court
papers. The firm also allegedly failed to disclose to CDIB it
had paid the ratings agencies fees of up to three times more
than usual to obtain a rating in return for assistance in
structuring the product. </p>
<p>The case is China Development Industrial Bank v. Morgan
Stanley, 650957/2010, New York state Supreme Court  Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Feb 28, 2011 10:03 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-28/jpmorgan-is-said-to-pick-stewart-to-run-proprietary-trading-ahead-of-curbs.html"><headline>JPMorgan Is Said to Pick Stewart to Run Proprietary Trading Ahead of Curbs</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> JPMorgan Chase  Co. picked Mike Stewart to head a proprietary trading unit the firm is moving
from its investment bank ahead of U.S. restrictions on making
bets for its own account, a person briefed on the decision said. </p>
<p>The bank may seed the group with as much as $2 billion,
Financial News reported earlier, citing an unidentified person
familiar with the situation. While plans aren''t final, the team
may start a core fund that invests mainly in emerging markets,
credit and equities, the newspaper reported. </p>
<p>Congress passed restrictions known as the Volcker rule last
year, limiting risk-taking by lenders to prevent a recurrence of
the credit crisis. Proprietary traders make trades on behalf of
their firm, rather than clients. New York-based JPMorgan said in
September it planned to shift proprietary traders in emerging
markets, structured-credit and equity units to its asset
management division, with Stewart overseeing the move. </p>
<p>Stewart, co-head of the bank''s global emerging markets
business, will lead investments in that area, Financial News
said. Fahad Roumani, a managing director in credit proprietary
trading, will run credit, and Deepak Gulati, head of global
equity proprietary trading, will oversee equities, the newspaper
said. </p>
<p> Jennifer Zuccarelli, a JPMorgan spokeswoman, said she
couldn''t comment. </p>
<p>JPMorgan plans to close its desk for proprietary trading of
commodities, affecting fewer than 20 traders, to comply with the
new rule, a person briefed on the matter said in August. </p>
<p>Two Years to Comply </p>
<p>The Volcker rule, a provision of the Dodd-Frank Act passed
last July, was named after former Federal Reserve Chairman Paul Volcker, who campaigned for limits on risk-taking by lenders
following the global financial crisis. The Federal Reserve said
this month that banks would generally have two years to comply
after the rule takes effect. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. last year shut down an equity
proprietary trading group, Goldman Sachs Principal Strategies,
to comply with the rule. Morgan Stanley, the world''s top merger
adviser, said last month that it plans to break off its largest
proprietary-trading group, Process Driven Trading, as an
independent advisory firm by the end of 2012. </p>
<p>JPMorgan will try to raise money from outside investors for
the fund, according to the report by Financial News carried on
the Wall Street Journal''s website. </p>
<p>The company''s shares climbed 34 cents, or 0.7 percent, to
$47.02 as of 10 a.m. in New York Stock Exchange composite
trading. The stock is up 11 percent this year. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Esteban Duarte" date="Feb 28, 2011  1:41 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-28/morgan-stanley-may-buy-a-stake-in-abertis-unit-negocio-says.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley May Buy a Stake in Abertis Unit, Negocio Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A Morgan Stanley fund may acquire a
stake in Abertis Infraestructuras SA''s parking unit, Negocio
reported, citing Pedro Mielgo, head of Madrilena Red de Gas, a
Spanish gas-distribution company owned by the U.S. investment
bank. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley Global Infrastructure Fund is analyzing the
business of Saba Infraestructuras, as the unit is known, before
taking a decision, the newspaper said. Morgan Stanley declined
to comment, Negocio said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Frye" date="Feb 28, 2011 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-02-28/goldman-to-win-fed-blessing-to-repay-berkshire-s-5-billion-buffett-says.html"><headline>Goldman to Win Fed Blessing to Repay Berkshire''s $5 Billion, Buffett Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Warren Buffett said Goldman Sachs
Group Inc. will probably win Federal Reserve approval this year
to repay the $5 billion he injected in the bank, pressuring
investment income at his Berkshire Hathaway Inc. </p>
<p>The Goldman Sachs stake and a $3 billion investment in General Electric Co., each of which pay 10 percent annual
interest to Berkshire, will likely be terminated by Dec. 31,
Buffett said Feb. 26 in his annual letter. While the Fed has
held back Goldman from repaying, the regulator will likely
give Goldman the green light before long, Buffett wrote. </p>
<p>GE and Goldman Sachs turned to Buffett in 2008 to bolster
their capital and increase confidence in the firms as borrowing
costs surged after the collapse of Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc.
Goldman and GE are each required to pay a 10 percent premium to
Omaha, Nebraska-based Berkshire to redeem the investments. </p>
<p>The redemptions are nevertheless unwelcome, Buffett
wrote. After they occur, our earning power will be
significantly reduced. </p>
<p> Michael DuVally, a spokesman for New York-based Goldman
Sachs, declined to comment. David Skidmore, a spokesman for the
Fed, didn''t return calls outside of normal business hours. </p>
<p>Dividends from GE, Goldman Sachs and Swiss Reinsurance Co.
helped bolster investment income at Buffett''s insurance units
when fixed-income yields declined and Wells Fargo  Co. slashed
its dividend. Berkshire is the largest investor in the San
Francisco-based bank, with more than 340 million shares. Swiss
Re struck a deal in November to repay Berkshire. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
Berkshire Hathaway Inc. Chairman and Chief Executive officer Warren Buffett. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tiffany Kary and Edvard Pettersson" date="Mar 01, 2011  8:14 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-01/walt-disney-objects-to-proposed-blockbuster-bankruptcy-auction.html"><headline>Blockbuster Sale Attacked by Disney, Universal, Landlords</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Blockbuster Inc.''s proposed sale
benefits a group of lenders at the expense of all other
creditors, said objectors including Walt Disney Co., Universal
Studios, Yahoo! Inc., the U.S. Trustee''s office, landlords and a
committee of unsecured creditors. </p>
<p>The objections, filed yesterday, set up a fight over how
the cash-strapped movie-rental chain should end its bankruptcy.
U.S. Bankruptcy Judge Burton Lifland in New York, in an order
today, adjourned a hearing that was scheduled for tomorrow to
consider a motion to sell the Dallas-based company to a group
including Monarch Alternative Capital LP. He rescheduled the
hearing for March 10. </p>
<p>Because Blockbuster filed bankruptcy with a partially
outlined reorganization and then became administratively
insolvent, the dispute was inevitable, said Steven Wilamowsky, a
Bingham McCutchen LLP partner who isn''t involved in the case. </p>
<p>If parties come in expecting a crash landing, they
negotiate with those expectations in mind, Wilamowsky said.
If they come in with a negotiated plan, they think they''ll
get paid in full and continue to ship. </p>
<p>Because Chapter 11 isn''t intended for companies that are
administratively insolvent, judges must resolve such conflicts,
he said. </p>
<p>Blockbuster, attempting to reorganize in Chapter 11 since
September, should liquidate under Chapter 7 because it can''t pay
the costs of its own bankruptcy, said the Office of the U.S.
Trustee, an arm of the Justice Department that oversees
bankruptcies. </p>
<p>Creditors'' Arguments </p>
<p>Unsecured creditors, business partner Yahoo and landlords
also objected to Blockbuster''s plan to sell itself under an
offer from lenders. </p>
<p>This court should not permit the Monarch group to abuse
the Chapter 11 process, unsecured creditors wrote, saying that
lenders who stepped in with a $125 million loan to fund
operations used a roll-up provision to pay themselves back
for pre-bankruptcy debt and get fees and expense reimbursement. </p>
<p>The lenders saddled other creditors with massive accrued
and unpaid administrative claims in excess of $250 million,
the creditors claimed. </p>
<p>The illusory loan induced landlords, studios and other
creditors to keep supplying Blockbuster with goods, and the sale
process will let the lenders walk away unscathed leaving
restructuring carnage behind as the company can''t cover
administrative expenses, the unsecured creditor said. </p>
<p>Blockbuster is proposing an auction using as a baseline the
$290 million stalking horse bid from Monarch, Owl Creek
Asset Management LP, Stonehill Capital Management LLC, and Varde
Partners Inc. </p>
<p>Cobalt Video Holdco </p>
<p>The stalking horse group, called Cobalt Video Holdco LLC,
holds more than half of Blockbuster''s $630 million debt in 11.75
percent senior secured notes. It made no commitment to continue
the business. A provision in the agreement gives Cobalt the
right to compel a conversion of the Chapter 11 reorganization
case to liquidation under Chapter 7. </p>
<p> Walt Disney, with a $9.2 million claim for merchandise
shipped to Blockbuster after its September filing, said a sale
may still be the best way to maximize assets. The current
proposal is unfair, it said. </p>
<p>Disney remains hopeful that the debtors'' sale process
yields results favorable for all constituents, the company''s
lawyers wrote. Disney objects, however, to the secured lender
apparently having dictated sale terms beneficial to itself and
detrimental to the debtors'' estates. </p>
<p>No True Financing </p>
<p>Disney said there is no true post-bankruptcy financing, or
debtor-in-possession loan, because the lenders, who are pre-
bankruptcy secured noteholders, never advanced any new cash
after the Chapter 11 filing. All there is, Disney says, is
$125 million in pre-bankruptcy notes that were transformed
through the so-called rollup. </p>
<p>Lifland also will consider a motion by Summit Entertainment
LLC, which wants to be paid $9.4 million for goods supplied
after bankruptcy. Summit wants the case converted to a
liquidation if the judge won''t allow it to reclaim its unsold
goods. </p>
<p>Universal Studios Home Entertainment LLC, owed $6.4 million
for movies including  Scott Pilgrim vs. the World, said
Blockbuster accepted its shipments post-bankruptcy without
intending to pay for them. </p>
<p>Blockbuster admits that the studios as business partners
are the lifeblood of their business, Universal said in court
papers. </p>
<p>Fox Documents </p>
<p>Twentieth Century Fox Home Entertainment LLC asked the
court to protect its collateral. It filed documents outlining
its arguments under seal. </p>
<p>Administrative expenses incurred in the bankruptcy through
Feb. 24 will be frozen, according to court papers. Those
beginning on Feb. 25 will be paid only if provided for in a sale
budget. The sale contract also requires the court to bar
creditors from taking any action to collect on a claim before
June 21. </p>
<p>Blockbuster said in court filings that there is a
possibility it won''t be able to pay all suppliers for goods
provided after the Chapter 11 filing. </p>
<p>The company began reorganization in September with 5,600
stores, including 3,300 in the U.S. and the rest abroad. Among
the U.S. stores, 3,000 were owned. The rest are franchised.
About 200 stores closed before the bankruptcy. </p>
<p>The petition listed assets of $1.02 billion against debt of
$1.47 billion. Blockbuster estimated it owes $57 million in
accounts payable in addition to the secured and subordinated
notes. </p>
<p>The case is In re Blockbuster, 10-14997, U.S. Bankruptcy
Court, Southern District of New York  Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Barbara Powell" date="Mar 01, 2011  5:37 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-01/exxon-said-to-shut-beaumont-s-catalytic-cracker-after-leak.html"><headline>Exxon Said to Shut Beaumont''s Catalytic Cracker After Leak</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Exxon Mobil Corp.''s Beaumont, Texas,
refinery shut a fluid catalytic cracker yesterday after a leak,
two people familiar with the plant''s operations said. </p>
<p>The unit, the plant''s only catalytic cracker, remains shut
today and may be down for a while, said the people, who declined
to be identified because they aren''t authorized to speak for the
refinery. Exxon is trying to identify the source of the leak,
one of the people said. </p>
<p>Kevin Allexon, a Fairfax, Virginia-based Exxon spokesman,
declined to comment, saying that we do not comment on day-to-
day operations. </p>
<p>The refinery is capable of processing 359,100 barrels a
day, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Exxon is the largest U.S. refiner. Its three Gulf Coast
plants account for 17 percent of that region''s operable crude
oil capacity, according to the Energy Department. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Mulholland" date="Mar 01, 2011  4:57 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-01/jpmorgan-s-commercial-mortgage-bonds-set-to-sell-as-spreads-widen-in-u-s-.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sells Commercial-Mortgage Bonds as Spreads Widen</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> JPMorgan Chase  Co. sold a $1.5
billion commercial-mortgage bond as Middle East turmoil slows a
three-month rally for the debt. </p>
<p>Top-rated securities tied to skyscraper, shopping mall and
hotel loans are yielding 1.95 percentage points more than
Treasuries, up from a spread of 1.88 percentage points on Feb.
18, the lowest level in at least three years, according to a
Barclays Plc index. </p>
<p>Investors are demanding higher yields as protests gain
momentum in Libya, sparking concern that rising oil prices could
hamper an economic recovery, said Brian Lancaster, a Stamford,
Connecticut-based analyst with Royal Bank of Scotland Plc. </p>
<p>Earlier in the year we had tremendous momentum,
Lancaster said in a telephone interview. The events in the
Middle East have caused a pull-back in the stock market, and
that impacts investor sentiment. </p>
<p>JPMorgan''s largest top-rated portion of the commercial-
mortgage bond, a $485.4 million slice maturing in 9.77 years,
yields 112 basis points more than the benchmark swap rate,
according to a person familiar with the transaction who declined
to be identified because terms aren''t public. The New York-based
bank had originally offered the debt for 105 basis points over
swaps, according to marketing materials distributed to investors
on Feb. 23. </p>
<p>$45 Billion Forecast </p>
<p>Banks have arranged about $6.5 billion in commercial
mortgage-backed securities this year, compared with $11.5
billion in all of 2010, according to data compiled by Bloomberg.
JPMorgan has forecast sales will rise to $45 billion this year
after plunged to $3.4 billion in 2009 amid the financial crisis.
Issuance peaked at a record $234 billion in 2007, Bloomberg data
show. </p>
<p>Investor appetite for bonds backed by commercial real
estate increases the credit supply for U.S. borrowers who need
to refinance maturing loans. About 63 percent of JPMorgan''s
offering is tied to retail properties, and almost 25 percent is
linked to office buildings, the person with knowledge of the
sale. </p>
<p>The securities comprise 45 loans on 109 properties, the
largest of which is a $215 million mortgage on a mall in
Holyoke, Massachusetts. Loans in Texas account for the highest
concentration, about 20 percent of the pool, followed by 16
percent in Massachusetts, said the person. </p>
<p>Competition among lenders has led to riskier loans being
included in more recent deals, Standard  Poor''s said in a Feb
24 report. Current offerings are more highly leveraged and have
less income to cover debt payments than those completed in late
2009, SP said. </p>
<p>In the short 15 months since we began seeing new CMBS
issuance again, transaction structures are becoming more complex
and underwriting standards are loosening somewhat, the
analysts wrote. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Brian Louis" date="Mar 01, 2011  4:26 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-01/general-growth-beats-analyst-estimates-with-positive-funds-from-operations.html"><headline>General Growth Beats Analyst Estimates With Positive Funds From Operations</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> General Growth Properties Inc., the
U.S. mall owner that left bankruptcy in November, reported a
surprise profit excluding some items in the fourth quarter as
impairment costs dropped. </p>
<p>Funds from operations were $254.9 million, or 26 cents a
share, compared with a loss of $413.9 million, or $1.29, a year
earlier, the Chicago-based company said yesterday in a
statement. The year-earlier loss included $793.9 million in real
estate writedowns, according to a statement last year. Analysts
projected negative FFO of 71 cents a share, the average of 10
estimates in a Bloomberg survey. </p>
<p>Fourth-quarter results are the first General Growth has
reported since the company emerged from the biggest real estate
bankruptcy in U.S. history. Sandeep Mathrani, a former Vornado
Realty Trust executive, took over as chief executive officer of
General Growth in January. The company plans to refinance about
$5 billion of mortgage debt, Mathrani said. </p>
<p>We will steadfastly guard our balance sheet and the
franchise to squarely focus on the task at hand, driving revenue
and creating value for our shareholders, Mathrani said today
in a conference call with analysts. We''ve embarked upon a
significant mortgage refinancing plan. An environment of low interest rates allows us to achieve more favorable terms than we
had imagined before. </p>
<p>Property Sales </p>
<p>Since November, the company sold eight shopping centers and
three other properties for $84.7 million in net proceeds and it
is under contract to sell three more properties for $154.8
million, Mathrani said. </p>
<p>Mathrani succeeded Adam Metz, who had been CEO since
October 2008. </p>
<p>General Growth filed for Chapter 11 protection in April
2009 after weighing itself down with $27 billion in debt that it
was unable to refinance because of the financial crisis and
collapse of the commercial mortgage-backed securities market. </p>
<p>The company spun off Howard Hughes Corp., an owner of
master-planned communities and other properties, as part of its
restructuring, making the company solely a mall owner. </p>
<p>FFO is a cash-flow measure used by real estate investment
trusts. It excludes depreciation and other items and doesn''t
conform to generally accepted accounting principles. </p>
<p>Lack of Forecast </p>
<p>General Growth did not provide financial forecasts in the
statement or in the conference call. Mathrani said the company
will make a projection in the third quarter. </p>
<p>The lack of a forecast for per-share FFO or same-store net
operating income for the year is disappointing, Benjamin
Yang and Patrick Glennon, analysts at Keefe Bruyette  Woods,
wrote in a report yesterday. </p>
<p> Simon Property Group Inc., the only U.S. mall owner larger
than General Growth, on Feb. 4 reported FFO that increased to
$630.6 million, or $1.78 a share, from $485.2 million, or $1.40,
a year earlier. </p>
<p>General Growth shares fell 39 cents, or 2.5 percent, to
$15.53 as of 4:15 p.m. in New York Stock Exchange composite
trading. The company has ownership and management interests in
169 malls in 43 states. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christine Harper" date="Mar 01, 2011  3:05 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-01/goldman-sachs-estimates-possible-losses-from-legal-cases-at-3-4-billion.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Estimates `Reasonably Possible'' Legal Losses at $3.4 Billion</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Goldman Sachs Group Inc., the fifth-
biggest U.S. bank by assets, said reasonably possible losses
from legal claims against the company may amount to as much as
$3.4 billion. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs hasn''t set aside a significant amount of
money against the possible losses, the New York-based bank said
today in a 10-K filing with the U.S. Securities and Exchange
Commission. The estimate, the first of its kind disclosed by the
firm, is the upper end of losses in matters where the risk
is more than remote but less than likely, the firm said. </p>
<p>Banks are releasing possible-loss estimates after the SEC
said in an October letter to corporate finance chiefs that they
should disclose such losses when there is at least a
reasonable possibility that they may be incurred, even if the
risk is too low to require reserves. </p>
<p>They''ve got the best lawyers, they''re going to drag these
claims out as far as they possibly can, said Brad Hintz, an
analyst at Sanford C. Bernstein  Co. in New York who has an
outperform rating on Goldman Sachs''s stock. Goldman has
3 years or 3 1/2 years to build reserves for what will
ultimately be settlements. </p>
<p>Hintz said securities law cases have a five-year statute of
limitations, so claims related to the financial crisis are
likely to peak in the next year. He said cases typically take
four or five years to be settled. </p>
<p>JPMorgan, Citigroup </p>
<p> Citigroup Inc. said last week that as much as $4 billion in
additional costs from pending legal matters are possible, but
not probable. JPMorgan Chase  Co. said yesterday that it''s
reasonably possible that legal proceedings may cause as much
as $4.5 billion in losses beyond its litigation reserves. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs''s estimate doesn''t include any amount for
cases that are at early stages or where there are significant
factual issues to be resolved or novel legal issues, according
to the filing. </p>
<p>The figure was calculated by adding up three categories of
potential liability, the filing said. The firm included the
amount of money damages claimed, where applicable. It also added
the amount of securities sold in cases where Goldman Sachs is
being sued by purchasers of a deal underwritten by the company
and where it''s not being indemnified. Finally, in cases where
parties are demanding that Goldman Sachs repurchase securities
they acquired from the firm, the calculation is based on the
difference between the price paid and the estimated value on
Dec. 31. </p>
<p>Profit Drop </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs reported a 38 percent drop in net income to
$8.35 billion in 2010 from a record $13.4 billion in 2009 as
trading revenue tumbled and non-compensation expenses, driven by
provisions for litigation and regulatory proceedings, increased
14 percent. </p>
<p>The 2010 litigation and regulatory costs include
$550 million to settle a fraud suit brought against the firm
last year by the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission, which
accused Goldman Sachs of misleading investors in a mortgage-
linked investment that was sold in 2007. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs said in today''s filing that it''s facing
complaints in federal and state courts from plaintiffs asserting
that its disclosures on mortgage-related products were improper. </p>
<p>The company estimates that aggregate cumulative losses by
the plaintiffs in active cases total about $457 million as of
Dec. 31. That total doesn''t include other potential claims. </p>
<p>The plaintiffs include the Federal Home Loan Banks of Seattle, Chicago and Indianapolis, Charles Schwab Corp.,
Cambridge Place Investment Management Inc., Basis Yield Alpha
Fund (Master) and Landesbank Baden-Wuerttemberg, the firm said. </p>
<p>The National Credit Union Administration also plans to
pursue similar claims on behalf of some credit unions, and a
number of other entities have threatened to assert claims
against the firm in connection with various mortgage-related
offerings, Goldman Sachs said in the filing. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Leela Landress" date="Mar 01, 2011 10:50 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-01/exxon-mobil-s-beaumont-refinery-in-texas-flares-gases.html"><headline>Exxon Mobil''s Beaumont Refinery in Texas Flares Gases</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Exxon Mobil Corp., the largest U.S.
oil company, flared gases at its refinery in Beaumont, Texas,
according to a message left on a community hot line. </p>
<p>Conditions at the refinery at the time necessitated that
we flare, Kevin Allexon, a company spokesman based in Fairfax,
Virginia, said in an e-mail today. Allexon declined to comment
further. </p>
<p>Outages can increase prices for refined products as
refiners turn to spot markets to help them meet supply
contracts. Operational disruptions can also depress prices for
crude oil because less feedstock is needed. </p>
<p>The plant can process 359,100 barrels of crude a day,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Leela Landress" date="Mar 01, 2011  9:41 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-01/chevron-phillips-has-power-failure-at-cedar-bayou-nrc-says.html"><headline>Chevron Phillips Has Power Failure at Cedar Bayou, U.S. Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Phillips Chemical Co. LLC
had a power failure at its Cedar Bayou chemical plant in
Baytown, Texas, according to a filing with the U.S. National
Response Center. </p>
<p>The company was attempting to shut down and block in all
feeds from the pipeline as safely as possible after the
incident at 7:12 p.m. local time yesterday, the report said. </p>
<p>Linda Koenig, a spokeswoman for The Woodlands, Texas-based
company, declined to comment. </p>
<p>U.S. refineries must notify the National Response Center if
they release hazardous substances in excess of reportable
quantities, according to the Comprehensive Environmental
Response, Compensation and Liability Act, commonly known as
Superfund. </p>
<p>Chemical plant outages can increase prices for products as
companies turn to spot markets to help them meet supply
contracts. </p>
<p>The Cedar Bayou plant is located about 32 miles (51
kilometers) east of Houston. The company is a joint venture of Chevron Corp. and ConocoPhillips. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christine Harper" date="Mar 01, 2011  8:13 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-01/goldman-sachs-liquidates-2-proprietary-trading-units-to-comply-with-rules.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Liquidates 2 Proprietary Trading Units to Comply With Rules</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Goldman Sachs Group Inc., the fifth-
biggest U.S. bank by assets, has closed or is closing two
trading units that made bets with the firm''s own capital, an
activity that has been prohibited under new U.S. financial rules. </p>
<p>To comply with provisions of the Dodd-Frank Act, Goldman
Sachs during 2010 liquidated substantially all of the
positions in the principal-strategies unit that operated
within the firm''s equities division, the New York-based company
said today in its annual 10-K filing with the U.S. Securities
and Exchange Commission. </p>
<p>In the first quarter of 2011, the firm commenced the
liquidation of the positions that had been held by the global
macro proprietary-trading desk within the fixed-income,
currencies and commodities division, according to the filing. </p>
<p>Net revenues from principal strategies and our global
macro proprietary-trading desk were not material for the year
ended December 2010, the filing said. We will continue to
assess our business, risk management, and compliance practices
to conform with developments in the regulatory environment. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christine Harper" date="Mar 01, 2011  7:59 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-01/goldman-sachs-group-says-it-lost-money-from-trading-on-25-days-last-year.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Group Says It Lost Money From Trading on 25 Days Last Year</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Goldman Sachs Group Inc., the fifth-
biggest U.S. bank by assets, lost money from trading on 25 days
during 2010, up from a record-low 19 days in 2009, according to
a regulatory filing. </p>
<p>After incurring losses on trades during 12 days in the
first 9 months, the full-year figures indicate that Goldman
Sachs lost money on 13 days in the fourth quarter. The firm''s
traders also made $100 million or more on 68 days in 2010, down
from the record 131 days in 2009, according to the New York-
based company''s annual 10-K filing with the Securities and
Exchange Commission. </p>
<p>Traders exceeded the firm-wide value-at-risk limit, or
VaR, on one occasion during 2010 to facilitate a client
transaction, according to the filing. The risk position was
reduced the following day to comply with the limit, which is one
of the gauges Goldman Sachs uses to measure potential trading
losses. In 2009, the firm-wide VaR was exceeded on two
consecutive days, the filing said. </p>
<p>Although the filing doesn''t say when the VaR limit was
exceeded, it includes a graph showing a one-day increase in
daily value-at-risk early in the fourth quarter to a high of
$223 million from a fourth-quarter range of between about $100
million and $140 million. The average value-at-risk for the year
was $134 million, down from $218 million in 2009. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
The headquarters of The Goldman Sachs Group Inc. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Danielle Kucera" date="Mar 01, 2011  7:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-01/jpmorgan-pnc-lead-in-taking-customers-from-rivals-study-says.html"><headline>JPMorgan, PNC Lead in Taking Customers From Rivals, Study Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>PNC Financial Services Inc., JPMorgan Chase  Co. and SunTrust Banks Inc. led U.S. banks in
taking customers from competitors, according to a J. D. Power
and Associates survey of consumers who switched banks last year. </p>
<p>Customers who changed banks increased to 8.7 percent from
7.7 percent during the past year, the survey of 25 banks showed.
The three lenders each increased new customers by more than 11
percent among 4,791 people surveyed, Rockwell Clancy, vice
president of the financial-services practice at Westlake
Village, California-based J.D. Power and Associates, said in an
interview. </p>
<p>There are more people in play, and they''re being more
diligent, Clancy said. They''re looking at more alternatives
when they shop, which means the competitive pressure on the
banks is going up. </p>
<p>Banks that gained the most customers marketed well, with
ads for specific products, such as gift cards and banking phone
applications, Clancy said. Less than half, or 43 percent, of
customers who bought additional products from banks made the
purchase from their primary lender, he said. Most were lured by
competitors'' promotional offers, Clancy said. </p>
<p>It has less to do with the absolute product than it has
to do with the perceived innovation, Clancy said. </p>
<p>Fees and interest rates carried relatively little
weight in consumers'' decisions, according to the study
conducted in November and December. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christine Harper" date="Mar 01, 2011  6:57 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-01/goldman-sachs-s-litton-mortgage-unit-resumes-some-foreclosures.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs''s Litton Mortgage Unit Resumes Some Foreclosures</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Goldman Sachs Group Inc.''s mortgage-
servicing unit, which suspended some evictions and foreclosures
in October, has recently resumed some of those activities,
according to a regulatory filing today. </p>
<p>Litton Loan Servicing LP said on Oct. 8 that it was
suspending some foreclosures to review its procedures. Attorneys
general from 50 states have been investigating the mortgage
industry''s foreclosure practices after discovering some firms
used faulty or falsified paperwork to seize homes. </p>
<p>At the date of this filing, the firm is not aware of
foreclosures where the underlying foreclosure decision was not
warranted, the New York-based company said in its annual 10-K
filing with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. As of
December 2010, the value of the firm''s mortgage servicing rights
was not material and any impact on their value would not be
material to the firm. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs said it is cooperating with requests from
regulators and state attorneys general and continues to review
Litton''s practices. The inquiries may result in the imposition
of fines or other regulatory action, the firm said. </p>
<p>Chief Financial Officer David A. Viniar said on Oct. 19
that the company was unlikely to have large losses from
mortgage-related issues because Goldman Sachs played a small
role in creating and packaging such loans. He said at the time
that an extensive review of Litton''s practices identified
certain process issues in the foreclosures. The firm still
believed the decision to foreclose was justified, he said. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs, the fifth-biggest U.S. bank by assets,
acquired Houston-based Litton in December 2007 as investors
including billionaire Wilbur Ross and Centerbridge Capital
Partners LLC bought mortgage servicers to help them better
understand the market and profit from buying discounted loans. </p>
<p>Viniar, 55, told analysts in December 2007 that the
purchase was not just to help us take advantage of the
distressed environment that we think we''re in, adding that
we think being able to purchase them is going to help us as
the whole mortgage market kind of unfolds going forward. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Diana ben-Aaron" date="Mar 01, 2011  4:42 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-01/jp-morgan-fund-manager-calls-nokia-good-bet-kauppalehti-says.html"><headline>JP Morgan Fund Manager Calls Nokia Good Bet, Kauppalehti Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Nokia Oyj shares are likely to gain
in the next three years, Patrick Vermeulen, a fund manager at JP
Morgan Asset Management, said according to the Finnish business
daily Kauppalehti. </p>
<p>Nokia is currently an indisputably cheap share, but the
company''s turn for the better will take time, Vermeulen said
according to the newspaper. Nokia Chief Executive Officer
Stephen Elop is taking the company in the right direction in
adopting smartphone software from Microsoft Corp., the newspaper
cited him as saying. </p>
<p>Click here for web link in Finnish </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Brian Womack and Jeffrey McCracken" date="Mar 01, 2011 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-01/jpmorgan-said-to-back-twitter-in-deal-that-values-startup-at-4-5-billion.html"><headline>JPMorgan Twitter Deal Is Said to Value Startup at $4.5 Billion</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> JPMorgan Chase  Co. has invested in
a fund that has bought about $400 million in Twitter Inc.
shares, valuing the blogging service at as much as $4.5 billion,
three people with knowledge of the matter said. </p>
<p>The fund, which has more than $1 billion, is being run by
Twitter investor Chris Sacca, said two of the people, who
declined to be identified because the arrangement isn''t public.
JPMorgan is committing the bulk of the financing for the fund,
the people said. </p>
<p>Twitter, founded in 2006, has seen its valuation climb in
tandem with the popularity of its site, which lets users post
140-character messages. The company was valued at $3.7 billion
in December after receiving $200 million in a funding round led
by venture-capital firm Kleiner Perkins Caufield  Byers.
Twitter was worth $1 billion in September 2009, a person
familiar with the matter said at the time. </p>
<p>JPMorgan''s investment management division said in a
regulatory filing last month that it''s raising as much as $1.22
billion in a venture-capital fund. </p>
<p>In February, venture firm Andreessen Horowitz said it was
investing more than $80 million in Twitter, whose online-
messaging service has more than 175 million registered users. </p>
<p>Sacca declined to comment, as did Darin Oduyoye, a
spokesman for JPMorgan, and Sean Garrett, a spokesman for San
Francisco-based Twitter. </p>
<p>The investment in closely held Twitter was reported earlier
by the Financial Times and technology blog TechCrunch. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Mar 02, 2011 11:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-02/morgan-stanley-names-martinez-negrete-head-of-mexico-business.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Names Martinez-Negrete Head of Mexico Business</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Morgan Stanley, the world''s top
merger adviser last year, named Jaime Martinez-Negrete to a
newly created position as president of operations in Mexico. </p>
<p>Martinez-Negrete joined the New York-based bank in 2008 as
co-head of investment banking in Mexico, according to an
internal memo obtained today by Bloomberg News. Mary Claire Delaney, a Morgan Stanley spokeswoman, confirmed the memo''s
contents. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley last year started an equity sales and
trading team in Mexico led by Miguel Machado. Mexican deals the
firm has handled include advising Mexichem SAB on its $300
million purchase of Rockwood Holdings Inc.''s AlphaGary
thermoplastic compounds business and the sale of Gruma SAB''s
stake in Grupo Financiero Banorte SAB. </p>
<p>Building our presence in Mexico is an important part of
our strategy for Latin America, Christopher Harland, the
firm''s regional head of Latin America, said in the memo. Last
year we launched a local equity cash-trading business and also
grew our fixed-income derivatives business. </p>
<p>Martinez-Negrete spent 10 years in Credit Suisse Group AG''s investment-banking business in Mexico before joining Morgan
Stanley, according to the memo. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Linda Sandler" date="Mar 03, 2011  7:40 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-03/jpmorgan-chase-made-907-million-from-madoff-held-deposits-study-finds.html"><headline>JPMorgan Made $907 Million From Cash Held in Madoff Accounts, Study Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the second-
biggest U.S. bank, made $907 million in pretax profit from
deposits held at the bank by imprisoned Ponzi scheme operator
Bernard L. Madoff, a study said. </p>
<p>The Madoff firm''s balances in its JPMorgan account
generated the profit from 1986 to 2008, according to Linus Wilson, an assistant finance professor at the University of
Louisiana at Lafayette. Entitled Madoff''s Dirty Money, the
study posted on the Social Science Research Network on Feb. 27
uses previously unanalyzed data from the Securities Investor
Protection Corp., which handles the Madoff firm''s bankruptcy,
Wilson said. </p>
<p>The profit calculation was arrived at by assuming that the
Madoff deposits were reinvested in JPMorgan''s stock through Feb.
18, 2011, the study says. </p>
<p> Joseph Evangelisti, a spokesman for New York-based
JPMorgan, declined to comment. </p>
<p>JPMorgan was sued by the trustee liquidating Madoff''s firm
for $6.4 billion for allegedly aiding the con man''s fraud.
JPMorgan denied wrongdoing, saying the earnings from Madoff were
wholly immaterial. </p>
<p>JPMorgan''s fees totaled $597,000 in the six years before
Madoff''s 2008 bankruptcy, Picard calculated. JPMorgan earned
less than $3.5 million in interest by loaning $145 million to
Madoff''s firm in 2005 and 2006, the bank said. </p>
<p>According to court filings, Madoff''s accounts with JPMorgan
included Treasury securities as well as cash. </p>
<p>The JPMorgan case is Picard v. JPMorgan Chase  Co., 10-ap-
4932, U.S. Bankruptcy Court, Southern District of New York
(Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jason Kelly" date="Mar 03, 2011  5:01 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-03/general-atlantic-agrees-to-buy-facebook-stake-cnbc-says-1-.html"><headline>General Atlantic Agrees to Buy Facebook Stake, CNBC Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>General Atlantic LLC agreed to buy a
stake in Facebook Inc., valuing the social-networking company at
about $65 billion dollars, CNBC''s David Faber reported, citing
unidentified people familiar with the matter. </p>
<p>The purchase of 2.5 million shares from former Facebook
employees must be approved by Facebook and amounts to one-tenth
of 1 percent of the company, Faber said. Jonathan Thaw, a
Facebook spokesman, declined to comment, as did Adam Weiner, a
spokesman for General Atlantic. </p>
<p>Facebook, owner of the world''s most popular social-
networking site, said in January it raised $1.5 billion in a
financing round led by Goldman Sachs Group Inc. That transaction
valued the company at $50 billion, the Palo Alto, California-
based company said at the time. </p>
<p>Facebook said that offering was oversubscribed and it chose
to raise less than the $2 billion it could have. The Goldman-led
funding was limited to non-U.S. investors amid concern that
selling to those in the U.S. would violate rules limiting the
marketing of private securities. </p>
<p>General Atlantic, founded in 1980, has $17 billion in
capital under management. The firm''s Internet and media
investments include luxury goods seller Gilt Groupe Inc. and
software company Kaspersky Lab. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Linda Sandler" date="Mar 03, 2011  2:46 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-03/jpmorgan-banks-say-madoff-trustee-would-break-secrets-pact-1-.html"><headline>JPMorgan, Citigroup Say Madoff Trustee Breaks Agreement on Trade Secrets</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), sued for $6.4
billion by the trustee for Bernard L. Madoff''s firm, said the
trustee has no right to abrogate a yearlong agreement to
protect trade secrets by revising his rules for handling
confidential information. </p>
<p>The trustee, Irving H. Picard, seeking $100 billion for
investors in Madoff''s Ponzi scheme in lawsuits, has asked a
judge for more freedom to use information demanded for his
investigations. JPMorgan''s objection is one of at least eight
filed yesterday by banks and investment managers including UBS
AG (UBSN), Citigroup Inc. (C) and HSBC Holdings Plc. (HSBA) </p>
<p>JPMorgan, based in New York, said it gave Picard documents
22 times in the past 15 months, relying on his agreement not to
share the information with competitors or other parties. </p>
<p>The proposed order would permit the trustee to disclose
JPMorgan''s confidential and proprietary information to any party
or its agent in any one of the more than one thousand adversary
proceedings that have been commenced by the trustee, the
second-biggest U.S. bank said in a filing in U.S. Bankruptcy
Court in New York. The trustee is not entitled to abrogate
confidentiality arrangements that have been relied upon by
JPMorgan and other parties. </p>
<p>If Picard has his way, the bank''s anti-money-laundering
policies, risk-assessment methods and internal reviews might be
shared with every major financial institution in New York and
thousands of other parties, it said. </p>
<p>Fatally Flawed'' </p>
<p>Citigroup called Picard''s proposal fatally flawed.
Thousands of pages of documents it delivered to Picard since
receiving his July 2009 subpoena might be passed around,
including pages identifying potential and actual
transactions contemplated by Citigroup, the New York-based
bank said in a court filing. </p>
<p>The documents were delivered under a confidentiality
agreement with Picard that he is seeking to undo, it said. </p>
<p>Amanda Remus, a spokeswoman for Picard, declined to
comment. </p>
<p>Picard''s Feb. 1 proposal would allow him to share a bank''s trade secrets with more than 4,000 parties, UBS calculated in
court papers. Names and account numbers of Madoff customers,
amounts of withdrawals, redemptions, transfers and transferees
would lose their protection, UBS said in its filing. </p>
<p>Ignoring Red Flags </p>
<p>The trustee is demanding more than $18 billion from banks,
accusing them of aiding Madoff''s fraud by ignoring red flags
that should have prompted them to investigate. </p>
<p>The banks have denied wrongdoing. Fees earned from dealing
with Madoff or feeder funds were minor for a big bank, giving no
motive to be willfully blind, JPMorgan said in its rebuttal of
the trustee''s allegations. </p>
<p>The bank is seeking a jury trial in a different court. </p>
<p>Picard''s lawsuits against banks are in a gray area of
the law, bankruptcy lawyer Harvey Miller told Bloomberg
Television in December. </p>
<p>It''s not clear a financial institution has fiduciary
duties to investigate fraud and go out and report it, he said. </p>
<p>A court hearing on Picard''s so-called litigation protective
order is set for March 16. </p>
<p>The JPMorgan case is Picard v. JPMorgan Chase  Co.,
10-ap-4932, U.S. Bankruptcy Court, Southern District of New York
 Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Aaron Kirchfeld and Jacqueline Simmons" date="Mar 03, 2011  1:07 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-03/morgan-stanley-said-to-shut-swiss-nordic-investment-management.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Said to Shut Swiss, Nordic Investment Management</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Morgan Stanley (MS), the sixth-largest
U.S. bank by assets, plans to shut its Swiss and Nordic
investment-management units as part of a plan to boost earnings
from the division, two people with knowledge of the matter said. </p>
<p>The closure of the Zurich and Stockholm offices will affect
six employees, said one of the people, who declined to be
identified because the plans are confidential. Teams in the U.K.
and Italy will cover existing clients in the affected regions,
the people said. </p>
<p>Greg Fleming, who became head of Morgan Stanley Investment
Management last year, said in November that the unit''s sales
efforts have been ineffective. Since then, he installed
Navtej Nandra as head of the division''s international operations
and Paul Price as head of international sales. </p>
<p>We continually evaluate our global distribution strategy
across regions and products to ensure that we are delivering
best-in-class service to clients in our key markets, Morgan
Stanley spokesman Hugh Fraser said in an e-mail today. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s core asset management revenue fell 2
percent in 2010, while a rebound in merchant banking, including
$431 million in gains from real estate funds, helped the unit to
return to profit after two years of losses. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Mulholland" date="Mar 03, 2011 12:28 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-03/general-growth-taps-ubs-morgan-stanley-to-refinance-u-s-mall-properties.html"><headline>General Growth Taps UBS, Morgan Stanley as Lenders Vie to Refinance Malls</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> General Growth Properties Inc. (GGP), the
U.S. mall owner planning to refinance $5 billion of mortgage
debt, tapped UBS AG and Morgan Stanley (MS) to fund loans as banks
rebuild inventory to back bonds tied to commercial real estate. </p>
<p>UBS agreed to provide a $375 million loan on the 977,000-
square-foot Providence Place Mall in Rhode Island, according to
a person with direct knowledge of the deal who declined to be
identified because the talks are private. Morgan Stanley will
lend about $150 million for a Humble, Texas property, according
to a person familiar with those negotiations. The banks plan to
package the loans for sale as securities, the people said. </p>
<p>General Growth, which emerged from the largest real estate
bankruptcy in U.S. history in November after piling up $27
billion in debt, plans to refinance $5 billion in mortgages in
2011, Chief Executive Officer Sandeep Mathrani said during a
March 1 conference call with analysts. Property owners
nationwide are benefiting as the Federal Reserve keeps its
benchmark interest rates near-zero to stimulate economic growth. </p>
<p>We''ve embarked upon a significant mortgage refinancing
plan, Mathrani said during the call. An environment of low
interest rates allows us to achieve more favorable terms than we
had imagined before. </p>




Photographer: Jin Lee/Bloomberg

<p>
Sandeep Mathrani, seen here as executive vice president of retail real estate for Vornado Realty Trust, participates in a panel discussion in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lars Paulsson and Chanyaporn Chanjaroen" date="Mar 03, 2011 11:08 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-03/morgan-stanley-s-brennan-replaces-trapp-as-head-of-oil-trading.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Names Michael Brennan Head of Oil Trading, Succeeding Trapp</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Morgan Stanley (MS) appointed Michael Brennan as global head of its oil liquids group, replacing Goran Trapp, who gave up the position he held since 2008. </p>
<p>After more than 20 years in the oil liquids group and
having headed both that business and Commodities in Europe,
Goran Trapp has asked to be able to step back from day-to-day
managerial responsibilities, the New York-based bank said,
according to a company memo dated Feb. 10 and obtained by
Bloomberg News. Trapp, 49, is staying on as chairman of the oil-
trading group. Both are based in London. </p>
<p>We have asked Michael Brennan to assume the role of
global head of oil liquids, and he will assume full managerial
and operating responsibility for this group, the memo to
employees said. Morgan Stanley spokesman Hugh Fraser in London
confirmed the memo''s contents. </p>
<p>Brennan, who worked as Trapp''s deputy, has been registered
as a Morgan Stanley employee since 2001, according to the U.K.''s
Financial Services Authority website. Morgan Stanley, which
trades crude and oil products from the U.S. Gulf coast to Asia,
was ranked second in Europe, behind Barclays Plc, for providing
over-the-counter derivatives for energy commodities, according
to a survey released yesterday by Greenwich Associates. </p>
<p>Cultural Alignment </p>
<p>This appointment makes excellent business sense due to
the extensive oil market experience of Michael Brennan as well
as his longevity within the Morgan Stanley commodities
business, said Colleen Quilty, a commodities recruiter since
1996 who is now managing director of London-based Quilty Group
Ltd. Conversely, on occasions, when certain firms have made
strategic external appointments, the individual may not have
been totally culturally aligned and best placed to capitalize on
the business model. </p>
<p>Crude oil this year exceeded $100 a barrel for the first
time since 2008 as political uprisings in the Middle East and
the civil conflict in Libya cut supplies of the world''s most
traded commodity. Crude for April delivery traded at $100.85 a
barrel today in electronic trading on the New York Mercantile
Exchange. Oil prices may surge to $220 a barrel if political
unrest in North Africa halts exports from Libya and Algeria,
Nomura Holdings Inc. said Feb. 23. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley considers itself the number one or two
bank in commodities, Chief Executive Officer James Gorman said
at the company''s U.S. Financials Conference on Feb. 1 in New
York. </p>
<p>Bullish Bets </p>
<p> Hedge funds and other large speculators raised bullish bets
on oil to a combined 240,572 options and futures contracts in
the week ended Feb. 22, according to the Commodity Futures
Trading Commission''s weekly Commitments of Traders report. </p>
<p>Companies acting as brokers for oil transactions, known as
swap dealers, had a net-short position of 94,046 futures and
options. That compares with a net-long position among swap
dealers a year ago of 42,086 futures and options. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s Charles Rankin was appointed head of
commodities for Europe, Middle East and Africa, replacing Trapp.
Rankin remains in charge of the company''s European power, gas
and emissions group. </p>
<p>Trapp was appointed head of global oil liquids in July
2008, replacing Olav Refvik, now global head of oil and oil
products at Noble Group Ltd. in London. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Barbara Powell" date="Mar 03, 2011 10:02 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-03/exxon-said-to-start-beaumont-s-catalytic-cracker-after-leak.html"><headline>Exxon Said to Start Beaumont''s Catalytic Cracker After Leak</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM)''s Beaumont, Texas,
refinery has restarted its fluid catalytic cracker after a Feb.
28 shutdown that followed a leak, two people familiar with the
plant''s operations said. </p>
<p>The unit, Beaumont''s only catalytic cracker, was restarted
the evening of March 1 and is moving toward planned rates, said
the people, who declined to be identified because they aren''t
authorized to speak for the refinery. </p>
<p>Kevin Allexon, a Fairfax, Virginia-based Exxon spokesman,
declined to comment, saying that Exxon doesn''t comment on day-
to-day operations. </p>
<p>The refinery is capable of processing 359,100 barrels a
day, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Exxon is the largest U.S. refiner. Its three Gulf Coast
plants account for 17 percent of that region''s operable crude
oil capacity, according to the Energy Department. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lananh Nguyen" date="Mar 03, 2011  7:25 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-03/chevron-sells-europe-gasoline-gasoil-crack-rises-oil-products.html"><headline>Chevron Sells Europe Gasoline; Gasoil Crack Rises: Oil Products</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>European gasoline fell from a 30-
month high as Chevron Corp. and Royal Dutch Shell Plc sold
barges of the motor fuel. Gasoil''s crack, or premium to Brent
crude, widened. </p>
<p>Light Products </p>
<p>Eurobob gasoline for immediate loading in Amsterdam-
Rotterdam-Antwerp traded at $977 to $986 a metric ton, according
to a survey of traders and brokers monitoring the Argus Bulletin
Board. That''s down from $967 to $990 yesterday, when the
benchmark grade hit its highest since Sept. 2, 2008. Ethanol is
added to make finished fuel. The prices are for so-called barge
lots, usually of 1,000 or 2,000 tons. </p>
<p>Chevron, Shell, Mabanaft BV and Trafigura BV sold mainly to
Morgan Stanley. </p>
<p>Gasoline''s crack widened to $7.30 a barrel, compared with
$7.05 in the previous session, according to data from London-
based brokerage PVM Oil Associates Ltd. on Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Naphtha''s discount to Brent shrank to $4.70 a barrel from
$5 the previous session. </p>
<p>April Brent futures fell 77 cents to $115.45 a barrel on
ICE Futures Europe exchange as of 12:01 p.m. London time. </p>
<p>Middle Distillates </p>
<p>Gasoil futures for March delivery on London''s ICE exchange
decreased $5.25, or 0.5 percent, to $959.50 a ton. The more
active April contract fell 0.5 percent to $962.75 a ton.
Gasoil''s crack advanced to $13.80 a barrel versus $12.97 at 4:30
p.m. yesterday, ICE data showed. The fuel is the European
equivalent of heating oil. </p>
<p>Refinery </p>
<p>Reliance Industries Ltd., owner of the world''s largest
refining complex, plans to start a fluid catalytic cracker at
its facility in western India next week, two people with
knowledge of the schedule said. </p>
<p>Mumbai-based Reliance said in a Feb. 3 statement that it
would shut the FCC on Feb. 7 for maintenance after five years of
continuous operations. The unit will begin start up procedures
on March 7, the people said, asking not to be identified as they
aren''t authorized to speak to the media. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kati Pohjanpalo" date="Mar 03, 2011  4:50 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-03/disney-buys-game-developer-rocket-pack-helsingin-sanomat-says.html"><headline>Disney Buys Finnish Game Developer Rocket Pack, Helsingin Sanomat Reports</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Walt Disney Co. (DIS) has acquired Finnish
game developer Rocket Pack, newspaper Helsingin Sanomat
reported, citing Disney spokesman Matthew Grossman.
  Rocket Pack develops games that work within Internet browsers,
the Helsinki-based newspaper said. The companies didn''t disclose
the purchase price, the newspaper said. </p>
<p>Click here for web link in Finnish </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ilya Khrennikov and Denis Maternovsky" date="Mar 03, 2011  1:44 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-03/goldman-sale-of-bank-of-moscow-stake-blocked-vedomosti-says.html"><headline>Goldman Sale of Bank of Moscow Stake Blocked, Vedomosti Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc.''s sale of
shares in Bank of Moscow to VTB Group was blocked by a London
court, Vedomosti reported, citing unidentified people familiar
with the matter. </p>
<p>A company affiliated with Bank of Moscow Chief Executive
Officer Andrei Borodin petitioned the court to stop the deal,
saying it has the right of first refusal to buy the shares, the
Moscow-based newspaper reported today, without identifying the
company. </p>
<p>VTB agreed to pay the city of Moscow 103 billion rubles
($3.6 billion) for its 46.5 percent of Bank of Moscow on Feb.
22, and then agreed to buy Goldman Sachs''s 3.88 percent for 7.14
billion rubles to boost its stake to more than 50 percent,
according to Vedomosti. Kommersant newspaper said March 1 that
Borodin and other Bank of Moscow executives agreed to sell their
combined 20 percent stake to VTB, citing VTB. </p>
<p>Vadim Sukhoverkhov, a spokesman for VTB, declined to
comment, as did Elena Zakrevskaya, a Goldman Sachs spokeswoman,
and Oleg Fedorchenko, a spokesman for Bank of Moscow. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By April Lee" date="Mar 04, 2011  3:35 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-04/jpmorgan-s-lau-hired-by-pinebridge-to-head-fixed-income-in-asia.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Lau Hired by PineBridge to Head Asia Fixed Income</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co.''s Arthur Lau
was hired by PineBridge Investments, the wealth-management firm
sold by American International Group Inc. (AIG) last year, to be head
of fixed income for Asia excluding Japan. </p>
<p>Lau, based in Hong Kong, will head a team of eight,
PineBridge said today in a statement posted on its website. He
was formerly a senior portfolio manager and head of Asian
credits at JPMorgan Asset Management in Hong Kong. </p>
<p>I look forward to working closely with him as PineBridge
continues to grow its market position in Asia, Rajeev Mittal,
head of emerging markets and international fixed income at
PineBridge, said in the statement. </p>
<p>PineBridge, based in New York, had $82 billion in assets
under management as of Dec. 31, according to the statement.
Closely held Pacific Century Group purchased PineBridge from
AIG, where the firm was called AIG Global Investment Corp., for
$500 million in March. </p>
<p>Lau has been a director in credit research at Barclays
Capital in Singapore, PineBridge said. He has a bachelor''s
degree from Chinese University of Hong Kong and a master''s
degree in business administration from the University of Western
Ontario. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Aaron Clark" date="Mar 04, 2011  2:58 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-04/exxon-baytown-plant-stops-feed-to-kerosene-hydrofiner-after-leak.html"><headline>Exxon Baytown Halts Kerosene Hydrofiner Feed After Leak</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM)''s Baytown refinery
in Texas halted feed to a kerosene hydrofiner yesterday after an
exchanger leak, according to a filing with state regulators. </p>
<p>We are operational, Neely Nelson, a spokeswoman for the
refinery, said in an e-mail. No impact on production. </p>
<p>Pressure and temperature were reduced and the unit''s feed
was stopped, according to the filing with the Texas Commission
on Environmental Quality. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Patricia Hurtado" date="Mar 04, 2011  2:25 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-04/goldman-ex-director-rajat-gupta-was-rajaratnam-co-conspirator-u-s-says.html"><headline>Rajat Gupta Was Rajaratnam Co-Conspirator, Prosecutor Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Rajat Gupta, a former member of the
board of Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) and the former head of
McKinsey  Co., was a co-conspirator with Raj Rajaratnam, the
Galleon Group LLC founder at the center of a probe of insider
trading at hedge funds, a U.S. prosecutor said. Gupta passed
information to Rajaratnam about Goldman''s earnings and about an
investment Berkshire Hathaway Inc. (BRK/A) made in Goldman, the
prosecutor said in a pre-trial court conference. Prosecutors
have not charged Gupta criminally. Rajaratnam''s criminal trial
starts March 8. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Mar 04, 2011  2:23 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-04/morgan-stanley-vice-chairman-gary-lynch-is-leaving-firm-bank-memo-says.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Former Chief Legal Officer Lynch to Leave Firm</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Gary Lynch, Morgan Stanley (MS)''s chief
legal officer from 2005 until 2010, is leaving the firm. </p>
<p>Lynch, now a vice chairman, will "pursue opportunities
outside the firm," according to an internal memo obtained today
by Bloomberg News. Pen Pendleton, a spokesman for the New York-
based bank, confirmed the contents of the memo. Lynch had been
advising Morgan Stanley on policy and strategy issues in his
current role, according to the memo. </p>
<p>Lynch, 60, announced in February 2010 that he would give up
his role as chief legal officer. In July, Morgan Stanley hired
Frank Barron, a litigation partner at Cravath, Swaine  Moore
LLP, to replace him in that position. </p>
<p>Lynch headed the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission''s
enforcement division from 1985 to 1989 and led insider-trading
investigations of Ivan Boesky and Michael Milken. Former Morgan
Stanley CEO John Mack hired Lynch to work at Credit Suisse First
Boston in 2001 and then at Morgan Stanley when Mack moved there
in 2005. Mack stepped down as CEO at the beginning of 2010 and
remains chairman. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joel Rosenblatt and David Glovin" date="Mar 04, 2011 11:20 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-04/goldman-s-blankfein-said-to-agree-to-be-u-s-witness-at-rajaratnam-trial.html"><headline>Blankfein Said to Agree to Be Prosecution Witness at Galleon Insider Trial</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) Chief
Executive Officer Lloyd Blankfein agreed to be a prosecution
witness in Galleon Group LLC co-founder Raj Rajaratnam''s insider
trading trial next week, said a person briefed on the matter. </p>
<p>Blankfein, 56, may not testify because prosecutors
typically line up potential witnesses before a trial who aren''t
later called on, said the person, who declined to be identified
because the talks are private. </p>
<p>Rajaratnam is at the center of the largest crackdown on
hedge-fund insider trading in U.S. history. The Sri Lankan-born
billionaire is charged with earning $45 million from
confidential information leaked by corporate insiders and hedge
fund traders. If convicted, the 57-year-old could spend as long
as 20 years in prison on the fraud charges. He denies
wrongdoing, saying he based his trades on Galleon research. </p>
<p>Prosecutors are likely calling Blankfein as a witness to
show that Rajaratnam traded on inside information about Goldman
Sachs, said Andrew Stoltmann, a securities lawyer in Chicago.
Rajaratnam got a tip from then-Goldman Sachs director Rajat Gupta about a $5 billion investment in the firm by Berkshire
Hathaway Inc., and Gupta allegedly passed the news immediately
to Rajaratnam, who bought shares, according to U.S. allegations
in court papers. </p>
<p>Timeline Issue </p>
<p>There''s no question it''s a timeline issue, Stoltmann
said in an interview. Also, they really want to rope Goldman
Sachs into the trial because the firm may be viewed
unfavorably by jurors, he said. </p>
<p>Gupta''s lawyer, Gary Naftalis, has called the allegation
baseless. Rajaratnam''s lawyer, John Dowd, said yesterday he
may call Gupta as a witness to explain why he was talking with
Rajaratnam. </p>
<p>Gupta may invoke his constitutional right not to testify if
he believes it would incriminate him, said Stoltmann, who is not
involved in the case. </p>
<p>The Securities and Exchange Commission has separately filed
administrative charges accusing Gupta of leaking confidential
information to Rajaratnam, including Berkshire''s investment in
Goldman, the securities firm''s quarterly earnings, and the
results of Procter  Gamble Co., where Gupta was also a
director. The action was filed March 1. </p>
<p>Gupta stepped down from Goldman Sachs''s board last year and
resigned from Procter  Gamble this week. Gupta is the former
managing director of McKinsey  Co., the consulting firm, and is
currently the firm''s senior partner emeritus. </p>




Photographer: Rick Maiman/Bloomberg

<p>
Raj Rajaratnam, co-founder of Galleon Group LLC, arrives for a hearing at federal court in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Janet Ong" date="Mar 04, 2011  1:37 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-04/general-plastic-february-sales-fall-4-80-table-6128-tt.html"><headline>GENERAL PLASTIC February Sales Fall 4.80% (Table) : 6128 TT</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>GENERAL PLASTIC said unconsolidated sales
in February fell 4.80% to NT$106,401,000 from NT$111,767,000,
according to a statement filed to the Taiwan Stock Exchange. </p>
<p>(Figures are in thousands of New Taiwan dollars) </p>
<p>================================================================= </p>
<p>2/2011           2/2010
Sales            106,401          111,767    
YOY%              -4.80%  </p>
<p>-----------------Year-to-date-----------------
Sales            230,070          233,639    
YOY%              -1.53% 
=================================================================
 </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lindsay Fortado" date="Mar 06, 2011 10:20 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2011-03-06/coca-cola-to-build-recycling-plant-in-england-sunday-times-says.html"><headline>Coca-Cola to Build U.K. Recycling Plant, Times Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>(Corrects name of company in first paragraph.) </p>
<p> Coca-Cola Enterprises Inc. (CCE) will
build Europe''s largest recycling plant for plastic bottles in
Lincolnshire, England, the Sunday Times reported, citing
private-equity investor Eddie Truell. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola has set up a joint venture worth 200 million
pounds ($325 million) with Eco Plastics, a recycling company
backed by Truell, the newspaper said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry></news>