<?xml version='1.0' encoding='us-ascii'?>
<news><entry author="By Chua Kong Ho" date="Sep 22, 2008  3:03 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-09-22/shenhua-astra-among-10-asia-stocks-tipped-by-goldman-to-double.html"><headline>Shenhua, Astra Among 10 Asia Stocks Tipped by Goldman to Double</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;China Shenhua Energy Co. (1088) and PT
Astra International (ASII) are among 10 Asian stocks likely to double
within three years because of higher profit growth and stronger
balance sheets, Goldman, Sachs  Co. said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shares have fallen by an average 46 percent from their
52-week highs and have ``attractive'' valuations relative to
their 10-year history, Goldman Sachs's Hong Kong analysts
including Paul Bernard wrote in a note to clients today. The
shares were subject to ``indiscriminate selling'' in the global
rout that drove a measure of Asian stocks outside Japan to the
lowest in more than two years last week, the analysts said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``We fully recognize the continued macro headwinds and
concerns over corporate earnings,'' they wrote. ``This report
does not try to minimize the significance of these near-term
pressures but aims to look beyond them to stock ideas that
assume `normalized' valuations and earnings over a two- to
three-year period.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The MSCI Asia Pacific excluding Japan Index has declined 32
percent this year as the global credit crisis dragged on
economic growth and corporate profits worldwide. Shares on the
index are valued at an average of 11.9 times reported profit,
compared to 19.2 times on Oct. 29, when the index closed at a
record, according to Bloomberg data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shares of China Shenhua, the country's biggest coal
producer, may climb because the nation is short of energy, coal
is ``under-priced,'' and the government has more room to raise
power tariffs, according to the Goldman report. Shenhua has
declined 50 percent this year in Hong Kong and trades at 15.8
times earnings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Astra, Indonesia's biggest auto retailer, is similarly
placed as it is a ``proxy for two of Indonesia's mega themes:
strong secular domestic demand growth for cars and motorcycles
and the booming commodity resources sector, mainly palm oil and
coal mining,'' the note said. The Jakarta-based company's stock
has fallen 32 percent this year, to 11.6 times profit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following is Goldman's list of stocks tipped to double
in the next three years: &lt;/p&gt;

PT Astra International (ASII IJ)
Axis Bank Ltd. (AXSB IN)
China Oilfield Services Ltd. (2883 HK)
China Shenhua Energy Co. (1088 HK)
Hong Kong Exchanges  Clearing Ltd. (388 HK)
HTC Corp. (2498 TT)
Mediatek Inc. (2454 TT)
Suntech Power Holdings Co. (STP US)
Tencent Holdings Ltd. (700 HK)
Want Want China Holdings Ltd. (151 HK)

&lt;p&gt;
To contact the reporter responsible for this story:
Chua Kong Ho in Shanghai at 
kchua6@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Darren Boey at 
dboey@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Shani Raja" date="Sep 25, 2008  2:44 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-09-25/australia-stocks-babcock-coca-cola-sino-timbercorp-vulcan.html"><headline>Australia Stocks: Babcock, Coca-Cola, Sino, Timbercorp, Vulcan</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;The SP/ASX 200 Index (AS51) slipped 54.50
points, or 1.1 percent, to 4,927.40 at the close in Sydney. The
broader All Ordinaries Index (AS30) lost 47.40 points, or 1 percent, to
4,960.80, while the futures index expiring in December declined
1.5 percent to 4,978. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Babcock  Brown Ltd. (BNB AU) jumped 67 cents, or 39 percent,
to A$2.37, the benchmark's best performer. Babcock climbed for a
fifth day in Sydney trading after Australia banned short selling
and Goldman Sachs Group Inc. won the backing of billionaire
investor Warren Buffett. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Centennial Coal Co. (CEY AU), Australia's fourth-largest
coal producer, fell for the fifth straight day, slumping 25 cents,
or 5.3 percent, to A$4.43, the lowest since Aug. 13. The company
yesterday said it's issuing 210,000 ordinary shares. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Amatil (CCL) , a soft-drinks maker that gets a
quarter of its sales from overseas, fell 35 cents, or 3.9 percent,
to A$8.65, the most since July 15. JPMorgan Chase  Co.
downgraded the company's rating to ``underweight.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GPT Group (GPT)  gained 4 cents, or 2 percent, to A$2.01,
the highest since Sept. 22. The Australian real estate investment
trust may be on the verge of selling Sydney's Four Points Hotel
to Thai billionaire Charoen Sirivadhanabhakdi, the Australian
newspaper reported, citing sources it did not name. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Paperlinx Ltd. (PPX) , the world's largest paper
distributor, plunged 25 cents, or 11 percent, to A$1.98, the most
in more than a month and the benchmark's second-worst performer.
ABN Amro Holding NV cut the company's rating to ``hold'' from
``buy.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sino Gold Mining Ltd. (SGX AU), an Australian gold mining
company, slumped 20 cents, or 4 percent, to A$4.80, the lowest
since Monday. Merrill Lynch  Co. cut the company's rating to
``neutral'' from ``buy.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tap Oil Ltd. (TAP) , a partner in Apache Corp.'s Harriet
joint venture in Western Australia, rose 4 cents, or 4.4 percent,
to 94 cents, the highest since Sept. 11. The company said repairs
to production systems are proceeding as planned after a fire on
Varanus Island in June, with production to resume in December. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Timbercorp Ltd. (TIM AU), an agribusiness investment manager,
slumped 10 cents, or 13 percent, to 68 cents, the most in more
than eight months. Timbercorp said Chairman Kevin Hayes will step
down on Oct. 1, to be replaced by present Deputy Chairman Rod
Fitzroy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vulcan Resources Ltd. (VCN AU) plunged 2 cents, or 16
percent, to 14 cents, the lowest in four years. The company
deferred development of a $170 million copper-cobalt mine in
Finland until it can secure sales agreements and equity markets
recover. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Shani Raja in Sydney at 
sraja4@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Darren Boey at 
dboey@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Maria Petrakis and Andrew Cleary" date="Oct 02, 2008 11:39 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-10-02/coca-cola-hbc-cuts-forecasts-on-weaker-russian-demand-update4-.html"><headline>Coca-Cola HBC Cuts Forecasts on Weaker Russian Demand</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Hellenic Bottling Co., the
bottler of Coke beverages in 27 European countries, cut forecasts
for the second time this year after cold weather and financial
turmoil hurt demand in Russia, the company's biggest market. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola HBC tumbled 19 percent to a 3 1/2-year low in
Athens trading. Earnings per share will be ``broadly stable''
versus last year, compared with a prior forecast for a gain of up
to 8 percent, the Athens-based company said today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Russia, the company said ``sustained high inflation and
recent volatility in the financial markets are weighing on
consumer confidence,'' while summer weather was ``exceptionally
poor.'' Coca-Cola HBC makes more than half its sales in emerging
markets such as Ukraine and Romania, where surging inflation is
sapping incomes that had outpaced growth in developed economies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``I suspect your average Russian doesn't do a lot of
investing in the stock market, but he's probably aware of how
weak the market's been, and that has an impact on consumer
confidence,'' said Andrew Holland, an analyst at Dresdner
Kleinwort with a ``hold'' rating on the Greek company's stock. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola HBC fell 2.94 euros to 12.52 euros in Athens, the
lowest closing price since Feb. 14, 2005. The percentage drop
was the steepest since June 13 and the biggest in the Dow Jones
Stoxx 600 Index today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Russian Shipments &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Russian drink shipments fell 4.5 percent in the third
quarter, Coca-Cola HBC said. Volume growth across the group was
4.5 percent, below its 7 percent forecast. Sales by volume will
climb about 4 percent for the year, less than the company's
previous prediction of 6 percent, the bottler said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About 17 percent of Coca-Cola HBC's sales volumes are
derived from Russia, where the company said it is seeing ``early
signs of economic deterioration through inflation and the
financial turmoil, especially in the latter part of September.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sentiment among Russian consumers has been hurt by surging
inflation, which rose 10.5 percent in the year through Sept. 29.
The falling oil price, which has declined 35 percent from a
record $147.27 in July, has also deterred consumer spending in
Russia, the world's second-biggest crude exporter, Holland said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``When the oil price was going inexorably upwards that
clearly had a beneficial impact on consumer confidence and
consumption,'' the Dresdner analyst said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The slowdown in sales isn't confined to Russia, Coca-Cola
HBC Managing Director Doros Constantinou said by e-mail. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Brewers Decline &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``Ireland is also looking weaker, and Hungary and the
Baltics are being affected by the spread of economic weakness,''
he said. An ``uncertain'' economic outlook for Europe was in part
offset by growth in markets such as Bulgaria, Poland and Nigeria. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``We plan to downgrade our estimates,'' John Stamatakos, an
analyst at Protonbank with a ``neutral'' rating on the stock,
wrote in an e-mailed note. ``We remain cautious given that the
current conditions limit short-term visibility.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European brewing stocks also declined on the Greek company's
prediction for a slump in Russian sales. Carlsberg A/S, (CARLB) the
industry leader in Russia, dropped 12 percent in Copenhagen, the
steepest drop since February 2003. Heineken NV (HEIA) slid 3.1 percent
in Amsterdam and SABMiller Plc fell 5.3 percent in London. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola HBC declined a record 21 percent on June 13 after
the bottler reduced its profit forecast on concern that emerging-markets consumers were spending less. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporters on this story:
Maria Petrakis in Athens at 
mpetrakis@bloomberg.net;
Andrew Cleary in London at 
acleary7@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editors responsible for this story:
Lars Klemming at 
lklemming@bloomberg.net;
Keith Campbell at 
k.campbell@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry></news>