
<news><entry author="By Mary Jane Credeur" date="Apr 18, 2007  4:24 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-04-18/coca-cola-s-isdell-keeping-promise-of-steady-growth-update2-.html"><headline>Coca-Cola''s Isdell `Keeping Promise'' of Steady Growth</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Coca-Cola Co. (KO) Chief Executive
Officer Neville Isdell said the world''s largest soft-drink maker
is ''''keeping our promise'''' to return the company to steady
growth by focusing on emerging markets such as China. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola''s profit has resumed growing after a two-year
slowdown, Isdell said today on a Webcast of the company''s annual
meeting in Wilmington, Delaware. The company reported yesterday
that first-quarter profit rose 14 percent on the biggest sales
gain in more than a decade. </p>
<p>''''Last year, I told you the company completed the
transition, and that stabilization would be achieved in 2006,''''
Isdell said. ''''I said as a result of that, the company would
return to sustainable growth, and my message to you today is
that we are keeping our promise.'''' </p>
<p>Coca-Cola is headed for its biggest increase in annual
profit since 2003, buoyed by demand for its drinks in fast-
growing markets such as China and Brazil. Worldwide volume
increased 6 percent in the first quarter, compared with a 3.3
percent average annual gain since Isdell became CEO in 2004. </p>
<p>Eleven analysts surveyed by Bloomberg estimate the Atlanta-
based company''s annual profit will jump 18 percent this year,
compared with a 4 percent gain last year and less than 1 percent
the prior year. </p>
<p>Shares of Coca-Cola rose 9 cents to $51.66 at 4 p.m. in New
York Stock Exchange composite trading, after closing yesterday
at their highest since June 2004. The shares have gained 25
percent in the past year, compared with 13 percent for PepsiCo
Inc. </p>
<p>U.S. `Problems'' </p>
<p>Coca-Cola is still ''''working through some problems'''' in
North America, its largest unit, where volume dropped 3 percent
in the first quarter after higher prices hurt soda sales. </p>
<p>The company is trying to bolster sales with more
advertising and healthy drinks such as juices and teas made by
Fuze Beverage LLC, which Coca-Cola bought in March. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola''s soft drink volume in the U.S. dropped 1.2
percent last year, according to data by industry journal
Beverage Digest. </p>
<p>The company wants to ''''reinvigorate'''' soda sales, Isdell
said. Coca-Cola has promoted and expanded Coca-Cola Zero, a
calorie-free drink formulated to taste like regular Coke. The
company has added a cherry-flavored version, and the drink will
be available in 40 countries by the end of this year. </p>
<p>''''Along the way, we will make corrections wherever we make
inevitable mistakes as we hit the bumps that occur on the
road,'''' Isdell said. </p>
<p>Also at the meeting, shareholders voted against proposals
seeking limits on executive pay and restricted stock grants. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Igor Muller" date="Apr 27, 2007 12:29 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-04-27/morgan-stanley-ups-forecast-for-emerging-markets-update1-.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Ups Forecast for Emerging Markets</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS), the world''s second-largest securities company, raised its forecast for emerging-market stocks this year on expectations for worldwide economic
growth and rising commodity prices. </p>
<p>Jonathan Garner, head of global emerging-market strategy in
London, raised his year-end projection for the Morgan Stanley
Capital International Emerging Markets Index by 8.2 percent to
1,060. That represents a gain of 7.8 percent from yesterday''s
close. </p>
<p>The benchmark has risen 6.8 percent so far this year after
recovering from a slump that began in late February when equity
markets dropped worldwide on concerns about slowdown of the U.S.
economy. </p>
<p>''''The global growth story is about strengthening economies
in Japan, European Union, especially Germany and emerging
markets,'''' Garner said in a telephone interview. ''''It''s
inappropriate to have such a U.S. centric view.'''' </p>
<p>A report showed today that last quarter''s growth rate in the
U.S. was the weakest since the first three months of 2003,
trimmed by the slump in home construction and a bigger trade
deficit. Growth in the 12 months ended in March slowed to 2.1
percent, the weakest year-over-year gain since the second quarter
of 2003, while inflation rose. </p>
<p>Garner said the slowdown is mostly led by non-traded housing
market in the world''s largest economy and doesn''t have a major
impact on global and emerging market stocks. </p>
<h2>Counterbalance </h2>
<p>Morgan Stanley expects the global economy to grow 4.5
percent this year, as it expects the slowdown of the U.S. economy
to be counterbalanced by reviving expansion in countries that
share euro currency, Garner said in the note. </p>
<p>At the same time Morgan Stanley sees commodity prices and
prices for oil to rise above prices in 2006. Garner has
recommended buying South African basic resource stocks in his
report from March 20. </p>
<p>Metals such as copper has gained 23 percent this year as
demand surged in China, the world''s largest copper consumer.
Crude oil has advanced 6.6 percent so far this year. </p>
<p>Garner added Dongfang Electrical Machinery Co. (600875), China''s
third-biggest maker of power-generation equipment, to its list of
recommended shares and removed OAO Gazprom (GAZP), Russia''s natural gas
export monopoly, citing concern about dividend yields and
earnings outlook in Russia. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry></news>