
<news><entry author="By Balazs Penz" date="Oct 08, 2008  9:58 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-10-08/east-europe-forecasts-cut-by-morgan-stanley-jpmorgan-update2-.html"><headline>East Europe Forecasts Cut by Morgan Stanley, JPMorgan</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Morgan Stanley and JPMorgan Chase  Co.
reduced their growth forecasts for central European economies for
next year, citing a weaker outlook for exports and investment and
severe strains on the credit market. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2009 growth outlook for the Czech Republic was cut to 2.9
percent from 4.2 percent, Morgan Stanley''s London-based Pasquale Diana said in an e-mailed note. Hungary''s rate was lowered to 1
percent from 2.7 percent, while Poland''s growth was cut to 3.5
percent from 4.6 percent and Romania''s rate fell to 3.8 percent
from 6.5 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The four eastern European Union members rely on western
European markets for their exports. Europe is on the brink of
recession as its economy contracted in the second quarter because
of declining company investment and consumer spending. Central
Europe may also face a shortage of credit, Diana said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''This is bound to affect the exports and investment outlook
across central Europe,'''' he wrote in his note today. ''''The ongoing
credit crunch is highly likely to hit the region, though with a
delay. The real risk is that the western European banks that have
financed the recent credit boom are forced to curtail lending.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;JPMorgan Cuts &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nora Szentivanyi and Miroslav Plojhar, London-based
economists at JPMorgan, cut the 2009 forecast for Czech (CZARANN) growth to
1.5 percent from 2.5 percent, for Hungary to 1 percent from 2
percent, for Poland to 3.5 percent from 4 percent, for Romania to
2.5 percent from 3.5 percent and for Slovakia to 1.5 percent from
2 percent, they said in a note to clients. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''Intensifying stress in the global financial system and
western Europe in recession have prompted a further cut in our
growth forecasts for thus far resilient central European
economies,'''' they wrote. ''''These small and open economies will be
hit by a drop in external demand, a drop in capital and financial
inflows.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slowing growth will probably help curb consumer prices and
prompt central banks to cut interest rates faster across the
region, except in Romania, where the local currency''s losses will
put pressure on inflation, according to the report. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Morgan Stanley''s cut its forecast for the Czech benchmark
rate to 2.25 percent by the end of next year from 3.25 percent,
for Hungary''s to 7 percent from 7.5 percent, Poland''s to 5.5
percent from 6.5 percent, while the Romania projection remained at
8.5 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Average Inflation &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Average inflation in the Czech Republic for next year is now
seen at 3.1 percent, compared with an earlier 3.3 percent
forecast. The Hungarian estimate was cut to 3.8 percent from 4
percent and Poland''s to 3 percent from 3.5 percent. Romania''s 2009
inflation forecast was increased to 5.3 percent from 4.8 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JPMorgan''s Szentivanyi and Plojhar cut their forecast for
2009 average inflation to 1.7 percent from 2.2 percent in the
Czech Republic, to 4 percent from 4.2 percent in Hungary, to 3.2
percent from 3.6 percent in Poland and to 3.2 percent from 3.4
percent in Slovakia. They raised the Romanian estimate to 7
percent from 6 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As inflation slows, the Czech and Polish central banks will
have more room to reduce interest rates, while a weakening
currency will keep Hungarian monetary policy makers cautious and
Romanian rates may rise further before declining, Szentivanyi and
Plojhar said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They cut the end-2009 interest rate forecast to 2 percent
from 2.5 percent in the Czech Republic, to 7.5 percent from 7.75
percent in Hungary, to 4.75 percent from 5.25 percent in Poland
and to 10 percent and 10.5 percent in Romania. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Howard Mustoe" date="Oct 17, 2008  6:40 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-10-17/dsg-slides-as-jp-morgan-cuts-target-says-covenants-a-concern.html"><headline>DSG Slides as JP Morgan Cuts Target, Says Covenants a Concern</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;DSG International Plc, the U.K.''s
largest electronics retailer, dropped to the lowest in more than
20 years in London trading after JP Morgan cut its price estimate
and said it''s concerned that loan covenants may be breached. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DSG fell as much as 5 pence, or 19 percent, to 21.25 pence
and traded at 22.5 pence as of 11:36 a.m. local time. A close at
that level would be the lowest since at least September 1988. The
stock has slumped 78 percent this year, cutting the company''s
market value to 394 million pounds ($681 million). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JP Morgan cut its price target to 25 pence from 50 pence and
lowered its earnings estimates for the next two years, analysts
led by Simon Irwin said today in a note. The brokerage predicts
no dividend for two years and rates the stock ''''underweight'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''There is a possibility that DSG could breach loan
covenants,'''' the analysts wrote, adding that the company''s
liquidity is ''''adequate.'''' The retailer may have to sell
profitable assets such as the Elkjop or Kotsovolos chains, close
money-losing units, or raise new equity, they said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DSG is ''''comfortable with our current position,'''' spokesman
Mark Webb said by e-mail. ''''We have the necessary resources to
continue to deliver our renewal and transformation plan.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JP Morgan reduced its estimate of DSG''s earnings per share
for the 2009 fiscal year to 2.77 pence from 4.83 pence and for
the following year to 2.09 pence from 5.03 pence. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capital Research and Management Company, DSG''s biggest
shareholder, cut its stake to 11.4 percent from 12.8 percent,
the retailer said today in a Regulatory News Service statement.
The investor has reduced its stake from 14 percent this month. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Alexis Xydias" date="Oct 28, 2008  7:29 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-10-28/volkswagen-overtakes-exxon-as-most-valuable-company-update2-.html"><headline>Volkswagen Overtakes Exxon as Most Valuable Company</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Volkswagen AG (VOW) became the world''s
biggest company by market value after Porsche SE announced plans
to raise its stake in the German carmaker to 75 percent, forcing
short-sellers to cover their bets on a decline in the stock. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BaFin, Germany''s financial-markets regulator, is monitoring
trading after Volkswagen rose more than fourfold in two days,
said spokeswoman Anja Engelland. At its high today, Wolfsburg,
Germany-based Volkswagen''s common shares were valued at 296
billion euros ($370 billion), more than Exxon Mobil Corp.''s $343
billion at yesterday''s closing price in New York Stock Exchange
composite trading, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gains follow Porsche''s Oct. 26 announcement that the
maker of the 911 sports car plans to increase its Volkswagen
holding from 42.6 percent, spurring short-sellers to buy from a
shrinking pool of stock to close their positions in a so-called
squeeze. Volkswagen, the world''s 16th-largest company by sales,
is the most shorted stock in Germany''s benchmark DAX Index. (DAX) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''The regulator needs to investigate,'''' said Piers Hillier,
head of European equities at WestLB Mellon Asset Management U.K.
Ltd. in London. ''''The bigger question has to be why they have
not done so already. If ever there was an example of market
manipulation, this is it. Porsche''s stake-building process is at
best obscure.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael Brendel, a Volkswagen spokesman, said the company
doesn''t comment on its stock price. Frank Gaube and Frank Scholtys, spokesmen for Stuttgart, Germany-based Porsche, didn''t
immediately respond to two messages left at their office or to a
message left on Gaube''s mobile-phone voicemail seeking comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Stock On Loan &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About 12.9 percent of Volkswagen''s common stock was on loan
as of Oct. 23, mostly for short sales, the highest proportion of
any company on the DAX, according to London-based Data
Explorers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''One of the biggest risks with the herd mentality approach
to shorting is that a lot of money can be made on the outset,''''
said Ed Oliver, a senior business consultant at Spitalfields
Advisors, a London-based firm specializing in securities
lending. ''''But you can end up losing the whole of it when you
try to close the position. There''s no limit.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stuttgart, Germany-based Porsche added to an earlier 35
percent stake and said two days ago that it holds options for
another 31.5 percent. Volkswagen rose as much as 485.01 euros
today, or 93 percent, to 1,005.01 euros. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;`Short Squeeze'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''Porsche heads for a domination agreement and triggers a
short-squeeze,'''' Horst Schneider, an HSBC Holdings Plc analyst
in Dusseldorf, Germany, wrote in a report yesterday, in which he
upgraded Volkswagen''s common shares to ''''neutral'''' from
''''underweight.'''' The stock ''''will be more driven by covering of
short positions rather than by fundamental valuations.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carmakers worldwide are struggling with plunging sales as
credit markets seize up and economies contract, deterring
consumers from making large purchases. U.S. industry-wide auto
sales fell 27 percent in September, the steepest monthly slide
since 1991, while nine-month deliveries in Europe declined 4.4
percent as September sales dropped 8.2 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Carmakers'' Debt Downgraded &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PSA Peugeot Citroen (UG), Europe''s second-largest carmaker, and
smaller French competitor Renault SA (RNO) both had their credit
ratings downgraded by Moody''s Investors Service because of the
risk that car markets won''t recover next year. Standard  Poor''s
said it may cut the credit rating of Fiat SpA (F), Italy''s biggest
carmaker, to less than investment grade. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until yesterday, when the stock more than doubled,
Volkswagen''s largest gain in almost two decades was a 27 percent
jump on Sept. 18. People familiar with securities lending said
at the time that the collapse of Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc.
caused the increase by triggering recalls of borrowings. The
stock fell 23 percent on Oct. 20, the steepest drop also in
almost two decades, as short-sellers predicted the price would
decline once Porsche gains control. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There may be little ordinary stock freely trading in
Volkswagen because most of the shares are owned by Porsche, the
German state of Lower Saxony and the banks that underwrote
Porsche''s options, Adam Jonas, a London-based analyst at Morgan
Stanley, wrote in a research report yesterday. Lower Saxony is
Volkswagen''s second-largest owner with a 20.1 percent stake. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Index-tracking funds also hold stakes in Volkswagen, now
the DAX''s most heavily weighted stock, and must retain the
holdings as long as the carmaker remains a member. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;DAX Membership Criteria &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deutsche Boerse AG (DB1), the operator of Germany''s main stock
markets, said Volkswagen will remain in the DAX unless the
carmaker announces the freely traded stock no longer meets
requirements. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''We''re applying our regulatory framework and, as long as
Volkswagen''s free float is above 5 percent, the index won''t be
changed,'''' said Torsten Baar, a spokesman for Frankfurt-based
Deutsche Boerse. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BaFin is analyzing trading in Volkswagen stock, though it
hasn''t opened a formal inquiry into whether there''s any
manipulation and ''''pure cash-settled options do not require
disclosure'''' under the country''s laws, said Engelland, a
spokeswoman for the Bonn-based agency. Results from any analysis
are unlikely this week, she added. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Porsche''s Intent &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until Oct. 26, Porsche had said it was aiming only for a
stake exceeding 50 percent, and Chief Executive Officer Wendelin Wiedeking said at the Paris Motor Show early this month that a
stake of as much as 75 percent would be ''''not realistic''''
because of market turmoil. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short sales have largely been undertaken by investors
betting on a decline in Volkswagen''s common stock, which hold
voting rights, or its underperformance relative to the preferred
shares, which carry no votes, according to analysts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The common shares, which outnumber the preferred equity
almost three to one, are the only stocks to gain this year on
the DAX and the nine-member Bloomberg Europe Autos Index. In
contrast, Volkswagen''s preferred stock has dropped 62 percent,
including a 14 percent decline yesterday, to 37.89 euros. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''Volkswagen has been one of the greatest shorts of hedge
funds, and it''s been an absolute, absolute disaster,'''' Emmanuel Roman, co-chief executive officer of GLG Partners Inc., said at
a conference in London on Oct. 23. ''''It''s been very painful.''''
GLG didn''t participate in short-selling trading of the
carmaker''s common shares, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Martin" date="Oct 29, 2008  3:13 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-10-29/walter-industries-surges-as-profit-doubles-on-coal-update1-.html"><headline>Walter Industries Surges as Profit Doubles on Coal</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Walter Industries Inc. (WLT), a coal
producer that''s shedding its homebuilding business, jumped after
reporting third-quarter profit doubled on higher coal prices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walter rose $5.23, or 17 percent, to $36.07 as of 2:48 p.m.
in New York Stock Exchange composite trading. The shares have
dropped 3 percent this year after gaining 35 percent in 2007. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company, based in Tampa, Florida, reported yesterday that
third-quarter net income rose to $55 million, or 97 cents a
share, from $24.4 million, or 46 cents, a year earlier. Sales
gained 24 percent to $388 million. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walter forecast record profit this year and next because of
higher priced long-term contracts and rising production. The
shares of competing oil suppliers also surged. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 13-member Bloomberg U.S. Coal Index rose 14 percent.
Pittsburgh-based Consol Energy Inc. (CNX) gained 25 percent to $30.34
and James River Coal Corp. climbed 23 percent to $17.77. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Walter held a conference call with analysts and investors
at 10 a.m. New York time. To listen to a replay, access the
company''s Web site at: http://www.walterind.com/) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Lars Klemming" date="Oct 31, 2008  2:36 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-10-31/wolfson-csr-recommendations-raised-to-buy-at-goldman-sachs.html"><headline>Wolfson, CSR Recommendations Raised to `Buy'' at Goldman Sachs</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Wolfson Microelectronics Plc and CSR
Plc (CSR), two U.K. semiconductor makers, had their stock
recommendations raised to ''''buy'''' at Goldman, Sachs  Co. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wolfson, the Scottish maker of semiconductors used in mobile
phones, had its recommendation raised from ''''neutral'''' by
analysts Simon Schafer and Robert Bartosik. They said it''s now
attractively valued as incremental cost savings and ''''a
significant currency tailwind are likely to ensure positive free
cash flow'''' in 2009. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CSR, which makes microchips used in Nokia Oyj mobile phones,
was raised from ''''sell'''' by Schafer and Bartosik, who said cost
discipline suggests there is ''''valuation upside.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry></news>