<?xml version='1.0' encoding='us-ascii'?>
<news><entry author="By Christine Harper" date="Dec 09, 2008 12:52 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-12-09/goldman-sachs-said-to-lose-two-special-situations-executives.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Said to Lose Two Special Situations Executives</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Two top executives from Goldman Sachs
Group Inc.&#8217;s (GS) special situations group, which invests in
distressed businesses, have left the company, according to a
person familiar with the matter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nick Weber, 36, who was co-head of the European special
situations group in London, and Alan Waxman, 34, who helped run
the Americas team from New York, both left the company recently,
the person said. They reported to Rich Ruzika, the New York-based
global head of the group. The three didn&#8217;t respond to calls
seeking comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The special situations group is contained within Goldman&#8217;s
fixed-income, currencies and commodities division, the company&#8217;s
largest by revenue. SSG, as it&#8217;s known, became a major
contributor to revenue over the last 10 years by reaping gains on
investments ranging from a Korean liquor maker, Japanese golf
courses and a Texas wind-power company. While SSG&#8217;s overall
performance isn&#8217;t made public, some of its one-time gains and
losses are included in company disclosures. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some analysts and investors expect that Goldman&#8217;s ability to
make large, illiquid investments will be limited after the firm&#8217;s
September conversion into a bank holding company and the U.S.
government&#8217;s $10 billion investment under its financial-rescue
program. While the special situations group&#8217;s sale of Horizon
Wind Energy LLC last year helped generate a $900 million profit,
falling asset values this year are expected to cause a loss from
investments in the fourth quarter that ended in November. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dow Jones reported the departures earlier. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Christine Harper in New York at 
charper@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Otis Bilodeau at  obilodeau@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Adria Cimino" date="Dec 09, 2008  2:50 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-12-09/renault-and-peugeot-rated-new-underweight-at-jpmorgan.html"><headline>Renault and Peugeot Rated New &#8216;Underweight&#8217; at JPMorgan</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;JPMorgan Chase  Co. initiated
coverage of shares of PSA Peugeot Citroen (UG), Europe&#8217;s second-largest automaker, and Renault SA (RNO), France&#8217;s second biggest, with
&#8220;underweight&#8221; recommendations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Western European car sales may continue to decline, but the
industry &#8220;may offer attractive entry points as early as the
first quarter once certain negative equity fundamentals play
out,&#8221; the analysts wrote in a note to investors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JPMorgan analysts rated Daimler AG (DAI) &#8220;overweight,&#8221; saying
they favor companies with an &#8220;improving product cycle, strong
balance sheets and the capacity/ability to restructure quickly.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The brokerage also rated Porsche Automobil Holding SE, Fiat
SpA (F) and Bayerische Motoren Werke AG &#8220;neutral,&#8221; as well as
preferential shares of Volkswagen AG. (VOW) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Adria Cimino in Paris at 
acimino1@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Daniel Hauck at 
dhauck1@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Louisa Nesbitt" date="Dec 10, 2008  3:26 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-12-10/greencore-raised-to-buy-at-goldman-on-expansion-update1-.html"><headline>Greencore Raised to &#8216;Buy&#8217; at Goldman on Expansion</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Greencore Group Plc, which supplies
more than 100 million ready meals a year to U.K. retailers, was
raised to &#8220;buy&#8221; from &#8220;neutral&#8221; at Goldman Sachs, which said
the company can absorb an industry slowdown and fund its U.S.
expansion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman cut its target price to 1.08 euros ($1.40) from 1.36
euros and raised its per-share earnings estimate for 2009 by 5.5
percent to 19 cents. It cut the 2010 estimate by 9.6 percent to
15 cents. Greencore rose as much as 4.7 percent in Dublin. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;The group has faced material headwinds including input cost
recovery lag, Irish property market devaluation and a cost
concealment issue,&#8221; Fulvio Cazzol and other analysts at Goldman
in London said in a note today. &#8220;However, the business is
supported by a relatively healthy balance sheet providing
headroom to absorb working capital pressures and expansionary
projects in the U.S., which is the center of its growth strategy
over the next five years.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cazzol said the &#8220;sell-off&#8221; in Greencore shares, which have
fallen around 60 percent in the last three months, is
&#8220;overdone.&#8221; Risks to his view include the loss of supply
contracts in the convenience food division and input cost
increases, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Greencore climbed as much as 4.4 cents to 97.4 cents, and
was 4.3 percent higher at 97 cents as of 8:15 a.m. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Louisa Nesbitt in Dublin at 
lnesbitt@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Keith Campbell at  k.campbell@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry></news>