<?xml version='1.0' encoding='us-ascii'?>
<news><entry author="By Carla Main" date="May 12, 2008  6:53 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-05-12/sanofi-fox-microsoft-orion-intellectual-property-update1-.html"><headline>Sanofi, Fox, Microsoft, Orion: Intellectual Property</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Sanofi-Aventis SA (SAN) fell the most in
three months in Paris trading after Switzerland's Schweizerhall
Holding AG said it will market a lower-priced copy of the Plavix
blood thinner, the French drugmaker's second-biggest seller. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sanofi fell 5.9 percent, the most since Jan. 23. Luzi Andreas von Bidder, chairman of Basel-based Schweizerhall, said
May 9 that German approval may come in a ``couple of weeks.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``The German authorities have basically finished the
registration procedure and we're now just waiting for the
paperwork,'' Von Bidder said in a telephone interview. The
company is working with a ``major generics company'' and expects
to start selling the product, called clopidogrel, this quarter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2006, a generic copy of Plavix from Apotex Inc. in the
U.S. cut as much as $1.75 billion in sales at Bristol-Myers
Squibb Co., which markets the product there with Sanofi. The
medicine brought in 2.42 billion euros ($3.74 billion) for the
Paris-based drugmaker last year, trailing only clot medicine
Lovenox. Plavix is patent protected until 2013, spokesman Jean-Marc Podvin said, declining to comment further. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``We expect the generic competitors to have the
infrastructure and marketing ability to launch generic Plavix in
an aggressive manner,'' Landsbanki Kepler analyst Denise Anderson
wrote in a note to investors. ``We expect cuts to forecasts to
potentially be substantial.'' Anderson has a ``buy'' rating on
Schweizerhall and a ``reduce'' on Sanofi. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clopidogrel may also win approval in Luxembourg in the
second quarter, Schweizerhall said. The Swiss company is
preparing applications for other European countries. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``We did not think at all Plavix hegemony would have been
disputed before 2013,'' Alexandre Iatrides, an analyst at
Richelieu Finance, said in an interview. ``There are fears for
Plavix competition all over Europe. In that case, it could cost
10 percent of Sanofi's net income.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plavix has EU regulatory data protection, Sanofi said Friday
in an e-mailed statement. The product is also sold as Iscover by
Bristol-Myers in Germany. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``Sanofi-Aventis is currently evaluating its legal and
regulatory options and will vigorously defend intellectual
property rights, including patent protection, in Germany,'' the
company said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Standard for Business-Method Patents Weighed by Appeals Court &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The federal appeals court that handles patent cases
struggled to define the term ``process'' as part of its
deliberations in a case that will decide whether a method for
buying or selling energy qualifies for protection. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 200 patent lawyers packed the Washington courtroom
of the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit last week to
hear arguments in a case involving a Philadelphia man who
developed a way to buy or sell energy at a fixed price based on
the expected weather for a season, rather than per unit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Patent and Trademark Office can grant patents to
machines, manufactured items, compositions of matter such as drug
compounds and processes. Courts have wrangled with how to define
processes for decades. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``We need some principles, some factors'' to follow, Chief
Circuit Judge Paul Michel said. ``The test has to be calibrated
to be used in the real world by real examiners'' at the patent
office, he later added. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies weighing in with court filings on the case
included Accenture Ltd., Royal Philips Electronics NV, Microsoft
Corp. (MSFT), Yahoo! Inc. (YHOO), and International Business Machines Corp. (IBM) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The patent office refused to grant a patent to Bernard
Bilski, whose company WeatherWise USA Inc. wanted to
commercialize his idea. The agency said he hadn't shown that his
concept was eligible for a patent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The appeals court is revisiting a 1998 decision involving
State Street Corp. that made clear that business methods are
entitled to patent protection. The decision, which came in the
midst of the dot.com boom when courts were becoming more
comfortable with technology, opened the door to a flood of such
patents, and Bilski's rejection came amid an effort by the patent
office to give applications stricter scrutiny. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patent office lawyer Ray Chen said the court doesn't need to
overturn the 1998 decision to find that a process must be
connected to a machine or must physically transform something to
be considered eligible for a patent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dispute has split the finance industry. The Financial
Services Roundtable, representing Bank of America Corp. and
Citigroup Inc. (C), said the standard should be even higher. William Lee of Wilmer Cutler in Boston, arguing on behalf of the group,
said most software shouldn't be eligible for patents. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regulatory DataCorp Inc., set up by Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)
and Bain Capital LLC to develop ways to detect suspicious
financial transactions, contends that Congress wants broad
protection for inventions. A strict rule would curtail new
technology, said RDC lawyer John Duffy of Fried Frank in
Washington. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the court agrees with Bilski, ``it may be that business
method patents are broadened,'' Kimberly Van Voorhis, of Morrison
 Foerster's Palo Alto, California, office, said in a telephone
interview before the hearing. ``No matter how they rule, the
lawyers will interpret it one way and the patent office will
interpret it another way.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is In Re Bernard Bilski, 07-1130, U.S. Court of
Appeals for the Federal Circuit (Washington). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Patriot Scientific Fails to Revive ARM Patent Suit &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patriot Scientific Corp. (PTSC) lost an appeals court bid to revive
a patent-infringement lawsuit against chip designer ARM Holdings
Plc (ARM) over software run on microprocessors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit, without
issuing an opinion, upheld May 9 a finding that ARM doesn't
infringe Patriot Scientific's patent. Patriot Scientific, based
in San Diego, had claimed the trial judge erred in his definition
of what the patent covered. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patriot Scientific's Technology Properties unit sued
electronics companies including Matsushita Electric Industrial
Co., Toshiba Corp. and Fujitsu Ltd. in federal court in Marshall,
Texas, in 2005 over this and other patents. Those companies
settled, leaving only Cambridge, England-based ARM. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``This is the first time they've litigated their patents to
finality and they lost,'' said ARM lawyer Kevin Anderson of Wiley
Rein in Washington, who argued the case before the appeals court
three days ago. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Federal Circuit, which specializes in patent law, posted
a notice on its Web site that it affirmed a lower court ruling
won by ARM. The company designs semiconductors for Intel Corp. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An outside spokesman for Patriot Scientific didn't
immediately return a message seeking comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Technology Properties Ltd. v. ARM Ltd., 2008-1020, U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit. The lower
court case is Technology Properties Ltd. v. Fujitsu Ltd.,
05cv494, U.S. District Court, Eastern District of Texas
(Marshall). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Orion Drops After Ending Parkinson's Drug Development &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Orion Oyj (ORNBV), the Finnish producer of the Stalevo and Comtan
Parkinson's disease treatments, fell 2 percent in Helsinki
trading on May 9 after the company stopped development of an
experimental drug. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Orion said an early trial in patients showed the drug
wouldn't work better than products already on the market. Orion
gets about one-third of its revenue from Stalevo and Comtan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Orion's patent on entacapone, the active ingredient in
Comtan and one of three in Stalevo, expired last year in all
parts of the world except the U.S. and Europe. The patent expires
in the U.S. in 2013 and in Europe in 2012, according to a
November presentation by Orion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Barr Wins FDA Approval for Generic Version of Bayer's Yasmin &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Barr Pharmaceuticals Inc. unit received final approval
from the U.S. Food and Drug Administration to sell a generic form
of the oral contraceptive pill Yasmin. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barr Laboratories Inc. said in a May 9 statement that the
FDA granted its application, allowing the company to make and
market the generic drug. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The name-brand Yasmin drug is sold by Bayer Schering Pharma
AG. A federal court in New Jersey ruled March 3 that Bayer's
patent was invalid because the pill's chemical composition was
``obvious.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bayer appealed April 1. The appeal will be heard by the U.S.
Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit, which hears patent
cases. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Bayer Schering Pharma AG v. Barr Pharmaceuticals
Inc., 2:05-cv-02308-PGS-ES, U.S. District Court, District of New
Jersey (Newark). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For other patent news from May 9, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Copyright &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Twentieth Century Fox Sued Over ``Borat'' Song Rights &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twentieth Century Fox Film Corp. and Christian singer
Timothy Spell were sued May 8 by Frank A. O'Brien, who claims he
owns the rights to a song used in the film ``Borat: Cultural
Learnings of America Make Benefit Glorious Nation of
Kazakhstan.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O'Brien, who is representing himself in the lawsuit in
federal court in Baton Rouge, Louisiana,, alleges that a scene in
Borat set in a Pentecostal Church in Mississippi features Spell
performing a ``substantial portion'' of a song written by O'Brien
called ``Nothin' Like Being Able.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O'Brien claims Spell falsely represented that he either
owned or controlled a portion of the copyright to the song and
received $25,000 from Twentieth Century Fox for the right to use
it. O'Brien said that had he been asked, he wouldn't have granted
permission to use the song because the film ``served only to
derogate his religion and tenets.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris Petrikin, a Twentieth Century Fox spokesman, said the
company wasn't yet aware of the suit. Spell didn't immediately
respond to an e-mail seeking comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is O'Brien v. Spell, 3:08-cv-00283, U.S. District
Court, Middle District of Louisiana (Baton Rouge). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Virgin Mobile Sued for Using Girl's Photo Without Permission &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virgin Mobile USA LLC and Virgin Mobile Pty Ltd. were sued
over billboard advertisements that used a girl's photograph
obtained from Yahoo! Inc.'s photo-sharing Web site Flickr. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 16-year-old girl's mother, Susan Chang, brought the
lawsuit alleging invasion of privacy, copyright infringement,
trademark infringement, libel and other claims. The amended
petition was filed May 8 in federal court in San Jose,
California. Justin Ho-Yee Wong, who says he took the photo, is
also a plaintiff. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chang alleges the use of the photograph, part of a Virgin
Mobile ad campaign to promote free text messaging and other
services since 2007, was ``unauthorized and exploitative.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jayne Wallace, a Virgin Mobile spokeswoman, didn't return a
call seeking comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Chang v. Virgin Mobile USA LLC, 5:08-mc-80095-JW, U.S. District Court, Northern District of California (San
Jose). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Microsoft Appeals 899 Million-Euro Fine to EU Court &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Corp., the world's largest software maker, asked a
court to overturn or reduce a record 899 million-euro ($1.4
billion) European Union fine over claims the company failed to
comply with an antitrust ruling. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The appeal was filed May 9 at the European Court of First
Instance in Luxembourg, Microsoft spokesman Jesse Verstraete said
in an e-mailed statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``We are filing this appeal in a constructive effort to seek
clarity from the court,'' Verstraete said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The European Commission, the EU's antitrust authority, fined
the company on Feb. 27 for failing to comply with a 2004
antitrust order. Under that decision, in which Microsoft was
fined 497 million euros, the EU ordered the software maker to
provide data to rivals to allow servers to connect to the Windows
platform. Microsoft was required to charge reasonable royalties
for the network data technology. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft was the first company in
50 years of EU competition policy to face a penalty for failing
to comply with an EU order. The commission found that Microsoft
overcharged for patent licenses that rivals needed to connect
products to the Windows operating system. The fine brought the
total penalty against Microsoft to 1.68 billion euros. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A European court upheld the commission's 2004 ruling against
Microsoft in September, meaning the company wasn't in compliance
for three years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``It's the company's legal right to appeal such fines,
particularly with respect to orders regarding compliance with
such a controversial and vague set of requirements,'' said Philip
Marsden, a competition lawyer and senior research fellow at the
British Institute of International and Comparative Law, who isn't
involved with the case. ``There's a fairly good record of the
court lowering fines the commission has made upon appeal.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has the right to an oral hearing at the EU court
before a final ruling. The company can appeal any decision to the
European Court of Justice, the EU's highest court. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``The commission is confident that the decision to impose
the fine is legally sound,'' spokesman Jonathan Todd said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For other copyright news from May 9, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Trademark &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bill Graham Enterprises Sues to Stop Use of Fillmore Name &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bill Graham Enterprises Inc., a unit of concert promoter
Live Nation Inc. (LYV) named for the late rock promoter Bill Graham,
sued a New York clothing manufacturer to stop it from using the
word Fillmore on clothing lines. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bill Graham Enterprises, which operates Fillmore Theaters in
San Francisco and other U.S. cities, claims International Direct
Group Inc. is using the name to sell clothes and has filed
notices with the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office indicating an
intention to use variations of Fillmore. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live Nation has used the trademark for several years and
owns a variety of federally registered trademarks on variations
of the word, according to the suit, filed in federal court in Los
Angeles. The suit alleges trademark infringement, false
designation of origin, trademark dilution and related claims. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A woman who answered the phone at International Direct
Group's offices, who declined to identify herself, said she had
no comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Bill Graham Enterprises Inc. v. International
Direct Group Inc., 08-cv-02930, U.S. District Court, Central
District of California, Western Division (Los Angeles). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For other trademark news from May 9, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;IP Moves &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Patent Office Deputy General Joins University, NLJ Says &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Whelan, the former deputy general counsel and solicitor
for the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office, left the government to
become a law school dean, the National Law Journal reported. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whelan joined the George Washington School of Law in
Washington as associate dean for intellectual property. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As solicitor, Whelan argued and briefed scores of appeals
before the Federal Circuit Court of Appeals, the appellate court
that frequently hears intellectual property cases. Along with his
staff, he also submitted many briefs on intellectual property
cases to the U.S. Supreme Court. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before joining the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office, Whelan
worked for the International Trade Commission, the newspaper
reported. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Bloomberg articles by lawyers on intellectual property topics
click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For daily Bloomberg legal analysis click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Carla Main in Jersey City, New Jersey at  cmain2@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Patrick Oster at  poster@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Carla Main" date="May 12, 2008 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-05-12/sanofi-fox-microsoft-virgin-mobile-intellectual-property.html"><headline>Sanofi, Fox, Microsoft, Virgin Mobile: Intellectual Property</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Sanofi-Aventis SA (SAN) fell the most in
three months in Paris trading after Switzerland's Schweizerhall
Holding AG said it will market a lower-priced copy of the Plavix
blood thinner, the French drugmaker's second-biggest seller. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sanofi fell 5.9 percent, the most since Jan. 23. Luzi Andreas von Bidder, chairman of Basel-based Schweizerhall, said
May 9 that German approval may come in a ``couple of weeks.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``The German authorities have basically finished the
registration procedure and we're now just waiting for the
paperwork,'' Von Bidder said in a telephone interview. The
company is working with a ``major generics company'' and expects
to start selling the product, called clopidogrel, this quarter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2006, a generic copy of Plavix from Apotex Inc. in the
U.S. cut as much as $1.75 billion in sales at Bristol-Myers
Squibb Co., which markets the product there with Sanofi. The
medicine brought in 2.42 billion euros ($3.74 billion) for the
Paris-based drugmaker last year, trailing only clot medicine
Lovenox. Plavix is patent protected until 2013, spokesman Jean-Marc Podvin said, declining to comment further. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``We expect the generic competitors to have the
infrastructure and marketing ability to launch generic Plavix in
an aggressive manner,'' Landsbanki Kepler analyst Denise Anderson wrote in a note to investors. ``We expect cuts to
forecasts to potentially be substantial.'' Anderson has a
``buy'' rating on Schweizerhall and a ``reduce'' on Sanofi. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clopidogrel may also win approval in Luxembourg in the
second quarter, Schweizerhall said. The Swiss company is
preparing applications for other European countries. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``We did not think at all Plavix hegemony would have been
disputed before 2013,'' Alexandre Iatrides, an analyst at
Richelieu Finance, said in an interview. ``There are fears for
Plavix competition all over Europe. In that case, it could cost
10 percent of Sanofi's net income.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plavix has EU regulatory data protection, Sanofi said
Friday in an e-mailed statement. The product is also sold as
Iscover by Bristol-Myers in Germany. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``Sanofi-Aventis is currently evaluating its legal and
regulatory options and will vigorously defend intellectual
property rights, including patent protection, in Germany,'' the
company said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Standard for Business-Method Patents Weighed by Appeals Court &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The federal appeals court that handles patent cases
struggled to define the term ``process'' as part of its
deliberations in a case that will decide whether a method for
buying or selling energy qualifies for protection. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 200 patent lawyers packed the Washington
courtroom of the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit
last week to hear arguments in a case involving a Philadelphia
man who developed a way to buy or sell energy at a fixed price
based on the expected weather for a season, rather than per
unit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Patent and Trademark Office can grant patents to
machines, manufactured items, compositions of matter such as
drug compounds and processes. Courts have wrangled with how to
define processes for decades. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``We need some principles, some factors'' to follow, Chief
Circuit Judge Paul Michel said. ``The test has to be calibrated
to be used in the real world by real examiners'' at the patent
office, he later added. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Companies weighing in with court filings on the case
included Accenture Ltd., Royal Philips Electronics NV, Microsoft
Corp. (MSFT), Yahoo! Inc. (YHOO), and International Business Machines Corp. (IBM) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The patent office refused to grant a patent to Bernard
Bilski, whose company WeatherWise USA Inc. wanted to
commercialize his idea. The agency said he hadn't shown that his
concept was eligible for a patent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The appeals court is revisiting a 1998 decision involving
State Street Corp. that made clear that business methods are
entitled to patent protection. The decision, which came in the
midst of the dot.com boom when courts were becoming more
comfortable with technology, opened the door to a flood of such
patents, and Bilski's rejection came amid an effort by the
patent office to give applications stricter scrutiny. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patent office lawyer Ray Chen said the court doesn't need
to overturn the 1998 decision to find that a process must be
connected to a machine or must physically transform something to
be considered eligible for a patent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The dispute has split the finance industry. The Financial
Services Roundtable, representing Bank of America Corp. and
Citigroup Inc. (C), said the standard should be even higher. William Lee of Wilmer Cutler in Boston, arguing on behalf of the group,
said most software shouldn't be eligible for patents. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regulatory DataCorp Inc., set up by Goldman Sachs Group
Inc. (GS) and Bain Capital LLC to develop ways to detect suspicious
financial transactions, contends that Congress wants broad
protection for inventions. A strict rule would curtail new
technology, said RDC lawyer John Duffy of Fried Frank in
Washington. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the court agrees with Bilski, ``it may be that business
method patents are broadened,'' Kimberly Van Voorhis, of
Morrison  Foerster's Palo Alto, California, office, said in a
telephone interview before the hearing. ``No matter how they
rule, the lawyers will interpret it one way and the patent
office will interpret it another way.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is In Re Bernard Bilski, 07-1130, U.S. Court of
Appeals for the Federal Circuit (Washington). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Patriot Scientific Fails to Revive ARM Patent Suit &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patriot Scientific Corp. (PTSC) lost an appeals court bid to
revive a patent-infringement lawsuit against chip designer ARM
Holdings Plc (ARM) over software run on microprocessors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit, without
issuing an opinion, upheld May 9 a finding that ARM doesn't
infringe Patriot Scientific's patent. Patriot Scientific, based
in San Diego, had claimed the trial judge erred in his
definition of what the patent covered. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patriot Scientific's Technology Properties unit sued
electronics companies including Matsushita Electric Industrial
Co., Toshiba Corp. and Fujitsu Ltd. in federal court in
Marshall, Texas, in 2005 over this and other patents. Those
companies settled, leaving only Cambridge, England-based ARM. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``This is the first time they've litigated their patents to
finality and they lost,'' said ARM lawyer Kevin Anderson of
Wiley Rein in Washington, who argued the case before the appeals
court three days ago. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Federal Circuit, which specializes in patent law,
posted a notice on its Web site that it affirmed a lower court
ruling won by ARM. The company designs semiconductors for Intel
Corp. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An outside spokesman for Patriot Scientific didn't
immediately return a message seeking comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Technology Properties Ltd. v. ARM Ltd., 2008-1020, U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit. The lower
court case is Technology Properties Ltd. v. Fujitsu Ltd.,
05cv494, U.S. District Court, Eastern District of Texas
(Marshall). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For other patent news from May 9, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Copyright &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Twentieth Century Fox Sued Over ``Borat'' Song Rights &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twentieth Century Fox Film Corp. and Christian singer
Timothy Spell were sued May 8 by Frank A. O'Brien, who claims he
owns the rights to a song used in the film ``Borat: Cultural
Learnings of America Make Benefit Glorious Nation of
Kazakhstan.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O'Brien, who is representing himself in the lawsuit in
federal court in Baton Rouge, Louisiana,, alleges that a scene
in Borat set in a Pentecostal Church in Mississippi features
Spell performing a ``substantial portion'' of a song written by
O'Brien called ``Nothin' Like Being Able.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;O'Brien claims Spell falsely represented that he either
owned or controlled a portion of the copyright to the song and
received $25,000 from Twentieth Century Fox for the right to use
it. O'Brien said that had he been asked, he wouldn't have
granted permission to use the song because the film ``served
only to derogate his religion and tenets.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chris Petrikin, a Twentieth Century Fox spokesman, said the
company wasn't yet aware of the suit. Spell didn't immediately
respond to an e-mail seeking comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is O'Brien v. Spell, 3:08-cv-00283, U.S. District
Court, Middle District of Louisiana (Baton Rouge). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Virgin Mobile Sued for Using Girl's Photo Without Permission &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virgin Mobile USA LLC and Virgin Mobile Pty Ltd. were sued
over billboard advertisements that used a girl's photograph
obtained from Yahoo! Inc.'s photo-sharing Web site Flickr. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 16-year-old girl's mother, Susan Chang, brought the
lawsuit alleging invasion of privacy, copyright infringement,
trademark infringement, libel and other claims. The amended
petition was filed May 8 in federal court in San Jose,
California. Justin Ho-Yee Wong, who says he took the photo, is
also a plaintiff. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chang alleges the use of the photograph, part of a Virgin
Mobile ad campaign to promote free text messaging and other
services since 2007, was ``unauthorized and exploitative.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jayne Wallace, a Virgin Mobile spokeswoman, didn't return a
call seeking comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Chang v. Virgin Mobile USA LLC, 5:08-mc-80095-JW, U.S. District Court, Northern District of California (San
Jose). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Microsoft Appeals 899 Million-Euro Fine to EU Court &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Corp., the world's largest software maker, asked
a court to overturn or reduce a record 899 million-euro ($1.4
billion) European Union fine over claims the company failed to
comply with an antitrust ruling. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The appeal was filed May 9 at the European Court of First
Instance in Luxembourg, Microsoft spokesman Jesse Verstraete
said in an e-mailed statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``We are filing this appeal in a constructive effort to
seek clarity from the court,'' Verstraete said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The European Commission, the EU's antitrust authority,
fined the company on Feb. 27 for failing to comply with a 2004
antitrust order. Under that decision, in which Microsoft was
fined 497 million euros, the EU ordered the software maker to
provide data to rivals to allow servers to connect to the
Windows platform. Microsoft was required to charge reasonable
royalties for the network data technology. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft was the first company
in 50 years of EU competition policy to face a penalty for
failing to comply with an EU order. The commission found that
Microsoft overcharged for patent licenses that rivals needed to
connect products to the Windows operating system. The fine
brought the total penalty against Microsoft to 1.68 billion
euros. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A European court upheld the commission's 2004 ruling
against Microsoft in September, meaning the company wasn't in
compliance for three years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``It's the company's legal right to appeal such fines,
particularly with respect to orders regarding compliance with
such a controversial and vague set of requirements,'' said
Philip Marsden, a competition lawyer and senior research fellow
at the British Institute of International and Comparative Law,
who isn't involved with the case. ``There's a fairly good record
of the court lowering fines the commission has made upon
appeal.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has the right to an oral hearing at the EU court
before a final ruling. The company can appeal any decision to
the European Court of Justice, the EU's highest court. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``The commission is confident that the decision to impose
the fine is legally sound,'' spokesman Jonathan Todd said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For other copyright news from May 9, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Trademark &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bill Graham Enterprises Sues to Stop Use of Fillmore Name &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bill Graham Enterprises Inc., a unit of concert promoter
Live Nation Inc. (LYV) named for the late rock promoter Bill Graham,
sued a New York clothing manufacturer to stop it from using the
word Fillmore on clothing lines. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bill Graham Enterprises, which operates Fillmore Theaters
in San Francisco and other U.S. cities, claims International
Direct Group Inc. is using the name to sell clothes and has
filed notices with the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office
indicating an intention to use variations of Fillmore. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live Nation has used the trademark for several years and
owns a variety of federally registered trademarks on variations
of the word, according to the suit, filed in federal court in
Los Angeles. The suit alleges trademark infringement, false
designation of origin, trademark dilution and related claims. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A woman who answered the phone at International Direct
Group's offices, who declined to identify herself, said she had
no comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Bill Graham Enterprises Inc. v. International
Direct Group Inc., 08-cv-02930, U.S. District Court, Central
District of California, Western Division (Los Angeles). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For other trademark news from May 9, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;IP Moves &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Patent Office Deputy General Joins University, NLJ Says &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;John Whelan, the former deputy general counsel and
solicitor for the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office, left the
government to become a law school dean, the National Law Journal
reported. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whelan joined the George Washington School of Law in
Washington as associate dean for intellectual property. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As solicitor, Whelan argued and briefed scores of appeals
before the Federal Circuit Court of Appeals, the appellate court
that frequently hears intellectual property cases. Along with
his staff, he also submitted many briefs on intellectual
property cases to the U.S. Supreme Court. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before joining the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office, Whelan
worked for the International Trade Commission, the newspaper
reported. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Bloomberg articles by lawyers on intellectual property
topics click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For daily Bloomberg legal analysis click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Carla Main in Jersey City, New Jersey at  cmain2@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Patrick Oster at  poster@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Elizabeth Amon" date="May 13, 2008 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-05-13/sprint-clear-channel-exxon-altria-wachovia-in-court-news.html"><headline>Sprint, Clear Channel, Exxon, Altria, Wachovia in Court News</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Sprint (S) Nextel Corp., the third-largest U.S. phone company, was sued by its IPCS Inc. affiliate,
which seeks to block a $14.5 billion WiMax venture with
Clearwire Corp., claiming the deal violates an exclusive
contract. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Clearwire project should be put on hold until it
complies with the terms of the Sprint-IPCS accord, IPCS said in
a complaint filed yesterday with the Cook County Circuit Court
in Illinois. Sprint had agreed not to compete with IPCS in areas
in the country where the affiliate offers service, IPCS said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IPCS's complaint follows a victory against Sprint in an
Illinois trial court, which ruled that Sprint's $36 billion
purchase of Nextel Communications Inc. put it in breach of an
exclusive-territory agreement. Sprint is appealing an order to
shed its Nextel operations in Illinois, Michigan, Iowa and parts
of Nebraska. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sprint said in a lawsuit filed last week that combining its
high-speed wireless business with Clearwire's network wouldn't
prohibit it from serving IPCS territory. IPCS manages Sprint's
network on the 1.9-gigahertz radio frequency, while the new
system using the WiMax standard would run at 2.5 GHz. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is IPCS Inc. v Sprint Nextel Corp., 08CH17214,
Circuit Court of Cook County, Illinois. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more new suits news from yesterday, click here. For copies
of recent civil complaints, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lawsuits/Pretrial &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Clear Channel Surges on Possible Buyout Settlement &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clear Channel Communications Inc. (CCU) surged as much as 18
percent on reports of settlement talks with six banks on a
proposal to finance the radio broadcaster's acquisition by two
buyout firms at a reduced price. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citigroup Inc. (C) and five other banks may fund the buyout for
$36 a share as part of a settlement of lawsuits pending in New
York and Texas state courts, the Wall Street Journal reported,
without saying where it got the information. That's below the
$39.20 price buyout firms agreed to pay last year and more than
an intraday high of $35.30 in New York Stock Exchange trading. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Judges delayed proceedings in both cases yesterday, without
explanation. The banks were to face a non-jury trial yesterday
in New York state court over whether they must fund the $19.5
billion acquisition by Boston-based Bain Capital LLC and Thomas
H. Lee Partners LP. The two firms alleged the banks wrongly
backed out of an agreement to finance the deal. The banks
rejected the claim and countersued. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``The way the case was developing it was likely the banks
would face a Texas jury,'' said Jake Newman, an analyst at
CreditSights, a fixed-income research firm in New York. ``They
may decide it could cost more to fight in court than fund the
deal.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lawyers for the banks and buyout firms declined to comment
on any settlement talks. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other banks named in the New York lawsuit are Credit
Suisse Group (CSGN), Morgan Stanley (MS), Royal Bank of Scotland Group Plc,
Wachovia Corp. (WB) and Deutsche Bank AG. (DBK) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main New York case on the Clear Channel buyout is BT
Triple Crown Merger Co. v. Citigroup, 08600899, New York State
Supreme Court, County of New York (Manhattan). The Texas case is
Clear Channel Communications v. Citigroup Global Markets Inc.,
08-ci-04864, 225th Judicial Circuit, Bexar County Court, Texas
(San Antonio). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Discovery Labs Wins Affirmation of Dismissed Securities Suit &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A federal securities suit brought against Discovery
Laboratories Inc. (DSCO), a biotechnology company developing Surfactant
Replacement Therapies for respiratory diseases, was dismissed by
an appeals court April 29. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 3rd U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals affirmed a lower
court's dismissal of the plaintiffs' complaint, which alleged
that Discovery Labs misled investors about the prospects for
regulatory approval of its lead product, Surfaxin, the
defendants said in a statement. Surfaxin is a medicine for the
prevention of Respiratory Distress Syndrome in premature
infants. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ruling ``should also help other biotech start-ups that,
like Discovery Labs, fully comply with the securities laws but
suffer a set-back in their efforts to obtain regulatory approval
of a new medicine,'' Robert L. Hickok, a lawyer at Pepper
Hamilton who represented Discovery Labs, said in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carol A. Mager, of the law firm Mager  Goldstein, who
represented the plaintiffs, didn't return a phone call seeking
comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is In re Discovery Laboratories Securities
Litigation, 07-2080, 3rd U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more lawsuits news from yesterday, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Trials/Appeals &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Companies Must Face Apartheid Suits After High Court Setback &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dozens of companies must defend against lawsuits accusing
them of helping South Africa's former apartheid regime repress
blacks, after the stock holdings of U.S. Supreme Court justices
left them unable to hear a company appeal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM), IBM Corp. (IBM), Credit Suisse Group and 30
other businesses sought reversal of an appeals court decision
allowing the suits, which at one point sought more than $400
billion. The Bush administration backed the companies, telling
the Supreme Court that the suits ``effectively seek to overturn
South Africa's post-apartheid policy of reconciliation.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In declaring itself unable to hear the case, the court said
only five of the nine justices could take part, one short of a
quorum. Three of the four recused justices -- John Roberts,
Stephen Breyer and Samuel Alito -- owned stock in at least one
of the companies, according to their financial disclosure forms.
The fourth, Anthony Kennedy, is the father of a Credit Suisse
banker. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The suits accuse the companies of ``aiding and abetting''
violations of international law committed by South Africa's
apartheid-era government. Those suing the companies include
torture victims and representatives of people who were murdered. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The defendants represent a cross-section of worldwide
businesses. Among the defendants are Citigroup Inc., Bristol-Myers Squibb Co. (BMY), Coca-Cola Co. (KO), DuPont Co. (DD), General Electric
Co. (GE), General Motors Corp. (GM), JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) and Xerox Corp. (XRX) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The suits name more than 50 companies, some of which
weren't involved in the Supreme Court appeal. The South African
government has called for rejection of the lawsuits. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cases invoke the U.S. Alien Tort Statute, a two-century-old law that lets federal courts hear suits by non-citizens claiming violations of international law. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The companies contended the lower court improperly expanded
that law to authorize aiding-and-abetting suits and opened the
door to a host of lawsuits against international companies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``It will encourage further litigation that does not belong
in U.S. courts and that adversely affects U.S. foreign policy,''
the appeal argued. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The victims urged the Supreme Court not to hear the case,
saying the ruling by the 2nd U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals in
New York was correct. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lower court ruling left open the possibility that the
companies ultimately could win dismissal on different grounds.
The three-judge panel didn't rule on the companies' contention
that the case raises political issues better suited to
resolution outside the courtroom. The appeals court said the
companies should press those arguments first at the trial court
level. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is American Isuzu Motors v. Ntsebeza, 07-919, U.S.
Supreme Court (Washington). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more trial and appeals news from yesterday, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Verdicts/Settlements &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tobacco Settlement Challenge Rejected by U.S. Supreme Court &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Supreme Court turned away an appeal from a
California smoker who blamed rising cigarette prices on the $206
billion settlement reached a decade ago between 46 states and
the nation's largest tobacco companies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The justices, without comment, yesterday refused to revive
Steve Sanders's antitrust lawsuit against California Attorney
General Jerry Brown and tobacco companies including Altria Group
Inc. (MO)'s Philip Morris USA unit and Reynolds American Inc. (RAI)'s R.J.
Reynolds Tobacco unit. A San Francisco-based federal appeals
court threw out the lawsuit in September. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sanders's lawyers argued unsuccessfully that the 1998
settlement led to lockstep price increases of $12.20 per carton
between 1998 and 2002 alone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The accord ``effectively established a horizontal cartel
that eliminated all incentive to increase market share or to
compete on price,'' Sanders argued in his appeal, filed in
Washington. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 1998 settlement resolved state lawsuits that sought to
recoup the cost of treating sick smokers. In addition to paying
$206 billion over 25 years -- plus another $40 billion to four
states that settled separately -- the industry agreed to scale
back marketing and take other steps to reduce youth smoking. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Sanders v. Brown, 07-995, U.S. Supreme Court
(Washington). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more verdict and settlement news from yesterday, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Litigation Departments &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wachovia Names Sherburne to Succeed Treanor as General Counsel &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wachovia Corp., the fourth-largest U.S. bank, named Jane Sherburne to succeed Mark Treanor, who is retiring, as the
company's top lawyer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sherburne, 57, is general counsel at New York-based
Citigroup Inc.'s global consumer group. She will join Charlotte,
North Carolina-based Wachovia later this year when Treanor, 61,
steps down, the company said yesterday in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sherburne will lead Wachovia's legal division and
government relations department. She previously served as
special counsel to former President Bill Clinton and was a
partner at the law firm now known as Wilmer Cutler Pickering
Hale  Dorr. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more litigation department news from yesterday, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Court News &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bush Nominates Virginia Judge to 4th Circuit Court of Appeals &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virginia federal judge Glen E. Conrad was nominated by
President George Bush for a position with the 4th U.S. Circuit
Court of Appeals. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conrad, a federal judge in the Western District of Virginia
since 2003, earned his law degree at the College of William 
Mary's Marshall-Wythe School of Law in 1974. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virginia's Republican Senator John Warner and Democratic
Senator Jim Webb jointly recommended Conrad to Bush, the
Associated Press reported. Conrad is the fifth person nominated
by the president for the five vacant seats on the 4th Circuit,
AP reported. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;On the Docket &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Jury Selection Begins in Lawsuit Over Death From Taser Stun Gun &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jury selection is set to begin today in a lawsuit against
Taser International Corp. (TASR) and the Salinas, California, police
department over the death of a man who went into cardiac arrest
after being allegedly shot 37 times with a stun gun. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Feb. 20, 2005, Robert Heston's father called Salinas
police, saying his son appeared to be on drugs, according to his
family's attorney. Officers initially decided Heston wasn't a
threat, then returned when he began throwing items out the front
door. They shot Heston with a Taser stun gun 37 times, causing
him to go into cardiac arrest, the family claims. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The family sued Taser, alleging a failure to warn of the
risks of using the stun gun multiple times, and the police
department, claiming it used excessive force. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Heston v. City of Salinas, C 05-03658 JW, U.S.
District Court, Northern District of California (San Jose). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bloomberg Law Reports &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Federal Judge Admits Evidence That Falls Outside Daubert &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bloomberg Weekly Litigation Report included an item
yesterday examining a federal court ruling admitting expert
evidence that fell outside the classic Daubert reliability
framework. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lawsuit was brought by Kevin Schmude against Tricam
Industries Inc. for injuries allegedly sustained when Schmude
fell off a stepladder made by Tricam. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stanley Johnson, an industrial designer, testified during
the trial that the ladder was unreasonably dangerous because of
a manufacturing defect. The defect, which wasn't disputed,
consisted of an improperly-installed rivet. It also wasn't
disputed that the rivet failed and the ladder's rear leg became
dislodged from the top cap of the ladder during the accident. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The court concluded that Johnson's opinion as to how the
ladder failed, though not subjected to scientific testing or
submitted for peer review or publication, was a matter over
which the trial judge has ``considerable leeway'' to decide. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Schmude v. Tricam Industries Inc. 07-cv-00457,
U.S. District Court, Eastern District of Wisconsin. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To read more about this case or the report in its entirety,
click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Bloomberg articles by lawyers on litigation topics, click
here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For news about bankruptcy litigation, click here. For news about
intellectual property litigation click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Elizabeth Amon in Brooklyn, New York, at 
eamon2@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Patrick Oster at  poster@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Janice Kew" date="May 16, 2008 10:39 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-05-16/nedbank-tops-jpmorgan-s-south-african-value-list-update1-.html"><headline>Nedbank Tops JPMorgan's South African `Value' List</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Nedbank Group Ltd. (NED), Allied Electronics
Corp. Ltd. and Aveng Ltd. (AEG) top JPMorgan Chase  Co.'s list of
South African stocks that show ``deep value'' for investors who
plan to buy and hold shares for more than 12 months. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investors who are willing to ``take on the risk of
distressed and out-of-favor shares that may continue to
underperform in the short-term,'' should buy these stocks,
strategists including Deanne Gordon and Jason Swartz wrote in a
report dated today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may be too early to ``tilt aggressively to value
opportunities'' given ``a still sticky South African inflation
outlook,'' the strategists added. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The South African Reserve Bank lifted its key interest rate
by half a percentage point to 11.5 percent on April 10, the fifth
increase in less than a year, forecasting that inflation would
stay above the 3 percent to 6 percent target range until the end
of next year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JPMorgan has an ``overweight'' recommendation on Nedbank,
South Africa's fourth-largest bank, Altron, the country's largest
publicly traded maker of telecommunications and power equipment,
and Aveng, the biggest local construction company by market
value. The recommendation means investors should hold more of the
shares than are represented in benchmark indexes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five South African banking stocks make the list of the top
13 companies that satisfy at least five out of ten conditions of
Benjamin Graham's style of investing, the strategists wrote. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Benjamin Graham, a value investor, was the man who taught
Warren Buffett to buy good companies at bargain prices, often
when they had fallen from favor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporters on this story:
Janice Kew in Johannesburg at 
jkew1@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Daniel Hauck at  dhauck1@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Janice Kew" date="May 16, 2008  9:40 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-05-16/nedbank-tops-jpmorgan-s-south-african-deep-value-stock-list.html"><headline>Nedbank Tops JPMorgan's South African `Deep Value' Stock List</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Nedbank Group Ltd. (NED), Allied
Technologies Ltd. and Aveng Ltd. (AEG) top JPMorgan Chase  Co.'s list
of South African stocks that show ``deep value'' for investors
who plan to buy and hold shares for more than 12 months. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investors who are willing to ``take on the risk of
distressed and out-of-favor shares that may continue to
underperform in the short-term,'' should buy these stocks,
strategists including Deanne Gordon and Jason Swartz wrote in a
report dated today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JPMorgan has an ``overweight'' recommendation on Nedbank,
South Africa's fourth-largest bank, Altron, the country's largest
publicly traded maker of telecommunications and power equipment,
and Aveng, the biggest local construction company by market
value. The recommendation means investors should hold more of the
shares than are represented in benchmark indexes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five South African banking stocks make the list of the top
13 companies that satisfy at least five out of ten conditions of
Benjamin Graham's style of investing, the strategists wrote. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Benjamin Graham, a value investor, was the man who taught
Warren Buffett to buy good companies at bargain prices, often
when they had fallen from favor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporters on this story:
Janice Kew in Johannesburg at 
jkew1@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Daniel Hauck at  dhauck1@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry></news>