
<news><entry author="By Ambereen Choudhury" date="Sep 01, 2014 11:45 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-01/goldman-sachs-loaned-banco-espirito-santo-funds-in-july.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Loaned Banco Espirito Santo Funds in July</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) loaned
Portugal''s Banco Espirito Santo SA $835 million in July, just
weeks before the group''s units sought creditor protection in a
cascade of insolvencies that resulted in the lender''s bailout. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs made the loan through Oak Finance Luxembourg
SA, an investment company that raised funds destined for a
Venezuelan oil refinery project, according to the unit''s offer
document. </p>
<p>Banco Espirito Santo, once Portugal''s biggest publicly
traded lender by market value, was bailed out Aug. 3 after it
disclosed potential losses on loans to other Grupo Espirito
Santo companies and regulators ordered the lender to raise more
capital. The bank was split in two with deposits and healthy
assets becoming Novo Banco in a bailout by the central bank''s
Resolution Fund. </p>
<p>The Wall Street Journal reported earlier today that Goldman 
Sachs sold some of Oak Finance''s securities at a loss to hedge 
funds and the New York-based firm is still holding some of the 
debt, citing a person it didn''t identify. </p>
<p>An official for Goldman Sachs in London declined to
comment. Novo Banco does not comment about operations that
involve clients, said a spokeswoman, who asked not to be named
in line with company policy. Officials for Portugal''s central
bank didn''t have an immediate comment. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs had agreed to the funding on May 16, the
offer document shows. Four days later, Banco Espirito Santo
warned investors buying stock in its rights offer of
irregularities in the accounts of a parent company and that the
serious financial situation of the parent firm could be
damaging to the bank''s reputation. Regulators are examining how
the group''s companies helped fund each other. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ben Elgin" date="Sep 02, 2014  4:27 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-02/chevron-makes-it-official-with-sale-of-renewable-energy-unit.html"><headline>Chevron Makes It Official With Sale of Renewable-Energy Unit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>     Sept. 2 (Bloomberg Businessweek) -- Chevron has finalized
the sale of its renewable-energy subsidiary, Chevron Energy
Solutions, to OpTerra Energy Services, a Chevron spokesman
confirmed today. </p>
<p>The sale, on Aug. 29, marks the latest in a series of moves
away from renewables by the oil company. Earlier this year,
Chevron sold a 48-person division that builds renewable projects
and energy-savings retrofits for federal agencies such as the
U.S. Department of Defense. </p>
<p>OpTerra is backed by Oaktree Capital Management, a private
equity firm in Los Angeles, according to OpTerra''s website. It
develops energy-savings projects, as well as clean-energy systems
from technologies like solar and fuel cells. </p>
<p>Bloomberg Businessweek first reported the expected sale of
Chevron''s clean-energy subsidiary in June. </p>
<p>Chevron declined to comment on the price of the transaction
or the number of its employees moving to OpTerra. The company
said in a statement that the sale is part of an internal
strategic focus on supporting Chevron''s Upstream and Downstream
businesses. Chevron continues to believe that energy efficiency
and renewable energy are an important part of the overall energy
mix, and operates a portfolio of renewables, including wind,
geothermal and solar. </p>
<p>A spokeswoman for Oaktree Capital declined to comment. An
OpTerra representative previously declined to comment about the
transaction and didn''t respond to a new request for comment
today. </p>
<p>Chevron Energy Solutions was first acquired by the oil
company in 2000 and has long been a centerpiece of Chevron''s
efforts to pursue renewable energy. A decade after acquiring the
division, Chevron boasted that the group had developed hundreds
of renewable and energy-efficiency projects that were reducing
greenhouse gas emissions by more than 3 million metric tons. </p>
<p>In addition, Chevron executives frequently touted the
division''s clean-energy work in speeches and in testimony (PDF)
before Congress. </p>
<p>Last month, though, Chevron confirmed that it had suspended
two solar projects at a refinery in Hawaii, which would have
spanned about 20 acres and reduced carbon dioxide emissions by
about 5,000 tons apiece. </p>
<p>And earlier this year, the company dismantled a renewable
power group whose mission was to launch large, profitable
clean-energy projects, Bloomberg Businessweek reported in May.
The group had almost doubled its internal profit targets in 2013,
while helping to launch solar and geothermal projects capable of
powering tens of thousands of homes.</p>
<p></p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hugh Son, Michael J. Moore and Yalman Onaran" date="Sep 02, 2014  4:08 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-02/jpmorgan-operating-risk-rises-with-past-seen-as-prologue.html"><headline>JPMorgan Operating Risk Rises With Past Seen as Prologue</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon has pledged billions of dollars to improve compliance and cybersecurity. That''s not stopping regulators from treating the bank as if it were riskier than ever. </p> <p>The firm''s operational risk-weighted assets, a measure devised by regulators that determines how much capital the bank needs to hold against potential losses from human error, external threats, fraud and litigation, rose 6.7 percent in the second quarter to $400 billion, according to an August filing. Regulators can point to $23 billion of legal settlements last year and a cyber-attack discovered last month as they push JPMorgan to boost its buffer against unforeseen losses. </p> <p>Wall Street firms including Citigroup Inc. (C) and Bank of America Corp. (BAC) that together racked up more than $100 billion in post-financial crisis legal costs are facing similar pressures. At JPMorgan, the largest U.S. bank, that means more than $35 billion that can''t be used for dividends or buybacks, prompting Dimon to call it stranded capital. </p> <p>Banks are saying, We''ve made huge investments in technology and compliance personnel and we aren''t getting credit for it,'' said Justin Fuller, a senior director at Fitch Ratings in Chicago. At the same time, the only verifiable data points are these huge litigation costs they''ve just had, and it''s hard to ignore those. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
Jamie Dimon, Chief Executive Officer of JPMorgan Chase  Co. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Nicholas Comfort" date="Sep 02, 2014  5:22 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-02/jpmorgan-sees-european-banks-rising-10-on-ecb-results.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sees European Banks Rising 10% on ECB Results</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Deutsche Bank AG (DBK) and Societe
Generale SA (GLE) are among lenders seen driving a 10 percent gain
among European banks by year-end as investor concerns over their
capital levels and legal bills ease, JPMorgan Chase  Co.
analysts said. </p>
<p>European bank shares, tracked by the benchmark Stoxx 600
Banks Index, will reverse their underperformance relative to the
broader market in recent months, the analysts including Kian Abouhossein wrote in an e-mailed report yesterday. The banks
index, down 3.2 percent in the six months through Sept. 1, today
rose 0.7 percent to 198.06 as of 11:15 a.m. in Frankfurt. </p>
<p>The European Central Bank is leading an unprecedented
regulatory scrutiny of the financial health of the region''s
biggest lenders as it prepares to assume their supervision, an
effort to restore confidence in the industry. European banks
have also faced investor concerns that fines and settlements
would erode capital after France''s BNP Paribas SA (BNP) paid a record
$8.97 billion penalty for breaking U.S. sanctions in July. </p>
<p>The ECB stress test should be a positive event, the
analysts wrote in the report. All 34 European banks JPMorgan
tested passed its own assessment, which used the same 5.5
percent minimum capital ratio the ECB will employ in the more
adverse of two stress test scenarios, they said. </p>
<p>The ECB is scheduled to release the results of its tests
and examination of the balance sheets of 128 euro area lenders
next month. Firms will have six months to raise equity to cover
any shortfalls identified in its balance sheet review or the
milder stress-test scenarios, and nine months to address
deficiencies resulting from the more-adverse scenario. </p>
<p>JPMorgan added Deutsche Bank, Germany''s biggest bank,
Societe Generale of France and Amsterdam-based ING Groep NV (INGA) to
its list of top picks, according to the report. The analysts
removed Caixabank SA (CABK) after the Barcelona-based lender rallied 21
percent this year, the analysts wrote. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Oliver Renick" date="Sep 03, 2014  4:56 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-03/mobileye-gains-as-morgan-stanley-says-shares-may-double.html"><headline>Mobileye Gains as Morgan Stanley Says Shares May Double</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Mobileye NV (MBLY), a maker of driver
assistance systems, climbed to a new high since going public
last month after Morgan Stanley said the company''s powerful
growth may lead the shares to double. </p>
<p>Mobileye jumped 9.2 percent to $46.97 at 4 p.m. in New
York, after gaining as much as 15 percent in intraday trading.
That''s the third-biggest increase on a closing basis since Aug.
1, when the stock surged 48 percent on its first day of trading. </p>
<p>The shares could reach $100 under the most optimistic
scenario, according to Morgan Stanley''s Ravi Shanker,
reiterating a similar prediction from a week ago. The New York-based bank was among those that led Jerusalem-based Mobileye''s
IPO. While Shanker has an overweight rating on the stock, the
equivalent of buy, his share-price target is $46 for the next 12
to 18 months. </p>
<p>The path to $100 does not involve heroic assumptions,
Shanker wrote in the report dated today. If MBLY can hold its
own and just retain its current position, let alone make further
inroads from here, the stock is likely to be closer to our $100
bull case. </p>
<p>To reach this level, Mobileye needs to hold its current
pricing and profitability, keep market share close to 80 percent
and see quicker-than-expected adoption of autonomous driving
programs in China, Shanker wrote. </p>
<h2>Earnings Report </h2>
<p>Some investors may be buying the stock ahead of the
company''s earnings report tomorrow, according to Jason Ader, an
analyst at William Blair  Co. Mobileye earned 5 cents a share
in the three months ended June, according to the average of
eight analyst estimates compiled by Bloomberg. On an annual
basis, the company is forecast to double its profit by next
year. </p>
<p>It''s a pretty unique story with high growth and high
profitability that distinguishes it from most of the tech
companies you see that are growing 60 to 100 percent and losing
money, Ader said via phone from Boston. It''s clearly a
momentum stock right now, it''s a darling. </p>
<p>Mobileye''s image-sensing technology stands apart from
competitors because it uses a single camera to capture and
display a vehicle''s surroundings, according to Ader. Other
vision-based driver assistance software that employ radar or
dual-camera systems have difficulty capturing stationary or far-away objects, he said. </p>
<p>Yonah Lloyd, chief communications officer at Mobileye, did
not immediately respond to an e-mail sent after working hours in
Israel. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lisa Abramowicz" date="Sep 03, 2014 12:09 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-03/morgan-stanley-brace-for-seven-years-of-bond-losses.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley: Brace for Seven Years of Bond Losses</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Here''s a grim forecast to consider:
It may be 2021 before you make any money on investment-grade
bonds again. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) Wealth Management''s Jonathan Mackay predicts
the securities will post annual returns of between 1 percent and
2 percent for the next seven years -- which means you''ll lose
money after accounting for inflation. That''s a big shift
considering the debt gained 8.7 percent annually on average in
the 30 years through 2012. </p>
<p>Investors should have a lower average allocation to bonds
than you would have in the previous cycle because they just
don''t provide the income and return, said Mackay, senior
market strategist at Morgan Stanley''s $2 trillion wealth
management unit. While central-bank stimulus is supporting bond
values, the collateral damage is going to be lower portfolio
returns. </p>
<p>The way to get around this is to buy higher-yielding
assets, he said. While higher-rated bonds have been
outperforming their riskier counterparts in 2014, that may be
poised to reverse. </p>
<p>What we''re suggesting is that you just have less of your
bond allocation in the perceived, or formerly perceived, safe
havens of bonds, Mackay said. </p>
<h2>Falling Yields </h2>
<p>About 45 percent of all government bonds are now yielding
less than 1 percent, according to a report yesterday by Bank of
America Corp. analysts led by Michael Hartnett. The Bank of
America Merrill Lynch Global Corporate Index has gained 6.5
percent this year, with yields on the notes plunging to 2.6
percent, within 0.17 percentage point of the record low set last
year. </p>
<p>Investors have already been plowing into junk-rated debt as
well as equities and less-traded assets like real estate and
private equity. </p>
<p>There''s also always the possibility of boosting leverage to
juice returns, which debt investors have been doing with credit
lines and credit-default swaps. </p>
<p>Outstanding bets on a credit-swaps index tied to North
American junk bonds have soared to the highest level since at
least 2011. Net wagers on the latest Markit CDX North America
High Yield Index rose to $34.4 billion as of Aug. 29, compared
with a peak of $29.1 billion on the last series in March,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<h2>Choosing Hubris </h2>
<p>All of this risk-taking has been paying off lately, as
credit investors largely shrug off escalating geopolitical
conflicts and with the speculative-grade default rate less than
half its long-term average. High-yield bonds globally are on
track to gain 8.9 percent this year, building on the 142.7
percent return during the previous five years, Bank of America
Merrill Lynch index data show. </p>
<p>Of course, not everyone''s as sanguine about just reaching
for more and more yield. Bank of America analysts recommended
yesterday that bond buyers be on the lookout for signs of
investor hubris, especially with the Federal Reserve set to
stop its monthly asset purchases. </p>
<p>But when the other option is losing money, as Morgan
Stanley''s Mackay suggests, it''s easy to understand why investors
might choose hubris. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alastair Marsh" date="Sep 03, 2014  9:59 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-03/jpmorgan-sees-ecb-buying-up-to-53-billion-of-asset-backed-bonds.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sees ECB Buying $53 Billion of Asset-Backed Bonds</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The European Central Bank will buy
as much as 40 billion euros ($53 billion) of asset-backed
securities as part of a program to stimulate the region''s
economy, according to JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) </p>
<p>The central bank will limit purchases to the new-issue
market over a three-year period and focus on securities with the
highest credit ratings, JPMorgan analysts led by Gareth Davies
wrote in a note. About 47 billion euros of asset-backed debt has
been sold in the region this year, according to data from the
New York-based bank. </p>
<p>The ECB is preparing to buy ABS as it strives to revive
lending to small-and medium-sized businesses that employ about
70 percent of the European Union''s private-sector workers. While
the region''s outstanding ABS market is as large as 1.2 trillion
euros, a purchase program of this magnitude would necessitate it
being expanded beyond SME-backed loans, the analysts said in the
note. </p>
<p>The purchase plan is important for a number of reasons,
but broadly because it puts downward pressure on the cost of
issuing ABS, and ultimately feeds into lower product margins on
real economy lending, Davies said by e-mail today. </p>
<p>The Frankfurt-based ECB has hired BlackRock Inc. (BLK) to provide
advice as it thrashes out the final design of its plan,
including how much, which assets, and what ranking of bonds it
will buy. </p>




Photographer: Martin Leissl/Bloomberg

<p>
ECB President Mario Draghi has been promoting securities backed by loans to SMEs in a bid to increase the supply of credit to Europe''s businesses. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Carla Main" date="Sep 03, 2014  7:31 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-03/jp-morgan-risk-citigroup-cantor-s-next-job-compliance.html"><headline>JP Morgan Risk, Citigroup, Cantor''s Next Job: Compliance</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) Chief Executive
Officer Jamie Dimon has pledged billions of dollars to improve
compliance and cybersecurity. That''s not stopping regulators
from treating the bank as if it were riskier than ever. </p>
<p>The firm''s operational risk-weighted assets, a measure
devised by regulators that determines how much capital the bank
needs to hold against potential losses from human error,
external threats, fraud and litigation, rose 6.7 percent in the
second quarter to $400 billion, according to an August filing.
Regulators can point to $23 billion of legal settlements last
year and a cyber-attack discovered last month as they push
JPMorgan to boost its buffer against unforeseen losses. </p>
<p>Wall Street firms including Citigroup Inc. and Bank of
America Corp. that together racked up more than $100 billion in
post-financial crisis legal costs are facing similar pressures.
At JPMorgan, the largest U.S. bank, that means more than $35
billion that can''t be used for dividends or buybacks, prompting
Dimon to call it stranded capital. </p>
<p>JPMorgan will spend an additional $2 billion from 2012
through this year on improving controls, with an annual $250
million on cybersecurity, Dimon said in April in his annual
shareholder letter. </p>
<h2>Courts </h2>
<h2>Hedge Fund Seeks Evidence from Citigroup Over Argentina Threats </h2>
<p>The U.S. judge overseeing a fight between Argentina and its
defaulted bondholders set a hearing for Sept. 10 on a hedge
fund''s subpoena for evidence that Citibank was threatened by the
South American nation. </p>
<p>Citibank''s parent, Citigroup Inc. (C), argued it might lose its
Argentine branch and face grave sanctions at the hands of
the Argentine government if a U.S. appeals court doesn''t allow
it to distribute money to Argentina''s restructured bondholders,
a move barred by U.S. District Judge Thomas Griesa in Manhattan,
unless defaulted debtholders are also paid. </p>
<p>The hedge fund NML Capital, a defaulted debtholder
controlled by billionaire Paul Singer, wants to compel the bank
to provide evidence of claims that Argentina threatened it with
punitive measures if it continues to comply with Griesa''s order. </p>
<p>NML said Citibank has presented no evidence of Argentina''s
threats other than a letter to the appeals court. </p>
<p>Danielle Romero-Apsilos, a spokeswoman for Citigroup,
didn''t immediately return a call seeking comment on the filing. </p>
<p>The case is NML Capital Ltd. v. Republic of Argentina, 08-cv-06978, U.S. District Court, Southern District of New York
(Manhattan). </p>
<h2>Interviews/Commentary </h2>
<h2>Almunia Says Samsung to Philips Fined for Chip Cartel </h2>
<p>European Competition Commissioner Joaquin Almunia talked
about the fines handed down to Samsung Electronics Co. (005930), Royal
Philips NV and Infineon Technologies AG for fixing the price of
chips used in mobile phones and bank cards. </p>
<p>For the video, click here. </p>
<h2>Countrywide''s Mozilo Says He''s Shocked by U.S. Lawsuit Plans </h2>
<p>Bloomberg''s Max Abelson recounted his conversation with
former Countrywide chief executive officer Angelo Mozilo as he
reacted to plans by the U.S. government to sue him in a civil
case over subprime loans. He spoke on Bloomberg
Surveillance. </p>
<p>For the video, click here. </p>
<h2>Comings and Goings </h2>
<h2>Ex-Republican Leader Cantor Gets Job at U.S. Investment Bank </h2>
<p>Former House Majority Leader Eric Cantor has taken a job at
the investment bank Moelis  Co. (MC) that will pay him at least $3.4
million, according to the company''s filings with the U.S.
Securities and Exchange Commission. </p>
<p>Cantor, 51, quit Congress effective Aug. 18 after losing
the Republican June primary in his congressional district near
Richmond, Virginia, to a Tea Party-backed newcomer, David Brat. </p>
<p>In seven terms in Congress, Cantor became a chief critic of
President Barack Obama, fighting such White House priorities as
the 2009 economic stimulus package and the 2010 health-care
overhaul. Moelis said that in his new role, Cantor, who fought
to lower taxes and unburden businesses from excessive
regulation, will provide strategic counsel to corporate and
institutional clients on key issues. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dana El Baltaji, Arif Sharif and Zahra Hankir" date="Sep 04, 2014  8:38 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-04/goldman-sachs-vehicle-hires-five-banks-to-sell-islamic-bonds.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Said to Hire Banks for Debut Islamic Bond Sale</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) is planning
its first foray into Islamic capital markets three years after
starting a sukuk program that it never used. </p>
<p>Five banks including the New York-based lender will manage
the dollar-denominated offering via JANY Sukuk Co., four people
with knowledge of the deal said. A benchmark-sized sale may
follow, they said, asking not to be identified as the plan is
private. Goldman Sachs in 2011 created a $2 billion program that
faced criticism from some Islamic advisers for not ensuring debt
would be traded at par value, as required by Shariah. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs is joining a growing number of issuers
seeking to tap demand among Muslim investors in an industry that
Ernst  Young LLP forecasts will double in the five years
through 2018 to $3.4 trillion. The U.K. became the first non-Muslim country to issue Islamic bonds in June with a sale that
lured bids for more than 10 times the amount offered. Luxembourg
and Hong Kong are also planning investor meetings for similar
offerings. </p>
<p>There''s so much pent up demand in the sukuk space,
Thomas Christie, the Dubai-based head of fixed income at
Prometheus Capital Finance Ltd., said by phone. Given the
controversy in the past, it would be interesting to see what
structure they''re going to use, how they''re going to use the
funds and how the Islamic community reacts to it. </p>
<h2>Previous Attempt </h2>
<p>The planned security will take the form of Sukuk al Wakala,
a Shariah-compliant structure in which one party entrusts
another to act on its behalf. Standard  Poor''s rated the issue
A-, the seventh-highest investment grade, the company said in an
e-mail today. </p>
<p>The lender established a sukuk program three years ago
based on a so-called commodity murabaha structure, or a cost
plus mark-up transaction, that was approved for listing on the
Irish Stock Exchange by the Central Bank of Ireland. Murabaha
certificates can only be bought and sold at par value because
they represent a future claim on the underlying assets. </p>
<p>The program, blessed by eight of the world''s top Islamic
scholars, became entangled in a debate on whether it met
Shariah-compliant guidelines and over lack of clarity on how
Goldman Sachs planned to use the funds it raised. </p>
<h2>Pent-Up Demand </h2>
<p>Goldman Sachs will hold investor meetings in the Middle
East on Sept. 10 and 11 and a so-called Regulation S
transaction, which exempts overseas offerings from registration
requirements under the SEC Securities Act of 1933, may follow,
the people said. A benchmark-sized sale usually raises at least
$500 million. </p>
<p>The notes would probably price tighter than Goldman
Sachs'' conventional bonds due to the pent-up demand in the
sukuk space, Christie of Prometheus said. The average yield on
debt that complies with Muslim tenets dropped 63 basis points
this year to 2.78 percent yesterday, the lowest since May,
according to the Deutsche Bank Sukuk Bond Index. </p>
<p>Islamic lenders will have 70 million customers by 2018, up
from 38 million last year, according to Ernst  Young forecasts.
Shariah-compliant banking assets will double in that period,
according to the advisory company. </p>
<h2>South Africa, Bangladesh </h2>
<p>South Africa last month picked banks for its debut sale of
Islamic notes, while Bangladesh and the Russian region of
Tatarstan are planning inaugural sales. In addition to itself,
Goldman Sachs hired Abu Dhabi Islamic Bank PJSC, National Bank
of Abu Dhabi PJSC, Emirates NBD Capital Ltd. and NCB Capital to
manage the offering, the people said today. </p>
<p>Demand for Islamic bonds is surging helped by ample
liquidity at banks. Al Hilal Bank PJSC, an Islamic lender owned
by the Abu Dhabi government, received about $5 billion in bids
for its $500 million sale of perpetual sukuk in June. </p>
<p>Clearly, this is a good time and the demand for sukuk is
still there, Apostolos Bantis, credit analyst at Commerzbank
AG in Dubai, said by phone. This does actually indicate that
the asset class of sukuk is expanding and diversifying. </p>
<p>JANY Sukuk will enter a murabaha agreement for 49 percent
of the issued amount and a wakala agreement for the remaining 51
percent with J. Aron  Co., a Goldman Sachs subsidiary,
according to SP. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lukanyo Mnyanda and Lucy Meakin" date="Sep 04, 2014  8:02 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-04/goldman-sees-severe-pound-selloff-on-scotland-vote-for-breakaway.html"><headline>Goldman Sees Severe Pound Selloff on Scots Breakaway Vote</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A win for Scottish nationalists seeking a breakaway from the U.K. may have severe consequences in the short term and spark a pound selloff, according to Goldman Sachs Group Inc. economist Kevin Daly. </p> <p>The uncertainty about whether Scotland will leave the sterling monetary union could create a crisis similar to the one that almost splintered the euro area, Daly said today in an interview with Anna Edwards on Bloomberg Television''s On The Move program in London. In the long run, there''s no reason to believe why Scotland couldn''t prosper as an independent country. Our concerns are predominantly about the short-to-medium term, but those concerns are pretty severe. </p> <p>As Scotland enters the final days of campaigning before the Sept. 18 plebiscite, the currency market is taking notice after a YouGov Plc poll for the Sept. 2 editions of the Times and Sun newspapers showed the pro-U.K. camp leading by six percentage points once undecided voters are stripped out, from being 14 points ahead in the last YouGov poll conducted on Aug. 12-15. </p> <p>Scotland''s Bid for Independence</p><p>After initially dismissing the referendum, investors realize that this is going to be disruptive in an economic sense if the Yes camp win, John Normand, head of foreign-exchange and international-rates strategy at JPMorgan Chase  Co., told Edwards and Mark Barton on the Countdown program. People realize increasingly that the undecided camp is big enough to swing this and that is why volatility is picking up, he said. </p> <h2>Volatility Surge </h2> <p>Implied one-month volatility in sterling against the dollar surged 23 percent after the survey was released, the most since 2008. Sterling has declined since then and today fell 0.2 percent to $1.6432 today, having reached $1.6440 yesterday, the weakest since Feb. 12. </p> <p>The question of whether a go-it-alone Scotland will be able to keep the pound in partnership with the remaining parts of the U.K. has dominated the independence debate with all the major parties in Westminster saying they would oppose it. Scottish First Minister Alex Salmond has argued they would change their view once negotiations began after a Yes vote and has said Scotland would refuse to pay its share of the U.K. national debt if they didn''t give in. </p> <p>The aftermath of a vote for separation will be absolutely chaotic, Andy Brough, executive director at Schroder Investment Management in London, said on Bloomberg Television. Companies will have to sit down and rational thinking will have to be made. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Adam Ewing and Cornelius Rahn" date="Sep 04, 2014  7:58 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-04/microsoft-announces-first-flagship-lumia-since-nokia-buy.html"><headline>Microsoft Shows First Lumia Phones Since Nokia Unit Deal</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) announced the Lumia
830, its first high-end smartphone since it bought Nokia Oyj (NOK1V)''s
devices unit for about 5.4 billion euros ($7.2 billion) in
April. </p>
<p>The device has a 5-inch display and a 10-megapixel camera,
will cost about 330 euros before taxes and subsidies and starts
shipping this month, the software giant said today at the annual
IFA consumer electronics show in Berlin. Microsoft also showed
the Lumia 730 and Lumia 735, which will cost 199 euros and 219
euros, respectively. </p>
<p>We''re bringing those flagship experiences to a more
affordable price segment, Chris Weber, head of mobile devices
sales at Microsoft, said at the conference. Apple can''t say
that and Samsung can''t say that. </p>
<p>Microsoft Chief Executive Officer Satya Nadella is
struggling to boost the market share of Windows Phone, which was
2.5 percent in the second quarter. Consumers are opting for
devices made by Apple Inc. or powered by Google Inc.''s Android
software, which together represent 96 percent of smartphones,
according to data from IDC. </p>
<p>Microsoft in July announced the biggest job cuts in its
history, planning to slash 18,000 positions as the company
integrates Nokia''s handset unit. </p>
<p>Microsoft shares have jumped 13 percent since the purchase
was completed on April 25, giving the Redmond, Washington-based
company a market value of $370 billion. Microsoft shares traded
at the equivalent of $45.03 at 1:27 p.m. in Frankfurt, compared
with the $44.96 close in New York yesterday. </p>
<p>Samsung Electronics Co. yesterday unveiled two new
smartphones and showed off a virtual-reality headset, developed
with Facebook Inc.''s Oculus unit, and a new smartwatch. Apple is
holding a Sept. 9 event, where the company is said to be
preparing to debut new iPhones and a wearable device, Bloomberg
News reported Aug. 28. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Greg Stohr" date="Sep 05, 2014  3:57 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-05/pfizer-joins-32-states-seeking-high-court-marriage-ruling.html"><headline>Pfizer Joins 32 States Seeking High Court Marriage Ruling</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Thirty prominent companies and 32
states urged the U.S. Supreme Court to rule on gay marriage,
adding to calls from both sides as the justices prepare in the
coming weeks to say whether they will intervene. </p>
<p>The companies include Deutsche Bank AG (DB), eBay Inc., Pfizer
Inc. (PFE), Target Corp. (TGT) and Viacom Inc. (VIA) In court papers filed this
week, they said inconsistent state marriage laws posed a human-resources problem. </p>
<p>The different laws force companies to affirm
discrimination we regard as injurious to our corporate missions
and contrary to non-discrimination laws and policies, the
group said in court papers. The businesses includes Bloomberg
LP, the parent of Bloomberg News. </p>
<p>Appeals in gay-marriage cases from Utah, Virginia and
Oklahoma are likely to be before the justices when they meet
Sept. 29 for a private conference in advance of the nine-month
term that starts the following week. Under its practices from
previous years, the court could act as quickly as Sept. 30. </p>
<p>The states weighing in are almost evenly divided in their
laws. Colorado is leading a group of 17 states that ban gay
marriage. That group said a Supreme Court ruling would stave
off the increasing burden of same-sex marriage litigation
against the states. </p>
<p>A second group of 15, led by Massachusetts, directly urged
the high court to declare same-sex marriage a constitutional
right. Denying same-sex couples access to marriage creates
second-class families, the group argued. </p>
<p>Proponents of gay marriage have won federal appeals court
victories in five states, with Indiana and Wisconsin joining the
list yesterday. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Sep 05, 2014 10:55 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-05/morgan-stanley-s-rise-will-slow-next-year-macquarie-says.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley''s Rise Will Slow Next Year, Macquarie Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS), the best-performing
stock among the largest Wall Street banks since the end of 2012,
will rise at a slower pace over the next year as the current
price anticipates the firm reaching its profitability goal, said
David Konrad, a Macquarie Group Ltd. analyst. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley dropped 1.9 percent, the most in a month, to
$34.04 at 10:37 a.m. in New York as Konrad cut his rating to
neutral from a buy recommendation he''d held since beginning his
coverage in June 2013. The shares have more than doubled in the
past two years, and climbed 11 percent this year through
yesterday, more than any of its four biggest U.S. investment
bank rivals. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer James Gorman has achieved success
with his strategy of relying more on wealth and asset management
and reducing the size of the firm''s fixed-income, currency and
commodities trading business, Konrad wrote. Still, the company
may be limited in its ability to return capital in dividends and
buybacks because of the need for regulatory approval and a
leverage ratio that lags behind peers, he said. </p>
<p>We believe the shares may take a pause until MS can
return significant capital to shareholders and improve the
returns of FICC, Konrad wrote, referring to the New York-based
company by its stock ticker. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
Morgan Stanley Chief Executive Officer James Gorman. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hugh Son and Michael Riley" date="Sep 05, 2014  1:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-05/jpmorgan-had-exodus-of-tech-talent-before-hacker-breach.html"><headline>JPMorgan Had Exodus of Tech Talent Before Hacker Breach</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>As hackers pierced JPMorgan Chase  Co.''s (JPM) defenses in June, the bank''s cybersecurity chief was just getting acquainted with his employer and its sprawling technology infrastructure. </p> <p>Greg Rattray, a former U.S. Air Force commander for information warfare, became JPMorgan''s head of information security that month after upheaval at the highest levels of the bank''s tech division. His predecessor, Anthony Belfiore, had resigned early this year to join at least five JPMorgan leaders at First Data Corp. In between, Anish Bhimani was acting security officer while holding at least one other tech role. </p> <p>It sucks that this happened at the beginning of Greg''s watch, but this is a legacy issue, said Tom Kellermann, chief cybersecurity officer at anti-virus software firm Trend Micro Inc. They had an acting person who was juggling way too much, with no one fully dedicated to the role for a bit of time. </p> <p>Related: Computers for Hire Send JPMorgan Data to Russia</p><p>JPMorgan, led by Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon, 58, has rushed to determine the scope of the assault and restore confidence in security at the biggest U.S. lender. While hackers targeted other banks'' systems, JPMorgan is the only bank said to have had gigabytes of data stolen, including information on customer accounts. </p>




Photographer: Ron Antonelli/Bloomberg

<p>
People stand inside the lobby of the JPMorgan Chase  Co. headquarters building in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bob Van Voris" date="Sep 08, 2014  4:04 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-08/microsoft-agrees-to-contempt-to-speed-e-mail-case-appeal.html"><headline>Microsoft Agrees to Contempt to Speed E-Mail Case Appeal</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), at its own request,
was found in contempt of a court order to comply with a U.S.
warrant for e-mails stored in a data center in Ireland, so that
it can promptly appeal the ruling. </p>
<p>U.S. District Judge Loretta Preska in Manhattan today
granted a joint request by Microsoft and the government to hold
the software maker in contempt. The judge imposed no further
sanctions and said the order permits the company to immediately
appeal her July 31 ruling that it has to produce e-mails of an
unidentified customer sought in a drug probe. </p>
<p>The judge in her July ruling rejected Microsoft''s argument
that the warrant,which requires the company to provide
investigators with the contents of the customer''s MSN.com Web-based e-mail, calls for an illegal search and seizure outside
the U.S. The nation in which the customer lives wasn''t
disclosed. </p>
<p>The government should be required to get the e-mails
through procedures dictated by a law-enforcement treaty between
the U.S. and Ireland, Microsoft attorney E. Joshua Rosenkranz
argued. The Redmond, Washington-based company is the world''s
largest maker of computer software. </p>
<p>Lawyers for both sides argued over the reach of the Stored
Communications Act, or SCA, which allows law enforcement agents
to obtain information through subpoenas, court orders or
warrants, depending on the records sought. </p>
<p>Microsoft''s general counsel, Brad Smith, said in a
statement after the July hearing that the company would appeal
promptly and continue to advocate that people''s e-mail
deserves strong privacy protection in the U.S. and around the
world. </p>
<p>The case is In the Matter of a Warrant to Search a Certain
E-Mail Account Controlled and Maintained by Microsoft Corp., 13-mj-02814, U.S. District Court, Southern District of New York
(Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Sep 08, 2014  2:14 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-08/goldman-sachs-earnings-to-get-boost-from-mobileye-stake.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Earnings to Get Boost From Mobileye Stake</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)''s third-quarter earnings stand to get a boost from a 2007 investment in an automated-driving technology company that''s more than doubled since a July initial public offering. </p> <p>The bank owned 17.5 percent of Jerusalem-based Mobileye NV (MBLY), mostly through its Goldman Sachs Investment Partners hedge fund, before it helped take the firm public in July, according to filings related to the IPO. The shares priced at $25, above the initial range of $17 to $19, and rose as high as $53.91 today. That advance may lead to a third-quarter gain for New York-based Goldman Sachs of more than $200 million, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p> <p>While calm markets have suppressed Goldman Sachs''s trading business, they have been a boon to investments the firm makes with its own money. The investing and lending unit earned the most profit of Goldman Sachs''s four major business segments in the 12 months ended in June, and gains in companies that went public drove better-than-expected earnings last quarter. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs has successfully established a strategy that should allow the firm to continue in the principal-investing business in the coming years, Brad Hintz, a Sanford C. Bernstein  Co. analyst, said in a July note. The wisdom of that strategy is clear, Hintz said, as such gains in the second quarter once again provided an unanticipated boost to performance. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs invested $100 million in Mobileye in 2007, the first year the company had its driver-assistance EyeQ chip and algorithms put in new cars. The firm hasn''t said whether it added to that investment. Mobileye''s image-sensing technology uses a single camera to capture and display a vehicle''s surroundings, and anticipates potential collisions, according to the company. </p> <h2>Honda, Tesla </h2> <p>Mobileye, whose customers include Honda Motor Co. (7267) and luxury electric-carmaker Tesla Motors Inc., has leaped from a $1.5 billion valuation in July 2013 to a market capitalization of $10.8 billion today. Its $1 billion IPO on July 31 was the biggest in the U.S. by an Israeli company. </p> <p>The investment shows the potential of Goldman Sachs''s strategy of serving as adviser and principal with key clients. The bank generated about $18 million from its role as lead underwriter of Mobileye''s IPO, according to a regulatory filing, and advised the company last year when it received investments from firms including BlackRock Inc. (BLK) </p> <p>Michael DuVally, a spokesman for the company, declined to comment on the firm''s holdings. </p> <p>The investing and lending unit includes direct investments in debt and equity, stakes in private equity and hedge funds, and loans to corporate and individual clients. The unit earned $4.26 billion before taxes in the 12 months ended in June, or 37 percent of the firm''s total, on $7.14 billion in revenue. </p> <h2>Equity Gains </h2> <p>Gains from equity investments drove better-than-expected earnings last quarter and in the final three months of 2013. Chief Financial Officer Harvey Schwartz said in July that two-thirds of the $1.25 billion in equity gains for the second quarter came from companies that went public or experienced an event that resulted in a new valuation. </p> <p>A $200 million gain would represent about a quarter of equity investment revenue for the average of the past 10 quarters. The firm had $18 billion of investments in private equity and $4.33 billion in public stock as of June 30. </p> <p>Analysts including Citigroup Inc.''s Keith Horowitz have said that shareholders give Goldman Sachs less credit for investing and lending gains because they''re seen as volatile and difficult to predict. Schwartz has said the activities are core competencies of the firm. </p> <h2>ELQ Investors </h2> <p>Eighty-six percent of Goldman Sachs''s stake in Mobileye before the IPO was held by Goldman Sachs Investment Partners, a hedge fund that includes client money and the bank''s own capital. The other 14 percent was a principal investment held through a subsidiary named ELQ Investors II Ltd. </p> <p>ELQ sold $36 million of its stake in the IPO, leaving it with 1.7 percent of Mobileye''s shares. The remaining stake would be worth $176 million at the Sept. 5 closing price if ELQ didn''t sell more shares after the IPO. GSIP sold $105 million of Mobileye stock in the IPO, leaving it with 12.3 percent of the company, which would be worth $1.3 billion. </p> <p>The third-quarter gain for Goldman Sachs will depend on a number of factors, including how Mobileye''s stock trades in September and whether ELQ and GSIP maintain their post-IPO stakes. </p> <p>The shares gained as much as 7.9 percent today, after General Motors Co. said it would introduce a Cadillac model in two years that uses automated-driving technology. Detroit-based GM didn''t name potential technology suppliers. </p> <h2>Mobileye Valuation </h2> <p>Goldman Sachs, which marks its investments to the current market price, hasn''t disclosed at what price it valued Mobileye on June 30. If it marked at $18, the midpoint of the original IPO range, ELQ would currently have a gain of $122 million. GSIP would have a $842 million gain, and Goldman Sachs would receive some cut of that as an investor in the fund. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs''s own money accounted for about 35 percent of the $7.5 billion in the fund in October 2009, according to marketing documents at the time. Since then, the assets have shrunk and Goldman Sachs has pulled money from hedge funds to eventually comply with the Volcker Rule, which sets a 3 percent limit for how much of a fund can be a bank''s own capital. </p> <p>The fund, which is managed by Kenneth Eberts, Raanan Agus and Nick Advani, had about $5 billion in assets at the end of June, the Wall Street Journal reported last month. DuVally declined to say how much of the fund is the bank''s own money. </p> <h2>Volcker Rule </h2> <p>Part of the unpredictability of investing and lending stems from Goldman''s need to exit $12 billion of the $14 billion in fund investments it had at the end of 2013 to comply with the Volcker Rule, Hintz wrote in June. The bank has said it will make those sales at a pace that won''t hurt other investors in the funds. </p> <p>Gains like the one from GSIP''s stake in Mobileye may provide an incentive for Goldman Sachs to take its time in redeeming its capital. Mobileye has jumped more than 35 percent since the start of trading on Aug. 26. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs''s own research analyst, Alexander Duval, issued his first recommendation of the stock that day. He rated the shares neutral. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joseph Ciolli" date="Sep 08, 2014 11:42 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-08/goldman-sachs-says-buy-global-stocks-after-ecb-s-stimulus.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Says Buy Global Stocks After ECB''s Stimulus</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The European Central Bank''s decision
to boost stimulus measures was enough to make Goldman Sachs
Group Inc. change its mind about the short-term fate of the
global equity market. </p>
<p>The bank raised its three-month rating on stocks to
overweight, the equivalent of buy, according to a report from
its portfolio strategy group. Higher bond yields pose less of an
imminent threat to equities following the ECB''s decision last
week to unexpectedly lower key interest rates and implement an
asset-buying plan, the firm said. </p>
<p>The upgrade is a reversal of a call made by Goldman Sachs
on July 26, when the firm cut its three-month rating on stocks
to neutral amid expectations that government bond yields would
increase. The bank maintained its 12-month overweight rating for
stocks. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs sees lower risk from bonds following the
ECB decision, analysts led by chief global equity strategist
Peter Oppenheimer wrote in a Sept. 5 client note. The net
effect of the policy action from here will be positive for
equity markets, they said. </p>
<p>The MSCI All-Country World Index has rebounded 3.6 percent
over the last month since falling to an 11-week low on Aug. 7.
The gauge declined 0.4 percent at 10:39 a.m. in New York. </p>
<p>The global equity measure climbed 0.2 percent last week as
the ECB reduced its three main interest rates by 10 basis
points, lowering the benchmark rate to 0.05 percent and the
deposit rate to minus 0.2 percent. ECB President Mario Draghi
said the central bank will announce details of an asset-backed
securities program after its October rate-setting meeting. </p>
<p>The Stoxx Europe 600 Index gained 1.1 percent on the day of
the Sept. 4 announcement as two-year note yields fell below zero
in eight countries. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs isn''t alone in getting more bullish on
equities. Morgan Stanley chief U.S. equity strategist Adam Parker announced today an increase in the firm''s 12-month SP
500 forecast to 2,125. Meanwhile, Deutsche Bank AG strategist
David Bianco increased his year-end SP 500 target to 2,050 from
1,850 and his 2015 projection to 2,150. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael P. Regan" date="Sep 08, 2014 10:39 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-08/morgan-stanley-channels-weird-al-to-raise-stock-forecast.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Channels Weird Al to Raise Stock Forecast</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Like many of us who''ve been in the
vicinity of an FM radio or Jersey Shore club in the past month,
the strategists at Morgan Stanley have Meghan Trainor''s song
All About That Bass stuck in their heads. </p>
<p>Unlike the rest of us, however, Adam Parker and company
managed to re-interpret the hit into a reason to be bullish
about U.S. stocks. In a report that reads as if Weird Al
Yankovic had taken a weird career turn and become a market
strategist, Morgan Stanley''s All About That Base (No
Trouble) note announced an increase in the firm''s 12-month
forecast for the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index (SPX) to 2,125. </p>
<p>The base case in Morgan Stanley''s view is earnings
growth of 7 percent in 2014 and 2015 and the low probability of
a bear case that would result in flat profits this year and
only a 2 percent increase next year. Hence the No Trouble
part of the title, playing off the no treble lyrics of the
song. </p>
<p>It wasn''t just the song title that caught the strategists''
attention. Here are the other lyrics that spurred the
imagination of Weird Adam Parker and crew: </p>
<h2>Small Caps </h2>
<p>*Momma told me not to worry about my size. The
strategists apply this piece of advice to market capitalization,
saying small-cap stocks are poised to do better than larger
companies between now and the end of the year. This would follow
some serious underperformance: The Russell 2000 Index (RTY) was up 0.6
percent in 2014 through last week, compared with an 8.6 percent
gain in the SP 500. The main reason, according to the report,
is the potential for greater profit-margin expansion among
smaller firms. </p>
<p>*All the right junk in all the right places. That right
place, apparently, is not in your portfolio right now, in Morgan
Stanley''s view. Instead, they recommend these high quality
small-cap stocks: Valmont Industries Inc., AmTrust Financial
Services Inc., Meredith Corp., UniFirst Corp., Texas Roadhouse
Inc. and Chemed Corp. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s not the only firm raising its forecast
today. Deutsche Bank AG strategist David Bianco increased his
year-end SP 500 target to 2,050 from 1,850 and his 2015
projection to 2,150. That leaves Wells Fargo  Co.''s Gina Martin-Adams alone at the bottom rung of the strategist table
with an 1,850 forecast for the end of 2014, which would require
a 7.7 percent slide from last week''s close. </p>
<p>Anyway, All About That Bass is currently No. 2 on
Billboard''s Hot 100 chart, right behind Taylor Swift''s Shake
It Off. Come to think of it, that one has lyrics applicable to
this bull market too: The players gonna play, play, play,
play, play. And the haters gonna hate, hate, hate, hate, hate. </p>
<p>The best the bears can do is probably No. 12, Ariana
Grande''s Problem in which guest rapper Iggy Azalea warns:
Smart money betting I''ll be better off without you. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Simon Kennedy" date="Sep 08, 2014  6:54 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-08/morgan-stanley-sees-decade-long-expansion-on-easy-money.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Sees Decade-Long Expansion on Easy Money</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Get set for one of the longest global economic expansions on record. </p> <p>That''s the view from Morgan Stanley''s chief international economist, Joachim Fels. He sees recovery from the great recession potentially lasting as long as a decade thanks in part to loose money. He issued a contrarian call yesterday that some of the world''s central banks will keep monetary policy easier for longer than many are betting. </p> <p>While the expansion is already five years old, it could easily extend another five, Fels wrote. </p> <p>The bad news is built into the forecast: Fels says weak growth and inflation are forcing policy makers to stand pat or consider even more stimulus. He cut his forecast for world growth this year to 3.1 percent from his 3.2 percent of June. He expects 3.5 percent in 2015 and 3.8 percent in 2016. </p> <p>Compared to earlier expansions, growth is decidedly sub-par and expected to remain so despite the projected pick-up, but then again this could help to make it one of the longest economic expansions on record, said Fels. The glass is half full. </p> <p>The sustained stimulus -- six years since the collapse of Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. slammed the world into recession - - is one of three reasons Fels reckons the subsequent period of growth is poised to be a record-breaker. The others are that the world is out of synch so economies aren''t at risk of overheating at the same time and that slack remains worldwide with inflation below where many central banks would like it to be. </p>




Photographer: Martin Leissl/Bloomberg

<p>
Morgan Stanley''s chief international economist Joachim Fels sees a 40 percent chance President Mario Draghi''s European Central Bank will buy government bonds. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Daria Solovieva and Samuel Potter" date="Sep 08, 2014  5:58 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-08/goldman-sukuk-lures-mideast-s-top-fund-manager-mashreq.html"><headline>Goldman Sukuk Lures Mideast''s Top Fund Manager: Islamic Finance</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) will
probably succeed in its latest attempt to sell sukuk as
investors clamor for Islamic bonds, according to the manager of
the Middle East and Africa''s best performing sukuk fund. </p>
<p>Buyers have to look at different opportunities with
demand outpacing supply, according to Abdul Kadir Hussain, who
oversees about $700 million as the chief executive officer of
Mashreq Capital DIFC Ltd. Goldman Sachs will meet investors in
the region this week before potentially selling a dollar-denominated, benchmark-sized issue through its unit JANY Sukuk
Co., people with knowledge of the deal said last week. </p>
<p>The New York-based lender''s first foray into the Islamic
capital markets three years ago ended without a sale amid
criticism from scholars about the structure of its sukuk program
and the use of funds raised. This time the planned security will
be a Sukuk al Wakala, where one party entrusts another to act on
its behalf. </p>
<p>We''ll definitely look at it, Hussain said in a phone
interview from Dubai yesterday. The structure was an issue
last time and there were a lot of other issuers in the
market, he said. Now the market is a lot tighter and there
is more capital. </p>
<p>Investors bid for 10-times the 200 million pounds ($327
million) that the U.K. sold in its debut offering in June. </p>
<h2>Best Funds </h2>
<p>Mashreq''s Capital DA01 and Al-Islami Income Fund are the
two best performing Islamic fixed-income funds in the Middle
East and Africa this year among 19 tracked by Bloomberg. They''ve
returned 7.7 percent and 6 percent respectively, compared with
5.6 percent for third placed Al Hilal Bank''s Global Sukuk Fund,
the data show. </p>
<p>Like the U.K. issue, the Goldman Sachs deal is a
broadening of the sukuk market issuer base, and like that issue
this deal isn''t about the pricing or the valuation, Hussain
said. It''s about the signal that it sends. </p>
<p>Average global sukuk yields declined 64 basis points this
year to 2.78 percent last week, according to an index from
Deutsche Bank AG. That compares with a 61 basis-point decline to
5.08 percent in average yields for emerging-market corporate
debt tracked by JPMorgan Chase  Co. indexes. </p>
<h2>Remaining Shy </h2>
<p>Goldman Sachs established a $2 billion program in 2011
based on a so-called commodity murabaha structure, or a cost
plus mark-up transaction. The program, blessed by eight of the
world''s top Islamic scholars, became entangled in a debate on
whether it met Shariah-compliant guidelines because it didn''t
ensure debt was traded at par, and it didn''t clarify how it
planned to use the funds raised. </p>
<p>This time Goldman Sachs along with Abu Dhabi Islamic Bank
PJSC, National Bank of Abu Dhabi PJSC, Emirates NBD Capital Ltd.
and NCB Capital will manage the new offering, the people said.
It plans to meet investors in the Middle East for two days
starting Sept. 10. </p>
<p>If the investors conclude that Goldman Sachs is going to
take this money into their books and use it to finance their
conventional activities, then the investors are going to remain
a little bit shy, Harris Irfan, managing director at European
Islamic Investment Bank, said by phone from London yesterday,
noting the new structure has solved the par-value obstacle, but
not issues with transparency. I do hope they will be more
transparent on the flow of money, he said. </p>
<h2>Main Critic </h2>
<p>Still, the presence of ADIB on the deal is very
positive as it was one of the main critics of Goldman Sachs''
earlier plans, Irfan said. The Shariah boards of ADIB and EIIB
share one scholar, according to the lenders'' websites. ADIB''s
outsourced public relations company didn''t answer e-mailed
questions yesterday, and Sophie Ramsay, spokeswoman for Goldman
Sachs in London, declined to comment by telephone. </p>
<p>About $72 billion of sukuk have been sold globally in the
year through yesterday, compared with $80 billion in the same
period in 2013, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Islamic finance is a growing market both in terms of
issuers and investors, Hussain said. Goldman Sachs clearly
has decided that they want to play a role in this market both as
an issuer and I am sure also as an arranger and adviser. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hugh Son" date="Sep 09, 2014  4:14 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-09/jpmorgan-hires-goldman-s-robert-kimmel-for-energy-group.html"><headline>JPMorgan Hires Goldman''s Robert Kimmel for Energy Group</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the biggest
U.S. bank, hired Goldman Sachs Group Inc. investment banker
Robert Kimmel as a managing director in the energy group. </p>
<p>Kimmel will remain in Houston, where he''ll be responsible
for covering oil and gas clients, Jay Horine, head of JPMorgan''s
power and utility group, said last week in an employee memo
obtained today by Bloomberg. Kimmel, who starts at New York-based JPMorgan in November, became a managing director at
Goldman Sachs at the start of this year. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Sep 09, 2014  3:37 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-09/morgan-stanley-will-cut-money-losing-fixed-income-assets.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Will Cut Money-Losing Fixed-Income Assets</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS), which has pledged to
shrink its fixed-income trading unit, said it can cut $25
billion of risk-weighted assets that are losing money in that
business even after it reaches its size target. </p>
<p>The bank won''t hit a brick wall once it reduces risk-weighted assets to $180 billion from the $192 billion it had at
the end of June, Chief Financial Officer Ruth Porat said today
at an investor conference in New York. The firm will let the $25
billion of RWAs roll off and may replace them with other assets
that earn a return of more than 10 percent, she said. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley is seeking to boost the return on equity in
its fixed-income trading business as the firm''s profitability
trails competitors. While Chief Executive Officer James Gorman,
56, has cut the amount of capital used by the fixed-income unit
by about half over the past three years, the firm''s ROE was
about 8 percent in the first half, below his goal of 10 percent. </p>
<p>The $25 billion of risk-weighted assets are primarily
structured-credit products and long-dated uncollateralized
derivatives, Porat said. The reduction will mostly come from
passive roll downs and the offsetting growth may be in corporate
credit and securitized-products trading, she said. </p>
<p>We have a number of franchises within fixed income where
there is an opportunity to continue to place capital and support
client activity where we''re already generating an attractive
return, Porat said. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley is reducing its balance sheet in interest
rates and currency trading, and reshaping its commodities
business to look more like it did in the 1990s, after those
units produced returns on equity of less than 5 percent last
year, Porat said. The firm''s credit and securitized-products
divisions each produced ROEs of more than 15 percent, she said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hugh Son" date="Sep 09, 2014  3:06 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-09/jpmorgan-ceo-says-greener-pastures-in-trading-possible.html"><headline>JPMorgan CEO Says Greener Pastures'' in Trading Possible</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Record low volatility across equity
and debt markets could ease next year, boosting Wall Street
firms'' trading operations, JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) Chief Financial
Officer Marianne Lake said. </p>
<p>The unusually calm markets and low client activity that
caused the worst first half in trading since the financial
crisis will probably continue through the middle of 2015, Lake
said today at a conference in New York. </p>
<p>It may be a tale of two cities where the first half looks
a little bit more like a continuation of some the things we''d
been seeing this year, but there may be greener pastures in the
second half, Lake said. When things change, they can change
very, very quickly, so we want to be positioned for that. </p>
<p>JPMorgan''s corporate and investment bank, run by Daniel Pinto, posted a 12 percent revenue drop to $17.6 billion in the
first six months of 2014. Firms may have to wait until 2016
before markets significantly improve, Pinto said in May. </p>
<p>JPMorgan will benefit from cost-cutting programs in retail
and institutional units and more finality on rules governing
capital at the biggest banks, Lake said today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Justina Lee" date="Sep 09, 2014 12:01 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-09/goldman-leads-wall-street-tapping-taiwan-insurer-cashpile.html"><headline>Goldman Leads Wall Street Tapping Taiwan Insurer Cashpile</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Wall Street banks including Goldman
Sachs Group Inc. and Citigroup Inc. are rushing to issue U.S.
dollar bonds in Taiwan after a rule change unlocked $586 billion
of funds held by the island''s insurance companies. </p>
<p>Goldman sold $974 million of 30-year notes last month in
the largest such issuance on the island, leading $7.3 billion in
greenback debt offers this year, versus zero a year earlier.
J.P. Morgan Securities LLC estimates U.S. issuers can obtain
lower costs than they would at home, after lawmakers in May
excluded locally issued foreign-currency bonds from a 45 percent
cap on the amount insurance firms can invest in overseas assets. </p>
<p>Taiwanese insurers'' yearly premium income has more than
doubled in the past decade as China''s export-manufacturing boom
boosted the island''s wealth. Their hunt for fixed-income
investments has cut the 10-year sovereign yield 116 basis points
in the past 10 years to 1.71 percent, the 13th-lowest globally,
compared with 2.49 percent in the U.S. </p>
<p>With Taiwan''s very low benchmark-rate environment, a lot
of domestic-currency investments have low yields, said Godwin Chang, head of Taiwan at Societe Generale AG, which sold $1.21
billion of bonds in the territory this year. Life insurers are
better off having more foreign-currency investments. </p>
<h2>Negative Spread </h2>
<p>The central bank cut its policy rate to a record low 1.25
percent in 2009 and maintained it at 1.875 percent in the past
13 quarters. As domestic rates fell, life insurance firms
boosted holdings of foreign assets to 44 percent as of June 30
from 38 percent at the end of 2011, according to the Taiwan
Insurance Institute. </p>
<p>The insurance industry''s 3.8 percent weighted average
liability cost was significantly higher than its recurring
investment yield of 2.8 percent in 2013, according to a June
presentation by the financial regulator. </p>
<p>Goldman issued its zero-coupon, 30-year bonds at a price to
yield 4.96 percent last week. Morgan Stanley''s notes due 2044
paid a coupon of 4.7 percent and Citigroup''s similar-maturity,
zero-coupon debt was sold at 4.88 percent. All of the dollar
notes sold on the island since May''s amendment are callable by
the issuer and mature in 20 or 30 years, while 74 percent pay
zero coupon, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. Foreign-currency notes issued in Taiwan are called Formosa bonds. </p>
<p>Callable notes are popular among insurers, which can demand
higher yields to boost returns, J.P. Morgan strategists led by
Joshua Younger wrote in an Aug. 22 note. </p>
<p>Because they are considered domestic investments from a
regulatory perspective, Formosa bonds are generally compared
against Taiwan dollar-denominated fixed-income products, the
strategists wrote. With Taiwan dollar rates quite low by
comparison, yield-sensitive investors are likely to lower their
return targets for U.S. dollar callable Formosa bonds relative
to those registered overseas. </p>
<h2>Bond Sales </h2>
<p>The May 20 amendment also spurred issuances in yuan bonds,
with lenders such as Agricultural Bank of China Ltd. and Bank of
China Ltd. selling 9.3 billion yuan ($1.5 billion) of debt in
Taiwan since then, compared with 1.5 billion yuan in the first
four months of 2014. </p>
<p>Local insurers'' total annual premium income grew an average
8 percent in each of the last 10 years to NT$2.7 trillion ($90
billion) in 2013 from NT$1.2 trillion in 2003, according to
Financial Supervisory Commission data. Premiums collected added
up to 17.6 percent of gross domestic product in 2013, the
world''s highest penetration rate, a Swiss Re Ltd. report shows. </p>
<h2>Insurer Interest </h2>
<p>For insurers whose investments abroad haven''t yet neared
the 45 percent limit, the locally issued foreign-currency bonds
are not the most attractive. Cathay Life Insurance Co. (2882), the
largest in the industry with NT$4.3 trillion of assets, has
bought very few of the foreign-currency notes as they offer
rates lower than similar securities overseas, executive vice
president Joseph Wang said at an Aug. 29 briefing. </p>
<p>Other companies have been more enthusiastic. Shinkong
Insurance Co. (2850) has spent NT$42.8 billion on locally issued
foreign debt and plans to buy more to boost returns, according
to an Aug. 28 presentation. Fubon Life Insurance Co. aims to
increase its holdings to NT$100 billion within a year, the
Economic Daily News reported on Aug. 22. </p>
<p>All of the dollar debt sold in Taiwan since May''s rule
change has been bought by the insurance industry, according to
Mark Liu, Taipei-based head of global markets at Societe
Generale. The French bank is speaking with European companies
both in and outside the financial sector regarding bond
issuances in Taiwan, Chang said. </p>
<h2>Expectations Tempered </h2>
<p>This may be a good time to sell debt as borrowing costs
will probably rise. Eight of 18 analysts in a Bloomberg poll
expect Taiwan to raise its policy rate at least once by the end
of this year. The island''s economy is showing signs of a
recovery this year. Data yesterday showed exports grew 9.6
percent in August, the most in 20 months. Sixty-six percent of
Taiwan''s shipments went to China, which this week posted a
record trade surplus for August. </p>
<p>In the U.S., 62 of 74 economists in another survey see a
Federal Reserve interest-rate increase by the third quarter of
next year. </p>
<p>Investors have already tempered their expectations for a
rate increase, according to Cosmas Lu, chief executive officer
at the Taipei branch of Barclays Plc, which lists its $600
million of 30-year bonds on the bond exchange GreTai Securities
Market today. Benchmark 10-year Treasury yields have declined 54
basis points in 2014 as Fed Chair Janet Yellen signaled the
monetary authority''s commitment to low borrowing costs amid
mixed U.S. economic data. </p>
<p>Taiwan''s investors have been pretty quiet in the first
half of the year, waiting for interest rates to rise, which
didn''t happen, Lu said in an Aug. 27 phone interview. So
they''re very cash-rich and they realize they can''t wait forever.
There''s definitely very big demand from investors. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Mark Milian" date="Sep 10, 2014  9:03 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-10/mobile-payments-forecast-hazy-with-a-chance-of-apple.html"><headline>Mobile Payments Forecast: Hazy With a Chance of Apple</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Analysts thought they had a pretty good idea about what the mobile payments industry would look like over the next few years. And then Apple came along.</p><p>Tim Cook stepped on stage yesterday in Cupertino, California, and with the wave of an oversized iPhone, the Apple CEO established a mobile-payments mechanism that average people may actually use. Apple fans are buzzing. Retailers, banks and credit card companies are taking it very seriously.</p><p>The timing of Apple Pay is impeccable. The U.S. is undergoing a shift to a different credit card technology that''s common in the rest of the developed world. Americans will be issued new "chip cards" that are designed to reduce fraud. Stores will be asked to upgrade their payment terminals by October 2015 or face higher transaction fees. The chips are different from the tap-to-pay components found in the iPhone and other smartphones, but if retailers are buying new point-of-sale equipment anyway, they might as well get a setup that supports mobile payments. Or so the thinking goes.</p><p>The switch had already been factored into analyst projections for mobile payments growth. But analysts are less confident to say what kind of impact Apple will have on it. This is what the U.S. market looked like, dating back to 2012 and forecasting out to 2018, according to research firm EMarketer.</p>
<p></p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sabrina Willmer" date="Sep 10, 2014 11:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-10/goldman-said-to-lead-350-million-buyout-of-fund-holdings.html"><headline>Goldman Said to Lead $350 Million Buyout of Fund Holdings</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)''s asset-management arm is the lead investor in a transaction to purchase stakes in two older distressed-debt funds overseen by a former unit of Carlyle Group LP''s TCW Group Inc., two people with knowledge of the deal said. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs Asset Management agreed to lead a syndicate that will buy stakes from investors in 2002 and 2005 funds run by Crescent Capital Group LP, which separated from TCW in 2011, said the people, who asked not to be identified because the information is private. The deal size would be about $350 million, including net asset value and new investment capital. </p> <p>Crescent Capital, the Los Angeles-based firm headed by co-founders Mark Attanasio and Jean-Marc Chapus, hired UBS AG to run the sales process, which would offer its investors a way to exit their holdings, the people said. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs''s asset-management arm, which oversees $935 billion, is deploying capital in a competitive secondary market where deal volume is expected to exceed $30 billion this year as buyers bid up prices to post-crisis highs, according to a July report from Dallas-based investment bank Cogent Partners. Goldman Sachs bid 94.8 percent of net asset value for stakes in the 2002 fund in August, according to memo on the Fresno County Employees'' Retirement Association website. </p> <p>Andrea Raphael, a spokeswoman at New York-based Goldman Sachs, declined to comment on the deal, as did Bill Mendel, a spokesman for Crescent Capital with Mendel Communications and Megan Stinson, a spokeswoman for UBS. </p> <h2>Fresh Capital </h2> <p>Several private-equity firms have sought to restructure older funds to gather fresh capital or secure time to sell investments in recent years. Chicago-based Lake Capital Partners LP, after deciding against raising another buyout fund more than a decade ago, was considering allowing clients to sell their stakes in its 2002 pool, two people briefed on the matter said in July. Diamond Castle Holdings LLC, the New York-based firm started by executives from Credit Suisse Group AG, and Boston-based J.W. Childs Associates LP have explored similar deals. </p> <p>Crescent Capital is letting investors exit TCW Shared Opportunity Fund IV, a $250 million pool nearing the end of its life. Crescent would manage the fund on Goldman''s behalf while it sells the remaining investments. </p> <p>Investors agreed to extend the term of the fund, originally scheduled to expire in December 2010, until the end of this year, according to the Fresno County memo. </p> <p>California''s Fresno County committed $15 million to the 2002 fund, which was producing a 6.5 percent net internal rate of return as of June 30, another memo shows. </p> <h2>Crescent Capital </h2> <p>Crescent Capital raised its last distressed-focused fund almost a decade ago. TCW Shared Opportunity Fund V, which gathered about $525 million in 2005, has backed Banc of California Inc. and First PacTrust Bancorp Inc. </p> <p>The private-equity firm, which invests in corporate debt securities, managed about $15 billion in commitments and capital as of Dec. 31, according to its website. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs Asset Management, which oversees $935 billion, invests in fixed income, money markets, public equity, commodities, hedge funds, private equity and real estate. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jasmine Ng" date="Sep 10, 2014  7:25 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-10/goldman-calls-end-to-iron-age-after-dramatic-drop-in-ore-price.html"><headline>Goldman Calls End to Iron Age After Dramatic'' Drop in Ore Price</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Iron ore declined sooner than
expected this year as supplies exceeded demand and prices are
unlikely to recover, according to Goldman Sachs Group Inc.,
which said 2014 will mark the end of a so-called iron age. </p>
<p>This year is the inflection point where new production
capacity finally catches up with demand growth, and profit
margins begin their reversion to the historical mean, analysts
Christian Lelong and Amber Cai wrote in a report today titled:
The end of the Iron Age.  The 2016 forecast for seaborne ore
was cut to $79 a metric ton from $82 and the 2017 outlook was
reduced to $78 from $85, according to the New-York based bank,
which stuck with a forecast for $80 next year. </p>
<p>The raw material tumbled into a bear market this year as
the biggest producers including Rio Tinto (RIO) Group expanded low-cost output, betting higher volumes would more than offset
falling prices while less competitive mines were forced to
close. The decline in prices came sooner than expected,
according to Goldman, which said in November that iron ore would
probably drop at least 15 percent this year. The commodity is
seen in a structural downtrend, JPMorgan Chase  Co. said today. </p>
<p>The price decline has been dramatic, but a weak demand
outlook in China and the structural nature of the surplus make a
recovery unlikely, Lelong and Cai wrote. Lower prices for
iron ore and steel are unlikely to boost demand in a material
way. Instead, the day when steel production in China will peak
gets ever closer. </p>
<h2>Lowest Level </h2>
<p>Ore with 62 percent content at the Chinese port of Qingdao
fell 39 percent to $82.22 a dry ton this year, the lowest level
since September 2009, according to data from Metal Bulletin Ltd.
The Bloomberg Commodity Index (BCOM), which doesn''t include iron ore as
a member, lost 2 percent in the period. Within the index,
soybeans fell the most. </p>
<p>Before the surplus emerged, iron ore supplies were tight
and producers had above-trend profits even as costs increased,
according to Lelong and Cai. That period, dubbed by the bank as
the Iron Age, is now ending, they wrote. </p>
<p>The current exploitation phase in iron ore could last for
a decade, the analysts wrote. Iron ore markets went through
a 20-year period of declining prices in real terms during the
previous exploitation phase that ended in 2004. </p>
<p>The global surplus will more than triple to 163 million
tons in 2015 from 52 million tons this year, according to
Goldman. The glut was seen expanding to 245 million tons in 2016
295 million tons in 2017 and 334 million tons in 2018. </p>
<h2>Producers'' View </h2>
<p>The biggest suppliers see higher prices. Ore may increase
as the higher-cost output exits the market, Nev Power, chief
executive officer of Perth-based Fortescue (FMG) Metals Group Ltd.,
said in an Aug. 20 interview on Bloomberg Television. Vale SA
also sees prices rebounding as supply growth slows and mines
close, Jose Carlos Martins, the Rio de Janeiro-based company''s
head of ferrous and strategy, said on July 31. </p>
<p>Iron ore may see a dramatic recovery this half, Paul Gait,
an analyst at Sanford C. Bernstein, said in a report on July 9,
citing factors including a seasonal increase in the second six
months and an end to China''s policy tightening. Asia''s largest
economy accounts for about 67 percent of seaborne demand. </p>
<p>Credit growth in China missed estimates in July and new-home prices fell in almost all the cities the government tracks,
putting pressure on policy makers to step up stimulus as they
seek to meet an economic growth target of 7.5 percent. </p>
<p>About 110 million tons of global supply will close next
year and a further 75 million tons in 2016, Goldman estimated in
the report. While the majority of closures would be in China,
seaborne producers will not go unscathed, it said. </p>
<h2>Exceed Demand'' </h2>
<p>New seaborne iron ore supply delivered into China is
expected to exceed demand growth over the next three to four
years, Daniel Kang, an analyst at JPMorgan Chase  Co. in Hong
Kong, said by e-mail in response to Bloomberg questions. In
short, we see iron ore in a structural downtrend. </p>
<p>Rio Tinto, the biggest supplier after Vale, plans to boost
output to more than 330 million tons in 2015, according to a
company estimate. Vale will raise production 8.4 percent to 348
million tons in 2015. BHP Billiton Ltd. sees an 8.9 percent
increase from its Western Australian mines in the year from July
1, while Fortescue may boost shipments by 25 percent. </p>
<p>Fortescue''s stock declined 32 percent in Australia this
year, while in London Rio shares lost 5 percent and BHP rose 0.4
percent. In Brazil, Vale dropped 23 percent. </p>
<p>The shift into structural oversupply is barely six months
old but seaborne prices have already declined 38 percent year-to-date, Lelong and Cai wrote. Rather than representing the
trough for this cycle, we believe the downward pressure is set
to continue. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Anil Varma" date="Sep 10, 2014 12:27 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-10/goldman-scraps-rbi-interest-rate-increase-view-on-better-monsoon.html"><headline>Goldman Scraps RBI Interest-Rate Increase View on Better Monsoon</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. has
scrapped its forecast for the Reserve Bank of India to raise
borrowing costs after a pickup in monsoon rains and a drop in
oil prices tempered the inflation outlook. </p>
<p>The U.S. lender, which had expected a 50-basis-point
increase in the benchmark repurchase rate this year followed by
a reduction of the same magnitude in the second half of 2015,
now sees the RBI staying on hold through the end of next year,
it said in a report. Consumer-price (INFUTOTY) gains slowed to 7.8 percent
in August, from as high as 11.16 percent in November, the median
estimate in a Bloomberg survey shows before data due Sept. 12. </p>
<p>Near-term risks to inflation have receded due to weaker
oil prices and a significantly improved monsoon, Tushar Poddar, an economist at Goldman in Mumbai, wrote in the report
dated yesterday. While our base case is now for the RBI to
remain on hold, the probability of a rate hike is higher than
that of a rate cut. The biggest change under the new government
has been a more investor-friendly mindset. </p>
<p>Measures taken by Prime Minister Narendra Modi, who took
office after a landslide election win in May, will spur economic
growth, lure capital inflows and support the rupee, Goldman said
in the report. A shortfall in India''s annual rains, crucial for
crops from sugar to rice and cotton, has narrowed to 11 percent
from more than 40 percent in June, official data show, and Brent
crude prices have retreated 14 percent from this year''s high of
$115.71 per barrel in June. </p>
<h2>Quickening Growth </h2>
<p>Goldman predicts Asia''s third-largest economy will expand
5.6 percent in the fiscal year through March 2015. Gross
domestic product increased 4.7 percent in the previous period, a
pace that was near the decade-low 4.5 percent recorded the year
before. The U.S. lender still sees the rupee weakening to 61 per
dollar, 62 and 63 in three, six and 12 months. The currency fell
0.4 percent to 60.8225 as of 9:21 a.m. in Mumbai, according to
prices from local banks. </p>
<p>RBI Governor Raghuram Rajan, who raised borrowing costs
three times in the past year to combat inflation, has left them
unchanged since January. The central bank will hold the
benchmark rate at 8 percent through the end of 2014, according
to 16 of 26 analysts surveyed by Bloomberg. Four see a reduction
to 7.75 percent, while five estimate a 25-basis-point increase
and one expects an advance to 8.5 percent. </p>
<p>Modi''s decisions to cut red tape and allow more foreign
investment in industries including railways and defense have
buoyed investor confidence, Goldman said in the report. The
rupee has rebounded 13 percent from a record low of 68.845 per
dollar reached in August 2013, the world''s best-performing
emerging-market currency over that period, data compiled by
Bloomberg show. </p>
<p>We think the Indian rupee will continue to trade in a
narrow range, with the RBI intervening to prevent any sharp
appreciation, Goldman''s Poddar wrote. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lucas Shaw" date="Sep 12, 2014  4:13 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-12/disney-to-build-frozen-attraction-at-epcot-park.html"><headline>Disney to Build Frozen'' Attraction at Epcot Park</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS) is bringing the hit
movie Frozen to its Epcot theme park in Florida. </p>
<p>A new attraction, based on the Arendelle kingdom in
Frozen, will replace the Maelstrom ride at Epcot''s Norway
Pavilion, Disney Parks  Resorts Chairman Thomas Staggs said
said today in a blog post. </p>
<p>Disney is adding Frozen attractions to a number of its
parks. Starting in November, the company will transform
Cinderella Castle at its Magic Kingdom near Orlando into an ice
palace for the holidays. Several Frozen characters will
appear in a Christmas parade. </p>
<p>Frozen, released in 2013, is the fifth-highest grossing
movie of all time, with $1.27 billion in global receipts,
according to Box Office Mojo. </p>
<p>Disney, based in Burbank, California, fell less than 1
percent to $89.67 at the close in New York. The shares have
advanced 17 percent this year. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Boris Korby" date="Sep 12, 2014 12:15 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-12/goldman-sees-ukraine-default-risk-increasing-as-economy-weakens.html"><headline>Ukraine Creditors Could See 50% Loss in a Default, Goldman Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Ukraine''s deteriorating economic
outlook is increasing the likelihood of a default that could
saddle bondholders with losses of about 50 percent, according to
Goldman Sachs Group Inc. </p>
<p>A six-month conflict with pro-Russian rebels has spurred
capital outflows and disrupted economic output to the point
where it brings into question Ukraine''s ability to continue
paying its debt, Goldman analysts including Clemens Grafe wrote
in an e-mailed report. Past restructurings indicate bondholders
could lose half their principal, according to the note. </p>
<p>A Sept. 5 truce is holding amid efforts to end a war the
United Nations estimates has claimed at least 3,000 lives. The
fighting in Ukraine''s Donetsk and Lugansk regions has destroyed
productive capacity, displaced a large share of the country''s
population and disrupted exports, prompting Goldman to raise
economic contraction estimates to 8 percent from 3 percent in
March and increase this year''s debt-to-GDP forecast to 70
percent from 55 percent. </p>
<p>Our current forecasts and the persisting uncertainty
surrounding the ongoing conflict in eastern Ukraine now raise
the question of whether the country can return to a sustainable
debt path without a restructuring, the Goldman analysts wrote. </p>
<p>Yields on Ukraine''s $2.6 billion of bonds due 2017 jumped
0.38 percentage points today to 12.84 percent, according to data
compiled by Bloomberg. Bond trading indicate investors are
pricing in about a 15 percent chance of a restructuring within
the next year and 35 percent chance in the next five years, the
analysts wrote. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dara Doyle" date="Sep 12, 2014 11:55 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-12/gambler-makes-1-3-million-wager-on-no-vote-in-scots-ballot.html"><headline>Gambler Makes $1.3 Million Wager on No'' Vote in Scots Ballot</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The odds of Scotland rejecting
independence shortened, as one gambler wagered 800,000 pounds
($1.3 million) on a no vote, William Hill Plc said. </p>
<p>Having been a 2/5 chance at the start of the week, no
odds shortened to 1/5 at William Hill, meaning a 5 pound wager
returns 1 pound profit. The odds on yes lengthened to 10/3
from 7/4. </p>
<p>All of the biggest bets we have taken, including one
customer staking 800,000 pounds and another 200,000 pounds, have
been for no'''' while the biggest we have taken for yes'''' is
10,000 pounds, Graham Sharpe, spokesman for the London-based
company, said in an e-mail today. </p>
<p>Scotland''s nationalists suffered a second straight setback
in the polls after YouGov Plc yesterday showed them trailing
less than a week after overtaking the anti-independence campaign
for the first time. Scottish residents vote in a referendum on
Sept. 18. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Carroll" date="Sep 12, 2014 11:55 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-12/exxon-s-700-million-arctic-well-feels-sanctions-fallout.html"><headline>Exxon''s $700 Million Arctic Well Feels Sanctions Fallout</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM)''s work on a $700 million Arctic well in Russia could be stopped before it''s finished under new U.S. and European Union sanctions that outlaw the drilling partnership. </p> <p>New sanctions ban U.S. and EU companies from working with Russian officials or companies to find or produce crude from deep seas, shale fields or the Arctic. The decrees, reported earlier this week by Bloomberg, were imposed today, the 35th day of drilling at the 9 billion-barrel Universitetskaya prospect off Russia''s northern coast that was scheduled to last for 70 days. </p> <p>American and European explorers such as Exxon and Royal Dutch Shell Plc (RDSA), which is drilling in Siberian shale rock formations, will have to act fast to avoid violating the bans, said Mark Herlach, an international lawyer and partner at the Sutherland Asbill Brennan LLP law firm in Washington. U.S. companies have until Sept. 26 to shut down sanctioned operations with Russian partners, according to the new rules. </p> <p>Arctic Opportunity</p><p>The purpose of the sanctions is penalizing Russian interests for their actions in Ukraine, so there''s no policy reason to allow a delay, Herlach said. The high likelihood is that there is no grace period for the oil companies. </p> <p>The U.S. and EU have been ratcheting up economic pressure on Russian President Vladimir Putin to halt support for pro-Russian separatists in eastern Ukraine since March. In an exclusive report Sept. 10, Bloomberg News spelled out the widest, hardest-hitting sanctions the EU and U.S. were preparing to impose. </p> <h2>Exxon Assessing'' </h2> <p>Exxon, which began drilling the well last month as part of a $3.2 billion venture with Moscow-based OAO Rosneft (ROSN), declined to say whether it has begun transporting employees or contractors from the drilling project, or if it has plans in place to do so. We are assessing the sanctions, a spokesman said in an e-mailed statement. </p> 
<p></p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jeremy van Loon" date="Sep 12, 2014 11:16 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-12/chevron-needs-partner-agreements-before-moving-on-kitimat-lng.html"><headline>Chevron Needs Partner, Agreements Before Moving on Kitimat LNG</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX) needs to find a
partner, secure natural gas contracts and assess engineering
costs before making a decision on its Canadian liquefied natural
gas project in Kitimat. </p>
<p>Chevron is continuing to work with aboriginal groups in the
area on the northwestern coast of British Columbia and doing
initial work on the site, said Chief Executive Officer John Watson, in a briefing in Calgary with reporters today. </p>
<p>We''ve seen pressure on LNG projects around the world,
he said. We have an advantaged resource in the Horn River
basin, but the costs are very high. You have to have good
alignment with partners. </p>
<p>Chevron is one of a handful of companies considering
exporting natural gas from British Columbia. The Canadian
province is closer to Asian markets than some competing parts of
the world including the U.S. Gulf Coast, and demand for energy,
including LNG, continues to grow, Watson said. </p>
<p>At the moment, LNG projects moving ahead are those in
the Gulf Coast where existing infrastructure makes them easier 
to develop, he said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Natalie Obiko Pearson" date="Sep 12, 2014 12:07 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-12/morgan-stanley-s-continuum-raises-india-wind-farm-loan.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley''s Continuum Raises India Wind Farm Loan</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley-backed Continuum
Wind Energy Pte. will get a $50 million loan from the World Bank
Group''s private-sector financing arm to build a wind farm in
India. </p>
<p>The International Finance Corp.''s loan will be used by
Continuum Wind''s two units, D.J. Energy Pvt. and Uttar Urja
Projects Energy Pvt., to develop a 170-megawatt project in
central Madhya Pradesh state, according to an e-mailed statement
yesterday from IFC. </p>
<p>IFC''s loan will also help facilitate an additional $100
million of financing for the project from Yes Bank Ltd. (YES),
according to the statement. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) Infrastructure Partners holds an undisclosed
majority stake in Singapore-registered Continuum, which has 150
megawatts of operating wind capacity in India. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Halia Pavliva" date="Sep 14, 2014  4:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-14/jpmorgan-s-buy-rating-spurs-rally-in-russia-s-md-medical.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Buy Rating Spurs Rally in Russia''s MD Medical</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>MD Medical Group Investments Plc,
which runs Russia''s largest chain of maternity centers, gained
for the first time in a week as JPMorgan Chase  Co. raised it
to buy, citing cheap valuation relative to regional peers. </p>
<p>JPMorgan''s recommendation on the company, which has a
market value of $620 million, comes as Aberdeen Asset Management
Plc sees Russian small-capitalization stocks as ridiculously
cheap after a sell-off. The MSCI Russia Small Cap Index is
down 22 percent this year, following a broad decline in the
country''s securities amid concern sanctions against Russia over
the Ukraine war will squelch economic growth. The U.S. and
European Union enforced new measures last week. </p>
<p>MD Medical gained 3.1 percent to $8.25 in London on Sept.
12, reducing its loss this year to 27 percent. Trading volume of
67,016 shares was 4.2 times the average of the past three
months. The Bloomberg Russia-US Equity Index rose 0.4 percent as
energy exporters including OAO Surgutneftegas and OAO Gazprom
Neft gained on speculation a weaker ruble will boost profits. </p>
<p>JPMorgan cited the stock''s compelling 30 percent
discount to peers in eastern Europe and the Middle East when
it raised MD Medical from the equivalent of hold. Analyst Elena Jouronova forecast compound annual revenue growth of 26 percent
through 2017 as regional expansion gathers pace, according to an
e-mailed research note. </p>
<h2>GDP Slowdown </h2>
<p>Growth in Russia''s $2 trillion economy has been slowed by
the international sanctions intended to punish President
Vladimir Putin for allegedly supporting the rebellion in eastern
Ukraine, a claim he denies. Barclays Plc., which projects a 0.1
percent decline in gross domestic product this year and a 0.6
percent contraction in 2015, said in a Sept. 11 research note
that new measures imply downside risks to that forecast. </p>
<p>Luis Saenz, head of equity sales and trading at BCS
Financial Group in London, said MD Medical isn''t as vulnerable
to the slowdown as other companies whose revenue comes from
domestic spending. </p>
<p>They focus on high-end maternity health care and are
diversifying operations throughout Russia, Saenz said by
phone. Even as the economy slows, people won''t cut spending on
maternity health care because it''s so critical. </p>
<h2>Sales Estimates </h2>
<p>MD Medical, which has 17 medical centers throughout Russia
including in Moscow, St.Petersburg, Perm, Samara and Irkutsk,
said on Aug. 20 that it bought Avicenne Medical Center in
Novosibirk for $45.5 million. The acquisition will help the
company increase revenue, according to JP Morgan''s Jouronova and
Saenz of BCS. </p>
<p>JP Morgan raised MD Medical''s revenue forecast by as 4.6
percent to $204 million for 2014 and increased its 2015 sales
estimate by 5.6 percent to $265 million, according to the bank''s
research note. </p>
<p>Their business model is beautiful, but low liquidity in
Russian small-capitalization stocks is a problem Saenz said.
Investors are worried about the geopolitical risks and want to
be able to get in and out of the market quickly. </p>
<p>The Micex Second-Tier Index of companies with lower market
capitalization fell 1 percent to 2,959.65 last week, extending
the decline this year to 4.9 percent. The benchmark Micex Index
dropped 1.1 percent last week to 1,458.52 and is down 3 percent
this year. The Bloomberg index of the most-trade Russian stocks
in the U.S. slid 3.3 percent to 85.46 in the five days through
Sept. 12 and has retreated 16 percent in 2014. </p>
<h2>Fund Flows </h2>
<p>Within the Russian space, the small-caps have sold off
ridiculously, Peter Taylor, a senior investment manager for
global emerging markets at Aberdeen Asset Management in London,
said in an interview on Sept. 5. Liquidity has completely
dried up. There are Russian small caps that are decent
businesses that are just looking ridiculously cheap. </p>
<p>MD Medical is a nice business, Taylor said. The
management team impresses us and the business model is an
attractive structural story in Russia and yet that stock has
just gone so off year-to-date. </p>
<p>Futures (VEA) on the dollar-denominated RTS index expiring this
month gained 0.7 percent to 122,230 in U.S. hours on Sept. 12.
The RTS Volatility Index, which measures expected swings in the
futures, declined 1.2 percent to 32.19. </p>
<p>The Market Vectors Russia ETF (RSX), the biggest U.S. exchange-traded fund that tracks the nation''s stocks, fell 3 percent last
week to $24.57. It gained 0.5 percent on Sept. 12. </p>
<p>Russia-dedicated funds attracted about $140 million in the
week through Sept. 10, after outflows in the previous week,
Cameron Brandt, research director at EPFR Global, a Cambridge,
Massachusetts-based company that tracks fund flows, said by e-mail. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Wes Goodman" date="Sep 14, 2014 10:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-14/morgan-stanley-seven-year-curse-spells-decline-australia-credit.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Seven-Year Curse Spells Decline: Australia Credit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley says Australian
bonds, the worst-performing government debt in the past month,
have further to decline as investment-grade securities globally
will stagnate for the next seven years. </p>
<p>Australian sovereign debt due in more than a year lost 0.7
percent in the month ended Sept. 12, the most among 26 indexes
compiled by Bloomberg and the European Federation of Financial
Analysts Societies. Bond prices will fall in tandem with
benchmark U.S. Treasuries as the Federal Reserve prepares to
raise interest rates, according to Morgan Stanley. </p>
<p>Higher borrowing costs would complicate Prime Minister Tony
Abbott''s efforts to sustain growth in an economy with decade-high unemployment and his goal of reining in the country''s
record A$337.7 billion ($306 billion) debt. The government''s
focus on sales of long-term securities will also help push
yields higher, Morgan Stanley says. </p>
<p>We''re bearish on bond markets generally as we get closer
to the Fed starting their tightening cycle, Geoffrey Kendrick,
head of Asian currency and interest-rate strategy at Morgan
Stanley in Hong Kong, said in a Sept. 10 telephone interview.
In Australia, that clearly will flow through to local bond
selling as well. </p>
<h2>Rising Unemployment </h2>
<p>Abbott won election a year ago after pledging in his
campaign to work toward turning the government budget deficit
into a surplus. He''s now battling rising unemployment, with the
jobless rate climbing to 6.4 percent in July, the highest level
in 12 years. The rate retreated to 6.1 percent in August as the
economy added a record 121,000 jobs, most of them part time. </p>
<p>Debt issuance will fall to an estimated A$67 billion in the
fiscal year that began July 1, from about A$85 billion in the
previous financial year, the Australian Office of Financial
Management said in May. Sales for 2014-2015 will cover A$27
billion of maturing bonds, A$36 billion of new securities and
A$4 billion of inflation-linked securities. </p>
<p>The nation''s government debt had a modified duration of
5.18 years at the end of June, compared with 4.85 a year
earlier, according to the AOFM website. Sales of longer
maturities extend duration, which is a gauge of bond volatility
used by investors. </p>
<p>You have still relatively large issuance, Kendrick
said. That probably means there''s going to be some pressure on
the back end of the maturity range particularly as global
bonds are somewhat softer, he said. </p>
<h2>Rising Yields </h2>
<p>Australia''s 10-year bond yield was at 3.61 percent at the
close of trading in Sydney last week, having climbed from this
year''s low of 3.28 percent set on Aug. 8. </p>
<p>The securities yielded about 104 basis points more than
similar-maturity Treasuries, and the spread should stay at about
110 for the next year, Kendrick said. U.S. 10-year yields will
rise to 2.95 percent in 12 months, Morgan Stanley said in a
report Sept. 7, from 2.56 percent. The company is one of the 22
primary dealers that trade directly with the Fed. </p>
<p>Australian government securities due in 10 years and longer
have a correlation of 0.94 with their U.S. counterparts, the
Bloomberg and EFFAS data show. A figure of 1 would mean the two
move in lock step. </p>
<p>The decline in Australia''s bonds accelerated after 10-year
futures contracts dropped below a support level last week
according to John Gorman, head of dollar interest-rate trading
for Asia and the Pacific at Nomura Holdings Inc. in Tokyo. </p>
<h2>Getting Out'' </h2>
<p>Using a chart of the contract price, Gorman drew an
ascending trend line connecting lows set in April and June and
extrapolated it out to today. The price fell below the line on
Sept. 5 and the decline quickened from there. </p>
<p>It broke that trend line, he said in a phone call Sept.
10. People who bought it before are getting out. </p>
<p>Declines in Australian bonds may be limited from here
because yields of more than 3 percent are still attractive to
investors, said Peter Jolly, head of research in Sydney at
National Australia Bank Ltd., the nation''s biggest lender as
measured by assets. </p>
<p>Australian government bonds will be a good investment,
he said by phone on Sept. 10. The RBA is on hold and the
Federal Reserve is on the path to raising interest rates. </p>
<p>Reserve Bank of Australia''s Governor Glenn Stevens repeated
this month the most prudent thing to do is keep the benchmark
interest rate, the target for overnight loans between banks, at
a record low of 2.5 percent. </p>
<h2>Fed Tightening </h2>
<p>The Fed is set to raise its target for overnight lending
next year, federal fund futures show. Thirty-day contracts for
delivery in September 2015 yielded 0.54 percent, signaling
traders are pricing in that the central bank will increase its
rate from the current range of zero to 0.25 percent by then. </p>
<p>Jonathan Mackay at Morgan Stanley Wealth Management in New
York said a three-decade decline in bond yields has come to an
end. Investors should seek risker securities such as high-yield
bonds, he said in an interview on Bloomberg Television this
month. The company manages $2 trillion. </p>
<p>What we''re suggesting is that you just have less of your
bond allocation in the perceived, or formerly perceived, safe
havens, he said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Sep 15, 2014  4:42 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-15/microsoft-to-buy-minecraft-maker-mojang-for-2-5-billion.html"><headline>Microsoft to Buy Minecraft Maker Mojang for $2.5 Billion</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), maker of the Xbox video-game console, agreed to acquire Mojang AB, the software company behind the popular game Minecraft, for $2.5 billion, in a bid to boost its Xbox and mobile businesses. </p> <p>Microsoft, the world''s largest software maker, said Stockholm-based Mojang will join its game-studio division, though the company''s founders will move on to other projects. The purchase is projected to close late this year, and will break even in fiscal 2015, Microsoft said today in a statement. </p> <p>Buying Mojang would be the biggest deal struck since Satya Nadella took over as Microsoft''s chief executive officer in February, succeeding Steve Ballmer. The purchase gives Nadella a game that is popular across consoles, computers and mobile devices made by Microsoft and rivals like Apple Inc. It also bolsters a push to woo serious gamers back to Xbox after a lackluster attempt to turn the system into an all-in-one device that serves up broader content such as movies and music. </p> <p>Acquiring the Minecraft game through the Mojang acquisition gives Mr. Nadella  Co. the right product at the right time as the company continues to invest in its Xbox strategy and begins its foray into the intensely competitive mobile-phone space with Nokia now under Microsoft''s hood and the restructuring plan under way, Daniel Ives, an analyst at FBR Capital Markets  Co., wrote in a note. </p>




Photographer:  Paul Warner/WireImage

<p>
A "Creeper" from the video game Minecraft on day three of the Chicago Comic  Entertainment Expo at McCormick Place on March 20, 2011. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Sep 15, 2014  1:10 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-15/morgan-stanley-fined-for-records-violations-tied-to-ponzi-scheme.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Fined for Violations Tied to Ponzi Scheme</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley was fined $280,000
for ignoring numerous red flags in opening an account tied
to a multimillion-dollar Ponzi scheme, a U.S. regulator said. </p>
<p>The bank''s Smith Barney unit was cited for improper
supervision and records violations, the Commodity Futures
Trading Commission said today in a statement. The New York-based
company also failed to enforce trading limits it assigned to the
account and adequately respond to regulators'' requests for
documents, the CFTC said. </p>
<p>The accounts were used by Benjamin Wilson, the owner of
SureInvestment, to continue a $35 million Ponzi scheme based in
the U.K., according to the statement. Wilson was sentenced to
seven years in prison this year after pleading guilty to charges
brought by that country''s Financial Conduct Authority, the CFTC
said. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley ignored warning signs even as the
account should have received special scrutiny because two
SureInvestment entities were based in the British Virgin
Islands. </p>
<p>The warning signs included documents that showed
SureInvestment had returns of 2,850 percent from 2003 to 2009
and 45 consecutive profitable months, according to the CFTC''s
order. SureInvestment also submitted an audit that included
numerous typographical errors, the regulator said. </p>
<h2>Fully Cooperated'' </h2>
<p>A simple Internet search would have revealed that neither
the SureInvestment entity that was the subject of the audits nor
the purported B.V.I. auditing firm and its principals actually
existed, the CFTC said in the order. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) didn''t admit or deny the charges, while
consenting to the entry of the CFTC''s findings. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley takes its regulatory responsibilities
seriously, Christine Jockle, a company spokeswoman, said in an
e-mailed statement. The firm fully cooperated with the CFTC''s
investigation. The events described in the settlement involve a
single account that traded for less than three months. CFTC did
not conclude that the firm''s conduct in this matter was willful,
intentional or fraudulent. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Duane D. Stanford" date="Sep 15, 2014 12:01 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-15/coca-cola-brings-back-surge-soda-to-tap-1990s-nostalgia.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Brings Back Surge Soda to Tap 1990s Nostalgia</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Coca-Cola Co. (KO)''s newest social-media campaign reaches back to a time when even MySpace didn''t exist. </p> <p>Surge, a citrus-flavored Mountain Dew knockoff that was discontinued by Coke about 12 years ago, has reappeared in limited supply today. The only place to get it: Amazon.com. </p> <p>Billed as the company''s first ever e-commerce reintroduction, the news was announced by the Facebook Fan site Surge Movement, whose 128,000 members lobbied for its return and paid for a billboard in Atlanta. Coke gave the drink a Twitter account, too, so loyalists can follow the brand''s journey. </p> <p>Surge is back, the Facebook page''s organizers said, urging readers to buy and spread the word. The Movement does not end here! </p> <p>At the website listserv.com, Surge is listed as No. 7 on a Top 10 list of discontinued sodas, beating out Hubba Bubba Soda. Surge, a sweet and caffeinated green pop, will be sold in 12-packs of 16-ounce cans printed with the original graphics for $14. Coke said it may expand the drink to other retailers and add to the campaign, depending on how consumers react. </p> <p>This will be a great learning experience for us and a refreshing opportunity for fans, Wendy Clark, Coke''s president of North America Sparkling  Strategic Marketing, said in a statement. </p> <p>Scott Williamson, a Coke spokesman, declined to say how much of the drink the company has produced intially. </p> <h2>Extremely Rare'' </h2> <p>Coca-Cola has struggled for decades to counter PepsiCo Inc. (PEP)''s Mountain Dew juggernaut. Surge was one of those efforts. Introduced in 1996, the last bottles and cans were offered in 2001, two years before the social-networking site Myspace debuted. Facebook would come even later. </p> <p>At the Surge Movement Facebook page, founded just before Christmas 2011, fans shared a 1997 commercial for the drink. Another post showed a way to get extremely rare Surge syrup on Ebay.com. One fan photo shows an artifact that was discovered at a flea market in Okoboji, Iowa: a giant Surge bottle once used at events to ice down drink samples. </p> <p>I stole one of these when Surge first came out, one commenter responded. Sadly, it was lost at the top of Happy Jack Mountains outside of Laramie Wyoming when someone got in it and tried to ride it down a mountain. It was a prize possession. </p> <p>The group sold The Surge Movement t-shirts, and it crowdfunded a $4,000 billboard near Coke headquarters in Atlanta that read: Dear Coke, We couldn''t buy Surge so we bought this billboard instead. It''s the largest to pledge for the revival of any discontinued product. </p> <h2>Mountain Dew </h2> <p>The site''s managers urged fans to call Coca-Cola routinely with reminders like, Did you make your call today? A mysterious undated video posted yesterday showed the Facebook page''s administrators meeting at a hotel in Atlanta. Users wanted to know why but they weren''t saying. </p> <p>It''s no wonder Coke keeps trying. Mountain Dew, the fourth-best-selling soft drink in the U.S., has been one of the few bright spots in PepsiCo''s soda lineup in recent years as consumers drink less soda. Popular with teens, video gamers and extreme sports enthusiasts, Mountain Dew outperformed both the soda category and Pepsi-Cola last year, according to Beverage Digest data. </p> <p>Coke may have found its opening, though. Dew''s volume sales declined last year. Sales volume for regular Dew fell 2.2 percent, compared with declines of 3.6 percent for Pepsi-Cola and 3 percent for the category. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Sep 15, 2014  7:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-15/morgan-stanley-adds-impact-portfolios-in-brokerage.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Adds Impact'' Portfolios in Brokerage</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS), which has set a
goal of attracting $10 billion of client assets to sustainable
investing products over the next few years, is adding two such
portfolios for its wealth-management customers. </p>
<p>The accounts invest with a range of outside managers who
either screen to avoid certain companies or actively seek out
businesses that have shown success in environmental or social
issues. The Investing with Impact portfolios feature one
balanced and one equity offering. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley already has about $3.5 billion in more than
100 products aimed at providing social benefits along with
financial returns, said Hilary Irby, who leads the New York-based bank''s so-called impact investing effort. The new
offerings may accelerate that growth by providing clients a pre-selected mix of holdings that are diversified while following
principles of sustainable investing. </p>
<p>These portfolios can absolutely be a client''s full
portfolio, Irby said in an interview. As the bank creates
products that allow customers to satisfy impact objectives,
and not necessarily have to give up those financial goals, then
we can move more of our clients'' resources to help address some
of the sustainability issues the world is facing broadly. </p>
<p>The biggest U.S. banks have sought to help allocate capital
to efforts such as community development, education and
environmental preservation both in response to client demand and
in the wake of public outrage and government rescues resulting
from the financial crisis. </p>
<h2>Affordable Housing </h2>
<p>Morgan Stanley Chief Executive Officer James Gorman pledged
$1 billion last year to help improve affordable housing as part
of the bank''s push into sustainable investing that included
promoting research and developing new products. The broader
trend has spanned public and private markets and has also been
called social-impact investing or socially    responsible
investing. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s brokerage, the world''s largest by number
of financial advisers, has 4 million clients with $2 trillion in
assets at the firm. </p>
<p>The bank constructed the portfolios to reduce the biases
typically associated with sustainable strategies, notably that
they are predominantly in small-cap growth companies, said Chad
Graves, who oversees impact investing for wealth management. The
equity portfolio should have similar risk and return
characteristics to broader indexes such as the Standard  Poor''s
500 (SPX) and the Russell 1000, he said. </p>
<h2>Steady Income </h2>
<p>We don''t think about this as a separate asset class, we
don''t think about this as something that has to sit off in a
corner because it''s a unique way of investing, Graves said.
It''s not unique in that the objectives of this are exactly the
same as they would be for a portfolio that wasn''t invested for
impact. We want to get the same financial returns. </p>
<p>The portfolios may also aid Morgan Stanley''s push to move
more clients into fee-based managed accounts that provide steady
income to the bank. The firm had $762 billion of client assets
in fee-based accounts at June 30, up 21 percent from a year
earlier, and it has set a goal of $1 trillion such assets. </p>
<p>The balanced portfolio, which invests about 60 percent in
equity and 40 percent in debt, has a minimum investment of
$750,000, while the equity portfolio has a $400,000 minimum,
Graves said. The bank is seeking to develop a similar donor-advised fund with a $25,000 minimum investment, said Jim Tracy,
who runs the brokerage''s consulting group. </p>
<p>This is an emerging opportunity for investors, and we
want to be known as the firm that when people see what we''re
doing, they know that we''re serious about it, Tracy said.
And it''s not just something we''re doing for the ultra-rich. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Vines" date="Sep 16, 2014  7:01 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-16/goldman-trader-swaps-financial-services-for-speedy-food-delivery.html"><headline>Goldman Trader Swaps Financial Services for Speedy Food Delivery</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Rahul Parekh became used to long hours and late nights at Goldman Sachs Group Inc. in London, where he was executive director of equity-derivatives trading. </p> <p>It was the food that took its toll. </p> <p>I remember when I was at Goldman Sachs, working late in the evening and nothing was open nearby, he said in an interview. You order online from one of the delivery businesses and can end up waiting 1-1/2 hours for a greasy takeaway that doesn''t feel healthy in any way. </p> <p>It may have been more a microwave moment than a light-bulb idea but Parekh decided he could do better. He quit Goldman earlier this year and co-founded EatFirst, a food-delivery service that cooks its own fresh meals and promises to get them to your office in the City of London within 15 minutes of an order being placed. </p> <p>EatFirst follows an initial public offering in Just Eat Plc, an online takeaway service whose shares began trading in April. Just Eat was started in Denmark in 2001 and expanded into the U.K. in 2006. Just Eat Plc has a market value of 1.6 billion pounds ($2.6 billion). </p> <p>Just Eat connects customers with restaurants for takeaway meals. Unlike EatFirst, it doesn''t make or deliver the food. Other companies in the market include Deliveroo, which supplies foods from restaurants and charges for delivery. </p> <p>Parekh''s partners are Humberto Ayres Pereira, who was at McKinsey  Co. and founded the Skin online cosmetics business in his native Portugal; and Torben Schulz, an entrepreneur who plans to start an EatFirst in Berlin, where he is based. </p> <p>EatFirst is backed by Berlin-based Rocket Internet AG, which invests in companies related to the Internet industry. </p> <h2>Two Dishes </h2> <p>The company currently offers a choice of two dishes, one of them vegetarian. They both change daily and are prepared in a kitchen in Farringdon, near the City of London. Recent options include chorizo and chicken jambalaya; Thai massaman curry; and goat cheese ratatouille. Each costs 7 pounds ($11.32). </p> <p>The executive chef is Jane Tran, who previously worked at Bar Boulud. A third option will be added in coming months. Customers may pay by debit or credit card or via an app. </p> <p>Parekh, 28, was born in Manchester, England, to a family that was originally from Gujarat, in India. His parents were born in Kenya. EatFirst is initially delivering in part of the City of London financial district. It''s a crowded market. </p> <p>At Goldman, I used to cycle between Itsu on a Monday, and a Pret on a Tuesday, and a Leon on a Wednesday and a Pod on a Thursday and it just gets so boring after a couple of weeks, he said. That''s what we really wanted to change with EatFirst so people can have a varied diet and don''t have to look elsewhere. </p> <p>Natalie Berg, global research director at Planet Retail Ltd. in London, said that while the trend toward healthy convenience food isn''t new, technology is changing things. </p> <h2>Working Lunch </h2> <p>Food delivery has been limited to pizza and other fast food without high-quality options, she said in a telephone interview. But technology is changing this and there''s an opportunity to tap into a very lucrative working-lunch market. </p> <p>What is especially interesting with EatFirst is that it''s based on simplicity -- just a couple of dishes -- which helps them to keep costs down and reinforces the ethos of high-quality, freshly prepared food. </p> <p>Parekh declined to disclose financial details or profit targets. He said the company plans to expand aggressively. </p> <p>In a place like London, which is so vast and so densely populated, the sky''s the limit, he said. Even the City, which is a tiny area, there''s almost 400,000 people during the day, so there''s no reason we can''t be pushing towards thousands a day and be the biggest food-delivery company in London. </p> <h2>Food Has Lagged </h2> <p>For the first year, I''d imagine within London we can get over 1,000 meals a day and that would be serving the City and central London and also expanding to Canary Wharf. We have a pretty aggressive expansion plan. We are working on a number of new kitchen locations and expanding our delivery network </p> <p>I see this as the future for food delivery. As other retail products move online, food has really lagged. Our expansion plan is realistic given the future that we expect for the food industry and the online-delivery landscape. </p> <p>Most Britons ordering food online currently do so through a restaurant''s own website such as Pizza Hut, according to Helena Childe, senior food service analyst at Mintel. </p> <p>Third-party sites such as Just Eat are increasing in popularity, she said. </p> <p>Most online restaurant habits (from online ordering to mobile payments) are most common among Londoners and the tech-savvy youth market (under-35s), Childe said in a Mintel report, Eating Out: The Decision-Making Process, earlier this year. </p> <h2>Small Cog </h2> <p>EatFirst leases its kitchens and delivery bikes, seeking to keep down costs while it expands. Fair enough but was it wise to quit Goldman to pursue such a venture? </p> <p>I had a fantastic experience at Goldman but everything we do now has a huge impact on the future of the business, he said. It''s different to working in an organization like Goldman Sachs, where you can feel like a small cog in a massive machine. </p> <p>This is a totally different thrill: There''s new things every day to do. I''ve been in the kitchen, cleaning dishes with the chefs. I''ve been handing out flyers with the marketing team. I''ve been involved in fund-raising meetings. There''s so much to do and it''s an all-round business experience. </p> <p>Information: https://www.eatfirst.co.uk/; the app is here: https://itunes.apple.com/app/id907506298. </p> <p>(Richard Vines is the chief food critic for Bloomberg. Opinions expressed are his own. Follow him on Twitter @richardvines) </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Katia Porzecanski" date="Sep 16, 2014  6:44 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-16/jpmorgan-s-silvani-says-markets-wrong-on-argentina-resolution.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Silvani Says Markets Wrong'' on Argentina Resolution</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Markets are wrong, Matias Silvani, a money manager at JPMorgan Asset Management, said at
an Emta conference in New York.
* Bond markets are mispricing not only the timing of when this
is settled but the actual fundamentals, which have been
deteriorating.
* When Argentina settles it will be done in a position of
weakness, not strength.
* Settlement with holdouts probably won''t happen before first
quarter of 2016, after there''s a new administration, Javier Kulesz, an analyst at Nomura Holdings Inc., said at the
conference. Three presidential candidates leading polls
understand cost of settling is low and upside is phenomenal,
he said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Carroll" date="Sep 16, 2014  6:08 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-16/chevron-s-search-for-alternative-fuels-stumps-best-minds.html"><headline>Chevron''s Search for Alternative Fuels Stumps Best Minds</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX)''s attempts to turn plants into alternative fuels for profitable, large-scale production have failed. </p> <p>The second-largest U.S. oil company by market value spent significant sums and assigned some of its best scientists to evaluate more than 100 kinds of feedstock and 50 techniques for converting them into fuels without success, Chevron Chairman and Chief Executive Officer John Watson said during an address to the Economic Club of Minnesota in Minneapolis today. </p> <p>The smartest minds in my company and others haven''t yet cracked the code on pairing the right feedstock conversion technology and logistics in an economic and scalable package, Watson said. </p> <p>Major crude producers from Chevron to BP Plc have been scaling back investment in renewables to focus on higher-profit ventures such as deep-water oil wells. Chevron''s setbacks echo those of Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM), which last year said its $600 million foray into algae-based fuel may not succeed for another 25 years. BP put $3.1 billion of wind assets for sale last year after withdrawing from solar in 2011. </p> <p>Chevron sold an energy-efficiency unit last month that had been losing money for half a decade, Watson said. The company remains dedicated to other forms of renewables such as geothermal and continues to pursue research into some types of biofuels, Watson told reporters after his speech. Chevron''s plants research focused on non-food crops, he said. </p>




Photographer: Patrick Fallon/Bloomberg

<p>
Corn is unloaded from trucks into the grain elevator in Missouri, U.S. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Barinka" date="Sep 16, 2014 11:47 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-16/ibm-touts-watson-to-back-office-amid-cloud-service-push.html"><headline>IBM Touts Watson to Back Office Amid Cloud Service Push</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM) is marketing its Watson analytics technology to rank-and-file workers across a swath of industries as it seeks to
encourage broader adoption of cloud-based data products. </p>
<p>The company is making available a standard version of its
data-crunching service, first unveiled in January, as a product
for clients like banks and pharmaceutical companies. The
software will be offered in a basic free format, with paid
features such as additional storage or connecting different
sources of data, said Alistair Rennie, IBM''s general manager of
business analytics, in an interview. </p>
<p>IBM has been trying to commercialize its Watson tool, which
lets users ask questions in plain English language and analyze
data for patterns, by showing how it can be used for tasks such
as customer service and cooking. The company has been investing
in analytics software like Watson, famous for winning the
Jeopardy! TV show, amid a slump in demand for hardware that
has led to nine straight quarters of falling sales. </p>
<p>Outreach to the individual through digital methods is a
critical element to getting these tools to as many people as
possible, Rennie said. We''re convinced more people will love
it and will want more advanced capabilities. </p>




Photographer: Ben Hider/Getty Images

<p>
International Business Machines Corp. has been investing in analytics software like Watson, famous for winning the Jeopardy! TV show, amid a slump in demand for hardware which has led to nine straight quarters of falling sales. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dinesh Nair" date="Sep 16, 2014  4:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-16/jpmorgan-names-credit-suisse-s-thiebaud-for-swiss-role.html"><headline>JPMorgan Names Credit Suisse''s Thiebaud for Swiss Role</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) hired Credit
Suisse Group AG (CSGN) banker Vincent Thiebaud as head of its corporate
finance business in Switzerland, amid a rise in investment
banking activity in the country. </p>
<p>Thiebaud was most recently a director at Credit Suisse''s
investment banking division in Switzerland, where he focused on
capital markets funding and mergers and acquisitions
transactions for Swiss companies, according to an internal memo
seen by Bloomberg News. Kate Haywood, a spokeswoman for JPMorgan
in London, confirmed the contents of the memo. </p>
<p>MA activity involving Swiss companies has more than
tripled this year compared to the same period in 2013, with
124.5 billion euros ($161.1 billion) of deals agreed, including
the 37.5 billion euro merger of Lafarge SA with Jona,
Switzerland-based Holcim Ltd., according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Thiebaud will be based in Zurich and report to Nick
Bossart, senior country officer for Switzerland. His appointment
is effective Sept. 24. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Paula Sambo and Filipe Pacheco" date="Sep 17, 2014  2:41 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-17/jpmorgan-writes-off-brazil-bond-pickup-as-elections-loom.html"><headline>JPMorgan Writes Off Brazil Bond Pickup as Elections Loom</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Companies in Brazil are shunning
the local bond market on speculation President Dilma Rousseff,
who''s presided over an economy plagued by surging inflation and
a lack of growth, will be re-elected. </p>
<p>Corporate borrowers have issued 35.44 billion reais ($15.24
billion) of bonds in the first eight months of the year, a 7.8
percent decrease from a year ago and the least since 2010,
according to the most recent data from Anbima, Brazil''s capital
markets association. </p>
<p>With the first round of elections less than three weeks
away, polls show Rousseff is regaining the popular support she
lost earlier this month. That''s revived concern a victory by the
incumbent will mean four more years of fiscal policies that led
to Brazil''s first recession since 2009, which may deter
companies from borrowing to expand, according to JPMorgan Chase
 Co. and Banco Votorantim SA. This month, companies have issued
2 billion reais of bonds, less than half as much as a year ago. </p>
<p>Companies are waiting until there is more clarity on what
the next government will be like, Ricardo Leoni, the head of
Brazil''s debt capital markets at JPMorgan, said in a telephone
interview from Sao Paulo. </p>
<p>Officials from the president''s office didn''t reply to e-mails and a call seeking comment. </p>
<p>Assuming Rousseff is one of the top finishers in first-round voting on Oct. 5, she would then probably garner 41
percent of the vote in an Oct. 26 election runoff, according to
a Vox Populi poll released Sept. 15. </p>
<h2>Dead Heat </h2>
<p>That puts her in a statistical tie with opposition
candidate Marina Silva, who received support from 42 percent of
those polled. The Sept. 13-14 survey of 2,000 people has a
margin of error of 2.2 percentage points. Silva''s lead was seven
percentage points in an Aug. 31-Sept. 2 poll. </p>
<p>An Ibope poll published yesterday showed a runoff between
Rousseff and Marina Silva would be too close to call while
backing for third-place candidate Aecio Neves increased.
Rousseff would win 36 percent of voter support in the first
round, with 30 percent for Silva and 19 percent for Neves,
according to the Sept. 13-15 survey. In an Oct. 26 runoff, Silva
would have 43 percent of voter support, compared with 40 percent
for Rousseff, according to the poll published on Jornal Nacional
television. </p>
<p>In the past three weeks, Rousseff has stepped up attacks
against Silva, saying the former environment minister doesn''t
have the experience to lead and would reduce investments in
offshore oil and gas reserves. Silva says the incumbent''s
policies contributed to a recession in the first half of this
year and quicker inflation. </p>
<h2>Government''s Role </h2>
<p>Since taking office in January 2011, Rousseff has increased
the government''s role in companies, changing concession-renewal
rules to lower electricity rates and capping gasoline prices to
tame inflation that last month exceed the 6.5 percent limit of
the central bank''s target range. Policy makers raised the
benchmark interest rate by 3.75 percentage points over nine
straight meetings through April before holding it at a two-year
high of 11 percent for the past three. </p>
<p>Latin America''s largest economy shrank 0.6 percent in the
April-June period from the previous three months, after
contracting 0.2 percent in the first quarter, the national
statistics agency said Aug. 29. </p>
<p>The real declined 0.3 percent to 2.3388 per dollar today as
of 2:40 p.m. in New York. </p>
<h2>Average Rates </h2>
<p>Silva has promised to cut inflation by half and called for
a fiscal-responsibility body to independently monitor budgets
and spending to verify that the government is complying with
fiscal targets. </p>
<p>The average interest rate on floating-rate local bonds with
maturities longer than 12 months issued this year was 10.99
percent, 0.12 percentage point above the average in the same
span last year, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>This has been a tough year for local companies, with all
the concerns regarding politics and the economic scenario we''ll
have starting next year,Carolina Lacerda, the head of
investment banking at UBS AG''s Brazil unit and a director at
Anbima, said in an interview in Sao Paulo. Companies are
cautious, especially because the cost of funding, in general, is
at a very high level. </p>
<p>While Brazilian companies are staying away from the local
debt market, they''re boosting overseas offerings to lock in
borrowing costs before U.S. policy makers raise interest rates.
They have issued $42.7 billion this year, a 45 percent increase
from the same period in 2013, data compiled by Bloomberg show. </p>
<h2>Growth Outlook </h2>
<p>Ricardo Carvalho, an analyst at Fitch Ratings, said that if
economic growth begins to recover later this year, issuance in
the local market will probably rebound. </p>
<p>Brazilian companies aren''t selling bonds because they are
not spending much, he said in an interview in Sao Paulo.
That could change once the economy starts to improve, which
could happen before the end of this semester. </p>
<p>While Carvalho sees the potential for growth to accelerate,
Moody''s Investors Service cut the outlook on Brazil''s credit
rating to negative on Sept. 9, saying the economy is unlikely to
rebound in the short term. </p>
<p>Companies seem to be waiting for what will happen in the
macroeconomic scenario and after elections before selling more
debt, Reinaldo Lacerda, who helps manage 43 billion reais in
assets as the investment director at the wealth management
division of Banco Votorantim SA, said in an interview in Sao
Paulo. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Fion Li" date="Sep 17, 2014  5:02 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-17/goldman-sees-surprising-china-demand-for-hong-kong-stocks.html"><headline>Goldman Sees Surprising China Demand for Hong Kong Stocks</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chinese purchases of Hong Kong
stocks through a planned exchange link may exceed estimates as
individual investors buy casino and technology shares
unavailable in Shanghai, according to Goldman Sachs Group Inc. </p>
<p>The link will give wealthy mainland investors access to 266
stocks traded in Hong Kong, including Galaxy Entertainment Group
Ltd. (27) and Tencent Holdings Ltd. (700) China currently limits most
overseas share investments to those made through asset managers. </p>
<p>We might be surprised by retail participation once the
stock connect is launched, given mainland investors'' preference
to invest and trade themselves instead of buying mutual funds,
Christina Ma, the head of Goldman''s cash trading, equities in
Asia Pacific ex-Japan, said in an interview in Hong Kong on
Sept. 15. </p>
<p>Goldman''s view follows a CLSA Ltd. survey last month
showing 77 percent of mainland investors don''t plan to
participate in the bourse link, turned off by rules on the
minimum account size and the exclusion of small-cap stocks.
China, the biggest emerging economy, is counting on a successful
exchange link to help liberalize its financial system, increase
the role of the yuan and give its citizens more investment
channels amid a slumping property market and increased risks
from local wealth-management products. </p>




Photographer: Brent Lewin/Bloomberg

<p>
An employee pulls a luggage trolley outside Galaxy Macau casino resort in Macau, China. Galaxy Entertainment, the Macau casino operator, and Tencent, Asia''s biggest listed Internet company, have more than tripled in the past three years, making them the best performers on Hong Kong''s benchmark Hang Seng Index. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Cristiane Lucchesi" date="Sep 18, 2014  4:37 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-18/goldman-s-leme-says-brazil-unit-returned-to-profitability.html"><headline>Goldman''s Leme Says Brazil Unit Returned to Profitability</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)''s Brazil
unit returned to profitability in the fourth quarter as the
departure of several managing directors helped cut costs and
fixed-income gains offset an investment-banking revenue drop. </p>
<p>We made the right decision in anticipating that this year
would be less vibrant for investment banking, and had some
opportunities for cost reductions when some executives left
after receiving good job offers, Paulo Leme, named Goldman
Sachs''s president and chief executive officer for Brazil today,
said in an interview in Sao Paulo. Leme, 59, didn''t say how long
the New York-based company had been losing money in Brazil. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs eliminated bonuses for some bankers in Brazil
this year, contributing to the departures of five executives in
January, people familiar with the matter said in February. The
company reduced employees in investment banking to 25 from 45,
the people said. Fabio Bicudo, the former co-head of investment
banking, left in January to become CEO of Rio de Janeiro-based
power company Eneva SA, Leme said. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs began trading Brazil Treasury bonds in the
second half of last year, and now we are the most active bank
in the primary market and one of the top four in the secondary
market, competing head-to-head with local players, Alejandro Vollbrechthausen, whom Leme is replacing, said in an interview. </p>
<p>Vollbrechthausen will move to New York after Leme''s
appointment is approved by Brazil''s central bank, to become
Goldman Sachs''s head of fixed-income, currencies and commodities
sales for Latin America. Leme was previously chairman for
Brazil, a position that will be eliminated. </p>
<h2>Private Equity </h2>
<p>The drag from lower investment-banking revenue is also
being offset by gains in private equity, structured credit,
mezzanine financing and non-performing loan acquisitions, said
Vollbrechthausen, who is a Goldman Sachs partner, a nod to the
firm''s history as a private partnership before going public in
1999. Leme is a managing director, one level below partner. </p>
<p>With about 300 employees in Brazil, about the same as the
level at the start of last year, the bank is well-staffed
for now, Leme said. </p>
<p>At least nine managing directors in Brazil left Goldman
Sachs during 2013 after the bank halted its growth plans when
the economy expanded less than analysts estimated. Goldman
Sachs''s revenue from investment banking had been falling in
Brazil while trading and wealth-management fees increased,
people familiar with the matter said last year. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hannah Elliott" date="Sep 18, 2014  5:14 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-18/electric-motorcycles-the-race-to-become-the-two-wheeled-tesla.html"><headline>Electric Motorcycles: The Race to Become the Two-Wheeled Tesla</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Mark Buche, 28, is just the type of guy Harley-Davidson (HOG) wants buying its bikes.</p><p>He wears vintage selvedge denim and Persol sunglasses. He trims his tawny long hair at an old-style barbershop in Long Beach, California, and camps in Big Sur with his 1975 Honda CB and a few similarly inclined twentysomething friends. </p><p>Hog-riding fat cats they''re not. But with their old caf racers and leather jackets scuffed more from use than the demands of fashion, they''re far from dilettantes. And motorcycle companies like Harley are targeting them with a provocative idea: Why not make an electric motorcycle that is as fast and good-looking as its conventional counterparts? </p><p>Everybody is very concerned with getting this new young rider, said Mark Hoyer, the editor-in-chief of Cycle World, on a recent phone call. And younger people are realizing these electric bikes are genuinely fast. In fact, with the kind of performance electric motorcycles have these days, anybody who rides would be impressed.</p><p>No one thinks electric bikes will save the industry -- or that the industry even needs saving, although sales have been gradually declining since record highs in the early 2000s -- but they will be a key factor in attracting the next generation of enthusiasts. The folks at Harley-Davidson certainly think so: Earlier this year they unveiled Project LiveWire, a futuristic 74-horsepower electric motorcycle prototype that goes 53 miles between charges and hits 92 miles per hour at top speed. If 53 miles seems paltry as far as road trips go, that''s because it is: You can barely get out of town on that, Hoyer pointed out. But Harley says it''s a start. Company reps are testing reactions to the bike from enthusiasts and prospective riders alike over the next few months, but doesn''t plan to actually produce LiveWire in volume. </p>
<p>Harley-Davidson is taking their 74-horsepower Project LiveWire bike on a roadshow to gauge reactions from enthusiasts and prospective riders alike.</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Sep 18, 2014  4:39 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-18/morgan-stanley-rises-to-post-crisis-record-as-banks-rally.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Rises to Post-Crisis Record as Banks Rally</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) shares rose to the
highest since the financial crisis and Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)
closed at an almost five-year peak as U.S. stocks climbed to a
record. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley jumped 1.6 percent to $36.13, the highest
since Sept. 12, 2008, the last business day before Lehman
Brothers Holdings Inc. went bankrupt. Goldman Sachs rose for a
seventh straight day, the longest streak since 2006, to $187.89. </p>
<p>The two investment banks, which converted to bank holding
companies during the 2008 financial crisis, have overcome doubts
about their survival as an improving economy helps U.S. stocks
reach record levels. Surging deal fees and booming markets have
helped allay concerns that lower trading volumes and stricter
capital rules are pressuring returns. </p>
<p>America comes back, it''s always come back. Frankly it''s
done better than I might have expected in the depths of the
financial crisis, Berkshire Hathaway Inc. Chairman Warren Buffett said today in a Bloomberg Television interview where he
sat next to Goldman Sachs Chief Executive Officer Lloyd C. Blankfein. Policy makers got the locomotive back on the
tracks. And it started from a dead start, but it has moved a
long way and it continues to move, Buffett said. </p>
<p>Berkshire has 13.1 million Goldman Sachs shares, valued at
more than $2 billion, that Buffett obtained through warrants
acquired as part of a 2008 capital injection in the bank.
Goldman Sachs in 2011 redeemed a $5 billion preferred stake on
which Berkshire earned a 10 percent annual coupon. </p>
<h2>Enjoying Payoff </h2>
<p>Morgan Stanley has sold investors on a safer business model
more dependent on its retail brokerage, while Goldman Sachs has
produced higher returns and says it will benefit when markets
become more active. Both are based in New York. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley is enjoying the payoffs from years of
investment to fix and rebuild the business, Christian Bolu, a
bank analyst at Credit Suisse Group AG who has a neutral
rating on the stock, wrote in a note to investors this week.
Morgan Stanley is well positioned to benefit from an improving
operating environment and a more favorable interest-rate
backdrop. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley has boosted margins in its wealth-management
division, which more than doubled in size from the firm''s 2009
purchase of Smith Barney from Citigroup Inc. It also shrank its
fixed-income trading business and has pledged to return more of
the capital that supported that business to shareholders. </p>
<h2>Tepid Support </h2>
<p>Still, the firm''s return on equity, a measure of
profitability, was about 8 percent in the first half of the
year, below Chief Executive Officer James Gorman''s target of 10
percent. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs''s 11 percent gain since Aug. 7 has come amid
tepid support for the shares among analysts. Just nine of the 34
analysts covering the bank recommended buying the shares,
compared with more than 80 percent four years ago. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs President Gary Cohn has said that
abnormal markets featuring low rates and low volatility have
crimped trading revenue, which fell 12 percent in the first half
of the year to the lowest since the crisis. </p>
<p>Still, rising markets and an increased number of mergers
have boosted its three other units, which all had revenue
increases in the first six months. The firm produced an 11
percent return on equity, ahead of Citigroup and Bank of America
Corp. and on par with JPMorgan Chase  Co. </p>
<p>We expect GS will continue to deliver fundamental results
that are at the high end of peers, Bolu wrote in a note last
week. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Cristiane Lucchesi" date="Sep 18, 2014  4:37 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-18/goldman-s-leme-says-brazil-unit-returned-to-profitability.html"><headline>Goldman''s Leme Says Brazil Unit Returned to Profitability</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)''s Brazil
unit returned to profitability in the fourth quarter as the
departure of several managing directors helped cut costs and
fixed-income gains offset an investment-banking revenue drop. </p>
<p>We made the right decision in anticipating that this year
would be less vibrant for investment banking, and had some
opportunities for cost reductions when some executives left
after receiving good job offers, Paulo Leme, named Goldman
Sachs''s president and chief executive officer for Brazil today,
said in an interview in Sao Paulo. Leme, 59, didn''t say how long
the New York-based company had been losing money in Brazil. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs eliminated bonuses for some bankers in Brazil
this year, contributing to the departures of five executives in
January, people familiar with the matter said in February. The
company reduced employees in investment banking to 25 from 45,
the people said. Fabio Bicudo, the former co-head of investment
banking, left in January to become CEO of Rio de Janeiro-based
power company Eneva SA, Leme said. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs began trading Brazil Treasury bonds in the
second half of last year, and now we are the most active bank
in the primary market and one of the top four in the secondary
market, competing head-to-head with local players, Alejandro Vollbrechthausen, whom Leme is replacing, said in an interview. </p>
<p>Vollbrechthausen will move to New York after Leme''s
appointment is approved by Brazil''s central bank, to become
Goldman Sachs''s head of fixed-income, currencies and commodities
sales for Latin America. Leme was previously chairman for
Brazil, a position that will be eliminated. </p>
<h2>Private Equity </h2>
<p>The drag from lower investment-banking revenue is also
being offset by gains in private equity, structured credit,
mezzanine financing and non-performing loan acquisitions, said
Vollbrechthausen, who is a Goldman Sachs partner, a nod to the
firm''s history as a private partnership before going public in
1999. Leme is a managing director, one level below partner. </p>
<p>With about 300 employees in Brazil, about the same as the
level at the start of last year, the bank is well-staffed
for now, Leme said. </p>
<p>At least nine managing directors in Brazil left Goldman
Sachs during 2013 after the bank halted its growth plans when
the economy expanded less than analysts estimated. Goldman
Sachs''s revenue from investment banking had been falling in
Brazil while trading and wealth-management fees increased,
people familiar with the matter said last year. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Neil Weinberg and Michael J. Moore" date="Sep 18, 2014  3:28 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-18/morgan-stanley-to-eat-mutual-fund-losses-after-tech-snafu.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley to Cover Some Fund Losses After Tech Snafu</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) will swallow some
losses incurred by customers who bought mutual funds after the
bank failed to make the fund prospectuses accessible online. </p>
<p>Brokerage clients who elected electronic delivery of
documents can rescind purchases of mutual funds they bought from
Nov. 8, 2013, through Aug. 14, New York-based Morgan Stanley
said in a letter addressed to fund companies and obtained by
Bloomberg News. Customers who have already sold such holdings at
a loss can be made whole, the bank said. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s brokerage, the world''s largest by
financial advisers, has 4 million clients with $2 trillion in
assets. While the bank didn''t provide an estimate of what it
would cost to cover client losses, doing so may shield the
company from litigation, according to the letter. </p>
<p>By conducting the rescission offer, the bank wrote,
clients should be precluded in the future from requiring us to
repurchase fund shares or maintaining an action against Morgan
Stanley. </p>
<p>The brokerage offers more than 4,000 mutual funds from more
than 300 companies, according to its website. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s costs may be muted by the fact very few
sectors lost money during the period, said Russell Kinnel,
director of research at Morningstar Inc. Commodities and
precious metals were among those areas that saw declines in the
past year, Kinnel said. </p>
<h2>System Issue'' </h2>
<p>The Standard  Poor''s 500 Index (SPX) rose in eight of the past
10 months, and U.S. corporate bonds have returned 6.24 percent
since Nov. 8, according to Bank of America Merrill Lynch index
data. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley better just hope the market holds up the
30 days of the rescission period, Kinnel said. </p>
<p>A system issue, which was fixed as of Aug. 15, caused a
failure to deliver the prospectuses in a timely manner, Morgan
Stanley said. The bank said it has notified the Securities and
Exchange Commission and the Financial Industry Regulatory
Authority about the mishap. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley bought Smith Barney from Citigroup Inc. in
2009, more than doubling the size of its wealth-management unit.
The firm completed the integration of the brokerage''s technology
platform in 2012, and last year Greg Fleming, 51, who runs the
business, pledged to spend $500 million to improve the systems
after flaws frustrated employees. </p>
<p>The issue was caused by an inadvertent error, Christine Jockle, a Morgan Stanley spokeswoman, said in a statement.
Morgan Stanley Wealth Management discovered this problem,
corrected it, and is offering clients the opportunity to rescind
affected purchases. </p>
<p>Jockle declined to estimate the cost to cover client
losses. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Sep 18, 2014 12:43 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-18/microsoft-cuts-2-100-workers-as-part-of-restructuring.html"><headline>Microsoft Cuts 2,100 Workers as Part of Restructuring</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) is firing 2,100
workers today, part of a plan announced in July to eliminate
18,000 jobs to streamline the workforce and integrate the
acquisition of Nokia Oyj''s handset unit. </p>
<p>The job reductions will take place across the company in
various divisions, said Peter Wootton, a spokesman for
Microsoft. In the Puget Sound region, where Microsoft is based,
747 people are being cut. </p>
<p>Nadella has been aggressive in making changes since he
became CEO in February, replacing Steve Ballmer. He has shuffled
management, emphasized making Microsoft''s software available for
all types of devices, and announced the job cuts. Earlier this
week, Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft said it would buy
Mojang AB, maker of the Minecraft video game, for $2.5 billion
in Nadella''s first deal as CEO. </p>
<p>Microsoft shares were little changed at $46.55 at 12:34
p.m. in New York. The stock has gained 24 percent this year. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Carroll and Alan Katz" date="Sep 19, 2014  4:27 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-19/exxon-gets-safety-extension-on-u-s-sanctions-on-arctic-w.html"><headline>Exxon Gets U.S. Sanctions Extension to Shut Russian Arctic Well</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) said the U.S. government is giving the company more time to shut its Russian Arctic well beyond the deadline for sanctions aimed at halting the $700 million project. </p> <p>Exxon asked Washington for an extension to allow it to continue performing shut-down work on the Universitetskaya-1 (University-1) well in Russia''s Kara Sea to make sure the well was safe before it''s temporarily abandoned. The Irving, Texas-based company already had ceased drilling the offshore well after U.S. sanctions set a Sept. 26 deadline for ending the work. </p> <p>The U.S. Treasury Department, recognizing the complexity of the University-1 well and the sensitive Kara Sea arctic environment, has granted a license to Exxon Mobil and other U.S. contractors and persons involved to enable the safe and responsible winding down of operations related to this exploration well, Exxon said in a statement today. </p> <p>The most-recent round of sanctions intended to punish Russia for its involvement in separatist violence in Ukraine barred U.S. and European Union companies from helping Russia exploit oil resources in the Arctic, deep seas and shale formations. </p> <p>Waging Financial War</p><p>The measures had prompted Exxon and its partner OAO Rosneft (ROSN) to temporarily halt drilling at the well, which lies about 260 feet (79 meters) beneath the sea surface off Siberia''s northern coast, according to three people familiar with the project. The well is aiming to tap a resource estimated to hold as much as 9 billion barrels of crude, worth $880 billion at current prices. </p> <h2>More Time </h2> <p>Exxon sought the exemption from the deadline after engineers involved in the project warned they needed more time to properly plug the well with cement and conduct tests to ensure there are no leaks, cracks or faults that could damage the reservoir or allow environmental contamination, according to a source with knowledge of the matter who asked not to be identified because he was not authorized to speak publicly. </p> <p>Exxon and Rosneft are exploring a geologic formation never before drilled by humans, which means the pressure changes, layer densities and temperatures at various depths are unknown, increasing the risks of unexpected collapses or pressure bursts. For that reason, the engineers closing the well need to map the formation a foot at a time as they back out of the well, a process that can take weeks. </p> <h2>Slowing Progress </h2> <p>The halt at Universitetskaya-1 is a blow to Russian President Vladimir Putin''s quest to find a new generation of oil fields to replace declining output from some of the country''s Soviet-era reserves. The Russian oil industry is dependent on expertise and equipment from the U.S. and Europe to penetrate crude reservoirs that are deeper, denser and more remote than anything they''ve attempted before. </p> <p>The disruption also is a setback for Exxon as the company seeks to lift production that touched a 4-year low in 2013 as the rate it''s replacing output with new discoveries tumbled to the lowest in half a decade. </p> <p>Exxon''s $3.2 billion exploration pact with Moscow-based Rosneft is a linchpin of the U.S. company''s bid to spur production and reserves growth in the next decade, said Brian Youngberg, an analyst at Edward Jones  Co. in St. Louis. </p> <h2>Enormous'' Potential </h2> <p>The Arctic drilling potential for Exxon is really enormous, said Youngberg, who has a hold rating on Exxon shares. It''s one of the key growth areas they''re looking to post-2020. </p> <p>Rosneft''s press office in Moscow declined to comment. Hagar Chemali, a U.S. Treasury Department spokesperson, declined to comment and referred a Bloomberg News inquiry to Exxon. </p> <p>Exxon is using the West Alpha rig owned by Seadrill Ltd. (SDRL)''s North Atlantic (NADL) Drilling unit at the Universitetskaya-1 site about 70 miles offshore. The rig departed a Norwegian shipyard in July and sailed around the northern coast of Scandinavia and into Russian territory right before the U.S. and EU prohibited exports of gear for Arctic, deep-water and shale drilling. </p> <p>Within weeks, the U.S. and EU moved to close loopholes in the sanctions by also banning the export of services such as engineering expertise and geological analysis for Russian Arctic, deep-water and shale projects. </p> <p>Exxon rose 0.5 percent to $97.12 at the close of trading in New York. Seadrill fell 4.1 percent today in Oslo to its lowest closing price since November 2011. </p> <p>The measures left untouched so-called conventional oil developments that aren''t part of Putin''s hunt for next-generation oilfields, including the Sakhalin-1 development off Russia''s Pacific Coast managed by Exxon and Rosneft. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lynn Doan" date="Sep 19, 2014  3:10 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-19/chevron-hires-investment-bank-to-sell-kapolei-refinery-in-hawaii.html"><headline>Chevron Seeking Buyer for Kapolei Oil Refinery in Hawaii</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX), the world''s third-largest oil producer by market value, is seeking a buyer for one
of its smallest refineries, the Kapolei plant on the Hawaiian
island of Oahu. </p>
<p>The sale of the the 54,000-barrel-a-day Kapolei complex is
part of a larger plan to divest $10 billion worth of assets over
the next three years. Closing the plant would leave Hawaii with
a single 93,500-barrel-a-day refinery, which Par Petroleum Corp. (PARR)
bought from Tesoro Corp. (TSO) last year. </p>
<p>Chevron shares were up $1.03, or 0.8 percent, at $125.17 at
2:42 p.m. New York time. Par Petroleum Corp., which operates the
only other plant in Hawaii, gained 6 percent to $16.58. </p>
<p>Chevron has decided to engage an investment banking firm
to identify potential parties interested in the purchase of our
assets in Hawaii, Braden Reddall, a spokesman at Chevron''s
headquarters in San Ramon, California, said by telephone late
yesterday. No decision has been made at this time other than
to determine the level of interest of potential buyers. </p>
<p>Deutsche Bank has been hired by Chevron, two people with
direct knowledge of the situation said, while asking not to be
identified because the information isn''t public. </p>
<p>Al Chee, a Chevron spokesman at the refinery, declined by
telephone to comment. Ari Cohen, a spokesman for Deutsche Bank
in New York, declined by e-mail to comment. </p>
<h2>Fourth-Smallest </h2>
<p>Chevron previously considered turning the Kapolei complex
into a terminal. After a review three years ago, the company
decided to continue to run it as a refinery. It''s Chevron''s
fourth-smallest by capacity, data compiled by Bloomberg show. </p>
<p>Selling the refinery in 2011 was not as competitive as
improving its value, Michael Wirth, Chevron''s executive vice
president of downstream and chemicals, said in a conference call
with analysts at the time of the review. </p>
<p>Everybody realizes that''s a small refinery, he said.
It''s not an especially complex refinery. It''s got a somewhat
isolated and finite market. And so we''re really in the space of
optimizing every dimension of performance there. </p>
<p>The refinery ran 39,000 barrels a day in 2013, down from
46,000 in 2012, the company said in its 10-K annual report. Last
year, the plant imported 87 percent of its oil from Indonesia,
Thailand and Vietnam, Energy Information Administration data
show. </p>
<p>Earlier this month, Chevron extended a supply contract with
Hawaiian Electric Co. Inc. for low-sulfur fuel. Meanwhile, Par
Petroleum said it was losing its contracts with the utility in
December and was aggressively pursuing other outlets. </p>
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. and Royal Dutch Shell Plc are the two
largest oil producers. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hannah Elliott" date="Sep 19, 2014  9:35 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-19/electric-motorcycles-the-race-to-become-the-two-wheeled-tesla.html"><headline>Electric Motorcycles: The Race to Become the Two-Wheeled Tesla</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Mark Buche, 28, is just the type of
guy Harley-Davidson (HOG) (HOG) wants buying its bikes. </p>
<p>He wears vintage selvedge denim and Persol sunglasses. He
trims his tawny long hair at an old-style barbershop in Long
Beach, California, and camps in Big Sur with his 1975 Honda CBR
and a few similarly inclined twentysomething friends. </p>
<p>Hog-riding fat cats they''re not. But with their old cafe
racers and leather jackets scuffed more from use than the
demands of fashion, they''re far from dilettantes. And motorcycle
companies like Harley are targeting them with a provocative
idea: Why not make an electric motorcycle that is as fast and
good-looking as its conventional counterparts? </p>
<p>Everybody is very concerned with getting this new young
rider, said Mark Hoyer, the editor-in-chief of Cycle World, on
a recent phone call. And younger people are realizing these
electric bikes are genuinely fast. In fact, with the kind of
performance electric motorcycles have these days, anybody who
rides would be impressed. </p>
<p>No one thinks electric bikes will save the industry -- or
that the industry even needs saving, although sales have been
gradually declining since record highs in the early 2000s -- but
they will be a key factor in attracting the next generation of
enthusiasts. The folks at Harley-Davidson certainly think so:
Earlier this year they unveiled Project LiveWire, a futuristic
74-horsepower electric motorcycle prototype that goes 53 miles
between charges and hits 92 miles per hour at top speed. If 53
miles seems paltry as far as road trips go, that''s because it
is: You can barely get out of town on that, Hoyer pointed
out. But Harley says it''s a start. Company reps are testing
reactions to the bike from enthusiasts and prospective riders
alike over the next few months, but doesn''t plan to actually
produce LiveWire in volume. </p>
<h2>Mixed Reviews </h2>
<p>For many young riders, the aesthetic of the bike is
essential, and response on LiveWire''s low-slung body has been
mixed. </p>
<p>I''m not completely sold on the design, but I definitely
want to try it, Adam Kallen said recently outside his
Brooklyn-based motorcycle coffee shop, Jane Motorcycles. Kallen
owns a Ducati and offered one caveat: It has to sound good.
That''s non-negotiable. Until then, the jury is still out. </p>
<p>It''s true. While the near silence of Tesla''s Model S
affords it a certain futuristic lan that bolsters the sedan''s
appeal, the low whir of electric motorcycles, on the other hand,
can act as a detractor. Many people buy motorcycles precisely
because they like their guttural roar. They like to feel the
rumble of the handlebars as they release the clutch and open
that throaty engine. </p>
<h2>Hear The Roar </h2>
<p>Critics of electric motorcycles say the sound of a
traditional bike''s engine alerts drivers and pedestrians about
its proximity, while a silent bike is easily overlooked.
Proponents counter that if a rider plans to rely simply on the
sound of the engine to protect him from a collision, he''s
already not riding safe enough. What''s more, they add, the quiet
nature of electric bikes makes them perfect for riding through
close-quartered city streets and back-road trails because they
don''t disturb the neighbors, whether human or animal. </p>
<p>Harley-Davidson has fabricated a distinctive sound for the
LiveWire bike so as to uphold that audio covenant with hog
loyalists. And it''s hardly alone in this battle to become the
Tesla (TSLA) (TSLA) of motorcycles. Within the last year, electric
bikes have become significantly more powerful, smoother and
longer-lasting than the first electrified attempts that started
appearing five years ago -- those early Zeros, Brammos, and
obscure Chinese makes were closer to glorified Vespas than
anything Ducati or Triumph would build. </p>
<h2>Increasing Power </h2>
<p>In contrast, Zero''s latest, the $17,000 SR, has highly
tuned suspension and power-train technologies, not to mention a
motor that hits 60mph in 3.3 seconds. A seven-hour charge gets a
range of around 130 miles. Brammo''s $11,000 Enertia Plus gets
434 MPGe (that''s electric miles-per-gallon equivalent) with a
top speed of 60mph, and the $30,000, 160hp Mission R racer has a
top speed of more than 150mph with a sub-3-second, 0-60mph
sprint time. Earlier this year the Italian firm Energica, led by
its young CEO, Livia Cevolini, debuted the $68,000, 134hp Ego 45
superbike (0-60mph in 2.9 seconds). It charges in just three
hours. </p>
<p>The electric bike does all of the things I ride for --
without any of the drama. Scot Harden, vice president of
global marketing for Zero Motorcycles said last month in New
York. I ride for the excitement, the thrill, the acceleration,
the sense of control, the sense of freedom. The Zero
Streetfighter gives me all of that. What it doesn''t give me is
loud noise, vibration, heat, exhaust fumes, or oil stains in the
garage. Plus I don''t have any routine maintenance on the power
train. I don''t have to work on it. I just basically ride it. </p>
<h2>Room For Growth </h2>
<p>The idea is that these electrics, with their 100-plus-mile-range, zero emissions, and gearless twist-and-go acceleration
are perfect both for urban and off-road fun. And that their
silent, maintenance-light sensibility might attract new riders,
particularly women, intimidated by the heavy clutches and grimy
responsibilities associated with caf racers and street bikes. </p>
<p>There''s certainly room for growth: Even though their
numbers have increased by double digits since 2003, women
represent only 25% of motorcycle riders nationwide, according to
the Motorcycle Industry Council. Last year BMW, Harley-Davidson,
Honda, Kawasaki, KTM, Piaggio, Suzuki, Triumph, and Yamaha sold
561,000 bikes nationwide, up from 557,000 in 2012 but down a
staggering 53% from the 1.2 million sold in 2006. This year
motorcycle sales remain relatively unchanged, according to MIC,
which tallied 139,922 new units sold in Q1, 17 units higher than
the same period in 2013. </p>
<h2>A Delicate Balance </h2>
<p>But if electric bikes hope to play a real role in boosting
the bottom line, they''ll have to reach that delicate balance
between batteries that can offer enough power for long rides but
that are also relatively lightweight and affordable enough for
regular consumers. Current price premiums on the smallest,
strongest, best lithium-ion batteries pump MSRPs up tens of
thousands of dollars, forcing those bikes far out of reach for
the average consumer. Add to that the fact that gasoline-powered
motorcycles are already fuel-efficient -- a Ducati Monster 696
gets 40 MPG on a 4-gallon tank, plenty of room for long
adventures without frequent pit stops -- leaving some to
question whether an electrified bike is even necessary. </p>
<p>Of course, for young riders with discretionary income and a
thirst for novelty, those things don''t matter so much. Just ask
Buche. </p>
<p>There is a different tool for each job, he said
grinning over coffee in a West Hollywood cafe. Some
motorcycles are magic bullets that do everything really well,
like a Swiss Army knife. But even if it''s your favorite bike,
you''re going to park it sometimes. Electric motorcycles are
really fun. I want them to come in a serious way -- and
quickly. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joseph Ciolli" date="Sep 19, 2014 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-19/jpmorgan-no-1-stock-picker-for-fifth-year.html"><headline>JPMorgan No. 1 Stock Picker for Fifth Year</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>When Citigroup Inc. (C) announced a plan to fire thousands of workers and scale back international operations in December 2012, it looked like one more piece of bad news for the big bank, which went on to fail its second consecutive U.S. Federal Reserve stress test. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs Group (GS) Inc. analyst Richard Ramsden didn''t see it that way. </p> <p>On Jan. 3, Ramsden lifted his rating on the New Yorkbased bank to what Goldman calls a conviction buy, even though the shares were near a 17-week high and some analysts thought they were poised for a downturn, Bloomberg Markets magazine will report in its October issue. </p> <p>The strategy we had going into 2013 was to look for restructuring stories that we felt were mispriced, and Citigroup was one, Ramsden says. We felt that the stronger banks had already done a pretty good job reducing funding costs and expenses and had less room to grow earnings. </p> <p>Related: The Dumb Money Is Getting Smarter Every Day</p><p>Citigroup''s shares surged 26 percent in the 11 months following his call, beating the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index. Ramsden''s confidence in Citi didn''t last out the year. On Dec. 3, he cut the rating to a hold and assigned a strong buy rating to U.S. Bancorp. (USB) He was right again. Citigroup slipped 8.5 percent through the end of the first quarter of 2014, while U.S. Bancorp climbed 9.9 percent over the period. </p> 
<p></p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jody Shenn" date="Sep 22, 2014  4:41 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-22/jpmorgan-mortgage-unit-garry-cipponeri-said-to-leave-bank.html"><headline>JPMorgan Mortgage-Unit Garry Cipponeri Said to Leave Bank</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Garry Cipponeri, the head of
capital markets for JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s U.S. mortgage unit,
is leaving the bank to start a new company, according to two
people with knowledge of the move. </p>
<p>Cipponeri, a senior vice president who joined JPMorgan in
2004 from Citigroup Inc., is planning to start a firm called
TradeRoom Capital Partners that will trade mortgages that
haven''t been packaged into bonds and do consulting, said the
people, who asked not to be named because the decision hasn''t
been announced. </p>
<p>He declined to comment when reached by telephone, as did
Jason Lobo, a spokesman for the New York-based bank. </p>
<p>JPMorgan is the second-largest U.S. home lender after Wells
Fargo  Co., according to newsletter Inside Mortgage Finance.
Cipponeri often represented the bank during panels at industry
events, such as a Mortgage Bankers Association conference in New
York in May and a workshop sponsored by the Federal Reserve
Banks of Boston and New York in 2012. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Daria Solovieva and Dana El Baltaji" date="Sep 22, 2014  7:30 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-22/goldman-sukuk-seen-too-risky-for-u-s-imitators-islamic-finance.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Sukuk Seen as Too Risky for U.S. Imitators</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>U.S. banks will probably wait to see if issuing Shariah-compliant bonds is worth the trouble after it took Goldman Sachs Group Inc. three years to sell its debut sukuk. </p> <p>Islamic finance in the U.S. is still underdeveloped, and misconceptions associated with it taint the industry, according to King  Spalding LLP, an adviser on Shariah transactions in the country for 35 years. HSBC Holdings Plc, the biggest underwriter of sukuk this year after Malaysia''s CIMB Group Holdings Bhd., says the need for tangible assets to structure deals, and the lack of legislation to address taxation issues, makes selling Islamic bonds a challenge. </p> <p>It''s highly likely that Goldman will be the sole player in the Islamic finance market in any meaningful way for the near term, George Thomas Conboy, chairman of Rochester, New York-based Brighton Securities Corp., a financial services company, said by phone from Istanbul on Sept. 18. There aren''t as many players willing to take risks in that area until Goldman blazes a trail and it''s clear that Islamic finance can be properly structured and profitable. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs, the fifth-biggest bank in the U.S., sold its debut sukuk last week, three years after its first foray into Islamic capital markets ended with controversy over the debt''s structure. It''s the fourth U.S.-based issuer to sell the securities. Borrowers raised $2 trillion from all bond sales in America last year, more than 46 times the amount sold in the Shariah market and more than the value of Islamic financial assets globally. </p> <h2>Negative Perception </h2> <p>Hong Kong, the U.K., South Africa and Sharjah, one of seven sheikhdoms in the United Arab Emirates, are among borrowers that have sold Islamic bonds for the first time this year. New York-based Goldman Sachs''s five-year notes yielded 21 basis points more than similar maturity non-Shariah compliant debt it issued in January at 3:21 p.m. in Dubai. The bank attracted orders for three times the $500 million it sold. </p> <p>Islamic finance''s level of awareness and depth of knowhow in general in the U.S. is at best at its infancy, with negative connotations stemming misconceptions, Rizwan Kanji, a Dubai-based partner at King  Spalding, said by telephone from Dubai Sept. 18. </p> <p>Islam is the most negatively perceived religion in the U.S., followed by atheism, according to a study by the Washington-based Pew Research Center published in July. About 1.9 million Muslims live in the country, the seventh-biggest religious group among about 319 million people, according to CIA World Factbook data. </p> <h2>Risk Premium </h2> <p>While Goldman Sachs''s sukuk won''t create a market of new issuers in the U.S., frequent conventional issuers will start to see sukuk as a new avenue for tighter pricing or diversification of their investor base, Kanji said. Citigroup Inc., Bank of America Corp. and JPMorgan Chase  Co. were among the biggest issuers of debt last year, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p> <p>Rob Julavits, a spokesman for Citigroup, Zia Ahmed from Bank of America and Jessica Francisco from JPMorgan declined to comment last week on whether the lenders will be pursuing Islamic financing deals. </p> <h2>Stamp Duties </h2> <p>Borrowers using sukuk need assets to underlie the debt and there''s an additional cost of hiring Shariah scholars or boards to structure the securities. </p> <p>If you''re a U.S. corporate that doesn''t have tangible assets it can utilize, it''s more challenging to structure a sukuk, Mohammed Dawood, HSBC''s Dubai-based global head of sukuk financing, said in a Sept. 11 interview. The U.S. hasn''t passed sukuk-specific legislation, unlike Hong Kong and the U.K., which have passed legislation to address tax and legal impediments. </p> <p>To adhere to Islam''s ban on interest, the bonds pay a return on assets and may attract double charges on stamp duties because of the sale and purchase of goods to back the debt. Profits or capital gains incur taxes, whereas interest is tax deductible. </p> <p>Islamic finance is too new for U.S.-based issuers, and the structures and impediments are too complicated, Conboy said. </p> <p>Anything with Shariah attached to it carries a small risk premium, he said. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Manuel Baigorri, David Welch and Ruth David" date="Sep 23, 2014  4:37 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-23/pfizer-said-to-approach-actavis-to-gauge-interest-in-deal.html"><headline>Pfizer Said to Approach Actavis to Gauge Interest in Deal</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE) has approached Actavis Plc (ACT) to express its interest in an acquisition, people with knowledge of the matter said, as the U.S. drugmaker continues to explore ways to cut its tax rate and gain a new product pipeline. </p> <p>The companies aren''t currently in formal talks and Pfizer hasn''t made an offer, the people said, asking not to be identified because the information is private. The approach comes after Pfizer in May abandoned a $114 billion bid for AstraZeneca Plc -- which would also have let it move its tax domicile abroad in a so-called tax inversion. </p> <p>Actavis, which is run from Parsippany, New Jersey, obtained an Irish tax domicile by acquiring Warner Chilcott Plc last year. Its shares rose 2.2 percent to $240.85 in New York trading today, giving Actavis a market value of about $63.6 billion. </p> <p>Although AstraZeneca rebuffed its approach after Pfizer refused to pay the British company''s price, the American drugs giant is still considering pursuing that deal as well as other options, the people said. The company has determined any such deal needs to be friendly, unlike the unsolicited offer made to Astra, these people said. </p> <p>Representatives for Pfizer and Actavis declined to comment. </p>




Photographer: Justin Sullivan/Getty Images

<p>
A bid for Actavis would insert Pfizer into a web of potential deals among pharmaceutical companies. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Duane D. Stanford" date="Sep 23, 2014  2:10 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-23/coca-cola-pepsico-pledge-to-cut-drink-calories-consumed-by-20-.html"><headline>Coca-Cola, PepsiCo Pledge to Cut Drink Calories Consumed by 20%</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Coca-Cola Co. (KO) and PepsiCo Inc. (PEP) agreed to cut the amount of beverage calories that Americans consume by 20 percent over the next decade, saying they''ll more heavily promote smaller portion sizes, water and diet drinks. </p> <p>The American Beverage Association-backed effort, which also involves Dr Pepper Snapple Group (DPS), made the commitment at the Clinton Global Initiative Annual Meeting in New York today. The move builds on a 2006 agreement to limit portion sizes targeted at school kids, which resulted in beverage calories shipped to schools falling 90 percent between 2004 and 2010. </p> <p>The latest campaign is a response to growing criticism of the industry, which is blamed for contributing to America''s obesity epidemic. Demand for sugary drinks has already been declining, though, suggesting that the industry could achieve these goals without much additional effort, said Jeff Cronin, a spokesman for the Center for Science in the Public Interest, one of the first groups to sound the alarm about sodas in the 1990s. </p> <p>Non-diet soda is already in a free fall, Cronin said in an interview. There is no reason to think that trend wouldn''t accelerate on its own. </p> <p>Cronin estimates sales for such drinks have declined 15 percent since 1998. Volume sales could drop another 20 percent within a decade with no action by soft-drink makers at all, he said. </p>




Photographer:  Daniel Acker/Bloomberg

<p>
The move by Coca-Cola Co. and PepsiCo Inc. builds on a 2006 agreement to limit portion sizes targeted at school kids, which resulted in beverage calories shipped to schools falling 90 percent between 2004 and 2010. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Julia Verlaine and Ambereen Choudhury" date="Sep 23, 2014  9:54 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-23/goldman-s-european-spot-fx-trading-head-said-to-leave.html"><headline>Goldman''s European Spot FX Trading Head Said to Leave</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)''s European head of spot foreign-exchange trading, Mitesh Parikh, is leaving after 12 years to join a hedge-fund firm, according to two people with knowledge of the move. </p> <p>Parikh, 35, is resigning to trade currencies at an investment firm, said the people, who asked not to be identified because the move isn''t public. Parikh, who worked in London, didn''t respond to a message left with a colleague or to e-mails to his work address. He joined Goldman Sachs in July 2002, according to his LinkedIn profile. </p> <p>A Goldman Sachs spokesman declined to comment on the move. </p> <p>His departure marks the continued exodus of traders from banks amid cost cutting and increased regulation that prevents proprietary trading and limits the capital trading desks may put at risk. The number of bankers doing business in the Group of 10 currencies shrank to 2,278 in the first half of this year from 2,929 in the same period of 2010, according to London-based consulting firm Coalition Ltd. </p> <p>Regulators are also probing the $5.3 trillion-a-day market over allegations dealers leaked confidential client information and colluded to rig benchmarks. The scandal may cost lenders as much as $15 billion in fines, according to Chirantan Barua, a London-based analyst at Sanford C. Bernstein Ltd. Parikh''s move is unrelated to any investigations, the people said. </p> <h2>Talented Individuals'' </h2> <p>It''s no surprise to see talented individuals looking to move to a less constrained environment, said John Purcell, chief executive officer of London-based executive-search firm Purcell  Co. In the political heat generated during the recent downturn, regulators became over zealous trying to out do each other with their bash the banks, tough-guy approach.'' </p> <p>Earlier this year, Citigroup''s Jeffrey Feig and Deutsche Bank AG''s Christopher Fahy were hired by Fortress Investment Group LLC, the first publicly traded private-equity and hedge-fund manager in the U.S. </p> <p>Rohan Ramchandani, Citigroup''s former European head of foreign-exchange spot trading, began at an online-trading firm earlier this month. Darren Coote, global head of spot foreign exchange at Lloyds Banking Group Plc, resigned for personal reasons in April. </p> <p>Deutsche Bank''s global head of foreign exchange, Kevin Rodgers, left in June after 15 years to join the performing arts. He recently sang the parts of four villains in Jacques Offenbach''s Tales of Hoffmann and is set to appear in the Gilbert and Sullivan operetta The Mikado in London. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elizabeth Dexheimer" date="Sep 24, 2014 12:10 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-24/visa-to-create-2-000-full-time-jobs-amid-global-tech-expansion.html"><headline>Visa to Create 2,000 Full-Time Jobs Amid Global Tech Push</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Visa Inc. (V), the world''s largest
payments network, is creating 2,000 full-time jobs as the
company expands teams in Singapore and the U.S. and opens a
technology center in India. </p>
<p>The total includes new roles and existing contractor jobs
that are being converted into full-time positions, the Foster
City, California-based company said today in a statement. </p>
<p>Recruitment efforts, which are currently under way and
will continue through 2017, will focus on a range of technology
needs spanning data scientists, engineers, platform architects
and mobile developers, the company said in the statement. </p>
<p>Visa plans to open a new technology-development center in
India and is adding staff in Austin, Texas; Ashburn, Virginia;
the San Francisco area and Denver. </p>
<p>The investment allows us to strengthen our talent pool
globally, and bring more of it in-house, Rajat Taneja,
executive vice president of technology, said in the statement. </p>
<p>The company opened a new outpost in San Francisco in July.
Visa has been expanding its digital and mobile products and
services, and in July introduced Visa Checkout, which it said
will allow consumers to make purchases faster online. </p>
<p>Earlier this month, Apple Inc. said its new iPhones include
a payment system that relies on card networks including Visa as
well as banks. As part of the partnership, Visa offers bank
clients a new service that replaces account information with a
digital token. </p>
<p>As Visa increases its investments in in-house capabilities,
the firm is reducing its stake in other startups. Visa said
Sept. 18 it was considering its options regarding an investment
in Monitise Plc, a London-based mobile-payments firm. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Rubin, Manuel Baigorri and Ruth David" date="Sep 24, 2014 10:27 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-24/pfizer-pursuing-inversions-shows-companies-undeterred-by-lew.html"><headline>Pfizer Seeking Inversions Shows Companies Unfazed by Lew</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. has approached Actavis Plc about a deal that could allow the U.S. drugmaker to move its address overseas and reduce taxes, in a sign the Obama administration''s efforts to curtail inversions might fall short. </p> <p>Pfizer made its approach before the U.S. Treasury Department announced new rules Sept. 22 to make such deals -- called tax inversions -- more difficult, people with knowledge of the matter said. Those changes won''t deter Pfizer, even if they are a complication, one of the people said, asking not to be identified discussing private information. </p> <p>Another high-profile inversion deal, Burger King Worldwide Inc.''s purchase of Tim Hortons Inc., will proceed, the Canadian company said after the rule changes were revealed. </p> <p>How U.S. Companies Buy Tax Breaks</p><p>While Treasury Secretary Jacob J. Lew could take further steps, he steered clear of putting an end to a key benefit of inversions, which allow companies to lower their U.S. earnings by shifting profits overseas using a technique known as earnings stripping. </p> <p>The ability to shelter future foreign earnings from U.S. tax seems to be a principal objective and, as far as I can see, that benefit remains, said Robert Willens, a corporate tax consultant in New York. </p>




Photographer: Chris Ratcliffe/Bloomberg

<p>
A blister pack containing Pfizer''s 0.50mg Viagra tablets. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dinesh Nair, Ercan Ersoy and Isobel Finkel" date="Sep 24, 2014  5:18 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-24/jpmorgan-hires-deutsche-bank-s-bagriacik-as-turkey-head.html"><headline>JPMorgan Hires Deutsche Bank''s Bagriacik as Turkey Head</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the biggest
U.S. bank, hired Mustafa Bagriacik from Deutsche Bank AG (DBK) to head
its business in Turkey and Azerbaijan. </p>
<p>Bagriacik, who has run the German lender''s investment
banking operations in Turkey since 2009, will start his new role
as senior country officer for the two nations on Oct. 1, the New
York-based bank said in an e-mailed statement. He will replace
Emre Derman who left the bank earlier this year, according to a
spokeswoman for JPMorgan. </p>
<p>Investment banking activity in the nation is recovering as
mergers and acquisitions pick up after two elections wins by the
ruling AK Party. Nomura Holdings Inc. (8604), Japan''s largest
brokerage, said in March it had received a license to open a
representative office in Turkey. In March, Finance Minister
Mehmet Simsek said that Goldman Sachs Group Inc. was applying to
the regulator to open a representative office in Turkey. </p>
<p>National Bank of Greece SA has hired banks including
Goldman Sachs Group Inc. to sell as much as 40 percent of
Turkish unit Finansbank AS (FINBN) in a secondary share offering, four
people familiar with the matter said Sept. 18. </p>
<p>Bagriacik will oversee the bank''s corporate, investment
banking and asset management business in both countries in his
new role, according to the statement. He will report to Sjoerd Leenart, senior country officer for the Middle East, Turkey and
Africa. Prior to Deutsche Bank, Bagriacik worked at Goldman
Sachs in London for 10 years, covering Turkish investment
banking. </p>
<p>Bagriacik and Deutsche Bank declined to comment when
contacted by phone. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Serena Saitto" date="Sep 25, 2014  1:11 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-25/goldman-bank-of-america-fund-context-relevant.html"><headline>Goldman, Bank of America Fund Context Relevant</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Context Relevant Inc., a maker of
software that analyzes data and makes predictions, raised $13.5
million from a group of investors including Goldman Sachs Group
Inc. (GS) and Bank of America Corp. to fund expansion. </p>
<p>Each bank will get a seat on the Seattle-based company''s
board, said Chief Executive Officer Stephen Purpura, who founded
the company in 2012. The banks will also use Context Relevant''s
technology, the company said in a statement today. </p>
<p>Context Relevant also raised funds from New York Life
Insurance Co. and existing venture investors Formation 8 and
Bloomberg Beta. The company raised $21 million three months ago,
and total funding to date is $42 million. Bloomberg Beta is a
unit of Bloomberg LP, the parent company of Bloomberg News. </p>
<p>We raised another round because we are growing
exponentially and achieved all the goals set by the previous
round, Purpura said in an interview. He declined to comment on
the company''s valuation. </p>
<p>Context Relevant''s technology can be used to predict
external and internal threats such as hacking, data theft and
insider trading, and the company generates revenue from annual
software licenses. The software developer is seeking to boost
the number of employees to 200 from the current 50, and needs to
hire analysts, sales staff and customer-service representatives,
Purpura said. </p>
<p>Context Relevant also said it hired Richard Clarke, former
U.S. National Coordinator for Security and Counter-terrorism, as
acting head of its security products. </p>
<h2>Data, Security </h2>
<p>In the wake of recent breaches at banks, exchanges, hedge
funds, payment processors and retailers, it is clear that there
is a market for Context Relevant to deliver automated
intelligent systems to help address these challenges, Clarke,
who was already advising Context Relevant, said in a statement. </p>
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. and at least other four banks were
attacked last month by Russian hackers who stole gygabites of
customers'' data people familiar with the investigation have
said. Home Depot Inc. (HD) and Target Corp. (TGT) have also been the target
of attacks. </p>
<p>Other startups such as Palantir Technologies Inc., a
software maker co-founded by Formation 8 partner Joe Lonsdale,
and DataRobot Inc. also develop predictive software that can
analyze data and detect potential threats. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Piotr Bujnicki and Maciej Martewicz" date="Sep 25, 2014  9:20 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-25/jpmorgan-to-bnp-mine-appetite-for-coal-eurobonds-poland-credit.html"><headline>JPMorgan Among Banks Mining Demand for Polish Coal Bonds</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Poland''s top three coal companies,
burdened by losses amid communist-era benefit payments and a
market glut, are hiring banks including JPMorgan Chase  Co. and
BNP Paribas SA to sell debut Eurobonds to raise cash. </p>
<p>Barclays Plc and BNP Paribas were picked by Katowicki
Holding Weglowy SA, the third-biggest coal-miner, to manage a
euro-denominated debt sale, two people familiar with the plan
said on Sept. 18, asking not to be identified because the
details are private. Deutsche Bank AG and Credit Suisse Group AG
were also hired by the miners, separate people said. </p>
<p>The unprecedented rush for international financing is
occurring as mining unions prepare protests against plans by the
state-controlled companies to restructure operations and clamp
down on benefits. Kompania Weglowa SA, the European Union''s
largest producer, said this week it will scrap free coal
allowances for 160,000 retired employees, which cost it about
260 million zloty ($79.1 million) annually. </p>
<p>Foreign issues are the only way for these companies to
gain funds, Mariusz Zarod, a money manager at BZ WBK Asset
Management in Poznan, Poland, with the equivalent of $3.7
billion under management, said by e-mail yesterday. If they
manage to pull it off, they will probably sell high-yield notes,
even though some investors won''t go near them. </p>
<h2>Falling Prices </h2>
<p>Kompania, which had a 675.7 million-zloty net loss last
year, chose Barclays, BNP and Deutsche Bank for its offering,
according to separate people familiar with the plan. The company
aims to meet three rating companies by early October, spokesman
Tomasz Zieba said last week, declining to comment on the sale. </p>
<p>The third miner, Jastrzebska Spolka Weglowa SA, hired
JPMorgan and Credit Suisse for a sale of at least $500 million
in notes in the fourth quarter, a person familiar with the
details said last month. Spokeswoman Katarzyna Jablonska-Bajer
declined to comment by phone yesterday. </p>
<p>Prices of European coal for delivery next year fell to
$75.2 a ton at 2:23 p.m. in Warsaw today, the lowest level since
March 2009, data compiled by Bloomberg show. Waning demand is
also compounded by overstaffing, mismanagement and numerous
unions, Zarod said. Scrapping the free coal benefits will help
Kompania avoid bankruptcy and pave the way for long-term
financing, the company said in the Sept. 23 e-mail. </p>
<p>Miners ran up a combined 772.3 million-zloty net loss in
the first half, compared with profit of 15.6 million zloty a
year earlier, the Economy Ministry said. </p>
<h2>Industry Headwinds </h2>
<p>Katowicki Holding will seek to raise 500 million euros
($636 million) of bonds in November to refinance existing debt
and boost working capital, Chief Financial Officer Artur Trzeciakowski told PAP newswire on Sept. 18. The company earlier
held talks with most banks in Poland and failed to convince
them to increase their funding, he said. </p>
<p>The Polish debt offerings come as some eastern European
miners face headwinds. Russia''s economy minister said last week
he saw no alternative to bankruptcy for OAO Mechel, the
country''s biggest producer of coking coal, following nine months
of unsuccessful efforts to refinance its debt. New World
Resources Plc, a Czech miner, is restructuring 775 million euros
of bonds after falling coal prices hit it with seven consecutive
quarterly losses. </p>
<p>Polish government debt has attracted investors seeking less
risky regional assets amid the fallout from the Ukraine crisis.
The yield on the 2019 euro-denominated sovereign bond declined
to a record low of 0.61 percent today. </p>
<p>It should be possible for Polish miners to place
Eurobonds (BEMC) as long as they are state-controlled, Clemens Hansmann, a money manager at Gutmann Kapitalanlage AG in Vienna,
which oversees 7 billion euros of assets, said by e-mail
yesterday. There is a structural decline in global demand for
thermal coal. For the Polish coal mines, this pressure will
continue and investors are well aware of these structural
issues, he said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Edvard Pettersson" date="Sep 26, 2014  5:04 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-26/disney-s-marvel-settles-with-hulk-co-creator-s-family.html"><headline>Disney''s Marvel Settles With Hulk Co-Creator''s Family</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS)''s Marvel
Entertainment settled its copyright dispute with the children of
the late comic book artist Jack Kirby, who helped create the
Incredible Hulk and X-Men characters. </p>
<p>Marvel and the family of Jack Kirby have amicably
resolved their legal disputes, and are looking forward to
advancing their shared goal of honoring Mr. Kirby''s significant
role in Marvel''s history, the company and the Kirby family
said in a joint statement today. </p>
<p>The family in March petitioned the U.S. Supreme Court to
review their case after both a federal judge in New York and a
federal appeals court had agreed with Marvel that their father''s
drawings were work-for-hire and the family couldn''t terminate
the publisher''s copyright to the characters. </p>
<p>Disney acquired Marvel for $4.2 billion in 2009. Since
then, characters such as Iron Man and Thor have proved box
office gold for the Burbank, California-based company. </p>
<p>Marvel''s The Avengers was the top-grossing film of
2012. This year''s Guardians of the Galaxy, based on lesser-known Marvel characters, also led the domestic box office with
$315 million in tickets sold since its August release. </p>
<h2>Spider-Man Fees </h2>
<p>Licensing fees from merchandise tied to Marvel characters
such as Spider-Man have boosted the results of Disney''s
consumer-products division. </p>
<p>In 2009, Kirby''s adult children sent 45 notices to Marvel
to terminate license renewals for the characters in comics
published from 1958 to 1963. Marvel sued in January 2010,
seeking a judgment that the termination notices were invalid. </p>
<p>Kirby, who died in 1994, also created or co-created the
Fantastic Four and the Avengers. His heirs said their father was
a freelance artist paid by the page who received no benefits
from Marvel. Stan Lee, who worked for Marvel as an editor, is
credited as co-author of the Hulk. </p>
<p>Marvel said in court papers that Kirby granted the company
rights to the characters in 1972 and that his children waited
too long to make their copyright claims. </p>
<p>The case is Marvel Worldwide Inc. v. Kirby, 10-00141, U.S.
District Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Gaspard Sebag" date="Sep 26, 2014  7:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-26/jpmorgan-to-hsbc-stall-eu-euribor-case-amid-bias-probe.html"><headline>JPMorgan to HSBC Stall EU Euribor Case Amid Bias Probe</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), HSBC Holdings
Plc (HSBA) and Credit Agricole SA (ACA) delayed by months the European
Union''s investigation into Euribor rigging amid scrutiny of
possible EU bias, according to three people familiar with the
case. </p>
<p>The trio gained more time to respond to the EU''s May
antitrust complaint after demanding to see files necessary for
their defense, said the people who asked not to be named because
the issue is private. These requests have been taken more
seriously since the EU''s ombudsman started inquiring into Credit
Agricole''s bias allegations, two of the people said. </p>
<p>The European Commission doesn''t want to appear to have
been too tough on Credit Agricole, Adrien Giraud, a lawyer at
Willkie Farr  Gallagher LLP, said. That might explain why
they were more lenient on deadlines than usually. </p>
<p>The Euribor-rigging investigation has been strained since
the three refused to join four other lenders including Deutsche
Bank AG (DBK) and Societe Generale SA (GLE) who paid a total of 1 billion
euros ($1.3 billion) to settle the case. The delays -- including
the latest scrapping of a mid-September deadline for responses -
- robbed Joaquin Almunia, the EU''s antitrust chief, of the
chance to impose another set of fines on the finance industry as
he prepares to leave office at the end of next month, the people
said. </p>
<p>Representatives for the commission, JPMorgan, HSBC and
Credit Agricole all declined to comment on the Euribor
investigation. </p>
<h2>Failed Settlement </h2>
<p>Almunia said this month that time has run out in his two-year long quest to clinch an antitrust settlement with Google
Inc. (GOOG) He''s also conceded that he won''t have time to complete an
antitrust probe into credit derivatives trading by 13 of the
world''s biggest banks. </p>
<p>It''s clear that Almunia has accepted that he won''t be
able to finalize several cases and Euribor is just one more
on his list, Giraud said. The officials working on the case
aren''t therefore in as much of a hurry. </p>
<p>The EU ombudsman, the internal EU watchdog, opened a case
on July 31 after Credit Agricole complained that public comments
made by Almunia indicated he had already made up his mind about
the conclusion of the Euribor investigation, Bloomberg News
reported this week. </p>
<p>Almunia''s stance explains the banks'' determination to try
to delay the case until after his departure, said the people. </p>
<h2>Fairness and Transparency'' </h2>
<p>His successor, former Danish Economy Minister Margrethe Vestager, is scheduled to take over the EU antitrust brief and
deal with the EU ombudsman''s inquiry at the start of November. </p>
<p>Vestager said this month that all cases should be treated
with fairness and transparency. </p>
<p>Aside from examining Euribor, Vestager will inherit a
preliminary probe into suspected rigging of foreign-exchange
markets, which is part of a global scandal that tarnished the
reputation of some of the world''s biggest lenders. Oil
benchmarks are also under scrutiny. </p>
<p>JPMorgan, HSBC and Credit Agricole were accused on May 20
by the commission of colluding to rig Euribor rates. </p>
<p>The so-called statement of objections was the next step in
the EU enforcement process after the banks dropped out of
settlement talks last year. The EU procedure allows them to
respond to the complaint in writing and request a hearing. If
companies fail to deflect accusations in antitrust cases they
are then usually fined. </p>
<p>The Euro Interbank Offered Rate, or Euribor, and Libor, the
London Interbank Offered Rate, gauge banks'' estimated cost of
borrowing over different periods of time. Libor alone is the
benchmark interest rate for more than $300 trillion of
securities. </p>
<h2>Banks Prejudged </h2>
<p>While JPMorgan, HSBC and Credit Agricole haven''t yet been
found liable, the December settlements spell out their role in
helping to manipulate Euribor, said another person familiar with
the confidential EU documents. This suggested the EU had
prejudged the three banks before they were given their full due-process rights, said the person who is familiar with the
reasoning of a settling bank and raised the issue with the
commission. </p>
<p>The commission shouldn''t make any allusion to the
liability of companies in a final decision -- such as the
December Euribor settlements -- before the firms are given a
chance to fend off charges, according to EU case law. </p>
<p>The companies could argue their case has been decided
before they had the chance to defend themselves, said Alfonso
Lamadrid, a lawyer at Garrigues in Brussels who''s not involved
in the case. This would give them new procedural ammunition to
challenge an eventual sanction in court. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Nicole Ostrow" date="Sep 27, 2014  6:45 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-27/pfizer-s-lung-cancer-drug-helps-patients-with-gene-defect.html"><headline>Pfizer''s Lung Cancer Drug Helps Patients With Gene Defect</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE)''s Xalkori for advanced
lung cancer shrunk tumors in those with a rare genetic mutation,
according to a study that may provide the first targeted
treatment for these patients. </p>
<p>Xalkori reduced the size of tumors in 36 of 50 patients in
the study while halting tumor growth in another nine, according
to company-funded research released today at the European
Society for Medical Oncology meeting in Madrid and online in the
New England Journal of Medicine. </p>
<p>About 15,000 people, or 1 percent of the estimated 1.5
million annual new cases of non-small-cell lung cancer, have an
abnormality to the ROS1 gene, according to New York-based
Pfizer. Today''s findings also showed that Xalkori was effective
for about 18 months in patients, longer than the average eight
to 12 months seen for some other targeted treatments, said Alice
Shaw, a lead study author. </p>
<p>We''re seeing much longer durations of remissions, Shaw,
an associate professor of medicine at Harvard Medical School and
Massachusetts General Hospital in Boston, said in a telephone
interview. This points to being a very good target in lung
cancer and this drug being a very effective targeted therapy for
these patients. </p>
<p>Xalkori helps shut off the ROS1 gene that is causing cancer
tumors to grow, she said. It was approved in 2011 to treat non-small-cell lung cancers in patients with mutations to the ALK
gene, which has structural similarities to the ROS1 gene. The
National Comprehensive Cancer Network, an alliance of 25 cancer
centers, already recommends that doctors use Xalkori in patients
who have this gene defect. </p>
<h2>More Testing </h2>
<p>Pfizer continues to support clinical research of Xalkori
in patients with ROS1 rearrangements to better understand the
compound''s activity in this population, Sally Beatty, a
company spokeswoman, said in an e-mail. </p>
<p>The cancer drug generated $282 million in 2013 sales,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. The drug may produce
revenue of more than $812 million in 2017, according to the
average of five analysts'' estimates. </p>
<p>Patients with a mutation to the ROS1 gene are often younger
and usually aren''t smokers, Shaw said. </p>
<p>Today''s study is an expansion of the original Phase 1
clinical trial of Xalkori in patients with the ALK gene
mutation. Researchers enrolled 50 patients who were ROS1
positive starting in late 2010 through August 2013. Those in the
study received Xalkori two times daily. </p>
<p>By the end of the trial, half of the patients were still
getting Xalkori and had no signs of their tumors growing, the
authors said. </p>
<p>We''re hopeful that because of showing how well this drug
works in ROS1 patients, this will let pathologists know they
need to screen their patients for this genetic abnormality,
Shaw said. In lung cancer there''s been a lot of progress made
in targeted therapies. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Niamh Ring" date="Sep 29, 2014  7:55 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-29/microsoft-plans-flagship-ny-store-blocks-from-apple-s.html"><headline>Microsoft Plans Flagship NY Store Blocks From Apple''s</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), maker of the Xbox
video-game consoles, said it plans to open its first flagship
store on Fifth Avenue in Manhattan, about six blocks from a
similar location operated by Apple Inc. </p>
<p>Microsoft''s store will open at 677 Fifth Avenue, according
to a blog post. The company didn''t say when the store would
open. The address is currently home to luxury retailer Fendi,
according to Google Maps. </p>
<p>Microsoft is acquiring Mojang AB, the software company
behind the popular game Minecraft, for $2.5 billion, in a bid to
boost its Xbox and mobile businesses. The Redmond, Washington-based company said the new store would showcase products such as
its Surface tablet and Windows Phones. The Mojang purchase would
give Microsoft a game that''s popular across consoles, computers
and mobile devices including those made by rivals like Apple. </p>
<p>Apple opened its flagship store at 767 Fifth Avenue in New
York in 2006. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alastair Marsh" date="Sep 29, 2014  6:40 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-29/jpmorgan-sees-covered-bond-purchases-as-ecb-s-first-port-of-call.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sees Covered Bond Purchases as ECB''s First Port of Call</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The European Central Bank will
start its asset-purchase program with covered bonds because
large trades in the debt are easier than for asset-backed
securities, according to JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) </p>
<p>The new-issue market for covered notes is more active than
for asset-backed debt and investors typically hold larger
amounts than ABS buyers, JPMorgan analysts led by Gareth Davies
wrote in a note to clients. With 791 billion euros ($1 trillion)
of covered bonds outstanding, compared with 251 billion euros of
ABS, the central bank will also find it easier to expand its
balance sheet, Davies said. </p>
<p>Policy makers are seeking to spur economic growth by
encouraging lending and will disclose the size and details of
the program after policy makers meet this week. ECB President
Mario Draghi, who has made the revival of the ABS market a top
priority this year as he seeks to channel credit to businesses
by freeing up bank balance sheets, mentioned purchases of
covered bonds for the first time this month. </p>
<p>The ECB is likely to begin its purchase program in the
covered bond space as it is unlikely to be able to do meaningful
size in the ABS market, London-based Davies said in a
telephone interview today. If the ECB wants a strong sentiment
change by making large purchases it''s hard to do that in the
secondary or new-issue ABS markets as there quite simply aren''t
enough bonds. </p>
<p>The debt-buying plans have been greeted with skepticism by
investors who suggest the central bank will struggle to buy
enough securities after the market contracted more than 40
percent since 2010. Covered bond purchases are being considered
to expand the amount of assets available to purchase. </p>
<h2>Retained ABS </h2>
<p>Draghi said earlier this month the Frankfurt-based central
bank will buy a broad portfolio of simple and transparent
securities that will include ABS and covered bonds. While
declining to disclose the size of the program, he signaled a
willingness to grow the ECB''s balance sheet by as much 1
trillion euros. </p>
<p>Europe''s public ABS market isn''t big enough to achieve that
goal and purchases of the 635 billion euros of notes created and
retained by banks to use as collateral for central bank funding
during the financial crisis wouldn''t effect the ECB''s balance
sheet, said Davies. </p>
<p>Banks create asset-backed securities by bundling individual
loans such as mortgages, auto credit and credit-card debt.
Covered bonds are guaranteed by the issuer and have a designated
pool of assets, such as mortgages and public sector loans, which
can be used to meet payments if the issuer can''t. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Edvard Pettersson" date="Sep 30, 2014  9:43 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-30/jpmorgan-rmbs-investors-can-proceed-as-group-in-fraud-lawsuit.html"><headline>JPMorgan Loses Ruling on Class Certification in RMBS Lawsuit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) lost a bid to
block buyers of $10 billion worth of residential mortgage-backed
securities it packaged in 2007 to proceed as a group with their
lawsuit alleging the bank misled them. </p>
<p>U.S. District Judge J. Paul Oetken in Manhattan today ruled
that the claims of investors in nine separate offerings of the
securities were similar enough for them to move forward as a
class on the question of whether JPMorgan is liable for making
false and misleading statements in the offering documents. </p>
<p>The ruling only applies to liability. Oetken said he wasn''t
convinced at this stage that there''s a damages calculation that
would cover the claims of all the investors included in the
group. </p>
<p>JPMorgan last year agreed to a $13 billion settlement with
the U.S. to resolve allegations the bank misled investors in
mortgage-backed securities about the soundness and risks of the
investments that helped bring on subprime-mortgage crisis of
2008. </p>
<p>Because the class is currently certified for liability
purposes, this phase of litigation will focus on the issue of
whether defendants made material false statements or omissions
in the offering documents that affected the value of the
certificates owned by the plaintiff class members, the judge
said. </p>
<p>Joe Evangelisti, a spokesman for New York-based JPMorgan,
declined to comment on today''s ruling. </p>
<p>Class certification will allow individual investors who
haven''t filed a lawsuit to be represented by the lead plaintiff
in a single case because their experiences and legal claims are
similar. Class-action status is less expensive for plaintiffs
than filing multiple lawsuits and provides leverage in
settlement negotiations. </p>
<p>The case is Fort Worth Employees'' Retirement Fund v. J.P.
Morgan Chase  Co., 09-cv-3701, U.S. District Court, Southern
District of New York (Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bianca Vzquez Toness" date="Sep 30, 2014  4:12 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-09-30/microsoft-builds-indian-data-centers-to-tap-new-market.html"><headline>Microsoft Builds Indian Data Centers to Tap New Market</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) will build data
centers in India to tap demand for cloud-based computing as it
plans to offer its Azure and Office 365 services in the world''s
second-most populous nation. </p>
<p>Azure, which lets businesses access computing resources and
run programs via the Internet, will be available from local data
centers by the end of 2015, Chief Executive Officer Satya Nadella told reporters in New Delhi today. Office 365, a cloud-based subscription version of Microsoft''s productivity programs,
will be available at the same time, he said. </p>
<p>Cloud computing is a key part of Nadella''s plan to
transform Microsoft and retain relevance as consumers shift from
desktops to tablets and smartphones by keeping information
stored on remote servers instead of a local hard drives. The
world''s biggest software maker competes against rivals including
Amazon.com Inc. (AMZN) and Google Inc. for clients in India, a market
expected to reach $1.7 billion by 2018 according to Gartner Inc. </p>
<p>Microsoft''s cloud services in India have grown over 100
percent in revenue in the past year, the company said in a
statement. Microsoft''s locally available cloud services will
open opportunities for banking, financial services, and
insurance companies, state-owned enterprises and government
departments. </p>




Photographer: Graham Crouch/Bloomberg

<p>
Microsoft Corp. Chief Executive Officer Satya Nadella speaks during a news conference in New Delhi, on Tuesday, Sept. 30. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Craig Giammona" date="Oct 01, 2014  4:35 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-10-01/coca-cola-reins-in-stock-compensation-plan-in-wake-of-criticism.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Trims Stock Compensation Plan After Criticism</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Coca-Cola Co. (KO), whose employee stock-compensation plan was called excessive by billionaire Warren Buffett and other investors, agreed to rein in the program. </p>
<p>Fewer shares will be issued to employees, and more
transparency will be provided into how the program works, the
Atlanta-based company said today in a statement. The number of
shares granted will be no more than 0.8 percent of total
outstanding stock in 2015 and an average of 0.4 percent for the
remainder of the plan. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola investor Wintergreen Advisers LLC, run by David
Winters, railed against the compensation plan this year, calling
it a raw deal for shareholders that was too generous and
diluted the stock. Buffett, Coca-Cola''s largest shareholder,
also spoke out against the program, though only after the plan
passed. He abstained from voting on it at Coca-Cola''s annual
meeting in April. </p>
<p>By approving the equity plan in April, our shareowners
authorized the compensation committee to manage something
precious - shares of the Coca-Cola company, Maria Elena Lagomasino, chairman of Coca-Cola''s compensation committee,
wrote in a letter to shareholders today. The existing equity
plan was designed to provide significant flexibility in how and
to whom long-term equity awards are made. These guidelines are
designed to be clear and simple, driven by our desire to enhance
transparency with our shareowners. </p>




Photographer: Daniel Acker/Bloomberg

<p>
Warren Buffett, Coca-Cola''s largest shareholder, also spoke out against the program, though only after the plan passed when he abstained from voting on it at Coca-Cola''s annual meeting in April. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Harry R. Weber" date="Oct 01, 2014 12:04 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-10-01/electricity-prices-fall-in-midwest-as-demand-seen-below-forecast.html"><headline>Electricity Prices Fall in Midwest as Demand Seen Below Forecast</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Power prices fell at the benchmark
Indiana hub in the Midwest amid below-forecast demand. </p>
<p>Electricity consumption on the Midcontinent Independent
System Operator Inc. network, which stretches from Canada to the
U.S. Gulf Coast, averaged 79,243 megawatts at 10:15 a.m. New
York time, down from the day-ahead forecast of 81,229 megawatts,
according to the grid''s website. </p>
<p>Spot power at the Indiana hub slid $7.46, or 20 percent, to
average $30.10 a megawatt-hour for the hour ended at 9 a.m.
local time from the same time yesterday, according to grid data
compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>On-peak power at the hub declined $3.03, or 8.8 percent, to
average $31.31 a megawatt-hour at 9 a.m., heading toward the
lowest full-day average since Sept. 19. </p>
<p>The high temperature today in Minneapolis may reach 64
degrees Fahrenheit (18 Celsius), 1 below normal, according to
AccuWeather Inc. in State College, Pennsylvania. </p>
<p>Spot power at the Minnesota hub declined $3.97, or 11
percent, to average $33.49. </p>
<p>Power at PJM Interconnection LLC''s benchmark Western hub,
which includes Washington, reversed earlier declines to gain
$5.46, or 16 percent, to average $40.38 a megawatt-hour for the
hour ended at 11 a.m. New York time from the same time
yesterday. Power at the Eastern hub, which includes New Jersey,
rose $5.03, or 15 percent, to average $38.61. </p>
<p>PJM West on-peak power traded $5.93 above the Eastern hub,
compared with a premium of $3.42 yesterday and a three-month
average discount of $3.92. </p>
<p>New York City power dropped $5.40, or 14 percent, to
average $32.80 a megawatt-hour at 11 a.m., while Boston power
declined $10.49, or 20 percent, to average $42.71. </p>
<p>New York on-peak power traded $3.02 below Boston, compared
with a discount of $15.97 yesterday and a three-month average
discount of $2.23. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Leslie Picker" date="Oct 01, 2014 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-10-01/morgan-stanley-promotes-guevara-kearns-to-tech-banking-co-heads.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Promotes Guevara, Kearns to Tech-Banking Co-Heads</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) promoted Andy Kearns
and Drew Guevara to co-heads of technology banking, replacing
Paul Chamberlain, who''s retiring after 26 years with the bank. </p>
<p>Kearns, who led software banking, and Guevara, who has
advised companies including Amazon.com Inc. and LinkedIn Corp.,
will join Michael Grimes in their new roles, according to
employee memos obtained by Bloomberg News and confirmed by Mary Claire Delaney, a spokeswoman. The Wall Street Journal
previously reported the moves. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley ranks second among advisers of global
technology and Internet deals this year so far, according to
data compiled by Bloomberg. The New York-based bank worked on
Facebook Inc.''s $18 billion purchase of WhatsApp Inc. and
Rakuten Inc.''s $1 billion purchase of Ebates Inc., the data
show. Goldman Sachs Group Inc., also based in New York, is the
top-ranked adviser on technology and web deals. </p>
<p>Among advisers for global technology initial public
offerings, Morgan Stanley ranks fourth, the data compiled by
Bloomberg show. Its technology banking team advised on Chinese
e-commerce giant Alibaba Group Holding Ltd.''s $25 billion share
sale, the biggest global IPO on record. </p>
<p>Paul Kwan, a consumer Internet and software banker, will
succeed Kearns and Guevara as sole head of West Coast technology
banking, one memo shows. Chamberlain plans to sit on corporate
boards, teach and continue work for charities, according to the
other memo. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hugh Son" date="Oct 02, 2014  7:39 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-10-02/jpmorgan-says-data-breach-affected-76-million-households.html"><headline>JPMorgan Employee Password Was Key in Hack Hitting 76 Million Homes</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co., the biggest U.S. bank, said a previously disclosed data breach affected 76 million households and 7 million small businesses. </p> <p>Customer names, addresses, phone numbers and e-mail addresses were taken, the New York-based bank said today in a regulatory filing. Hackers also obtained internal data identifying customers by category, such as whether they are clients of the private-bank, mortgage, auto or credit-card divisions, said a person briefed on the matter. </p> <p>The breach affected anyone who visited the company''s websites, including Chase.com, or used its mobile app, said the person, who requested anonymity because that information wasn''t publicly disclosed. Some of those affected by the incursion are former clients of JPMorgan, which currently has 65 million customers and reaches half of all U.S. households, the person said. </p> <p>Graphic: Top U.S. Data Breaches</p><p>The bank, led by Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon, hasn''t detected any unusual customer fraud related to the attack, and clients aren''t liable for unauthorized transactions that are promptly reported to the company, according to the filing. </p> <p>There is no evidence that account information for such affected customers - account numbers, passwords, user IDs, dates of birth or Social Security numbers - was compromised during this attack, the company said. </p>




Photographer: Ron Antonelli/Bloomberg

<p>
The JPMorgan Chase  Co. headquarters in New York City. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri" date="Oct 02, 2014  4:24 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-10-02/disney-extends-ceo-iger-s-contract-for-two-years-to-2018.html"><headline>Disney Extends CEO Iger''s Contract for Two Years to 2018</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS) extended Robert Iger''s contract as chairman and chief executive officer for two
years to June 2018, giving more time to a manager who''s seen the
company''s stock more than triple under his tenure. </p>
<p>Disney will name a chief operating officer next year, most
likely from within, a person close to the company said. That
executive will be considered Iger''s heir apparent, said the
person, who asked not to be named discussing internal matters. </p>
<p>The move extends the term of an executive who''s produced
record sales and profit since taking over the Burbank,
California-based company in 2005. Iger, 63, has steered the
company through technology shifts in Hollywood, such as the
collapse of the DVD market and the rise of video streaming
services like Netflix Inc. (NFLX) </p>
<p>This is great for Walt Disney shareholders, because Bob
has been a huge value creator, said Laura Martin, an analyst
with Needham  Co. in Los Angeles who has a hold rating on the
stock. </p>
<p>Iger rebuilt Disney''s animation business with the purchase
of Pixar and the production of hits such as Frozen at Walt
Disney Animation Studios. He also bought Marvel, which delivered
a string of blockbusters from The Avengers to Guardians of
the Galaxy. Iger acquired Lucasfilm, which will release a new
Star Wars film next year. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
Walt Disney Co. extended Robert Iger''s contract as chairman and chief executive officer for two years to June 2018. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Rob Golum" date="Oct 02, 2014  2:29 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-10-02/disney-said-planning-to-name-chief-operating-officer.html"><headline>Disney Said Planning to Name Chief Operating Officer</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. plans to appoint a
chief operating officer next year, establishing an heir apparent
to Chief Executive Officer Robert Iger, a person with knowledge
of the matter said. </p>
<p>The world''s biggest entertainment company is weighing
internal candidates for the position, said the person, who asked
not to be identified because board deliberations are private. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andy Hoffman" date="Oct 02, 2014  1:46 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-10-02/jpmorgan-s-commodities-sale-to-mercuria-said-to-shrink.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Commodities Sale to Mercuria Said to Shrink</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Mercuria Energy Group Ltd.''s six-month-old agreement to buy JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s physical
commodities business for $3.5 billion was revised to cover only
$800 million of assets, according to people familiar with the
change. </p>
<p>JPMorgan plans to sell the rest of the business in separate
transactions, said the people, who asked not to be identified
because the final deal''s terms haven''t been made public. Some
separate sales have already been agreed, one person said. The
Wall Street Journal reported on the changes earlier today. </p>
<p>Trading houses such as Mercuria are filling the void as
banks from JPMorgan and Barclays Plc to Deutsche Bank AG and
Morgan Stanley (MS) withdraw from or scale back physical commodity
operations amid increased regulatory scrutiny of lenders owning,
storing and trading raw materials. Founded in 2004 by former
Goldman Sachs Group Inc. traders Marco Dunand and Daniel Jaeggi,
Mercuria has grown to become the world''s fourth-largest
independent commodity trader with 2013 revenue of $112 billion. </p>
<p>Among the assets not being purchased by Mercuria include a
crude oil supply agreement to a refinery in St. Paul, Minnesota,
the refinery''s owner, Northern Tier Energy LP, said in a
regulatory filing last month. </p>
<h2>Earnings Boost </h2>
<p>JPMorgan''s physical commodity business, formerly led by
Blythe Masters, has previously generated annual operating profit
before compensation costs of $750 million, according to people
who have seen documents related to the unit''s sale. That would
bring Mercuria, which posted net income of $273 million last
year, closer to earnings achieved by competitors Vitol Group and
Trafigura Beheer BV. </p>
<p>Mercuria competed with Macquarie Group Ltd. and Blackstone
Group LP to enter exclusive negotiations for the unit in
February, people with knowledge of the bidding said at the time.
The JPMorgan unit, put up for sale last year, was slated to give
Mercuria gas and power trading operations on both sides of the
Atlantic, physical assets spanning about 40 locations in North
America and 6 million barrels of storage leases in the Canadian
oil sands. </p>
<p>Mercuria also gets Henry Bath  Sons Ltd., a 220-year-old
metal-warehouse operator based in Liverpool, England, that will
be operated as a stand-alone subsidiary separated from
Mercuria''s trading operations. Henry Bath was a founding member
of the London Metal Exchange, and handles products that include
aluminum, steel and copper as well as cocoa and coffee,
according to its website. </p>
<p>Mercuria, which is registered in Cyprus and has its main
trading operations in Geneva, offered jobs to about 200 people,
or about half of the unit''s staff, a person familiar with the
matter said in March. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Adam Williams and Joe Carroll" date="Oct 02, 2014 11:35 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-10-02/exxon-signs-pemex-accord-as-mexico-prepares-oil-opening.html"><headline>Exxon Signs Pemex Accord as Mexico Prepares Oil Opening</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM), the world''s most
valuable crude producer, signed an agreement with Petroleos
Mexicanos as Mexico''s oil industry opens to private investment. </p>
<p>Exxon and Pemex, as the state-owned producer is known,
signed a three-year memorandum of understanding and cooperation
to exchange academic, scientific and technical knowledge,
according to e-mailed statements by both companies. The
companies agreed to analyze exploration, drilling and refining
opportunities, according to Pemex''s statement. </p>
<p>The Irving, Texas-based company joins a growing list of
major oil producers to express interest in entering Mexico''s
energy industry, which is ending a 76-year state oil monopoly.
Congress passed legislation last year to allow private companies
to tap the country''s 13.4 billion barrels of proven reserves,
which the government estimates will bring in $50 billion of
investment between 2015 and 2018. </p>
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX), Noble Energy Inc. (NBL) and BHP Billiton Ltd. are
among companies interested in exploring for oil in Mexico.
Authorities next year will auction 169 oil blocks -- 109 for
exploration and 60 for production. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elizabeth Dexheimer" date="Oct 02, 2014  9:16 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-10-02/visa-fends-off-usurpers-by-joining-apple-in-pay-system.html"><headline>How Visa Chief Is Fighting Back as Transactions Go Digital</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A 4-foot-tall robot with a video screen for a head swerves past an orange couch and bumps into the wall of a conference room. A few feet away, an engineer tests a virtual reality headset that can allow a coffee-shop owner to forecast hot-chocolate sales during a blizzard. </p> <p>This is Visa Inc.''s new outpost in San Francisco -- part executive office, part design laboratory and entirely the brainchild of Charlie Scharf, Visa''s chief executive officer. </p> <p>Scharf, who this July day had unveiled the latest version of the company''s digital wallet, is sitting in an office overlooking San Francisco Bay one floor above the lab. He''s wearing jeans, loafers and a gray shirt with no tie. One leg is propped up on his desk. </p> <p>Moving into the heart of the city, 23 miles (37 kilometers) from Visa''s suburban headquarters in Foster City, California, and three blocks from a Google Inc. office, is a statement about how Scharf is seeking to embrace the new technologies transforming the way consumers make payments, Bloomberg Markets will report in its November issue. </p> <p>More from the November issue of Bloomberg Markets:</p>
Coinbase Leads Move to Bring Bitcoin to Masses

How Funding Circle Is Challenging Mainstream Lenders

The Story Behind This Popular Bitcoin Photograph
<p>We have to think and act much more like a technology company than we have before, Scharf says a few weeks later at a restaurant in Sag Harbor, New York, where he''s on vacation with his family. The payments world is changing. There are new entrants, new opportunities for people to get into our business and other opportunities for us to grow our business in ways that didn''t exist before. </p>




Photographer: Ian Allen/Bloomberg Markets

<p>
Visa CEO Charlie Scharf at the company''s new design lab in San Francisco. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri" date="Oct 03, 2014  4:24 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-10-03/disney-extends-iger-term-keeps-staggs-rasulo-race-alive.html"><headline>Disney Extends Iger Term, Keeps Staggs-Rasulo Race Alive</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS)''s board found a way
to keep Chairman and Chief Executive Officer Bob Iger in place
until 2018 while maximizing the chances the internal candidates
most likely to succeed him stick around. </p>
<p>Disney, based in Burbank, California, yesterday extended
Iger''s contract by two years to June 2018. The move keeps in
place a manager who has spearheaded high-profile acquisitions
like Marvel, turned around the company''s historic animation
business and tripled Disney''s stock price. </p>
<p>At the same time, the company has decided to name a chief
operating officer next year -- and that executive, most likely
coming from within, would be Iger''s heir apparent, according to
a person close to the company. Giving a time frame to the
internal candidates, Chief Financial Officer Jay Rasulo and
Parks  Resorts Chairman Thomas Staggs, makes them less likely
to bolt before a decision is made. </p>
<p>There''s no doubt Bob Iger has been performing at an
outstanding level, said William Simon, an executive recruiter
who heads the entertainment industry practice at Korn Ferry (KFY) in
Los Angeles. Asking a potential successor to wait four years
could prove to be difficult. </p>
<p>The company said in a filing today that Iger could earn a
retention bonus of $60 million if Disney''s operating income
increases to a cumulative $78.3 billion for the five years
ending in September 2018. He will earn a smaller bonus if that
number tops $76 billion. For the year that ended in September
2013, the company generated operating income of $10.7 billion. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
Bob Iger, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer of Walt Disney Co. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hugh Son and Michael Riley" date="Oct 03, 2014 10:06 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-10-03/jpmorgan-password-said-to-lead-hackers-to-76-million-households.html"><headline>JPMorgan Password Leads Hackers to 76 Million Households</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Hackers exploited an employee password to crack a JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) server and ultimately pull off one of the largest cyber-attacks ever, accessing data on 76 million households and 7 million small businesses. </p> <p>JPMorgan, the largest U.S. bank, outlined the scope of the previously disclosed breach yesterday, reassuring clients there''s still no evidence account numbers and passwords were compromised, even as names and contact data were exposed. People who logged on to certain websites or mobile apps had contact information stolen, the New York-based company said. </p> <p>Related:</p>
JPMorgan Breach Probed by Connecticut Attorney General

Graphic: Top U.S. Data Breaches

<p>The bank has been struggling to head off damage since the incident, first reported by Bloomberg News in August. New details on how attackers accomplished the feat over months, including their initial entry, were provided by two people briefed on the investigation, who requested anonymity because it''s private. JPMorgan said the threat now is phishing, in which criminals try to trick people into handing over more valuable data, such as user IDs and passwords. </p> <p>Internet Security</p><p>If they find the CEO of a company, they know this person''s worth a lot of money, they would try to attack that person, said Jeff Tjiputra, program chairman for Cybersecurity at the University of Maryland University College. Still, it''s not an easy hack or scam. </p>




Photographer: Emmanuel Dunand/AFP via Getty Images

<p>
The JP Morgan Chase  Company headquarters in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Heesu Lee" date="Oct 03, 2014  3:30 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-10-03/goldman-losing-faith-in-100-brent-while-wti-discount-seen-wider.html"><headline>Goldman Losing Faith in $100 Brent as WTI Spread Seen Wider</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. says it''s
losing confidence in its forecast that Brent crude will recover
to $100 a barrel next year. </p>
<p>While the Wall Street bank is maintaining its projection
for now, it says that a lack of signs of accelerating global
economic growth and uncertainty over OPEC''s production plans
amid rising Libyan output are weakening its conviction. Brent,
the benchmark for more than half the world''s oil, closed at
$93.42 a barrel yesterday, the lowest in more than two years. </p>
<p>Prices slumped as U.S. crude production climbed last month
to the highest level since 1986 and the Organization of
Petroleum Exporting Countries pumped the most oil in a year. The
International Energy Agency cut its projections for global
consumption growth through next year due to a weakening economic
outlook while Saudi Arabia lowered prices this week, signaling
the world''s biggest exporter is prepared to let them fall rather
than cede market share. </p>
<p>Given the lack of strong catalyst for higher prices, the
path of least resistance seems for further declines, Goldman
analysts including New York-based Jeffrey Currie said in an e-mailed report. However, the downside from here starts to
become limited as further declines in Brent prices would help
rebalance the oil market, incentivizing stronger demand growth
and weighing on production growth in the U.S. </p>
<p>Brent for November delivery was 39 cents higher at $93.81 a
barrel on the London-based ICE Futures Europe exchange, at 3:29
p.m. Singapore time. Futures plunged 16 percent in the three
months to Sept. 30, the worst quarterly performance since June
2012. They have declined 15.3 percent this year. </p>
<h2>WTI Spread </h2>
<p>West Texas Intermediate, the U.S. benchmark grade, for
November delivery was at $91.52 a barrel in electronic trading
on the New York Mercantile Exchange, bringing its decline this
year to 7 percent. </p>
<p>WTI''s discount to Brent shrank to $2.41 yesterday based on
settlement prices, the smallest since August 2013. The spread is
far too narrow given logistic economics and needs to
widen, Goldman said in its report. </p>
<p>At this level, the spread will boost U.S. imports,
increasing inventories on the Gulf Coast and at Cushing,
Oklahoma, the delivery point for WTI, Goldman said. The bank
forecasts the difference will rebound to $10 a barrel in 2015. </p>
<p>Goldman''s conviction in its 2015 Brent forecast is waning
due to lack of tangible signs of sequential acceleration in
global economic growth, including in China, during the second
half of 2014, it said in the report. </p>
<p>Economists have cut estimates for this year''s gross
domestic product growth in China after data on industrial
profits, factory output and credit showed a deteriorating
outlook. </p>
<p>The Asian nation will account for about 11 percent of
global oil demand this year, compared with 21 percent for the
U.S., forecasts from the IEA in Paris show. </p>
<h2>Brent Recovery </h2>
<p>The chance of a price recovery to Goldman''s $100 forecast
for 2015 may also be capped if longer-term prices, which have
risen this year, catch up with the slide in prompt contracts,
the bank said. </p>
<p>Stabilizing geopolitical risk and growing perception of a
demand-constrained oil market could well combine to reverse some
of this remaining $4 a barrel year-to-date rally in five-year
forward Brent prices, it said. </p>
<p>Brent''s decline probably isn''t sustainable, data compiled
by Bloomberg show. On the weekly chart, the relative strength
index has dropped to 27.4, the lowest level since June 2012,
when futures fell to an 18-month low of less than $90 a barrel.
Readings below 30 typically signal a market is oversold and may
rebound. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Karen Gullo" date="Oct 04, 2014 12:10 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-10-04/microsoft-says-samsung-paid-1-billion-in-royalties-deal.html"><headline>Microsoft Says Samsung Paid $1 Billion in Royalties Deal</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) said in a patent
lawsuit against Samsung Electronics Co. that the South Korean
smartphone maker paid it as much as $1 billion in royalties last
year under a now-disputed 2011 licensing agreement. </p>
<p>The payment was disclosed for the first time in a court
filing in Microsoft''s complaint alleging Samsung breached an
agreement to share patents. The seven-year accord requires
Samsung to pay Microsoft royalties for phones and tablets that
use the software maker''s patented technology, according to the
filing yesterday in Manhattan federal court. </p>
<p>Samsung has refused to pay $6.9 million in interest owed
under the agreement, according to the filing. </p>
<p>Samsung has suggested that Microsoft has breached the
business collaboration agreement, David Howard, Microsoft''s
deputy general counsel, said yesterday in a blog post. We
disagree, and that''s why we asked the court to rule that
Microsoft is not in breach. </p>
<p>Microsoft claims Samsung is using Microsoft''s acquisition
of Nokia Oyj (NOK1V)''s phone business as an excuse to stop complying
with the contract. The license agreement contains explicit
provisions that grant a patent license to both companies''
subsidiaries, including Nokia, Microsoft said in the complaint. </p>




Photographer: David Paul Morris/Bloomberg

<p>
Microsoft Corp. claims Samsung Electronics Co. is using Microsoft''s acquisition of Nokia Oyj''s phone business as an excuse to stop complying with the contract. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry></news>