<?xml version='1.0' encoding='us-ascii'?>
<news><entry author="By Marco Bertacche" date="Feb 05, 2008 12:15 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-02-05/fiat-stock-drops-as-jpmorgan-cuts-recommendation-update1-.html"><headline>Fiat Stock Drops as JPMorgan Cuts Recommendation</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Fiat SpA (F) fell the most in almost two
weeks in Milan trading after JPMorgan Chase  Co. downgraded
Italy's largest manufacturer, saying the likelihood of a disposal
of the auto division was reduced. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stock slipped 1.03 euros, or 6.5 percent, to 14.79 euros
in the biggest drop since Jan. 23. The shares have fallen 16
percent this year, valuing the Turin, Italy-based company at 18.3
billion euros ($26.9 billion). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JPMorgan analysts including Philippe Houchois in London cut
Fiat shares to ``neutral'' from ``overweight'' in a note to
clients today, saying ``unfavorable economic conditions''
decrease chances of Fiat getting rid of carmaking operations.
Chief Executive Officer Sergio Marchionne told Automotive News in
a December interview that Fiat may consider spinning off the unit
if the company's shares trade lower than the value of its parts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stock may also have been hurt by the collapse of Italian
Prime Minister Romano Prodi's administration, which may prevent
extension of tax incentives on cars that the outgoing government
planned for 2008, pending final approval by parliament, said
Patrizio Pazzaglia, who helps manage the equivalent of $400
million at Bank Insinger de Beaufort NV in Rome. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``Concern that car incentives may not be confirmed in the
current government crisis is also weighing on the stock,''
Pazzaglia said. ``That would hurt earnings per share by as much
as 3 percent.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without prolonged tax reductions, Italian car sales might
drop 14 percent this year, trade group Promotor International SpA
has estimated. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Marco Bertacche in Milan at 
mbertacche@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Chris Jasper at  cjasper@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Steven Bodzin" date="Feb 11, 2008  6:44 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-02-11/venezuela-threatens-economic-war-over-exxon-freeze-update2-.html"><headline>Venezuela Threatens `Economic War' Over Exxon Freeze</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Venezuelan President Hugo Chavez
threatened to halt oil shipments to the U.S. and wage ``economic
war'' in retaliation for Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM)'s bid to freeze state
oil company assets held overseas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``Listen to me, Mr. Bush, Mr. Danger,'' Chavez said
yesterday during his weekly television show. `If the economic
war continues against Venezuela, the price of oil will reach
$200. Venezuela will take up the economic war and more than one
country is inclined to join us.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exxon last week said it won court orders blocking Petroleos
de Venezuela SA from selling assets as part of a legal battle
over the seizure of operations. Chavez held U.S. President
George W. Bush partly responsible for the freeze and worsening
relations between the two countries. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exxon's move may cut into Chavez's popularity by forcing
him to curb spending. Venezuela counts on oil income for 90
percent of its foreign exchange and half of federal tax revenue.
PDVSA, as the company is commonly called, also provides social
services outside the budget, such as the company's sale this
month of 252 tons of powdered milk. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;`Grave Problem' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``Exxon is the most grave problem the administration has
faced,'' said Pedro Benitez, an oil consultant and professor at
Central University of Venezuela. ``Clearly their cash flow is
very tight.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chavez and his ministers have previously alleged the U.S.
government is meddling in Venezuela's internal affairs. Chavez
accuses the U.S. of supporting a 2002 coup that ousted him for
two days. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chavez called Bush ``the devil'' in a visit to the United
Nations in 2006. When Argentine authorities found $800,000 on a
chartered jet carrying a PDVSA executive in 2007, Foreign
Minister Nicolas Maduro said the money was planted by the
Central Intelligence Agency, without providing evidence. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chavez's threat yesterday is second time in three months he
has warned of shutting oil shipments to the U.S. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``If you freeze us, if you succeed at freezing us and doing
us damage, we'll do you damage. Know this: We're not going to
send oil to the U.S.,'' Chavez said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;U.S. State Department spokesman Sean McCormack said the
legal case between Exxon and Venezuela ``should be resolved on
the basis of existing and accepted international laws, norms and
standards.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reliance on U.S. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chavez's threats may help strengthen his image at home and
represents no real intention to cut off supplies, Benitez said.
That's because most of the refineries able to handle Venezuelan
crude are in the U.S. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Statistics show that Venezuela's petrochemical industry
relies on U.S. refining capacity, McCormack told reporters today
in Washington. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``Based on our experience over the past nine years, this
type of threat isn't fulfilled,'' Benitez said. ``His political
goals for the year depend on oil prices breaking the $100
barrier.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crude oil for March delivery rose $1.82, or 2 percent, to
settle at $93.59 a barrel at 2:46 p.m. on the New York
Mercantile Exchange, the highest close since Jan. 14. Futures
have fallen 6.5 percent since touching a record $100.09 a barrel
Jan. 3. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mutual Dependence &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Venezuela was the second-biggest supplier of crude oil to
the U.S. through October last year, providing an average 1.74
million barrels a day of oil and petroleum products to the U.S.
and the Virgin Islands. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Venezuela sells more than half its oil output to the U.S.
It can't quickly shift to new customers because its thick,
sulfur-rich oil can only be handled by refineries designed
specifically for its characteristics. Most of those are on the
U.S. Gulf Coast. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rather than cutting oil shipments, Venezuela might
conceivably default on its $45 billion of external debt
obligations, Win Thin, senior currency strategist at Brown
Brothers Harriman  Co. in New York, wrote in an analysis today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``While we do not think that Chavez will resort to drastic
measures, we acknowledge that the probability is non-zero,''
Thin wrote. ``Look for Chavez to make more inflammatory comments
in the coming days, but without actually following through on
these threats.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Nationalization &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exxon is suing PDVSA in international arbitration for the
seizure of control and a majority stake in a multibillion-dollar
oil production project in Venezuela last year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The U.S. oil company said it won court orders in the U.K.,
Netherlands and Netherlands Antilles blocking the state oil
company from selling assets and transferring wealth out of those
countries if moving the money would reduce available assets
below $12 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exxon also won a U.S. court order freezing as much as $315
million that would otherwise have been transferred to Petroleos
de Venezuela as part of a bond buyback transaction last month,
according to federal court filings in New York. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Steven Bodzin in Caracas at 
sbodzin@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Andrew J. Barden at 
barden@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Feb 14, 2008  4:22 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-02-14/yahoo-investor-munder-prefers-microsoft-to-news-corp-update1-.html"><headline>Yahoo Investor Munder Prefers Microsoft to News Corp.</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Yahoo! Inc. (YHOO) shareholder Ken Smith,
director of technology investment at Munder Capital Management,
said he prefers Microsoft Corp. (MSFT)'s offer to acquire Yahoo to an
alliance with News Corp. (NWSA) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yahoo may seek to avoid a Microsoft takeover by combining
Internet operations with News Corp. The two companies are
discussing a transaction, according to a person with knowledge of
the talks. That won't help Yahoo because News Corp. is having
trouble finding ways to make money on the Internet, Munder said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``I don't see what it brings to the table for Yahoo or News
Corp.,'' Smith said. ``News Corp. has a lot of traffic but
they're having trouble monetizing it.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Munder, based in Birmingham, Michigan, manages $33 billion,
including 1.9 million Yahoo shares and 1.3 million Microsoft
shares as of Dec. 31, according to Bloomberg data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smith said he still would like Redmond, Washington-based
Microsoft to raise its $31 a share bid to $35. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yahoo, in Sunnyvale, California, rose 10 cents to $29.98 at
4 p.m. New York time in Nasdaq Stock Market trading. Microsoft
fell 46 cents to $28.50. News Corp.'s Class A shares declined 7
cents to $19.18 on the New York Stock Exchange. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Dina Bass in Seattle at 
dbass2@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Cesca Antonelli at 
fantonelli@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Rudy Ruitenberg" date="Feb 20, 2008  8:24 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-02-20/france-telecom-software-venture-challenges-microsoft-update1-.html"><headline>France Telecom Software Venture Challenges Microsoft</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;France Telecom SA (FTE), Europe's third-largest phone company, set up a venture with Thomson SA and
Sagem Communications to develop a standard for home networking
software that will compete with Microsoft Corp. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company, called Soft at Home, will develop software to
let digital devices such as Internet set-top boxes, televisions
and computers work together, Georges Penalver, France Telecom's
head of strategic marketing and the Orange Labs research
division, said today at a press conference in Paris. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soft at Home will help phone companies and device makers
keep down their development costs by avoiding duplication of
effort, Penalver said. The venture will adapt its software
based on input from network operators instead of imposing a
standard, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``Operators and equipment suppliers will jointly discuss
what they'll do,'' Penalver said. ``It's not necessarily the
goal of the company to compete with Microsoft. (MSFT) The difference
is, Microsoft doesn't discuss with its clients.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;France Telecom holds 60 percent of the venture, to be
based in Nanterre outside Paris. Thomson and Sagem each own a
20 percent stake. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Penalver said two telephone companies are ``very
interested'' in using the software standard, while another
three or four are awaiting the first product. Penalver said
France Telecom is open to other network operators taking a
stake in Soft at Home. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Home Applications &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``It's desirable that the operators continue to have
control of this company,'' Penalver said. ``We have to make the
round of operators that may be interested.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The software will, for example, allow consumers to use
televisions to look at photos stored on a computer, or take a
phone call using a television remote control, the companies
said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Soft at Home will use open-source code as the basis for
its programs, and build on software already developed by France
Telecom, Thomson and Sagem, Penalver said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``Microsoft has a standard that it seeks to implement,''
Penalver said. ``The goal is to have a standard that is
compatible with what France Telecom uses today. We'll develop
the functionality that we need at the rhythm that we need.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company will employ 70 to 80 people and the first new
software will be commercially available before the end of this
year, Penalver said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Rudy Ruitenberg in Paris at 
rruitenberg@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Lars Klemming at  lklemming@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Catherine Larkin" date="Feb 21, 2008  4:27 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-02-21/watson-wins-u-s-approval-to-copy-pfizer-cancer-drug-update2-.html"><headline>Watson Wins U.S. Approval to Copy Pfizer Cancer Drug</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Watson Pharmaceuticals Inc. (WPI), the
second-largest U.S. maker of generic drugs, won U.S. clearance to
sell the first lower-cost copy of Pfizer Inc. (PFE)'s cancer drug
Camptosar. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Food and Drug Administration gave final approval to
Watson's generic irinotecan hydrochloride after patents on the
brand-name drug expired, according to a notice posted today on
the agency's Web site. The Corona, California-based company said
yesterday that it is entitled to 180 days of market exclusivity
under U.S. law before the FDA can approve another generic. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting a generic on the market first is important because
prices generally fall as competition increases. Camptosar,
approved by the FDA in 1996, brought in $539 million in U.S.
sales for New York-based Pfizer last year. The product is an
injectable medicine used to treat colon or rectal cancer that has
spread to other parts of the body. Doctors often administer it
with other cancer treatments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watson ranks second among U.S. generic drugmakers by sales,
after Mylan Inc. (MYL), according to data compiled by research firm IMS
Health Inc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Watson fell 95 cents, or 3.4 percent, to $27.26 at 4:05 p.m.
in New York Stock Exchange composite trading. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Catherine Larkin in Washington at 
clarkin4@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Reg Gale at  rgale5@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry></news>