
<news><entry author="By Elizabeth Campbell" date="Nov 03, 2008  2:42 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-11-03/burger-king-davita-goldman-nordstrom-u-s-equity-movers.html"><headline>Burger King, DaVita, Goldman, Nordstrom: U.S. Equity Movers</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;The following companies are having
unusual price changes in U.S. trading. Stock symbols are in
parentheses, and share prices are as of 2 p.m. in New York. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advanced Medical Optics Inc. (EYE US) added 21 percent to
$7.44 and earlier climbed to $7.83, the highest intraday price
since Oct. 20. The maker of eye-care products was raised to
''''hold'''' from ''''underperform'''' at Jefferies Group Inc. based on
the stock''s 39 percent drop since the firm''s prior downgrade. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allegheny Energy Inc. (AYE US) fell 3.8 percent to $29.02
and earlier slumped 9.9 percent for the biggest intraday loss
since Oct. 22. The owner of utilities in four U.S. states
reported third-quarter profit declined 23 percent because of
higher costs for coal and milder weather. Earnings before certain
items were 19 percent less than the average analyst estimate,
according to Bloomberg data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ATT Inc. (T)  gained the most in the Dow Jones Industrial
Average, adding 4.3 to $27.92. Wachovia Corp. said the largest
U.S. phone company had a ''''compelling'''' valuation and it should
benefit as a ''''safe haven'''' stock. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verizon Communications Inc. (VZ)  was also highlighted
with ATT by Wachovia, which cited both companies'' free cash flow
and dividend yields. Verizon rose 2.3 percent to $30.34. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Burger King Holdings Inc. (BKC US) added 9.1 percent to
$21.68 and earlier rose to $22.58, the highest intraday price
since Oct. 9. The second-largest U.S. hamburger chain was raised
to ''''outperform'''' from ''''market perform'''' by Wachovia Corp. after
the stock price slid relative to earnings expectations. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Danaos Corp. (DAC)  added 6.6 percent to $8.94 and earlier
increased to $9.19, the highest intraday price in two weeks. The
largest publicly traded container shipper in the U.S. posted
third-quarter profit excluding some items of 48 cents a share,
beating the average analyst estimate by 6.7 percent. The company
also said it added more vessels to its fleet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DaVita Inc. (DVA)  slid 5.8 percent to $53.45, and earlier
fell 8.1 percent in the biggest intraday retreat in three weeks.
The second-largest U.S. operator of kidney dialysis centers said
profit declined less than one percent from a year earlier.
Revenue gains were eroded by greater patient-care costs and bad
debt provisions, and the company said there is risk of
''''continued downward pressure'''' on payments rates from insurers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DryShips Inc. (DRYS)  rose 17 percent to $22.52 and
earlier climbed 24 percent for the biggest intraday gain in three
weeks. The Greek owner of ships that haul iron ore and coal said
third-quarter profit increased 71 percent because of higher
shipping rates and a larger fleet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)  slid 4.1 percent to $88.68.
The New York-based firm is likely to report a fourth-quarter
loss, according to Guy Moszkowski, an analyst at Merrill Lynch 
Co., because of the ''''terrible'''' stock market. Richard Bove, an
analyst at Ladenburg Thalmann Inc., slashed his price target for
Goldman by 43 percent to $80 and said the company''s short-term
outlook is ''''poor.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goodyear Tire  Rubber Co. (GT)  added 9 percent to $9.2
and earlier gained 20 percent for the biggest intraday rise since
February 2004. The largest U.S. tiremaker reported third-quarter
profit, excluding some items, of 43 cents a share, more than the
average analyst estimate of 30 cents, according to Bloomberg
data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Halliburton Co. (HAL)  slid 9.4 percent to $17.93 and
earlier slumped 11 percent for the biggest intraday loss in a
week. The world''s second-largest oilfield-services provider was
cut to ''''neutral'''' from ''''buy'''' at Goldman Sachs on ''''product
risks and valuation.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hartford Financial Services Group Inc. (HIG)  rose the
most in the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index, surging 43 percent to
$14.74. The Connecticut-based insurer that tumbled 75 percent
last month said it has the capital to withstand further market
declines. The insurer will have $2 billion more than required to
qualify for an AA rating if the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index falls
to 900 on Dec. 31, the company said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NewBridge Bancorp. (NBBC)  plunged 14 percent to $3.25 and
earlier lost 19 percent for the biggest intraday drop since Oct.
23. The bank holding company suspended its cash dividend after
posting a loss of 10 cents a share for the third quarter. The
company also applied for $52 million under the U.S. Treasury''s
TARP program. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nordstrom Inc. (JWN)  dropped 9.7 percent to $16.29, the
biggest intraday fall since Oct. 24. Goldman Sachs Group Inc.
lowered earnings estimates for the department-store chain to
reflect ''''a more challenging backdrop for luxury consumer
spending over the next several quarters.'''' Goldman also lowered
estimates for clothing designer Polo Ralph Lauren Corp. (RL) 
and jewelers Tiffany  Co. (TIF)  and Zale Corp (ZLC US). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tiffany slid 7.9 percent to $25.27. Zale lost 5.7 percent to
$16.08. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Office Depot Inc. (ODP)  slid the most in the SP 500,
losing 18 percent to $2.95. Credit Suisse Group AG questioned the
''''quality'''' of the retailer''s quarterly results said the stock is
''''expensive'''' after more than doubling last week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oshkosh Corp. (OSK)  increased 6.5 percent to $8.16 and
earlier gained 19 percent for the biggest intraday jump in three
weeks. The Wisconsin-based maker of military trucks won a
contract valued at $1.2 billion to build heavy-duty trucks for
the U.S. army. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Walt Disney Co. (DIS)  fell the most in the Dow average,
slumping 6.5 percent to $24.23. Merrill Lynch  Co. cut its
share-price estimate for the second-largest U.S. media company by
11 percent to $24, saying the slowing economy would hurt its
theme park and television income. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Jeff Kearns" date="Nov 03, 2008 11:28 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-11-03/use-boeing-options-put-spreads-to-hedge-shares-goldman-says.html"><headline>Use Boeing Options &#8216;Put Spreads&#8217; to Hedge Shares, Goldman Says</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Investors should use Boeing Co. put
options to protect against a further share-price decline because
airliner sales may drop 50 percent next year as the global
economy slows, Goldman Sachs Group Inc. said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contracts on the world&#8217;s second-largest commercial-aircraft
maker behind Airbus SAS are &#8220;attractive&#8221; because their implied
volatility, a measure of expected price swings and the key gauge
of options prices, is low compared with similar companies,
options strategists John Marshall and Stuart Kaiser wrote. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;On a relative basis Boeing options are near a five-year low
versus both the SP 500 and its industrials peers, which we
believe is not reflective of near-term catalysts/risks,&#8221; the New
York-based strategists said in a note to clients. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They recommended a &#8220;put spread&#8221; strategy, specifically
buying a January $50 put while simultaneously selling a January
$40 put. Boeing retreated 1.9 percent to $51.43 in 10 a.m. New
York Stock Exchange composite trading, extending its loss this
year to 41 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trade is intended for investors who own the stock and
wish to protect against a decline or those who don&#8217;t own the
shares and want to profit from a drop. It protects against a drop
of 5 percent to 24 percent, the strategists said in the note,
published today before the open of U.S. exchanges. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selling options when using a put-spread strategy helps
finance the transaction because the seller collects the premium
paid by the buyer. Spreads also cap profit if the stock falls
below the lower strike price. Puts give the right to sell a
security for a certain amount, the strike, by a given date. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&#8216;Sell&#8217; Rating &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marshall and Kaiser cited analyst Richard Safran, who in a
separate note added the planemaker to Goldman&#8217;s &#8220;conviction sell&#8221;
list after the shares rallied as machinists ended an eight-week
strike. The analyst, who has kept a &#8220;sell&#8221; rating on the stock
since June, wrote today that he expects orders to drop by half
next year amid &#8220;weakening airline fundamentals.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Boeing Co. (BA) machinists accepted a four-year contract offer
Nov. 1, ending a strike that idled the planemaker&#8217;s factories and
cut profit by about $10.3 million a day. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Safran cut his estimate for Boeing&#8217;s 2010 earnings per share
to $5.95 from $6.25, predicting that production rates will
decline and that the Chicago-based manufacturer will buy back
less of its stock. Another delay to the 787 Dreamliner is likely
at the same time that airlines may have difficulty obtaining
financing, the analyst said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Victoria Slind-Flor" date="Nov 24, 2008  6:48 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-11-24/kodak-time-warner-disney-intellectual-property-update1-.html"><headline>Kodak, Time Warner, Disney: Intellectual Property</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Research In Motion Ltd. (BB), maker of
the BlackBerry e-mail device, sued Eastman Kodak Co. to
challenge four of its patents, including ones for digital-camera
technology used in mobile phones. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kodak, the 128-year-old photography company, filed a U.S.
trade complaint against Samsung Electronics Co. (005930) and LG
Electronics Inc. (066570) last week seeking to ban imports of mobile
phones with digital cameras and alleging infringement of two of
the patents. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kodak has claimed BlackBerrys, including the Pearl, also
use the technology, and the company demanded ''''exorbitant
royalties'''' during five meetings over the past year, Research In
Motion said in the complaint filed Nov. 20 in federal court in
Dallas. Research In Motion wants a court to rule that the
patents are invalid, not infringed or unenforceable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an Aug. 16, 2007, in a letter sent to Research In Motion
Chief Executive Officer Jim Balsillie, Kodak claimed that
''''devices that include a digital camera are utilizing Kodak''s
patented technology,'''' according to the complaint. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research In Motion, based in Waterloo, Ontario, has its
U.S. offices in Irving, Texas. The company started selling the
new BlackBerry Storm, a touch-screen phone, to compete with
Apple Inc.''s iPhone 3G. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kodak, based in Rochester, New York, said in the August
letter that it began a program in 2001 to license its patents
for digital imaging technology. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''We are disappointed that RIM has chosen to end
discussions that appeared to be on a reasonable path forward,''''
David Lanzillo, a Kodak spokesman, said Nov. 21 by e-mail. ''''The
Kodak patents targeted by RIM are valid and enforceable.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company last month said digital revenue would increase
1 percent to 4 percent this year, down from its initial
projection for growth of as much as 10 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kodak Chief Executive Officer Antonio Perez told investors
in February that the company could make an average of
$250 million to $350 million a year in licensing revenue from
its patent portfolio. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Research In Motion Ltd. v. Eastman Kodak Co.,
08cv2075, U.S. District Court, Northern District of Texas
(Dallas). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Star Scientific Chief Says Suit May Net $1 Billion &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Star Scientific Inc. (STSI), a maker of smokeless tobacco
products, may be awarded as much as $1 billion in damages in a
lawsuit asserting Reynolds American Inc. (RAI)''s R.J. Reynolds Tobacco
unit purposely infringed Star''s patents on low-toxin tobacco
curing, Chief Operating Officer Paul Perito said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Star is seeking $261 million to $311 million in damages in
a Maryland federal court trial scheduled for next year, Perito
said in an interview from Star''s headquarters in Petersburg,
Virginia. If jurors find the infringement an intentional
violation, the judge has the option to increase the amount by up
to triple the jury''s verdict, Perito said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The court has told counsel for both sides to be prepared
for a two- to three-week trial between April 20 and May 29. A
case-planning conference for the trial is set for Nov. 25. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''We believe we have powerful evidence that we''ve shown
through the discovery period and feel very comfortable with the
record that we''ve built in this case,'''' Perito said. ''''Reynolds
has now run out of delay arrows in their shrinking quiver.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Star sued Winston-Salem, North Carolina-based Reynolds in
2001 for using its StarCured process to make tobacco with lower
levels of cancer-causing chemicals and has been in court ever
since. In a victory for Star in August, the U.S. Court of
Appeals for the Federal Circuit in Washington ruled that a judge
was wrong to throw out the case in 2007. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that case, Carter G. Philips of Chicago''s Sidley Austin
made the oral argument on behalf of Star Scientific. Richard A.
Kaplan of Chicago''s Brinks, Hofer, Gilson  Lione argued the
case for Reynolds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''These legal battles have clearly impacted us,'''' Perito
said. ''''Not only have we had the diversion of cost and
personnel, but some other companies, who may have wanted to
lawfully license our technology, are perhaps sitting on the
sidelines waiting to see what happens.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reynolds, which argued the Star patents were unenforceable
and invalid, plans to ask the U.S. Supreme Court to hear its
case, company spokesman David Howard said. The company is
preparing to go to trial and is ''''confident'''' it will prevail,
Howard said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reynolds is the second-largest U.S. cigarette maker, with a
market capitalization of $12 billion. Philip Morris
International Inc. (PM) is the world''s largest publicly traded
tobacco company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The appellate court case is Star Scientific Inc. v. R.J.
Reynolds Tobacco Co., 2007-1448, U.S. Court of Appeals for the
Federal Circuit. The lower court case is Star Scientific Inc. v.
R.J. Reynolds Tobacco Co., 01cv1504, U.S. District Court,
District of Maryland (Greenbelt). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For more patent news from Nov. 21, click here &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Copyright &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;RDR Appeals Court Order in Potter Lexicon Infringement Case &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RDR Books, the publisher of ''''The Harry Potter Lexicon,''''
filed notice that it will appeal a copyright infringement
verdict in favor of author J.K. Rowling and Time Warner Inc. (TWX)''s
Warner Bros. Entertainment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RDR of Muskegon, Michigan, is appealing a Sept. 8 federal
court ruling barring publication of the guide to the popular
Harry Potter book and film series. Rowling and Warner argued the
Lexicon infringed Rowling''s work about the boy wizard. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The court awarded Rowling and Warner $6,750 in damages.
Rowling, whose books have sold more than 375 million copies, was
the only writer on Forbes magazine''s 2008 list of the world''s
wealthiest people, with a net worth of $1 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The notice of appeal was filed by Anthony T. Falzone and
Julie A. Ahrens of the Stanford Law School Center for Internet
and Society, which represented RDR at trial. The center took on
the case to demonstrate that copyright law''s fair-use doctrine
protects the Lexicon, Falzone said in a statement released last
year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tennessee University Downloading Law Goes into Effect &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tennessee Governor Phil Bredesen signed a bill requiring
universities in the state to prevent their students from
illegally downloading and sharing copyright content. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He signed the bill Nov. 12 at a ceremony celebrating the
Country Music Association, a Nashville-based organization
established to promote that musical genre. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the measure, Tennessee Senate Bill 3974, colleges and
universities must put a policy into place that describes and
prohibits copyright infringement over the schools'' computer and
network resources and lays out the penalties under federal law
and the school code. The schools also must ''''reasonably
attempt'''' to prevent infringement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The law also specified that any school that receives more
than 50 ''''legally valid notices of infringement'''' under the
Digital Millennium Copyright Act must make a report to the
Tennessee Higher Education Commission. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new law went into effect the day it was signed by the
governor. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''The illegal downloading of music has a profoundly
negative effect on the music industry,'''' Bredesen said in his
signing statement, according to the state Web site. ''''As home to
so many record companies, music publishers, writers and artists,
I am proud that Tennessee is taking action to prevent it.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conservatives Urge Copyright Reform in Canada''s `Throne Speech'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Canada''s Conservative government will pursue copyright
reform in the coming year, according to the annual policy
statement known as the ''''Throne Speech.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The speech, which outlines the government''s goals, was
released Nov. 19. The government said it ''''will proceed with
legislation to modernize Canada''s copyright laws and ensure
stronger protection for intellectual property.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reform is needed because ''''cultural creativity and
innovation are vital, not only to a lively Canadian cultural
life, but also to Canada''s economic future,'''' according to the
speech text. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The speech made ''''a much needed step'''' toward reforming
Canada''s ''''current outdated legislation,'''' the Canadian
Intellectual Property Council said in a statement Nov. 20. The
council seeks the criminalization of trademark counterfeiting
and sale of pirated goods, and ''''the adoption of stronger
penalties for counterfeiting and piracy,'''' according to the
statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Among the members of the council are Canadian units of
Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), EBay Inc. (EBAY), Cisco Systems Inc. (CSCO) and Pfizer Inc. (PFE) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michael Geist, a professor at the University of Ottawa, has
a blog that frequently discusses Canadian copyright issues.
Reader postings made after the throne speech was released were
generally negative about copyright reform the Conservative
government may envision. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''`Cultural creativity and innovation'' can only flourish in
an environment where all knowledge and culture is locked down
under armed guard,'''' one poster wrote. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another suggested the content industries won''t make changes
in their business models to reflect realties of new technology
''''when they can make criminals of us all instead. So much for
promoting innovation and all that stuff.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Conservative government had also promised copyright
reform in last year''s throne speech. A bill amending the
copyright act was introduced in June 2008. No reforms have been
enacted yet. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For more copyright news from Nov. 21, click here &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Trademark &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;`Goth milk?'' Costume Maker Denies Infringing Milk Board Slogan &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The California Fluid Milk Processor Advisory Board, the
marketing group for the state''s dairy farmers, was sued by a New
York-based maker of Halloween costumes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forum Novelties Inc., of Richmond Hill, New York, asked the
court to declare it''s not infringing the board''s ''''got milk?''''
slogan, according to a complaint filed Nov. 14 in federal court
in Manhattan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The California dairy industry is the largest in the U.S.,
producing 38.8 billion pounds of milk generating $4.49 billion
in sales in 2006, according to the California Department of Food
and Agriculture. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two of Forum''s customers received cease-and-desist letters
from the Berkeley, California-based milk board Oct. 6, alleging
that their sale of a particular costume made by Forum Novelties
infringed the trademark, according to court papers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At issue is a ''''Goth Cow Costume'''' with a black and silver
print hood with attached cow ears pierced with silver hoops, a
black nose ring, a bodysuit with silver-studded wrist bands, and
udders that are pierced and connected with silver chains,
according to court papers. ''''Goth Milk'''' is printed across the
costume''s chest, in ''''a bubble-style squiggly font,'''' Forum says
in its court papers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forum notes that the milk board''s U.S. trademark
registration for the ''''got milk?'''' phrase doesn''t cover costumes
for adults or children. The board does sell T-shirts and other
clothing items printed with ''''got milk?'''' through its Web site. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no likelihood of confusion between the costumes
and the milk board, Forum asserts, insisting the words ''''Goth
Milk?'''' are used only ''''for the expressive, clever and parodic
purpose of conveying a message in comedic form.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Goth milk costume ''''pokes fun at the wholesome goodness
and purity'''' represented by the milk board, Forum said in its
court papers. Potential customers for the costume are ''''young
people who seek to go against the trend of wholesomeness and
purity and are deliberately wearing outrageous and potentially
offensive or counterculture clothing,'''' Forum argues in its
pleadings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Forum asked the court to declare that its costumes don''t
infringe the milk board''s trademark, and for other unspecified
relief. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Andrew S. Langsam and Nia J.C. Castelly of New York''s Pryor
Cashman represent Forum. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Forum Novelties Inc. v. California Fluid Milk
Processor Advisory Board, 1:08-cv-09894-LLS, U.S. District
Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For more trademark news from Nov. 21, click here &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Trade Secrets/Industrial Espionage &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cost of Cow Manure-Derived Power a Trade Secret, Agency Claims &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A California government agency is refusing to reveal how
much it will pay a cheese maker for electricity generated from
cow manure, claiming the information is a trade secret, the
Modesto Bee reported Nov. 19. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Modesto Irrigation District, in California''s central
valley, agreed Nov. 18 to buy electricity from Fiscalini Cheese
Co., which has installed a system to extract methane from the
cow manure and burn it to generate electrical power, according
to the Modesto Bee. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The price must remain a trade secret because revealing the
information would put the utility at a competitive disadvantage
when negotiating with other dairy farmers planning to install
similar systems, Tim O''Laughlin, the agency''s attorney said and
the Modesto Bee reported. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The agency said that while the cow-derived electricity was
more expensive than conventional energy-generation systems, it
was cheaper than some other systems derived from renewable
energy, according to the Modesto Bee. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Out-of-State Ticket Company Subject to Arkansas Law, Judge Rules &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Walt Disney Co. (DIS)''s Hannah Montana character performed
in Little Rock, Arkansas, in the person of Miley Cyrus, the
speed with which the tickets sold out trigged an investigation
by the state attorney general''s office, the Arkansas Democrat
Gazette reported Nov. 20. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In March, in response to complaints from Cyrus'' management
and Ticketmaster Entertainment Inc. -- which had the exclusive
right to sell tickets -- the state sued Ticket Software LLC of
Vernon, Connecticut, seeking disclosure of its clients who were
using the Web to sell tickets, according to the Arkansas
Democrat Gazette. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ticket Software refused, saying its clients'' names were a
trade secret, and that as a Connecticut company, its operations
didn''t come under Arkansas law, the newspaper reported. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Nov. 19, a state court judge ruled that the company is
subject to Arkansas law, and refused to toss out the attorney
general''s request for the client names, according to the
Arkansas Democrat Gazette. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;IP Moves &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Foley Hoag Hires Patent Lawyer Rajesh Vallabh from WilmerHale &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Foley Hoag hired Rajesh Vallabh for its IP group, the
Boston-based firm said in a statement Nov. 21. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vallabh, a patent specialist, joins from Washington''s
WilmerHale. He has also practiced at New York-based Kenyon 
Kenyon. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before he was a lawyer, Vallabh worked as a design engineer
at Airborn Connectors, a maker of electronic connectors for
aerospace and commercial aviation applications. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He is listed as the attorney of record on four issued U.S.
patents, according to the database of the U.S. Patent and
Trademark Office. He has helped clients procure patents in the
computer software and hardware, telecommunications, computer
networks, semiconductor, e-commerce, business methods, medical
devices, machinery and industrial processes areas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vallabh has undergraduate degrees in both electrical and
mechanical engineering from Southern Methodist University and a
law degree from Columbia University. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Bloomberg articles by lawyers on intellectual property
Topics click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;For daily Bloomberg legal analysis click here &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry></news>