<?xml version='1.0' encoding='us-ascii'?>
<news><entry author="By Mary Jane Credeur" date="Sep 14, 2007  4:13 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-09-14/coca-cola-will-sell-odwalla-juice-based-energy-drink-update3-.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Will Sell Odwalla Juice-Based Energy Drink</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola Co. (KO), the world's largest
soda maker, will begin selling an energy drink under its Odwalla
juice line to capture more sales in the faster-growing market. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first variety of Odwalla Serious Energy is made with
pineapple, mango, guava and passion-fruit juices, Atlanta-based
Coca-Cola said today in an e-mailed statement. The 15.2-ounce
drinks will have a suggested retail price of $3.29. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola is adding more juice and tea-based beverages to
woo consumers who have cut back on soda amid obesity concerns.
Coca-Cola's energy drink sales almost doubled last year, to 17.8
million cases, led by Full Throttle and Tab Energy, according to
data from industry journal Beverage Digest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company's soft-drink sales have dropped for four
straight quarters in North America. Coca-Cola Classic, the top-
selling soda, posted a 2 percent drop in volume last year to
1.76 billion cases in the U.S., according to Beverage Digest. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Odwalla energy drink has extracts of guarana, yerba
mate, green tea and ginseng, which the company says help
increase alertness. Some of those ingredients have naturally
occurring caffeine, although no additional caffeine is added,
Coca-Cola spokesman Ray Crockett said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most energy beverages, such as those made by Red Bull GmbH
as well as Hansen Natural Corp.'s Monster Energy, use caffeine
and guarana as stimulants. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coca-Cola rose 53 cents, or 1 percent, to $56.40 at 4:03
p.m. in New York Stock Exchange composite trading. The shares
have gained 17 percent this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Mary Jane Credeur in Atlanta at 
mcredeur@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Michael Nol at  mnol@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Jeremy van Loon" date="Sep 21, 2007 12:45 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-09-21/fiat-renault-gain-on-goldman-auto-industry-report-update3-.html"><headline>Fiat, Renault Gain on Goldman Auto Industry Report</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Fiat SpA (F), Renault SA (RNO) and other
European carmakers rose after Goldman Sachs Group Inc. analysts
said automobile industry shares are ``attractive'' as
manufacturers deliver earnings growth. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fiat increased rose 92 cents, or 4.8 percent, to 20.15
euros in Milan, while Renault gained 3.20 euros, or 3.3 percent,
to 100 euros in Paris. DaimlerChrysler AG, Volkswagen AG (VOW) and
Bayerische Motoren Werke AG (BMW) all advanced. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Turin, Italy-based Fiat, which sold businesses and
introduced new models, may rise 60 percent over the next 12
months, London-based Goldman analysts Stefan Burgstaller, Shane McKenna and Tim Rothery said in a note today. The automotive
industry will ``improve returns'' over the next three years,
they said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``Almost half the value creation we estimate to be derived
from restructuring benefits as the industry gradually implements
its new cost structure with every new product launch,'' the
analysts said. ``We believe the European manufacturers are well
placed to benefit from emerging market growth.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Goldman analysts also said they expect Renault shares
to rise 60 percent over the next year. ``We believe that 2006
marked a low point for Renault's earnings, while the recent
first-half results highlight that the company is well positioned
to deliver on its 3 percent operating margin target,'' the
analysts said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Growth Markets &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;European carmakers have expanded into growing markets such
as Russia, China and India with new factories and sales networks
as demand stagnates in their domestic markets, the U.S. and
Japan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fiat has introduced new models such as the 500, an updated
version of the small car popular in the 1950s and 1960s, which
join vehicles such as the Grande Punto that are helping Italy's
biggest manufacturer boost sales. Sales gained 7.2 percent in
the first six months of this year, making it the fastest-growing
European carmaker. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporters on this story:
Jeremy van Loon in Berlin at 
jvanloon@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Christopher Jasper at  cjasper@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry></news>