
<news><entry author="By Drew Armstrong" date="Apr 06, 2014 12:29 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-06/pfizer-lilly-breast-cancer-drugs-slow-tumors-in-studies.html"><headline>Pfizer, Lilly Breast Cancer Drugs Slow Tumors in Studies</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Experimental breast cancer drugs from Pfizer Inc. (PFE) and Eli Lilly  Co. (LLY) slowed or halted growth of advanced tumors in studies, potentially adding a new treatment option for patients and top-selling therapies for the companies. </p> <p>Pfizer''s palbociclib doubled to 20.2 months the time in which patients'' advanced breast cancer didn''t progress, the drugmaker said today. In an unrelated study, Lilly''s drug, bemaciclib, aided 61 percent of patients with metastatic, hormone-sensitive breast cancer, meaning the size of their tumors shrunk by 30 percent or didn''t increase for 24 weeks. </p> <p>Doctors and investors have been awaiting results for the medicines, part of a class called cyclin-dependent kinase 4/6 inhibitors. The therapies offer a new treatment avenue for about 80 percent of patients whose breast tumors are hormone receptor-positive. Palbociclib is projected to sell $3.11 billion in 2020 as it expands to fight other cancers. </p> <p>We took a new drug and asked how it works in a specific set of breast cancers based on science, said Richard Finn, an associate professor at the University of California at Los Angeles''s Jonsson Comprehensive Cancer Center, and co-principal investigator of Pfizer''s study. This is really the type of benefit we''re aiming for, and it''s the type of benefit that results from a rational development program. </p>




Source: Universal Images Group via Getty Images

<p>
A breast cancer cell is seen photographed by a scanning electron microscope. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Zajac" date="Apr 07, 2014  7:34 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-07/disney-and-other-studios-sue-megaupload-over-copyright-claims.html"><headline>Disney, Movie Studios Sue Megaupload Over Copyright Claims</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Disney Enterprises Inc., Warner
Bros. Entertainment Inc. and four other movie studios accused
the closed file-sharing service Megaupload.com of massive theft
of intellectual property in a copyright-infringement lawsuit. </p>
<p>While billing itself as a private data storage provider,
Megaupload.com functioned as a hub for uploading and downloading
copyrighted movies and TV shows, according to the complaint
filed today in federal court in Alexandria, Virginia, which
names Megaupload Ltd., the owner of the Megaupload.com website,
company founder Kim Dotcom, a second company and two other
individuals as defendants. </p>
<p>Dotcom was accused in an indictment unsealed in January
2012 of belonging to a global criminal organization prosecutors
called Mega Conspiracy that was involved in copyright
infringement and money laundering and generated more than $175
million in illicit proceeds. </p>
<p>When Megaupload.com was shut down in 2012 by U.S. law
enforcement, it was by all estimates the largest and most active
infringing website targeting creative content in the world,
Steven Fabrizio, senior executive vice president and global
general counsel of the Motion Picture Association of America,
said in today in a statement. </p>
<p>Megaupload.com had a business model designed to encourage
theft -- and make its owners very rich in the process,
Fabrizio said. </p>
<h2>Bogus'' Claims </h2>
<p>The @MPAA repeats bogus DOJ claims that we induced
copyright infringement. No. 1 reward rule published on MU site:
No copyright infringement,'' according to a post on Kim
Dotcom''s Twitter feed. </p>
<p>The studios'' lawsuit is a meritless re-hash of issues
raised in the criminal case, Ira Rothken, Dotcom''s San Rafael,
California-based attorney, said in a phone interview. We will
vigorously defend against the claims, he said. </p>
<p>Megaupload.com built up its library of illicit offerings by
encouraging users to upload movies and other entertainment
through an Uploader Rewards program. Amounts paid through
the program were based on how often pirated material was
downloaded for viewing by others, according to the studios''
complaint. </p>
<p>Megaupload.com made money by charging subscriptions
enabling faster downloads and by selling advertising on the
heavily trafficked website, the movie makers said in the filing. </p>
<h2>Rewards Program </h2>
<p>Rothken said the rewards program was limited to files that
are far too small to transmit movies. The studios'' assertion the
rewards program encouraged copyright infringement wouldn''t
pass the giggle test, he said. </p>
<p>Dotcom and two others named in the complaint, Mathias
Ortman, a German citizen, and Bram van der Kolk, a Dutch
citizen, are fighting extradition from New Zealand, according to
Peter Carr, a Justice Department spokesman. </p>
<p>Ortman and van der Kolk provided technological expertise to
Megaupload and are part-owners of it, according to the suit. </p>
<p>In February, a New Zealand appeals court ruled that search
warrants used in a 2012 raid on Dotcom''s home were valid,
bolstering the U.S. effort to extradite him. </p>
<p>The suit also names Vester Ltd., a Hong Kong company of
which Dotcom is the sole shareholder. Vester is majority
shareholder of Megaupload Ltd. </p>
<p>Besides the unit of Burbank, California-based Walt Disney (DIS)
Co., plaintiffs in the case include Paramount Pictures Corp.,
Universal City Studios Productions LLLP, Columbia Pictures
Industries Inc. and Twentieth Century Fox Film Corp. </p>
<p>The case is Twentieth Century Fox v. Megaupload.com, 14-cv-362, U.S. District Court, Eastern District of Virginia
(Alexandria). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Charles Mead" date="Apr 07, 2014  6:47 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-07/jpmorgan-deutsche-bank-said-to-manage-potential-greek-bond-sale.html"><headline>JPMorgan, Deutsche Bank Said to Manage Potential Greek Bond Sale</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Greece tapped JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)
and Deutsche Bank AG to manage an expected debt offering as it
seeks a return to the capital markets, according to people with
knowledge of the transaction. </p>
<p>The firms will underwrite the deal as the nation with the
worst jobless rate in the euro area attempts to sell bonds for
the first time since being shut out in early 2010, said the
people, who asked not to be identified, citing lack of
authorization to speak publicly. </p>
<p>Greece''s Finance Minister Yannis Stournaras suggested last
week that the government would issue notes in the first half of
2014. </p>
<p>Growing confidence among officials on the prospect of
selling debt has risen as bond yields have fallen to a four-year
low. Their optimism rests on the premise of persuading investors
that Greece will shake off a six-year recession. </p>
<p>The yield on Greek 10-year bonds has dropped below 6.2
percent from more than 30 percent in 2012. Greek securities have
returned 31 percent this year, the best performance among the 34
sovereign debt markets tracked by the Bloomberg World Bond
Indexes. </p>
<p>Germany has welcomed the planned bond sale as evidence that
confidence of the financial markets is returning to Greece,
Nadine Kalwey, a spokeswoman for Germany''s Finance Ministry,
said yesterday. </p>
<p>Greece''s financing situation has already benefited from a
budget surplus before interest costs of almost 3 billion euros
($4.1 billion), which the government expects the European
Union''s statistics agency to confirm this month. </p>
<p>Last week, three officials said that the government planned
to sell 2 billion euros of bonds. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hugh Son" date="Apr 07, 2014 10:33 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-07/jpmorgan-s-pinto-shuffles-deputies-names-hernandez-unit-co-head.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Pinto Shuffles Deputies, Names Hernandez Unit Co-Head</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) named Carlos Hernandez co-head of global banking with Jeff Urwin as corporate
and investment-banking chief Daniel Pinto overhauls the
division''s leadership. </p>
<p>Hernandez and Urwin, 58, will manage corporate banking,
investment banking and treasury services, according to a staff
memo today from Pinto. Hernandez previously led New York-based
JPMorgan''s investor-services team. Don McCree, 52, who was named
head of corporate banking and treasury services in a 2012
reorganization, is leaving the firm, according to the memo. </p>
<p>Pinto, 51, became sole investment-banking chief of the
biggest U.S. lender by assets last month after Mike Cavanagh,
48, left to join private-equity firm Carlyle Group LP. The
surprise departure forced Pinto to restructure reporting lines,
promoting veterans including Hernandez, who joined JPMorgan in
the 1980s and rose to head of global equities and other roles. </p>
<p>John Horner, who managed the markets and investor-services
financing units, will succeed Hernandez as head of investor
services. Joyce Chang was named global head of research, filling
the position after Tom Schmidt asked for a new role. </p>
<p>Oversight of the bank''s remaining commodities operation
will be shared by James Kenny and Troy Rohrbaugh, who were named
co-heads of global rates, foreign exchange, commodities and
emerging markets, according to the memo. Blythe Masters, 45,
said last week she planned to leave the firm after helping
complete the $3.5 billion sale of its physical commodities unit
to Mercuria Energy Group Ltd. </p>




Source: JPMorgan Chase  Co. via Bloomberg

<p>
Daniel Pinto became sole investment-banking chief of JPMorgan Chase  Co. last month after Mike Cavanagh left to join private-equity firm Carlyle Group LP. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Eric Ombok" date="Apr 07, 2014  9:09 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-07/jpmorgan-u-k-government-invest-in-fund-for-african-business.html"><headline>JPMorgan, U.K. Government Invest in Fund for Africa Business</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> JPMorgan Chase  Co. and the U.K.''s
Department for International Development will contribute a
combined $20 million to a private-equity fund investing in
startup businesses operating in East Africa. </p>
<p>DFID''s Impact Fund, which is managed by CDC Group, a
development finance institution owned by the U.K. government,
will provide $15 million to Novastar Ventures and JPMorgan the
rest, the companies said today in an e-mailed statement. The
money will finance health care, education, housing, energy and
sanitation projects that are expected to reach as many as 2
million people over the next decade, they said. </p>
<p>Private sector capital is crucial to economic growth in
East Africa, Peter Scher, head of corporate responsibility at
JPMorgan Chase, said in an e-mailed reply to questions. There
is a recognition that governmental and aid organizations cannot
do this alone. </p>
<p>Investors should accelerate investments to build
infrastructure in Africa and form public-private partnerships
that will help improve economic and social conditions, Kenyan
President Uhuru Kenyatta said on April 2. </p>
<p>It marks the first investment released from the 75 million-pound ($124 million) Impact Fund announced by the U.K. in 2012
to provide capital to companies and programs that will generate
returns in sub-Saharan Africa and South Asia. </p>
<h2>Social Good </h2>
<p>Novastar is focusing its investments on early-stage
businesses that offer massive social benefits to low-income
households, Managing Director Steve Beck said on April 5 by
phone from Nairobi, the Kenyan capital. </p>
<p>Novastar will accelerate the existing investment program
of SpringHill Equity Partners, an informal investor circle that
has been making venture investments in East Africa, Beck said. </p>
<p>Novastar in March made its initial investment in Bridge
International Academies, which has built more than 250 schools
in Kenya, according to the statement. The Nairobi-based chain of
nursery and primary schools charges students an average of $5 a
month, according to its website. </p>
<p>Market-based approaches, along with interested investors,
can attract the private sector capital necessary to create
change, Scher said. </p>
<p>Private equity funds invested more than three times as much
in sub-Saharan Africa last year as they did in 2012 as the
number of deals during the period rose to 84 from 58, according
to the 2014 East Africa Private Equity Confidence Survey
released by Deloitte. In East Africa, the number of deals in
Kenya last year was 12, five in Rwanda, and three each in Uganda
and Tanzania, according to the report. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarmad Khan and Arif Sharif" date="Apr 07, 2014  5:20 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-07/morgan-stanley-former-mideast-equity-head-joins-amwal-as-ceo.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Former Mideast Equity Head Joins Amwal as CEO</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Fahmi Alghussein, Morgan Stanley (MS)''s
former head of Middle East equity sales and trading, has joined
Qatar asset management company Amwal as chief executive officer. </p>
<p>Alghussein, who was most recently at Dubai-based financial
boutique HK Advisory Services Ltd., joined Amwal QSC on March 31
after leaving HK at the end of January, he said in a phone
interview from Doha. Amwal is working to win more mandates to
manage funds for companies, family offices, and high net worth
individuals, he said. </p>
<p>Alghussein left Morgan Stanley in February 2013 after more
than five years and has also worked for Citigroup Inc. and HSBC
Holdings Plc. Morgan Stanley shifted its Middle East and North
Africa equities business to Riyadh from Dubai last year, a
banker familiar with the matter said at that time. </p>
<p>Institutions including Qatar National Bank SAQ, the
country''s biggest lender, private equity company Abraaj Group
Ltd. and Dubai-based investment bank Shuaa Capital PSC
previously held stakes in Amwal. They sold out to company
founder Sheikha Hanadi Nasser bin Khaled Al Thani in 2013,
leaving her the sole shareholder, Alghussein said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Rachel Evans" date="Apr 07, 2014  4:25 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-07/goldman-sees-chance-to-cut-china-junk-debt-holdings-after-gains.html"><headline>Goldman Sees Chance to Cut Its China Junk Debt Holdings</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) says now
may be a good time to cut holdings of Chinese high-yield bonds
after the longest winning streak in six weeks. </p>
<p>Investors should use the recent rally to reduce
overweight positions, analysts led by Hong Kong-based Kenneth Ho wrote in a note dated April 4. We believe that there will
be more headlines noises to come out of China and expect to see
further credit differentiation. </p>
<p>Dollar-denominated junk bonds from the nation gained 0.95
percent in the seven days through April 4 for the second
straight weekly advance, according to Bank of America Merrill
Lynch indexes. While recent improvement in emerging-market
sentiment and China''s announcement of stimulus last week fueled
the rally, better-quality issuers remain Goldman''s preferred bet
amid continued concern about the world''s second-biggest economy,
according to the note. </p>
<p>China unveiled a package of measures to support the economy
including railway investment and tax breaks last week, as the
government seeks to bolster slowing growth. Exports (CNFREXPY) likely rose
4.9 percent in March from a year earlier, according to the
median estimate of 37 analysts surveyed by Bloomberg News before
trade data this week, after the biggest drop since 2009 in
February. Manufacturing contracted a third month in March, an
HSBC Holdings Plc and Markit Economics gauge showed last week. </p>
<h2>Sinopec Sells </h2>
<p>China Petrochemical Corp., known as Sinopec Group and
parent of Asia''s largest oil refiner, sold $5 billion of bonds
on April 2, the biggest dollar-denominated sale by an Asian
issuer in a decade, data compiled by Bloomberg show. China Citic
Bank International Ltd. meets investors from today about a
possible offering of notes in the U.S. currency, a person
familiar with the matter said last week. </p>
<p>We expect China issuance to increase and to catch up in
the remaining quarters, especially given the improvement in
market sentiment in recent weeks, wrote Ho. Offerings from the
nation slumped to $12.7 billion in the first three months of the
year, from $15.1 billion during the same period last year,
according to Goldman data. </p>
<p>Sri Lanka plans to sell as much as $500 million of notes as
soon as today, a person familiar with the matter said. The
sovereign is marketing five-year bonds at about 5.5 percent, the
person said, asking not to be identified because the terms
aren''t set. </p>
<p>Pakistan plans to price five- and 10-year dollar-denominated debt as soon as tomorrow, a separate person said.
Bangladesh''s Banglalink Digital Communications Ltd. is
considering a $300 million offering of five-year securities,
Moody''s Investors Service wrote in an e-mailed note today. </p>
<p>The cost of insuring Asian corporate and sovereign bonds
from default was little changed today, according to traders of
credit-default swaps. </p>
<h2>Asia Risk </h2>
<p>The Markit iTraxx Asia index of 40 investment-grade
borrowers outside Japan was little changed at 124 basis points
as of 8:08 a.m. in Hong Kong, Australia  New Zealand Banking
Group Ltd. prices show. The benchmark is holding at its lowest
level since April 2, when it touched a six-month low, according
to CMA, which is owned by McGraw-Hill Cos. and compiles prices
quoted by dealers in the privately negotiated market. </p>
<p>The Markit iTraxx Australia index slipped 0.5 basis point
to 97.5 basis points as of 9:35 a.m. in Sydney, according to
Westpac Banking Corp. The gauge is on course for its lowest
close since April 2, according to data provider CMA. </p>
<p>The Markit iTraxx Japan index was little changed at 83.5
basis points as of 8:40 a.m. in Tokyo, Citigroup Inc. prices
show. </p>
<p>Credit-default swap indexes are benchmarks for protecting
bonds against default and traders use them to speculate on
credit quality. A drop signals improving perceptions of
creditworthiness, while an increase suggests the opposite. </p>
<p>The swap contracts pay the buyer face value in exchange for
the underlying securities if a borrower fails to meet its debt
agreements. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass and Cliff Edwards" date="Apr 07, 2014 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-07/microsoft-goes-hollywood-in-amazon-like-programming-push.html"><headline>Microsoft Goes Hollywood in Amazon-Like Programming Push</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. is going Hollywood with a cast including comedians Sarah Silverman and Seth Green, aspiring World Cup players and eerily human robots. </p> <p>All are involved in shows that Microsoft''s new Xbox television studio plans to roll out globally starting in June. Helmed by former CBS Corp. honcho Nancy Tellem, who Microsoft hired 19 months ago to build a TV powerhouse from the ground up, the studio now has six series lined up -- including a science-fiction thriller called Humans about humanoid robot workers -- and more than a dozen projects in development. </p> <p>It''s unfamiliar ground for the world''s largest software maker, which has zero experience in original TV programming and is wading into a crowded field where Netflix Inc. and Amazon.com Inc. have generated hits such as House of Cards. Yet Microsoft is betting on the new studio to produce shows that will attract consumers to its Xbox game console, lure subscribers to its Xbox Live online service and eventually anchor a consumer home entertainment network that will tie the company''s devices together. </p> <p>TV, as the highest-reach form of entertainment you can find, is a critical part of wooing consumers to Microsoft, said Phil Spencer, who was last week named head of the Xbox business. </p>




Photographer: Patrick T. Fallon/Bloomberg

<p>
A visitor''s shadow falls on a logo as he plays on an Xbox One video games consoles during the Microsoft Corp. midnight launch event in Los Angeles. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael P. Regan" date="Apr 08, 2014 11:34 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-08/goldman-sees-67-chance-of-pothole-on-road-to-flat-market.html"><headline>Goldman Strategist Sees High Chance of 10% Market Drop</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc.''s David Kostin has some good news, and some bad news. </p> <p>First, the bad news. There''s a good chance the U.S. stock market will see a 10 percent drop sometime during the next 12 months. Well, as far as precision goes, good chance is not good enough for a quant like Kostin, so he gives an exact probability: 67 percent odds of a 10 percent retreat from a peak in the next 12 months. </p> <p>Though quant work can be complicated, his rationale is actually quite simple -- the market has gone way too long without a so-called correction, or a drop of at least 10 percent from a peak. The biggest declines from highs this year and last year were about 6 percent, and it''s been 22 months since the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index (SPX) saw a 10 percent drop. Mix in a little fancy math, and Kostin ends up with 67 percent odds we''ll see a correction in the next 12 months. </p> <p>Now for the good news, if you can call it that: He still expects the market to end the year higher, though not by much. Kostin is sticking with his year-end SP 500 forecast of 1,900, according to a note to clients dated yesterday. That implies a gain of less than 2.8 percent for the year and less than 3 percent from yesterday''s close. In other words, a relatively flat market given the ferocity of the gains seen in this bull run. </p> <p>Next year will be better in Kostin''s view, with a gain of 11 percent to 2,100 from his 2014 forecast. The SP 500 will add another 4.8 percent on top of that to 2,200 in 2016, he predicts. </p> <h2>Ho Hum </h2> <p>Since the beginning of the year, Wall Street strategists have held firm to forecasts for a ho-hum market this year following last year''s 30 percent rally in the SP 500. The average projection on Jan. 3 called for a 5.8 percent gain to 1,955 in 2014, according to estimates compiled by Bloomberg. By April 1, the mean forecast had only moved up six points to 1,961. </p> <p>It''s important to note in here that these oracles sort of missed the boat last year. The average estimate on Jan. 2, 2013, called for a 7.6 percent gain by the end of the year, while the SP 500 ended up jumping 30 percent to 1,848.36. Citigroup Inc.''s Tobias Levkovich was closest at 1,615, still more than 200 points off. Kostin forecast a 2013 close of 1,575, almost 300 points off. </p> <p>So if Wall Street strategists were meteorologists, last year they called for a few inches of snow and the market ended up getting a blizzard. This year, they''re calling for a dusting and so far they haven''t been too far off -- no accumulation. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ben Sharples" date="Apr 08, 2014  3:52 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-08/morgan-stanley-says-coal-exporters-making-loss-as-estimates-cut.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Says Coal Exporters Making Loss as Estimates Cut</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Coal producers may need to cut
exports of the steel-making variety after the lowest contract
settlement with Asian buyers in seven years made more than half
of global shipments uneconomical, according to Morgan Stanley. </p>
<p>About 157 million metric tons, or 60 percent, of exports
from countries such as Australia and the U.S. will be shipped at
a loss under the second-quarter contract agreed at $120 a ton,
Joel Crane, an analyst at Morgan Stanley in Melbourne, said in a
note today. The bank cut its 2014 and 2015 estimates for prices
of coking coal, used to make steel, and the thermal variety. </p>
<p>Asian steelmakers are paying a record low for hard coking
coal contracts on a quarterly basis while utilities in Japan
have agreed to the lowest annual supply deal in five years as a
glut crimps prices. About 13 percent of thermal exports are
uneconomic under the Japanese deal of $81.80 a ton, said Morgan
Stanley, which cut its 2014 spot forecast 9 percent to $77 a ton
and its 2015 estimate by 5 percent to $85 a ton. </p>
<p>A growing share of the seaborne supply community is
operating at negative margins to cash cost, a consequence of
committed development prior to the sustained price slump,
Crane wrote, referring to thermal coal. Recovery likely
requires a supply response. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley cut its 2014 coking coal estimate by 12
percent to $131 a ton and its 2015 projection by 4 percent to
$165 a ton. Spot prices fell 11 percent to $113 a ton in March,
data from Energy Publishing Inc. shows. </p>
<h2>Coal Contracts </h2>
<p>Metallurgical-coal suppliers traditionally held annual
talks with steelmakers to fix benchmark contracts for the 12
months from April 1, the start of the Japanese financial year.
They changed to quarterly accords in 2010. Prices were settled
at $98 a ton in 2007. </p>
<p>Thermal coal at Australia''s Newcastle port, an Asian
benchmark price, was at $73.52 a ton in the week ended April 4,
according to globalCOAL, a London-based data provider. Prices
slid 4 percent in March for a third monthly decline. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley increased its estimate of a glut in the
thermal market this year to 37 million tons, from a January
projection of 4.9 million. </p>
<p>The bank also trimmed its 2014 price forecast for uranium
by 4 percent to $38.84 a pound and its 2015 estimate by 5
percent to $45.50 a pound. The restart of reactors in Japan will
remove uncertainty surrounding a supply overhang in the nation,
Crane said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andras Gergely and Krystof Chamonikolas" date="Apr 08, 2014  3:48 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-08/goldman-sees-orban-risk-as-hungary-bonds-lag-east-europe-credit.html"><headline>Goldman Sees Orban Risk as Hungary Bonds Lag: East Europe Credit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. said
Hungarian Prime Minister Viktor Orban''s re-election means
unpredictable policies that risk weighing on growth, as the
nation''s bonds suffer East Europe''s worst returns after Russia. </p>
<p>Government bonds lost 1.6 percent this year in dollar
terms, while the Bloomberg Emerging Market Local Sovereign Index
gained 1.6 percent. The forint weakened as much as 0.6 percent
from a two-month high and bonds dropped yesterday after Orban''s
Fidesz party won 67 percent of the seats in parliament in an
April 6 vote, according to preliminary results. </p>
<p>While Orban cut the biggest debt burden among former
communist European Union members, he roiled investor sentiment
in his last term by appropriating $13 billion of pension assets,
saddling banks with mortgage losses and driving out foreign-owned utilities. His unpredictable style of policymaking
will last as his past policies weigh on Hungary''s growth
prospects, Magdalena Polan, a London-based economist at
Goldman Sachs, said by e-mail April 6. </p>
<p>Fidesz won''t really have an incentive to change its
economic policy after this victory, Zsolt Kondrat, head of
research at MKB Bank Zrt., a unit of Bayerische Landesbank, said
by phone from Budapest yesterday. And unless it does, there
won''t be much of a sustained gain in the forint or a drop in
yields. </p>
<h2>Unambiguous'' Mandate </h2>
<p>MKB expects Hungary''s 10-year forint bond yield to rise to
6.2 percent by the end of the year from a close of 5.66 percent
yesterday and an average of 5.85 percent in the past 12 months. </p>
<p>Fidesz secured an unambiguous mandate to continue the
policy course it started four years ago, Orban said in Budapest
yesterday. The Economy Ministry declined to respond to e-mailed
questions regarding the government''s future policy. </p>
<p>Hungarian stocks underperformed peers in emerging markets
during Orban''s first term as his government changed the
constitution, levied extraordinary taxes on industries from
banks to telecommunications providers, and rejected concern over
the erosion of democracy as lobbying for foreign interests. The
BUX index tumbled 29 percent in the past four years compared
with a 3.2 percent retreat in the MSCI Emerging Markets Index. </p>
<h2>Riskless Returns </h2>
<p>While gains of 39 percent on forint-denominated debt were
the best among the three major eastern European countries since
Orban took office in May 2010, those returns shrunk to a region-worst 6.6 percent when adjusted for price fluctuations,
according to the Bloomberg riskless return ranking. Polish debt
handed investors 9.4 percent and Czech securities 7.2 percent in
a risk-adjusted ranking of indexes from the European Federation
of Financial Analysts Societies in the period through the end of
last week. </p>
<p>Orban''s cabinet will continue to hold an unprecedented
degree of control over the direction of economic policies,
Goldman''s Polan wrote. The government will press on with its
plans to extend the state''s control over the economy. </p>
<p>The premier has used the proceeds from the pension takeover
and industry taxes to keep the budget deficit below the EU
ceiling of 3 percent of gross domestic product since 2011. GDP
grew 1.1 percent last year after contracting in 2012. Industrial
production increased 8.1 percent in February from a year
earlier, the biggest jump in three years, statistics office data
showed today. </p>
<p>Hungary''s Eurobonds are attractive as the economy picks up
and the yields exceed peers such as Romania, Gyula Toth, who
oversees $550 million of assets as a money manager at Ithuba
Gapital AG in Vienna, said by e-mail yesterday. </p>
<h2>Extra Yield </h2>
<p>The premium investors demand to hold Hungary''s dollar bonds
over Treasuries widened two basis points to 266 today, compared
with 198 for Romania, according to indexes from JPMorgan Chase 
Co. The forint strengthened 0.3 percent to 305.7 per euro by
9:31 a.m. in Budapest while yields on the government''s 10-year
local-currency debt fell five basis points, or 0.05 percentage
point, to 5.61 percent. </p>
<p>Hungary''s public debt burden fell to about 78 percent of
GDP last year from 82 percent in 2010, data from the European
Commission show. The country''s current-account surplus also
reached a record 2.9 billion euros in 2013, the central bank
said March 31. </p>
<p>While Orban''s policies helped reduce Hungary''s budget gap,
domestic yields fell too low after 20 consecutive months of cuts
in the benchmark interest rate to a record 2.6 percent,
according to Lutz Roehmeyer, a money manager at Berlin-based LBB
Invest overseeing $1.1 billion of developing-nation debt. </p>
<h2>Too Low'' </h2>
<p>Interest rates in Hungary are too low and politically
influenced by the new setup of the central bank, he said by e-mail yesterday. It doesn''t pay to go into Hungarian risk,
said Roehmeyer, who has an underweight position on the country. </p>
<p>Gyorgy Matolcsy, the central bank''s president, was the
architect of much of Orban''s self-styled unorthodox policies
as the economy minister until March 2013. </p>
<p>The election gave an opposition alliance headed by the
Socialist Party 19 percent of the parliament seats, while the
Jobbik party, which wants a referendum on EU membership, secured
12 percent. Jobbik''s showing may embolden Fidesz to pursue
similar or even more drastic policies than it did in its last
term, Nora Szentivanyi, a London-based economist at JPMorgan,
said in an e-mailed report yesterday. </p>
<p>Potential for renewed confrontation with the EU and
increasingly nationalistic rhetoric are risks worth watching,
Szentivanyi wrote. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Carroll" date="Apr 09, 2014  5:08 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-09/chevron-output-fall-as-it-seeks-to-reverse-declines.html"><headline>Chevron Output Fall as It Seeks to Reverse Declines</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX), seeking to reverse
the longest string of production declined in a decade, said oil
and natural gas output fell in the first two months of the year. </p>
<p>The second-largest U.S. energy producer by market value
pumped the equivalent of 2.579 million barrels of oil a day
during January and February, according to a statement on its
website today. That compares with 2.645 million in the first
quarter of 2013. </p>
<p>When Chevron reports results for the entire three-month
period on May 2, output is expected to come in at 2.61 million
barrels, based on the average of three analysts'' estimates
compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Chevron is accelerating oil exploration from Argentina to
China to add reserves and revive output. Chairman and Chief
Executive Officer John Watson is spending almost $40 billion
this year to find, extract, transport and process oil and gas.
Watson''s strategy also calls for auctioning off $10 billion in
oilfields and other assets to hone the San Ramon, California-based company''s focus on the highest-profit projects. </p>
<p>Chevron has fallen 4.7 percent this year to $119.10, after
advancing 16 percent in 2013. In March, Watson cut the company''s
long-term production target by 6.1 percent to the equivalent of
3.1 million barrels a day in 2017. </p>
<p>The company''s output fell for a third consecutive year in
2013, the longest streak of declines since the 2001-2004 period,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. is the biggest U.S. energy company. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Zachary Tracer" date="Apr 09, 2014  5:05 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-09/jpmorgan-s-dimon-says-cyber-intruders-could-breach-bank-defenses.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Dimon Says Cyber Intruders Could Breach Bank Defenses</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) is facing
increasingly complex and more dangerous cyberattacks and
some of the intruders may get through, Chief Executive Officer
Jamie Dimon said. </p>
<p>It is going to be a continual and likely never-ending
battle to stay ahead of it -- and, unfortunately, not every
battle will be won, Dimon wrote today in his annual letter to
shareholders of the New York-based bank. The company will boost
spending on cybersecurity to $250 million this year from $200
million in 2012, with future efforts expanding
exponentially, he wrote. </p>
<p>Global corporations have increased their focus on how to
repel hackers since breaches were revealed by retailers
including Target Corp. (TGT) JPMorgan, the biggest U.S. bank by
assets, is building three cybersecurity operations centers in
regional headquarters to coordinate information and respond to
threats, Dimon wrote. </p>
<p>Regulators have pressed lenders to strengthen measures
against cyber intrusions, and Richard Davis, the CEO at U.S.
Bancorp, said in November that when a cyberattack does succeed
against a bank, the impact probably will be big. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Victoria Slind-Flor" date="Apr 09, 2014  6:26 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-09/microsoft-lacoste-malibu-media-intellectual-property.html"><headline>Microsoft, Lacoste, Malibu Media: Intellectual Property</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>China''s Ministry of Commerce
approved Microsoft Corp. (MSFT)''s bid to take over Nokia Oyj''s phone
business after winning pledges from both that the transaction
won''t mean higher fees for the nation''s smartphone makers. </p>
<p>Microsoft pledged not to raise fees for its patents after
the deal is complete, according to a statement posted on the
ministry''s website. Nokia pledged no large changes in its
current compensation structure for standard-essential patents. </p>
<h2>Amazon.com Didn''t Infringe Rovi TV Guide Patents, Court Rules </h2>
<p>Rovi Corp., a provider of data and technology for on-screen
television listings, lost a patent-infringement case against
Amazon.com Inc. (AMZN) over interactive programming. </p>
<p>Amazon.com''s Instant Video and IMDB Video didn''t infringe
two patents owned by Rovi''s TV Guide for electronic program
guides, the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit in
Washington said in an opinion posted on its website. </p>
<p>Rovi, which licenses data for television guides, has
agreements with companies such as Sony Corp. and Google Inc. (GOOG) The
Santa Clara, California-based company has had mixed results when
companies balk at paying royalties on its technology. In
November, it lost a lawsuit over Netflix Inc''s software-development kits after a U.S. trade agency said other Rovi
patents weren''t infringed. </p>
<p>Rovi pledged to pursue other claims against the online
retailer. </p>
<p>The case is United Video Properties Inc. v. Amazon.com
Inc., 2013-1396, U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit
(Washington). The lower court case is 11-cv-00003, U.S. District
Court, District of Delaware (Wilmington). </p>
<p>For more patent news, click here. </p>
<h2>Trademark </h2>
<h2>Lacoste''s L.12.12 Trademark Registered for Use in Singapore </h2>
<p>Lacoste SA, the French polo-shirt manufacturer, was given
authorization to register L.12.12 as a trademark in
Singapore over the objections of Carolina Herrera Ltd., the
Straits Times reported. </p>
<p>New York-based Herrera tried to block the registration,
saying the mark was too similar to its 212 marks used with
fragrances, according to the newspaper. </p>
<p>Although Lacoste uses L.12.12 with a fragrance,
Singapore authorities said there was no visual, aural or
conceptual similarity between the marks, the Times said. </p>
<h2>DHX Objects to Event With Same Name as Children''s TV Program </h2>
<p>After receiving a cease-and-desist notice from counsel for
Canada''s DHX Media Ltd. (DHX), a U.K. promoter dropped The Night
Garden as the name for an event set in a London cafe, the
Hackney Gazette reported. </p>
<p>DHX produces In the Night Garden, a children''s
television program airing on the U.K.''s child-oriented CBBC
network, and didn''t want the name to be associated with an event
where alcohol would be sold, according to the newspaper. </p>
<p>Alistair Siddons, the event promoter, told the Gazette he
hadn''t intended any association with the TV program and felt
bullied into changing the name of the event to Star Garden. </p>
<p>For more trademark news, click here. </p>
<h2>Copyright </h2>
<h2>Malibu Media Says No Defendant Passed Polygraph Examination </h2>
<p>Malibu Media LLC, a producer of adult films, said in an
April 16 court filing that in the first three months of 2014, at
least 175,000 U.S. residents infringed its copyrights through
the use of the BitTorrent file-sharing protocol. </p>
<p>In that same filing, the company said it has been using
polygraph examinations and has agreed to dismiss infringement
cases against any defendants who pass such a test. So far,
Malibu Media said, no defendant has passed a test and all
polygraph examinations have led to a settlement. </p>
<p>The filing was made in one of 268 cases Malibu has filed in
federal court in Chicago. Malibu claims that each defendant
infringed, on average, 17.9 copyrighted works. </p>
<p>The case is Malibu Media LLC v. Doe, 14-cv-00693, U.S.
District Court, Northern District of Illinois (Chicago). </p>
<p>For more copyright news, click here. </p>
<h2>Trade Secrets/Industrial Espionage </h2>
<h2>FBI Warns About Russian Venture-Capital Companies </h2>
<p>The Federal Bureau of Investigation told Boston-area
technology companies to be wary of joint ventures with Russian
venture-capital firms. </p>
<p>In an opinion piece published in the Boston Business
Journal, Lucia Ziobro, assistant special agent in charge of the
FBI''s Boston division, said the agency believes the true motive
of some venture-capital firms funded by the Russian government
is industrial espionage. </p>
<p>The warning was also directed toward research facilities
and Boston-area universities, the FBI said. </p>
<p>Officials from two Russian venture-capital firms -- Russian
Venture Co. and Rusnano OAO''s Rusnano USA -- said they were
doing nothing wrong and the FBI''s allegations were unfounded,
the Boston Globe reported. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Pablo Gonzalez" date="Apr 10, 2014 12:04 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-10/chevron-to-invest-1-6-billion-with-ypf-in-argentina-shale-wells.html"><headline>Chevron to Invest $1.6 Billion With YPF in Argentina Shale Wells</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX), the world''s third-largest oil company, signed an accord with Argentina''s YPF SA to
invest $1.6 billion this year in shale development and become
the country''s largest foreign producer of shale oil and natural
gas. </p>
<p>Chevron and state-run YPF plan to drill 170 wells in a
96,000-acre area this year in Argentina''s Vaca Muerta formation,
the world''s second-largest shale gas deposit and fourth-largest
shale oil reservoir, both companies said today in separate
statements. </p>
<p>Argentine President Cristina Fernandez de Kirchner''s
government expropriated a 51 percent stake in YPF from Spain''s
Repsol SA (REP) in April 2012 after saying the Spanish oil company
hadn''t invested enough in exploration. Repsol''s board agreed in
February to accept $5 billion in compensation for Argentina''s
expropriation of the unit. Ending the two-year international
dispute may help attract investors to the country. </p>
<p>This is a significant step in our subsidiaries'' joint
efforts with YPF to develop one of the most exciting shale plays
in the world today, Chevron Vice Chairman George Kirkland said
in the company''s statement. Vaca Muerta could become an
important contributor to Chevron''s long-term production
growth. </p>
<h2>Pilot Investment </h2>
<p>The latest investment follows an initial $1.24 billion
pilot investment financed by Chevron and paves the way for a
total plan of $15 billion. The joint venture partners are
targeting daily output of 50,000 barrels of shale oil and 3
million cubic meters of shale gas by drilling 1,500 wells. </p>
<p>Vaca Muerta, Spanish for dead cow, may hold 23 billion
barrels of oil equivalent, according to a report by independent
auditor Ryder Scott released in February 2012 by YPF. </p>
<p>YPF''s American depositary receipts were little changed at
$30.65 at 11:52 a.m. in New York Chevron fell 1.2 percent to
$117.64. </p>
<p>Chevron late yesterday said it is on track to post its
lowest first quarter production in eight years after bad weather
disrupted operations in Central Asia and North America. </p>
<p>Chevron is the third most valuable oil producer after Exxon
Mobil Corp., and Royal Dutch Shell Plc. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Jones" date="Apr 10, 2014  4:25 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-10/goldman-s-rothesay-life-signs-gbp111m-bulk-annuity-deal.html"><headline>Goldman''s Rothesay Life Signs GBP111m Bulk Annuity Deal</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Rothesay enters into second deal
with Western United Group Pension Scheme, securing another
tranche of pensioner liabilities for Vestey Group employees,
according to statement.
* Deal involved cash and U.K. gilts for the policy
* Rothesay says it has written GBP1.7b of new business in last
12 months
* CEO Addy Loudiadis says co. continues to see interest in
companies reducing risk in pension liabilities, 2014 on track to
be a record year </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David Yong" date="Apr 10, 2014 12:53 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-10/goldman-says-china-junk-debt-not-paying-enough-for-default-risk.html"><headline>Goldman Says China Junk Debt Not Paying Enough for Default Risk</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Investors in high-yield bonds from
China, the majority of which come from the real estate industry,
aren''t being paid enough for assuming the risk of economic
slowdown and defaults, Goldman Sachs Group Inc. said. </p>
<p>For China high yield, we do not think there is sufficient
premium to compensate for these risks, especially given the
potentially high correlation risks in the real estate sector,
analysts at the New York investment bank including Hong Kong-based Kenneth Ho wrote in a report today. There is better
value in investment grade. </p>
<p>Dollar bonds from issuers in China returned 2.24 percent
since Dec. 31, tied with South Korea for third-worst performer
in 15 Asian markets tracked by JPMorgan Chase  Co. The
country''s policy makers have set a 7.5 percent growth target for
this year, which would be the slowest expansion since 1990. </p>
<p>Exports and imports unexpectedly fell in March,
underscoring the depth of China''s slowdown. Overseas shipments
declined 6.6 percent from a year earlier, the customs
administration said in Beijing today, attributing the drop
partly to distortions from inflated data in early 2013. Imports
fell 11.3 percent, leaving a trade surplus of $7.71 billion. </p>
<p>Concern about non-payment in the real estate industry is
mounting after Zhejiang Xingrun Real Estate Co., a builder in a
city south of Shanghai, collapsed with 3.5 billion yuan ($564
million) in liabilities last month. The nation''s credit default
swaps rose to 87 basis points on April 9 from as low as 64 in
November, after Shanghai Chaori Solar Energy Science 
Technology Co. on March 7 became the first company to default on
corporate bonds in its home market. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Carroll" date="Apr 11, 2014 11:12 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-11/exxon-defuses-green-critics-with-risk-disclosure-promises.html"><headline>Exxon Defuses Green Critics With Risk-Disclosure Promises</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM), a lightning rod
for environmental activists since the Valdez oil spill a
quarter-century ago, is appeasing some of its harshest critics
by agreeing to disclose internal risk and cost assessments. </p>
<p>Shareholders of the world''s second-largest corporation by
market value will vote on just one environmental resolution on
May 28, according to a proxy filing today. That''s after Irving,
Texas-based Exxon convinced activist investors to withdraw two
proposals dealing with greenhouse gas restrictions and hydraulic
fracturing. </p>
<p>Environmentalists and corporate-governance activists from
groups including the Sisters of St. Dominic and Arjuna Capital
have made Exxon''s annual meeting a focal point for objecting to
everything from drilling shale to producing motor fuels linked
to climate change. </p>
<p>This year, the company sought to head off criticism by
striking deals with some of its opponents after months-long
negotiations. On March 20, Exxon agreed to provide details on
oilfields and other assets whose value may be threatened by
carbon limits; two weeks later, the producer promised to
disclose risks associated with hydraulic fracturing, or
fracking. </p>
<p>In exchange, resolutions on both issues were withdrawn by
their proponents. Exxon satisfied the first agreement on March
31 by issuing a report that said its oil and natural gas
reserves won''t lose value because demand for energy will trump
efforts to curtail climate change. </p>
<h2>Binary Outlook </h2>
<p>The fracking report will be released later this year, Alan Jeffers, an Exxon spokesman, said in an April 3 interview. </p>
<p>The disclosure agreements haven''t been enough to silence
all of Exxon''s critics. Mark Lewis, an analyst at investment
bank Kepler Cheuvreux SA in Paris, said the company still hasn''t
faced up to the risk that high-cost, carbon-intensive reserves
such as the tar sands in western Canada could deter some
investors who find it socially unacceptable. </p>
<p>Exxon''s view of climate risk appears naively binary,
Lewis said in a blog post the day after Exxon issued its
reserves-threat report. The reality is much more nuanced. </p>
<p>The environmental resolutions brought before investors at
last year''s annual meeting failed to garner enough votes to
succeed. </p>
<p>A proposal calling on Exxon to disclose risks associated
with shale drilling was supported by 30 percent of shareholders,
unchanged from 2012. A separate item on greenhouse gases
gathered 27 percent of the vote, also little changed from a year
earlier. </p>
<p>In 1989, the Exxon Valdez spilled 11 million gallons of oil
into Alaska''s Prince William Sound, devastating wildlife and
local businesses. Victims of the spill sued Exxon and won a $5
billion punitive damage award in 1994 that was cut to $507.5
million in 2008 by a divided U.S. Supreme Court. </p>
<p>Apple Inc. is the biggest corporation by market value. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hugh Son" date="Apr 11, 2014 10:39 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-11/jpmorgan-drops-after-profit-misses-analysts-estimates.html"><headline>JPMorgan Drops After Profit Misses Analysts'' Estimates</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) tumbled as much as 5 percent, the most in 17 months, after reporting first-quarter profit that fell short of analysts'' estimates on lower revenue from fixed-income trading and mortgages. </p> <p>JPMorgan, the biggest U.S. bank, declined 3.2 percent to $55.59 at 10:32 a.m., after dropping to $54.55 earlier today. Excluding one-time items, profit at the New York-based company was $1.35 a share, David Konrad of Macquarie Group Ltd. said today in a note, falling short of the $1.46 average estimate of 10 analysts surveyed by Bloomberg. </p> <p>Earnings slumped in every major division at JPMorgan, the first of the top U.S. banks to post results for the period, amid a 42 percent drop in mortgage revenue and a 21 percent slide in fixed-income trading. The results fell short of analysts'' estimates by the most since Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon, 58, took over at the start of 2006, data compiled by Bloomberg show. </p> <p>Related:</p>

Opinion: JPMorgan Is Keeping Busy

JPMorgan''s Masters Said to Have Angled to Be CEO in Sale
<p>This was not the usual upside surprise for JPMorgan, said Jeff Morris, head of U.S. equities at Standard Life Investments, which manages $305 billion in assets. Mortgage was under pressure and, despite the company warning about trading revenues in February, the 17 percent year-over-year drop in markets revenues feels softer than many were expecting, Morris said in an e-mail. </p>




Photographer: Pete Marovich/Bloomberg

<p>
The results for JPMorgan Chase  Co. fell short of analysts'' estimates by the most since Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon took over at the start of 2006, data compiled by Bloomberg show. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hugh Son" date="Apr 11, 2014  7:59 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-11/jpmorgan-profit-falls-19-on-trading-mortgage-declines.html"><headline>JPMorgan Profit Falls 19% on Trading, Mortgage Declines</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co., the biggest U.S. bank, said first-quarter profit fell 19 percent on lower revenue from fixed-income trading and mortgages, themes that may be repeated across Wall Street next week. The shares declined 2.9 percent. </p> <p>Net income dropped to $5.27 billion, or $1.28 a share, from $6.53 billion, or $1.59, a year earlier, according to a statement today from New York-based JPMorgan. Ten analysts surveyed by Bloomberg estimated $1.46 a share on average. </p> <p>JPMorgan, the first of the top U.S. banks to post results for the period, said profit fell in every major division, amid a 42 percent drop in mortgage revenue and a 21 percent slide in fixed-income trading. Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon, 58, warned investors in February that trading had fallen 15 percent for the first two months of 2014, a decline analysts including David Konrad of Macquarie Group Ltd. blamed on a reduction in the Federal Reserve''s bond purchases. </p> <p>Related:</p>

Opinion: JPMorgan Is Keeping Busy

Masters Said to Have Angled to Be CEO in Sale
<p>It''s been a tough quarter for the industry, said Pri de Silva, senior banking analyst at CreditSights Inc. in New York. I''m not overly worried about JPMorgan unless I see something else going on apart from what we already know is lower fixed-income trading and mortgage results. </p>




Photographer: Ron Antonelli/Bloomberg

<p>
People stand inside the JPMorgan Chase  Co. headquarters building in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Katia Porzecanski" date="Apr 14, 2014 11:51 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-14/jpmorgan-names-luis-oganes-as-head-of-emerging-markets-research.html"><headline>JPMorgan Names Luis Oganes as Head of Emerging Markets Research</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) named Luis Oganes as global head of emerging markets research amid a
leadership overhaul in the global banking division. </p>
<p>Oganes was promoted from head of Latin America research to
replace Joyce Chang, who was named global head of research
earlier this month, according to Veronica Navarro Espinosa, a
spokeswoman for the bank. Jahangir Aziz, the head of emerging
markets Asia research, and Michael Marrese, the head of emerging
Europe, Middle East, and Africa research, will report to Oganes. </p>
<p>JPMorgan''s corporate and investment-banking chief Daniel
Pinto announced 15 staff changes in a memo April 7, including
the promotion of Carlos Hernandez and Jeff Urwin to co-heads of
global banking. Chang succeeded Tom Schmidt, who had asked for a
new role earlier this year, the memo said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Finbarr Flynn and Emi Urabe" date="Apr 14, 2014 11:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-14/goldman-profits-as-abe-spurs-convertible-debt-boom-japan-credit.html"><headline>Goldman Profits as Abe Spurs Convertible Debt Boom: Japan Credit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) helped
regional Japanese banks sell the most dollar-denominated
convertible debt since at least 1999, as the lenders took
advantage of a stock-market rally to fund overseas expansion. </p>
<p>The world''s largest underwriter of the notes helped to
arrange three of the firms'' five U.S. currency sales in the last
12 months. It co-managed deals by Yamagata Bank Ltd., Bank of
Iwate Ltd. and Shizuoka Bank Ltd., whose convertible offering
last April was the first by a Japanese company since 2002,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. Goldman had only
underwritten seven Japanese convertible-note sales in the decade
prior to 2013. </p>
<p>Convertible bonds have established themselves as one
funding tool, so all regional lenders have no choice but to
consider them to some extent, Hiroyuki Sugiura, a vice
president at Goldman''s investment banking division at the
company''s Japanese unit in Tokyo said in an April 11 interview.
They offer the regional lenders cheaper funding, he said. </p>
<p>Abe''s stimulus program to overcome 15 years of deflation
has spurred a stock market recovery that has allowed banks to
get favorable terms on their convertibles, with the three
lenders all selling zero-coupon notes. The regional institutions
will use the funds to lend to clients expanding overseas as a
shrinking domestic population curtails growth prospects at home. </p>
<h2>Quickest Proposal </h2>
<p>Goldman Sachs underwrote $330 million of the $1.3 billion
of dollar convertible bonds sold by regional banks over the past
12 months, a figure exceeded only by Nomura Holdings Inc. Morgan
Stanley, the next biggest overseas manager, managed $120
million, Bloomberg-compiled data show. Nomura, Japan''s largest
brokerage, arranged $585 million in debt, including an issuance
by Yamaguchi Financial Group Inc. </p>
<p>Goldman was the quickest in bringing us a proposal,
Katsunori Nakanishi, the president of Shizuoka Bank, said
yesterday in an interview. After looking at the success of our
deal, it became easier for other regional banks to follow. </p>
<p>Sales of convertible notes, which combine a fixed-income
security with an option to buy stock, have surged since Abe''s
stimulus program sparked a 51.5 percent gain in the Topix
benchmark index last year. While the index is down 13 percent
since the start of this year, it''s still higher than at any
point from 2009 to 2012. </p>
<p>Demand for Japanese convertibles has been 10 to 15 times
more than the amount of notes on offer since the beginning of
2014, Takashi Masuda, head of equity linked products at Goldman
in Tokyo, said in the same interview. Outstanding issuances have
fallen to about 1.5 trillion yen ($14.8 billion) from about 10
trillion yen in 2000, he said. </p>
<h2>Bond Returns </h2>
<p>Japanese exchangeable-note returns fell 3.9 percent this
year, following a 35 percent gain in 2013 which was their best
performance since 1999, data from UBS AG show. While the bonds
have insulated investors somewhat from stock-market declines,
they''re underperforming the 2.4 percent gain in convertible debt
globally. </p>
<p>All Japanese companies including Joyo Bank Ltd. sold $900
million in dollar convertibles so far this year, compared with
$1 billion for all of 2013. </p>
<p>There are more than 100 companies in Yamagata with
overseas operations and we will use the money to help meet their
funding needs, said Nobuhiro Konno, the manager of the general
planning and coordination division at Yamagata Bank, based in
northern Japan. Since the sale of dollar convertibles by
Shizuoka, Iwate and Yamaguchi Financial, a lot of brokerages
came to explain the product, and that was the catalyst for our
sale. The bank sold $100 million of five-year convertible
debentures this month. </p>
<h2>Yen Convertibles </h2>
<p>Other regional banks including Nagano Bank Ltd. and Daisan
Bank Ltd. have issued yen-denominated convertibles this year,
with financial institutions accounting for the biggest amount of
sales by sector after industrials. </p>
<p>Shizuoka Bank''s dollar notes due 2018 can be exchanged for
shares at $13.46, or 18 percent above the closing stock price on
April 9 in dollar terms. The stock was at the equivalent of
$9.38 yesterday. Shares in Yamagata Bank closed at $4.01 April
14, compared with a conversion price of $5.09 on its 2019 debt. </p>
<p>It''s cheap dollars, and all the larger regional banks are
trying to increase their U.S. dollar lending as their clients
increasingly venture overseas, Graeme Knowd, an associate
managing director who overseas financial institutions at Moody''s
Investors Service in Tokyo said in a phone interview. Given
they lend to Japanese corporates, they probably need to fund as
cheaply as possible. </p>
<h2>Abe Stimulus </h2>
<p>Abe came to power in December 2012 calling for fiscal
spending, deregulation and Bank of Japan monetary easing to
raise the inflation rate to 2 percent. BOJ stimulus has helped
weaken the yen more than 14 percent against the dollar since the
end of 2012, bolstering the overseas earnings of Japanese
companies. </p>
<p>The yen traded at 101.61 per dollar as of 5:22 p.m. in
Tokyo yesterday, while the benchmark 10-year bond yield was at
0.605 percent, the world''s lowest. </p>
<p>Non-yen-denominated lending by Shizuoka Bank rose 91
percent to the equivalent of 414.4 billion yen at the end of
last year, compared with a 5.5 percent increase in total loans
to 6.98 trillion yen. The bank said yesterday it will seek to
boost lending at overseas branches to $3 billion by March 2019
from an estimated $1.72 billion for the fiscal year just ended
as part of a medium-term plan. </p>
<h2>Biggest Underwriter </h2>
<p>Goldman Sachs has been the biggest manager of global
convertible bonds for the last three years, underwriting about
$14 billion in 2013 including notes sold by Yahoo Inc., Tesla
Motors Inc. and Air France-KLM, Bloomberg-compiled data show. </p>
<p>The New York-based bank hasn''t underwritten any yen-denominated convertible bonds since it helped manage Sony
Corp.''s 150 billion yen issue in November 2012. Prior to that
Goldman helped manage one convertible bond deal each in 2009,
2008 and 2007, by Japanese issuers, the data show. </p>
<p>Convertible sales this year may exceed last year, said
Goldman''s Masuda, adding the bank is looking to underwrite both
yen and dollar-denominated deals. </p>
<p>If issuance continues to climb, we''re confident of taking
market share, Masuda said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Phoebe Sedgman" date="Apr 14, 2014  8:36 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-14/goldman-predicts-commodity-declines-amid-rally-in-bullion-crops.html"><headline>Commodities Seen by Goldman Down After Transient Events''</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. expects
commodity prices to decline this year even after precious metals
and crop prices rallied on Ukraine tension and weather concerns. </p>
<p>The SP GSCI Enhanced Commodity Index may drop 4 percent in
the next 12 months from a 4.3 percent decrease predicted in
February, analysts led by Jeffrey Currie wrote in a report dated
yesterday. Precious metals will decline 15 percent, compared
with a 14 percent retreat forecast in February, it said.
Agriculture prices will drop 10 percent, from February''s
estimate of a 9 percent loss, it said. </p>
<p>Gold rose 10 percent in 2014, rebounding from the biggest
drop since 1981, as unrest in Ukraine and concerns the global
recovery may be uneven boosted demand for a haven. Tensions in
Ukraine also contributed to corn''s 20 percent jump this year on
speculation supply may be disrupted and dry weather in the U.S.
pushed wheat 12 percent higher. The six-month rolling
correlation of commodities and equities returns has averaged 23
percent this year, the lowest since 2008, Goldman says. </p>
<p>Since the beginning of the year, transient events
including cold weather, Chinese credit concerns and tensions in
Crimea have driven commodity prices, Goldman said. Although
these drivers are transient in nature, they are idiosyncratic,
which has helped to drive down the correlations not only with
other asset classes but also within the commodity space itself,
reinforcing the diversifying component of the strategic
investment case for commodities. </p>
<h2>Gold Forecast </h2>
<p>Bullion''s recent rally was spurred by poor U.S. data
probably linked to the weather and rising tension in Ukraine,
Goldman said, maintaining a year-end forecast of $1,050 an
ounce. With the tapering of the Federal Reserve''s bond-buying
program, U.S. economic releases will return as the driving force
behind lower prices, it said. </p>
<p>Corn will drop to $4 a bushel in 12 months on expectations
U.S. plantings will be higher than the U.S. Department of
Agriculture forecasts, increasing stockpiles, Goldman said.
Wheat will decline to $5.75 a bushel on production prospects in
Europe and the Black Sea, and normalization of U.S. rains, it
said. Soybeans may drop to $10.50 a bushel on record South
American output, slowing Chinese imports and as U.S. acreage
reaches an all-time high, it said. </p>
<p>Nickel may climb to as much as $20,000 a metric ton should
Indonesia''s ore export ban remain in place after its July
presidential election, according to Goldman. Prices in London
surged 28 percent this year as Indonesia, the largest miner of
nickel, curbed ore exports to spur local processing. Copper will
drop to $6,200 a ton over the next 12 months, it said. </p>
<p>Energy prices are set to decline 2.5 percent in the next 12
months, from a 3.5 percent drop forecast in February, Goldman
said today. Livestock will retreat 2 percent, from a February
forecast of unchanged prices, it said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Glenys Sim" date="Apr 14, 2014  7:48 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-14/goldman-stands-by-1-050-gold-target-at-year-end-on-u-s-growth.html"><headline>Goldman Stands by $1,050 Gold Target on Outlook for Recovery</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Gold will resume a decline as U.S.
economic growth accelerates, according to Goldman Sachs Group
Inc., which reiterated a forecast for the metal to end the year
at $1,050 an ounce. </p>
<p>Bullion''s rally this year was spurred by poor U.S. data
probably linked to the weather and rising tension in Ukraine,
analysts led by Jeffrey Currie wrote in a report, describing the
reasons as transient. With the tapering of the Federal Reserve''s
bond-buying program, U.S. economic releases will return as the
driving force behind lower prices, he wrote. </p>
<p>Gold''s 12-year bull run ended in 2013 as the Fed prepared
to reduce monthly bond-buying that fueled gains in asset prices
while failing to stoke inflation. Prices rose 10 percent this
year even as the Fed cut purchases, with Russia''s annexation of
Crimea and mixed U.S. economic data boosting haven demand. Last
year, Currie described gold as a slam-dunk sell for 2014. </p>
<p>It would require a significant sustained slowdown in U.S.
growth for us to revisit our expectation for lower gold prices
over the next two years, Currie wrote in the report, dated
yesterday. While further escalation in tensions could support
gold prices, we expect a sequential acceleration in both U.S.
and Chinese activity, and hence for gold prices to decline. </p>
<p>Gold for immediate delivery traded 0.3 percent higher at
$1,322.01 an ounce at 7:43 p.m. in Singapore, according to
Bloomberg generic pricing, after the United Nations Security
Council met to address the Ukraine crisis. Bullion last traded
below $1,050 an ounce in February 2010. </p>
<h2>Morgan Stanley </h2>
<p>Bullion is the least preferred commodity among metals as
prices resume a decline this year on the outlook for rising U.S.
interest rates and low inflation expectations, Morgan Stanley
said in a report on April 8. Average prices are expected to drop
for the next four quarters, it said. </p>
<p>Stronger U.S. growth this year and next will help the world
economy withstand weaker recoveries in emerging markets,
according to the International Monetary Fund. The world''s
largest economy will expand 2.8 percent this year and 3 percent
in 2015, unchanged from forecasts in January, the IMF said in
its World Economic Outlook report last week. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Manuel Baigorri" date="Apr 14, 2014  2:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-14/jpmorgan-names-zethraeus-head-of-sweden-investment-bank.html"><headline>JPMorgan Names Zethraeus Head of Sweden Investment Bank</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) named Bo Zethraeus as head of investment banking for Sweden as dealmaking
picks up in the Nordic region, replacing Johan Lustig, who left
to join Bank of America Corp. (BAC) </p>
<p>Zethraeus, who was the New York-based bank''s head of equity
capital markets for the Nordic countries, has more than 25 years
of experience as an investment banker in Sweden and  built
relationships with companies, private-equity firms and the
government, according to a memo obtained by Bloomberg News. </p>
<p>A spokeswoman confirmed the contents of the memo and said
Zethraeus will report to Jake Donavan, senior country officer
for the Benelux and Nordic nations. The memo was written by
Donavan as well as Klaus Hessberger and Achintya Mangla, co-heads of the equity capital markets team in Europe, the Middle
East and Africa. </p>
<p>Zethraeus joined JPMorgan from Skandinaviska Enskilda
Banken AB (SEBA) in 2001. JPMorgan plans to announce his replacement as
head of Nordic equity capital markets soon, the memo said. </p>
<p>JPMorgan advised Nets Holding A/S on its sale to Advent
International Corp., Bain Capital LLC and Danish pension fund
ATP last month, as well as Jyske Bank A/S on its acquisition of
BRFkredit A/S for about $1.36 billion in February. </p>
<p>Bank of America hired Lustig to be head of global corporate
and investment banking in the Nordic region, according to a memo
to the bank''s staff on April 7. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrea Tan and Kit Chellel" date="Apr 14, 2014  1:12 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-14/goldman-client-trade-lawsuits-over-singapore-stock-rout.html"><headline>Goldman, Client Trade Lawsuits Over Singapore Stock Rout</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) and Lynne Ng Su Ling, an independent director at LionGold Corp., traded
lawsuits in London over payment demands after shares owned by Ng
and held by the bank as debt collateral plunged in an October
stock rout. </p>
<p>Two Goldman Sachs units are seeking $17.5 million from Ng,
money the bank says she owes after it sold her shares, according
to a countersuit by the bank filed March 24 and made available
over the weekend. In a complaint served on Goldman Sachs in
February, Ng says the bank failed to use reasonable efforts to
get the best price available when it sold her stock. </p>
<p>Ng''s portfolio with Goldman Sachs totaled S$113 million
($90 million) including shares in Asiasons Capital Ltd. (ACAP), Blumont
Group Ltd. (BLUM) and LionGold, as of Sept. 30, according to court
papers. She is the third client Goldman has sued over unpaid
debts related to a stock crash over three days in October that
wiped $6.9 billion off the market value of LionGold, Blumont
Group Ltd. and Asiasons Capital Ltd. </p>
<p>The sudden declines prompted the city''s central bank and
white-collar crime agency to probe suspected stock-trading
irregularities around the tumble. Banks and brokers are seeking
to recover at least $230 million from the stock rout. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
Lynne Ng Su Ling, an independent director at LionGold Corp., is the third client Goldman Sachs  Co. has sued over unpaid debts related to a stock crash over three days in October that wiped $6.9 billion off the market value of LionGold, Blumont Group Ltd. and Asiasons Capital Ltd. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Duane D. Stanford" date="Apr 15, 2014  4:23 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-15/coca-cola-profit-meets-estimates-as-global-volume-increases.html"><headline>Coca-Cola First-Quarter Results Soothe Soda Slowdown Fear</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Coca-Cola Co. (KO) Chief Executive
Officer Muhtar Kent can exhale now. </p>
<p>The world''s largest soda maker today showed signs of a
rebound in the first three months of the year, easing the
concerns that arose when the company unsettled investors with
surprisingly sluggish global sales in the fourth quarter.
Earnings met estimates, sales volume in North America halted its
slide, and sales gains were strong in markets such as China. </p>
<p>After the fourth-quarter report, Kent promised improvement
and implemented a cost-cutting program that''s already showing
some progress. Global sales volume rose 2 percent, and an
emphasis on new package sizes helped boost pricing by 2 percent. </p>
<p>Add it all together and profit excluding some items was 44
cents a share in the three months ended March 28, Atlanta-based
Coca-Cola said today in a statement. That matched the average of
18 analysts'' estimates compiled by Bloomberg. Net income fell
7.5 percent $1.62 billion, or 36 cents a share, from $1.75
billion, or 39 cents, a year earlier. </p>
<p>We don''t think this is a great result, but satisfying as
one step in the right direction to restore momentum, Kent said
during a conference call. </p>
<p>Volume in North America was little changed in the first
quarter, compared with a 1 percent decline in the fourth
quarter. Sales on that basis strengthened in emerging markets,
including a 12 percent gain in China. </p>




Photographer: Kiyoshi Ota/Bloomberg

<p>
Coca-Cola Co. Chief Executive Officer Muhtar Kent, facing sluggish soft drink sales in the U.S., has implemented a cost-cutting program to boost earnings and is collaborating with Keurig Green Mountain Inc. to compete in at-home soda making. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Olga Kharif and Peter Burrows" date="Apr 15, 2014  2:23 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-15/microsoft-ceo-nadella-unveils-data-analysis-tools.html"><headline>Microsoft CEO Nadella Unveils Data-Analysis Tools</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) Chief Executive Officer Satya Nadella touted new products at an event in San Francisco for the third time in as many weeks, part of an effort to re-establish the software maker as an innovator. </p> <p>Nadella, who took the top job in February, unveiled new tools and software for sifting through large amounts of data to identify trends and patterns at a meeting with developers today at the Bentley Reserve Building. </p> <p>The company has been rolling out products for corporate clients that are seeking to manage Web-linked devices and crunch the information they generate. Nadella, who took the top job in February after leading the cloud and enterprise group, is working to remake Microsoft for an era where mobile gadgets have become central, corporations run software from remote servers and household electronics get more connected. </p> <p>The most imporant thing is to create a data culture, Nadella said at the event. </p> <p>Analytics tools are in demand as a greater number of hardware devices, from personal-fitness monitors to thermostats to industrial equipment, connect to the Web, generating a sea of data. By 2020, the amount of information created may reach 5,247 gigabytes per person, according to Microsoft. That''s twice as many bytes of data than liters of water in the world''s oceans, the Redmond, Washington-based company said last month. </p> <p>It''s yet another boost to the volume of data, said Dan Vesset, an analyst at researcher IDC, referring to the surge in smart devices. That''s another reason why they should be, and are, investing more in this space. </p> <h2>Sorting Data </h2> <p>Microsoft''s Analytics Platform System is the latest of Microsoft''s efforts to beef up its products for storing and sorting through all the information produced by connected devices, known as Big Data. On April 1, Microsoft released its SQL Server 2014 database software. </p> <p>I think Microsoft has an advantage in here, Andrew Snodgrass, an analyst at researcher Directions on Microsoft, said in an interview. If you take a look at the databases out there, they are already Microsoft anyway. What they are saying is, they want companies to do more with their data, while they still are using its databases. </p> <p>A number of technology companies -- Microsoft, Oracle Corp. (ORCL), and International Business Machines Corp. among them -- are competing in the Big Data market, which reached $13 billion last year and will grow at a compounded annual rate of 27 percent through 2017, according to IDC. That includes software, hardware and services. </p> <p>Now we are into real investment, Vesset said. There''s more and more evidence that having this technology can make a difference from the competitive perspective, or increase productivity. There''s demand out there. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alaa Shahine" date="Apr 15, 2014  6:03 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-15/jpmorgan-targeting-gulf-leaps-to-no-2-for-bonds-arab-credit.html"><headline>JPMorgan Targeting Gulf Leaps to No. 2 for Bonds: Arab Credit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. is gaining
ground in the debt markets of Gulf Cooperation Council states
after the biggest U.S. bank helped manage this month''s Islamic
bond sale by Saudi Arabia''s utility. </p>
<p>JPMorgan is the biggest bond underwriter after HSBC
Holdings Plc (HSBA) in the six-nation GCC in 2014, its best start to a
year since 2007, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. The
New York-based lender advised on six deals, including Saudi
Electricity (SECO) Co.''s $2.5 billion sukuk sale on April 1. </p>
<p>Its jump from sixth place in the rankings at the end of
2013 partly reflects the rise of Islamic finance, which will
become a $2.7 trillion market by 2017, according to
PricewaterhouseCoopers. Sukuk made up more than 70 percent of
total bond issuance this year in the GCC, which supplies one-fifth of world oil, data compiled by Bloomberg show. </p>
<p>Islamic finance now has the biggest slice of the bond
market, Samer Mardini, a vice president of fixed income at SJS
Markets Ltd. in Dubai, said in a phone interview yesterday.
Issuers are more comfortable with big names like JPMorgan.
They can act as market-makers and bookrunners to ensure a
successful issuance. </p>
<p>JPMorgan hired former UBS AG banker Hussein Hassan last
year to head global Shariah-compliant financing. It has also
intensified its focus on corporate clients'' needs in the Gulf
region over the past few years, Hani Deaibes, head of Middle
East and North Africa debt capital markets at the bank, said in
an e-mailed response to questions yesterday. </p>
<h2>Rate Clarity </h2>
<p>This effort, combined with more market certainty, has
better positioned us to assist them in raising funding across
the international and domestic markets. </p>
<p>International bond-market conditions have become
conducive since the start of the year as the U.S. Federal
Reserve provided more clarity on interest rates, encouraging
companies to raise long-term funding, he said. </p>
<p>Saudi Electricity raised $1 billion in 30-year sukuk and
$1.5 billion in 10-year securities. HSBC and Deutsche Bank AG
also worked on the transaction. Deutsche Bank is the region''s
third-biggest underwriter this year, data compiled by Bloomberg
show. </p>
<p>The GCC has become a battleground for international banks
as other parts of the Middle East and North Africa struggle to
recover from political turmoil following a series of popular
uprisings that first erupted in 2011. </p>
<p>Economic growth in the oil-rich Gulf region is set to
accelerate to 4.4 percent this year, compared with 2.8 percent
for non-oil producers, according to HSBC forecasts released in
January. </p>
<h2>Sales Drop </h2>
<p>JPMorgan''s performance has come even as bond sales dropped
almost 50 percent this year to $8 billion as some regular
issuers, such as cash-flushed banks, refrain from tapping the
market and offer cheaper loans to companies, data compiled by
Bloomberg show. </p>
<p>New York-based JPMorgan said Hassan, previously global head
of Islamic structuring for UBS, is focusing on clients in
countries including Saudi Arabia and Malaysia, according to an
e-mailed statement at the time of his appointment in January
2013. Malaysia hosts the world''s biggest market for Islamic
bonds, or sukuk, while Saudi Arabia boasts the world''s biggest
share of Shariah-compliant assets. </p>
<p>More Saudi borrowers may still issue debt after Fitch
Ratings upgraded the kingdom one level in March to AA, the
third-highest investment grade, according to John Sfakianakis,
chief investment strategist at MASIC in Riyadh. </p>
<p>The recent sovereign upgrade should also help issuers who
are looking for more competitive pricing, he said in an e-mailed response to questions yesterday. Economic growth in Saudi
Arabia may accelerate to 4.2 percent in 2014, from 3.8 percent a
year earlier, according to economists'' estimates provided to
Bloomberg. </p>
<p>JPMorgan has helped arrange bond sales for Saudi Arabia''s
National Commercial Bank, Abu Dhabi Commercial Bank PJSC, Qatar
National Bank QD, as well as Kuwait Projects Co., data compiled
by Bloomberg show. </p>
<p>At the end of the day, it''s all about being competitive
in pricing against the rest, Sfakianakis said. That''s the
only way it can be done in a market that is price sensitive. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bob Van Voris and Alex Barinka" date="Apr 16, 2014  1:55 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-16/ibm-sued-by-mexico-s-iusacell-for-2-5-billion-over-deal-1-.html"><headline>IBM Sued by Mexico''s Iusacell for $2.5 Billion Over Deal</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM) was sued by Iusacell SA, Mexico''s third-biggest mobile-phone provider, for $2.5 billion in lost profits tied to a 2010
deal that failed. IBM claims the lawsuit is intended to avoid
arbitration over the contract. </p>
<p>Iusacell consulted with IBM in connection with a multiyear
plan to increase market share and revenue, the company said in a
heavily redacted complaint filed today in Manhattan federal
court. Iusacell alleged IBM made fraudulent misrepresentations
that caused it to suffer damages and lose profits. </p>
<p>IBM both knowingly misrepresented and wrongfully
concealed from Iusacell material facts both before and during
the parties'' relationship, Iusacell said in the complaint. The
public version of the filing doesn''t explain the alleged
wrongdoing. </p>
<p>IBM said today that Iusacell and IBM Mexico entered into a
long term contract under which IBM Mexico made significant
investments in Iusacell''s business operations that resulted in
major improvement to Iusacell''s information technology
infrastructure and growth in Iusacell''s revenues. </p>
<p>The matter is in arbitration, said Doug Shelton, a
spokesman for Armonk, New York-based IBM. </p>
<p>Iusacell, co-owned by billionaire Ricardo Salinas and by
Grupo Televisa SAB (TLEVICPO), the country''s largest broadcaster, has
struggled to compete with larger rivals such as America Movil
SAB (AMXL) and Telefonica SA. (TEF) The company had 8 million subscribers at
the end of 2013, or about 8 percent of the market. </p>
<p>Televisa recorded a fourth-quarter loss from joint ventures
of 4.74 billion pesos ($363 million), mostly to write down the
value of Iusacell. It acquired its 50 percent stake in the
company from Salinas for $1.6 billion in 2012 and invested an
additional 1.59 billion pesos last year. </p>
<p>Salinas is Mexico''s fourth-richest person and No. 129 on
the Bloomberg Billionaires Index, with a net worth of $9.1
billion. He has sued to block Mexico''s stock exchange from
removing his retail company from the benchmark index and the
government''s plans to auction off wireless airwaves. </p>
<p>Dan McCosh, a spokesman for Salinas''s group of companies,
declined to immediately comment. </p>
<p>The case is Iusacell SA de CV v. International Business
Machines Corp., 14-cv-02697, U.S. District Court, Southern
District of New York (Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Nicole Gaouette" date="Apr 16, 2014 10:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-16/jpmorgan-aids-u-s-agency-with-market-based-foreign-aid.html"><headline>JPMorgan Aids U.S. Agency With Market-Based Foreign Aid</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Foreign aid has long been one of
the most unpalatable dishes on the federal plate. Why should
U.S. taxpayers give billions of dollars to ungrateful countries
that will waste it and whose people don''t like America anyway? </p>
<p>Quietly, though, the U.S. Agency for International
Development has been undergoing a market-oriented sea change
that has attracted fans such as Amy Bell, an executive director
of JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), and hundreds of Wall Street veterans. </p>
<p>They''re really showcasing the power of business to do
well and do well in a prudent way, said Bell, the head of
principal investments for JPMorgan''s Social Finance unit in New
York, in a telephone interview. I think they''ve done a
remarkable job. </p>
<p>The U.S. government''s global anti-poverty agency backs a
private equity fund that Bell''s JPMorgan unit runs for African
agriculture businesses. It helped General Electric Co. (GE) secure
$10 million in local financing for small maternal-health clinics
in Kenya. It''s supported loans by Root Capital, a social-investment fund, to help coffee farmers in Latin America supply
Starbucks Inc. (SBUX) </p>
<p>It''s a sea change for an agency that for years simply gave
out money. The program, called the Development Credit Authority,
was begun in 1999 under President George W. Bush with authority
from Congress to provide loan guarantees, but in the 10 years
before 2011 it backed only $2.2 billion in credit. Since 2011,
the authority has issued $1 billion in guarantees. </p>
<h2>Shrinking Funding </h2>
<p>That''s still a fraction of the aid agency''s effort. AID has
seen its funding shrink from $22.5 billion in fiscal year 2010
to $20.4 billion in fiscal 2014, not adjusted for inflation. The
Obama administration has asked Congress for $20.1 billion in
fiscal 2015. </p>
<p>Our developmental objectives -- ending extreme poverty in
15 years, ending preventable child death, ending large-scale,
widespread child hunger -- will only be achieved if we can
effectively harness and deploy massive amounts of private
investment against those goals, said Rajiv Shah, the agency''s
administrator. </p>
<p>When Shah and Ben Hubbard, former director of the credit
authority, arrived in January 2010, they saw an underutilized
asset. </p>
<p>We don''t look at these problems and say, How do we get
the appropriations budget to solve this?'' Hubbard said in an
interview. It''s, How do I attract the private sector to get
this done, because it''s inherently more sustainable?'' Rather
than building and paying for solar power plants, we can attract
private capital to pay for them. </p>
<h2>Former Bankers </h2>
<p>The agency''s credit authority, with a few dozen private
sector, deal-oriented former bankers and financial analysts,
has brought tools from Wall Street to hone a model that Shah
said he hopes will transform not only development work, but also
the thinking in his agency. </p>
<p>Since 2011, the credit unit has leveraged private capital
to help companies expand while assisting some of the world''s
most vulnerable people. </p>
<p>The credit authority guaranteed an $8 million loan by New
York-based JPMorgan to the African Agricultural Capital Fund,
which helped attract equity investors and boost the Uganda-based
fund to $25 million. The arrangement allowed the bank to
experiment with a new market, lending to the small- and medium-sized businesses that are the engine of economic growth. </p>
<h2>Republican Applause </h2>
<p>The private-sector approach has drawn applause from critics
of foreign aid such as Republican Representative Ileana Ros-Lehtinen of Florida, who''s praised the credit agency''s proven
track record of significantly leveraging private financing in
support of development aid, even as she''s called for cuts to
other parts of the foreign aid budget. </p>
<p>The development credit agency works in a number of ways.
Most often, it encourages banks in developing countries to loan
to smaller businesses, usually in underserved sectors such as
farming that align with U.S. development goals, by sharing the
risk if there''s a default. </p>
<p>There''s a lot of wealth in these banks, but they''re risk-averse, said Hubbard. We don''t take out all the risk, so
they have skin in the game, but we lower it. </p>
<p>When Nereus Capital LLC was struggling for funds, the
credit authority partnered with U.S.-based institutional
investors to help raise a $100 million investment in the Mumbai-based company''s fund for clean-energy projects. </p>
<h2>Deploying Wealth </h2>
<p>Learning how to deploy that wealth to tackle development
challenges, environmental challenges in India, is how we will
solve extreme poverty and its consequences of child hunger and
child death there, said Shah, 41, who earned a medical degree
from the University of Pennsylvania and previously was chief
scientist for the U.S. Agriculture Department and worked for the
Bill  Melinda Gates Foundation. </p>
<p>The credit authority''s default rate has been 1.89 percent,
with the aid agency paying out $11.6 million in claims since
1999 and collecting $14.1 million in bank fees. It also provide
credit enhancement to companies such as Cambridge,
Massachusetts-based Root Capital, which identified a gap in
financing for farmers'' cooperatives that were too large for
microcredit loans and too small for bank loans. </p>
<p>The cooperatives use the funding to help small farmers
improve their yields, reduce post-harvest losses -- enhancing
food security -- and earn more by selling collectively to
companies such as Seattle-based Starbucks, the world''s largest
operator of coffee shops. </p>
<h2>Loan Guarantees </h2>
<p>This year, the president has asked Congress to raise the
annual cap on the credit authority''s loan guarantee program to
$2 billion from $1.5 billion. It''s an idea whose time had come,
Hubbard said. </p>
<p>Still, change is sometimes difficult, Shah acknowledges.
The aid agency, created in 1961 by an executive order from
President John F. Kennedy, has 9,421 people worldwide who are
steeped in a culture of giving money away, not raising it. Now,
Hubbard said, overseas missions are being held accountable to
targets for attracting private capital to fund their programs. </p>
<p>There''s a huge amount of enthusiasm and excitement, and
also resistance in any system to doing things in new and
innovative ways, Shah said. </p>
<p>One solution has been to recruit Wall Street veterans to
the government aid agency, with almost 1,000 joining since the
end of the Bush administration, Hubbard said. </p>
<p>Reasons for signing up vary, said Hubbard, who has left the
agency to start a firm funding businesses in Africa. Some lost
their jobs because of the financial crisis and found purpose in
our mission, he said. Others could command a bigger salary
elsewhere, they just didn''t have a lot of purpose and meaning in
those positions. As a group, he adds, they''re very counter-cultural inside the agency. </p>
<h2>Cairo Reality Show </h2>
<p>These field investment officers work across the
agency''s silos, Hubbard said, bringing a financial viewpoint
to help health or agricultural specialists figure out how to
bring private capital into their programs. </p>
<p>Chris Lee, a former energy trader from Newtown,
Connecticut, now works as a field investment officer in Cairo,
where he''s developed a loan program for small- and medium-sized
businesses, helps run a local reality TV show about
entrepreneurs, and is looking at ways to support business people
in the informal economy. </p>
<p>It''s amazing how simple ideas can be effective, he
said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri" date="Apr 17, 2014  6:14 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-17/disney-officials-say-online-offerings-boost-espn-audience.html"><headline>Disney Officials Say Online Offerings Boost ESPN Audience</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS) executives said
consumers who listen to ESPN radio and interact with the sports
channel''s websites spend triple the amount of time with the
company as those who just watch the TV network. </p>
<p>Fans who take part in ESPN.com''s fantasy football or use
the Watch ESPN app are with the company 17 hours a month on
average, versus five hours for people who only watch TV. The
data demonstrate that online and mobile offerings boost
engagement with ESPN, as well as the potential for ad sales,
executives told analysts today at ESPN''s offices. </p>
<p>It''s exploded the misconception that digital media would
cannibalize television, Arthur Bulgrin, ESPN''s senior vice
president of global research and analytics, said at the investor
event in Bristol, Connecticut. The overall time spent with
ESPN media more than triples and at the same time TV viewing
goes up. It''s a rising tide that floats all boats. </p>
<p>Disney, the world''s largest entertainment company, is using
the event to showcase ESPN, one of the company''s most profitable
businesses, Chairman and Chief Executive Officer Robert Iger
said. </p>
<p>A new studio ESPN plans to begin using next month for its
flagship SportsCenter news show is a great example of us
investing in the value of a franchise, investing not only to
continue to protect it but to continue to grow its value, Iger
said. </p>
<p>ESPN''s online offerings attract larger audiences than Yahoo
Sports, Bleacher Report and NFL.com, Bulgrin said. Mobile use by
customers also exceeds the time spent on desktop computers, he
said. Watch ESPN''s typical user is 29 years old, compared with
age 47 for the traditional TV viewer. The median income of
$74,000 is 54 percent more. </p>
<h2>Changing Habits </h2>
<p>TV networks, which accounted for more than half of Disney''s
profit, face challenges from new video options, the migration of
ad sales to online media and escalating costs for sports rights,
ESPN President John Skipper said. </p>
<p>A deal Disney signed last month that lets Dish Network
Corp. (DISH) create a Web-based service with its programming will
attract customers who don''t have pay TV now, rather than ones
who trade down from an existing service, Skipper said. He
expects more such deals. </p>
<p>Pay television is going to remain a large business,
though it will exist in a more complicated and dynamic
atmosphere, which will require some evolution of our current
business model, he said. </p>
<p>Disney, based in Burbank, California, rose 1.3 percent to
$79.99 at the close in New York. The stock has gained 4.7
percent this year. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Apr 17, 2014 12:58 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-17/morgan-stanley-says-deal-with-russia-s-rosneft-on-track.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Says Deal With Russia''s Rosneft on Track</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) still expects to
complete the sale of a physical oil business to OAO Rosneft (ROSN) amid
U.S. sanctions of Russian leaders, Chief Financial Officer Ruth Porat said. </p>
<p>We''re still looking at closing in the second half of this
year, and that''s of course subject to all necessary regulatory
approvals, Porat said in a telephone interview today. Of
communications with regulators, she said, We haven''t heard
anything at this point. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley agreed last year to sell a unit that stores,
trades and transports oil products to a subsidiary of Russia''s
OAO Rosneft. The firm has also said it''s exploring strategic
options for its stake in TransMontaigne Inc., the Denver-based
petroleum and chemical transportation and storage company. </p>
<p>Regulators and lawmakers have questioned banks'' involvement
in the physical commodities businesses, saying the operations
could pose catastrophic risks to the firms and potentially lead
to their collapse and public bailouts. </p>
<p>The White House has discussed including Rosneft Chief
Executive Officer Igor Sechin on an updated list of sanctioned
Russian individuals, the New York Times reported this week,
citing people familiar with the matter. Sechin, an ally of
Russian President Vladimir Putin, said last month that he didn''t
expect the existing U.S. sanctions to affect the deal. </p>
<p>Porat, 56, has said that the unit Morgan Stanley is selling
to Rosneft broke even last year on a pretax basis. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s first-quarter fixed-income and commodities
revenue climbed 9 percent to $1.65 billion, driven by strength
in commodities trading. Excluding the oil business its selling
and the TransMontaigne unit, the fixed-income division''s revenue
rose slightly versus a year earlier, Porat said on a
conference call today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri" date="Apr 17, 2014 11:21 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-17/disney-offers-obama-minimum-wage-to-florida-park-workers.html"><headline>Disney Offers Obama Minimum Wage to Florida Park Workers</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS) has offered to
raise starting pay at its Florida theme parks by 25 percent to
$10 an hour over two years, almost matching the federal minimum
wage sought by President Barack Obama. </p>
<p>Disney presented the proposal yesterday to the Service
Trades Council, a consortium of six labor groups, the company
and union representatives said. They are scheduled to resume
bargaining over a contract on May 28. </p>
<p>The unions, which represent more than 30,000 employees at
Walt Disney World near Orlando, asked for at least $10.10 an
hour, the amount congressional Democrats and Obama propose as a
new U.S. minimum. Starting pay at the Florida parks is now $8.03
an hour, according to Burbank, California-based Disney. That
would reach the rate Disney is offering by July 2016. </p>
<p>I''m very pleased, Ed Chambers, president of the
council, said in a telephone interview. We''re well on our way
to getting a deal done. </p>
<p>The contract being negotiated covers full-time hourly
employees at the world''s most-popular theme-park complex. Disney
reported record profit of $6.6 billion on revenue of $45 billion
last year from its TV networks, parks, studios and consumer
products. </p>
<p>It is more generous than they have been in the past,
said Donna-Lynne Dalton, secretary-treasurer of the council.
It comes at a cost. </p>
<p>Disney also told the unions it wants to stop offering
pensions to new hourly employees starting in 2016. </p>
<p>New hires would be offered a 3 percent company match to a
401(k)-style retirement plan, said Dalton. The company doesn''t
currently contribute to that plan, which is available to
employees from bell staff to costumed entertainers, she said. </p>
<h2>Union Opposition </h2>
<p>Chambers said the union would oppose the pension change. </p>
<p>This offer reflects our appreciation and care for our
cast members and our commitment to providing a leading
employment package, Kim Prunty, a Disney World spokeswoman,
said in an e-mailed statement. We look forward to working with
the union and engaging in constructive negotiations to finalize
and reach a collective bargaining agreement. </p>
<p>Disney''s last contract with the council took effect in
October 2010, according to the Orlando Sentinel. The pact
included annual raises of 3 percent to 4 percent for workers who
hadn''t already reached the top of their pay scales, as well as
$650 one-time bonuses for non-tipped, full-time employees. </p>
<p>Disney''s parks and resorts business, the company''s second-largest division after television, generated operating income of
$2.22 billion last year on sales of $14.1 billion. </p>
<p>Robert Iger, Disney''s chairman and chief executive officer,
said at the annual meeting in March the company has good
relations with its unions and doesn''t expect that to change. </p>
<p>It is our intention to behave very responsibly and fairly
with all of our cast members and compensate them in ways that
reflect the value that they create for the company and for our
customers, Iger said. </p>
<p>Disney rose 0.7 percent to $79.53 at 11:18 a.m. in New
York. The stock had gained 30 percent in the past year through
yesterday. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Apr 17, 2014  9:56 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-17/morgan-stanley-sees-lone-trading-jump-as-goldman-drops.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Sees Lone Trading Jump as Goldman Drops</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) posted a jump in first-quarter trading revenue while Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)''s dropped, the first such divergence in two years. </p> <p>Morgan Stanley today reported a surprise 9 percent increase in fixed-income trading revenue, the only gain among major Wall Street banks, and had the biggest improvement in equity trading as it overtook its larger rival for the top spot in that business. Goldman Sachs suffered the sharpest decline in equity trading, citing a slump in Japan and emerging markets. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs, led by Chief Executive Officer Lloyd C. Blankfein, still beat analysts'' estimates as the firm posted the most investment-banking revenue among U.S. banks for the first time since the financial crisis. Morgan Stanley CEO James Gorman got a rare win as fixed-income revenue was the highest in two years even as the company continued to shrink capital used by the unit. </p> <p>When the Street disappoints in fixed-income, Morgan Stanley does well, and when the Street does well, Morgan Stanley tends to disappoint, Brad Hintz, an analyst at Sanford C. Bernstein  Co., said in a Bloomberg Radio interview. Weak fixed-income quarter: Morgan Stanley did well. </p> <p>Morgan Stanley rose 4.1 percent to $31.11 at 9:51 a.m. in New York, the biggest intraday advance since January. Goldman Sachs climbed 1.4 percent to $159.42. </p> 
<p></p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Apr 17, 2014  8:19 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-17/goldman-beats-estimates-on-jump-in-investment-banking.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Sees Lone Trading Jump as Goldman Drops</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) posted a jump in first-quarter trading revenue while Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)''s dropped, the first such divergence in two years. </p> <p>Morgan Stanley today reported a surprise 9 percent increase in fixed-income trading revenue, the only gain among major Wall Street banks, and had the biggest improvement in equity trading as it overtook its larger rival for the top spot in that business. Goldman Sachs suffered the sharpest decline in equity trading, citing a slump in Japan and emerging markets. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs, led by Chief Executive Officer Lloyd C. Blankfein, still beat analysts'' estimates as the firm posted the most investment-banking revenue among U.S. banks for the first time since the financial crisis. Morgan Stanley CEO James Gorman got a rare win as fixed-income revenue was the highest in two years even as the company continued to shrink capital used by the unit. </p> <p>When the Street disappoints in fixed-income, Morgan Stanley does well, and when the Street does well, Morgan Stanley tends to disappoint, Brad Hintz, an analyst at Sanford C. Bernstein  Co., said in a Bloomberg Radio interview. Weak fixed-income quarter: Morgan Stanley did well. </p> <p>Morgan Stanley rose 4.1 percent to $31.11 at 9:51 a.m. in New York, the biggest intraday advance since January. Goldman Sachs climbed 1.4 percent to $159.42. </p> <p>Gorman''s firm still had the lowest trading revenue among the Wall Street banks at $3.36 billion, and both it and Goldman Sachs trailed JPMorgan Chase  Co. and Citigroup Inc. All of the New York-based firms are facing a prolonged slump in fixed-income trading, which has fallen in nine of the past 13 quarters. </p> <h2>Business Mix </h2> 
<p></p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore and Zeke Faux" date="Apr 17, 2014  8:05 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-17/morgan-stanley-beats-estimates-on-brokerage-increase.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Beats Estimates on Brokerage Increase</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley reported profit that beat analysts'' estimates as a surprise jump in fixed-income results helped the firm post the only increase in trading revenue among the six biggest U.S. banks this year. The stock rose 3 percent in early New York trading. </p> <p>First-quarter net income advanced 56 percent to $1.51 billion, or 74 cents a share, from $962 million, or 48 cents, a year earlier, the New York-based company said today in a statement. Excluding an accounting gain tied to the firm''s own debt, profit from continuing operations was 68 cents a share, topping the 60-cent average estimate of 26 analysts surveyed by Bloomberg. </p> <p>A five-quarter rally in U.S. stocks has helped Chief Executive Officer James Gorman boost revenue from wealth management and gain market share in equities trading. The firm also saw a 9 percent increase in fixed-income trading revenue to a two-year high while its peers posted declines. </p> 
<p></p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kit Chellel" date="Apr 17, 2014  7:16 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-17/goldman-sachs-to-seek-early-dismissal-of-libya-wealth-fund-suit.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs to Seek Early Dismissal of Libya Wealth Fund Suit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) will seek
to have a $1 billion lawsuit by the Libyan Investment Authority
thrown out before trial. </p>
<p>The bank will ask a London judge to decide whether the case
has a realistic chance of success and issue a so-called summary
judgment, according to court documents released this week.
Libya''s sovereign wealth fund says Goldman made about
$350 million selling investments that turned out to be
worthless. </p>
<p>The LIA said in a statement it considers this application
to be misconceived and looks forward to full and proper
determination of all issues by the English court. </p>
<p>Libya''s sovereign wealth fund is one of dozens of small
companies and government agencies that have sued lenders over
deals the investors claim were too complicated to understand. It
also sued Societe Generale SA (GLE) in a $1.5 billion lawsuit, saying
that the French bank paid about $58 million to a friend of the
Qaddafi family to secure investments. </p>
<p>Fiona Laffan, a spokeswoman for New York-based Goldman
Sachs, declined to comment on the case. </p>
<p>The LIA must convince a judge that its claim has some
chance of success to defeat the summary judgment application.
The case has been put on hold until the court decides on whether
it can continue. </p>
<p>The case is The Libyan Investment Authority v. Goldman
Sachs International, case no. 14-310, High Court of Justice,
Chancery Division. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri" date="Apr 17, 2014 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-17/disney-offers-25-raise-over-two-years-to-florida-workers.html"><headline>Disney Offers 25% Raise Over Two Years to Florida Workers</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS) has offered to
raise starting pay at its Florida theme parks by 25 percent to
$10 an hour over two years, almost matching the federal minimum
wage sought by President Barack Obama. </p>
<p>Disney presented the proposal yesterday to the Service
Trades Council, a consortium of six labor groups, the company
and union representatives said. They are scheduled to resume
bargaining over a contract on May 28. </p>
<p>The unions, which represent more than 30,000 employees at
Walt Disney World near Orlando, asked for at least $10.10 an
hour, the amount congressional Democrats and Obama propose as a
new U.S. minimum. Starting pay at the Florida parks is now $8.03
an hour, according to Burbank, California-based Disney. That
would reach the rate Disney is offering by July 2016. </p>
<p>I''m very pleased, Ed Chambers, president of the
council, said in a telephone interview. We''re well on our way
to getting a deal done. </p>
<p>The contract being negotiated covers full-time hourly
employees at the world''s most-popular theme-park complex. Disney
reported record profit of $6.6 billion on revenue of $45 billion
last year from its TV networks, parks, studios and consumer
products. </p>
<p>It is more generous than they have been in the past,
said Donna-Lynne Dalton, secretary-treasurer of the council.
It comes at a cost. </p>
<p>Disney also told the unions it wants to stop offering
pensions to new hourly employees starting in 2016. </p>
<p>New hires would be offered a 3 percent company match to a
401(k)-style retirement plan, said Dalton. The company doesn''t
currently contribute to that plan, which is available to
employees from bell staff to costumed entertainers, she said. </p>
<h2>Union Opposition </h2>
<p>Chambers said the union would oppose the pension change. </p>
<p>This offer reflects our appreciation and care for our
cast members and our commitment to providing a leading
employment package, Kim Prunty, a Disney World spokeswoman,
said in an e-mailed statement. We look forward to working with
the union and engaging in constructive negotiations to finalize
and reach a collective bargaining agreement. </p>
<p>Disney''s last contract with the council took effect in
October 2010, according to the Orlando Sentinel. The pact
included annual raises of 3 percent to 4 percent for workers who
hadn''t already reached the top of their pay scales, as well as
$650 one-time bonuses for non-tipped, full-time employees. </p>
<p>Disney''s parks and resorts business, the company''s second-largest division after television, generated operating income of
$2.22 billion last year on sales of $14.1 billion. </p>
<p>Robert Iger, Disney''s chairman and chief executive officer,
said at the annual meeting in March the company has good
relations with its unions and doesn''t expect that to change. </p>
<p>It is our intention to behave very responsibly and fairly
with all of our cast members and compensate them in ways that
reflect the value that they create for the company and for our
customers, Iger said. </p>
<p>Disney rose 1.7 percent to $78.95 at the close in New York
yesterday. The stock has gained 30 percent in the past year. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hugh Son" date="Apr 17, 2014 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-17/jpmorgan-looks-to-uber-seamless-to-plot-mobile-future.html"><headline>JPMorgan Looks to Uber, Seamless to Plot Mobile Future</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) digital chief
Gavin Michael, who joined the firm a year ago, has a certain
disdain for some competitors'' staid mobile-banking apps. </p>
<p>While functional, the apps aren''t intuitive or personalized
enough. So when it came time for the New York-based company to
update its app, with a new iPhone version available today,
Michael, 49, said he studied software produced by technology
startups. </p>
<p>How do I make this simple, human, cohesive? How do we
change the principles we''re chasing? he said in an April 15
interview. We looked at what a lot of the startups are doing,
whether it''s Seamless and the way I order takeout food, or Uber
and the way I catch a cab, or OpenTable and the way I book
restaurant reservations, or the way Apple iOS is shaped. </p>
<p>Lenders including JPMorgan, the biggest U.S. bank by
assets, are leaning on mobile and online offerings to win
loyalty while lowering the cost of retail services. The firm''s
mobile users rose 24 percent from a year ago to 16.4 million.
Bank of America Corp., the No. 2 U.S. lender, said mobile
customers increased 19 percent to 15 million. </p>
<p>Michael, who reports to consumer-banking chief Gordon Smith, joined JPMorgan from consulting firm Accenture, where he
was head of technology innovation. He has since hired executives
from outside finance, including Tim Parsey, a former senior vice
president of design at Yahoo! Inc. and Josh Klenert, a former
designer for the Huffington Post. Both are based in San
Francisco. </p>
<p>Prior versions of the bank''s mobile app for the iPhone drew
3 1/2 out of five stars on Apple Inc.''s App Store as of late
yesterday. Bank of America''s had a similar rating. Apps from San
Francisco-based Wells Fargo  Co. (WFC) and New York-based Citigroup
Inc. both had three stars. </p>
<h2>New Greetings </h2>
<p>JPMorgan''s redesigned app for the iPhone has a simpler
login and location-based greetings to give users a more
personalized experience, Michael said. The background photo
shown to a customer in New York may feature the Brooklyn Bridge,
for example, while a client in San Francisco sees streetcars. </p>
<p>People work on an emotional level before they go to the
rational level, Michael said. What we''re trying to do with
banking is create that emotional experience inside the way which
images are used, the way we greet and the way we understand how
customers bank with us. </p>
<p>Future versions will probably detect users'' location to
tailor their experience and ease transactions including in-store
purchases and pulling cash from automated teller machines, he
said. </p>
<h2>Cutting Branches </h2>
<p>When I''m near an ATM, how do I get the two to work so I
can preload transactions? Michael said. We want a cohesive
experience across our digital and live interactions. So things
should work together and feel like they belong together. </p>
<p>Mobile technology has helped firms including Charlotte,
North Carolina-based Bank of America reduce bank branches.
Customers effectively carry a branch in their pocket, Chief
Executive Officer Brian T. Moynihan, 54, said yesterday on a
conference call. </p>
<p>Still, branches will remain a key fixture for lenders,
Michael said. They are evolving into places where customers seek
financial advice, while performing routine activities like
depositing checks with mobile phones or ATMs. </p>
<p>It changes the relationship you have with the branch, as
opposed to replacing it, Michael said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Yalman Onaran" date="Apr 21, 2014  7:51 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-21/jpgoldman-stanley-intact-as-basel-change-keeps-bank-ties.html"><headline>JPGoldman Stanley Intact as Basel Change Keeps Bank Ties</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The largest U.S. banks can remain entangled with each other now that global regulators have loosened proposed limits on the financial web that led to investor panic in 2008 and prompted bailouts. </p> <p>The Basel Committee on Banking Supervision, which set out a year ago to block banks from relying too heavily on each other, changed course last week, opting to let firms preserve most derivatives and repurchase agreements among themselves. The panel revised formulas for evaluating exposure and used a broader definition of capital. Those tweaks spare about $1 trillion in deals at seven of the biggest U.S. banks that would have exceeded proposed limits, according to a November study by the Clearing House, an industry group. </p> <p>The Basel panel of regulators from 27 countries has bowed to industry pressure before to weaken new rules. Liquidity standards and leverage ratios also were altered so the largest firms came much closer to being in compliance. </p> <p>Related:</p>
Ex-Barclays Executive Sees Golden Decade'' for Banking
U.K. Tax Authorities Question Banks on VAT Swindlers
<p>That seems to be the name of the game, fighting every rule to the ground, said Anat Admati, a Stanford University finance professor. The fact that the banks were so concerned with counterparty limits and fought them so hard shows how interconnected they are. That makes them too big to fail. </p>




Photographer: Timothy A. Clary/AFP via Getty Images

<p>
The Citibank building in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Drew Armstrong and Aaron Kirchfeld" date="Apr 21, 2014  4:14 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-21/pfizer-said-to-have-held-talks-to-acquire-astrazeneca.html"><headline>Pfizer Said to Have Held Talks to Acquire AstraZeneca</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE), the world''s biggest
drugmaker, held informal, now-discontinued talks with
AstraZeneca Plc about buying the London-based maker of asthma 
and heart drugs, said two people familiar with the matter. </p>
<p>The companies aren''t currently negotiating, said the
people, who asked not to be identified. One said the talks
happened several months ago and there are no plans to resume.
The discussions were first reported yesterday by London''s Sunday
Times, whose unnamed bank and industry sources said New York-based Pfizer made a tentative approach about a takeover valuing
AstraZeneca at more than 60 billion pounds ($101 billion). </p>
<p>If revived, such an acquisition would be among the largest
ever in the industry. Pfizer has reorganized its business over
the past three years, shuttering some research projects and
emphasizing others. A deal with AstraZeneca (AZN) would add early-stage drugs in a field of cancer treatments that use the body''s
own immune cells to recognize and attack cancer. </p>
<p>We don''t comment on market speculation or rumors, said
Andrew Topen, a Pfizer spokesman, in an e-mail. Esra Erkal-Paler, am AstraZeneca spokeswoman, declined to comment. </p>
<p>American depositary receipts for AstraZeneca gained 8.8
percent to $69.10 at 4 p.m. New York time. Pfizer rose 2 percent
to $30.86. The stock has increased about 37 percent in the last
two years as Pfizer benefited from the revamping that focused it
into three units: two for new drugs, and one for older products. </p>
<h2>AstraZeneca Treatments </h2>
<p>AstraZeneca in January announced an agreement with
Immunocore Limited to develop the new cancer treatments that use
the body''s own immune cells, and it also has several of its own
immune-based drugs being tested in multiple cancers. The
company''s shares in London have risen about 34 percent over two
years, even as sales have fallen from $33.6 billion in 2011 to
$25.7 billion last year, with further losses projected by some
analysts as drugs lose patent protection. </p>
<p>While a deal would be highly accretive through cost
cutting, Pfizer shareholders may have doubts about AstraZeneca''s
pipeline as well as its eroding revenue, said Mark Schoenebaum,
an analyst with ISI Group LLC. </p>
<p>The consensus AstraZeneca model is hugely dependent on
pipeline assumptions, as the base business will deteriorate
massively by 2020 as several key products go off patent, he
said in a note to clients. </p>
<h2>Mega-Mergers </h2>
<p>A merger of this reported size would top Pfizer''s 2000
purchase of Warner-Lambert Co. for $87 billion, the industry''s
largest deal, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. Pfizer
has been at the center of the biggest drugmaker mega-mergers,
making up three of the 10 deals worth more than $30 billion in
the last two decades. </p>
<p>It would also provide a use for Pfizer''s cash from profits
that have been stashed overseas instead of being brought back to
the U.S., where they would be taxed at a higher rate. Pfizer had
$69 billion in untaxed cash overseas as of last month, according
to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>A purchase of AstraZeneca could also potentially allow
Pfizer to move its tax domicile to the U.K. through a so-called
inversion transaction, a move that has allowed other U.S.
drugmakers to lower their tax bill. </p>
<p>AstraZeneca shares in London rose 0.6 percent to close at
3,781.50 pence on April 17, giving the company a market value of
47.7 billion pounds. The London stock market was closed for a
holiday April 18 and today. </p>
<h2>Merger Comments </h2>
<p>Since taking over in 2010, Pfizer Chief Executive Officer
Ian Read''s answers to whether or not he would pursue a mega-merger such as a deal with AstraZeneca have shifted. </p>
<p>On a January conference call in 2012 he said, I''m very
disinclined to be looking at any possibility of another mega-acquisition. You never say never, but we have all of the science
we need. </p>
<p>In July 2013, when Read was asked on another conference
call about the size of deals he might pursue, he replied:
We''ll look at any type of acquisition -- never say never to a
larger acquisition that made sense. </p>
<p>Schoenebaum said there were signs Pfizer could pursue a
large target. Pfizer has been signaling since last summer
that, in theory, the company would not be opposed to a larger
MA deal if the numbers made sense, Schoenebaum said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Greg Stohr" date="Apr 21, 2014  9:36 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-21/exxon-rejected-by-court-on-105-million-new-york-award.html"><headline>Exxon Rejected by Court on $105 Million New York Award</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The U.S. Supreme Court rejected
Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM)''s appeal of a $105 million jury verdict it was
ordered to pay for contaminating underground water in New York
City with a gasoline additive. </p>
<p>The Irving, Texas-based oil and gas company argued
unsuccessfully that any award was premature because the city
isn''t planning to use the disputed wells in southeastern Queens
for another 15 to 20 years. </p>
<p>Exxon used the additive, methyl tertiary butyl ether, to
comply with a 1990 federal law that required an increase in the
oxygen content of gasoline in the smoggiest parts of the
country. New York later banned MTBE, as the additive is known,
because of contamination concerns. </p>
<p>New York sued Exxon Mobil and other oil companies in 2003,
alleging that they knew MTBE would pollute groundwater. A New
York-based federal appeals court last year upheld the 2009 jury
verdict against the company. </p>
<p>At the Supreme Court, Exxon Mobil argued that the Clean Air
Act shields oil companies from liability for using the safest,
most feasible means of complying with the oxygen requirement. </p>
<p>The case is one of scores across the country by
municipalities, states and individuals against oil refiners,
distributors and retailers over MTBE. </p>
<p>The case is Exxon Mobil v. City of New York, 13-842. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tara Lachapelle and Drew Armstrong" date="Apr 22, 2014  4:40 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-22/pfizer-astrazeneca-are-ripe-for-pharma-deal-real-m-a.html"><headline>Pfizer, AstraZeneca Are Ripe for Pharma Deal: Real M&amp;amp;A</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Large deals make sense for Pfizer Inc. (PFE) and AstraZeneca Plc (AZN), even if not with each other. </p> <p>While the talks between Pfizer, the world''s biggest drugmaker, and $87 billion AstraZeneca have fizzled, an analyst at Citigroup Inc. expects Pfizer to approach the company again, or AstraZeneca could opt to merge with another peer such as Amgen Inc. (AMGN) as a defense tactic. Pfizer''s backup plan could be to acquire Dublin-based Shire Plc, Albert Fried  Co. said. </p> <p>Both companies face stalling growth over the next few years, with Pfizer needing new products to replace drugs that lost patent protection and AstraZeneca''s promising cancer treatments still years from hitting the market. At the same time, smaller rivals are scooping up assets and building their presence as drug takeovers surged to a five-year high, led by Actavis Plc''s $21 billion bid for Forest Laboratories Inc., according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p> <p>Related:</p>
Novartis to Buy Glaxo Cancer Drugs, Sell Animal Health
Novartis CEO Still Optimistic'' About ThromboGenics Drug
Ackman Amassed Allergan Stake Under Botox Maker''s Radar
<p>Everybody''s scrambling for these assets, Sachin Shah, a special situations and merger arbitrage strategist at Albert Fried in New York, said in a phone interview. When you have these large transactions back to back to back, it just begs the question of what do the big pharma guys think about this? Right now, Pfizer''s probably coming to the conclusion that it needs to have a buy'' mentality. </p>




Photographer: JB Reed/Bloomberg

<p>
AstraZeneca spent the last couple of years trying to restock its own pipeline as patents expire on some of its best-selling medicines, such as Crestor for cholesterol and Nexium for heartburn. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Noah Buhayar and Laura Marcinek" date="Apr 23, 2014  2:28 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-23/coca-cola-wins-compensation-vote-overcoming-winters-opposition.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Wins Compensation Vote, Overcoming Winters''s Fight</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Coca-Cola Co. (KO) won investor approval
for its plan to award employees with stock, overcoming an
argument from money manager David Winters that lavish pay
packages are diminishing returns for shareholders. </p>
<p>Eighty-three percent of votes cast supported the equity
plan, according to preliminary results in an e-mailed statement
today from the company. The annual meeting was held in Atlanta,
the city where Coca-Cola is based. </p>
<p>Winters had waged a campaign since March to persuade
investors to reject the soft-drink maker''s proposal. The new
plan, in addition to ones already enacted, could transfer $29.8
billion to the managers, he said. Investors such as the Ontario
Teachers'' Pension Plan and Calvert Investments had sided with
Winters, who runs the firm Wintergreen Advisers LLC. Coca-Cola
said its board was pleased with the vote. </p>
<p>The company''s compensation programs are performance-based
and the equity plan is fair, competitive and consistent with
shareowners'' interests and our pay for performance philosophy,
according to the statement. </p>
<p>In making his case, Winters appealed directly to Berkshire
Hathaway Inc. Chief Executive Officer Warren Buffett, who
controls the biggest stake in Coca-Cola. Buffett, the world''s
third-richest person, used to be on Coca-Cola''s board, and his
son is a director. </p>
<h2>Extraneous Factors'' </h2>
<p>His fiduciary duty is to all of the Berkshire
shareholders, Winters said in an interview yesterday. Buffett
shouldn''t vote based on any other extraneous factors. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola has said that stock repurchases, including $4.8
billion of buybacks in 2013, cushion the dilution tied to
employee awards. Dilution related to equity plans has been less
than 1 percent annually over the past three years, and is
expected to be in this range going forward, the company said
in a presentation. Coca-Cola also said that the link of the pay
to performance means that all the potential awards may not be
earned. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola said a separate advisory vote on executive
compensation won 90 percent support. Investors also voted
against a measure that called for an independent board chairman. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alex Barinka" date="Apr 23, 2014  1:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-23/ibm-introduces-new-power-server-amid-repositioning-of-unit.html"><headline>IBM Introduces New Power Server Amid Repositioning'' of Unit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines Corp. (IBM), seeking to revitalize hardware sales, introduced a new Power Systems server with an open platform that gives programmers more flexibility to develop uses for the device. </p> <p>IBM spent $2.4 billion in more than three years to create the hardware, which is used in data centers. The system has more than 11 miles (18 kilometers) of copper wiring, which helps the servers process large amounts of data, the company said today in a statement. </p> <p>The new offering comes after a 22 percent decline in first-quarter sales for Power Systems, a unit which Chief Financial Officer Martin Schroeter this month said the company is aggressively repositioning. The new products are designed to address growing areas like cloud computing and data analytics, helping IBM counter weak demand for older hardware that has dragged down total revenue for eight straight quarters. </p> <p>IBM Tries to Adapt. Again.</p><p>We are thinking differently about how to help clients transform their business with the right infrastructure, Tom Rosamilia, IBM''s senior vice president for systems and technology, said in an interview. This is leveraging a lot of the things we''ve done with open systems before but never really around the hardware. </p> <p>IBM, based in Armonk, New York, got advice in building the servers from fellow members of the OpenPower Foundation -- a 25-member group of companies that support open-source technology. Members of the group, which includes Google Inc. and Nvidia Corp., are working with IBM and on their own on other technology based on the same Power8 processor chip that the new Power Systems servers use. </p> <p>The new IBM systems will sell for around $8,000, which is about $2,000 less than past models, Rosamilia said. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bei Hu" date="Apr 23, 2014 12:01 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-23/goldman-sachs-said-to-lose-seven-asia-prime-brokerage-staff.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Said to Lose Seven Asia Prime-Brokerage Workers</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc., the
largest prime broker in Asia, lost seven of its employees on the
regional team this year, said a person with knowledge of the
matter. </p>
<p>The departures include Alain Bordoni, a former managing
director, and Mark Wittet, who was an executive director, said
the person, who asked not to be identified as the information is
private. Most of the jobs vacated have been filled with internal
transfers and new hires, he added. </p>
<p>Connie Ling, a Hong Kong-based spokeswoman for the New
York-based bank, declined to comment. Bordoni''s Goldman Sachs
license was removed Jan. 28, according to information posted on
the website of Hong Kong''s Securities and Futures Commission.
Wittet''s was removed April 5, it showed. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs was ranked by London-based trade journal
AsiaHedge as the region''s largest prime broker, with an
estimated 179 mandates and $24.6 billion of assets as of April
2013. Global hedge-fund capital hit $2.7 trillion in March, the
seventh consecutive quarterly record, according to Chicago-based
Hedge Fund Research Inc. </p>
<p>Given the healthy state of the hedge-fund industry, the
major service providers to hedge funds are likely facing a
harder time competing for specialized talent, both versus rivals
as well as versus hedge funds themselves, said Daniel Celeghin, Asia head at Casey Quirk  Associates LLC, a Darien,
Connecticut-based adviser to asset managers. </p>
<p>Prime brokers provide services such as stock and cash
lending, trade clearing for hedge funds, as well as linking them
with potential investors. </p>
<h2>Joining Funds </h2>
<p>Asia-based hedge funds oversee a combined $79.7 billion of
assets, having recovered by 41 percent from the April 2009
trough, according to Singapore-based data provider Eurekahedge
Pte. </p>
<p>Banks like Goldman Sachs have been trying to balance
regulatory pressure to tie compensation to long-term performance
with shareholders'' desire for flexibility to cut pay costs, if
needed. Chief Executive Officer Lloyd C. Blankfein cut
compensation to 37 percent of revenue last year, the second-lowest portion since the company went public in 1999 </p>
<p>With the exception of Bordoni, the other Goldman Sachs
prime-brokerage departures in Asia were executive directors or
lower-level employees, said the person. Some left to join
rivals, others have been hired by funds, he added. </p>
<p>Bordoni couldn''t immediately be reached, while Wittet
didn''t reply to a message seeking comment sent through social
media. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs counts as its clients some of the largest
regional hedge funds, including ones led by alumni such as
Azentus Capital Management Ltd. founded by Morgan Sze. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs''s 14th annual Asia hedge-fund event in
Singapore in October attracted the likes of Azentus as well as
Asia teams of Fortress Investment Group LLC, Och-Ziff Capital
Management Group LLC and Highbridge Capital Management LLC,
according to a document seen by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jonathan D. Salant" date="Apr 23, 2014  7:25 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-23/general-dynamics-beats-analysts-estimates-on-jet-sales.html"><headline>General Dynamics Beats Analysts'' Estimates on Jet Sales</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>General Dynamics Corp. (GD), the U.S.
government''s No. 3 contractor, reported first-quarter profit
exceeding analysts'' estimates on higher Gulfstream jet sales. </p>
<p>Net income from continuing operations in the quarter rose
4.2 percent to $595 million, or $1.71 a share, compared with
$571 million, or $1.62 a share, a year earlier, the company said
in a statement today. That beat estimates of $1.64, the average
of 20 analysts surveyed by Bloomberg. Sales fell 1.1 percent to
$7.32 billion. </p>
<p>Sales in the company''s aerospace division rose 20 percent
to $2.13 billion as it delivered more of its Gulfstream business
jets. </p>
<p>Defense companies such as Falls Church, Virginia-based
General Dynamics are fighting for a shrinking pool of federal
contracts as the U.S. withdraws combat troops from Afghanistan
and reduces spending under a process known as sequestration. </p>
<p>Some of the across-the-board cuts were averted when
President Barack Obama in January signed a $1.1 trillion
spending bill to fund the government through Sept. 30. </p>
<p>General Dynamics has risen 61 percent in the last 12 months
through yesterday, compared with a 19 percent gain in the
Standard  Poor''s 500 Index during that time. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jonathan Levin" date="Apr 24, 2014  6:15 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-24/general-atlantic-said-in-talks-to-buy-sanfer-stake-ahead-of-ipo.html"><headline>General Atlantic Said in Talks to Buy Sanfer Stake Ahead of IPO</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>General Atlantic LLC is in talks to
buy a minority stake in closely held drug company Laboratorios
Sanfer SA in its first investment in a Mexican firm, people with
knowledge of the matter said. </p>
<p>With the stake, the private-equity firm would provide a
capital infusion as the manufacturer of antibiotics and blood
pressure medications moves toward a possible initial public
offering in the next two years, the people said, asking not to
be identified because the information is private. </p>
<p>While talks are at an advanced stage, they could still fall
apart, one of the people said. Sanfer had about $400 million in
revenue last year, according to the person. </p>
<p>A constitutional overhaul approved last year to open up the
energy industry in Mexico is raising expectations for a pickup
in investment and economic growth in Latin America''s second-biggest economy. Bain  Co. said in a report last year that
higher per-capita output would probably increase demand for
hospitals and medicine, making health care among the most likely
industries to benefit from private-equity funding. </p>
<p>Sanfer''s IPO would be the first by a Mexican pharmaceutical
company since Genomma Lab Internacional SAB (LABB) raised about 2.09
billion pesos ($160 million) in 2008. The shares have almost
quadrupled since the Mexico City-based company''s debut. </p>
<h2>Mexico Office </h2>
<p>An official for General Atlantic declined to comment on the
investment, while Sanfer didn''t respond to phone calls and an e-mail seeking comment. </p>
<p>General Atlantic is in the process of opening an office in
Mexico, one person said. </p>
<p>The Greenwich, Connecticut-based firm, with about $17
billion in assets, already has an office in Sao Paulo, and has
invested about $1 billion in companies in Latin America,
according to its website. Its investments in the region include
Smiles SA (SMLE3), the Brazilian frequent flier program that conducted
an IPO last year. </p>
<p>More Pharma Corp., the Mexican drug marketer backed by
Evercore Partners Inc. and Southern Cross Group, has hired
JPMorgan Chase  Co. to seek a buyer, a person with knowledge of
the matter said last month. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Apr 24, 2014 11:10 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-24/goldman-sees-growth-in-beta-products-after-westpeak-deal.html"><headline>Goldman Sees Growth in Beta Products After Westpeak Deal</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), the Wall
Street bank that once generated millions of dollars in fees from
its Global Alpha hedge fund, is turning to beta strategies for
growth. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs Asset Management, which oversees $30 billion
in such products, agreed this week to buy Westpeak Global
Advisors LLC, without disclosing terms. Westpeak, which
supervises just $300 million of assets, can help spur growth in
the firm''s beta products, which are drawing more interest from
clients, Armen Avanessians, head of GSAM''s quantitative
business, said in an interview. Beta refers to how much an
asset''s price moves in relation to the broader market. </p>
<p>While many indexes are weighted based on market
capitalization, Westpeak develops so-called active beta
strategies by investing in groups of stocks using other
characteristics. The idea is to offer the low fees and liquidity
that have drawn investors to passive exchange-traded funds,
while providing more value than a proxy for the Standard 
Poor''s 500 Index. </p>
<p>Anyone who wants to be in the passive space has already
shifted into that space, and they enjoy a certain degree of
liquidity and transparency, said Avanessians, a partner and
29-year veteran of New York-based Goldman Sachs. The question
is, Can they do something more than just slavishly follow the
market cap?'' </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs, which has avoided large mergers throughout
its history, has made several purchases in the past two years to
grow an asset-management business that saw outflows in three
straight years ended in 2012. Chief Executive Officer Lloyd C. Blankfein, 59, said in May that he''s devoting a very high
percentage of his attention to improving the division''s
performance. </p>
<h2>Assets Increase </h2>
<p>Last year, assets under supervision topped $1 trillion for
the first time and pretax profit climbed 20 percent to $1.11
billion. The division produced $1.57 billion of revenue in the
first quarter, a 20 percent increase from a year earlier. </p>
<p>Avanessians, 54, declined to set a growth target for the
advanced beta strategies business. He said only that it can get
much bigger and will help the bank attract a bigger slice of
clients'' portfolios. </p>
<p>We see it as being purely additive to our business, he
said. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs shut Global Alpha in 2011 as clients pulled
money from what was the firm''s biggest hedge fund. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Noah Buhayar" date="Apr 24, 2014  9:32 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-24/jpmorgan-to-help-oversee-12-billion-for-resolution-life.html"><headline>JPMorgan to Help Oversee $12 Billion for Resolution Life</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) won a contract
to help manage about $12 billion in bonds for Resolution Life
Holdings Inc., a startup insurer that plans to acquire policies
from other U.S. carriers. </p>
<p>The partnership represents a comprehensive investment
management relationship that includes fixed-income portfolio
management, asset-liability management and product hedging,
according to a statement today from Resolution. It will also
cover asset-allocation strategy and investment accounting and
reporting support. </p>
<p>Resolution said last month that it plans to initially
invest $2 billion to build a "lasting, sizable and
differentiated" insurance company in the U.S. comprised of
businesses that are no longer adding new clients. The
announcement followed its agreement to buy Lincoln Benefit Life
from Allstate Corp. (ALL) in July. Insurers including Hartford
Financial Services Group Inc. have been looking to sell U.S.
life operations as low interest rates pinch profit. </p>
<p>Resolution Chairman Clive Cowdery pursued a similar
strategy in the U.K., where he amassed a personal fortune
consolidating the industry. Over the last decade, his Resolution
Group bought 25 insurers, comprising more than 10 million
policyholders and $200 billion in policy assets. </p>
<p>Money managers including New York-based JPMorgan, BlackRock
Inc. and Goldman Sachs Group Inc. have been vying to win
contracts with insurance clients to boost fee income. Insurers
have sought Wall Street investment expertise to diversify their
portfolios and meet regulatory requirements. Outsourcing also
allows the insurers to focus on underwriting. </p>
<p>JPMorgan said March 31 that its Highbridge Principal
Strategies LLC will manage funds for Watford Re Ltd., a Bermuda-based reinsurer. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Glenys Sim" date="Apr 24, 2014  8:31 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-24/goldman-backs-case-for-commodity-holdings-on-returns-inflation.html"><headline>Goldman Backs Case for Commodity Holdings as Rivals Cut</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. said that
the case for holding commodities remains strong, bolstering the
rationale for investments in oil and metals even as other banks
exit the market. </p>
<p>Commodities still offer a way to diversify holdings
together with equities and bonds, and are best suited as a hedge
against inflation, analysts led by Damien Courvalin and Jeffrey Currie wrote in a report dated yesterday. The appeal of holding
commodities will improve as global growth picks up in the next
few years, they wrote, without giving a forecast. </p>
<p>While returns from commodities lagged behind those from
shares and bonds over the past five years, the case for
retaining an allocation in a portfolio over the long term
remains, the Goldman analysts wrote. Barclays Plc, JPMorgan
Chase  Co. and Morgan Stanley are leaving parts of their
commodities businesses, boosting speculation that Goldman will
be able to increase its market share. </p>
<p>Having commodities will be a very useful diversifier for
most portfolios, said Jason Wang, chief executive officer at
Singapore-based Stamford Management Ltd., which had about $300
million under management at the end of 2013 after returns of
more than 20 percent from its Iridium Alpha Fund. Even within
commodities, it''s so heterogeneous that it''s possible to have
diversification within the sector itself. </p>




Photographer: Vincent Mundy/Bloomberg

<p>
While returns from commodities returns lagged behind those from shares and bonds over the past five years, the case for retaining an allocation in a portfolio over the long term remains, the Goldman analysts wrote. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Oliver Suess" date="Apr 24, 2014  8:29 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-24/generali-joins-german-insurers-buying-high-yield-loans.html"><headline>Generali Joins German Insurers Buying High-Yield Loans</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The German unit of Assicurazioni
Generali SpA (G), Italy''s biggest insurer, is planning to begin
investing in high-yielding U.S. loans as it seeks to boost
returns held down by low interest rates. </p>
<p>Generali Deutschland Holding AG (GE1) will allocate as much as
400 million euros ($553 million) to leveraged loans, according
to Fabrizio Vitiello, Generali''s Milan-based head of asset
management and alternative fixed income. The Cologne-based
division also wants to invest as much as 200 million euros in
infrastructure loans and the same amount to small and medium-sized enterprises in Germany. </p>
<p>We are currently in the process of building up a number
of alternative fixed income investments such as senior secured
loans, loans to small and medium-sized corporations as well as
infrastructure and leveraged loans, Vitiello said in a
telephone interview. We invest predominantly via specialized
funds, positioning ourselves on the more senior part of the
capital structure. </p>
<p>Generali is joining German insurers including Gothaer Group
and Versicherungskammer Bayern buying into leveraged loans to
boost yields and diversify assets. The Italian firm''s life
division reported a 3.8 percent return on 282 billion euros of
investments in 2013 from 4.1 percent the year before. </p>
<p>Generali wants to team up with German banks to help it
invest in loans, according to Vitiello. Getting bank partners
is key for an investment in corporate loans, he said. </p>
<p>The insurer has selected BNP Paribas SA to work with its
French unit on a 300 million-euro fund focused on company debt. </p>
<h2>Record Issuance </h2>
<p>The U.S. junk-loan market has seen record issuance this
year with at least $85 billion raised to finance acquisitions,
data compiled by Bloomberg show. With defaults by borrowers
approaching record lows, buyout firms are also taking advantage
of the Federal Reserve''s easy-money policies to extract payouts
by piling more debt onto the companies they own. </p>
<p>Versicherungskammer Bayern, with 42.5 billion euros in
investments, and Gothaer Group, which oversees 25 billion euros,
have been buying into loans for several years. </p>
<p>We currently observe a massively growing interest in
senior secured loans, said Klaus-Michael Menz, the Cologne-based head of credit investments at Gothaer Asset Management AG,
the insurer''s asset management unit. Currently, the market is
almost priced to perfection and we have become very cautious as
it could quickly turn and lose its attractiveness. </p>
<h2>Bank Partner </h2>
<p>Gothaer achieved a return of about 13 percent on its senior
secured loans in the past two years, Menz said. The insurer is
working with IKB Deutsche Industriebank AG, the Dusseldorf-based
lender, to invest as much as 150 million euros in debt to
medium-sized German companies. </p>
<p>Bayerische Versorgungskammer, Germany''s biggest public
pension fund, is also planning to start investing in loans,
Munich-based spokeswoman Kathrin Reus said. It wants to allocate
as much as 600 million euros to syndicated facilities starting
next month, according to Reus. </p>
<p>Leveraged loans are rated below BBB- by Standard  Poor''s
and less than Baa3 at Moody''s Investors Service, the lowest
investment-grade levels. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kathleen Miller" date="Apr 24, 2014 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-24/ibm-enlists-watson-ahead-of-pentagon-health-solictation.html"><headline>IBM Enlists Watson Ahead of Pentagon Health Solictation</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM) will add technology from its Watson supercomputer, known
for beating humans on Jeopardy!, to its federal health unit
before the Pentagon seeks bids on a $11 billion health-records
project. </p>
<p>The world''s biggest computer services provider also is
hiring Keith Salzman, a former chief medical information officer
at the Army hospital in Tacoma, Washington, where the Pentagon
plans to test the new health records project, for its U.S.
federal team. Salzman will become the division''s chief medical
officer, IBM said in a news release today. </p>
<p>IBM, whose U.S. agency contracts have slipped over the past
two years, is making the changes as companies prepare to compete
to deliver a new electronic medical-records system for the
Defense Department. The lifecycle cost of the project may be as
much as $11 billion, Jonathan Woodson, assistant secretary of
defense for health affairs, said in testimony before a U.S.
House appropriations subcommittee this month. </p>
<p>You have to bring a lot to the table in federal health
care, Andrew Maner, IBM''s managing partner for its U.S.
federal division, said in a telephone interview. Watson is not
going to implement an electronic medical-records solution, but
it can be used to make clinicians better or more efficient. </p>
<p>The Armonk, New York-based company, which had $1.2 billion
in U.S. agency contracts during the fiscal year that ended Sept.
30, was the government''s No. 51 supplier, according to a
Bloomberg Government ranking of the top 200 vendors released
April 22. It slipped six spots from the prior year, when it had
about $1.5 billion in U.S. contracts. </p>
<h2>Jeopardy'' Success </h2>
<p>IBM will offer technology from its Watson Group to
aggregate and study clinical information for U.S. health
agencies, according to the press release. Watson, an artificial-intelligence system best known for its success on the
Jeopardy! television quiz show, can analyze large amounts of
data. That may help cut costs, speed medical research and
improve care, the company said in its release. </p>
<p>Maner declined to comment on whether IBM would compete for
the records project or include Watson technology in a potential
bid. It wants to see the government''s solicitation for the work
first, he said. </p>
<p>If IBM does bid, you need to show up with everything,
Maner said. That includes the right commercial and federal
experience, the best bidding partners, as well as innovative
technology, such as Watson, he said. </p>
<p>Information technology services companies such as Hewlett-Packard Co. (HPQ), based in Palo Alto, California; Leidos Holdings
Inc. (LDOS), based in Reston, Virginia; and IBM are likely to bid on
the Pentagon health records work, said Brian Friel, a Bloomberg
Industries analyst. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elizabeth Dexheimer" date="Apr 25, 2014  4:18 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-25/visa-tumbles-as-russia-sanctions-threaten-to-crimp-profit.html"><headline>Visa Tumbles as Russia Sanctions Threaten to Crimp Profit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Visa Inc. (V) fell 5 percent, the most
since July, after the world''s biggest bank-card network said
economic sanctions against Russia could crimp profit this year. </p>
<p>The shares tumbled $10.47 to close at $198.93 in New York,
the worst performance in the Dow Jones Industrial Average. Visa
is the biggest component of the 30-company (INDU) index, which slid 0.8
percent. The sanctions may trim several pennies per share
from fiscal 2014 earnings, Chief Financial Officer Byron Pollitt
said yesterday after the firm reported quarterly results. </p>
<p>The U.S. imposed sanctions on more than two dozen
individuals and St. Petersburg-based OAO Bank Rossiya, prompting
Visa and MasterCard Inc. (MA) to stop processing payments for some
banks. Russian President Vladimir Putin responded to the
sanctions by recommending that his country create its own
payments system and change its laws. He said the two companies
will lose market share. </p>
<p>The geopolitical situation will create additional risk
for Visa and MasterCard in coming months, Christopher Donat,
an analyst at Sandler O''Neill  Partners LP, said today in a
note to clients. Pending Russian law could be negative for
earnings. </p>
<p>MasterCard, the second-biggest U.S. network, also dropped 5
percent, the most since January. The Purchase, New York-based
company is scheduled to report quarterly results May 1. </p>




Photographer: Andrey Rudakov/Bloomberg

<p>
Logos for Visa Inc., Maestro and Mastercard Inc. payment systems sit on an automated teller machine (ATM) inside a Credit Bank of Moscow bank branch in Moscow, Russia, on April 22, 2014. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Adam Ewing" date="Apr 25, 2014  8:14 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-25/microsoft-completes-nokia-phone-unit-purchase-in-push-to-mobile.html"><headline>Microsoft Completes Nokia Phone-Unit Deal in Push to Mobile</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) completed the
takeover of Nokia Oyj (NOK1V)''s phone business, ending a seven-month
wait to renew its assault on the mobile market and leaving the
Finnish company seeking growth in wireless networks. </p>
<p>The final price may be slightly higher than the 5.44
billion euros ($7.5 billion) announced in September, Nokia said
today. About 30,000 employees are transferring to Redmond,
Washington-based Microsoft as part of the transaction, which was
delayed amid regulatory scrutiny. </p>
<p>Microsoft, the world''s largest software maker, is gaining a
device business that it''ll rely on to catch up with Apple Inc. (AAPL)
and Google Inc. (GOOG) in the tablet and mobile-phone markets. Nokia is
left seeking a turnaround for its network-equipment business and
is said to consider the division''s head, Rajeev Suri, as chief
executive officer to challenge rivals such as Ericsson (ERICB) AB. </p>
<p>The deal alone doesn''t immediately solve the problem for
either company, said Sami Sarkamies, an analyst at Nordea Bank
AB in Helsinki. Now, they have to roll up their sleeves and
starting working to play catch-up. </p>
<p>The purchase of the unprofitable division makes Microsoft
the world''s second-largest maker of mobile phones with about 14
percent of the market, according to researcher IDC. Samsung
Electronics Co. is the market leader. </p>




Photographer: Simon Dawson/Bloomberg

<p>
Nokia, once the smartphone market leader, is evaluating its strategy for its future without the phone business. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Makiko Kitamura and Robert Hutton" date="Apr 28, 2014  7:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-28/pfizer-s-bid-may-have-been-invited-by-u-k-s-tax-policy.html"><headline>Pfizer''s Bid May Have Been Invited by U.K.''s Tax Policy</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The U.K. may have opened the door
for Pfizer Inc. (PFE)''s $98.7 billion bid for AstraZeneca Plc (AZN), the
country''s second-biggest drugmaker, with a tax policy designed
to draw research investment from abroad. </p>
<p>While the U.K. tightened takeover rules following Kraft
Foods Inc.''s hostile bid for candy maker Cadbury Plc, the
country has created incentives for drugmakers to increase
research and capital investments. A program implemented last
year enables companies to apply a lower corporate tax rate to
profits from patents. That encouraged GlaxoSmithKline Plc,
AstraZeneca''s larger British rival, to build its first U.K.
factory in almost four decades. </p>
<p>While Britain would lose AstraZeneca if Pfizer pulls off
the biggest-ever U.K. takeover, the nation would become the
domicile of the world''s biggest pharmaceutical company and
receive a $100 billion boost to its economy, Pfizer Chief
Executive Officer Ian Read said on a conference call with
reporters yesterday. A spokesman for U.K. Prime Minister David Cameron said there were rules in place governing acquisitions,
and declined to comment further. </p>
<p>If Pfizer incorporate in the U.K., you''re bringing in
inward investment, said Dan Mahony, who helps manage about $12
billion at Polar Capital Holdings Plc in London. You could
argue that government policy has driven that, in which case,
they''re hardly going to try to nix the deal. </p>




Photographer: Simon Dawson/Bloomberg

<p>
A box of Arthrotec 50 tablets, produced by Pfizer Inc., top, and a box of EMLA cream, produced by AstraZeneca Plc, are seen in this arranged photograph taken in London. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Drew Armstrong and Oliver Staley" date="Apr 28, 2014  4:19 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-28/pfizer-confirms-proposing-98-7-billion-astrazeneca-deal.html"><headline>Pfizer Still Wants AstraZeneca After Bid Rejected</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE) is back in the megamerger game. </p> <p>The U.S. drugmaker proposed buying AstraZeneca Plc (AZN) for about 58.8 billion pounds ($98.7 billion) in what would rank as the industry''s biggest-ever takeover, surpassing Pfizer''s $64 billion purchase of Wyeth in 2009. AstraZeneca spurned the offer as too low, and Pfizer said it''s considering its options. </p> <p>If AstraZeneca eventually agrees, a deal would create a company incorporated in the U.K. for tax purposes and run from New York. London-based AstraZeneca''s operations would be sewn into Pfizer''s three new business units. </p> <p>Related:</p>

Video: Pfizer and AstraZeneca: Are These Dinosaurs Mating?

Amgen, AbbVie Seen as Possible AstraZeneca White Knights
Pfizer Is Said to Plan Renewed Push for AstraZeneca Deal
<p>Pfizer offered 46.61 pounds a share in cash and stock for AstraZeneca in January, and AstraZeneca declined to pursue negotiations, Pfizer said in a statement today. The proposal is about 14 percent above the April 25 close for AstraZeneca. The stock today climbed above that price, gaining the most in more than two decades. </p> <p>For now, Pfizer is still trying to draw AstraZeneca into talks. </p> <p>We tried to get a mutual announcement to say we were in preliminary discussions, Pfizer Chief Executive Officer Ian Read said on a conference call today. AstraZeneca rebuffed that, which is why we were forced to make the announcement. </p>




Photographer: Chris Ratcliffe/Bloomberg

<p>
An employee fills a tray with cell compound solution at Neusentis Ltd.''s research laboratory, a unit of Pfizer Inc., in Cambridge, U.K., Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Apr 28, 2014 11:50 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-28/microsoft-rushes-to-fix-security-flaw-in-explorer-browser.html"><headline>Microsoft Rushes to Fix Security Flaw in Explorer Browser</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) is rushing to fix a
security flaw in its Internet Explorer browser that is already
being used in limited, targeted attacks, as antivirus firms
and the U.S. government advise switching to alternate products. </p>
<p>To take over a user''s personal computer through the
browser''s vulnerability, a hacker would have to persuade that
person to click on a link to view a malicious website, Microsoft
said in an advisory. </p>
<p>The Explorer security concerns come just weeks after the
public discovery of Heartbleed, a flaw in the design of an
encryption tool that runs on as many as two-thirds of all active
websites. Some edition of Internet Explorer runs on 58 percent
of all desktop PCs, according NetMarketShare, compared with 18
percent for Google Inc.''s Chrome, the No. 2 browser. </p>
<p>An attacker who successfully exploited this vulnerability
could gain the same user rights as the current user, Microsoft
said in the advisory, issued on April 26. On completion of
this investigation, Microsoft will take the appropriate action
to protect our customers, which may include providing a solution
through our monthly security update release process, or an out-of-cycle security update, depending on customer needs. </p>
<h2>Windows XP </h2>
<p>The flaw exists in Internet Explorer versions 6 through 11,
which means it will affect users of Windows XP, the operating
system that Microsoft stopped supporting with security updates
earlier this month. </p>
<p>Symantec Corp., the biggest maker of PC-security software,
advised customers to switch to another browser until Microsoft
releases a software patch to fix the vulnerability and to use a
security mitigation tool kit that Microsoft recommended and that
will work with Windows XP. The U.S. Department of Homeland
Security''s Computer Emergency Readiness Team issued similar
advice today. </p>
<p>The vulnerability was found on April 26 by researchers at
security firm FireEye Inc. (FEYE), who also discovered the related
attacks and named the campaign Operation Clandestine Fox.
FireEye, in a statement on its blog, declined to provide details
of the campaign except to say that it was targeted at Internet
Explorer versions 9 through 11, which account for about a
quarter of the total browser market. </p>
<h2>Zero-Day Threat </h2>
<p>This type of security flaw is known as a zero-day threat
because there is no time between the discovery of the weakness
and attacks attempting to exploit it. </p>
<p>Earlier this month, researchers disclosed discovery of the
Heartbleed bug, a flaw in OpenSSL encryption software.
Researchers pushed out a fix for the vulnerability, which could
have enabled hackers to gain access to user names, passwords and
other sensitive information, and users were urged to change
their website passwords. Companies such as BlackBerry Ltd.,
Cisco Systems Inc. and Yahoo! Inc. were affected by the bug. </p>
<p>Consumer-data breaches at Target Corp. and Neiman Marcus
Group Ltd. in recent months and the spying scandal involving the
National Security Agency have also raised concerns about the
security of networks and private information. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Rick Green" date="Apr 28, 2014 11:49 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-28/jpmorgan-says-lender-curbs-daily-risk-in-triparty-repos.html"><headline>JPMorgan Says Lender Curbs Daily Risk in Triparty Repos</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), one of two
banks that dominate clearing in the $1.8 trillion tri-party
repurchase agreement market, said it curtailed daily credit risk
that regulators blamed for fueling the 2008 financial crisis. </p>
<p>All clients have been moved to a system that includes
rolling settlement, simultaneous exchange of cash and collateral
and creation of a secured committed clearance advance facility,
JPMorgan said today in a statement. Collectively, the changes
provide the bank with more protection against losses while
reducing the need of Wall Street dealers for intraday loans. </p>
<p>The Federal Reserve has been urging JPMorgan and Bank of
New York Mellon Corp. to speed improvements in repo markets,
which are used by the Fed''s primary dealers for short-term
funding. The system neared collapse in 2008 amid the demise of
Bear Stearns Cos. and Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. Bankers had
pledged to finish upgrades by 2016, prompting the Fed to say
industry-led efforts were too slow. </p>
<p>Every new piece of functionality introduced over the last
four years has allowed us to reduce materially the systemic risk
previously created by over-reliance on clearing-bank credit,
Michael Albanese, head of JPMorgan''s U.S. tri-party repo
clearing and collateral management, said in the statement. </p>
<p>BNY Mellon, the industry leader, and JPMorgan act as
middlemen to process repo transactions and keep charge of
collateral. The role required the two New York-based banks to
temporarily extend hundreds of billions of dollars in credit for
several hours during the day, which puts their safety at risk if
the market breaks down before the deals are unwound. </p>
<h2>Curbing Risk </h2>
<p>The Fed''s goal was to curb the need for the lenders to
finance the deals, people familiar with the plans have said. The
market is the biggest source of financing for primary dealers,
the 22 firms that act as counterparties for the central bank. </p>
<p>BNY Mellon is fully on track for practically eliminating
intraday credit risk this year and enabling market participants
to continue to efficiently and effectively fund their
operations, Kevin Heine, a spokesman for the company, said in
an e-mailed statement. The lender, which handles about 80
percent of the transactions, expects to have the final pieces of
its upgrade in place by the end of this year, according to the
firm''s website. </p>
<p>Ben S. Bernanke, the Fed''s chairman during 2008, told the
Financial Crisis Inquiry Commission that a breakdown of the tri-party market in 2008 almost created a black hole as
financial firms lost access to cash for daily operations. The
commission in a report cited structural flaws in the market as
one of the biggest causes of the crisis. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matt Townsend" date="Apr 28, 2014 11:36 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-28/disney-s-frozen-leads-sales-of-licensed-toys.html"><headline>Disney''s Frozen'' Leads Sales of Licensed Toys</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The love fest between little girls
and the film Frozen helped Walt Disney Co. (DIS) maintain its
domination of the U.S. licensed toy industry last quarter. </p>
<p>Elsa dolls and other Frozen merchandise sold better
than any other licensed toys in the first three months of the
year, according to NPD Group Inc. The animated movie, released
in November, has generated more than $1.1 billion in ticket
sales, according to Box Office Mojo. That''s made it the highest-grossing animated film of all time. </p>
<p>For Disney, the Frozen surge is helping continue its
winning streak in toy licensing. The company had four of the top
five toy franchises in the first quarter, including Disney
Princess, Mickey  Friends and Star Wars. The lone non-Disney
franchise was Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles, owned by Viacom Inc. </p>
<p>Cars, another Disney property, led the list last year,
when retail sales of from licensed toys climbed to $5.3 billion,
according to Port Washington, New York-based NPD. The toy
industry is increasingly relying on entertainment franchises to
spur sales. While total U.S. toy sales declined 1 percent last
year, revenue from licenses rose 3 percent. </p>
<p>Disney, based in Burbank, California, also dominated the
list of fastest-growing licenses last quarter with three titles:
Frozen, Planes and Sofia the First. The top spot
went to toys based on Despicable Me, owned by Comcast
Corp.''s Universal Pictures. </p>




<p>
Elsa, voiced by Idina Menzel, in "Frozen." Photograph: Walt Disney Pictures/Everett Collection Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Charles Mead" date="Apr 28, 2014  9:44 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-28/walter-bonds-jump-following-debt-for-equity-swap.html"><headline>Walter Bonds Jump Following Debt-for-Equity Swap</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Co.''s $500 mln of 9.875% bonds due
December 2020 up 4.1 cents on the dollar to 67.6 cents at 9:30
a.m., according to Trace data.
* Up from record low of 63.5 cents reached on April 25, before
co. agreed to issue equity in exchange for $35 mln of the bonds.
* Co.''s $450 mln of 8.5% notes due April 2021 up 1 cent to
61.25.
* For filing, DOCC CF 0001104659-14-030701 GO </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Greg Stohr" date="Apr 28, 2014  9:38 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-28/microsoft-wins-antitrust-case-as-top-court-rejects-novell.html"><headline>Microsoft Wins Antitrust Case as Top Court Rejects Novell</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The U.S. Supreme Court ended a
lawsuit that accused Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) of illegally protecting its
Windows computer operating system from competition 20 years ago
by undercutting a rival word-processing program. </p>
<p>Declining to take up a lingering antitrust case stemming
from Microsoft''s software dominance in the 1990s, the justices
today rejected without comment an appeal by Novell Inc., which
once made the WordPerfect application. </p>
<p>Novell was looking to revive a lawsuit that accused
Microsoft of anticompetitive conduct during development of its
Windows 95 operating system in 1994. Novell said that, late in
the rollout process, Microsoft withheld software components
known as namespace extensions so competing developers would have
trouble making their programs run smoothly on Windows. </p>
<p>Novell said the move slowed the development of WordPerfect,
a word-processing program that posed a threat to Microsoft''s
Word. </p>
<p>In throwing out the lawsuit, a Denver-based federal appeals
court said antitrust laws rarely impose on firms -- even
dominant firms -- a duty to deal with their rivals. The ruling
upheld a federal trial judge''s opinion. </p>
<p>Novell, now part of privately held Wizard Parent LLC,
argued in its appeal that Microsoft made its own operating
system less attractive to consumers in order to crush
competition and protect its operating system monopoly. </p>
<p>The case bore some similarities to the 1998 Justice
Department lawsuit that at one point produced a court order that
would have split Microsoft into two companies. An appeals court
overturned that order, and the company later settled the case by
agreeing to let computer makers promote rival software products. </p>
<p>Chief Justice John Roberts didn''t take part in the Supreme
Court action. He was involved as a lawyer in the Justice
Department''s antitrust case against Microsoft. </p>
<p>The case is Novell v. Microsoft, 13-1042. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Rabil and Alex Barinka" date="Apr 29, 2014  4:29 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-29/ibm-increases-quarterly-dividend-by-16-to-1-10-a-share.html"><headline>IBM Boosts Quarterly Dividend by 16% as Buybacks Slow</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines Corp. (IBM) raised its quarterly dividend by 16 percent to $1.10 per share as Chief Executive Officer Ginni Rometty tries to appease shareholders while the company shifts businesses. </p> <p>IBM announced the increase from 95 cents a share in a press release today before the start of its annual meeting. The new dividend is more than the $1.05 a share projected, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. The 15-cent increase will cost Armonk, New York-based IBM about $625 million a year. </p> <p>Earlier this month, IBM reported its eighth straight quarterly decline in revenue as it shifts its business from hardware to cloud computing and data analysis. Rometty is banking on a strong comeback in the coming quarters as she aims to deliver on a forecast for adjusted earnings of at least $18 a share this year. The larger-than-expected dividend boost comes as IBM plans to reduce its pace of stock buybacks following an $8.2 billion splurge in the first quarter. </p> <p>Today''s announcement reinforces our commitment to delivering value to shareholders, Rometty said in the statement. We will continue to invest aggressively in our strategic growth areas including cloud, big data analytics, social, mobile and security to position the company to drive growth and higher value for our clients. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
Earlier this month, International Business Machines Corp. reported its eighth straight quarterly decline in revenue as it shifts its business from hardware to cloud computing and data analysis. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David Voreacos and Michael J. Moore" date="Apr 29, 2014  4:24 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-29/goldman-sachs-morgan-stanley-swiss-units-seek-tax-deals.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs, Morgan Stanley Swiss Units Seek Tax Deals</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The Swiss units of Goldman Sachs
Group (GS) Inc. and Morgan Stanley (MS) are among 106 banks seeking U.S.
non-prosecution agreements after saying they had reason to
believe they helped Americans violate tax laws, according to
three people familiar with the banks'' actions. </p>
<p>Both Goldman Sachs and Morgan Stanley applied to a Justice
Department program that requires banks to disclose how they
helped Americans hide assets, hand over data on undeclared
accounts and pay penalties, according to the people who asked
not to be identified because they weren''t authorized to discuss
the matter publicly. </p>
<p>To gain non-prosecution deals, banks must pay 20 percent of
the value of accounts not disclosed to the Internal Revenue
Service on Aug. 1, 2008, 30 percent for such accounts opened
between then and February 2009 and 50 percent for accounts
opened afterward. Banks submitted letters of intent by Dec. 31. </p>
<p>Andrea Raphael, a spokeswoman for Goldman Sachs, and Wesley
McDade, a spokesman for Morgan Stanley, declined to comment. </p>
<p>The voluntary disclosure program, offered last year to more
than 300 Swiss banks, is part of the U.S. crackdown on offshore
tax evasion. It wasn''t open to 14 institutions already under
criminal investigation, including Credit Suisse Group AG, the
second-biggest Swiss bank; the Swiss unit of HSBC Holdings Plc;
Julius Baer Group Ltd., Switzerland''s third-largest wealth
manager; and Zuercher Kantonalbank, the largest state-owned
regional bank. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley is considering strategic options for its
Swiss private bank, including a sale or wind-down, a person
briefed on the discussions said last month. </p>
<h2>Undeclared Accounts </h2>
<p>Those under criminal investigation are known as Category 1
banks, while those seeking non-prosecution agreements are called
Category 2. If no undeclared U.S. accounts are found, banks can
apply as Category 3. Category 4 banks are those with mainly
local clients. </p>
<p>Banks seeking non-prosecution agreements must disclose the
total number of U.S. accounts since 2008, their highest dollar
value, and the employees who managed them. The banks also must
use independent examiners to certify findings. </p>
<p>Assistant Attorney General Kathryn Keneally said in January
that the department is reviewing the letters of intent to see if
applicants qualify as Swiss banks. Some banks are still
reviewing records, and some may withdraw, she said. </p>
<p>At least 33 banks announced that they will join the program
in Category 2, including Cie. Lombard, Odier SCA, Geneva''s
oldest bank, and BSI Group, the Swiss private bank owned by
Italy''s Assicurazioni Generali SpA. </p>
<p>Banks that said they will participate include: Union
Bancaire Privee, the Geneva-based bank founded by Edgar de
Picciotto in 1969; Edmond de Rothschild Group, owned by Baron
Benjamin de Rothschild; and EFG International AG, controlled by
Greek billionaire Spiro Latsis and his family. Another 15 banks,
mainly regional lenders, declared they will opt for Category 3
or 4. </p>
<p>Category 3 banks seek Justice Department letters saying
they''re not a target of a criminal probe. In return, an
independent examiner must confirm the bank broke no laws. </p>
<p>The Wall Street Journal earlier reported about the banks''
participation in the U.S. program. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Rubin and Zachary R. Mider" date="Apr 29, 2014  1:41 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-29/pfizer-bids-for-u-k-address-as-u-s-tax-revamp-stalls.html"><headline>Pfizer Bids for U.K. Address With U.S. Tax Revamp Stalled</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>U.S. companies looking for lower tax bills are heading for the exits, and Congress is doing nothing to stop them. </p> <p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE) is the latest corporation to consider reducing its tax bill by moving its legal address outside the U.S., proposing an acquisition of London-based AstraZeneca Plc (AZN) that would allow Pfizer to reincorporate in the U.K. while top executives remain in New York. </p> <p>Pfizer would join at least 19 other companies making or contemplating similar transactions, including Chiquita Brands International Inc. (CQB) and Omnicom Group Inc. (OMC), the largest U.S. advertising firm. A stalled proposal from President Barack Obama to limit such deals would raise $17 billion over a decade. </p> <p>U.S. lawmakers have responded with little outrage and no plans for a quick law to limit the transactions, known as inversions. Instead, they cite the deals as fuel for a revamp of the tax code that''s probably years away. That inaction gives companies a window to look for offshore mergers. </p> <p>Members of Congress are not swayed as easily nowadays by all the rhetoric about corporate tax cheats and companies being traitors because they''re moving to Ireland, said Herman Bouma, a Washington-based senior tax counsel at Buchanan, Ingersoll  Rooney P.C. There doesn''t seem to be that many members upset about the inversions happening. They''re more upset about the way their tax code is, that causes companies to want to do that. </p>




Photographer: Michele Tantussi/Bloomberg

<p>
A Pfizer Inc. office in Berlin. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Manuel Baigorri" date="Apr 29, 2014  6:22 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-29/jpmorgan-vice-chairman-ponti-leaving-for-health-care-fund.html"><headline>JPMorgan Vice Chairman Ponti Leaving for Health-Care Fund</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Andrea Ponti, JPMorgan Chase 
Co. (JPM)''s vice chairman of global health-care investment banking, is
preparing to leave and set up an investment firm targeting the
industry. </p>
<p>Rakesh Patel and Cathrin Petty will continue to run
JPMorgan''s health-care investment banking business in Europe,
the Middle East and Africa, according to a memo from Laurence Hollingworth, head of EMEA coverage, that was obtained by
Bloomberg News. The contents of the document were confirmed by a
spokeswoman for the bank in London. </p>
<p>Ponti joined New York-based JPMorgan in 2008 from Goldman
Sachs Group Inc. to help build the pharmaceutical and health-care practice in the region, according to the memo. He wasn''t
immediately available for comment. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore, Bradley Olson and Sara Forden" date="Apr 29, 2014  5:09 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-29/morgan-stanley-deal-with-rosneft-may-wait-amid-sanctions.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Rosneft Deal Seen in Limbo Amid Sanctions</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley''s (MS) sale of its
physical oil unit to OAO Rosneft (ROSN) hasn''t been submitted for
regulatory approval, and the companies will probably wait until
tensions cool after the U.S. sanctioned Rosneft''s chief,
according to a person with knowledge of the situation. </p>
<p>The deal would almost certainly be rejected if submitted
now to the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States,
or CFIUS, said five people involved in previous national-security reviews, asking not to be identified because they
aren''t directly involved in the transaction. The U.S. announced
yesterday that Rosneft Chief Executive Officer Igor Sechin is on
a list of people facing sanctions. </p>
<p>Regulatory resistance could threaten a sale that addresses
concerns held by Morgan Stanley''s own banking regulators, who
are considering whether to limit banks'' ownership of physical-commodities operations. Even if sanctions aren''t levied directly
against Rosneft, clients'' hesitation to do business with the
Moscow-based company may harm the value of the unit it''s buying. </p>
<p>Just the threat of the U.S. sanctioning Igor Sechin might
throw off this deal, said Amy Myers Jaffe, executive director
of energy and sustainability at the University of California-Davis. That''s the power of these sanctions. </p>




Photographer: Andrey Rudakov/Bloomberg

<p>
The U.S. announced yesterday that OAO Rosneft Chief Executive Officer Igor Sechin is on a list of people facing sanctions. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Eduard Gismatullin" date="Apr 29, 2014  4:44 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-29/exxon-shell-have-capacity-for-bg-bid-after-ceo-exit-rbc-says.html"><headline>Exxon, Shell Have Capacity for BG Bid After CEO Exit, RBC Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil (XOM) Corp., Royal Dutch
Shell Plc (RDSA) and Chevron Corp. (CVX) have the capacity to bid for BG
Group Plc (BG/) after Chief Executive Officer Chris Finlayson resigned
yesterday, said RBC Capital Markets. </p>
<p>Finlayson''s sudden departure has started speculation that
the U.K.''s third-largest oil company may become a target as bids
for European companies including drugmaker AstraZeneca Plc (AZN) and
Alstom SA (ALO) show an increased appetite for deals. BG, which has
oil assets in Brazil, gas discoveries in Tanzania and a gas-export plant in Australia, has a market value of 39.6 billion
pounds ($66.7 billion). </p>
<p>Changing CEO after 15 months and review of operating,
investment and portfolio management plans raises questions on a
possible takeover, Peter Hutton, a London-based analyst at
RBC, said in a note yesterday. Exxon Mobil, Shell and Chevron
have the capacity to pursue a cash acquisition and may need
to offer a 20 percent premium to the current share price. </p>
<p>BG, trading at a materially greater discount to its
peer group, may also examine plans to sell some assets in Brazil
or Tanzania, Deutsche Bank AG said in a note e-mailed today. The
company shares dropped 14 percent on Jan. 27, when Finlayson
unveiled project delays, and haven''t recovered yet. </p>
<h2>Permanent Successor </h2>
<p>The company, based in Reading, England, yesterday said that
the CEO resigned for personal reasons after a little more than a
year in the job. He has been replaced by Chairman Andrew Gould
until a permanent successor is found. </p>
<p>BG yesterday also ditched an output forecast for 2015
that''s just three months old. At the same time, the directors
reiterated their commitment to the company''s strategy presented
by Finlayson in May. </p>
<p>This was a strange announcement, Neill Morton, a
London-based analyst at Investec Bank Plc, wrote in an e-mailed
report yesterday.  Directors seems happy to usher the CEO
through the exit while staying committed to his strategy. </p>
<p>BG rose as much as 2.4 percent to 1,174 pence in London
trading today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Drew Armstrong and Robert Langreth" date="Apr 29, 2014 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-29/pfizer-drops-less-is-more-strategy-with-astrazeneca-bid.html"><headline>Pfizer Drops Less-Is-More Strategy With AstraZeneca Bid</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>For three years, Pfizer Inc. (PFE) Chief
Executive Officer Ian Read has been firing people, trimming
research initiatives and shedding businesses in a less-is-more
strategy designed to cut back the excesses from a decade of
megamergers. No more. </p>
<p>Yesterday''s announcement that Pfizer is seeking to buy
AstraZeneca Plc (AZN) in a new $100 billion megamerger is putting the
industry on notice that a company that was once the world''s
biggest drugmaker is seeking to quickly reclaim its title. A
consummated deal would generate more than $75 billion in
combined yearly revenue, based on current sales. It may also
offer new growth opportunities and tax advantages for Pfizer,
and reopen a door on a promising family of cancer medications. </p>
<p>There are palatable aspects to the deal, said Timothy Anderson, an analyst with Sanford C. Bernstein  Co., in a note
to clients. Yet doing yet another big merger can certainly be
viewed as a potential failure of sorts. </p>
<p>Pfizer''s offer, quickly rebuffed by AstraZeneca as too low,
was revealed after a pair of experimental drugs thought to have
billion-dollar potential for Pfizer, Eliquis and Xeljanz,
fizzled in their starts and a third, the breast cancer treatment
palbociclib, will soon face a potent competitor in Eli Lilly 
Co.''s experimental drug bemaciclib. </p>




Photographer: Simon Dawson/Bloomberg

<p>
A box of EMLA cream, produced by AstraZeneca Plc, top, sits on a box of Arthrotec 50 tablets, produced by Pfizer Inc., in this arranged photograph taken in London. Pfizer''s offer for AstraZeneca was quickly rebuffed as too low. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Katia Porzecanski" date="Apr 30, 2014  1:32 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-30/jpmorgan-promotes-werning-to-head-of-latin-america-research.html"><headline>JPMorgan Names Werning Head of Latin America Research</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. named
Argentine economist Vladimir Werning as the head of Latin
America research amid a leadership overhaul in the global
banking division. </p>
<p>Werning will replace and report to Luis Oganes, who was
promoted earlier this month to global head of emerging-markets
research, according to bank spokeswoman Veronica Navarro Espinosa. Oganes, who will move to London in August, succeeded
Joyce Chang after she was named global head of research. </p>
<p>Benjamin Ramsey, Franco Uccelli, Gabriel Lozano and Iker Cabiedes will keep their current responsibilities as Latin
America economists and report to Werning, who will continue to
cover the economies and fixed-income markets of Argentina and
Chile, according to Espinosa. </p>
<p>Werning started as an economist at JPMorgan''s Buenos Aires
office in the late 1990s after teaching at Torcuato Di Tella
University, where he studied economics. He moved to the bank''s
New York office in 2004. </p>
<p>The promotions come after JPMorgan''s corporate and
investment banking chief Daniel Pinto announced 15 staff changes
in a memo April 7 including the promotion of Carlos Hernandez
and Jeff Urwin to co-heads of global banking. Chang succeeded
Tom Schmidt, who asked for a new role earlier this year,
according to the memo. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Apr 30, 2014 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-04-30/microsoft-xbox-one-console-rolls-out-in-china-in-fall.html"><headline>Microsoft Xbox One Console Rolls Out in China in Fall</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) will begin selling its Xbox One video-game console in China in September after a 13-year ban on such equipment was lifted in January. </p> <p>The device will be sold through Microsoft''s partnership with BesTV New Media Co. (600637), a unit of Shanghai Media Group Inc., the company said yesterday in an e-mailed statement. Microsoft didn''t provide details on game titles for the Chinese market, except to say the venture will invest to establish an innovation program that will enable creators and developers to build, publish, and sell their games on Xbox One in China. </p> <p>China''s video-game industry will generate about $10 billion in sales next year, according to PricewaterhouseCoopers LLP, and the rule change has set off a flurry of activity. TCL Multimedia Technology Holdings Ltd. said this month it will make a game player, and ZTE Corp. announced plans for its Fun Box in March. Sony Corp. and Nintendo Co. are also weighing Chinese entries. </p> <p>China took over as the No. 1 consumer of TVs in the world ahead of the U.S. last year, said P.J. McNealy, analyst and CEO at Digital World Research in Natick, Massachusetts. Having an entertainment console attached to follow those coattails makes a lot of sense. </p> <p>To succeed, Microsoft will have to lower the Xbox One''s $499 price for the Chinese market and line up game titles between now and September, McNealy said. </p> <h2>Microsoft''s Challenges </h2> <p>Hands down the two biggest challenges for Microsoft are content and pricing, he said. Right now they don''t have a clear value proposition of what content they are going to sell on the gaming front, the music front, the TV front or the movie front. </p> <p>Microsoft formed the $79 million venture with BesTV in September to enter the Chinese market. Microsoft will make an official announcement tomorrow in China about the Xbox debut. </p> <p>Consoles such as the Xbox, Nintendo''s Wii U and Sony''s PlayStation were banned under a 2000 rule to protect youths from the perceived corrupting influence of video games. China announced last year that the ban would be lifted within the Shanghai free-trade zone, which opened in September. </p> <p>In January, China''s ruling State Council temporarily suspended the ban for the entire country and said it will draft new rules. </p> <p>BesTV invested $40.3 million for a 51 percent stake in the joint venture, while Microsoft put in $38.7 million for the rest, according a September filing. </p> <p>The Xbox One, which went on sale in November, has been outgunned in U.S. sales by Sony''s PlayStation 4 for three consecutive months, according to market research firm NPD Group Inc. </p> <p>Sales of the $399 PlayStation 4, also released in November, have surpassed 7 million units worldwide through April 6, Sony said in an April 16 statement. Microsoft has sold more than 5 million of its $499 Xbox One units, according to an April 17 blog posting on its Xbox site. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Manuel Baigorri, David Welch and Drew Armstrong" date="May 01, 2014  6:02 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-05-01/pfizer-said-to-plan-sweetening-astrazeneca-bid-with-cash.html"><headline>Pfizer Planning to Raise AstraZeneca Bid Above $106 Billion</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. is preparing to sweeten its bid for AstraZeneca Plc to more than 63 billion pounds ($106 billion) in an attempt to lure the U.K.''s second-biggest drugmaker to the negotiating table, people with knowledge of the matter said. </p> <p>The offer may value AstraZeneca at more than 50 pounds a share and include a larger cash component, and could come as early as next week, said the people, who asked not to be identified discussing confidential information. The London-based company rejected a cash-and-stock proposal of 46.61 pounds a share. Pfizer will report its earnings on May 5. </p> <p>The new bid and its timing aren''t final and may change, two of the people said. After speaking with some AstraZeneca shareholders, Pfizer sees an offer in the low 50 pound-per-share range gaining their support for the companies to hold talks, two people said. </p> <p>Pfizer''s Chief Executive Officer Ian Read is on a charm offensive in the U.K. this week and would prefer to negotiate a friendly deal. Buying AstraZeneca would give Pfizer a lower tax rate and a portfolio of experimental cancer drugs. </p> <p>AstraZeneca rose 3.2 percent to 4,815 pence a share in London today, giving it a market value of 60.8 billion pounds. Pfizer fell 0.4 percent to $31.15. </p> <p>The companies have several large investors in common, including BlackRock Inc., Wellington Management Co. and Vanguard Group Inc. Pfizer''s top-20 shareholders collectively own 27.6 percent of AstraZeneca, Bloomberg data show. </p> <h2>Government Meetings </h2> <p>Until we see something officially, there is no comment we can provide, said Esra Erkal-Paler, an AstraZeneca spokeswoman. Pfizer spokeswoman Joan Campion declined to comment. </p> <p>Pfizer''s earlier offer, made in January, valued AstraZeneca at 58.8 billion pounds. The proposed deal would be the largest ever in the drug industry and the biggest of a U.K. company, data compiled by Bloomberg show. </p> <p>Read met with U.K. government ministers April 29 to discuss a potential takeover, according to a person familiar with the meetings. The CEO emphasized the American company''s plans to carry out research, development and manufacturing in the U.K. as well as the appeal of the British tax system, the person said. </p> <h2>Global Company </h2> <p>British lawmakers this week mobilized against Pfizer''s attempt, demanding Business Secretary Vince Cable secure assurances on jobs and research investment. Part of Pfizer''s pitch to British skeptical officials and media is that AstraZeneca is a global company and has substantial operations and people outside the country, said one of the people. </p> <p>About 40 percent of AstraZeneca''s revenue in 2013 came from North America, and another 34 percent from outside of Europe, data compiled by Bloomberg show. </p> <p>AstraZeneca Chairman Leif Johansson said the drugmaker will return to growth as an independent company and listed the reasons for rejecting the Pfizer offer, in a video today. The bid significantly undervalued the company and it''s concerned that the offer was too heavily weighted in stock. </p> <p>Pfizer''s pursuit of AstraZeneca is eclipsing a deal announced April 22 by Novartis AG of Basel, Switzerland, and GlaxoSmithKline Plc. Novartis agreed to buy Glaxo''s cancer business for as much as $16 billion, form a consumer-health joint venture with Glaxo, sell its veterinary unit to Eli Lilly  Co. for $5.4 billion and sell most of its vaccines business to Glaxo for as much as $7.1 billion. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Carroll" date="May 01, 2014  4:57 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-05-01/exxon-s-first-quarter-profit-declines-less-than-expected.html"><headline>Exxon''s First-Quarter Profit Declines Less Than Expected</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) posted higher-than-expected profit as international sanctions against Russian
interests clouded the U.S. oil explorer''s efforts to tap some of
the world''s biggest crude reserves. </p>
<p>First-quarter net income was $9.1 billion, or $2.10 a
share, compared with $9.5 billion, or $2.12, a year earlier, the
Irving, Texas-based company said in a statement today. Per-share
profit exceeded all 20 estimates from analysts in a Bloomberg
survey and surpassed the average by 22 cents. </p>
<p>Russia''s oil and gas riches are key to Chairman and Chief
Executive Officer Rex Tillerson''splans for reviving output at
the world''s biggest energy explorer by market value. Exxon''s
global production has fallen in 10 of the past 11 quarters and
net income is in the midst of the longest slide since the
worldwide financial crisis of 2008-2009. </p>
<p>Tillerson, 62, slashed spending on drilling and
acquisitions outside the U.S. by 41 percent to $5.2 billion and
almost tripled asset sales to amass cash. The balance-sheet
measures helped offset a larger-than-expected 5.6 percent drop
in oil and natural gas production exacerbated by lower crude
prices. </p>
<p>Cash flow looks good and their projects are proceeding on
schedule, so all in all it was a good quarter, Brian
Youngberg, an analyst at Edward Jones  Sons in St. Louis, said
in a telephone interview today. Cost-containment and the absence
of major deals akin to last year''s $3.1 billion Celtic
Exploration Ltd. purchase in Canada were a boon, he said. </p>




<p>
Gas prices are displayed as cars drive past an Exxon Mobil Corp. station in Cincinnati. Worldwide demand growth for fuels to run trucks, trains, airplanes and cars slowed to 0.9 percent during the first three months of this year from 1.3 percent a year earlier, according to the International Energy Agency. Photograper: Luke Sharrett/Bloomberg Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Oliver Staley and Kitty Donaldson" date="May 01, 2014  8:17 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-05-01/pfizer-bid-for-astrazeneca-faces-obstacles-from-target.html"><headline>Pfizer Bid for AstraZeneca Faces Obstacles From Target</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer (PFE) Inc.''s $106 billion bid for
AstraZeneca Plc (AZN) faces increased resistance as the unwilling
target''s chairman listed the reasons the offer was rejected and
British lawmakers began efforts to block the buyout attempt. </p>
<p>The offer significantly undervalued AstraZeneca,
Chairman Leif Johansson said today in a video posted to the
company website. </p>
<p>Pfizer, the biggest U.S. drugmaker, offered 46.61 pounds a
share in cash and stock in January, and London-based AstraZeneca
declined to pursue negotiations. On April 28, Pfizer made the
offer public and said it wanted to restart discussions.
AstraZeneca was also concerned that the offer was too heavily
weighted in stock, and about the proposed tax structure of the
new entity, Johansson said in the four-minute video. </p>
<p>AstraZeneca has a clear innovation-based strategy,
focused on achieving scientific leadership and returning to
growth, he said. The board is also confident in our ability
to successfully execute that strategy as an independent
company. </p>
<p>The deal may run into barriers set by U.K. officials
worried about the loss of jobs and research investment. </p>
<p>Pfizer executives likely will be summoned before
parliament''s Business Committee to explain their intentions,
Adrian Bailey, the committee''s chairman, said April 29.
Yesterday, Julian Huppert, a Liberal Democrat member of
parliament, submitted a motion calling for ministers to act as
necessary to protect employment and skills in the U.K. </p>
<h2>Largest Takeover </h2>
<p>There is a great deal at stake here, Huppert said in a
statement. This would be the largest takeover of a British
firm. I want to make sure AstraZeneca retains its position in
the U.K. It is extremely important for those people employed by
the company and our economy generally. </p>
<p>Under the terms of Pfizer''s offer, a deal would create a
company incorporated in the U.K. for tax purposes and run out of
New York, where Pfizer is based. The U.S. company has until May
26 to make an offer for AstraZeneca, or say that it won''t bid,
under U.K. takeover rules. </p>
<p>On a conference call with reporters, Pfizer Chief Executive
Officer Ian Read said he wouldn''t commit to preserving British
jobs, although he added the U.K. was an attractive jurisdiction
in which to do business. </p>
<p>AstraZeneca shares have climbed 32 percent since Jan. 1.
That growth shows that shareholders have endorsed the company''s
strategy, Johansson said. </p>
<p>The stock rose 1.1 percent to 4,715.50 pence at 11:37 a.m.
in London. </p>
<h2>Pfizer Meeting </h2>
<p>Read met with U.K. government ministers April 29 to discuss
a potential takeover, according to a person familiar with the
meetings. Read emphasized the American company''s plans to carry
out research, development and manufacturing in the U.K. as well
as the appeal of the British tax system, the person said. </p>
<p>Pfizer''s reputation in Parliament isn''t helped by its 2011
decision to close a research hub in the coastal town of
Sandwich, southeast England, with the loss of 2,000 jobs.
AstraZeneca is moving to a new global headquarters and research
center in Cambridge, which is represented by Huppert. </p>
<p>Bailey''s committee will discuss on May 6 whether to hold
hearings with executives. </p>
<p>I view it with great concern, Bailey, who is a Labour
lawmaker, told reporters. We have a company which closed its
operations in Sandwich for tax purposes and now says it''s buying
a British company for tax purposes. </p>
<p>If the bid goes ahead and is subject to a European
Commission investigation, the U.K. may ask for it to be referred
back on public interest grounds, at which point ministers could
block it. Or the government could try to amend the Enterprise
Act, which allows ministers to intervene to protect national
security, media plurality and the stability of the financial
system. </p>
<p>Jean-Christophe Gray, spokesman for Prime Minister David
Cameron, called AstraZeneca''s research center in Cambridge a
significant part of the U.K.''s developing science skill base. </p>
<p>Would you expect senior figures in government to take
close interest? Of course, Gray said in London today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hugh Son" date="May 02, 2014  8:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-05-02/jpmorgan-sees-20-drop-in-second-quarter-markets-revenue.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sees 20% Drop in Second-Quarter Markets Revenue</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the world''s
biggest investment bank by revenue, said Wall Street''s trading
slump has deepened and could last through the second quarter. </p>
<p>Fixed-income and equities trading revenue will drop about
20 percent from a year earlier at the New York-based company
amid a continued challenging environment and lower client
activity levels, JPMorgan said yesterday in its quarterly
regulatory filing. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon, 58, was the first head
of a major U.S. bank to warn investors this year that trading
was down, saying in February that revenue had fallen 15 percent.
Continued weakness has spurred analysts including Chris Mutascio
of Stifel Financial Corp.''s KBW unit to ponder whether the drop
in fixed-income trading might persist through 2014 and beyond. </p>
<p>It''s an industry phenomenon, and other banks allow
JPMorgan to grease the skids for them so there can be a gentle
letdown process, said Charles Peabody, an analyst at Portales
Partners LLC. </p>
<p>A 20 percent revenue slide from the $5.37 billion JPMorgan
posted in last year''s second quarter would mean results of $4.3
billion this period. That figure, along with the first quarter''s
$5.06 billion, would mark the bank''s worst first half in trading
since the financial crisis. </p>




Photographer: Pete Marovich/Bloomberg

<p>
The results for JPMorgan Chase  Co. fell short of analysts'' estimates by the most since Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon took over at the start of 2006, data compiled by Bloomberg show. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="May 02, 2014  4:41 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-05-02/goldman-sachs-americas-equities-co-head-wang-plans-to-retire.html"><headline>Goldman Americas Equities Co-Head Wang Plans to Retire</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Ted Wang, Goldman Sachs Group Inc.''s
co-head of equities trading for the Americas, is retiring after
18 years at the company and will become an advisory director. </p>
<p>Wang also was global co-head of the One Delta trading unit,
according to an internal memo from trading co-heads Isabelle Ealet, Pablo Salame and Ashok Varadhan. Michael DuVally, a
Goldman Sachs spokesman, confirmed the contents of the memo. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs, the top equity-trading bank last year,
posted a 6 percent decline in first-quarter revenue for that
business from a year earlier, the biggest drop among its U.S.
peers. The firm said it had challenges in market-making in Japan
and certain emerging-markets amid falling prices. </p>
<p>Ted has played an integral role in the growth of our
market-leading equities franchise and has been at the center of
many of our most significant transactions, Ealet, Salame and
Varadhan wrote in the memo. </p>
<p>So-called delta-one desks provide clients with strategies
to hedge holdings or bet on directional moves in markets using
derivatives or baskets of securities, which can be cheaper to
trade than obtaining all of the stocks involved. </p>
<p>Wang joined Goldman Sachs in 1996 and became a partner in
2006, according to the memo. He took on his most recent role in
2012, after leading convertibles trading and the Americas One
Delta business. </p>
<p>Peter D. Selman is the other co-head for the Americas
equities business, while Brian T. Levine serves as co-head of
One Delta. DuVally declined to comment on whether new co-heads
would be named. </p>
<p>Prior to joining Goldman Sachs, Wang co-founded Xeotron
Corp., a company that specialized in DNA biochips, according to
a biography on the website of the Committee of 100, a
nonpartisan group of Chinese Americans seeking to encourage
positive relations between the two nations. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Oliver Staley and Robert Hutton" date="May 02, 2014  4:29 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-05-02/pfizer-raises-astrazeneca-offer-to-106-5-billion.html"><headline>AstraZeneca Snubs Pfizer Approach That U.K. Won''t Block</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>AstraZeneca Plc (AZN) rejected Pfizer Inc.''s (PFE) sweetened takeover proposal, saying the 62.6 billion-pound ($105.6 billion) offer fails to appreciate the value of the promising medicines under development by the U.K.''s second-biggest drugmaker. </p> <p>The cash-and-stock offer, which values AstraZeneca at about 50 pounds a share based on today''s closing price for Pfizer, also still relies too heavily on equity, London-based AstraZeneca said in a statement. AstraZeneca earlier rejected a proposal of 46.61 pounds a share, announced April 28. </p> <p>Pfizer''s proposal would dramatically dilute AstraZeneca shareholders'' exposure to our unique pipeline and would create risks around its delivery, AstraZeneca Chairman Leif Johansson said in the statement today. As such, the board has no hesitation in rejecting the proposal. </p> <p>Related:</p>
Pfizer-AstraZeneca Deal Threatens Spending on New Drugs
U.K. Signals It Won''t Block Pfizer''s Bid for AstraZeneca
Pfizer Planning to Raise AstraZeneca Bid Above $106 Billion
<p>AstraZeneca may not get much help from the government of U.K. Prime Minister David Cameron in fending off Pfizer. The government today signaled it wouldn''t interfere, rebuffing calls from members of other political parties to step in to protect jobs in the country''s science base. </p> <p>AstraZeneca declined less than 1 percent to 48.08 pounds in London. Pfizer fell 1.3 percent to $30.75 in New York. </p> <h2>CEO Meetings </h2> <p>Pfizer raised its bid after Chief Executive Officer Ian Read met with AstraZeneca shareholders and government officials in the U.K. In a letter to Cameron, New York-based Pfizer pledged to follow through on AstraZeneca''s plan to build a substantial campus in Cambridge, England, and to keep key scientific management at the site. </p> <p>This is ultimately a decision for AstraZeneca shareholders, said Universities and Science Minister David Willetts in an interview. </p> <p>The U.K. government has been in talks with Pfizer about preserving jobs, particularly in research and manufacturing, in the country, Willetts said. </p> <p>I think those messages are getting home to Pfizer, but there''s a lot more hard-headed negotiation to come, Willetts said. </p> <p>Cameron spoke with Johansson today about the deal, said Jean-Christophe Gray, Cameron''s spokesman. </p> <p>AstraZeneca has a fantastic role in the British economy, Cameron told reporters today in Newcastle-Under-Lyme, England. Action on any merger is a decision for both companies. We''ve sought and received robust assurances from Pfizer should the deal go ahead. </p> <h2>Tax Rate </h2> <p>Buying AstraZeneca would give Pfizer a lower tax rate because the combined company would be a corporate resident of England. The company, which would maintain its head office in New York, also would gain a portfolio of experimental cancer drugs from the purchase. </p> <p>AstraZeneca in its April 28 statement rejecting the initial offer said Pfizer''s decision to move its tax domicile to the U.K. may be problematic. The U.K. company highlighted that issue again in today''s statement. </p> <p>Pfizer''s earlier offer, made in January, valued AstraZeneca at 58.8 billion pounds. The acquisition would be the largest ever of a U.K. company, according to data compiled by Bloomberg, and would create the world''s biggest drugmaker by sales. </p> <p>The consistent message from leading shareholders reinforces our belief that there is a highly compelling strategic, business and financial rationale for combining our businesses, with significant benefits for all our stakeholders, Read said in a letter to Johansson. We believe our revised terms will be viewed by the market as a basis for engagement. </p> <h2>Cash Mix </h2> <p>Stockholders would get 15.98 pounds in cash and 1.845 shares of the combined company for each share in AstraZeneca, Pfizer said. The new bid was 7.3 percent above the previous proposal and 39 percent above the closing price Jan. 3, before AstraZeneca made its initial offer. </p> <p>The new proposal consists of about 32 percent cash and 68 percent stock, versus about 30 percent cash and 70 percent stock in the original offer. AstraZeneca said April 28 the initial bid very significantly undervalued the company, and said it was concerned that too much of the payment was in stock rather than cash. </p> <h2>Limited Commitment </h2> <p>Pfizer, in the letter to Cameron, pledged to keep at least 20 percent of the combined company''s research and development workforce in the U.K., retain substantial manufacturing facilities at AstraZeneca''s site in Macclesfield, England, and invite at least two AstraZeneca directors to join Pfizer''s board. </p> <p>The U.S. company is committing to the steps for at least five years, though it could adjust these obligations should circumstances significantly change, according to the Pfizer statement. </p> <p>AstraZeneca employs almost 2,000 people in Macclesfield, and the company is in the process of moving its corporate headquarters from London to Cambridge. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Carroll" date="May 02, 2014  4:16 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-05-02/chevron-first-quarter-profit-declines-on-bad-weather.html"><headline>Chevron''s Goal of Record Output Slips as Production Drops</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX) Chairman and Chief
Executive Officer John Watson''s goal of breaking a production
record three years from now just got harder to reach. </p>
<p>After spending more than $100 million a day on average
during the first three months of the year on new oil wells and
other projects, Chevron posted its lowest first-quarter crude
and natural gas output since 2006 today. The company pumped the
equivalent of 2.59 million barrels a day during the period, 1
percent below the average estimate of three analysts in a
Bloomberg survey. </p>
<p>The output disappointment comes less than two months after
Watson scaled back his 2017 output target to 3.1 million barrels
a day from 3.3 million amid low gas prices that stalled some
drilling and scant new discoveries. For Chevron, the world''s
third-largest energy company by market value, production in the
era after its 2001 takeover of Texaco Inc. peaked at 2.78
million a day in 2010. </p>
<p>They are having to battle quite hard to get bottom-line
production growing, Stephen Clark, who helps manage $305
billion, including Chevron shares, at Standard Life Investments
in Boston, said in a telephone interview today. The sheer size
of some of the projects is an issue. </p>
<p>Watson cited winter weather in Kazakhstan, the source of
one in every eight barrels Chevron pumps worldwide, and a storm
in Thailand for the production decline. We continue to advance
our key development projects that will begin boosting output
next year, he said in a statement today. </p>
<h2>Still Viable </h2>
<p>The Chevron-operated $10 billion Angola LNG complex in
Africa that chills gas for shipment to overseas markets has been
shut since a pipe failure in mid-April, Chief Financial Officer
Pat Yarrington said during a conference call today. </p>
<p>An internal investigation into the incident should be
concluded in a matter of days, she said. Yarrington didn''t
provide an expected restart date, though she said the outage
will have a negative impact on Chevron''s overall production. </p>
<p>Watson''s 2017 goal still seems viable because they have a
lot of big projects coming on, said Stewart Glickman, an
equity analyst at SP Capital IQ in New York who rates Chevron a
buy and doesn''t own any shares. New contributions to output will
include fields beneath the Gulf of Mexico and off the Australian
coast, he said in an interview today. </p>
<p>First-quarter net income was $4.51 billion, or $2.36 a
share, compared with $6.18 billion, or $3.18, a year earlier,
San Ramon, California-based Chevron said in the statement. Sales
fell 6.1 percent to $50.98 billion. The company increased
capital spending 5.6 percent to $9.4 billion during the quarter. </p>
<h2>Russia Pipeline </h2>
<p>Chevron is among international energy explorers caught in
the middle of an intensifying row between the U.S. and its
European allies on one side, and Russian President Vladimir Putin on the other. Putin put foreign oil companies on the spot
on April 29 when he said they may be shut out of his country if
their governments continue to ratchet up sanctions against
Russian nationals and institutions. </p>
<p>Chevron and its partners are in the midst of a $5.4 billion
expansion of a pipeline that carries oil across Russia''s
Caucasus region from fields in neighboring Kazakhstan that
account for 12 percent of the company''s global supplies. </p>
<h2>Spending, Selling </h2>
<p>Watson is spending almost $40 billion this year to drill
for new discoveries and transport oil, gas and fuels such as
diesel to markets. In tandem with exploration forays that span
the globe from Argentina to China, Watson is overseeing $10
billion in asset sales to narrow the company''s focus on its
highest-profit projects. </p>
<p>Brent crude futures, the benchmark for more than half the
world''s oil, declined by 4.2 percent to an average of $107.92 a
barrel during the quarter, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. U.S. gas prices climbed 35 percent to average $4.712
per million British thermal units during that period. </p>
<p>Chevron dropped 0.2 percent to $124.72 at the close in New
York. </p>
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. is the world''s largest energy company by
market value, followed by Royal Dutch Shell (RDSA) Plc. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Katia Dmitrieva" date="May 02, 2014  2:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-05-02/morgan-stanley-hires-radchuck-desjardins-adds-cabel-vlaad-says.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Hires Radchuck, Desjardins Adds Cabel, Vlaad Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Morgan Stanley (MS) added investment-banking associate Paul Radchuck from Canadian Imperial Bank of
Commerce, according to Vlaad and Co., a Toronto-based financial-services recruiting firm. </p>
<p>Other moves in the Bill''s Buzz weekly newsletter
include: </p>
<p>* Eiraj Sohail left his associate position at Northleaf Capital
Partners Ltd. for the same role at Healthcare of Ontario Pension
Plan. </p>
<p>* Desjardins Securities Inc. added Bill Cabel as an analyst for
senior power producers and clean technology. He was previously
at Stifel Financial Corp. in Canada as managing director, equity
research. Mark Jarvi is also joining from Paradigm Capital Inc. </p>
<p>* Vlaad and Co. added Mark Stipe and Jean-Pierre Interlino as
equity partners. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Katia Porzecanski" date="May 02, 2014  7:09 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-05-02/goldman-alums-private-equity-shop-backs-mexico-bond-sale.html"><headline>Goldman Alums'' Private Equity Shop Backs Mexico Bond Sale</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Two months after Partners Group
Holding AG bought a majority stake in a Mexican gas pipeline
operator, the $43 billion investment firm is capitalizing on
unprecedented demand for the nation''s corporate debt. </p>
<p>Fermaca Enterprises, owned by the Zug, Switzerland-based
firm that specializes in private equity, sold $550 million of
bonds overseas yesterday. The sale was the seventh first-time
offering since August, when President Enrique Pena Nieto
proposed changes to the state oil industry that were signed into
law four months later. In the same span, only one debut issuer
came from Brazil, the biggest developing-nation bond market. </p>
<p>Partners Group, founded by three former Goldman Sachs Group
Inc. money managers in 1996, is seeking to profit from Mexico''s
energy industry after the government ended its 76-year-old oil
monopoly and from a boom in shale gas, according to the firm''s
managing director, Jean Perarnaud. Fermaca, purchased from New
York-based hedge fund Ospraie Management LLC for $750 million in
February, has a 25-year transportation agreement with state-owned utility Comision Federal de Electricidad. </p>
<p>The momentum is there for Mexico, fundamentally and
sentiment-wise, Perarnaud said by phone. The timing is
right. </p>
<h2>Refinance Debt </h2>
<p>Fermaca, based in Mexico City, sold the bonds due 2038 to
yield 6.375 percent. The senior secured amortizing notes, which
will have an average maturity of 15 years, are backed by Fermaca
assets including pipelines. Fitch Ratings and Standard  Poor''s
rate the bonds BBB-, the lowest investment grade. </p>
<p>Mexico''s peso weakened 0.1 percent to 13.0537 per U.S.
dollar at 7:02 a.m. in New York, paring its advance this week to
0.6 percent. </p>
<p>Partners Group, started by Alfred Gantner, Marcel Erni and
Urs Wietlisbach, will use proceeds of the sale to refinance both
the debt that it took on to buy Fermaca and a loan the company
used to finance construction of a pipeline, according to
Perarnaud. It bought the 86 percent stake in Fermaca from
Ospraie Management in February. </p>
<p>The agreement with CFE will last throughout the life of the
bonds, giving investors comfort that they will get paid, said
Ray Zucaro, who manages $390 million at SW Asset Management LLC. </p>
<p>That kind of long-term contract with government agencies
beyond the life of the bond where effectively you neutralize
that counterparty risk -- those are the kind of bonds that will
let you sleep at night, he said in a telephone interview from
Newport Beach, California. </p>
<h2>CFE Plan </h2>
<p>CFE, as the company is known, plans to take advantage of
legal changes to the energy industry to sell natural gas, Chief
Executive Officer Enrique Ochoa said March 20. After allowing
foreign investors to drill for oil for the first time since
1938, Mexico is looking to increase natural-gas supply, reduce
its dependence on U.S. imports and lower the cost of electricity
generation. </p>
<p>That push will increase demand for Fermaca''s gas pipelines,
said Partners Group''s Perarnaud. The company is also bidding on
multiple pipeline contracts being auctioned by CFE, he said. </p>
<p>We found Fermaca was the perfect asset, Perarnaud said.
It would be an upside if the oil and gas exploration happen in
Mexico because our pipelines are actually located in one of the
prospective areas for shale gas in Mexico. When you combine
everything together, you end up with a good story. </p>
<p>While Fermaca is taking advantage of the investor demand
for Mexican assets after the country passed constitutional
changes in December, the company is not dependent on those
measures to prosper in Mexico, he said. </p>
<h2>Secondary Laws </h2>
<p>After pushing through sweeping changes in his first year in
office that earned Mexico its highest-ever credit rating, Pena
Nieto has struggled to overcome opposition to pass the secondary
laws needed to implement the new oil legislation, damping demand
for Mexican assets. He submitted his proposals on April 30, the
last day of the congressional session. Lawmakers plan to vote on
the bills during special sessions in June after Congress missed
a mid-April deadline to pass the rules. </p>
<p>The delays helped spark a 0.14 percent loss in Mexican
government debt in April, trailing the emerging-market average
for the first time since January, according to Bank of America
Corp. indexes. </p>
<h2>Right Place'' </h2>
<p>Fermaca is also the first debut issuer from Mexico since
Oceanografia SA de CV defaulted on $495 million in February,
when the government seized the oil services provider following
allegations it took out a $400 million loan from Citigroup Inc.
under fraudulent circumstances. Citigroup determined that
Oceanografia, which provides oil services to state-run producer
Petroleos Mexicanos, overstated the collateral from its billings
to the company that were used to back the loans. </p>
<p>Unlike Oceanografia''s agreement with Pemex, Fermaca''s
contract with CFE doesn''t involve a third party and is
transparent, Perarnaud said. </p>
<p>Fermaca''s in the right place at the right time,Rafael Elias, a New York-based analyst at Credit Agricole SA, said in
an April 22 note to clients. These bonds should do well. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dan Hart and Lorraine Woellert" date="May 03, 2014 12:28 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-05-03/general-motors-recalls-almost-52-000-suvs-for-engine-software.html"><headline>GM''s Newest Recall Covers 52,000 SUVS Over Software Flaw</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>General Motors Co. (GM) is recalling 51,640
sport-utility vehicles to fix software that may not register
correct fuel levels, the latest in a series of safety actions
this year involving about 7 million vehicles. </p>
<p>A flawed engine-control module in some 2014 Buick Enclave,
Chevrolet Traverse and GMC Acadia SUVs may result in empty tanks
or stalled engines that could lead to crashes, according to a
notice posted today on the U.S. National Highway Traffic Safety
Administration''s website. The company will recalibrate the fuel
system free of charge. </p>
<p>The planned fix follows other GM recalls including that of
2.59 million small cars for faulty ignition switches that
allowed keys to slip out of their on positions, cutting
engine power and disabling air bags. GM took a $1.3 billion
charge in the quarter ended March 31 to cover recall costs. </p>
<p>Federal safety regulators, Congress and the Justice
Department are investigating why it took the company more than a
decade to recall some of the vehicles linked to 13 deaths in
accidents. In contrast, it took GM eight days after being
notified of the fuel-gauge software flaw on April 14 to decide
on a recall, according to NHTSA documents. </p>
<p>Last July, NHTSA''s head of defects investigations
complained to GM that the company was slow to communicate,
slow to act on recall investigations. </p>
<h2>Compensation Talks </h2>
<p>In 2005, GM shrugged off complaints about faulty ignition
switches, saying the loss of power steering wasn''t a genuine
safety risk. In 2010, it recalled thousands of cars to address
just that symptom. </p>
<p>In 2011, Mary Barra, who became the automaker''s chief
executive officer in January, was told that regulators were
investigating steering problems with the Saturn Ion. GM didn''t
recall the Ions until March 2014, a day before Barra testified
to the House Energy and Commerce Committee about the unrelated
faulty ignition switches. </p>
<p>Yesterday, GM adviser Kenneth Feinberg began preliminary
talks with a lawyer for accident victims over claims stemming
from the ignition switches. Bob Hilliard, a Texas attorney,
described the conversation as a settlement meeting to
discuss compensation for about 300 victims. </p>
<p>GM lawyers also appeared in a Manhattan bankruptcy court to
fight lawsuits seeking compensation for economic losses, saying
the automaker''s government-led bankruptcy in 2009 absolved it of
such responsibility. GM has agreed to address death and injury
claims and hired Feinberg, who ran compensation funds for
victims of the Sept. 11 terrorist attacks and the 2010 BP oil
spill, to advise it on a resolution. </p>
<p>Claims for economic loss can eclipse the cost of
compensating dead or injured car owners. Hilliard, who has
brought a lawsuit seeking economic damages, wants as much as $10
billion so his clients can buy new vehicles. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Brian Womack and Dina Bass" date="May 03, 2014 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-05-03/microsoft-to-warn-users-of-government-requests-for-information.html"><headline>Microsoft to Warn Users of Government Requests for Information</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) will start giving
users more information about government requests for data,
seeking to provide greater transparency and reassure consumers
about how their activities are being monitored. </p>
<p>Microsoft is updating its policy to expand routine
notification of users about government requests for data, unless
specifically prohibited by law, Kathy Roeder, a spokeswoman
for the Redmond, Washington-based company, said. </p>
<p>Technology companies are changing their policies to offer
more disclosure amid growing government demands for information
about what people do online. Concerns over security increased
after Edward Snowden last year leaked information that Internet
companies are being compelled under court orders to give the
U.S. National Security Agency information about citizens and
other users. </p>
<p>Facebook Inc. hasn''t changed its policy and is reviewing
the matter, according to Jodi Seth, a Facebook spokeswoman. </p>
<p>We are committed to transparency, and providing notice
about government requests is an important part of being
transparent, Seth wrote in an e-mailed statement. We are
always working to improve our notification process as the law
permits. </p>
<p>Facebook Chief Executive Officer Mark Zuckerberg earlier
this year blasted President Barack Obama over how the government
handles user data, saying it threatened the future of the
Internet. </p>
<p>Google said it makes efforts to tell users about on legal
requests. </p>
<h2>User Notification </h2>
<p>We notify users about legal demands when appropriate,
unless prohibited by law or court order, the company said in
an statement. </p>
<p>In January, Google, Apple Inc. and other technology
companies won U.S. permission to disclose more about government
orders for customer data. Companies are permitted to say broadly
how many accounts are covered by government requests and whether
the content of users'' communications was sought. </p>
<p>The Washington Post reported May 1 that the companies
updating their policies to expand routine notification of
users about government data seizures. </p>
<p>Kristin Huguet, a spokeswoman for Apple, didn''t respond to
a request for comment. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry></news>