<?xml version='1.0' encoding='us-ascii'?>
<news><entry author="By Will McSheehy and Claudia Maedler" date="Feb 07, 2007 10:17 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-02-07/jpmorgan-bear-stearns-hired-for-mideast-buyout-fund-update2-.html"><headline>JPMorgan, Bear Stearns Hired for Mideast Buyout Fund</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;JPMorgan Cazenove Ltd. and Bear
Stearns Cos. will help raise up to $2 billion for a Kuwaiti
buyout fund offering international investors a way to tap oil-fueled economic growth in the Middle East and North Africa. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global Investment House KSCC (GI5B), Kuwait's biggest investment
bank, will open its Global Buyout Fund to investors tomorrow,
Shailesh Dash, head of the lender's strategic investment group,
said in a phone interview today from Kuwait. It aims to raise
about $1.5 billion for conventional private equity, and another
$500 million for Islamic investments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``This is the first time a Gulf fund has attracted two
international placement agents without giving them a role on
the fund's management board,'' Dash said. ``This region's
current account surpluses, construction boom and opening
economies are really attracting investors now.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The economy of Saudi Arabia, the world's biggest oil
producer, will expand by 6.5 percent this year as the
government spends oil surpluses on new infrastructure, the
International Monetary Fund forecasts. Economic growth in Egypt
will accelerate to 7.5 percent this year after the government
cut taxes and tariffs to spur investment, Prime Minister Ahmed Nazif said in a Jan. 25 interview. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IMF expects Middle Eastern countries will earn a
combined current account surplus of $306 billion in 2007, up
from $282 billion in 2006, it says on its Web site. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wall Street &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JPMorgan Cazenove and Bear Stearns, Wall Street's fifth-biggest firm, join Western investors including Deutsche Bank AG (DBK)
and Carlyle Group raising money to buy Middle East and North
African companies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deutsche in May started a $2 billion Islamic private
equity fund for the region with Dubai's Abraaj Capital and
Bahrain's Ithmaar Bank that aims to grow investors' money by 15
percent a year. Muslim Shariah law forbids investment in
companies with high levels of debt or that are active in
proscribed businesses like gaming and alcohol sales. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carlyle, manager of more than $44 billion worldwide, plans
to hire 15 people to buy companies and identify potential
partners in the Middle East, North Africa and Turkey, Walid Musallam, the U.S. buyout firm's regional managing director,
said in November. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;20 Percent Return &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global Investment's 7-year fund will seek buyouts of
between $100 million and $150 million to achieve an internal
rate of return of 20 percent for its investors, according to
Dash. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Private equity raised $432 billion globally last year, led
by buyout funds which raised $212 billion, London-based Private
Equity Intelligence Ltd. said in a Jan. 25 report. Investors
like pension funds, endowments and wealthy individuals have
poured increasing amounts of money into private equity as some
funds outperform public markets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blackstone Group LP's 2002 $6.45 billion fund had annual
returns of 63 percent to July compared with an annual return of
6.3 percent in the Standard  Poor's 500 Index from 2002. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buyout firms typically aim to increase a company's profit
by changing managers or strategy before selling their holdings
within five years to a new buyer or to investors in an initial
stock sale. The firms raise cash from institutional investors
and use a combination of cash and loans to make purchases. The
acquired company's cash flow is then used to pay down debt. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global Investment manages about $1 billion of private
equity investments within a total $7.2 billion of assets under
management, according to Dash. The bank's shares closed down 1
percent to 960 fils ($3.3) in Kuwait today and have fallen by
13 percent this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporters on this story:
Will McSheehy in Dubai on 
wmcsheehy@bloomberg.net
Claudia Maedler in Dubai at 
cmaedler@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Gavin Serkin at  gserkin@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry></news>