<?xml version='1.0' encoding='us-ascii'?>
<news><entry author="By Adam Satariano" date="Jun 18, 2009  5:38 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-06-18/electronic-arts-names-microsoft-s-schappert-as-coo-update1-.html"><headline>Electronic Arts Names Microsoft&#8217;s Schappert as COO</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Electronic Arts Inc. (EA) hired Microsoft
Corp.&#8217;s John Schappert as chief operating officer, bringing back
the video-game executive who developed top-selling &#8220;Madden
NFL&#8221; and &#8220;Tiger Woods&#8221; titles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schappert was vice president of Microsoft Interactive
Entertainment, which includes Xbox Live and the company&#8217;s game
studios, Redwood City, California-based Electronic Arts said
today in a statement. He replaces John Pleasants, who left to
run social-game developer Playdom. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The appointment highlights Chief Executive Officer John Riccitiello&#8217;s push to develop hits and generate more revenue
from games played over the Web. At Microsoft, Schappert oversaw
Xbox Live, the online service that has 20 million users, as well
as the top-selling title &#8220;Halo.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;His years of experience with EA and in Microsoft&#8217;s Xbox
business, provide him great insight into recognizing what
consumers want,&#8221; Riccitiello said in the statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electronic Arts, the second-largest video-game publisher
behind Activision Blizzard Inc. (ATVI), fell 31 cents, or 1.5 percent,
to $20.52 today in Nasdaq Stock Market composite trading. The
shares have gained 28 percent this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schappert joined Electronic Arts in 1998 with the purchase
of his independent studio, which had developed &#8220;Madden NFL&#8221;
&#8220;NCAA Football&#8221; and &#8220;Tiger Woods,&#8221; and left in 2007. Those
games are now among the company&#8217;s best sellers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The departing Pleasants is becoming chief executive of
Mountain View, California-based Playdom, according to a separate
statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schappert will receive a one-time bonus of $1 million to
return, according to an Electronic Arts regulatory filing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Adam Satariano in San Francisco at 
asatariano1@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Anthony Palazzo at  apalazzo@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry></news>