
<news><entry author="By Francesca Cinelli" date="Apr 09, 2009 12:14 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-04-09/italian-stocks-autogrill-bulgari-stmicro-tenaris-trevisan.html"><headline>Italian Stocks: Autogrill, Bulgari, STMicro, Tenaris, Trevisan</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Italy&#8217;s benchmark SP/MIB Index rose
469, or 2.8 percent, to 17,408. The measure has increased 3
percent this week. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following stocks were among the most active on the
Italian market today. Symbols are in parentheses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Atlantia SpA (ATL)  gained for a second day, adding 47
cents, or 3.9 percent, to 12.42 euros. Europe&#8217;s largest toll-highway operator authorized bond sales of as much as 3.5 billion
euros ($4.6 billion) through 2010. The company also said its
main shareholders expect to draw other investors to a new
shareholder pact &#8220;in the near future.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;This news, if confirmed, would be quite positive for the
company, as a new pact would give more stability to the
ownership structure and would partially remove the overhang
risk,&#8221; Cheuvreux analyst Francesca Pezzoli wrote in a note. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Autogrill SpA (AGL)  rose 39.75 cents, or 8.2 percent, to
5.26 euros, taking this week&#8217;s increase to 13 percent. The
world&#8217;s biggest manager of airport restaurants said it will open
McDonald&#8217;s restaurants at the highway rest stops it operates in
France. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The agreement may lead to Autogrill operating McDonald&#8217;s
branches at airports and other areas in France that are run by
the Italian company, Autogrill said in a statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bulgari SpA (BUL IM) rose for the first time in five
sessions, adding 21.75 cents, or 6.6 percent, to 3.53 euros.
Shares of the world&#8217;s third-largest jeweler advanced as a
document obtained by Bloomberg News said the Japanese government
will propose $154 billion in stimulus aid. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fiat SpA (F)  added 11 cents, or 1.6 percent, to 6.81
euros. Cassa Lombarda increased its price estimate on Italy&#8217;s
largest manufacturer to 6.5 euros from 5 euros and kept a
&#8220;hold&#8221; recommendation. The brokerage cited potential for a
recovery in the car market during the second quarter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gruppo Coin SpA (GCN IM) jumped 45 cents, or 26 percent, to
2.18 euros, the highest in more than three months. Full-year
results by Italy&#8217;s largest department-store chain &#8220;beat
estimates at Ebitda and net profit level,&#8221; and were coupled
with a &#8220;sound balance sheet,&#8221; UniCredit Markets  Investment
Banking analyst Davide Vimercati wrote in a note. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intesa Sanpaolo SpA (ISP IM), Italy&#8217;s second-biggest bank
by assets, surged 14.25 cents, or 6.8 percent, to 2.23 euros.
Banks and raw-material producers led Europe&#8217;s gains, as
investors speculated government measures to rescue lenders and
revive the economy are working. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luxottica SpA (LUX)  added 36 cents, or 2.9 percent, to
12.7 euros, a third day of gains this week. The world&#8217;s biggest
maker of eyeglasses said it renewed a license to produce and
distribute eyewear under the Donna Karan label for five years
through December 2014. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mediobanca SpA (MB)  rose 27.5 cents, or 4.2 percent, to
6.86 euros, erasing this week&#8217;s losses. The Italian investment
bank&#8217;s results improved in its fiscal third quarter, which runs
through March 31, and it probably posted a profit, the Ansa news
agency reported, without saying where it got the information. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pirelli  C. Real Estate SpA (PRS) , the real estate unit
of tiremaker Pirelli  C. SpA, surged 47 cents, or 11 percent,
to 4.58 euros. The company said joint Vice Chairman Carlo Puri
Negri resigned. Giulio Malfatto joined the company as managing
director with responsibility for the business. Malfatto&#8217;s goal
is &#8220;to implement the industrial plan announced in February,&#8221;
according to Intermonte Sim SpA. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;STMicroelectronics NV (STM) , Europe&#8217;s largest
semiconductor maker, gained 35.25 cents, or 8.3 percent, to 4.62
euros. Goldman Sachs Group Inc. upgraded European technology
stocks to &#8220;neutral&#8221; from &#8220;underweight,&#8221; suggesting investors
to increasingly favor cyclical industries. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tenaris SA (TEN) , the world&#8217;s biggest maker of seamless
steel tubes for pipelines, advanced 48 cents, or 6 percent, to
8.55 euros after seven steel manufacturers, including U.S. Steel
Corp., filed a petition with U.S. trade agencies accusing China
of illegally dumping pipes used to extract oil and gas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Positive anti-dumping ruling could help volumes in
2010,&#8221; Frank McGann and Shariff Koya, analysts at Bank of
America Corp. who rates Tenaris a &#8220;buy,&#8221; wrote in a note. They
added that &#8220;an expected recovery in oil prices from late 2009
through 2011 should set the stage for better earnings trends.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tod&#8217;s SpA (TOD)  gained 1.5 euros, or 4.4 percent, to
35.7 euros. The Italian luxury-goods maker known for its rubber-studded driving shoe had its price estimate increased to 40
euros from 36 euros at Societe Generale SA and to 32.5 euros
from 27.8 euros at Citigroup Inc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trevisan Cometal SpA (TRV IM) climbed 21.7 cents, or 28
percent, to 99.9 cents, the steepest gain since its 2003
listing. The aluminum coatings and engineering company said in a
statement today that initial negotiations with banks have taken
place in relation to a moratorium agreement concerning existing
credit lines. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UniCredit SpA (UCG)  rose to the highest in almost three
months, adding 8.4 cents, or 5.3 percent, to 1.68 euros. Equita
Sim SpA increased the weighting of Italy&#8217;s largest bank in its
recommended portfolio. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Elizabeth Amon" date="May 01, 2009  9:23 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-05-01/citigroup-jpmorgan-chrysler-madoff-in-court-news-update1-.html"><headline>Citigroup, JPMorgan, Chrysler, Madoff in Court News</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Former Citigroup Inc. (C) investment
banker Maher Kara was sued for insider trading by U.S.
regulators who claim he fed tips on health-care industry deals
to people who reaped more than $6 million in illegal profits. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kara, 37, once a director in Citigroup Global Markets&#8217;
health-care group in New York, told his brother Michael Kara
about transactions, including takeovers of Andrx Corp. in 2006
and Biosite Inc. in 2007, the Securities and Exchange Commission
said in a lawsuit at federal court in San Francisco yesterday.
Michael Kara, 48, used nonpublic information to bet on more than
20 firms involved in dealings with his brother&#8217;s group and
spread the tips to friends and family members, the agency said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;These individuals netted millions of dollars in illegal
windfall profits by trading on confidential information they
knew was obtained improperly,&#8221; Marc Fagel, the head of the
SEC&#8217;s San Francisco office, said in the statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The federal case is at least the second this year targeting
an alleged insider-trading ring tied to Wall Street. In
February, the SEC and prosecutors in Manhattan accused UBS AG (UBSN)
and Blackstone Group LP (BX) takeover advisers of feeding
confidential information to a network of people, including a
former money manager. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Maher Kara is innocent and looks forward to his
vindication at trial,&#8221; said his attorney, Carl Loewenson, in an
e-mailed statement. John Kirke, a lawyer representing Michael
Kara, didn&#8217;t immediately return a phone call seeking comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Citi cooperated fully with the authorities during this
investigation,&#8221; spokeswoman Danielle Romero-Apsilos said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is SEC v. Maher Kara, 09-1880, U.S. District
Court, San Francisco. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To read more of this story, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;MBIA Sues Merrill Lynch Over Subprime-Debt Protection &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MBIA Inc. (MBI), the largest bond insurer, said two of its units
sued two Merrill Lynch  Co. businesses now owned by Bank of
America Corp. (BAC) over protection sold against mortgage-debt
defaults. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lawsuit, filed in New York State Supreme Court, seeks
to unwind or recover payouts for $5.7 billion of credit-default
swaps and related insurance sold against collateralized debt
obligations, Armonk, New York-based MBIA said yesterday in a
statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merrill Lynch misrepresented the nature of the debt being
protected as part of a &#8220;deliberate strategy to offload&#8221;
billions of dollars of &#8220;deteriorating&#8221; subprime mortgages
between July 2006 and March 2007, as homeowner defaults began to
soar, the insurer said in the statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Today&#8217;s action is consistent with our intention to pursue
all available remedies against those parties whose improper
actions have directly resulted in substantial losses for MBIA
and its shareholders,&#8221; MBIA Chief Executive Officer Jay Brown
said in the statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;William Halldin, a spokesman for Charlotte, North Carolina-based Bank of America, declined to comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bond insurers including MBIA and Ambac Financial Group Inc.
have sued banks including JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) and GMAC LLC over
the quality of the home-loan securities they agreed to back.
Those suits have generally involved mortgage-backed bonds, not
the CDOs tied to them. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is MBIA Insurance Corp and LaCrosse Financial
Products LLC v. Merrill Lynch, Pierce, Fenner and Smith Inc. and
Merrill Lynch International, 09601324, Supreme Court of New York
(Manhattan). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To read more of this story, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Citadel&#8217;s Edsparr Sues JPMorgan in London Over Bonus &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JPMorgan Chase  Co. was sued for $2.3 million by former
executive committee member Patrik Edsparr over an unpaid bonus
payment in the latest dispute involving a group of senior
managers who left the bank last year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edsparr, 43, said in a lawsuit filed this month that
JPMorgan&#8217;s London unit refused to pay a deferred bonus after he
left the bank to work at Citadel Investment Group LLC. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JPMorgan, the second-biggest U.S. bank, last year sued
executive search firm IDW Group over the hiring of Edsparr and
three other bank executives by Citadel. It also stopped trading
with Citadel for a day last year before reaching an agreement
with the hedge fund over the departures. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edsparr resigned in March 2008 to become global fixed-income head and European CEO of Citadel, the Chicago-based
hedge-fund firm founded by Kenneth Griffin. At JPMorgan he had
been on the executive committee and ran businesses including
foreign exchange, securitized products and principal
investments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;David Wells, a spokesman for New York-based JPMorgan,
declined to comment. Roberto Moruzzi, Edsparr&#8217;s lawyer, said he
couldn&#8217;t immediately comment when contacted by phone yesterday.
Edsparr didn&#8217;t respond to an e-mail seeking comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edsparr claims that JPMorgan first halved, and then refused
to pay an expected $5 million bonus that vested in January 2007
for payment this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JPMorgan sent Edsparr a letter in December saying that
because of the performance of the business and changes in the
level of the London interbank offered rate, or Libor, the
payment had been reduced to about $2.3 million, according to the
lawsuit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On March 25, JPMorgan attorneys in New York contacted him
saying they planned to pay him nothing due to &#8220;an
unparticularized allegation of violation of non-solicitation
agreements contained in unidentified agreements&#8221; with the bank,
the filing said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Edsparr v. JPMorgan, High Court of Justice,
Queen&#8217;s Bench Division, HQ09X01552. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Chrysler Files for Bankruptcy to Seal Fiat Accord &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chrysler LLC, the automaker that survived a near-death
experience in 1979, filed yesterday for bankruptcy protection to
streamline operations and shed debt in a reorganization that
includes Italy&#8217;s Fiat SpA (F) as a partner. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The third biggest among U.S. automakers missed a U.S.
government deadline to come up with a restructuring plan by
yesterday that was rigorous enough to avoid bankruptcy and
qualify for more bailout aid. The carmaker tried to negotiate an
alliance with Fiat, reduce $6.9 billion in secured loans and cut
$10.6 billion owed to a pension fund. Some lenders refused to
slash the debt to $2.25 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The carmaker and the government plan to use the bankruptcy
process to revitalize Chrysler by putting its best assets, such
as its Jeep and Dodge Ram brands, in a new company that wouldn&#8217;t
be burdened by current costs and debt. A slimmed-down version of
Chrysler, armed with Fiat&#8217;s small-car technology, would emerge
from such a process, giving the carmaker a &#8220;new lease on
life,&#8221; U.S. President Barack Obama said yesterday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Bankruptcy could do a lot of good for Chrysler&#8221; by
allowing it to &#8220;shrink down to the size it needs&#8221; quickly,
said Stephen Lubben, who teaches bankruptcy law at Seton Hall
University School of Law in Newark, New Jersey. &#8220;Fiat has shown
that it knows how to turn around a troubled business.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bankruptcy can involve uncertainty and delay. Dissident
creditors intend to object to the company&#8217;s reorganization plan,
a person familiar with their thinking said. That might thwart
President Barack Obama&#8217;s goal of a &#8220;surgical&#8221; bankruptcy that
would put a viable carmaker quickly into the market. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case will be heard by Arthur Gonzalez in U.S.
Bankruptcy Court in New York. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To read more of this story, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Financier Meyer Charged in New York Pension Scandal &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saul Meyer, a partner at Dallas-based Aldus Equity
Partners, was charged in a broadening scandal over New York
pension investments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meyer was accused of violating the Martin Act, a state
business law, from January 2003 to December 2006. Aldus is an
outside consultant to public pension funds including New York&#8217;s,
prosecutors said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meyer appeared yesterday in court with his lawyer, Paul Shechtman, and was released after hearing the charge. He must
post $200,000 bail by May 4 and not travel outside New York and
Texas, Judge Barry Kamins said. He is due back in court Aug. 6. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;I learned years ago that it&#8217;s far easier for the
prosecutor to file a complaint than to prevail at a trial,&#8221;
Shechtman said in an interview after the court appearance.
&#8220;Time and the evidence will show Saul Meyer did nothing
wrong.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The accusation resulted from the two-year investigation by
state Attorney General Andrew Cuomo&#8217;s office and the U.S.
Securities and Exchange Commission into alleged illegal conduct
by placement agents who arranged for private firms to manage
city pension funds, the government said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more new suits news from yesterday, click here. For copies
of recent civil complaints, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lawsuits/Pretrial &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;UBS Says Meeting U.S. Demand Would Violate Swiss Criminal Laws &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UBS AG, responding to a U.S. lawsuit, said revealing the
names of 52,000 American customers would require it to violate
Swiss criminal laws barring such disclosures. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UBS, Switzerland&#8217;s largest bank by assets, responded
yesterday in federal court in Miami to the Feb. 19 lawsuit,
saying the U.S. action seeks to trample on Swiss sovereignty by
trying to enforce summonses from the Internal Revenue Service.
Such a request also would violate tax treaties between the U.S.
and Switzerland, according to the court filing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;The IRS now asks this court to force a Swiss financial
institution and its employees, over the express objection of the
Swiss government, to violate Swiss law by producing a massive
quantity of confidential account information located exclusively
in Switzerland,&#8221; according to the Zurich-based bank&#8217;s response. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lawsuit came one day after UBS avoided U.S. prosecution
for helping wealthy Americans evade taxes. UBS agreed to pay
$780 million in penalties, admitted it helped taxpayers hide
money in Swiss accounts, and gave the IRS more than 250 client
names. Two UBS clients have been prosecuted for tax crimes since
then, and the IRS is encouraging others to avoid criminal
charges by disclosing their offshore accounts voluntarily. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is U.S. v. UBS AG, 09-20423, U.S. District Court,
Southern District of Florida (Miami). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To read more of this story, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ex-Credit Suisse Broker Tzolov in Plea Talks With Prosecutors &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Julian Tzolov, a former broker for Credit Suisse Group AG (CSGN)
who&#8217;s accused of fraudulently selling clients subprime mortgages
linked to auction-rate securities, is trying to negotiate a plea
with prosecutors, court records show. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzolov, 35, will likely &#8220;not be proceeding to trial,&#8221; his
lawyer, Benjamin Brafman, told U.S. District Judge Jack Weinstein at an April 22 hearing in Brooklyn, New York. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;It is my expectation that the case against him will be
resolved,&#8221; Brafman told the judge, according to a transcript. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tzolov and his co-defendant, Eric Butler, 37, were
scheduled to go to trial before Weinstein on April 27. Weinstein
has rescheduled the trial to begin June 29. They are accused of
falsely telling clients their products were backed by federally
guaranteed student loans, according to a September indictment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The scheme &#8220;foisted more than $1 billion in subprime-related securities&#8221; upon customers, the U.S. Securities and
Exchange Commission said when the two men were first charged.
They allegedly said the investments were a safe alternative to
bank deposits or money-market funds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the original indictment, Tzolov and Butler were charged
with securities fraud and conspiracy. The government filed new
counts on April 1, accusing the two men of wire fraud stemming
from e-mails they sent. Both men pleaded not guilty to the new
indictment at their April 1 arraignment before U.S. Magistrate
Judge Ramon Reyes in Brooklyn. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assistant U.S. Attorney Greg Andres, who is prosecuting the
case, declined to comment yesterday about Tzolov. Brafman didn&#8217;t
return a voice-mail message left at the Brafman  Ross office
seeking comment about his client. Paul Weinstein, a lawyer for
Butler, couldn&#8217;t immediately be reached for comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is U.S. v. Tzolov and Butler, 08-CR-370, U.S.
District Court, Eastern District of New York (Brooklyn). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Hedge-Fund Adviser Arthur Nadel Pleads Not Guilty in Fraud Case &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arthur Nadel, the jailed Florida hedge-fund adviser
arrested in January, pleaded not guilty to a 15-count federal
indictment accusing him of fraud. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nadel, who is being held in prison until he posts a $5
million bond, entered his plea yesterday before U.S. District
Judge John Koeltl in New York. The indictment, which was
unsealed on April 28, also seeks to force Nadel to forfeit $360
million and property. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nadel, a money manager and founder of Scoop Management Inc.
in Sarasota, Florida, disappeared for two weeks in January after
Florida authorities began investigating investor complaints
about missing money. He was charged Jan. 21 in federal court in
New York with securities and mail fraud. Nadel, 76, surrendered
six days later in Tampa and was transferred to Manhattan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At least 350 investors in Nadel&#8217;s funds were told they had
more than $360 million in their accounts when there was less
than $125,000, prosecutors say. Assistant U.S. Attorney Maria Douvas previously said in court that Nadel took in $63.9 million
in fees and trading profits in recent years, including $45
million from 2005 to 2007. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nadel is represented by a public defender because his
assets were frozen in a civil case brought by the U.S.
Securities and Exchange Commission. Lawyer Mark Gombiner has
said the case is more complicated than it appears. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The indictment, which marks the formal filing of charges,
includes six counts of securities fraud, eight counts of wire
fraud and one count of mail fraud. Nadel faces a maximum 280
years in prison if convicted. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The criminal case is U.S. v. Nadel, 1:09-mj-00169, U.S.
District Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Third Madoff-Linked Fund Ordered Liquidated by Court &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luxembourg&#8217;s financial regulator yesterday received court
approval to liquidate Luxembourg Investment Fund, the third fund
to be dissolved in the country after disclosing losses tied to
Bernard Madoff. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Judge Christiane Junck ordered the dissolution at a hearing
in Luxembourg yesterday, appointing two liquidators &#8220;with the
widest possible powers.&#8221; Junck on April 2 also ordered the
liquidation of the LuxAlpha Sicav-American Selection and Herald
(Lux) US Absolute Return funds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three funds were among 17 funds and sub-funds forced to
suspend customer redemptions after disclosures of losses from
investments with Madoff. The regulator, the Commission de
Surveillance du Secteur Financier, in the last two months struck
the three funds from its official list, saying it would seek
their liquidation to &#8220;safeguard&#8221; investors&#8217; rights. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To read more of this story, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more lawsuits news from yesterday, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Trials/Appeals &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Grace Judge Dismisses Charges Against Second Former Executive &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The judge in the criminal trial of W.R. Grace  Co. threw
out charges against William McCaig, one of five individuals
first charged along with the company in the asbestos
contamination of Libby, Montana. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;McCaig, a former manager of operations at Grace&#8217;s
vermiculite mine in Libby, is the second defendant this week to
be dismissed from the case. On April 26, at the request of
prosecutors, U.S. District Judge Donald Molloy in Missoula,
Montana, dropped charges against Robert Walsh, a former senior
vice president. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The judge took both actions after prosecutors told the
judge they couldn&#8217;t prove their cases against the men because of
court rulings on evidence. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three men and W.R. Grace, the Columbia, Maryland-based
supplier of chemical, construction and container products, are
still on trial for the contamination of Libby, a town in
northwestern Montana. Prosecutors say asbestos-tainted
vermiculite ore sickened more than 1,200 people, hundreds of
them fatally. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is U.S. v. W.R. Grace, 05-00007, U.S. District
Court, District of Montana (Missoula). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wyeth Loss Before Supreme Court Breaks Drug Litigation Logjam &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just two months after the U.S. Supreme Court decided
patients can sue drugmakers over injuries from medicines
approved by the government, long-stalled lawsuits against
GlaxoSmithKline Plc (GSK) and Bristol-Myers Squibb Co. (BMY) are again
moving toward trials, Bloomberg News&#8217; Margaret Cronin Fisk and
Jef Feeley report. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The March 4 decision in a case on Wyeth&#8217;s nausea treatment
Phenergan broke a logjam of cases in state and federal courts.
Federal regulatory approval of a medicine and information about
side effects doesn&#8217;t shield drugmakers from claims that patients
and doctors weren&#8217;t adequately warned, the high court ruled. The
decision already affected more than 250 lawsuits involving at
least 10 companies that were in limbo before the ruling. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Glaxo this month settled two cases on claims its
antidepressant Paxil can make patients suicidal, after judges
set trials citing the Wyeth decision. A Barr Pharmaceuticals
hyperactivity-drug case is to be tried in August in federal
court in Tallahassee, Florida. And a group of Bristol-Myers
lawsuits over the blood-thinner Plavix may now proceed to trial
in federal court in Trenton, New Jersey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court decision may cost the industry &#8220;billions
of dollars,&#8221; said attorney Mark Herrmann at Jones Day in
Chicago, who defends companies in similar suits. &#8220;There&#8217;s no
way to quantify it, but the number has as many zeroes in it as
attacked Pearl Harbor.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The court, on a 6-3 vote, said U.S. Food and Drug
Administration approval of a drug doesn&#8217;t necessarily preempt
lawsuits under state law. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lawsuits include Turek v. GlaxoSmithKline, 2006-3595,
Court of Common Pleas, Philadelphia County, Pennsylvania; Van
Dyke v. GlaxoSmithKline, 05-cv-153, U.S. District Court,
District of Wyoming (Cheyenne); Schrock v. Wyeth, 5:08-cv-00453,
U.S. District Court, Western District of Oklahoma (Oklahoma
City); Munroe v. Barr Pharmaceuticals, 07-395, U.S. District
Court, Northern District of Florida (Tallahassee); Tucker v.
SmithKline Beecham Corp., 1:04-cv-01748, U.S. District Court,
Southern District of Indiana (Indianapolis); and In re Seroquel
Products Litigation, 06-MD-01769, U.S. District Court, Middle
District of Florida (Orlando). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To read more of this story, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;France Telecom Says Bundling TV Sports With Internet Is Legal &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;France Telecom SA should be able to bundle its pay-television sports channel with its high-speed Internet and
telephone services, a lawyer for the company told a Paris
appeals court yesterday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Europe&#8217;s third-largest phone company asked the court to
reverse a February commercial court ruling ordering it to stop
selling its Orange Sport channel as a package, blocking it from
gaining subscribers for soccer matches that cost it 135 million
euros ($180 million) annually to air. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case comes down to &#8220;Is a television option, within a
multiservice offer, allowed?&#8221; Hugues Calvet, a France Telecom
lawyer, said to the court. &#8220;It is absolutely legal.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;France Telecom has been criticized by rivals and regulators
for bundling its Orange Sport cable channel, where the matches
are aired, with the other services through its &#8220;Triple Play&#8221;
subscription. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company has been expanding into television through its
Orange unit and building its pay-TV services to get more revenue
from existing clients. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To read more of this story, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more trial and appeals news from yesterday, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Verdicts/Settlements &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Gen Re&#8217;s Graham Gets 12 Months for AIG Investor Fraud &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Graham, former assistant general counsel at General
Reinsurance Corp., was sentenced to 12 months in prison and
fined $100,000 for helping to defraud American International
Group Inc. (AIG) investors in 2000. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graham, 61, also must serve two years of supervised release
after prison, ruled U.S. District Judge Christopher Droney.
Graham and four other insurance executives were convicted in
February 2008 for their roles in a fraud that Droney previously
said cost AIG shareholders as much as $597 million. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Mr. Graham was aware of how harmful his conduct could be
in the market&#8221; and knew that regulators would attack the deal
if they learned of it, Droney said in federal court in Hartford,
Connecticut. &#8220;An important factor here was that Mr. Graham did
not personally gain, and his intent was not to personally gain
by the transaction.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graham was the last of five defendants sentenced for a
fraud centered on what prosecutors called a sham transaction to
inflate AIG&#8217;s loss reserves by $500 million. It preceded by
several years the recent financial crisis of New York-based AIG,
which got a bailout of $182.5 billion from U.S. taxpayers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Graham attorney Alan Vinegrad sought leniency in his
sentencing memos filed with Droney. He argued that Graham&#8217;s role
was minimal and directed by former General Counsel Timothy
McCaffrey, whom prosecutors said was an unindicted
coconspirator. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vinegrad wrote that Graham&#8217;s 35-year reputation for
integrity as an attorney &#8220;evaporated, along with his
professional existence, as a result of a few hours&#8217; work on one
transaction eight years ago.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is U.S. v. Ferguson, 06-cr-137, U.S. District
Court, District of Connecticut (Hartford). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To read more of this story, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;New York Judge Cancels Escalating Alfa Fines in Telenor Dispute &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New York Federal Court Judge Gerard E. Lynch canceled the
fines that were imposed on four companies controlled by Russia&#8217;s
Alfa Group as part of a dispute with Telenor ASA. (TEL) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fines were dropped after Alfa Group complied with the
judge&#8217;s requirements that included reducing a stake in Turkcell
Iletisim Hizmetleri AS and dismissing litigation by Ukraine&#8217;s EC
Venture, Telenor said in a statement on its Web site yesterday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is one of several court battles between Fornebu,
Norway-based Telenor and billionaire Mikhail Fridman&#8217;s Alfa
Group as they jockey for control of OAO VimpelCom (VIP), Russia&#8217;s
second-largest mobile-phone company, and Ukraine&#8217;s ZAT Kyivstar
GSM. The escalating fines threatened to cost Alfa $12 billion
annually or lead to the loss of assets if it didn&#8217;t comply with
all the requirements, according to Alfa&#8217;s Altimo unit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;We are happy that we have managed to restore corporate
governance to Kyivstar through our legal efforts in the U.S. and
look forward to running Kyivstar based on this common platform
in the future,&#8221; Jan Edvard Thygesen, who heads Telenor&#8217;s
operations in central and eastern Europe, said in the statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To read more of this story, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more verdict and settlement news from yesterday, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Litigation Departments &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Chrysler&#8217;s Lead Lawyer Is Called Best Able to Cut Deal &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The lawyer behind Chrysler LLC&#8217;s bankruptcy is a
&#8220;brilliant&#8221; strategist who is the most qualified person to cut
a deal with the automaker&#8217;s holdout lenders, said attorneys who
work with Corrine Ball regularly. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Because she is involved there is a better chance of a
deal,&#8221; attorney Margot B. Schonholtz, co-chair of restructuring
and creditor rights at the Kaye Scholer law firm in New York.
&#8220;I&#8217;d say if there is anyone who can find a solution, and if
people want a solution, she is it.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ball, with the Jones Day law firm in New York, is the lead
lawyer on Chrysler&#8217;s bankruptcy, said David G. Heiman, another
Jones Day lawyer who also is working on the case. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ball, through a Jones Day spokeswoman, declined to comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To read more of this story, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more litigation department news from yesterday, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Court News &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Souter Said to Be Retiring, Giving Obama Court Choice &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;U.S. Supreme Court Justice David Souter is planning to
retire, giving President Barack Obama his first chance to shape
the nation&#8217;s highest court, a person familiar with the decision
said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Souter, 69, a Republican appointee who became a supporter
of abortion rights and affirmative action on the court, plans to
step down when the court&#8217;s term concludes in late June or early
July, the person said. The White House was informed of his
intentions, the person said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because Souter has generally been a member of the court&#8217;s
liberal wing, his replacement isn&#8217;t likely to shift the court&#8217;s
balance on many issues. Still, by naming a younger successor,
Obama will have a chance to put his imprint on the court for
decades. White House officials didn&#8217;t immediately respond to
requests for comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obama is almost certain to nominate a woman, according to
many court watchers. Ruth Bader Ginsburg, a 76-year-old who is
being treated for pancreatic cancer, is currently the only
female justice. The president also will come under pressure to
name the first Hispanic to the high court. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Potential nominees include Elena Kagan, 49, who Obama named
to be the first female solicitor general, the administration&#8217;s
top courtroom lawyer; Sonia Sotomayor, 54, a Hispanic federal
appeals court judge in New York; and Diane Wood, 58, a federal
appeals court judge in Chicago who served with Obama on the
faculty at the University of Chicago Law school. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obama also might look to Homeland Security Secretary Janet Napolitano, 51, or Michigan Governor Jennifer Granholm, 50. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To read more of this story, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Chrysler Judge Gonzalez Steered Enron, WorldCom Cases &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chrysler LLC&#8217;s bankruptcy, a complex case that will include
the U.S. government as a key player, will be steered by the same
judge who oversaw the bankruptcies of Enron Corp. and WorldCom
Inc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;U.S. Bankruptcy Judge Arthur Gonzalez in Manhattan
yesterday was assigned to oversee the Chapter 11 case of
Chrysler, the smallest of the Big Three U.S. automakers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;President Barack Obama said the company will undergo a
&#8220;surgical&#8221; bankruptcy putting a viable carmaker quickly into
the market. Gonzalez will be responsible for balancing the
administration&#8217;s plan for a speedy emergence with the letter of
the bankruptcy code. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Gonzalez I think is harder to ruffle than a lot of
folks,&#8221; said Nancy Rapoport, a law professor at the University
of Nevada, Las Vegas and editor of a book on Enron&#8217;s collapse.
&#8220;He&#8217;s so experienced by now that if he hasn&#8217;t seen it all, he&#8217;s
seen most of it. And obviously he&#8217;s no stranger to mega-cases.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The judge declined to comment. Gonzalez has scheduled the
first hearing in the Chrysler case for 10 a.m. today in his
courtroom on the fifth floor of the federal courthouse at
Bowling Green in lower Manhattan. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gonzalez, 62, was appointed in 1995 to a 14-year term and
is up for reappointment in October. At the time he was named to
the bench, Gonzalez was the U.S. Trustee for New York,
Connecticut and Vermont. The U.S. Trustee&#8217;s Office is the arm of
the Justice Department that monitors bankruptcy cases. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is In re Chrysler LLC, 09-50002, U.S. Bankruptcy
Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To read more of this story, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;On the Docket &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Microsoft Gets June Hearing in EU Antitrust Case &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), the world&#8217;s largest software maker, will
argue against European Union charges that the company illegally
ties its Internet browser to the Windows operating system during
a hearing in June. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft will present its case during a closed-door
hearing starting June 3, said Jonathan Todd, a spokesman at the
European Commission, the EU&#8217;s antitrust authority in Brussels. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three-day proceeding will be attended by officials from
the commission and competition authorities from the 27-nation
EU. Legal and economic experts can testify on behalf of
Microsoft. Following the hearing, the commission&#8217;s hearing
officer will report to Competition Commissioner Neelie Kroes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jesse Verstraete, a Microsoft spokesman in Brussels, had no
immediate comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To read more of this story, click here. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry></news>