
<news><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jun 02, 2014  2:37 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-02/goldman-names-scherr-strategy-head-as-chisolm-retires.html"><headline>Goldman Names Scherr Strategy Head as Chisolm Retires</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) named
Stephen Scherr as the firm''s chief strategy officer to replace
Andrew Chisholm, who''s retiring after 29 years. </p>
<p>Scherr, 50, will remain head of Latin America in addition
to the new role, according to an internal memo today from Chief
Executive Officer Lloyd C. Blankfein and President Gary Cohn.
David Wells, a spokesman for the New York-based bank, confirmed
the memo''s contents. </p>
<p>Blankfein''s strategy since the financial crisis has been to
remain in the firm''s primary businesses even as some competitors
more aggressively exit areas of trading. While Goldman Sachs has
cut costs and assets, Blankfein has said he won''t risk missing
out on the opportunities of a rebound in trading activity for
short-term gains in profitability. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs earned an 11 percent return on equity last
year, higher than peers while one-third of the returns it posted
before the financial crisis. Cohn said last month that the
current environment is abnormal and features trading clients
that are the least active in years. </p>
<p>Scherr''s role will include seeking opportunities for
revenue growth even if broader market conditions don''t improve
in the near term, said a person with direct knowledge of the
assignment. </p>




Photographer: Jon Halty/Bloomberg

<p>
Stephen Scherr, global head of the financing group for Latin America at Goldman Sachs  Co., speaks at the World Economic Forum on Latin America 2012 in Puerto Vallarta, Mexico, on April 17, 2012. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christie Smythe" date="Jun 02, 2014  1:54 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-02/pfizer-agrees-to-325-million-settlment-over-neurontin.html"><headline>Pfizer Agrees to $325 Million Neurontin Marketing Accord</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE) agreed to pay $325
million to settle a lawsuit brought by health-care benefit
providers who claimed the drugmaker marketed the epilepsy drug
Neurontin for unapproved uses. </p>
<p>The settlement, which needs approval from a federal judge
in Boston, would end a case over claims that the company''s
Parke-Davis unit schemed to market the drug for unapproved
conditions as early as 1994. </p>
<p>The accord was disclosed in court papers filed May 30 in
Boston federal court, about six weeks after New York-based
Pfizer agreed to a $190 million settlement over Neurontin in a
separate case. </p>
<p>The Boston accord will resolve all third-party payer
claims regarding off-label promotion and state antitrust
claims over Neurontin sales, Steve Danehy, a company spokesman,
said in a statement. Pfizer didn''t admit wrongdoing, he said. </p>
<p>After more than ten years of hard-fought litigation, the
parties have reached a settlement that will bring this
litigation to a close, lawyers for the benefit firms said in a
memorandum filed May 30. </p>
<p>The companies alleged that Parke-Davis, part of Warner-Lambert Co., paid kickbacks to doctors to encourage them to
prescribe the anti-seizure drug for unapproved uses such as
bipolar and panic disorders. </p>
<p>Pfizer acquired Warner-Lambert in 2000 and deliberately
expanded the promotion of off-label uses, lawyers for the
benefits firms said in an amended complaint filed in 2011. </p>
<h2>Unapproved Uses </h2>
<p>Companies including Louisiana Blue Cross/Blue Shield sought
to recover billions of dollars they paid as a result of a
scheme to market and sell Neurontin for a variety of uses for
which it is not approved or medically efficacious, according
to the complaint. </p>
<p>The drug is approved for the treatment of epilepsy and pain
from shingles or herpes zoster. </p>
<p>In the other settlement, disclosed in April, Pfizer agreed
to pay $190 million to end a suit over claims it violated U.S.
antitrust law by delaying generic versions of Neurontin. </p>
<p>The drugmaker delayed competition by improperly listing
certain patents with the U.S. Food and Drug Administration,
engaging in illegal promotion and sales of Neurontin for
unapproved uses, filing and maintaining sham litigations with
respect to certain patents, and making misrepresentations to the
patent courts, according to the 12-year-old lawsuit. </p>
<p>The marketing case is In re Neurontin Marketing, Sales
Practices and Products Liability Litigation, 1:04-cv-10981, U.S.
District Court, District of Massachusetts (Boston). The
antitrust case is In re Neurontin Antitrust Litigation, 02-cv-1390, U.S. District Court, District of New Jersey (Newark). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Boris Korby, Cristiane Lucchesi and Gerson Freitas Jr." date="Jun 02, 2014 10:22 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-02/jpmorgan-joins-morgan-stanley-in-losing-jbs-business.html"><headline>JPMorgan Joins Morgan Stanley in Losing JBS Business</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The bidding war for Hillshire Brands
Co. (HSH) is proving costly for the Brazilian bankers at JPMorgan
Chase  Co. (JPM) and Morgan Stanley. </p>
<p>After firing Morgan Stanley from a bond sale, Sao Paulo-based JBS SA (JBSS3) pulled JPMorgan from a stock offering because the
two banks are helping Tyson Foods Inc. (TSN) counter its bid for
Hillshire, two people familiar with the situation said, asking
not to be identified as the matter is private. </p>
<p>The two investment banks are advising Springdale, Arkansas-based Tyson in a $6.2 billion offer for the maker of Jimmy Dean
sausages that trumped a $5.6 billion proposal from JBS, the
world''s largest meat producer. The Brazilian company''s firing of
JPMorgan follows at least a dozen bond sales that the bank
helped manage for JBS since 2006 and a $6.3 billion takeover of
Bertin SA in 2009 where it acted as one of JBS''s advisers. </p>
<p>Tyson, the world''s No.2 meat producer, announced its bid
and said it hired the two New York-based banks two days after
JBS''s May 27 offer, saying JPMorgan is also likely to join
Morgan Stanley (MS) in providing bridge financing for the deal. </p>
<p>Jeremiah O''Callaghan, investor relations director for JBS,
declined to comment, as did Mary Claire Delaney, a spokeswoman
for Morgan Stanley, andVeronica Navarro Espinosa, a spokeswoman
for JPMorgan. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley is the No. 2 global deals adviser this year,
handling $394 billion of announced mergers and acquisitions and
trailing only Goldman Sachs Group Inc., according to data
compiled by Bloomberg. JPMorgan is fifth. </p>
<p>JPMorgan ranks second among underwriters of Latin American
dollar- and euro-denominated bonds in 2014, while Morgan Stanley
is 10th, the data show. </p>
<h2>First IPO </h2>
<p>JBS is seeking regulatory approval to sell shares of its
JBS Foods SA unit in what would be Brazil''s first initial public
offering this year. Voting shares of the unit holding JBS''s
Brazilian pork, poultry and food-processing operations will be
listed in Brazil''s Novo Mercado subject to regulatory approval
and market conditions, it said in a May 20 filing. </p>
<p>The unit was formed after JBS agreed to buy Seara food-processing assets from Marfrig Global Foods SA for 5.85 billion
reais ($2.6 billion) in June 2013. JBS hired units of JPMorgan
and Banco Bradesco for a 3 billion-real IPO of the unit, two
people with direct knowledge of the matter said in April. JBS
also hired Banco Itau BBA SA, Banco Santander SA, Grupo BTG
Pactual and Banco do Brasil SA to underwrite the share offering. </p>
<p>Wells Fargo  Co. was helping manage JBS''s planned $750
million bond sale, which the meatpacker has temporarily
withdrawn as it seeks a new leading coordinator, according to a
May 29 statement. </p>
<h2>Reviewing Options </h2>
<p>Shares of JBS rose 0.8 percent today to 7.56 reais as of
11:22 a.m. in Sao Paulo. </p>
<p>JBS has spent $17 billion on acquisitions in the past
decade to overtake Tyson in the meat industry. JBS''s Pilgrim''s
Pride Corp. unit offered $45 a share for Hillshire, compared
with Tyson''s $50 offer. </p>
<p>Following Tyson''s May 29 bid, Pilgrim''s is reviewing its
options, according to a person familiar with the matter. It''s
too early to say whether the company will raise its offer, said
the person, who asked not to be identified because the
deliberations are private. </p>
<p>The acquisition of Hillshire, potentially JBS''s largest
takeover since the acquisition of Bertin in 2009, would boost
the company''s debt levels to at least the highest in four years. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Nathan Gill and Ye Xie" date="Jun 03, 2014  2:43 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-03/goldman-sachs-gets-ecuador-gold-as-correa-steps-up-hunt-for-cash.html"><headline>Goldman Gets Ecuador Gold as Correa Steps Up Cash Hunt</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Ecuador, one of only eight countries
to adopt the U.S. dollar as its official currency, swapped gold
with Goldman Sachs Group Inc. for liquid assets in a sign the
nation is short on cash, according to Loomis Sayles  Co. </p>
<p>It does raise a red flag, Bianca Taylor, a sovereign
analyst who helps oversee $210 billion at Loomis Sayles, said
yesterday in a phone interview from Boston. Whenever a country
needs to sell or monetize its gold reserves, it''s definitely a
signal that the sovereign is strapped for cash. </p>
<p>President Rafael Correa is stepping up his search for
financing at home and abroad after borrowing more than $11
billion from China since defaulting on $3.2 billion of foreign
debt five years ago. Ecuador''s use of the dollar means it can''t
finance deficits by printing money like other countries. Correa,
a self-described revolutionary socialist, is now planning to
raise about $700 million in an overseas bond sale this year and
agreed to allow the International Monetary Fund to perform an
economic review for the first time since 2008. </p>
<p>Ecuador''s central bank, stripped of its autonomy in a
constitutional referendum a year after Correa took power in
2007, says it invested the gold with Goldman Sachs in return
for assets that can be liquidated within seven days. The country
will get the same quantity of gold back three years from now and
expects to earn a profit of $16 million to $20 million from the
deal, it said. </p>
<h2>Productive Asset </h2>
<p>The operation didn''t imply any payment of financing costs
by the central bank to Goldman Sachs, the bank said today in an
e-mailed response to questions from Bloomberg News. The central
bank said it also doesn''t need the liquidity to finance
spending. </p>
<p>Gold that was not generating any returns in vaults,
causing storage costs, now becomes a productive asset that will
generate profits, the central bank said in the statement on
its website disclosing the operation. These interventions in
the gold market represent the beginning of a new and permanent
strategy of active participation by the bank, through purchases,
sales and financial operations, that will contribute to the
creation of new financial investment opportunities. </p>
<p>The Finance Ministry said yesterday the deal wasn''t a sale
and was a normal operation of investing reserves for profit. </p>
<p>Michael DuVally, a spokesman for New York-based Goldman
Sachs, declined to comment. </p>
<h2>Puzzling Transaction'' </h2>
<p>The transaction covers 466,000 ounces of gold, according to
the central bank. That''s 1,165 gold bars, worth about $580
million at yesterday''s prices. </p>
<p>A clue to the operation came last week, when the central
bank reported a $605 million drop in its gold reserves to $493
million during the week ending May 23. Net currency reserves
rose by $434 million. At the time the central bank didn''t
explain the change. </p>
<p>It''s not clear what Goldman Sachs plans to do with the
bullion, said George Gero, a vice president and precious-metals
strategist in New York at RBC Capital Markets. </p>
<p>It''s really a puzzling transaction, Gero said yesterday
in a telephone interview. The idea that there was a large sale
and you don''t know when it will come out into the market is
probably pressuring prices. </p>
<h2>Venezuela Proposal </h2>
<p>Spot gold prices had fallen for five straight days before
today, when they rose 0.1 percent to 1,244.96 an ounce as of
2:31 p.m. in New York. They''re still down 34 percent from a peak
of $1,900.20 an ounce in September 2011. Prices have gained 3.6
percent so far this year and will fall to $1,240 by the end of
the year, according to the median estimate of 34 analysts
surveyed by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Money managers cut their net-long position, or bets on
higher gold prices, by 24 percent in the week ended May 27,
based on U.S. Commodity Futures Trading Commission data. Short
holdings, or bets on a gold-price decrease, surged 72 percent,
the most in six months, the data show. </p>
<p>Last year, Goldman Sachs proposed a swap with Venezuela to
provide $1.68 billion in cash to be backed by $1.85 billion of
gold, documents obtained by Bloomberg News showed. </p>
<p>The deal, which wasn''t completed, would have carried an
interest rate of 7.5 percent plus the three-month London
interbank offered rate. Venezuela would have kept its exposure
to gold, with the nation posting the precious metal or cash to a
margin account if the price fell and Goldman Sachs posting U.S.
dollars if it rose, the documents show. </p>
<p>Ecuador''s transaction with Goldman Sachs has nothing to
do with the proposed Venezuelan deal, the central bank said in
its e-mail today. </p>
<h2>Financing Options </h2>
<p>Ecuador will probably use the transaction proceeds to
finance public spending, said Martin Castellano, a senior
economist for Latin America at the Institute of International
Finance, a trade association of banks and money managers
including Goldman Sachs. Given the country''s use of the
greenback as its official currency, the government needs to
ensure it has enough liquidity to avoid balance-of-payment
problems, he said. </p>
<p>The measure reflects the government''s willingness to
pursue whichever financing option is at hand in order to avoid a
fiscal adjustment, Castellano said yesterday in a telephone
interview from Washington. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elizabeth Dexheimer" date="Jun 03, 2014 11:22 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-03/visa-says-cfo-pollitt-plans-to-retire-within-12-months.html"><headline>Visa CFO Pollitt Plans to Retire Within 12 Months</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Visa Inc. (V) Chief Financial Officer
Byron H. Pollitt Jr., who joined the biggest bank-card network
the year before its 2008 IPO, will retire within the next 12
months. </p>
<p>Pollitt, 62, who has been CFO for seven years, will assist
in the search for a successor and in the transition, Foster
City, California-based Visa said today in a regulatory filing. </p>
<p>Pollitt''s retirement will leave four executives remaining
on the company''s management team from before its initial public
offering: Antonio Lucio, chief brand officer; Jim McCarthy, head
of innovation and strategic partnership; Ellen Richey, chief
legal and risk officer; and head of corporate strategy Bill Sheedy. </p>
<p>Elizabeth Buse, 53, who previously ran most of the firm''s
international business, retired in March after more than 16
years at the company. </p>
<p>Pollitt previously served as CFO at Gap Inc. and Walt
Disney Co. and is a graduate of the University of California
Riverside and Harvard Business School. He received total
compensation of about $7.6 million in 2013, which included stock
awarded in prior years, according to a regulatory filing. </p>
<p>Kelly Mahon Tullier, a senior vice president at PepsiCo
Inc., will join as general counsel and a member of the firm''s
executive committee in October, Visa said in April. Former
General Counsel Josh Floum left last year to return to private
practice and was replaced on an interim basis by Richey, the
company said in December. </p>
<p>Visa fell 0.9 percent to $211.65 at 10:10 a.m. in New York
and has slid 4.8 percent this year. The shares have increased
almost fivefold since the company went public. </p>
<p>Paul Cohen, a spokesman for Visa, declined to elaborate on
Pollitt''s retirement or the firm''s succession plans. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David McLaughlin" date="Jun 04, 2014 11:03 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-04/goldman-sachs-barclays-bofa-fined-over-trading-data.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs, Barclays, BofA Fined Over Trading Data</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), Barclays
Plc and Bank of America Corp.''s Merrill Lynch unit were fined $1
million each for submitting inaccurate information about
securities trading to regulators. </p>
<p>The banks failed to provide complete and accurate
information about trading, known as blue sheet data, that
regulators use to investigate potential insider trading and
market manipulation, the Financial Industry Regulatory Authority
said in a statement today. </p>
<p>When firms fail to submit timely and accurate blue sheet
data, it compromises the ability of every regulator to identify
the perpetrators of illegal insider trading and other market
abuses, said Cameron Funkhouser, the head of Finra''s fraud
detection office. </p>
<p>Finra said the violations included submissions that failed
to include some customer names, contained incorrect names, and
failed to include some transactions. Goldman Sachs, Barclays and
Merrill Lynch each has a history of inaccurate blue sheet data,
according to the statement. </p>
<p>Michael DuVally, a spokesman for New York-based Goldman
Sachs and Bill Halldin, a spokesman for Bank of America, based
in Charlotte, North Carolina, declined comment. A spokesman for
London-based Barclays didn''t immediately respond to an e-mail
seeking comment. </p>
<p>The firms didn''t admit or deny wrongdoing. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Brian Womack" date="Jun 05, 2014  1:35 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-05/mobile-apps-to-cut-into-google-s-share-of-mobile-search.html"><headline>Mobile Apps to Cut Into Google''s Share of Mobile Search</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Google Inc. (GOOG)''s leadership in mobile
search is under pressure as cell phone and tablet users look for
information from applications rather than from their browser
query bar. </p>
<p>By 2016, Google''s share of the U.S. market should fall to
64 percent in 2016 from 83 percent in 2012, according a new
report by EMarketer Inc. Meanwhile, Yelp Inc. (YELP), whose popular
application helps users find ratings and information on local
restaurants and dry cleaners, will grow to 1.9 percent from 0.5
percent. </p>
<p>Google became the most valuable Internet company in the
world based on its desktop-based query engine. While its revenue
tied to smartphones and tablets is growing, the Mountain View,
California-based company is grappling with rising competition to
its search product on mobile devices. Spending on mobile search
is set to make up 86 percent of the U.S. digital search market
by 2018, up from 13 percent in 2012, according to EMarketer. </p>
<p>Even though browser-based search is a common behavior
among mobile owners, search engines are not necessarily the
first place smartphone and tablet users turn, Cathy Boyle, an
an analyst at EMarketer, said in the report. The explosion of
mobile app development and usage means mobile users have more --
and more specialized -- alternatives for finding information. </p>
<h2>Growing Rivals </h2>
<p>Other search products are growing as well. A category
including direct Google rivals such as Microsoft Corp. (MSFT)''s Bing,
as well as applications tailored to more specific industries,
such as e-commerce giant Amazon.com Inc., travel-focused Kayak
and job-hunting service Indeed Inc., will have 30 percent of the
market by 2016, up from 5.4 percent, according to the report. </p>
<p>While Google has its own phone- and tablet-based search
application, it gets much of its traffic through small query
boxes that appear at the top of browsers as users surf the Web.
The company has the default search engine on Apple Inc.''s iPhone
and on many devices made by partners, including Samsung
Electronics Co., that use Google''s Android operating system. </p>
<p>Google is providing a new feature on its search ads that
brings consumers directly to an application from a mobile query-results page -- instead of staying within a Web browser. So, a
user looking for a hotel in San Francisco, for example, could go
immediately to the specific page inside the installed
HotelTonight Inc. application. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tiffany Kary" date="Jun 05, 2014 10:52 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-05/jpmorgan-unit-s-mmodal-wins-approval-of-bankruptcy-terms.html"><headline>JPMorgan Unit''s MModal Wins Approval of Bankruptcy Terms</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>MModal Inc., the medical-transcription company indirectly controlled by JPMorgan Chase 
Co. (JPM), won court approval of the rough terms of a plan to
reorganize and will seek final approval July 15 to exit
bankruptcy. </p>
<p>U.S. Bankruptcy Judge Robert Grossman yesterday approved
MModal''s disclosure statement, which explains how much creditors
will get. The reorganized company is projected to earn $57
million before taxes and other items this year and $71 million a
year by 2017, enough to support its new debt load of about $320
million in secured debt, according to court papers. </p>
<p>The disclosure statement complies with the requirements
of the bankruptcy code and has enough information to allow
creditors to vote on the plan, Grossman wrote in an order in
U.S. Bankruptcy Court in Manhattan. </p>
<p>MModal, acquired by New York-based JPMorgan''s One Equity
Partners in a $1.14 billion leveraged buyout in August 2012,
filed for bankruptcy on March 20. The Franklin, Tennessee-based
company listed assets of $626.8 million and liabilities totaling
$876.3 million. </p>
<p>MModal struggled to make payments on the debt as software
and other products supplanted its transcription business, which
converts health-care providers'' dictation to text and generated
more than 80 percent of revenue. Sales fell more than 9 percent
last year to $411 million as earnings dropped almost 12 percent. </p>
<p>The company''s $250 million in 10.75 percent senior
unsecured notes due in 2020 last traded at 26 cents on the
dollar, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. They sold for
46.93 cents at the beginning of the year, on Jan. 2. </p>
<p>The case is In re Legend Parent Inc., 14-bk-10701, U.S.
Bankruptcy Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bloomberg News" date="Jun 05, 2014 10:51 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-05/ibm-cites-shanghai-airport-trust-as-cyber-tensions-climb.html"><headline>IBM Wins Shanghai Airport Cloud-Computing Contract</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines Corp. (IBM)
won a contract with China''s state-owned Shanghai Airport
Authority to use cloud computing to help move traffic more
efficiently. </p>
<p>The IBM system, the first phase of which was completed in
March, helps the airport manage everything from airplane taxi
times to passengers waiting on a concourse, the Armonk, New
York-based company said in a statement today. The system
dramatically improved the punctuality of flight departures,
according to the statement, which didn''t provide specific
figures. </p>
<p>The contract gives IBM a boost as it seeks to reverse
declining sales in China, where revenue fell 20 percent last
quarter, dragged down by declining hardware spending. U.S.
companies have also been grappling with tensions over
cybersecurity in China after U.S. prosecutors last month charged
five Chinese military officers with allegedly hacking into
computers of American companies. </p>
<p>China is reviewing whether domestic banks'' reliance on
IBM''s high-end servers compromises the nation''s financial
security, Bloomberg News reported May 27 citing people familiar
with the matter. IBM said last month it wasn''t aware of any
government policy against use of its servers. The company''s
Shanghai-based spokesman Anthony Guerrieri said today''s
announcement is unrelated to any government reviews. </p>
<h2>Shanghai Airport </h2>
<p>We are proud to be selected by Shanghai Hongqiao
International Airport as its trusted partner, Ernie Hu, IBM''s
vice president for its software group in China, said in the
statement. IBM has a long history of innovation in
transportation, working with the world''s leading airlines and
airports. </p>
<p>IBM was little changed at $184.23 at 10:10 a.m. in New
York. </p>
<p>The system supplied to the Shanghai Airport Authority,
which operates the city''s Pudong International Airport and
Hongqiao International Airport, features IBM''s DB2 data server,
and the Tivoli Directory Server and Security Identity Manager,
according to IBM''s statement today. </p>
<p>IBM Chief Financial Officer Martin Schroeter has said the
company''s challenges in China are related to the normal cycle of
upgrades for hardware such as servers. While IBM doesn''t break
out sales figures by country, 14 percent of its 2013 revenue
came from the Asia-Pacific region excluding Japan, according to
data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarmad Khan and Dinesh Nair" date="Jun 05, 2014  8:29 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-05/jpmorgan-middle-east-investment-banker-rody-yared-said-to-leave.html"><headline>JPMorgan Middle East Investment Banker Rody Yared Said to Leave</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Rody Yared, an executive director at
JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s investment bank in the United Arab
Emirates, is leaving the U.S. lender, according to two people
with knowledge of the matter. </p>
<p>Yared left the bank for personal reasons, said the people,
who asked not to be identified as the information is private. </p>
<p>A spokeswoman for JPMorgan declined to comment. Yared
previously worked for Dubai-based Shuaa Capital where he was
head of equity capital markets. </p>
<p>JPMorgan has been boosting its presence in the region by
hiring executives from banks including Nomura International Plc
and HSBC Holdings Plc. The bank appointed Declan Hegarty as
general manager of its Abu Dhabi office earlier this month. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Natalie Obiko Pearson" date="Jun 05, 2014  1:25 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-05/goldman-s-renew-orders-101-megawatts-of-suzlon-turbines.html"><headline>Goldman''s ReNew Orders 101 Megawatts of Suzlon Turbines</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>ReNew Power Ventures Pvt., majority
owned by Goldman Sachs Group Inc., has agreed to buy 101
megawatts of wind turbines from Suzlon Energy Ltd. (SUEL) </p>
<p>The 48 turbines will be delivered to the Bhesada project in
Jaisalmer district in Rajasthan state, Suzlon said in an e-mailed statement today. </p>
<p>Financial terms weren''t disclosed. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ambereen Choudhury, Julia Verlaine and Michael J. Moore" date="Jun 06, 2014  7:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-06/morgan-stanley-is-said-to-cut-london-fixed-income-traders.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Said to Cut Rates Traders Amid Slump</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) eliminated fixed-income trading jobs in London, New York and Toronto this week
because of tough market conditions, people with knowledge of the
plan said. </p>
<p>The dismissals focused on traders in foreign exchange and
interest rates, the people said, asking not to be identified as
the details are private. The cuts were made starting June 3, two
of the people said. Hugh Fraser, a spokesman for Morgan Stanley
in London, declined to comment. </p>
<p>The biggest trading banks have warned investors about a
slump in fixed-income trading activity this quarter amid low
volatility. That threatens Morgan Stanley''s quest to boost the
return on equity of its fixed-income business to 10 percent. </p>
<p>The cuts included closing the interest-rates trading desk
in Toronto, according to three of the people. The desk consisted
of four employees, said one of the people. The Toronto desk was
started in 2012, when the rates business was run by Glenn Hadden, a Canadian who left the bank earlier this year. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s fixed-income business, which is run by
Robert Rooney and Michael Heaney and overseen by Colm Kelleher,
earned at least a 10 percent ROE in three of its five units last
year, with interest rates and commodities as the laggards,
according to the bank. The firm agreed to sell part of its
commodities business to Russian company OAO Rosneft (ROSN) to boost
returns. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley, which generates more revenue from equities
trading than fixed income, was alone among major U.S. banks in
registering a trading increase during the first three months of
2014, though Chief Financial Officer Ruth Porat said in April
that she saw weakness ahead. </p>
<h2>Lower Activity'' </h2>
<p>The volumes that we talked a lot about during the first
quarter -- lower activity -- we''re continuing to see that really
does persist into the second quarter, Porat said at the time. </p>
<p>Investment-banking revenue at five of the top securities
firms may drop 7 percent on average in the second quarter as
clients cut back on fixed-income trading and margins narrow,
JPMorgan Cazenove analysts said in a note to clients on May 29. </p>
<p>Average sales from fixed-income, currencies and commodities
trading may fall about 10 percent, while revenue from advising
on deals and underwriting securities will probably rise about 1
percent, the analysts wrote. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley had 55,883 employees as of March 31, down
from 62,494 three years earlier, according to its filings. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jonathan N. Crawford" date="Jun 06, 2014  5:07 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-06/electricity-prices-fall-on-northeastern-grids-on-lower-demand.html"><headline>Power Prices Climb From Mid-Atlantic to Midwest on Higher Demand</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Spot wholesale electricity gained in
the markets stretching from the mid-Atlantic region to the
Midwest as demand surpassed forecasts. </p>
<p>Power use on the 13-state PJM Interconnection LLC network
averaged 100,582 megawatts for the hour ended at 4 p.m., up 1
percent, or 1,023 megawatts, from the forecast average for the
hour ending at 4:30 p.m., data from the grid manager showed. </p>
<p>The temperature in Washington was 80 degrees Fahrenheit (27
Celsius) at 4:30 p.m., the projected high for the day, according
to AccuWeather Inc. of State College, Pennsylvania. Analysts
typically use 65 degrees as a benchmark for weather that
requires no heating or cooling. </p>
<p>PJM''s benchmark Western hub, which includes deliveries to
Washington, gained $2.47, or 4.8 percent, to average $54.25 a
megawatt-hour in the hour ended at 4 p.m. from the same time
yesterday, grid data compiled by Bloomberg show. </p>
<p>PJM West on-peak power traded $1.60 below the Eastern hub,
compared with a discount of 79 cents yesterday and a three-month
average discount of $3.75. </p>
<p>The hub for New York City fell 37 cents, or 1 percent, to
average $35.89. </p>
<p>Spot power across Texas dropped as wind output exceeded
forecasts. For the total Electric Reliability Council of Texas
Inc. market, power declined $2.11, or 4.8 percent, to average
$41.61 a megawatt-hour for the hour ended at 3 p.m. local time. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David Glovin and Neil Weinberg" date="Jun 06, 2014  2:31 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-06/gambler-linked-to-icahn-mickelson-faced-15-million-loss.html"><headline>Gambler Linked to Icahn-Mickelson Faced $15 Million Loss</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>William Billy Walters, the Las Vegas gambler U.S. authorities are said to be investigating in connection with possible insider trading in 2011 and 2012, was at the time facing a multimillion-dollar debt to the government over a soured golf-course deal, according to court records. </p> <p>In early 2011, Walters told CBS''s 60 Minutes in a rare interview that he wagered millions of dollars on football and basketball and had never had a losing year as one of Vegas''s biggest sports bettors. Walters had a $20 million jet and seven homes, the program reported. </p> <p>Around the same time, though, Walters owed as much as $15.25 million to the Federal Deposit Insurance Corp. stemming from the 2006 sale of the Stallion Mountain golf club in Las Vegas by a company he owned, according to documents in two lawsuits reviewed by Bloomberg News. </p> <p>The buyers purchased the club using a bank loan personally guaranteed by Walters. After the buyers defaulted in 2008, Community Bank of Nevada told Walters he had to make good on the loan. When the bank failed and was taken over by the FDIC, Walters owed the money to the agency. </p> <p>In 2012, a judge ordered Walters to make a payment of $11.2 million to satisfy the loan, interest and other fees, FDIC spokesman Greg Hernandez said. Mr. Walters did pay, Hernandez said in an e-mail. </p>




Photographer: Sam Greenwood/Getty Images

<p>
Phil Mickelson looks over his shot on the 11th hole during the second round of the Memorial Tournament presented by Nationwide Insurance at Muirfield Village Golf Club on May 30, 2014 in Dublin, Ohio. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Katia Dmitrieva" date="Jun 06, 2014  2:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-06/goldman-sachs-hires-dewji-and-lipson-joins-national-vlaad-says.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Hires Dewji and Lipson Joins National, Vlaad Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Abraheem Abdulla left Canadian
Imperial Bank of Commerce where he was director of mergers and
acquisitions to become a principal at Verus Partners  Co.,
according to Vlaad and Co., a Toronto-based financial-services
recruiting firm. </p>
<p>Other moves in the Bill''s Buzz weekly newsletter
include: </p>
<p>* Gregg Reilly joined CIBC as an investment-banking analyst from
Deloitte LLP, where he was a senior accountant. </p>
<p>* Brandon Dewji left Aurora Investment Managers LLC where he was
an equity analyst for Goldman Sachs Group Inc. where he''s a
credit research analyst. </p>
<p>* Aaron Rowlatt left MGI Securities as an equity trader to take
up the same role at Industrial Alliance Insurance and Financial
Services Inc. </p>
<p>* National Bank of Canada hired Michael Lipson as an analyst for
media, technology and telecommunications from AGF Management
Ltd. where he was an analyst. </p>
<p>* Dylan Steuart joined Industrial Alliance as a financial
analyst from Jennings Capital Inc. where he was an equity
research analyst. </p>
<p>* Christopher Metrakos left Direct Energy where he was a vice
president of MA for Ontario Teachers'' Pension Plan where he''s
now a portfolio manager of the natural resources group. </p>
<p>* Tim Cowan joined Brookfield Asset Management Inc. as vice
president of the energy private equity group from Cormark
Securities Inc., where he was director of investment banking. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Caroline Chen" date="Jun 06, 2014  1:11 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-06/morgan-stanley-sees-high-yield-funds-adding-riskier-debt.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Sees High-Yield Funds Adding Riskier Debt</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Mutual funds focusing on speculative-grade bonds and loans are adding riskier debt as they search for
higher yields, according to a Morgan Stanley report today. </p>
<p>Funds surveyed by the bank were five percent overweight in
debt rated B in the first quarter compared with Citigroup''s High
Yield Index, which is used as a benchmark for the broad market,
analysts led by Adam Richmond wrote in the report. The funds
were five percent underweight in higher-rated BB securities. In
2012, allocations were very much in line with the broader
market, the analysts wrote. </p>
<p>Investors are taking on more credit risk in an effort to
boost returns as central banks around the world keep interest
rates near zero. The European Central Bank yesterday lowered the
main refinancing rate to an unprecedented 0.15 percent and
annnounced new stimulus measures. Buyers have poured $23.3
billion into junk bond funds this year, EPFR Global data show. </p>
<p>Loan funds have also lowered the quality of their holdings,
which is a sign of investors reaching for yield, consistent
with what we have seen across most markets, the analysts
wrote. </p>
<p>Credits rated BB comprised 37.4 percent of the loan funds
surveyed by Morgan Stanley, compared with 41.2 percent in the
SP/LSTA Leveraged Loan Total Return Index. Lower-graded B loans
made up 55.4 percent of portfolios, compared with 51.9 percent
for the benchmark, according to the report. </p>
<p>High-yield, high-risk debt is rated below Baa3 by Moody''s
Investors Service and lower than BBB- at Standard  Poor''s. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kathleen M. Howley" date="Jun 06, 2014 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-06/walter-gains-share-in-ocwen-nationstar-rivalry-mortgages.html"><headline>Walter Gains Share in Ocwen-Nationstar Rivalry: Mortgages</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walter Investment Management Corp. (WAC),
the third-largest non-bank mortgage servicer, has been 
expanding while its bigger rivals shrink amid probes from 
regulators. </p>
<p>Walter Investment, which was spun off from a coal-mining
and homebuilding conglomerate in 2009, increased its mortgage
servicing business by 20 percent in the first quarter, according
to data compiled by Bloomberg from regulatory filings. Tampa,
Florida-based Walter Investment rose to No. 3 in the period by
surpassing PHH Corp. (PHH) </p>
<p>The business of collecting mortgage payments is undergoing
a transformation as large banks retreat from the $9.4 trillion
market and regulators investigate non-bank servicers. The two
largest non-bank operators, Ocwen Financial Corp. (OCN) and Nationstar
Mortgage Holdings Inc. (NSM), both lost market share in the first
quarter, while Walter Investment enlarged its loan holdings to
$234 billion, according to company filings. </p>
<p>The huge shift in servicing from banks to non-banks has
created a landscape that''s rapidly changing, said Karen Shaw Petrou, managing partner of research firm Federal Financial
Analytics Inc. in Washington. No one can know who the winners
and the losers will be until the dust settles. </p>
<p>Walter Investment had a 2.4 percent share of the servicing
market in the first quarter compared with Ocwen''s 4.5 percent
and Nationstar''s 3.9 percent, according to Bloomberg data. Wells
Fargo  Co. led with 18 percent. </p>
<p>Walter Investment''s stock price gained 13 percent to $28.99
from the beginning of May through June 4, exceeding the 11
percent advance by Lewisville, Texas-based Nationstar, which is
majority owned by Fortress Investment Group LLC. (FIG) Atlanta-based
Ocwen, which is controlled by billionaire founderWilliam Erbey,
gained 3.1 percent in the period. </p>
<h2>Lawsky Probes </h2>
<p>The New York Department of Financial Services is
investigating both Ocwen and Nationstar. The companies about
doubled their holdings of mortgage servicing rights, or MSRs, in
2013, according to company reports. </p>
<p>Ocwen said on Feb. 6 that the department had blocked its
deal to buy $39 billion of servicing rights from Wells Fargo. </p>
<p>It is appropriate for regulators, where warranted, to
halt the explosive growth in the nonbank mortgage servicing
industry to protect homeowners, Benjamin Lawsky, the
department''s head, said a week later in a speech in New York. </p>
<p>Lawsky also sent a letter in February to Ocwen citing his
concerns about potential conflicts of interest among four
companies headed by Erbey that provide mortgage-related services
to each other. </p>
<p>In a letter to Nationstar in March, the regulator said it
was probing the impact of the firm''s rapid growth on homeowners
and asked for data about its servicing. </p>
<h2>Ocwen Shrinks </h2>
<p>Both companies have disputed Lawsky''s comments, saying they
have better performance records than the nation''s biggest banks.
The companies are cooperating with the probes. </p>
<p>Spokesmen for Ocwen and Nationstar declined to comment for
this story. </p>
<p>Ocwen''s loan portfolio dropped 3.2 percent to $440.7
billion in the first quarter, and Nationstar''s portfolio fell
7.5 percent to $384 billion. PHH, which also manages car and
truck fleets, declined 1 percent to $225.7 billion, putting it
in fourth place. </p>
<p>Walter is buying loans, and in the last few months we''ve
seen a slowdown in the acquisitions by Ocwen and Nationstar,
said Douglas Harter, a director and servicing analyst at Credit
Suisse Group in New York. Ocwen and Nationstar will have to
adjust to a different environment where deal sizes are smaller
and there is more focus on integration. That''s going to slow
them down. </p>
<p>Two years ago, Walter Investment and other non-banks held
MSRs on less than 2 percent of U.S. home loans. Banks have been
selling these rights since the Federal Reserve began drafting
new rules in 2012 to implement an international banking
agreement known as Basel III aimed at preventing the type of
financial shock seen in 2008. </p>
<h2>New Rules </h2>
<p>The agreement increases the amount of capital banks are
required to have to hold MSRs on their books. Non-banks such as
Walter Investment are not bound by the new rules. </p>
<p>Today, non-banks control a total of about 14 percent of the
market, according to Bloomberg data. In the next two years,
banks probably will sell another $1 trillion in MSRs, according
to Harter. That would push the non-bank share to 24 percent,
according to Bloomberg data. </p>
<p>Walter Investment is also under scrutiny. In February, the
company disclosed in a filing that the Federal Trade Commission
and the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau informed it of a
possible enforcement action. The details have not been made
public. </p>
<h2>Mortgage Settlement </h2>
<p>We''re currently in discussions, said Denmar Dixon,
Walter Investment''s chief investment officer. We''d like to
find a resolution to that in the near term. Right now, we can''t
predict when that will come. </p>
<p>Joseph Smith, who oversees a $25 billion mortgage
settlement between state and federal agencies and five banks,
said in May that Green Tree Servicing LLC, a unit of Walter
Investment, didn''t use proper procedures in servicing loans it
bought last year from Residential Capital LLC, a company covered
by the agreement. The former ResCap loans make up about 14
percent of Walter''s portfolio. </p>
<p>This was our first time through the testing, said
Dixon. We are a pretty compliant shop, and highly rated. This
was layered on top of that. We will be tested again on the
metrics, and expect to pass, he said. </p>
<h2>Green Tree </h2>
<p>Compass Point Research  Trading LLC in March ranked Walter
Investment as the top performer among all loan servicers, based
on customer-complaint data from CFPB. Walter had a 0.8 percent
complaint ratio when measured against the amount of delinquent
loans in its portfolio, followed by Nationstar at 1.3 percent
and Ocwen at 2 percent. The average rate for servicers, most of
them banks, was 4.3 percent. </p>
<p>Mark O''Brien, CEO of Walter Investment, has his roots in
the homebuilding industry. He was CEO of PulteGroup Inc. in
2001, when it was known as Pulte Homes, and oversaw the $1.8
billion purchase of Del Webb that created what was then the
nation''s largest residential builder. </p>
<p>O''Brien left Pulte in 2003, saying he was retiring. In
2005, he joined Walter Industries Inc. as a director and in 2009
became head of Walter Investment when it was spun off. </p>
<p>Walter Investment has more than tripled its holdings of
MSRs under O''Brien''s leadership. Last year, the company acquired
servicing rights on more than $125 billion of mortgages from
companies including Bank of America Corp., according to Walter
regulatory filings. </p>
<p>O''Brien comes from a homebuilder background that includes
financing those home purchases and really knowing those
customers, said Credit Suisse''s Harter. It''s a good platform
for building a large-scale servicer. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Jones" date="Jun 08, 2014  7:01 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-08/jpmorgan-asset-management-hires-goldman-s-von-reiche.html"><headline>JPMorgan Asset Management Hires Goldman''s Von Reiche</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Asset Management hired
Christoph Von Reiche in a new position as head of Europe for its
institutional business. </p>
<p>Von Reiche joins JPMorgan from Goldman Sachs Asset
Management, where he was head of institutional business in
Germany and Austria, according to a statement today. He will
split his time between London and Frankfurt. </p>
<p>Mike O''Brien, the firm''s global head of institutional
business, has been building out the European business, hiring a
number of executives including James Peagam, European head of
insurance solutions, who joined from BlackRock Inc. this year. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jun 09, 2014 10:13 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-09/morgan-stanley-agrees-to-sell-transmontaigne-stake-to-ngl.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Agrees to Sell TransMontaigne Stake to NGL</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) agreed to sell its
stake in oil-transportation company TransMontaigne Inc. to NGL
Energy Partners LP for $200 million as part of the bank''s effort
to reduce capital used by the commodities business. </p>
<p>NGL, a Tulsa, Oklahoma-based propane company, will also buy
physical inventory from Morgan Stanley for as much as $550
million depending on prevailing commodity prices, a person
briefed on the terms of the agreement said today, asking not to
be named because some details aren''t public. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley is divesting physical oil businesses to 
improve returns in fixed-income trading and avoid increased 
regulatory scrutiny on banks'' ownership of those units. The 
New York-based firm agreed to sell its oil-merchanting business 
to Moscow-based OAO Rosneft in December. </p>
<p>Following this transaction, Morgan Stanley''s leading
commodities division will be leaner, more client-focused and
better aligned with the rest of the firm''s businesses, Colm Kelleher, head of the investment-banking and trading division,
said in the statement. The bank will continue to service the
supply and risk-management needs of our clients across the oil,
power and gas, and metals sectors. </p>
<p>The sale, expected to be completed in the third quarter,
will generate a gain that''s not material, Morgan Stanley said in
a statement. NGL (NGL) will also assume obligations under terminal-storage contracts. </p>
<h2>Ownership Structure </h2>
<p>The deal includes Morgan Stanley''s 100 percent interest in
TransMontaigne Inc., which is the indirect parent of
TransMontaigne GP LLC, the general partner of publicly traded
TransMontaigne Partners LP. (TLP) NGL is gaining a 19.7 percent stake
in the public company, NGL said in a separate statement. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley bought TransMontaigne Inc. in 2006 for $778
million. Since then, it has changed the structure of its
holdings and divested some pieces, including the March sale of
its Canadian terminal business for $110 million. </p>
<p>NGL, a master-limited partnership that began trading
publicly in 2011, handles shipments of oil and natural-gas
liquids, sells propane and offers water-treatment services.
Atanas Atanasov, NGL''s chief financial officer and treasurer,
didn''t immediately return an e-mail seeking comment. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tim Higgins" date="Jun 10, 2014 10:19 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-10/general-motors-bans-reporters-from-e-mailing-at-annual-meeting.html"><headline>GM Bans Reporters From E-Mailing in Annual Meeting Room</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>     June 10 (Bloomberg) -- General Motors Co., on the heels of
claiming a renewed focus on transparency, prohibited reporters
from e-mailing from within its shareholder meeting. </p>
<p>The company allowed reporters into its annual meeting while
requiring them to turn off their cellular phones in a departure
from previous gatherings. </p>
<p>Reporters were allowed to send e-mails from another room
nearby that the automaker set up at its Detroit headquarters for
the media gathered to watch the meeting on monitors. There, GM
served coffee and bagels and prohibited reporters from
photographing or videotaping the monitors. </p>
<p>The company had last week pledged to be more transparent
after the release of an internal report on why it took more than
a decade to recall 2.59 million cars linked to 13 deaths. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jun 10, 2014  6:17 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-10/morgan-stanley-crude-oil-trader-tom-o-connor-said-to-depart-firm.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Crude-Oil Trader Tom O''Connor Said to Depart Firm</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Tom O''Connor, Morgan Stanley''s (MS) head
of crude-oil trading in New York, resigned last week, according
to a person briefed on the departure. </p>
<p>O''Connor was named a managing director at the New York-based bank in 2009. The person asked to remain anonymous because
the departure wasn''t publicly announced. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley is scaling back its physical oil-trading
business, agreeing to sell a stake in oil-transportation company
TransMontaigne Inc. to NGL Energy Partners LP and its oil-merchanting business to Moscow-based OAO Rosneft. </p>
<p>Sparkspread reported the departure earlier today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jonathan D. Salant" date="Jun 10, 2014  5:51 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-10/ibm-epic-team-to-vie-for-11-billion-pentagon-it-system.html"><headline>IBM-Epic Team to Vie for $11 Billion Pentagon IT System</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM), the world''s biggest computer services provider, and Epic
Systems Corp. will team up to compete for an $11 billion project
to manage U.S. troops'' electronic health records. </p>
<p>IBM announced its plans to bid today, even before the
Defense Department formally starts the competition for the
information-technology system. Rival bids may come from
Accenture Plc (ACN) and Northrop Grumman Corp. (NOC) </p>
<p>The winner gets one of the biggest opportunities in federal
information technology, where new projects are under scrutiny
after the flawed rollout of the Obamacare website. A better
Pentagon system is needed so troops'' health records can be
shared quickly with the Department of Veterans Affairs, which is
struggling to reduce backlogs in disability claims. </p>
<p>I hope people expect results, because this is where we
show up, Andy Maner, managing partner for IBM''s U.S. federal
division, said in a phone interview. We don''t bid on
everything, but when we do, we want to change the world. </p>
<p>The Pentagon''s solicitation for the contract, possibly with
a 10-year duration, may be posted as early as next month, Maner
said. IBM, based in Armonk, New York, already has more than 100
employees working to develop a proposal, he said. </p>
<p>This has been a thing we''ve had circled for more than
three years, Maner said. </p>
<h2>Website Fixes </h2>
<p>The contract may attract bids from companies such as
Dublin-based Accenture and Falls Church, Virginia-based
Northrop, according to Brian Friel, a Bloomberg Industries
analyst. </p>
<p>The U.S. government this year turned to Accenture for help
fixing healthcare.gov, the enrollment website for the federal
health-care overhaul. The company succeeds Montreal-based CGI
Group Inc. (GIB/A), criticized for the website''s early troubles. </p>
<p>Other competitors for the Pentagon program might include
Palo Alto, California-based Hewlett-Packard Co. (HPQ) and Reston,
Virginia-based Leidos Holdings Inc. (LDOS), Friel said. </p>
<p>Northrop built the original system, which is now being
maintained by Leidos, he said. </p>
<p>The planned system, which will replace the older one, will
track U.S. forces'' health records no matter where they receive
care, whether on base, on a ship, in a military hospital or
close to combat. It will handle the health records of 9.7
million beneficiaries, including active-duty military, retirees
and their dependents. </p>
<h2>Epic''s Software </h2>
<p>Service members, their families and health-care providers
who care for them deserve the best health care our country can
provide, Carl Dvorak, president of Verona, Wisconsin-based
Epic, said in a statement. They would benefit from an
integrated system that leverages best practices from other large
and successful health-care organizations. </p>
<p>Epic''s enterprise software is widely used in the health-care industry, including by Johns Hopkins Medicine, Kaiser
Permanente and the Cleveland Clinic. </p>
<p>IBM and Epic have worked together on other health-care
projects, including for Kaiser. </p>
<p>IBM was the 51st biggest federal contractor in the fiscal
year that ended Sept. 30, receiving $1.2 billion in prime, or
direct, awards, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. The
company ranked 45th in 2012, when it had $1.5 billion in U.S.
contracts. </p>
<p>The IBM-Epic collaboration will be led by Keith Salzman, a
former Army hospital chief medical information officer who is
now IBM''s chief medical information officer, and use technology
from its Watson supercomputer, best known for beating human
contestants on the Jeopardy! TV game show. </p>
<h2>Claims Backlog </h2>
<p>The Pentagon and the Department of Veterans Affairs have
been pressured by lawmakers, White House officials and veterans
to help fix the VA''s backlog in processing disability claims.
The military has contributed to that bottleneck, some lawmakers
and the Veterans of Foreign Wars have said. </p>
<p>The Pentagon announced in May 2013 that it would build its
own electronic health-records system. Defense Secretary Chuck Hagel promised to work with the VA to develop a seamless
system. </p>
<p>The military''s plan raised concerns among lawmakers and
veterans'' organizations that had pushed the two agencies to
build a single system for current and former troops'' health
records. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jun 10, 2014  5:42 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-10/morgan-stanley-s-gorman-sees-roe-climb-next-year.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley''s Gorman Sees ROE Climb Next Year</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) will boost
profitability as it pays brokers a smaller cut of revenue and
the firm''s commodities business earns better returns following
sales of two units, Chief Executive Officer James Gorman said. </p>
<p>The company, which earned a return on equity of about 5
percent each of the past two years, has a plan to in 2015 and
beyond, sustainably drive ROE at 10 percent or higher, Gorman
said today at his bank''s investor conference in New York. He
didn''t provide a return target for this year. Last year, he said
the firm could post a 10 percent ROE by 2014 if regulators
allowed it to return a reasonable amount of capital to
shareholders through dividends and buybacks. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s shares jumped 64 percent last year as the
company increased brokerage margins and equity-trading revenue.
Gorman today laid out the potential drivers of further growth in
revenue and profitability, including additional lending, lower
cost ratios and greater payouts of capital. </p>
<p>The bank will seek to lower the compensation-to-revenue
ratio in its wealth-management unit to 55 percent or less from
58 percent in 2013, Gorman said. He also set targets of a 40
percent ratio for the New York-based firm''s investment bank and
asset-management divisions. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s commodities division eventually can more
than double its return on equity from less than 5 percent in
2012 following sales of two oil businesses, he said. ROE is a
measure of how well a firm reinvested profit to generate
additional earnings. </p>
<p>The bank announced this week an agreement to sell its stake
in oil-transportation company TransMontaigne Inc. to NGL Energy
Partners LP (NGL) for $200 million. Morgan Stanley agreed in December
to sell its oil-merchanting business to Moscow-based OAO
Rosneft. (ROSN) </p>
<p>Gorman said today he expects the Rosneft deal to be
completed in the third quarter. Bloomberg News reported in April
that the two companies probably would wait to seek regulatory
approval until political tensions cooled after the U.S.
sanctioned Rosneft CEO Igor Sechin, an ally of Russian President
Vladimir Putin, over the turmoil in Ukraine. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Simon Kennedy" date="Jun 10, 2014 10:58 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-10/goldman-shuns-new-neutral-after-doubting-new-normal-.html"><headline>Goldman Shuns New Neutral'' After Doubting New Normal''</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. didn''t buy the new normal and it''s not rushing to embrace the new neutral either. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs economists led by Jan Hatzius and Dominic Wilson are questioning the bet made last month by investor Bill Gross that Federal Reserve monetary tightening will be much less aggressive than in the past -- when it comes. </p> <p>We do not disagree that the Fed funds rate will on average be at least modestly lower over the next 20 years than it was over the 20 years preceding the crisis, New York-based economist Kris Dawsey wrote in a June 6 report. We lean towards the view that the difference will not be drastic. </p> <p>Related:</p>
Gross Says U.S. Job Growth Remains Stuck in New Normal Scenario
Gross Says ''New Neutral'' Rate Lower for Years to Come
Goldman Shuns Bonds Pimco''s Gross Favors in New Neutral''
<p>Goldman Sachs is not alone in questioning the new neutral, the level at which the Fed benchmark neither stimulates nor slows the economy. The term was coined by Bloomberg News in a March 17 report and then promoted by Gross''s Pacific Investment Management Co. It describes the view that the Fed is unlikely to raise the rate much beyond 2 percent because potential growth is weaker and debt higher than before the recession. </p> <p>Using bond yields and surveys of forecasters, Dawsey reckons investors anticipate a neutral rate of 3.8 percent, in line with the 4 percent projected by Fed officials. While Goldman Sachs still doesn''t expect the Fed to begin raising before 2016, it predicts the key rate will reach 4 percent at the end of 2018. </p>




Photographer: Jonathan Fickies/Bloomberg

<p>
In 2012, Goldman Sachs Chief Economist Jan Hatzius sided with the view that monetary stimulus could help reduce unemployment, while Bill Gross argued joblessness was permanently elevated and would only by eased at the margin by easy monetary policy. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bloomberg News" date="Jun 10, 2014  6:10 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-10/goldman-sees-china-commodity-financing-unwinding.html"><headline>China Commodity Financing Seen Declining by Goldman Sachs</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Foreign banks are projected by
Goldman Sachs Group Inc. to lend less money against commodity
inventories in China amid a probe into metals stockpiles in the
biggest consumer of raw materials. </p>
<p>Claims that single batches of copper and aluminum at
Qingdao Port were pledged as collateral for multiple loans risks
undermining a broader practice in which traders use everything
from iron ore to rubber to get funding. The investigation is
already weighing down copper prices and may curb foreign
exchange inflows to China, according to a report by Goldman. </p>
<p>The probe may affect metals stockpiles at the northeastern
port held by Citic Resources Holdings Ltd., the trader
controlled by China''s largest state-owned company said today.
Standard Chartered Plc said last week it was reviewing financing
to some companies in China and Standard Bank Group started
looking at potential irregularities with metals at Qingdao.
Citigroup Inc. said it would work closely with authorities and
warehousing companies to resolve any problems for clients. </p>
<p>The developments in Qingdao are likely to continue the
significant scaling back of FX inflows from foreign banks into
China via commodity financing business, analysts at New York-based Goldman said in the report dated yesterday. As foreign
banks reduce their exposure to Chinese commodity financing
deals, the profitability of these could be reduced
meaningfully. </p>
<h2>Price Drop </h2>
<p>Copper in London may fall to $6,200 a metric ton before the
end of this year, analysts including Roger Yuan and Max Layton
said in a report. Benchmark three-month futures on the London
Metal Exchange slumped 9.7 percent this year and traded at
$6,645 at 5:45 p.m. Shanghai time, putting them on course for
the lowest closing price since May 1. </p>
<p>Currency flows may be affected because Chinese borrowers
often use commodities as collateral to get low interest loans
from overseas lenders in dollars. They then bring the money
onshore to invest in the nation''s higher interest rate
environment before later repaying the sum. </p>
<p>Qingdao Port said in a June 6 statement that public
security authorities were probing alleged fraud involving
material held in its Dagang bonded storage area. </p>
<p>Public security authorities in Qingdao have not responded
to calls by Bloomberg News seeking comment. </p>
<p>The authenticity of warehouse receipts is critical to the
practice of inventory financing in bonded warehouses, Barclays
Plc analyst Sijin Cheng wrote in a report last week. Feedback
from trading house contacts suggests that this investigation has
cast a pall on the financing trade as a whole. </p>
<h2>Port Shares </h2>
<p>Shares (6198) of Qingdao Port International Co., which listed on
the stock exchange in Hong Kong on June 5, have fallen 3.5
percent from their offer price to $HK3.63 today. </p>
<p>The investigation is into the owner of some metals and a
third party storing them in the Dagang area and not Qingdao Port
itself, according to the June 6 statement. </p>
<p>The company continues to provide regular port services to
other clients and for all metal ore products, including aluminum
and copper products, it said. </p>
<p>Separately, some Chinese banks have raised margins for
letters of credit for iron ore financing to as much as 50
percent from as much as 30 percent previously, said two people
with knowledge of the matter. </p>
<p>Others reduced overall credit available for iron ore
financing and set a cap on credit used in some locations
including Rizhao, a port located about 100 kilometers (65 miles)
southeast of Qingdao, according to the people, who asked not to
be identified because they aren''t authorized to speak publicly. </p>
<h2>Locked Gates </h2>
<p>The Dagang area has been sealed and gates to the area are
chained and padlocked, Reuters reported. The amount of metal
involved in the probe was about 20,000 tons of copper, almost
100,000 tons of aluminum ingots and about 200,000 tons of
alumina, Reuters said, citing a source it didn''t name. </p>
<p>Jiangxi Copper Co., China''s biggest smelter of the metal,
said the problems at Qingdao don''t represent a systemic risk and
won''t hurt demand or production of industrial metals. </p>
<p>As well as industrial metals, Qingdao port also handles
iron ore and agricultural commodities including cotton and
rubber. </p>
<p>Shanghai is China''s biggest port and storage center for
industrial metals. Copper inventories in bonded zones in
Shanghai were estimated to be about 815,000 tons in April by
CRU, a London-based consultant. Citrine Capital Management LLC
said in June that stockpiles in bonded warehouses across China
may be about 900,000 tons. </p>
<p>The probe will make China''s banks extremely cautious
about financing deals, though lenders will continue to help fund
shipments to end-users, Colin Hamilton, Macquarie Group Ltd.''s
head of commodities research, said June 4. </p>
<p>Some copper may be moved from China to LME warehouses in
South Korea, and possibly Singapore and Malaysia, Jeremy Goldwyn, head of business development in Asia for Sucden
Financial Ltd., said June 5. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Shannon Pettypiece" date="Jun 11, 2014  4:34 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-11/pfizer-cfo-says-astrazeneca-deal-broke-down-over-price.html"><headline>Price the Reason Pfizer-AstraZeneca Deal Died, CFO Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE) Chief Financial Officer
Frank D''Amelio said the company''s $117 billion bid for
AstraZeneca Plc (AZN) broke down over price. </p>
<p>Pfizer, the largest U.S. drugmaker, set a ceiling for how
much it would pay for London-based AstraZeneca and wasn''t
willing to go over that limit, D''Amelio said today at an
investment conference organized by Goldman Sachs Group Inc.
While New York-based Pfizer can approach AstraZeneca again after
a U.K. regulatory period ends in six months, D''Amelio said he
couldn''t comment about whether it will do so. </p>
<p>D''Amelio also said Pfizer''s attempt at a mega-merger
doesn''t rule out the possibility the company will instead break
up into smaller parts. AstraZeneca last month rejected a
takeover offer valued at 55 pounds a share. </p>
<p>In a word it was price, that kept the two companies
from sealing a deal, D''Amelio said. Any other issues that were
raised during negotiations and conversations I think we were
able to adequately, effectively address those. </p>
<p>New York-based Pfizer was seeking to lower its tax rate
through the deal by moving its official headquarters to London.
The company also sought to gain from AstraZeneca''s experimental
immune therapy cancer drugs, a new class of treatments that
would have filled a hole in Pfizer''s product portfolio.
AstraZeneca has predicted those products may help raise its
annual sales by 75 percent to $45 billion by 2023. </p>




Photographer: Simon Dawson/Bloomberg

<p>
Frank D''Amelio, chief financial officer of Pfizer Inc. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jonathan D. Salant" date="Jun 11, 2014  4:18 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-11/ibm-epic-team-vies-for-11-billion-pentagon-it-system.html"><headline>IBM-Epic Team Vies for $11 Billion Pentagon IT System</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines Corp. (IBM), the world''s biggest computer-services provider, has joined with Epic Systems Corp. to compete for an $11 billion project to manage U.S. troops'' electronic health records. </p> <p>IBM announced its plans to bid yesterday, before the Pentagon''s official start of the competition. Rival bids for the information-technology contract may come from Accenture Plc (ACN), Northrop Grumman Corp. (NOC) and Leidos Holdings Inc. (LDOS), which said today it is interested in the work. </p> <p>The winner will get one of the biggest opportunities in federal information technology, where new projects are under more scrutiny after the flawed rollout of the Obamacare website. An improved military system is needed so troops'' health records can be shared faster with the Department of Veterans Affairs, which is struggling to reduce backlogs in disability claims. </p> <p>I hope people expect results, because this is where we show up, said Andy Maner, managing partner for IBM''s U.S. federal division. We don''t bid on everything, but when we do, we want to change the world. </p> <p>The Pentagon''s solicitation for the contract, possibly with a 10-year duration, may be posted as early as next month, Maner said. IBM, based in Armonk, New York, already has more than 100 employees working to develop a proposal, he said. </p> <p>This has been a thing we''ve had circled for more than three years, Maner said. </p> <h2>Website Fixes </h2> <p>Leidos, based in Reston, Virginia, has unmatched depth and breadth of experience in commercial and government electronic health-record systems, Melissa Koskovich, a Leidos spokeswoman, said in an e-mail today when asked about the prospect of seeking the contract. </p> <p>We look forward to the opportunity to respond to the needs of this important program, she said. </p> <p>The contract might also attract bids from companies such as Dublin-based Accenture, Falls Church, Virginia-based Northrop, and Palo Alto, California-based Hewlett-Packard Co. (HPQ), according to Brian Friel, a Bloomberg Industries analyst. </p> <p>The U.S. government this year turned to Accenture for help fixing healthcare.gov, the enrollment website for the federal health-insurance overhaul. The company succeeded Montreal-based CGI Group Inc. (GIB/A), criticized for the website''s early troubles. </p> <h2>U.S. Troops </h2> <p>Northrop built the original Pentagon health-records system, which is now being maintained by Leidos, Friel said. </p> <p>The system planned to replace the older one will track U.S. forces'' health records no matter where they receive care, whether on base, on a ship, in a military hospital or close to combat. It will handle the records of 9.7 million beneficiaries, including active-duty military, retirees and their dependents. </p> <p>Service members, their families and health-care providers who care for them deserve the best health care our country can provide, Carl Dvorak, president of Verona, Wisconsin-based Epic, said in a statement. They would benefit from an integrated system that leverages best practices from other large and successful health-care organizations. </p> <p>Epic''s enterprise software is widely used in the health-care industry, including by Johns Hopkins Medicine, Kaiser Permanente and the Cleveland Clinic. </p> <p>IBM and Epic have worked together on other health-care projects, including for Kaiser. </p> <p>IBM was the 51st biggest federal contractor in the fiscal year that ended Sept. 30, receiving $1.2 billion in prime -- or direct -- awards, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p> <h2>Watson Supercomputer </h2> <p>The IBM-Epic collaboration will be led by Keith Salzman, a former Army hospital chief medical information officer who is IBM''s chief medical information officer. It will use technology from its Watson supercomputer, best known for beating human contestants on the Jeopardy! television game show. </p> <p>The Pentagon and the Department of Veterans Affairs have been pressured by lawmakers, White House officials and veterans to help fix the VA''s backlog in processing disability claims. The military has contributed to that bottleneck, some lawmakers and the Veterans of Foreign Wars have said. </p> <p>The Pentagon said in May 2013 that it would build its own electronic health-records system. Defense Secretary Chuck Hagel promised to work with the VA to develop a seamless system. </p> <p>The military''s plan raised concerns among lawmakers and veterans'' organizations that had pushed the two agencies to build a single system for current and former troops'' health records. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Carter Dougherty" date="Jun 11, 2014  1:50 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-11/mobile-financial-services-input-sought-by-consumer-bureau.html"><headline>Mobile Financial Services Input Sought by Consumer Bureau</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The U.S. Consumer Financial
Protection Bureau today said it is seeking public comment on how
consumers, especially the economically vulnerable, are using
mobile services to manage their finances. </p>
<p>We want to learn more from the American public about the
opportunities and challenges associated with mobile financial
products and services, especially as they may affect underserved
consumers, Richard Cordray, the agency''s director, said in
remarks prepared for delivery tomorrow in New Orleans. </p>
<p>In 2013, 74,000 new customers began using mobile banking
services each day, according to the bureau''s notice requesting
comment. The information CFPB gathers will be used to inform
the bureau''s consumer education and empowerment strategies. </p>
<p>Comments are due to the bureau by Sept. 11. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alan Levin" date="Jun 11, 2014 12:45 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-11/mobile-phone-use-eyed-in-i-5-bridge-collapse-ntsb-says.html"><headline>Mobile-Phone Use Eyed in I-5 Bridge Collapse, NTSB Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A safety escort ahead of the over-size truck that struck and collapsed a bridge over Interstate 5
north of Seattle last year was on the phone and didn''t radio a
warning about the structure''s height, a U.S. report shows. </p>
<p>The woman at the wheel of the pilot car told
investigators she was speaking on a mobile-phone call May 23,
2013, as the truck behind her hit a steal beam that sent the
structure plummeting into the Skagit River, according to records
released today by the National Transportation Safety Board. </p>
<p>She was watching the accident truck cross the bridge in
her rear-view and side mirrors and saw dust and the bridge
collapse, the NTSB said in a summary of an interview with the
pilot-car driver. </p>
<p>The bridge failure severed the major transportation artery
between Canada and the U.S. West Coast and sent three people
into the river, causing minor injuries. </p>
<p>The NTSB released dozens of reports, interview transcripts,
photos and other documents. The agency is planning to issue a
cause for the accident later this year. The NTSB is looking at
how the bridge height was marked, how previous bridge collisions
were investigated by state authorities and the actions of the
drivers involved, according to the records. </p>
<p>The bridge gave way about 7 p.m. after the impact fractured
a steel support beam. </p>
<h2>Bridge Repaired </h2>
<p>The structure was built using a now out-of-date design that
is vulnerable to failure if only one of its steel support
members is damaged. Current bridges are built with redundant
structures so that damage to any individual component won''t
cause a complete breakdown. </p>
<p>The driver of the truck that hit the bridge told
investigators he had to swerve to the right, where the structure
of the bridge was lower, to avoid another truck passing him,
according to the NTSB. </p>
<p>The pilot car ahead of the truck was carrying a pole about
the same height as the truck''s load so that it would serve as a
warning in case the bridge was too low. The pilot-car driver
said her pole never hit the bridge, so she didn''t warn the truck
driver, according to the NTSB. </p>
<p>A temporary span was installed in June 2013 and a permanent
repair was installed in September. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Hugh Son" date="Jun 11, 2014 12:11 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-11/jpmorgan-cfo-says-investment-bank-may-need-job-cuts.html"><headline>JPMorgan CFO Says Investment Bank May Need Job Cuts</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the world''s
biggest investment bank, may have to cut jobs and reduce
compensation if trading revenue fails to rebound as expected,
Chief Financial Officer Marianne Lake said. </p>
<p>With results holding at current levels, compensation will
come down, Lake said today at an investor conference in New
York. Then in the longer term, the question is whether we will
have too much capacity. </p>
<p>JPMorgan warned investors last month that second-quarter
fixed-income and equities trading would probably drop about 20
percent from a year earlier amid low volatility across asset
classes. Lake, 45, affirmed the New York-based bank''s forecast
today and said the slowdown appeared to be cyclical, rather than
a permanent shift. </p>
<p>Over time, we should expect to see these cyclical
headwinds abate and get replaced with tailwinds, including
stronger global economic growth and higher interest rates, Lake
said. </p>
<p>The bank''s size allows it to withstand market lulls without
overreacting, she said, while acknowledging the possibility that
job cuts could be needed over the longer term. Rivals including
Morgan Stanley have reduced staff and Zurich-based Credit Suisse
Group AG is weighing the sale of additional stakes in an
electronic interest-rates trading unit. </p>




Photographer: Jin Lee/Bloomberg

<p>
Marianne Lake, chief financial officer of JPMorgan Chase  Co. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Heesu Lee and Mark Shenk" date="Jun 11, 2014 11:36 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-11/goldman-says-keeping-u-s-oil-export-ban-to-add-value-to-economy.html"><headline>Goldman Says Keeping U.S. Oil-Export Ban Helps Economy</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A four-decade-old U.S. ban on crude
exports should remain until a saturation point when domestic
refining capacity can''t absorb increased oil production,
according to Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) </p>
<p>Maintaining the statutory curb on shipments overseas will
deliver the highest value to the U.S. economy, the bank said
in an e-mailed report today. At current extraction costs, the
export ban may start to weigh on U.S. output growth in coming
years, it predicted. </p>
<p>The Goldman view is very credible, said Sarah Emerson,
managing principal of ESAI Energy Inc. in Wakefield,
Massachusetts. Refiners are processing increasing output here
and that''s a greater benefit to the economy. </p>
<p>Rising production from shale formations has allowed the
U.S., the world''s biggest oil consumer, to import less crude,
fueling speculation that the curb on exports could be lifted. A
1975 federal law bans most shipments overseas, with only
deliveries of refined products including gasoline and diesel
allowed. Supporters of the ban say keeping U.S.-produced oil at
home helps reduce fuel prices for industry and consumers. </p>
<h2>Optimal Decision'' </h2>
<p>Keeping the ban in place would be the optimal decision
until saturation is reached to maximize the contribution of the
refining sector, said Damien Courvalin, a Goldman analyst in
New York. Once saturation is reached, it would then be optimal
to lift the ban as value added from higher production
outperforms value added from the refining sectors. </p>
<p>Uncertainty over the future of the ban is probably delaying
investment in U.S. refining capacity, according to Goldman. Oil
companies are seeking ways around it by using simple, one-step
plants capable of turning crude into products for exports. BP
Plc signed on to take at least 80 percent of the capacity of a
new $360 million mini-refinery in Houston that will process just
enough to escape the restrictions. </p>
<p>IHS Inc. last month said the ban should be lifted because
the U.S. will benefit from higher oil production and reduced
gasoline prices. The nation may save an average of $67 billion a
year from its import bill in 2016 and add 964,000 jobs by 2018,
according to the Colorado-based consultant. </p>
<h2>Premature'' Urgency </h2>
<p>The urgency of the debate has been premature, Emerson
said. We aren''t at the saturation point and won''t be for a
long time because there are a bunch of ways refiners are able to
transform these molecules and make products for export. </p>
<p>U.S. crude production rose 77,000 barrels a day to 8.46
million last week, the Energy Information Administration said
today. Output reached 8.47 million barrels a day in the week
ended May 23, the most since October 1986, according to the EIA,
the Energy Department''s statistical arm. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Isobel Finkel and Dinesh Nair" date="Jun 11, 2014  3:37 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-11/goldman-sachs-to-advise-bank-asya-on-qatar-stake-sale-talks.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs to Advise Bank Asya on Qatar Stake Sale Talks</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Asya Katilim Bankasi AS (ASYAB), the Turkish
banks in talks to sell a stake to Qatar Islamic Bank, said it
hired Goldman Sachs Group Inc (GS) as exclusive financial adviser on
the deal. </p>
<p>The Istanbul-based lender said in March that it was in
exclusive talks with QIB for a strategic partnership, while the
Doha-based bank said it was interested to take a stake in the
lender. Bank Asya, in today''s filing, didn''t give more details. </p>
<p>Merger and acquisition activity in Turkey''s banking
industry is increasing as international rivals seek to tap the
country''s economic growth. Industrial  Commercial (1398) Bank of China
Ltd. agreed to buy 76 percent of Turkey''s Tekstil Bankasi AS (TEKST) for
$316 million in April, while a Bank Asya takeover would be the
second by Qatari investors after Commercial Bank of Qatar bought
Alternatifbank AS (ALNTF) last year. </p>
<p>Bank Asya fell 2.9 percent to 1.66 liras at 10:35 a.m. in
Istanbul. It''s gained about 14 percent this year. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jun 11, 2014 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-11/morgan-stanley-sees-roe-climb-on-brokers-pay-ratio-commodities.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Sees ROE Climb on Brokers'' Pay Ratio, Commodities</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) will boost
profitability as it pays brokers a smaller cut of revenue and
the firm''s commodities business earns better returns following
sales of two units, Chief Executive Officer James Gorman said. </p>
<p>The company, which earned a return on equity of about 5
percent each of the past two years, has a plan to in 2015 and
beyond, sustainably drive ROE at 10 percent or higher, Gorman
said yesterday at his bank''s investor conference in New York. He
didn''t provide a return target for this year. Last year, he said
the firm could post a 10 percent ROE by 2014 if regulators
allowed it to return a reasonable amount of capital to
shareholders through dividends and buybacks. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s shares jumped 64 percent last year as the
company increased brokerage margins and equity-trading revenue.
Gorman yesterday laid out the potential drivers of further
growth in revenue and profitability, including additional
lending, lower cost ratios and greater payouts of capital. </p>
<p>The bank will seek to lower the compensation-to-revenue
ratio in its wealth-management unit to 55 percent or less from
58 percent in 2013, Gorman said. He also set targets of a 40
percent ratio for the New York-based firm''s investment bank and
asset-management divisions. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s commodities division eventually can more
than double its return on equity from less than 5 percent in
2012 following sales of two oil businesses, he said. ROE is a
measure of how well a firm reinvested profit to generate
additional earnings. </p>
<p>The bank announced this week an agreement to sell its stake
in oil-transportation company TransMontaigne Inc. to NGL Energy
Partners LP (NGL) for $200 million. Morgan Stanley agreed in December
to sell its oil-merchanting business to Moscow-based OAO
Rosneft. (ROSN) </p>
<p>Gorman said yesterday he expects the Rosneft deal to be
completed in the third quarter. Bloomberg News reported in April
that the two companies probably would wait to seek regulatory
approval until political tensions cooled after the U.S.
sanctioned Rosneft CEO Igor Sechin, an ally of Russian President
Vladimir Putin, over the turmoil in Ukraine. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jun 12, 2014  6:08 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-12/goldman-sachs-partners-shefter-freedman-weissman-depart.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Partners Shefter, Freedman Weissman Depart</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. partners
Daniel Shefter, who ran the corporate finance solutions group,
and Orit Freedman Weissman, the firm''s head of Israel, have left
the bank. </p>
<p>Shefter and Freedman Weissman were absent from a list of
partners released today. Shefter is now an advisory director and
Freedman Weissman agreed to become an international country
adviser for New York-based Goldman Sachs, according to internal
memos earlier this year. </p>
<p>Shefter joined the company in 1996 after working as a tax
lawyer and became a partner in 2010. Freedman Weissman started
at the firm in 1993 and established the bank''s business in
Israel a few years later. </p>
<p>David Wells, a Goldman Sachs spokesman, confirmed the
contents of the memos. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Leslie Picker" date="Jun 12, 2014  5:55 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-12/mobileiron-raises-about-100-million-pricing-ipo-at-midpoint.html"><headline>MobileIron Jumps in Debut After Raising $100 Million in IPO</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>MobileIron Inc., a maker of software
that protects data accessed by employees on smartphones, gained
in its debut after raising about $100 million in its initial
public offering </p>
<p>MobileIron, based in Mountain View, California, surged 22
percent to $11.02 at the close in New York, giving it a market
value of about $823 million. The company sold 11.1 million
shares for $9 each in its IPO yesterday, according to data
compiled by Bloomberg, after offering them for $8 to $10. </p>
<p>MobileIron is tapping the public markets during a
transitional time in the mobile-device management, or MDM,
industry. Demand for software that manages data is growing as
employees bring their own smartphones and tablets into the
workplace instead of relying on company-issued devices. However,
MDM has become a highly competitive market, causing pricing
pressure, according to MobileIron''s prospectus. </p>
<p>MobileIron has 9 percent of the MDM market, ranking fourth
among competitors, based on 2012 revenue, according to data
compiled by Bloomberg Industries from IDC. SAP AG holds the top
spot, followed by Good Technology Corp. and AirWatch LLC --
owned by VMware Inc. -- the data shows. </p>
<p>MobileIron remains unprofitable even amid revenue growth
that more than doubled in 2013 to $105.6 million, the company''s
prospectus shows. The net loss narrowed to $32.5 million last
year from $46.5 million in 2012. </p>
<p>MobileIron was among at least three technology companies
that delayed their IPOs when the market for new issues slumped,
people familiar with the matter said last month. Technology
stocks have since rebounded from a selloff. Good Technology
filed for a U.S. IPO last month. </p>
<p>MobileIron plans to use the proceeds from the IPO for
working capital, corporate expenditures and potentially to
acquire technology or complementary businesses. Morgan Stanley,
Goldman Sachs Group Inc., Deutsche Bank AG and Barclays Plc
managed the offering. </p>
<p>The stock is listed on the Nasdaq Stock Market under the
symbol MOBL. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Greg Stohr" date="Jun 12, 2014  2:37 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-12/coca-cola-must-face-pomegranate-drink-suit-court-says.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Must Face Pomegranate Drink Suit, Court Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Coca-Cola Co. (KO) must defend against
accusations that it deceived consumers about the amount of
pomegranate juice in one of its beverages, as the U.S. Supreme
Court revived a lawsuit by rival drink-maker POM Wonderful LLC. </p>
<p>The unanimous ruling gives companies a greater role in
policing competing product labels for misleading advertisements.
The justices said private parties can press false-advertising
suits under a federal law known as the Lanham Act even when the
U.S. Food and Drug Administration regulates a product. </p>
<p>The FDA does not have the same perspective or expertise
in assessing market dynamics that day-to-day competitors
possess, Justice Anthony Kennedy wrote for the court. Lanham
Act suits draw upon this market expertise by empowering private
parties to sue competitors to protect their interests on a case-by-case basis. </p>
<p>The label on Coca-Cola''s drink says Pomegranate Blueberry
Flavored Blend of 5 Juices, with the first two words appearing
in larger letters. A lower court had said FDA juice-labeling
regulations authorized the Coca-Cola product''s name. </p>
<p>POM Wonderful says the label is misleading because the
drink contains only 0.3 percent pomegranate juice and 0.2
percent blueberry juice. Apple and grape juice constitute 99
percent of the juice, POM Wonderful says. </p>




Photographer: Tish Wells/MCT via Getty Images

<p>
POM Wonderful says the label on Coca-Cola''s Pomegranate Blueberry Flavored Blend of 5 Juices, is misleading because the drink contains only 0.3 percent pomegranate juice and 0.2 percent blueberry juice. POM Wonderful is separately fighting accusations over its own advertising. In a case now pending at a federal appeals court, the Federal Trade Commission says POM is deceiving consumers with claims about the health benefits of its pomegranate drinks. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kevin Buckland and Hiroko Komiya" date="Jun 12, 2014  9:56 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-12/morgan-stanley-turns-aussie-bull-to-predict-parity-currencies.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Turns Aussie Bull to Predict Parity</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley is breaking from the
pack, becoming the first forecaster to predict Australia''s
dollar will regain parity with its U.S. counterpart. </p>
<p>Demand from Japanese investors for the world''s highest-yielding top-rated debt will help push the Aussie to $1 this
year for the first time since May 2013, Morgan Stanley
estimates, extending the 5.3 percent advance that has made it
2014''s second-best performer among Group of 10 currencies. The
median of 51 estimates in a Bloomberg strategist survey still
calls for a 5 percent drop to 89 U.S. cents by year-end. </p>
<p>The tide has turned for Aussie now that the Japanese have
come back to the market, Geoffrey Kendrick, Morgan Stanley''s
head of Asian currency and interest-rate strategy in Hong Kong,
said by phone on June 10. Their switch back into Aussie bonds
signals a turn in global long-term investor sentiment. More will
follow. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley regards Japanese investors, the biggest
holders of Australia''s long-term debt after U.S. and U.K. funds
last year, as a bellwether for the Aussie. Drawn by the Reserve
Bank of Australia''s decision to stop lowering interest rates,
Japan''s money managers have been net buyers every month this
year through April, purchasing a total of 356.4 billion yen
($3.5 billion) of the country''s sovereign debt. </p>
<h2>Opportunity Seen </h2>
<p>Compared with other developed nations, there''s still
yield to be had in Australia, Shinji Kunibe, the head of
foreign-bond management at Daiwa SB Investments Ltd. in Tokyo,
said by phone on June 10. Japanese tend to see any yen
strength as an opportunity to buy Australian assets. </p>
<p>At 3.82 percent for 10 years, Australia''s debt has the
highest yield of bonds holding top credit grades from the three
main rating companies. That''s 1.22 percentage points more than
the next-highest yield, Norway''s, and 2.43 more than German
bunds. (GACGB10) The extra returns on offer helped push foreign holdings
of Australian government debt to an all-time high of A$226
billion ($212 billion) in the first quarter. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s view on Australia''s currency carries
weight. A year ago, the U.S. investment bank had the most
bearish call in a Bloomberg survey of more than 50 strategists,
predicting a drop to 88 cents by the end of 2013, compared with
a median estimate of 97. The Aussie ended the year at 89.17. </p>
<h2>Too Strong </h2>
<p>Australia''s dollar started tumbling in April 2013 as a
slump in commodities prices hurt the economy. It has been
appreciating since reaching a 3 1/2-year low of 86.60 U.S. cents
on Jan. 24, and touched 94.14 today, its highest level in two
months. The Aussie traded at 94.23 as of 9:52 a.m. in New York,
after rising every day this week. </p>
<p>The rally saw the RBA complain last month that the currency
was high by historical standards, even as its shift to a neutral
interest-rate policy was one of the main reasons for the
Aussie''s gains. </p>
<p>With the economy improving, the central bank signaled in
February an end to two years of rate cuts that brought the
benchmark to a record 2.5 percent. A Credit Suisse Group AG
swaps index has started to indicate a small boost to borrowing
costs over the next 12 months, after signaling no increase as
recently as last week. </p>
<h2>China Threat </h2>
<p>A spike in Aussie approaching parity cannot be ruled
out, Todd Elmer, a Singapore-based strategist at Citigroup
Inc., the world''s largest currency trader, said by phone on June
10. There''s a greater risk we''ll see rate hikes sooner than
the market is pricing in, and that''s supported by stronger
economic data. </p>
<p>Citigroup sees the Aussie rising to 95 cents this year. </p>
<p>Australia''s economy grew 1.1 percent in the first quarter,
the fastest pace in two years, while the unemployment rate held
at a six-month low of 5.8 percent in May. </p>
<p>The prospect of a downturn in China, Australia''s biggest
export market, remains a threat to the Aussie, according to
Barclays Plc, which predicts a decline to 87 cents by year-end. </p>
<p>China''s economy grew 7.4 percent in the first quarter,
matching the slowest pace since 2009, while Australia''s largest
export, iron ore, fell below $100 per metric ton last month for
the first time since 2012. </p>
<p>Our view on the Australian dollar is bearish primarily
because of what we''re seeing in China, and the weakness we''re
seeing in commodity prices as a result of that, Hamish Pepper,
a Singapore-based strategist at Barclays, said by phone on June
10. Aussie at parity this year doesn''t look likely. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s Kendrick said he''s very comfortable
with his forecast for the Aussie to match the greenback''s value. </p>
<p>The probability of hitting parity this year is more than
50 percent, which is why I''m going for it, Kendrick said. If
the RBA hiked rates this year -- or even early next year -- then
my parity call would probably look too tame. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chris Dolmetsch" date="Jun 13, 2014  5:47 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-13/goldman-sachs-wins-dismissal-of-mortgage-security-suit-in-n-y-.html"><headline>Goldman Wins Dismissal of $450 Million Mortgage-Bond Suit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) won
dismissal of a suit over $450 million in residential mortgage-backed securities, with a New York judge saying that the firms
that bought the bonds should have done more research beforehand. </p>
<p>State Supreme Court Justice Charles Ramos dismissed the
claims against Goldman Sachs today, saying the investors only
reviewed data presented in offering documents for the securities
and never asked to review files for the underlying loans. </p>
<p>The true nature of the risk being assumed could,
admittedly, have been ascertained from reviewing these loan
files and plaintiffs never asked for them, Ramos wrote. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs was among financial firms including Bank of
America Corp. and JPMorgan Chase  Co. sued over more than $1.8
billion in mortgage-backed securities in 2012 by Phoenix Light
SF Ltd., a company based in Dublin that inherited claims from
six legal entities that collapsed or nearly collapsed,
according to court filings. </p>
<p>The entities include WestLB, the 180-year-old German state-owned lender, based in Dusseldorf, that ceased operations in
2012 as part of European Union conditions tied to a 17 billion-euro ($23 billion) bailout after the 2008 financial crisis,
according to a complaint. </p>
<p>Pools of home loans securitized into bonds were a central
part of the housing bubble that helped send the U.S. into the
worst recession since the 1930s. The housing market collapsed,
and the market for the securities evaporated. </p>
<h2>No Request </h2>
<p>The plaintiffs said Goldman Sachs didn''t share the files
for the loans underlying the securities. Ramos said there were
no allegations that that they asked for them and Goldman Sachs
denied access. </p>
<p>It does not matter if the failure to seek this
information was because of blind faith in the process of
origination and/or securitization, or if it was attributable to
the desire to quickly get on board of what the investors thought
was a profitable bandwagon, the judge wrote. The obligation
of a sophisticated investor to inquire cannot be merely
excused. </p>
<p>Nathan Lindell, an attorney with Robbins Geller Rudman 
Dowd LLP representing the plaintiffs in the case, didn''t
immediately respond to a phone message seeking comment on the
ruling. </p>
<p>Michael DuVally, a spokesman for Goldman Sachs, didn''t
immediately respond to an e-mail seeking comment on the ruling. </p>
<p>The case is Phoenix Light SF Ltd. v. Goldman Sachs Group
Inc., 652356/2013, New York State Supreme Court, New York County
(Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Carroll" date="Jun 13, 2014  1:21 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-13/chevron-sells-africxan-oilfield-and-pipeline-for-1-3-bln.html"><headline>Chevron Sells Africxan Oilfield and Pipeline For $1.3 Bln</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp., the world''s third-largest energy producer by market value, sold its stakes in an
African oilfield and pipeline for $1.3 billion. </p>
<p>Chevron sold a 25 percent stake in an oil concession in
southern Chad that produced about 18,000 barrels of crude daily,
the San Ramon, California-based company said in a statement
today. That equated to less than 1 percent of Chevron''s
worldwide output last year, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. </p>
<p>The transaction also involved divestiture of Chevron''s
interest in a pipeline that connects the Chadian oilfield to a
port on Cameroon''s coast. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jody Shenn" date="Jun 13, 2014  1:02 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-13/morgan-stanley-puts-mesznik-atop-mortgage-trading-teams.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Puts Mesznik Atop Mortgage Trading Teams</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) reorganized parts of
it U.S. residential-mortgage business, putting Jared Mesznik in
charge of all of its trading groups focused on the debt. </p>
<p>The changes included shifting oversight of trading in a
government-backed type of the debt known as agency mortgage
pass-throughs under Mesznik in the bank''s securitized-products
group, from its interest-rates team, according to a June 10
internal memo. Mesznik, who managed trading of agency
collateralized mortgage obligations before the moves, now
oversees trading in those two types of bonds, non-agency CMOs
and residential loans. </p>
<p>Mark Lake, a spokesman for the New York-based bank,
confirmed the contents of the memo and declined to comment
further. Mesznik joined Morgan Stanley in 2005 after attending
Brown University, according to regulatory records. </p>
<p>Brian Zakutansky, who returned to Morgan Stanley in 2012
after attending Harvard Business School and holding a Treasury
Department position similar to an internship, will continue to
lead agency pass-through trading, reporting to Mesznik,
according to the memo. </p>
<p>The shifts will also bolster collaboration between trading
desks, lending to mortgage banks and bond issuance teams,
according to the memo, signed by Jay Hallik, the firm''s global
head of securitized products, and Mitchell Nadel and Jakob Horder, global co-heads of rates. </p>
<p>We are focused on firmly establishing Morgan Stanley as a
top player in the residential mortgage space, the executives
said in the memo. This organizational change as well as
Brian''s background in housing policy and Agency MBS trading are
key to achieving this goal. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tony Capaccio" date="Jun 13, 2014 11:30 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-13/general-dynamics-lockheed-units-praised-by-u-s-navy.html"><headline>General Dynamics, Lockheed Units Praised by U.S. Navy</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Business divisions of General
Dynamics Corp. (GD), Lockheed Martin Corp. and Raytheon Co. (RTN) are among
nine recognized by the U.S. Navy as superior suppliers. </p>
<p>The  units named today by Sean Stackley, the Navy''s
assistant secretary for acquisition, will be invited by the
service to make a pitch for reduced regulation such as less
frequent inspections. An earlier version of the pilot program
dangled the prospect of more tangible post-award advantages,
such as favorable payment terms. </p>
<p>The winners were chosen based on standardized Pentagon
criteria including cost, meeting schedules, performance, quality
and business relations. They were evaluated using performance
data going back three years for about 80 business divisions of
the service''s top 30 contractors, according to service
officials. </p>
<p>The only thing this will allow them to do is to get
an invitation from us to enter into a dialog for how we
might be able to mutually improve Navy business processes and
relieve them of some requirements, Elliott Branch, Navy deputy
assistant secretary for acquisition, said in an interview. </p>
<p>We are reaching out to them: What''s your shopping list?
Let''s talk,'' Branch said. The recognition won''t give them
advantages in weapons contract awards, he said. </p>
<h2>Weapons Costs </h2>
<p>The units recognized received about 20 percent of the Navy
dollars spent in fiscal 2013 on weapons, major systems and
related research, according to service figures. </p>
<p>The Navy''s Superior Supplier Incentive program is a pilot
project under the Pentagon''s Better Buying Power initiative,
unveiled in September 2010 by Defense Secretary Robert Gates. It
was designed to reduce weapons costs, streamline the weapons-buying bureaucracy and provide incentives for companies to
improve their internal processes. </p>
<p>The business divisions recognized today are: </p>
<p>-- General Dynamics'' Marine and Combat Systems units </p>
<p>-- Lockheed (LMT)''s Mission Systems and Training </p>
<p>-- GE Aviation (GE) </p>
<p>-- Northrop Grumman Corp. (NOC)''s Aerospace Systems </p>
<p>-- Raytheon''s Integrated Defense Systems and Intelligence,
Information and Services units </p>
<p>-- Rolls-Royce Holdings Plc (RR/)''s defense aerospace unit </p>
<p>-- Lockheed and United Technologies Corp.''s joint venture
for maritime military helicopter support and repair. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tanya Angerer" date="Jun 13, 2014  1:21 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-13/goldman-warns-on-korea-bonds-as-gs-caltex-shows-demand-still-hot.html"><headline>Goldman Warns on Korea Bonds as GS Caltex Shows Demand Still Hot</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Investors in Europe and U.S. bought
half of GS Caltex Corp.''s dollar bonds this week as Goldman
Sachs Group Inc. warns demand from developed markets is making
yield premiums on top Korean names too tight. </p>
<p>The Seoul-based oil refiner is paying a 3 percent coupon on
its $400 million of notes, the lowest yet for its sales in the
U.S. currency, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. Spreads
on South Korean dollar bonds average 139 basis points more than
Treasuries this year, JPMorgan Chase  Co. indexes show, the
least since 2007, before the collapse of Lehman Brothers
Holdings Inc. and the global financial crisis. </p>
<p>Developed-market money managers'' search for yield, as well
as onshore investor demand, is making Korea''s dollar bonds a
less attractive bet, according to a June 12 Goldman Sachs
report. Spreads for top-rated non-financial companies are an
average 50 basis points more than their U.S. peers, compared
with 120 basis points about a year ago, the New York-based
investment bank said. </p>
<p>We see limited upside given the tight spreads, analysts
led by Hong Kong-based Kenneth Ho wrote. We see better value
elsewhere in Asia investment grade, even though we believe
search-for-yield motives will likely keep Korean spreads
tight. </p>
<p>Far East Horizon Ltd., part owned by China''s biggest
supplier of chemical products, Sinochem Group, is meeting
investors from today for a proposed dollar bond sale, people
familiar with the matter said, asking not to be identified
because the details are private. </p>
<h2>Sales Drop </h2>
<p>Oversea-Chinese Banking Corp. sold $1 billion of Tier 2
subordinated bonds at 175 basis points more than Treasuries
yesterday, while Goodman Hong Kong Logistics Fund borrowed $400
million at a 180 basis-point spread. The issues contributed to
the $3.3 billion of sales this week, down 36 percent from the
previous five business days, Bloomberg-compiled data show. </p>
<p>The cost of insuring corporate and sovereign bonds against
non-payment in the Asia-Pacific region climbed to the highest in
a week today, credit-default swap prices show. </p>
<p>The Markit iTraxx Asia index of 40 investment-grade
borrowers outside Japan rose 2 basis points to 105 basis points
as of 8:34 a.m. in Singapore, Standard Chartered Plc prices
show. The gauge is set for its highest close since June 5,
according to data provider CMA. On the week, it''s poised for a
3.8 basis-point climb after falling for the past six periods. </p>
<p>The Markit iTraxx Japan index increased 1 basis point to 70
as of 9:42 a.m. in Tokyo, Mizuho Securities Co. prices show. The
measure is at its highest level since June 6 and set to rise for
a fourth-straight day, the longest series of increases since
March 14, CMA data show. </p>
<p>The Markit iTraxx Australia index rose 2 basis points to
83.75 basis points as of 10:30 a.m. in Sydney, National
Australia Bank Ltd. prices show. The benchmark, on track for its
biggest one-day gain in a week, last closed higher on June 5,
CMA data show. </p>
<p>The indexes are benchmarks for insuring bonds against
default and traders use them to speculate on credit quality. A
drop signals improving perceptions of creditworthiness, while an
increase suggests the opposite. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sonali Basak and David Welch" date="Jun 16, 2014  7:01 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-16/morgan-stanley-s-valeant-e-mails-call-client-a-house-of-cards-.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley''s Valeant E-Mails Call Client a House of Cards''</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Put this in the category of, if you
can''t say something nice, don''t write it in an e-mail. </p>
<p>A few weeks ago, Morgan Stanley (MS) pitched its defense
services to Allergan Inc. (AGN), which was fighting a hostile takeover
bid from Valeant Pharmaceuticals International Inc. (VRX) Valeant was
a house of cards with an unsustainable business model,
Morgan Stanley bankers wrote in the e-mails to Allergan, which
released them yesterday. </p>
<p>Allergan decided not to hire Morgan Stanley -- while
Valeant recently did. </p>
<p>The unusual disclosure of the e-mails was intended to
bolster Allergan''s argument that Valeant is a flawed buyer --
and shows how antagonistic the battle between the two
pharmaceutical companies has become. </p>
<p>Mary Claire Delaney, a spokeswoman for Morgan Stanley,
declined to comment on the release of the e-mails. Valeant Chief
Executive Officer Michael Pearson said in an e-mail that
Allergan''s release is a sign of desperation, and we look
forward to proving the naysayers wrong. </p>
<p>The Morgan Stanley e-mails were sent to Allergan Chief
Executive Officer David Pyott and other company officers. </p>
<p>On May 13, according to Allergan, Robert Kindler, Morgan
Stanley''s global head of mergers and acquisitions, wrote that
Allergan is not being nearly aggressive enough in going after
the Valeant business model and currency. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
The e-mails from Morgan Stanley bankers were sent to Allergan Inc. Chief Executive Officer David Pyott and other company officers. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Jun 16, 2014 11:15 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-16/microsoft-unveils-machine-learning-service-for-prediction.html"><headline>Microsoft Unveils Machine Learning Service for Prediction</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) is introducing a new
Internet-based service that helps companies use data analysis to
predict behavior, in a bid to gain more customers in the fast-growing field of machine learning. </p>
<p>The service lets users more easily build algorithms to
predict purchasing patterns, electricity usage and more. The
work and results can be hosted on the Web through Microsoft''s
Azure cloud offering. The new product, dubbed Azure Machine
Learning, has been in a trial period for about a year and now
has about 100 customers testing it, said General Manager Eron
Kelly. </p>
<p>Microsoft, under new Chief Executive Officer Satya Nadella,
is trying to boost its focus on cloud software as more companies
gravitate to hosting data and other operations on the Web.
Nadella ran the cloud business before becoming CEO in February.
The Redmond, Washington-based software maker wants to bolster
usage of Azure as it tries to narrow the gap with market leader
Amazon.com Inc. (AMZN)''s Web Services business. </p>
<p>Machine learning, which is an artificial intelligence field
that involves constructing systems that automatically analyze
and learn from data, has been on the rise. Even as companies
collect more information, the challenge has been how to extract
value from it. As a result, the market for analysis software is
growing about 18 percent a year and will reach $6.5 billion by
2019, according to Transparency Market Research. </p>
<h2>Data Scientists </h2>
<p>One of the challenges is as you create more data -- data
in and itself isn''t all that valuable, Kelly said. It''s the
insights you can create from it, and as the datasets get larger,
it becomes harder to analyze. </p>
<p>Microsoft said its new product can be used by full-fledged
data scientists to speed up their work, as well as by analysts
who aren''t trained in the mathematical underpinnings of the
field. </p>
<p>Microsoft''s own retail stores are using the software to
predict fraud, while another unnamed retailer is analyzing past
customer purchases to decide future inventory, said Kelly.
Carnegie Mellon University is tracking weather patterns and
electricity usage in its buildings and has told Microsoft the
system will enable them to save 30 percent on energy, he said. </p>
<p>Microsoft will offer a public preview of the service, which
was code-named Project Passau, in July. It''s the product of work
from the company''s research unit and its data platform team,
helmed by Joseph Sirosh, a machine-leaning executive who
Microsoft hired from Amazon in July 2013. </p>
<p>Soon machine learning will help to drastically reduce
wait times in emergency rooms, predict disease outbreaks and
predict and prevent crime, Sirosh wrote in a blog post. To
realize that future we need to make machine learning more
accessible. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Paul Burkhardt" date="Jun 16, 2014  9:19 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-16/goldman-sees-no-winners-in-platinum-strike-as-final-deal-awaited.html"><headline>Goldman Sees No Winners in Platinum Strike as Final Deal Awaited</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Neither South Africa''s dominant
platinum union nor the top three producers it has targeted in an
almost five-month pay strike will emerge as winner from the
standoff, according to Goldman Sachs Group Inc. </p>
<p>The companies will be left with damage to some mines and
delays while they get their workforce back up to speed, while
the Association of Mineworkers and Construction Union will fall
short of delivering for members on their demands, Goldman Sachs
said in a June 13 note to clients. </p>
<p>Union members late last week accepted a pay proposal in
principle from Anglo American Platinum Ltd. (AMS), Impala Platinum
Holdings Ltd. (IMP) and Lonmin Plc. (LMI) The AMCU has said it has
conditions to put to the companies before agreeing to a deal. </p>
<p>We are not expecting any developments until the long
weekend is over, Alan Fine, a Johannesburg-based spokesman
representing the producers, said in an e-mail today. June 16 is
a public holiday in South Africa. AMCU Treasurer Jimmy Gama
didn''t answer a call or respond to a text message seeking
comment. </p>
<p>The union''s members have been on strike since Jan. 23 in
support of their demand to more than double basic monthly pay to
12,500 rand ($1,165). The producers'' latest offer includes wage
increases of as much as 1,000 rand. </p>
<p>AMCU members have raised conditions on issues including the
length of the agreement, back pay, increases in living-out
allowances and the reinstatement of jobs, union President Joseph Mathunjwa said at rallies last week. </p>
<h2>Slightly Improved'' </h2>
<p>We believe the deal is only slightly improved for workers
compared to the offer which was proposed within a month of the
strike, and was accepted by the union because of pressure from
members, Eugene King, a Goldman Sachs analyst, wrote in in the
note. Mines will be damaged as panels will have collapsed,
while organizing and retraining workers will take time. </p>
<p>The three companies said they have lost 22.8 billion rand
($2.1 billion) in revenue in the longest and costliest strike in
South Africa, source of about 70 percent of the global platinum
mined. </p>
<p>Lonmin will likely rebound strongly post-strike as
inventory can be converted to cash quickly and the mining
restart will see concentrate coming through in the next two
months, King wrote. Impala will be confronted by delays to new
shafts following the strike, he said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Eduard Gismatullin" date="Jun 16, 2014  7:37 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-16/exxon-chief-hails-russia-plans-alongside-sanctioned-rosneft-ceo.html"><headline>Exxon Chief Hails Russia Plans Alongside Sanctioned Rosneft CEO</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) Chief Executive
Officer Rex Tillerson talked up his company''s prospects in
Russia, appearing in Moscow alongside OAO Rosneft (ROSN) CEO Igor Sechin, who''s been sanctioned by the U.S. government. </p>
<p>Work between Texas-based Exxon, the world''s largest oil
company by market value, and state-run Rosneft on Sakhalin
Island in Russia''s Far East provides a template for further
exploration, especially in the Arctic''s Kara Sea, Tillerson said
at the World Petroleum Congress in Moscow today. </p>
<p>We look forward to taking advances achieved in the
cutting-edge success in the Far East of Russia and building on
them to unlock new supplies of oil and gas, Tillerson said. </p>
<p>Exxon Mobil is pursuing a global alliance with Rosneft even
after the U.S. imposed sanctions on Sechin, a close ally of
President Vladimir Putin, as part of a package to punish Russia
for annexing Crimea from Ukraine. The two companies plan to
drill a well in the Kara Sea later this year, targeting a
formation that could hold more than 8 billion barrels of oil. </p>
<p>All major projects this year are related to our joint
work with Exxon, Sechin, who''s banned from traveling to the
U.S., said at the same event. It''s business as usual. </p>
<p>Tillerson declined to comment on U.S. sanctions on Sechin. </p>
<p>As well as the Sakhalin project and Kara Sea exploration,
Exxon''s alliance with Rosneft includes shale exploration in
Siberia and joint venture fields in Texas. </p>
<p>The remoteness of the Arctic well -- four days voyage from
the nearest port in iceberg-prone seas -- means it will be among
the most expensive Exxon has ever drilled, costing at least $600
million. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Campbell" date="Jun 17, 2014  7:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-17/pfizer-to-at-t-made-political-footballs-in-shaky-recovery.html"><headline>Pfizer to AT&amp;amp;T Made Political Footballs in Shaky Recovery</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Amid the raft of multi-billion-dollar mergers and acquisitions this year, a new player has entered negotiations: politicians. </p> <p>Two Congressional committees are studying ATT Inc. (T)''s $48.5 billion takeover of DirecTV (DTV), while Comcast Corp. (CMCSA)''s $45.2 billion offer for Time Warner Cable Inc. (TWC) faced tough questioning last month at a House hearing. Politicians are also trying to crack down on overseas mergers intended to escape U.S. corporate taxes. Across the Atlantic, U.K. lawmakers fought Pfizer Inc. (PFE)''s shelved $118 billion offer for AstraZeneca Plc (AZN), and their French counterparts have challenged General Electric Co. (GE)''s $17 billion bid for Alstom SA (ALO)''s power assets. </p> <p>As the U.S. and Europe struggle with weak job creation and stalled wages, lawmakers are increasingly injecting themselves into announced mergers by raising concerns over layoffs or industries dominated by a few huge companies. Such attempts are putting some of the biggest transactions under the magnifying glass, and are likely to become more common, especially in high-profile industries like telecommunications and healthcare. </p> <p>Once in a blue moon, takeovers do spill into the public consciousness, and in terms of doing deals it completely changes the dynamics, said Stephen Blackshaw, a partner in London at law firm Sidley Austin LLP. There''s no doubt that we are in a wave of popular debate or outrage. </p>




Photographer: Drew Angerer/Bloomberg

<p>
Senator Carl Levin, a Democrat from Michigan and chairman of the Senate Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations. Levin has submitted a bill that would require U.S. companies seeking a so-called tax inversion to acquire a company with a market value at least 50 percent of their own, up from 20 percent currently. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael P. Regan" date="Jun 17, 2014 10:36 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-17/goldman-sachs-rating-lowest-ever-in-calm-market-casualty.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Rating Lowest Ever in Calm-Market Casualty</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The big trend among the young and
restless in New York this summer is to bash Goldman Sachs Group
Inc. interns on Yik Yak, an anonymous social-media app. The big
trend for analysts covering Goldman is to bash the stock. </p>
<p>The average rating on Goldman Sachs shares has fallen to
3.21, according to data compiled by Bloomberg that assigns a
score of 5 to ratings of buy or the equivalent, 3 to holds and 1
to sells. Apart from some similar scores earlier this year,
Goldman''s rating has never been lower in data starting in 2006. </p>
<p>Here''s a sample of the ribbing the summer associates are
taking on Yik Yak: GS interns clap when the plane lands.
Here''s a sample of what analysts are saying about Goldman Sachs:
Trading revenue from fixed income, commodities and currencies
will drop 16 percent this quarter, according to Sanford C.
Bernstein  Co.''s Brad Hintz, who on June 5 cut his second-quarter earnings estimates by 8 percent to $3.35 a share. </p>
<p>The slump in Goldman''s ratings, not to mention the 6
percent drop in its stock this year, is a casualty of the
pervasive calm that has overtaken financial markets and sent
measures of volatility in various asset classes to multi-year,
if not record, lows. Citigroup Inc. has warned of a drop of as
much as 25 percent in second-quarter trading revenue and
JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) estimated a 20 percent decline. </p>
<h2>Never Move'' </h2>
<p>As Goldman Sachs President Gary Cohn said at an investor
conference last month: What drives activity in our business is
volatility. If markets never move or don''t move, our clients
really don''t need to transact. </p>
<p>Analysts on average predict Goldman''s earnings per share
before unusual items will slide 16 percent this quarter, 2
percent next quarter and 9 percent in the final three months of
the year before rebounding 8 percent in all of 2015. </p>
<p>Goldman''s 3.21 analyst rating ranks the stock 68th among 83
financial stocks in the SP 500 and 14 percent below the average
3.72. Banks less reliant on trading revenue are faring better.
JPMorgan Chase ranks 11th among financials with a 4.3 rating;
Citigroup''s is 4.1; Morgan Stanley and Wells Fargo  Co. are
each at about 3.9. </p>
<p>For the entire SP 500, Goldman''s consensus rating ranks it
440th and 16 percent below the average of 3.84. </p>
<p>While Goldman''s shares outperformed the benchmark stock
index by more than 9 percentage points in 2013 and 28 percentage
points in 2012, its 139 percent return including dividends is
far behind the SP 500''s 220 percent return and an almost 300
percent jump for financial shares since the start of the bull
market in 2009. </p>
<p>You can''t blame the summer interns for that. Even if,
according to Yik Yak, they all wait for the light to change
before crossing the street. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri" date="Jun 17, 2014 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-17/disney-s-defunct-toontown-remade-by-unsanctioned-teen.html"><headline>Disney''s Defunct Toontown Remade by Unsanctioned Teen</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Toontown Online, loosely based on the 1988 Walt Disney Co. (DIS) film Who Framed Roger Rabbit, was a multiplayer Internet game for kids and families that drew more than 1 million users after it was introduced in 2003. </p> <p>Disney shut it down last year amid a shift away from subscription-based games. Now, it''s getting a second life thanks to fans who have created a knockoff version without the company''s permission. </p> <p>In the original game, animal characters called Toons tried to prevent the takeover of their town by corporate robots called Cogs. After Disney closed Toontown Online in September to focus on other projects, about two dozen developers, many in high school or college, created Toontown Rewritten. The site is flourishing: traffic has grown so fast that users have to wait in line to play, according to the 16-year-old project leader. </p> <p>We''re all just a bunch of nostalgic players who think that the game deserves to live a little longer, said the teenager, Joey Ziolkowski, in a telephone interview from his parents'' home in Princess Anne, Maryland. </p> <p>Whether to allow Toontown Rewritten to continue is a tricky decision for Disney. If the company lets Ziolkowski and his collaborators keep going, it builds goodwill with fans. On the other hand, Disney may want to sell the content in the future, and the company could suffer reputational damage if something bad happens to players online, according to Scott Landsbaum, a copyright attorney in Los Angeles. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
High school student Joey Ziolkowski and 24 or so others, including programmers, texture artists and composers, began working from around the world on their version of Toontown almost immediately after hearing the game was being discontinued. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Steve Matthews" date="Jun 18, 2014 11:49 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-18/goldman-s-hatzius-says-fomc-could-lift-rate-forecasts-in-dots.html"><headline>Goldman''s Hatzius Says FOMC Could Lift Rate Forecasts in Dots</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Jan Hatzius, chief economist at
Goldman Sachs Group Inc., said Federal Reserve meeting
participants could increase their forecasts for interest rates
for 2015 and 2016 from their view in March. </p>
<p>There is an economic argument for the dots to move up
slightly, Hatzius said in a Bloomberg Television interview.
The inflation numbers have been a little firmer, and the labor
market numbers have generally been good. So you could see a
slight move upward. </p>
<p>The Federal Open Market Committee, which releases its
policy statement as well as forecasts at 2 p.m. today, has
scaled back its monthly asset purchases in $10 billion
increments at four consecutive meetings since December. </p>
<p>Chair Janet Yellen, who holds a press conference today, has
said the FOMC will look at a wide range of data in determining
when to raise its benchmark interest rate from zero. At a press
conference in March, she warned against paying too much
attention to the forecasts, which are depicted as dots on a
chart. </p>
<p>A change in the composition of the FOMC might argue for
more stability and the discussion around the long-term neutral
rate is probably also a reason to expect if at all only a very
small upward move in the 2015 and 2016 dots, Hatzius said. </p>
<p>Pacific Investment Management Co. has argued central banks
will keep interest rates at a new neutral rate because of
slower global growth, with more stable top speeds. Fed officials
have lowered their long-run estimate for U.S. growth to 2.2
percent to 2.3 percent in March from 2.5 percent to 2.8 percent
in January 2010. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kyungji Cho" date="Jun 18, 2014 11:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-18/jpmorgan-bullish-as-goldman-cools-amid-debt-sales-korea-markets.html"><headline>JPMorgan Bullish as Goldman Cools Amid Debt Sales: Korea Markets</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Asset Management Ltd. and
PineBridge Investments said South Korean global corporate debt
is still attractive, even as Goldman Sachs Group Inc.
recommended shunning yield premiums near a seven-year low. </p>
<p>Borrowers have sold $20.5 billion of international bonds
this year, shy of the record $21 billion in the first half of
2012, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. Korea Gas Corp.,
Kookmin Bank and Korea National Oil Corp. are holding investor
meetings this week for possible dollar- or euro-denominated note
offerings, people familiar with the matter said. </p>
<p>South Korea''s sovereign default risk fell to a lowest since
2008 this month and the won reached the strongest in almost six
years as investors show confidence in Asia''s fourth-largest
economy, which the central bank forecasts will grow at its
fastest pace in five years in 2015. A global hunt for yield has
driven profound outperformance of Korea credit, making other
Asian bonds seem better value, Goldman Sachs wrote in a report
this month. </p>
<p>We are active participants in Korean paper, Stephen Chang, head of Asian fixed income in Hong Kong at JPMorgan Asset
said on June 12. Korean credit spread levels are still
attractive versus U.S. investment grade, he said, adding that
decisions on whether to buy new issues depend on valuations. </p>
<h2>Goldman Warning </h2>
<p>South Korean investment-grade notes yield 2.13 percent on
average, according to a Bank of America Merrill Lynch index.
That compares with 1.49 percent for corporate bonds from
developed markets, a Merrill Lynch and Pacific Investment
Management Co. measure shows. </p>
<p>The average premium for dollar bonds sold by Korean issuers
over U.S. Treasuries has contracted 37 basis points this year to
124 on June 17. It touched 121 on April 25, the least since July
2007, JPMorgan Chase  Co. indexes show. </p>
<p>The outperformance of Korea has been profound, Goldman
Sachs analysts led by Kenneth Ho wrote in a June 12 report. We
retain our negative view, because we see better value elsewhere
in Asia investment grade, even though we believe that search for
yield motives will likely keep Korea spreads tight, Ho said. </p>
<p>Investors have been seeking extra yield after rates sunk
globally as the world''s major central banks held key lending
rates near zero and enacted unprecedented monetary easing. </p>
<h2>High Quality </h2>
<p>While credit spreads of Korean bonds may look tight, the
volatility of them is also very low, Arthur Lau, head of Asia
ex-Japan fixed income at PineBridge in Kong Kong, which oversees
about $71 billion, said in June 13 interview. The high credit
quality nature of Korean bonds also appeals to many long-term
investors who are looking for stable and predictable returns. </p>
<p>The 90-day historical volatility of Korean sovereign dollar
debt maturing in April 2019 has fallen to 2.82 percent from as
high as 14.46 percent in 2009. </p>
<p>Global investors are seeking higher yields in longer-maturity bonds. The extra yield investors demand to hold 10-year
U.S. Treasuries over five-year securities contracted 38 basis
points to 91 this year, Bloomberg-compiled data show. </p>
<p>Now seems like a good time to sell long-dated dollar
bonds, Lee Sang Wook, a spokesperson for Korea Gas based in
Seongnam near Seoul, said by phone on June 17. We are
considering sales for refinancing maturing debt and possible
overseas use. </p>
<h2>Korea Oil, Kookmin </h2>
<p>Korea National Oil is mulling offshore issuance to
refinance debt, Choi Hong Seok, a spokesperson for the Anyang,
South Korea-based company, said by phone on yesterday. Kookmin
Bank declined to comment. </p>
<p>The won touched 1,015.25 per dollar, the strongest level
since August 2008, on June 10. Its 2.67 percent advance this
year is the second biggest among emerging-market currencies.
Ten-year won-denominated government bond yields have fallen 21
basis points since March 31 to 3.305 percent yesterday. </p>
<p>Credit-default swaps insuring South Korea''s sovereign debt
against non-payment for five years fell to 49.5 basis points on
June 6, the lowest close since January 2008, according to data
provider CMA. That compared with 68.5 basis points for China,
whose sovereign debt is rated Aa3 by Moody''s Investors Service,
the same as South Korea. </p>
<p>Foreign-currency corporate bond sales rose 52 percent this
year, data compiled by Bloomberg show. Demand has been driven by
onshore and offshore investors and a drop in net issuance,
Goldman Sachs said. Borrowers face more than $47 billion of
maturing offshore bonds this year, almost double the $26.7
billion in 2013, according to Bloomberg-compiled data. </p>
<p>Investors in the north-east Asian country increased
holdings of Korean paper to $20.5 billion as of end-March,
compared with $11.95 billion at the end of 2010, according to a
May statement from the Bank of Korea. </p>
<p>Supply of Korean bonds is expected to be limited this
year, PineBridge''s Lau said. There may be room for spreads
to tighten further. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore and David McLaughlin" date="Jun 18, 2014 10:37 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-18/morgan-stanley-rosneft-deal-wins-u-s-antitrust-approval-1-.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley-Rosneft Deal Wins U.S. Antitrust Approval</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley''s proposed sale of
its oil merchanting business to Russia''s OAO Rosneft won
antitrust approval in the U.S., regulators said. </p>
<p>The Federal Trade Commission announced the approval on its
website in a notice dated yesterday. The transaction still needs
approval from the Committee on Foreign Investment in the U.S.,
an inter-agency panel that examines acquisitions of companies by
foreign investors for national security concerns. </p>
<p>The two companies probably will wait until political
tensions between Russia and the U.S. cool before seeking
approval from CFIUS, a person familiar with the matter said in
April. Reviews by CFIUS can last up to 75 days. The U.S.
government imposed sanctions in April on Rosneft''s chief
executive officer, Igor Sechin. </p>
<p>The lack of hard assets such as pipelines should smooth the
approval process if the political situation eases, said the
person, who asked not to be identified because the process isn''t
public. Morgan Stanley (MS) CEO James Gorman said last week that he
expects the deal to be completed in the third quarter. </p>
<p>Mark Lake, a spokesman for New York-based Morgan Stanley,
declined to comment on whether the firm had submitted the deal
for CFIUS approval, as did a press official for Rosneft who
asked not be identified. Holly Shulman, a spokeswoman for the
U.S. Treasury Department, also declined to comment. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley, which agreed in December to sell the unit
to Moscow-based Rosneft, is divesting physical oil businesses to
boost returns in its trading unit and avoid increased regulatory
scrutiny. The firm also agreed earlier this month to sell its
stake in TransMontaigne Inc., an oil-transportation company, to
NGL Energy Partners LP. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dan Levy" date="Jun 19, 2014  6:29 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-19/jpmorgan-said-to-buy-property-in-downtown-san-francisco.html"><headline>JPMorgan Said to Buy Property in Downtown San Francisco</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)''s asset-management unit bought a San Francisco property from Jamestown
LP in a $415 million deal that includes offices, a hotel and a
development site, said two people with knowledge of the deal. </p>
<p>The purchase of 22 Fourth St. near Union Square closed
today, said the people, who asked not to be named because the
transaction is private. JPMorgan will acquire 430,000 square
feet (40,000 square meters) in two buildings known as Pacific
Place, as well as a land parcel, the people said. Tenants
include the 198-room Hotel Palomar, software maker Intuit Inc.
and retailers Old Navy, Levi''s and the Container Store. </p>
<p>Melissa Shuffield, a spokeswoman for New York-based
JPMorgan, declined to comment. Jamestown, a closely held real
estate investment firm based in Atlanta, confirmed the sale
without naming the buyer or price in a statement today. </p>
<p>San Francisco''s office market is luring property investors
after a surge in leasing demand led by technology companies
pushed rents up 70 percent since 2010, according to Jones Lang
LaSalle Inc. The metropolitan area has California''s lowest
unemployment rate at 4.3 percent and an economy that has added
jobs each month for almost five years, state labor data show. </p>
<p>It''s a very strong market, with tons of tenant activity
driving investment activity, Grant Lammersen, a sales broker
at Cushman  Wakefield Inc. with a waterfront office listing at
188 Embarcadero, said in a telephone interview. </p>
<h2>Salesforce Tower </h2>
<p>Salesforce.com Inc. in April agreed to lease 714,000 square
feet in a skyscraper being built by Boston Properties Inc. that
will be the city''s tallest and named for San Francisco-based
Salesforce, the biggest maker of customer-management software. A
unit of Shenzhen, China-based developer Genzon Property Group
Co. last month bought a majority stake in 225 Bush St. offices
in the financial district, in a deal valued at $350 million. </p>
<p>Pacific Place, two blocks from Union Square''s cluster of
upscale shops and theaters, has 202,000 square feet of offices
fully leased to Mountain View, California-based Intuit''s
Demandforce unit and 200 feet (61 meters) of retail frontage on
Market Street, Jamestown said. The area is the main transit
corridor for city buses and Bay Area Rapid Transit, or BART, the
regional subway and rail system. </p>
<p>The addition of a signature tenant like Intuit and its
long-term lease created an attractive investment for a buyer,
Jamestown Chief Operating Officer Michael Phillips said in the
statement. We remain committed to the San Francisco Bay Area
as we are very engaged in the community through our other local
properties. </p>
<p>JPMorgan buys properties on behalf of institutional
investors through its Global Real Assets business. The unit, run
by Joe Azelby, invests and manages in real estate,
infrastructure and maritime assets around the world. </p>
<p>Eastdil Secured LLC was the listing broker for Jamestown. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Mark Clothier" date="Jun 19, 2014  4:16 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-19/electric-hogs-roll-across-u-s-as-harley-tests-no-exhaust-demand.html"><headline>Hogs With Muted Growls Tour U.S. as Harley Tests e-Bikes</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Forget about the snarly Harley, the folks at Harley-Davidson Inc. (HOG) want to know what you think of a quieter Hog that whistles down the road on electric power. </p> <p>After generations of growling gasoline engines with their powerful potato-potato rumble, the Milwaukee-based motorcycle maker has come up with a green bike that runs on electricity. It''s sound is high-toned, but still very strong, said Mark-Hans Richer, the company''s chief marketing officer, sort of like a fighter jet landing on an aircraft carrier. </p> <p>Whether it''s riding by or you''re riding on it, the sound needed to have an emotional character, he said. When you hear it go by, you say, Wow. That''s cool.'' </p> <p>The motorcycle maker, whose storied highway cruisers are as loud as they are large, will take 22 electric bikes on a U.S. tour starting next week to solicit reactions that will help shape the environmentally aware vehicle''s development. Depending on the feedback, the no-exhaust Harley may never make it out of RD, said Richer. </p> <p>It''s how we like to explore product, through the eyes of our customers, he said in an interview. We couldn''t imagine this sitting on a turntable at a show with models handing out brochures. It needed to be something real, something that customers could have a first-hand experience with. </p>




Photographer: Daniel Acker/Bloomberg

<p>
A Harley-Davidson dealership in Ottawa, Illinois. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrea Jaramillo" date="Jun 19, 2014  2:45 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-19/goldman-sachs-100-year-bond-pitch-captivates-colombia.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs 100-Year Bond Pitch Captivates Colombia</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>After helping Mexico sell 100-year
bonds overseas for the first time in 2010, Goldman Sachs Group
Inc. is seeking to do the same for Colombia. </p>
<p>The Andean nation may issue the notes later this year after
the New York-based bank offered to arrange the sale, Finance
Minister Mauricio Cardenas said June 11. Goldman Sachs helped
underwrite Mexico''s offering of dollar bonds due 2110 as well as
its pound-denominated century bonds in March. </p>
<p>Colombia is seeking to exploit soaring demand for its
longer-maturity debt as its economy grows twice as fast as the
regional average and the Federal Reserve reiterates that
interest rates will stay low for a considerable time after
it stops buying bonds. Yields on Colombia''s $2 billion of bonds
due in 2044, its longest-term notes, have plunged 0.67
percentage point to 4.98 percent since they were issued Jan. 21.
That''s more than the average 0.48 percentage point decline in
long-dated bonds with the same rating. </p>
<p>Colombia shines in the midst of underperforming economies
in emerging markets, and investors are noticing, Mario Castro,
a strategist at Nomura Holdings Inc, said by phone from New
York. There''s no doubt there''s appetite for Colombia risk, and
Colombia would be getting long-term financing at still very low
yields. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs didn''t answer calls and messages seeking
comment. </p>
<h2>General Receptiveness'' </h2>
<p>Colombia would use funds from a sale to cover its 2015
financing needs, Cardenas told investors at the June 11
presentation. Goldman Sachs proposed a reference yield of around
5.7 percent for a Colombian 100-year debt offering, he said. </p>
<p>Yields on Mexico''s $2.68 billion of bonds due 2110 have
fallen 0.67 percentage point this year to 5.55 percent, data
compiled by Bloomberg show. </p>
<p>Mexico, whose BBB+ rating from Standard  Poor''s is one
level higher than Colombia''s, is the only nation to have issued
100-year notes in both dollars and pounds. China and the central
bank of the Philippines sold $100 million of century bonds in
1996 and 1997, respectively. </p>
<p>There has been a general receptiveness to longer
maturities recently, Michael Roche, an emerging-market
strategist at Seaport Group LLC, said by telephone from New
York. Institutional investors, particularly pension funds and
insurance companies, generally have a need for longer
duration. </p>
<h2>Growth Outlook </h2>
<p>Colombia''s economy will grow 4.5 percent this year,
compared with an average expansion of 2.7 percent in Latin
America, according to the median forecast in a Bloomberg survey.
The economy expanded 6.4 percent in the first quarter from a
year earlier, the national statistics agency said today, higher
than the 5.2 percent median estimate in a Bloomberg survey. </p>
<p>The peso advanced 0.4 percent to 1,882.50 per dollar at the
close today in Bogota. </p>
<p>The country''s sale of 30-year bonds in January attracted
$4.2 billion in bids, according to the government. </p>
<p>The government plans $3 billion in overseas debt offerings
next year. </p>
<p>Appetite for Colombia''s last bond sale was huge, and that
shows there definitely is willingness to invest in the
country, said Nomura''s Castro. Selling a century bond would be
another step in positioning Colombia in the international
capital market. It''s an exclusive club. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Olga Kharif" date="Jun 19, 2014 12:44 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-19/mobile-marketing-stumbles-as-pandora-plays-sf-ads-in-ny.html"><headline>Mobile Marketing Stumbles as Pandora Plays San Francisco Ads in New York</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A smartphone user who signs up for Pandora Media Inc. (P)''s downloadable app in San Francisco and then moves to New York could still be getting ads for California restaurants months later. </p> <p>Therein lies the challenge for advertisers trying to reach a specific mobile-using audience: A lot of locally targeted ads get lost along the way. </p> <p>Marketers spend as much as $2.4 billion a year on mobile ads aimed at users based on geography, and Pandora is far from the only app whose ads sometimes go awry. About 65 percent of location-targeted mobile ads are materially off from their intended location, according to research from mobile-ad network Thinknear, a unit of Telenav Inc. (TNAV) </p> <p>Local mobile ad spending is on the rise, Catherine Boyle, an analyst at EMarketer Inc., said in a phone interview. But the definition of local for one advertiser can be very different from another. It''s when you want to get into a one-to-three block radius around a specific location, that''s where the advertiser really needs to do a lot of research. </p> <p>That has big implications for developers, advertisers and big Internet companies like Facebook Inc. and Google Inc. that are racing to make money from the growing number of consumers who are shunning traditional computers to spend more time on apps, social media and websites on mobile phones. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
Pandora lets advertisers target users by the zip code they use at sign-up. If customers don''t manually change zip-code information when they move, ads will continue to be misdirected. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Halia Pavliva" date="Jun 19, 2014  8:22 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-19/jpmorgan-joins-russia-bulls-after-rally-as-risks-fade.html"><headline>JPMorgan Joins Russia Bulls After Rally as Risks Fade</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Russian stocks have been so volatile
amid the turmoil in Ukraine that it took a bull market to
convince JPMorgan Chase  Co. that it''s time to buy. </p>
<p>The bank''s upgrade from sell yesterday follows a 21 percent
advance in the benchmark Micex Index (INDEXCF) from its bear-market low in
March. Stocks are rallying as President Vladimir Putin signals
that he''s willing to work with Ukraine''s new leader, reducing
concern that Russia will face more sanctions. Bank of America
Corp., which has had a buy rating on Russian stocks since
September, reiterated its bullish view on June 17. Deutsche Bank
AG strategist John-Paul Smith predicted a rebound six weeks ago. </p>
<p>The two key catalysts are the fading of the Ukraine
crisis and the shift in positioning, JPMorgan analysts
including David Aserkoff and Christian Kern wrote in a report on
June 18. Global emerging-market funds are underweight for the
first time since 2009. The emerging-market value trade seems to
be working, which should benefit Russia. </p>
<p>The analysts raised their rating on Russian shares to
overweight after cutting it to underweight on March 6 as Putin
began the annexation of Crimea. The Micex entered a bull market
on June 6. The gauge''s 30-day historical volatility, a measure
of price swings, reached a five-year high of 46.2 percent on
April 11. </p>
<h2>Ukraine Conflict </h2>
<p>Ukraine President Petro Poroshenko yesterday reiterated a
plan to end fighting in the country''s southeast region after
talks with Putin. The Micex gained for the second day, rising
0.7 percent to 1,504.23 by 8:20 a.m. in New York. The Bloomberg
Russia-US Equity Index of the most-traded Russian companies in
the U.S. jumped 1.9 percent yesterday. </p>
<p>Russia still provides better value than other emerging
markets, David Hauner, a strategist at Bank of America, said
in a telephone interview from London yesterday. The risk
reward is not as high as it was a couple of months ago, but our
view on global equities is positive and Russia will outperform
the market. </p>
<p>Smith, the Deutsche Bank strategist who predicted Russia''s
1998 stock-market crash and had been bearish on the country for
more than three years, said in May that investors were
overreacting to the conflict in Ukraine. </p>
<p>Russia''s second-biggest oil producer OAO Lukoil (LUKOY), eastern
Europe''s biggest lender OAO Sberbank (SBRCY) and Russia''s second-biggest
mobile phone company OAO Megafon (MFON) are among JPMorgan''s top
emerging-market stock picks, according to the note. </p>
<p>Aserkoff in London and Kantarovich in Moscow weren''t
available for comment on the timing of their overweight
recommendation when contacted by phone and e-mail outside
regular business hours yesterday. </p>
<h2>Pretty Negative'' </h2>
<p>Morgan Stanley raised Russian stocks to overweight on May 8
before Ukraine elected Poroshenko. Citigroup Inc. has an
overweight recommendation on Russia in its global emerging
markets portfolio, according to a report this month. </p>
<p>Capital Economics Ltd., in an e-mailed research note
yesterday, said it is relatively downbeat on the outlook for
Russian equities and expects stocks and the ruble to fall. </p>
<p>Our view on the Russian market is pretty negative, Liza Ermolenko, a London-based emerging-market economist at Capital
Economics, said by phone yesterday. While the economy is
slowing, no one really knows what is next in the Ukraine crisis
and whether further sanctions against Russia will be approved.
The Russian market is very sensitive to the Ukraine crises, and
there is no quick solution. </p>
<h2>International Sanctions </h2>
<p>Ukraine will call a unilateral cease-fire to help end three
months of fighting with pro-Russian separatists, Poroshenko said
in Kiev yesterday. Insurgents will be given a limited window to
lay down their arms, with those who haven''t committed any
serious crimes to be offered an amnesty and safe passage out of
the country, he said. </p>
<p>The U.S. and European Union have imposed sanctions
including travel bans and asset freezes on Putin allies in
Russia and Ukraine to punish the country for its standoff with
Ukraine. Russia''s gross domestic product grew 0.9 percent in the
first quarter from the same period in 2013, the slowest pace in
a year, the Federal State Statistics Service said on May 15. </p>
<p>While the $2 trillion economy was stalling before the
sanctions, the U.S. and EU have warned the nation faces further
penalties if fails to de-escalate the conflict. Ukraine and
Russia are also in conflict over gas, with Russia cutting off
supplies on June 16 because of unpaid bills. The International
Monetary Fund said April 30 that Russia is already in recession. </p>
<p>The Micex trades at 5.4 times estimated 12-month earnings,
compared with a ratio of 15.5 for India''s SP BSE Sensex Index,
10.7 for Brazil''s Ibovespa and 7.6 for the Shanghai Composite. </p>
<p>The RTS Volatility Index, which measures expected swings in
the index futures, was little changed today, while RTS stock-index futures increased 1.6 percent to 132,920 yesterday. The
Market Vectors Russia ETF (RSX), the biggest U.S.-traded exchange-traded fund that holds Russian shares, rose 2.6 percent to
$26.88. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Edvard Pettersson and Sophia Pearson" date="Jun 20, 2014  5:39 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-20/exxon-chevron-sued-by-pennsylvania-over-gas-additive.html"><headline>Exxon, Chevron Sued by Pennsylvania Over Gas Additive</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) and Chevron Corp. (CVX)
were among oil companies accused by Pennsylvania of polluting
groundwater with a gasoline additive in lawsuits similar to ones
brought by New York City, New Hampshire and Vermont. </p>
<p>BP Plc (BP/) and Citgo, the Houston-based unit of Venezuela''s
state-owned Petroleos de Venezuela SA, also were named in two
complaints made public today in state court that seek damages
for costs to clean up groundwater tainted by Methyl Tertiary
Butyl Ether, or MTBE. Pennsylvania Attorney General Kathleen Kane and Governor Tom Corbett''s office of general counsel filed
the complaints. </p>
<p>MTBE-related spills over the past 20 years have cost
Pennsylvania hundreds of millions of dollars, James Schultz,
the governor''s general counsel, said yesterday in a statement.
We cannot take the health of Pennsylvania''s waters for granted
and their protection must remain our utmost priority. </p>
<p>The Pennsylvania lawsuits follow scores of claims filed by
cities, states and individuals around the U.S. against oil
refiners, retailers and distributors over MTBE. Exxon Mobil,
Chevron and BP were among two dozen U.S. refiners sued this
month by Vermont Attorney General William Sorrell. </p>
<p>The U.S. Supreme Court in April upheld a jury''s $104.7
million damage award against Irving, Texas-based Exxon Mobil for
contaminating New York City wells with the additive. </p>
<h2>Clean Air </h2>
<p>The city sued oil companies in 2003, alleging they knew the
additive would pollute groundwater. Exxon Mobil argued that
state laws were pre-empted by the federal Clean Air Act, which
required oil companies to reformulate gasoline to reduce air
pollution from vehicle emissions. Oil companies added MTBE to
make the fuel burn more efficiently. </p>
<p>Reasonable alternatives to MTBE were available at the time
oil companies jointly promoted gasoline with the additive,
Pennsylvania claims in its lawsuit. </p>
<p>Braden Reddall, a spokesman for San Ramon, California-based
Chevron, said the company hadn''t yet seen the suit and couldn''t
comment. </p>
<p>BP acted at all times in good faith, said Scott Dean, a
spokesman in Houston for the London-based company. BP plans to
defend itself against the allegations. </p>
<p>Todd Spitler, an Exxon Mobil spokesman, said the company is
reviewing the claims, although such litigation is flawed in
that energy companies are being held liable not for spilling
gasoline, but for simply including oxygenates in gasoline as
required.'''' </p>
<h2>Second-Guessing </h2>
<p>If a company spills gasoline in Pennsylvania, it is
required to clean it up, as should be the case,'''' Spitler said.
These cases are about second-guessing decisions made by state
and federal regulators to rely on MTBE-blended gasoline to
reduce air pollution. We take very seriously our responsibility
to operate in an environmentally sound manner.'''' </p>
<p>Fernando Garay, a Citgo spokesman, didn''t immediately
return an e-mail seeking comment. </p>
<p>Pennsylvania wants the companies held liable for
manufacturing a defective product, creating public nuisances and
negligence. The complaint also seeks punitive damages for
wanton, malicious, oppressive and fraudulent conduct,''''
according to the filing. </p>
<p>The case is Commonwealth of Pennsylvania v. Exxon Mobil
Corp., 140602881, Court of Common Pleas of Philadelphia County
(Philadelphia). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jody Shenn" date="Jun 20, 2014  1:25 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-20/jpmorgan-said-to-plan-sale-of-304-million-mortgage-bonds.html"><headline>JPMorgan Said to Plan Sale of $304 Million Mortgage Bonds</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) is planning a
sale of U.S. home-loan bonds without government backing, adding
to evidence that the market for the securities is beginning to
pick up steam. </p>
<p>The deal will be tied to $303.7 million of prime 15-year
mortgages, according to a person with knowledge of the
transaction who asked not to be identified without authorization
to speak publicly. While most of the loans had original balances
larger than the current threshold for jumbo mortgages, the
market''s focus since its revival, 14.5 percent of the debt is
smaller than $400,000, the person said. </p>
<p>Premium Point Investments LP''s WinWater Home Mortgage LLC
yesterday completed its first non-agency bond transaction, a
deal tied to about $250 million of jumbo loans, and Citigroup
Inc. (C) is planning a similar $219 million offering. After reviving
from the paralysis caused by the 2008 financial crisis the debt
helped spark, issuance of non-agency securities had slowed after
the middle of last year as banks seek jumbo loans to hold as
investments and bond buyers pay less for the debt. </p>
<p>We''re seeing repeat and new issuers attempt to bring the
market back,Michele Patterson, a senior director at Kroll
Bond Rating Agency, said in a telephone interview. We are not
at last year''s levels, and we don''t anticipate getting to last
year''s levels. I think the second half will probably be about
the same as the first half of the year in terms of sales. </p>
<h2>September Collapse </h2>
<p>Justin Perras, a spokesman for New York-based JPMorgan,
declined to comment. </p>
<p>While total issuance of non-agency securities tied to new
loans jumped to $13.4 billion last year from $3.5 billion in
2012, sales collapsed after September, according to data
compiled by Bloomberg. Issuance totals about $1.8 billion this
year. Sales peaked at $1.2 trillion in both 2005 and 2006. </p>
<p>Jumbo mortgages are those larger than allowed in
government-supported programs. Limits now range from $417,000 to
$625,500 for Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac loans with the lowest
costs for borrowers using 20 percent down payments. </p>
<p>The average age of the loans in the JPMorgan transaction is
about one year, with 5.2 percent of the mortgages older than 30
months, the person said. First Republic Bank originated 55
percent of the mortgages, while JPMorgan''s bank made 38 percent,
the person said. </p>
<h2>Loss Protection </h2>
<p>The amount of loss protection for investors known as credit
enhancement, totaling 5.5 percent for part of the AAA portion of
the transaction, is the lowest yet seen by Kroll, which was
founded after the crisis and has been hired to grade the deal,
Patterson said. The inclusion of only mortgages with terms of 15
years or less, a first since the credit seizure, improves the
quality of the transaction because the loans typically perform
better than 30-year debt, she said. </p>
<p>Some other AAA portions of the deal have 10 percent
enhancement, the person said. Most of WinWater''s top-rated bonds
carried 15 percent of credit enhancement, with a smaller amount
offering a buffer of 8.25 percent. The safety margin is provided
by features such as some bonds losing principal amid losses on
the underlying loans before others. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Todd White" date="Jun 20, 2014  5:14 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-20/electricity-rates-taking-effect-for-spain-s-clean-energy.html"><headline>Electricity Rates Taking Effect for Spain''s Clean Energy</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Spain set new rates for electricity
suppliers that use renewable sources, waste and co-generation
based on a reasonable return, formally ending a subsidy
system dating to the 1990s that had spun out of control. </p>
<p>The Industry Ministry today published the new formulas and
tables to be used for generators ranging from wind turbines to
solar collectors and waste incinerators in a 1,761-page
regulation that takes effect tomorrow. The new return is based
on a host of factors, including the cost of investment and the
10-year Spanish government bond yield in the secondary market. </p>
<p>Spain became a world leader in clean-energy, spurring
projects by awarding more than 50 billion euros ($68 billion) in
subsidies in the last 25 years. At the same time it failed to
secure all the money needed to fund the incentives, which
accelerated and in 2013 totaled about 9 billion euros. </p>
<p>The system, modeled on Germany''s in the 1990s and paid for
mostly by consumers, was increasingly attacked as an
unacceptable burden by traditional utilities, some consumer
groups and the government. A series of new laws dismantled much
of it, aiming to achieve an economic and financial stability
of the electric system and avoid the incorporation of new
costs, the government said in today''s regulation. </p>
<p>While incentives were guaranteed to plant owners for 20
years or longer, the system failed to ensure the government
would set prices, or tariffs, paid by consumers at high enough
levels to fund the subsidies. That created a soaring tariff
deficit -- a debt carried temporarily by traditional power
distributors and securitized in chunks to private investors. </p>
<p>One legacy is that Spain, like almost no other country, can
supply more than half of electricity demand from clean sources
during stretches of the day that are sunny and windy. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Takako Taniguchi and Finbarr Flynn" date="Jun 20, 2014  4:08 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-20/goldman-swaps-aiful-loan-for-8-bond-luring-funds-japan-credit.html"><headline>Goldman Swaps Aiful Loan for 8% Bond Luring Funds: Japan Credit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. is set to
get bonds with more than double the interest rate local Japanese
banks will receive on loans when Aiful Corp. (8515) refinances. </p>
<p>The consumer lender, which postponed repayments to avoid
bankruptcy in 2009, said June 13 it will exchange part of 161.7
billion yen ($1.6 billion) of debt for notes bearing an 8
percent coupon. While that''s in line with U.S. notes with
similar credit scores, it''s among the highest for Japanese bonds
in the past 15 years, data compiled by Bloomberg and Bank of
America Merrill Lynch show. Domestic banks will extend new loans
at about 3 percent, a person familiar with the matter said. </p>
<p>Local banks are accepting lower interest because they have
collateral on loans to Aiful, while the debentures won''t be
secured. The consumer lender is seeking to refinance for a
second time in five years as Bank of Japan stimulus lowers
funding costs and the burden of refunding customers for excess
interest-rate charges declines. </p>
<p>A coupon of 8 percent looks very attractive, said
Taketoshi Tsuchiya, a senior executive at Mizuho Securities Co.
who heads a team dealing with distressed fixed income. We''ve
had a number of requests from overseas hedge funds saying they''d
like to buy the bonds if they come on the market. </p>
<h2>Informal Agreement </h2>
<p>Goldman Sachs and Aiful have reached an informal agreement
that the U.S. bank will apply to swap loans for notes, according
to two people familiar with the matter, who asked not to be
identified because the details are private. Aiful triggered
Japan''s first auction to determine the payout of credit-default
swaps when it obtained lender approval to postpone repayment on
280 billion yen in 2009. </p>
<p>Japanese banks may be avoiding the risk of default by
extending loans with collateral, according to Junichi Shimizu, a
Tokyo-based credit analyst at Deutsche Bank AG. </p>
<p>While the principal on loans gradually decreases as
payments are made, corporate bonds are repaid at one go, so
there''s the risk of a default depending on the business
environment, Shimizu said. </p>
<p>Only one yen bond offered by bankrupt Takefuji Corp. had a
higher coupon in the past 15 years than the Aiful notes to be
issued to Goldman, according to data compiled by Bloomberg.
Takefuji''s securities issued overseas in 2009 paid 10 percent. </p>
<h2>Debt Repayment </h2>
<p>Aiful will obtain a loan from Japanese banks of a little
under 80 billion yen with which it will repay part of its
outstanding debts, according to a person familiar with the
matter. Foreign creditors including Goldman Sachs will exchange
more than 30 billion yen in liabilities for the new bonds due at
the end of April 2020, according to the person. </p>
<p>Aiful will also postpone repayment of 52.7 billion yen of
existing loans, it said in a statement on June 13. </p>
<p>In difficult negotiations, we were compelled to accept
tough terms on the bonds, said Kenichi Hashimoto, an Aiful
spokesman. Realistically, there''s not such a big difference
between the rate and that being charged in secondary markets. </p>
<p>The extra yield on Aiful''s 1.99 percent bonds due in
October 2015 was 7.4 percentage points over sovereign notes,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. The Tokyo-based lender
is graded CCC+ by Japan''s Rating  Investment Information Inc.,
or the equivalent of seven steps below investment level. </p>
<p>U.S. corporate bonds with CCC or lower ratings had an
average yield of 8.8 percent, while it was 9.2 percent for
global notes with such scores, according to Bank of America
Merrill Lynch data. </p>
<h2>BOJ Stimulus </h2>
<p>Borrowing costs have fallen in Japan as the BOJ buys about
7 trillion yen of sovereign bonds a month to spur inflation. The
benchmark 10-year debt yield has dropped 15 1/2 basis points, or
0.155 percentage point, to 0.58 percent this year. The yen has
gained 3.3 percent in 2014 to 101.93 per dollar as of 5:06 p.m.
in Tokyo, after tumbling 18 percent last year. </p>
<p>An investment unit of Goldman Sachs held 14.5 billion yen
of Aiful''s debt, while a unit of Barclays Plc (BARC) had 9.4 billion
yen at the end of March, according to material provided by Aiful
to shareholders. The company''s single largest creditor was the
banking unit of Sumitomo Mitsui Trust Holdings Inc., the
documentation showed. </p>
<p>Hiroko Matsumoto, a spokeswoman for Goldman Sachs in Tokyo,
declined to comment on the plan, as did Kyota Narimatsu, a
spokesman at Barclays in Japan, and Hiroshi Kashimoto at
Sumitomo Mitsui Trust. </p>
<h2>Credit Event </h2>
<p>Aiful''s December 2009 agreement with creditors to delay
debt repayment resulted in a dispute over whether the action had
caused a so-called restructuring credit event. Buyers of Aiful
credit-default swaps, which insure bondholders against
nonpayment, had to wait three months for the International Swaps
 Derivatives Association to rule that the plan had triggered
payouts. </p>
<p>Sellers of credit-default protection agreed in 2010 to pay
holders 66.125 yen for each 100 yen of insured debt, in Japan''s
first credit default auction, according to bid administrators at
the time. </p>
<p>Aiful racked up 636.1 billion yen in net losses in the
eight years ended March 31 as a crackdown on coercive lending
practices and court rulings forced Japan''s consumer lenders to
repay billions of dollars in overcharged interest. </p>
<p>That regulatory action led to the bankruptcy of Takefuji
with 433.6 billion yen of liabilities. </p>
<p>Aiful recorded a profit of 30.5 billion yen in the 12
months ended March 31, its biggest in eight years and the third
in succession. Interest repayments fell for a fourth year last
fiscal year, dropping 57 percent to 33.1 billion yen from three
years earlier. </p>
<p>As the business environment is improving, banks can
increase their recovery rate by continuing to support Aiful and
its turnaround, said Shintaro Niimura, a credit analyst at
Nomura Securities Co., Japan''s largest brokerage. For
investors rationally seeking a profit, they''re emphasizing
better repayment terms. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Fion Li" date="Jun 22, 2014 12:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-22/jpmorgan-buys-larger-developers-as-bubble-deflates-china-credit.html"><headline>JPMorgan Buys Larger Developers as Bubble Deflates: China Credit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Asset Management and
Invesco Asset Management say China''s cooling property market is
an opportunity to boost dollar bond holdings as the government''s
targeted stimulus benefits the largest developers. </p>
<p>Chinese real-estate companies accounted for six of the 10
best-performing Asian notes in the past three months, according
to a Bank of America Merrill Lynch index. The yield on 2018 debt
of China Overseas Land  Investments Ltd., the nation''s largest
developer by market value, dropped to 3.35 percent last week,
from a record 4.31 percent on Feb. 5, while that on similar-maturity bonds of China Vanke Co. fell to 3.95 percent, from an
all-time high of 5.07 percent on March 20. </p>
<p>We will pick the winners from these trends, said
Stephen Chang, head of Asian fixed income at JPMorgan Asset,
which oversees $39 billion in emerging-market debt. Although
sales and prices are falling along with margins, we have
identified the larger developers are gaining market share and
executing well. </p>
<p>Premier Li Keqiang has pledged to safeguard this year''s
growth target of 7.5 percent, fueling bets the government will
encourage increased lending to selected projects and relax
restrictions in the real-estate market. Larger developers may
benefit from industry consolidation as smaller builders face a
funding squeeze with a record amount of property trusts maturing
next year and prices falling in the most cities in two years. </p>
<h2>Softening Prices </h2>
<p>Home prices declined in 35 of China''s 70 cities last month
from April, the most since May 2012, official data showed June
18. In the financial center of Shanghai, prices decreased 0.3
percent, the first drop in two years, while they fell 0.2
percent in the southern business hub of Shenzhen. </p>
<p>Softening prices are good because they imply there isn''t
a bubble anymore, said Ken Hu, Hong Kong-based chief
investment officer of fixed income for Asia Pacific at Invesco,
which manages $787 billion globally. We pick developers with
high turnover and those who tend to build smaller-sized flats.
Profit margin isn''t that key to bondholders like us. Our
approach is to buy on dips. </p>
<p>Developers including Vanke that cut prices by 10 percent to
15 percent achieved good sales volume, Deutsche Bank AG analysts
led by Hong Kong-based Tony Tsang wrote in a June 13 report.
Vanke, headquartered in Shenzhen, recorded a 16.2 percent
increase in sales value in the first five months of 2014 from a
year earlier, it said in a June 3 statement to the Shenzhen
stock exchange. </p>
<h2>Taking Advantage </h2>
<p>Larger industry players are able to tap overseas capital
markets for funds. Sales of dollar bonds by Chinese companies
totaled $91 billion in 2014, compared with $89 billion in the
previous year, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Smaller builders, which rely on property trusts for
financing, have to repay 203.5 billion yuan ($32.7 billion) in
2015, according to research firm Use Trust. That''s almost double
the 109 billion yuan due this year. China''s banking regulator
said on June 6 it will monitor developer finances, a sign of
concern defaults may spread after the March collapse of Zhejiang
Xingrun Real Estate Co., a builder south of Shanghai. </p>
<p>It won''t be surprising to have a few defaults in the
sector in an economic slowdown, given you have thousands of
developers and many of them are small ones, BOCI''s Wang said.
The bigger ones, especially those listed, can take advantage
to lower their funding costs as the industry consolidates. </p>
<p>China South City Holdings Ltd. (1668), which runs logistics parks
for industrial materials, sold 1 billion yuan of five-year bonds
at a coupon of 7.5 percent in the interbank market on May 9. It
plans to use the proceeds to repay short-term bank loans.
Greenland Holding Group has hired banks to arrange investor
meetings from today for a potential dollar bond offering,
according to a person familiar with the matter. </p>
<h2>Borrowing Costs </h2>
<p>Vanke''s bond borrowing costs dropped to 3.45 percent on a
weighted average last week, compared with 5.5 percent in the
first quarter of 2011, according to data compiled by Bloomberg.
It also managed to extend the average maturity of its notes to
3.95 years, from 2.43 years in 2011. </p>
<p>Slowing growth is causing declines in the yuan and onshore
interest rates. The Chinese currency has fallen 2.8 percent
against the dollar this year, the worst performance in Asia. The
yield on the benchmark 10-year government bond has dropped 52
basis points to 4.04 percent in the same period as investors
sought safe havens. Gross domestic product will probably expand
7.3 percent this year, the slowest pace since 1990, according to
a Bloomberg survey. </p>
<h2>Prolonged Downturn </h2>
<p>The downturn in the property market will be more prolonged
this time than in previous corrections, Tom Byrne, senior vice
president at Moody''s, said at a June 19 conference in Shanghai.
Broad price cuts are likely to come in late August or in
September when more new projects are set to be introduced, UBS
AG Hong Kong-based analyst Eva Lee wrote in a report last week. </p>
<p>Moody''s revised its credit outlook for Chinese developers
to negative from stable on May 21. The Shanghai Stock Exchange
Property Index, which tracks 24 real-estate companies listed in
the city, has slumped 6.3 percent this year, exceeding the 4.2
percent decline for the benchmark Shanghai Composite Index. </p>
<p>Overall, the housing market is cooling in some parts,
like in third- or fourth-tier cities, said Chang at JPMorgan
Asset. But we do see a silver lining. There''s actually a
healthy pickup in transactions at specific locations after some
discounting. </p>
<h2>''Minor Stimulus'' </h2>
<p>The nation has introduced measures to help the real-estate
industry, which JPMorgan Chase  Co. says poses the biggest
near-term risk to growth in the world''s second-largest economy.
The People''s Bank of China told 15 banks in May to improve
efficiency of service, give timely approval and distribution of
mortgages to qualified buyers. The southeastern city of Fuzhou
has removed home-purchase limits for buyers who make one-time
payments, the Securities Times reported on June 18, citing sales
people from two developers. </p>
<p>The government may announce additional minor stimulus
measures after Premier Li said in London last week that the
nation will maintain a minimum growth rate of 7.5 percent,
according to a China Securities Journal commentary on June 20.
The PBOC may release more targeted steps to prevent expansion
from falling short of the goal, it added. </p>
<p>Policy makers are actually putting out more measures to
support this sector, said Arthur Lau, Hong Kong-based head of
Asia ex-Japan fixed income at PineBridge Investments, which
oversees about $71 billion. I think, volume-wise, it could
catch up a little bit in the second half, especially those who
are not aggressively buying land. There is still a wide
selection, even within this sector. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Mikael Holter" date="Jun 23, 2014  6:34 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-23/exxon-s-norway-output-threatened-as-union-readies-pension-strike.html"><headline>Exxon''s Norway Output Threatened as Union Readies Pension Strike</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A Norwegian oil-workers union said
it''s ready to go on strike over pensions in a move that
threatens to cut oil production from Exxon Mobil Corp.''s
platforms in the North Sea by more than 60,000 barrels a day. </p>
<p>A court in Oslo today ruled that a strike notice by the
Safe union that would affect three Exxon platforms is legal,
clearing the way for a walkout, according to the group''s leader,
Hilde-Marit Rysst. While the union is yet to decide on a public
mediator''s proposal that seeks to bridge differences with
employers, it will do so by the June 27 midday deadline, she
said by phone today. </p>
<p>Everything is set for a strike, Rysst said. The
mediator''s proposal, endorsed by the Norwegian Oil and Gas
Association, which represents employers in wage negotiations,
is not good enough, she said. </p>
<p>A strike would set Safe apart from two other unions that
reached wage agreements in talks that covered 7,615 offshore
oil-platform workers. In 2012, workers from all three unions
walked out in their longest action, disrupting oil and gas
production until the government intervened to stop companies
imposing a full lockout that would have halted output from
western Europe''s largest producer. </p>
<p>The conflict centers on pension terms for 31 Safe-affiliated workers at Exxon, the world''s largest oil company by
market value. While the Norwegian Oil and Gas Association argued
that the issue isn''t relevant for industry-wide wage talks, the
Oslo court ruled Safe''s strike notice is legal. </p>
<h2>Union Threat </h2>
<p>The Norwegian Oil and Gas Association could meet with Safe
again this week after last week''s state-backed mediation, though
there are no talks planned yet, the oil-industry lobby group''s
spokeswoman Eli Ane Nedreskaar said by phone. Exxon declined to
comment on talks with the union as it''s represented by the
Norwegian Oil and Gas Association, spokesman Knut Riple said. </p>
<p>Safe has threatened to take out 154 of its members from
Exxon''s Balder, Ringhorne and Jotun platforms, shutting down
production that reached 61,000 barrels of oil in April,
according to figures from the Norwegian Petroleum Directorate. A
strike would also halt production at Det Norske Oljeselskap
ASA''s Jette field, which goes through Jotun and amounted to
2,000 barrels of crude a day in April. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jun 24, 2014  1:08 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-24/morgan-stanley-receives-90-000-applications-for-summer-program.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Gets 90,000 Summer-Program Applications</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS), owner of the world''s
largest brokerage, received about 90,000 applications for its
summer program for analysts and associates. </p>
<p>More than 1,000 people, or roughly 80 percent who received
offers, accepted a spot and began working in the past few weeks,
Chief Executive Officer James Gorman, 55, said today in a memo
to employees. Mary Claire Delaney, a spokeswoman for the New
York-based bank, confirmed the contents of the memo. </p>
<p>Wall Street firms have been touting the selectivity of
their programs for recruiting junior talent to counter worries
that they''re less attractive employers in the wake of the
financial crisis. The acceptance rate of less than 2 percent is
lower than Harvard College''s 5.9 percent for the coming year''s
freshman class. </p>
<p>It''s not going to be a constraint, Gorman said of
attracting new employees in March 2012. There will always be
somebody who says Well, I always wanted to be an investment
banker, but I''ve had this sort of moral epiphany, and now I''m
not.'' I mean, it''s ridiculous. </p>
<p>The title of analyst typically is used for undergraduate
students who intern for the summer, and doesn''t refer to
research analysts who recommend stocks to investors. Associates
are usually graduate school students. </p>




Photographer: Simon Dawson/Bloomberg

<p>
Morgan Stanley Chief Executive Officer James Gorman said in his memo that more than 80 percent of those who were offered a spot for its summer program for analysts and associates had accepted. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Maria Kolesnikova" date="Jun 24, 2014  9:06 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-24/goldman-sees-commodities-dropping-5-5-after-iraq-driven-rally.html"><headline>Goldman Sees Commodities Dropping 5.5% After Iraq-Driven Rally</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Commodities are poised to decline
5.5 percent over the next 12 months after climbing amid tensions
in Iraq, Goldman Sachs Group Inc. said. </p>
<p>Energy prices will be 5 percent lower a year from now,
precious metals will drop 15 percent and agricultural products
will retreat 10 percent, the bank said in an asset-allocation
report dated yesterday. Commodities will decline 4 percent in
the next three months, according to the report. </p>
<p>Despite the negative return we forecast after the recent
rally driven by events in Iraq, we stay neutral commodities due
to the hedging benefits they offer against these risks,
Goldman analyst Jeffrey Currie in New York said in the report. </p>
<p>Brent crude reached a nine-month high in London on June 19
after Iraqi insurgents captured the northern city of Mosul and
advanced to towns just north of Baghdad, sparking concern oil
output might be interrupted in OPEC''s second-largest producer.
Gold futures touched the highest price since April 15 today in
New York trading. </p>
<p>Today Brent fell as much as 0.5 percent after Iraqi forces
regained control of the Baiji refinery in the north from
Islamist militants, and fighting has yet to spread to the south,
home to more than three-quarters of the country''s crude output.
Saudi Arabia was the only producer in the Organization of
Petroleum Exporting Countries that pumped more oil than Iraq
last month, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<h2>Larger Stockpiles </h2>
<p>Still, risks in energy are skewed to the upside in an
environment of heightened geopolitical risks and very limited
OPEC spare capacity, the Goldman analyst wrote. Precious
metals will drop amid rising real interest rates, while
agriculture prices are set to decline as inventories increase,
according to the bank. </p>
<p>Commodity prices as measured by the Standard  Poor''s GSCI
Enhanced Commodity Index rose 3.4 percent so far this month and
are up 7.1 percent in 2014. </p>
<p>Goldman forecast May 14 the enhanced index might have zero
total return in three months and decline 2.2 percent over 12
months. The bank projected a 4 percent drop over 12 months in an
April 13 note. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Takahiko Hyuga, Hiroko Komiya and Kevin Buckland" date="Jun 24, 2014 12:34 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-24/goldman-sachs-tokyo-fx-salesman-wako-ogawa-said-to-resign.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Tokyo FX Salesman Wako Ogawa Said to Resign</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)''s Tokyo-based foreign exchange salesman Wako Ogawa is leaving the firm,
according to two people familiar with the situation. </p>
<p>Ogawa, 44, a vice president at Goldman Sachs Japan Co.,
will leave the firm later this year to join a financial
institution, the people said, declining to be identified because
the matter is confidential. Goldman Sachs''s Tokyo-based
spokeswoman Hiroko Matsumoto declined to comment. </p>
<p>Ogawa, who joined Goldman Sachs in 2007, regularly appears
as a commentator on TV Tokyo (9413)''s early morning financial news
program, Morning Satellite. </p>
<p>Banks globally are seeing income from foreign exchange
squeezed by a decline in market volatility as global central
banks provide unprecedented liquidity. </p>
<p>Deutsche Bank AG''s Currency Volatility Index, which
measures the market''s expectation of future price swings for
nine currency pairs, slumped to a record 5.3 percent on June 19.
The index was as high as 15.8 percent in September 2011. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs ranked 10th in global currency trading, up
from 11th a year earlier, Euromoney reported in its survey of
the market published this year, with a 2.5 percent share. The
bank has seen its proportion of transactions shrink each year
since 2010, the data show. Citigroup Inc. was the leader in the
latest survey with a 16 percent share. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Harry R. Weber" date="Jun 25, 2014  5:08 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-25/electricity-advances-from-washington-to-boston-as-use-rises.html"><headline>Electricity Advances From New York to Boston as Demand Rises</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Spot wholesale electricity jumped in
the Northeast as natural gas futures rose and demand exceeded
expectations. </p>
<p>Consumption on the ISO New England Inc. network was 21,069
megawatts at 4:10 p.m. New York time, versus the day-ahead
forecast of 20,700 megawatts, according to the grid''s website. </p>
<p>The temperature today in Boston reached 88 degrees
Fahrenheit (31 Celsius), 9 above the normal high, according to
AccuWeather Inc. in State College, Pennsylvania. </p>
<p>Boston power tripled, advancing $101.05 to average $149.65
a megawatt-hour at 4 p.m. from the same time yesterday, grid
data compiled by Bloomberg show. New York City spot power gained
$35.22, or 70 percent, to average $85.51. </p>
<p>New York on-peak power traded $11.60 below Boston, compared
with a premium of $6.03 yesterday and a three-month average
discount of 13 cents. </p>
<p>Natural gas futures rose for a second day in New York on
speculation that hotter weather will boost demand for
electricity. Power plants account for 31 percent of U.S. gas
demand. Gas for July delivery rose 1.8 cents, or 0.4 percent, to
settle at $4.553 per million British thermal units on the New
York Mercantile Exchange. </p>
<p>At PJM Interconnection LLC''s benchmark Western hub, which
includes Washington, spot power reversed earlier gains and fell
$17.23, or 19 percent, to average $74.50 a megawatt-hour at 4
p.m. Prices at the Eastern hub, which includes New Jersey,
advanced $49.33, or 46 percent, to average $155.56, as operators
at PPL Corp.''s (PPL) Susquehanna nuclear power plant near Berwick,
Pennsylvania, began shutting Unit 2 to inspect its turbine
blades. Unit 1 continued to operate at full power, PPL said in a
statement today. </p>
<p>PJM West on-peak power traded $87.49 below the Eastern hub,
compared with a discount of $8.25 yesterday and a three-month
average discount of $4.26. </p>
<p>In the Midwest, spot power at the Indiana hub, a regional
benchmark, slid $12.60, or 20 percent, to average $50.52 a
megawatt-hour for the hour ended at 2 p.m. local time from the
same time yesterday. </p>
<p>The Midcontinent Independent System Operator Inc., based in
Carmel, Indiana, added its Gulf Coast territory to its network
in December 2013. </p>
<p>Output at Entergy Corp.''s Grand Gulf reactor near
Vicksburg, Mississippi, rose to 82 percent from 58 percent
yesterday, according to the U.S. Nuclear Regulatory Commission.
Nameplate capacity at the unit is 1,373 megawatts. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jody Shenn" date="Jun 25, 2014  4:36 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-25/jpmorgan-said-to-sell-304-million-mortgage-bond-issue.html"><headline>JPMorgan Said to Sell $304 Million Mortgage-Bond Issue</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) sold bonds tied
to about $304 million of U.S. home loans without government
backing, adding to signs of life in the market. </p>
<p>The transaction included $171 million of top-rated
securities paying a 3 percent coupon, which were sold at 102.2
cents on the dollar, according to a person with knowledge of the
offering who asked not to be identified citing lack of
authorization to speak publicly. That''s about 1.5 cents on the
dollar less than comparable benchmark Fannie Mae-guaranteed
bonds, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>The notes are unlike other recent deals because they''re
backed almost entirely by 15-year mortgages, which are often
taken by more financially secure borrowers relative to more
common 30-year loans, according to a presale report by Standard
 Poor''s. The average size of the mortgages, at about $558,000,
was also smaller than the $850,000 in previous JPMorgan deals
since the 2008 financial crisis, SP said. They were mainly
jumbo loans, it said. </p>
<p>The transaction''s contracts included an untested and
rigid process for forcing JPMorgan or other originators of the
underlying loans to buy back misrepresented debt, SP said.
Seeing that the framework is more restrictive than those in
other recent prime transactions, we imposed additional loss
coverage requirements in our review. </p>
<p>While issuance of non-agency securities tied to new loans
jumped to $13.4 billion last year from $3.5 billion in 2012,
sales collapsed after September, Bloomberg data show. Issuance
totals about $2.1 billion this year, and Citigroup Inc. (C) has been
also planning a sale this month. Offerings peaked at $1.2
trillion in both 2005 and 2006. </p>
<p>Jumbo mortgages are those larger than allowed in
government-supported programs. Limits now range from $417,000 to
$625,500 for Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac loans with the lowest
costs for borrowers using 20 percent down payments. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By James Callan and Jaime Myslik" date="Jun 25, 2014  4:20 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-25/general-mills-to-cut-costs-as-earnings-miss-estimates.html"><headline>General Mills to Cut Costs as Earnings Miss Estimates</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>General Mills Inc. (GIS) reported fiscal
fourth-quarter earnings that trailed analysts'' estimates and
said it began a review of its North American manufacturing and
distribution network as part of a wider effort to reduce costs. </p>
<p>The maker of Cheerios cereal said the cost-cutting plan is
expected to generate pretax savings of $40 million in fiscal
2015, and will have additional savings in 2016, according to a
statement today. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Ken Powell said sales and operating
profit were disappointing in the last fiscal year as
promotional spending in developed markets was less effective
than planned. Revenue in the quarter ended May 25 dropped 2.9
percent to $4.28 billion. </p>
<p>General Mills fell 3.6 percent to $51.76 at the close in
New York, the biggest decline since Feb. 17, 2012. The stock has
gained 3.7 percent this year. </p>
<p>The cost savings at General Mills will likely go into
product development and market support, Erin Lash, an analyst at
Morningstar Inc. in Chicago, said today in a phone interview.
The question is whether General Mills will lower prices to drive
sales volume or if it will bring in higher cost products popular
with consumers, she said. </p>
<p>By taking costs out of the business -- we''re not
expecting that to drive material margin improvement, said
Lash, who has a hold rating on the shares. We''re expecting
them to reinvest that back into the brand. </p>
<h2>Earnings Miss </h2>
<p>Adjusted earnings per share in the quarter were 67 cents,
the Minneapolis-based company said. Analysts projected 72 cents,
the average of estimates compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>The results came in slightly less than expectations, but
from our view the shares are more or less valued at the current
price, Lash said. </p>
<p>Earlier this year Warren Buffett of Berkshire Hathaway Inc. (BRK/B)
said he''s looking for elephants or large acquisitions.
General Mills may fit the bill. After Berkshire''s purchase of
H.J. Heinz Co. last year, a shareholder said General Mills could
be a possibility because both brands are recognizable and sell
their products in similar stores. </p>
<p>General Mills makes a lot of sense, Jeff Matthews, the
author of Warren Buffett''s Successor: Who It Is and Why It
Matters, said in a phone interview in February. It''s another
kind of sleepy, Heinz-type business that has a lot of potential.
The distribution channels really overlap. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Greg Stohr" date="Jun 25, 2014  3:37 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-25/mobile-phone-searches-by-police-limited-by-u-s-supreme-court.html"><headline>Police Need Warrant to Search Cell Phones, Top Court Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Police usually must get a warrant before searching the mobile phone of a person being arrested, the U.S. Supreme Court ruled, saying the vast trove of information on modern devices requires broad constitutional protections. </p> <p>The unanimous decision comes in two cases that tested the reach of privacy rights in the digital age. More than 90 percent of American adults own mobile phones, giving the ruling wide practical significance. </p> <p>Modern cell phones are not just another technological convenience, Chief Justice John Roberts wrote for the court. With all they contain and all they may reveal, they hold for many Americans the privacies of life. </p> <p>The disputes, which tested the Constitution''s Fourth Amendment and its ban on unreasonable searches, were part of a wider debate over electronic privacy that ultimately may produce a Supreme Court showdown over the National Security Agency''s telephone-data surveillance program. </p> <p>Lower courts had reached different conclusions, with some saying police can constitutionally look through a phone just as they can search other objects in the person''s possession at the time of arrest. </p> <h2>Cigarette Case </h2> <p>The Supreme Court today rejected that reasoning, saying mobile phones are unlike the cigarette case the justices said could be searched in a 1973 dispute. </p>




Photographer: Karen Bleier/AFP via Getty Images

<p>
The U.S. Supreme Court in Washington, DC. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Meghan Morris and Devin Banerjee" date="Jun 25, 2014  3:06 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-25/general-atlantic-hires-advent-s-crawford-for-retail-investments.html"><headline>General Atlantic Hires Advent''s Crawford for Retail Investments</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>General Atlantic LLC, the private-equity firm with stakes in Tory Burch LLC and Alibaba Group
Holding Ltd., hired Andrew Crawford from Advent International
Corp. to head retail and consumer deals as investment in the
sector increases. </p>
<p>Crawford will be a managing director in New York. He was
previously a principal at Advent working with Lululemon
Athletica Inc. (LULU) and helping lead an investment in Bojangles''
Restaurants Inc., General Atlantic said today in a statement.
The Greenwich, Connecticut-based firm, which has $17 billion
under management, has announced eight investments this year,
including in a Mexican pharmaceuticals company and a Chinese
beauty products retailer. </p>
<p>Private-equity deals in consumer companies have risen 57
percent to $31.9 billion so far this year, compared with the
same period in 2013, according to data compiled by Bloomberg.
Lululemon, the yogawear company, has climbed this week amid
speculation that founder Chip Wilson will push for a sale,
including to a private-equity firm. The Vancouver-based company
has a market capitalization of about $6 billion. </p>
<p>Andy''s investing acumen, retail and consumer expertise
and leadership qualities will be a significant addition to our
team, General Atlantic''s Chief Executive Officer William Ford
said in the statement. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jun 25, 2014 12:37 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-25/goldman-merges-health-retail-investment-banking-groups.html"><headline>Goldman Merges Health, Retail Investment-Banking Groups</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), the top
merger adviser this year, is combining its health-care and
retail investment-banking groups amid a boom in deals involving
pharmaceutical companies. </p>
<p>Kathy Elsesser and Francois-Xavier de Mallmann, co-heads of
the retail team, will lead the new group with Marshall Smith,
who runs the health-care unit, according to an internal memo
obtained today by Bloomberg News. David Wells, a spokesman for
New York-based Goldman Sachs, confirmed the memo''s contents. </p>
<p>Wall Street firms have been seeking to boost efficiency as
lower trading revenue and new capital rules damp returns. The
combined group would be among the bank''s largest by total
investment-banking fees, trailing financial institutions and
financial sponsors, according to data from New York research
firm Freeman  Co. covering the past three years. </p>
<p>The change will allow bankers to be deployed more widely
across a broader client base, Goldman Sachs''s co-heads of
investment banking, Richard J. Gnodde, David Solomon and John S. Weinberg, wrote in the memo. We see growing convergence
between sub sectors. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs is the top-ranked adviser this year on deals
involving health-care companies, which this quarter announced
about $200 billion of deals, the most ever, according to data
compiled by Bloomberg. The firm ranked second for retail deals,
behind Morgan Stanley, the data show. </p>
<p>Elsesser started working for Goldman Sachs in 1989, while
de Mallmann and Smith joined in 1993 and 2005, respectively. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs is an adviser to Allergan Inc. on Valeant
Pharmaceuticals International Inc.''s $54 billion hostile
takeover bid, as well as to medical-device maker Covidien Plc on
its $46 billion acquisition by Medtronic Inc. On retail deals,
the firm is advising Safeway Inc. on its $9.1 billion sale to
Albertsons LLC. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Alastair Marsh" date="Jun 25, 2014  5:11 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-25/goldman-sachs-offers-triple-recourse-bonds-targeting-aaa-buyers.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Offers Triple-Recourse Bonds Targeting AAA Buyers</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) is
marketing a new type of bond designed to give investors access
to top-rated assets as the supply of covered bonds and other
high-grade securities continues to shrink. </p>
<p>The 1 billion euros ($1.3 billion) of notes are
provisionally rated AAA by Standard  Poor''s and will be sold
through FIGSCO Issuer Ltd., SP said in a statement. The bonds
are secured by fixed-income assets and offer investors three
levels of protection in the event of default. </p>
<p>Goldman is seeking to meet investor demand for the safest
assets as AAA rated bonds become harder to find in Europe.
Redemptions of covered bonds and U.K. RMBS are outpacing new
issues in Europe as cheap central bank funding and regulatory
pressure prompt lenders to trim balance sheets. </p>
<p>The current context of the supply/demand imbalance in the
markets is well known, Societe Generale SA analysts led by
Jean-David Cirotteau said in a report. A new senior secured
bond backed by a portfolio of financial assets by a large U.S.
investment firm is probably a good thing for hungry investors. </p>
<p>Sophie Ramsay, a spokeswoman for Goldman Sachs in London,
declined to comment on the notes. </p>
<p>The collateral backing the AAA bonds will be transferred to
FIGSCO through a total return swap with Goldman Sachs Mitsui
Marine Derivative Products LP, a joint venture between the U.S.
bank and Japan''s Mitsui Sumitomo Insurance Co., according to
SP. The securities offer investors a claim on the assets
backing the deal, as well as on Goldman and Mitsui if the joint
venture defaults. </p>
<p>The U.S. bank has set up a 10 billion-euro program to sell
the debt. Goldman Sachs, Barclays Plc, Credit Agricole SA,
Natixis, and UBS AG are holding investor meetings for the bonds
this week, a person familiar with the matter said June 23. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By James Nash" date="Jun 25, 2014 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-25/mobile-web-siphons-revenue-from-cities-as-landlines-fade.html"><headline>Mobile Web Siphons Revenue From Cities as Landlines Fade</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Tweeting, Facebooking, Skyping smartphone users are costing U.S. states and cities revenue as taxes rooted in old-fashioned telephone service fail to keep up with the Internet era. </p> <p>In Phoenix, the loss of $1.3 million in telephone tax revenue translates to the cost of training and equipping 10 police officers, said Mario Paniagua, the budget and research director. In Springfield, Illinois, a $200,000 shortfall in telecommunications revenue is keeping the library from extending hours. </p> <p>I imagine at some point you''ll have an app called the Call Your Friend'' app and you won''t be using the phone network at all, said Max Behlke, the manager of state-federal relations for the National Conference of State Legislatures in Washington. It is a concern for states and localities because this has been one of the most reliable revenue streams they have. Phone service is almost as much a necessity as food. </p> <p>Just as they created new business models for retail sales, taxi service, short-term accommodations and watching movies and listening to music, smartphones and the Internet are changing how people dial each other up. Tax-dependent governments, still struggling to recover from the 18-month recession that ended five years ago, find themselves seeking to compensate for a once-reliable source of money. </p>




Photographer: Aaron M. Sprecher/Bloomberg

<p>
Just as they created new business models for retail sales, taxi service, short-term accommodations and watching movies and listening to music, smartphones and the Internet are changing how people dial each other up. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David Welch, Matthew Campbell and Albertina Torsoli" date="Jun 26, 2014  7:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-26/pfizer-failure-gives-abbvie-lessons-in-pursuit-of-shire.html"><headline>Pfizer Failure Gives AbbVie Lessons in Pursuit of Shire</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>AbbVie Inc. (ABBV), in its pursuit of
drugmaker Shire Plc (SHP), has hired some of the same advisers that
Pfizer Inc. worked with in its failed push for AstraZeneca Plc. (AZN)
They''re trying to learn from the experience. </p>
<p>Richard Gonzalez, AbbVie''s chief executive officer,
yesterday made clear that a hostile bid is an option for his
company, a move Pfizer ruled out. AbbVie''s effort also differs
in that it''s appealing directly to Shire shareholders early,
offering what it calls a significant premium to win their
support to pressure its board or prepare the ground for a
hostile offer, according to people familiar with the matter. </p>
<p>This year''s boom in health-care takeovers is giving
companies and their banks, lawyers, and public-relations firms
plenty of real-life experience to draw upon. AbbVie is being
advised on its $46.5 billion bid by JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) as well
as PR firm Brunswick Group, both of which also worked with
Pfizer on AstraZeneca. </p>
<p>They don''t want to back themselves into a corner, Navid Malik, an analyst at Cenkos Securities Plc in London, said of
AbbVie. </p>
<p>Gonzalez''s team is trying to keep debate focused on the
strategic logic of a deal, rather than on using Shire''s Irish
legal domicile to escape U.S. taxes -- a topic that came to
dominate the Pfizer-AstraZeneca transaction, said one of the
people, who asked not to be identified because talks are
private. </p>
<p>However, they''re also stressing that tax benefits could
enable bigger payouts to investors in the future. The pitch:
that a combination would enrich Shire shareholders beyond what
the company could achieve alone. </p>
<p>Shire, for its part, has said the bid undervalues the
company, and that it has strong prospects on its own. </p>
<p>A spokeswoman for AbbVie and a spokesman for Brunswick
didn''t immediately return calls seeking comment. A JPMorgan
spokeswoman declined to comment. </p>
<p>North Chicago, Illinois-based AbbVie heads into possible
negotiations with advantages Pfizer lacked. Unlike AstraZeneca,
Shire doesn''t have a large workforce or substantial research
base in the U.K. that politicians will fight to keep under local
control, as they did in AstraZeneca''s case. </p>
<h2>No History </h2>
<p>And AbbVie, spun off from Abbott Laboratories (ABT) last year,
has no history of past acquisitions to defend. Pfizer''s record
of presiding over large-scale layoffs after buying companies
including Wyeth and Pharmacia Corp. helped rally British
politicians and unions to AstraZeneca''s side. </p>
<p>Shire, domiciled in Dublin for tax purposes and with
management offices in Basingstoke, England, has rejected three
takeover offers from AbbVie. The companies are at odds over how
to benchmark Shire''s shares, with AbbVie arguing Shire''s share
price has been inflated since the AstraZeneca deal highlighted
the attractiveness of U.K. and Irish-domiciled health-care
companies. </p>
<p>Citigroup Inc. (C), Deutsche Bank AG, Evercore Partners Inc. (EVR),
Morgan Stanley (MS) and Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) are advising Shire. </p>
<h2>Final Offer </h2>
<p>AbbVie CEO Gonzalez''s statement yesterday that he would
keep a hostile bid on the table contrasted with Pfizer''s
approach. </p>
<p>Pfizer on May 18 said its latest $117 billion proposal for
AstraZeneca was final and that it wouldn''t try to woo
shareholders directly. Under U.K. takeover rules, deeming an
offer final makes it nearly impossible for it to be further
increased. That''s another pitfall AbbVie is keen to avoid, two
of the people said. </p>
<p>Those pledges marked the end -- at least for now -- of what
would have been the industry''s biggest-ever acquisition, raising
questions about Pfizer''s tactics. </p>
<h2>Parliament''s Reaction </h2>
<p>Separately, AbbVie is trying to head off concerns that set
off a heated public debate over AstraZeneca, one of the people
familiar with the situation said. </p>
<p>Members of Parliament in the U.K. expressed reservations
over Pfizer''s history of large transactions followed by firings
and the shutdown of research facilities. </p>
<p>In response, Pfizer promised to locate 20 percent of its
global research workforce in Britain. That in turn fuelled
concern from public officials in the U.S. and Sweden, where
AstraZeneca also has significant operations, and exacerbated
animosity between the two companies. </p>
<p>Shire employs fewer than 500 people in the U.K. and only
about 100 in Ireland. CEO Flemming Ornskov and Phil Vickers,
Shire''s research head, work in the U.S., and other top managers
are joining them there. </p>
<p>In a message to its employees yesterday, AbbVie said no
jobs would be lost in the Chicago area in a Shire deal, and the
combined company would be managed from there. AbbVie is also
arguing that a deal would strengthen Shire''s research and
development capacity and give it global scale. </p>
<h2>Political Scrutiny </h2>
<p>Buying Shire would give AbbVie a growing stable of
treatments for rare diseases. The U.S. company is dependent on
the rheumatoid arthritis drug Humira for about 60 percent of
sales. </p>
<p>Gonzalez yesterday stressed the strategic advantages he
believes a transaction would bring to both companies in areas
such as rare diseases, neurosciences and ophthalmology. He also
pointed to the common ground between AbbVie and Shire. </p>
<p>Both strategically and culturally, there is great
alignment between our companies, he said. They are both
specialty-focused biopharmaceutical companies, pursuing similar
strategies, targeting diseases of high unmet medical need. </p>
<p>While AbbVie has said the proposed deal would cut its tax
rate by almost 10 percentage points, in its 39-page slide deck
presentation to Shire investors the word tax surfaces only
on page 20. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Peter Levring" date="Jun 27, 2014  6:06 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-27/goldman-s-cash-drives-dong-hybrid-debt-to-record-nordic-credit.html"><headline>Goldman''s Cash Drives Dong Hybrid Debt to Record: Nordic Credit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Since Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)
bought a stake in Dong Energy A/S last year, the utility''s
hybrid debt has soared to a record, boosting investor returns as
the Danish firm uses the cash to rebuild its business. </p>
<p>Investors holding Dong''s 4.875 percent bond due 3013 have
enjoyed a 14 percent return since the debt was issued in July
last year and a 5.5 percent note maturing in 3005 gained 4.6
percent. Creditors holding Vattenfall AB''s 5.25 percent
perpetual note received 4.3 percent in Sweden''s biggest utility
over the same period. </p>
<p>Bringing in Goldman was a good idea, Finance Minister
Bjarne Corydon said in an interview at Denmark''s parliament in
Copenhagen. </p>
<p>Half a year after Goldman''s purchase of a stake in state-held Dong split the minority coalition of Prime Minister Helle Thorning-Schmidt, investors are benefiting from the transaction.
The Wall Street bank''s $1.5 billion purchase of an 18 percent
stake was part of a deal, made together with pension funds ATP
and PFA, that helped cauterize losses after Dong failed to turn
a profit on natural gas projects. </p>
<h2>Put Option </h2>
<p>Goldman, which bought the stake through its European
merchant banking unit in a company named New Energy Investment
S.a.r.l., has already seen the value of its stake grow. </p>
<p>Horsens, Denmark-based utility Insero this month exercised
a put option to sell a 1.8 percent stake in Dong to Denmark for
942 million kroner. That price values all of Dong at more than
50 billion kroner. </p>
<p>Dong was valued at 31.5 billion kroner ahead of Denmark
selling shares worth 13.1 billion kroner to Goldman, pension
funds ATP and PFA and a group of shareholders in February. </p>
<p>Insero''s price was based on a 2005-2006 valuation with
added interests minus dividends, Peter Brixen, the head of the
unit that manages the ministry''s stake, said in an e-mailed
reply to questions. Other minority holders, such as SEAS-NVE and
Syd Energi A/S, which control more than 10 percent, were also
able to sell shares at the same terms at Insero. </p>
<p>The yield on Dong''s 3013 hybrid bond eased to about 2.8
percent this week, compared with 5.238 when it was issued in
July last year. Its spread to the government yield curve has
narrowed to about 264 basis points from a high of 355 basis
points in January, a month after the government split. </p>
<h2>Popular Protest </h2>
<p>Goldman became the target of a popular protest in Denmark
after it emerged in December that the investment bank will
receive some veto rights over how Dong is managed in exchange
for its capital injection. Goldman has said it plans to follow
the current management''s strategy. </p>
<p>Dong explores for oil and natural gas in the North Sea and
is the world''s biggest builder of offshore wind turbine parks.
The company said yesterday net losses are narrowing and debt
shrinking after it completed a program of cuts and asset sales. </p>
<p>According to Jakob Magnussen, an analyst at Danske Bank
A/S, Dong''s hybrid bonds have also benefited from a general
appetite from investors for yields and risk-taking. </p>
<p>He recommends investors to buy into Dong''s two most recent
hybrid bonds with call options in 2018 and 2022, respectively,
as the bonds carry a limited risk to get extended. </p>
<p>Dong has very solid financial metrics, Magnussen said.
They''re actually much better than the company''s long-term
targets, so we''re expecting them to increase their leverage in
the coming quarters. They want to lower their funds from
operations to net debt margin to 30 percent from 55 percent
currently after they received new equity from Goldman and the
other shareholders. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jim Polson" date="Jun 29, 2014  5:48 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-29/exxon-mobil-reports-fire-oil-spill-at-nigeria-s-terminal.html"><headline>Exxon Mobil Reports Fire, Oil Spill at Nigeria''s Terminal</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) said thunderstorms
caused a tank fire June 27 and an oil spill today at the Mobil
Producing Nigeria Qua Iboe Terminal it operates in Akwa Ibom
state. </p>
<p>Offshore production and loading of oil continue, the
Irving, Texas-based company said today in a e-mailed statement.
No fatalities or injuries were reported. The amount of oil lost
to the fire and spill hasn''t been calculated, the company said. </p>
<p>Lightning ignited the tank and the fire was extinguished by
noon local time June 27, according to the statement. </p>
<p>Lightning knocked out power to the terminal again today,
resulting in a spill. Emergency response systems were activated
to contain it, shoreline restoration has begun and relevant
authorities and community leaders notified, according to the
statement. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ramsey Al-Rikabi" date="Jun 30, 2014  7:15 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-06-30/morgan-stanley-sees-no-flood-of-u-s-condensate-on-export-ruling.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Sees No Flood of U.S. Condensate on Export Ruling</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>U.S. approval for exporting some of
its ultra-light crude after minimal processing only broadens the
definition of refined products and won''t mean a sudden jump in
overseas shipments, according to Morgan Stanley. </p>
<p>While some producers are interested in exports, the ruling
to allow Pioneer Natural Resources Ltd. and Enterprise Products
Partners LP to ship condensates that have been run through a
distillation tower won''t significantly increase U.S. shipments
or limit supplies, Adam Longson, a New York-based analyst at the
bank, said in an e-mailed report today. </p>
<p>Anadarko Petroleum Corp. (APC), Marathon Oil Corp. (MRO) and Devon
Energy Corp. (DVN) also have access to similar technology and are
looking at the opportunity, Longson said, citing discussions
with the companies. </p>
<p>Our conversations don''t suggest a significant amount of
underutilized distillation capacity is available to drive up
exports anywhere near some of the estimates we have seen in the
press, he said. We are skeptical about reports of 500,000 to
1 million barrels a day of potential exports by year end. </p>
<p>Shipments could be challenged by limited infrastructure,
unattractive economics and uncertainty about the quality of
processed condensates, Longson said. </p>
<p>Limited pipeline connections and port capacity may restrict
volumes, and refining and exporting condensates may cost at
least $4 to $5 a barrel, leaving domestic use as the best
option, Longson said. Processing will affect the quality as
propane, butane and other light hydrocarbons, which are key
parts of traditional condensates, will be missing, he said in
the report. </p>
<h2>Distillation Tower </h2>
<p>Crude that has been processed through a distillation tower
to make petroleum products is no longer raw oil and can be
exported without a license, Jim Hock, a U.S. Commerce Department
spokesman, said June 24 in a written statement. The U.S.
prohibits most exports of unprocessed crude. </p>
<p>A distillation tower is traditionally used to heat crude or
condensate to remove fuels as they boil off at different
temperatures. It can also be used for condensates to remove
volatile hydrocarbons for safer storage and transport. </p>
<p>U.S crude production has boomed in recent years, spurred by
horizontal drilling and hydraulic fracturing in shale fields.
Output has risen 46 percent since the start of 2012 to almost
8.5 million barrels a day. Inventories reached 399.4 million
barrels in April, the highest since the Energy Information
Administration began publishing weekly data in 1982. </p>
<p>U.S. benchmark West Texas Intermediate crude has this year
traded at an average discount of $8.11 a barrel to Brent in
London, the international marker. Even with large scale
exports from the U.S., WTI will still trade at a discount of $5
to $8 a barrel to Brent, Longson said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bob Van Voris and Max Abelson" date="Jul 01, 2014  8:09 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-01/goldman-sachs-boys-club-accused-of-mocking-women.html"><headline>Goldman Boys Club'' Accused of Mocking Women as ''Bimbos'' and ''Party Girls''</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) was accused of widespread gender discrimination and a boy''s club atmosphere that included bouts of binge drinking and trips to strip clubs, as two former female employees seek to expand their lawsuit against the firm with new evidence. </p> <p>The women asked a federal judge in Manhattan today to let them sue on behalf of current and former female associates and vice presidents. Support for their claims includes statements of former Goldman Sachs employees, expert statistical analyses and evidence on earnings and promotions from the firm''s own records, they said in a court filing. </p> <p>Women report a boy''s club'' atmosphere, where binge drinking is common and women are either sexualized or ignored, according to the filing. </p> <p>Related:</p>
Rakuten''s Female Executive Strives to Narrow Gender Gap
Canada Told to Encourage More Women on Company Boards

Video: Why Do Professional Women Get the `Mom'' Question?

<p>The two women, H. Cristina Chen-Oster and Shanna Orlich, sued in 2010 and are seeking to broaden the case to include more than a decade of claimed discrimination at Goldman Sachs. A decision by U.S. District Judge Analisa Torres to allow the women to sue as a class would increase the risk to Goldman Sachs. </p> <p>In the lawsuit, filed in 2010, the women seek unspecified damages and an order requiring Goldman Sachs to fix the alleged gender bias at the firm. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
A pedestrian passes in front of the headquarters of Goldman Sachs Group Inc., in New York City. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jul 01, 2014  7:26 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-01/jpmorgan-ceo-dimon-will-undergo-treatment-for-throat-cancer-1-.html"><headline>JPMorgan Investors Show Support for Dimon in Cancer Fight</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Jamie Dimon, whose eight years atop JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) have made him one of Wall Street''s most powerful leaders, said he''ll start treatment for throat cancer, raising new questions about succession plans at the biggest U.S. bank. </p> <p>Dimon, the company''s chairman and chief executive officer, told employees and shareholders in a memo his condition is curable and that he''ll continue running the firm as normal during eight weeks of radiation and chemotherapy. The treatment will start soon at Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center in New York, limiting his travel, the CEO said. </p> <p>Dimon, 58, has led New York-based JPMorgan since the end of 2005, navigating the 2008 financial crisis without a loss and doubling annual profit as the lender''s shares climbed 45 percent. Six months ago, the board credited his ability to resolve government probes of the bank. The illness will revive questions about how the panel would theoretically handle his succession, said Ralph Cole, a portfolio manager at Ferguson Wellman Capital Management Inc. in Portland, Oregon. </p> <p>Transition has always been a question and now that will be at the top of investors'' minds, Cole said. They have to be very vocal about who''s going to be stepping up during the eight-week period. They''ve got to be clear with everybody about who that is. </p>




Photographer: Jason Alden/Bloomberg

<p>
Jamie Dimon, chief executive officer of JPMorgan Chase  Co. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Partington" date="Jul 01, 2014 10:53 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-01/jpmorgan-sells-corporate-dealing-services-business.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sells Corporate Dealing Services Business</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) agreed to sell a
business that manages stock-based pay plans for companies to
Equiniti Group Ltd., a closely held U.K. financial-services
provider. </p>
<p>Equiniti, based in Lancing, England, didn''t disclose what
it will pay for JPMorgan''s Corporate Dealing Services unit. The
transaction is scheduled to be completed by Aug. 31, Equiniti
said in a statement today. </p>
<p>The acquisition further strengthens our position, Paul
Matthews, managing director of corporate markets at Equiniti,
said in a statement. </p>
<p>The world''s biggest investment bank by revenue will partner
with Equiniti to offer dealing services for share-based
compensation packages to its corporate broking clients,
according to the statement. JPMorgan is the largest corporate
broker to companies in the FTSE 100, offering advice to 34
clients in the index, according to Adviser Ranking Ltd. </p>
<p>Equiniti was started in 2007 when Advent International
Corp. acquired Lloyds Banking Group Plc''s Lloyds TSB Registrars
shareholder-services business in a management buyout. The firm,
which manages share plans on behalf of customers, has 2,700
employees and a client base of 1,600 companies, a spokeswoman
for Equiniti said in an e-mail. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jul 01, 2014  9:58 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-01/goldman-fined-800-000-by-finra-over-dark-pool-pricing.html"><headline>Goldman Fined $800,000 by Finra Over Dark-Pool Pricing</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) was fined
$800,000 by the Financial Industry Regulatory Authority for
failing to have procedures in place to ensure clients in its
dark pool got the best price while trading stocks. </p>
<p>More than 395,000 transactions were executed in the New
York-based bank''s Sigma X pool at an inferior price to the
national best bid and offer from July 29 to Aug. 9, 2011, Finra
said today in a statement. Stock venues in the U.S. are obliged
to price trades at the NBBO or better. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs discovered the pricing errors and sent checks
to customers to compensate for the mistakes, people with direct
knowledge of the matter said in March. Finra said today that the
firm returned $1.67 million to affected customers. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs was unaware of the errors at the time,
according to the Finra statement. The Standard  Poor''s 500
Index tumbled 13 percent through the first eight days of August
2011, while the Chicago Board Options Exchange Volatility Index
hit a multiyear high of 48 on Aug. 8. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs neither admitted nor denied Finra''s charges.
Tiffany Galvin, a spokeswoman for the bank, declined to comment. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Jones" date="Jul 01, 2014  7:52 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-01/goldman-sachs-hires-jpmorgan-s-nuttall-to-multi-asset-tea.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Hires JPMorgan''s Nuttall to Multi Asset Team</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Asset Management (GSGEPPA) hired Neill Nuttall from JPMorgan Asset Management to join its multi asset investment strategy team. </p> <p>Nuttall was appointed co-chief investment officer of Goldman''s Global Portfolio Solutions Group and chairman of the GPS investment committee. He joined the firm in June and is based in London, said a spokesman for Goldman Sachs, confirming his appointment. </p> <p>Nuttall left JPMorgan in April after 30 years at the firm, where he most recently headed the Global Multi Asset Group, or GMAG, which oversees about $153 billion. JPMorgan last month appointed John Bilton from Bank of America Corp. to head the global strategy team, a role Nuttall also previously covered. </p> <p>We are delighted to have further strengthened our investment team with the recent appointment of Neill, Andrew Wilson, Goldman Sachs Asset Management''s CEO for Europe, the Middle East and Africa, said by e-mail. With over 30 years of investment experience, Neill will serve as the head of all of our investment activities, overseeing strategic and tactical allocation for the GPS Group. </p> <p>Firms including Invesco Perpetual and Aviva Investors have sought to capitalize on the growing demand for multi asset investing, where money is deployed across asset classes from equities to infrastructure. Two-thirds of money managers expect multi-asset investment strategies will be the biggest contributor to growth in the next three years, according to a State Street Corp. survey last month. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs''s GPS Group team includes about 70 globally. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sebastian Boyd" date="Jul 01, 2014  7:12 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-01/goldman-doubts-oil-rally-is-enough-for-venezuela-andes-credit.html"><headline>Goldman Doubts Oil Rally Is Enough for Venezuela: Andes Credit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Venezuelan bonds are posting the
world''s best returns after a surge in the price of oil, the
country''s biggest export. Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and Morgan
Stanley say buyers are unwise to bet $115-a-barrel crude can fix
a broken economy. </p>
<p>The government''s dollar-denominated notes have gained 5.9
percent since rebels took over swaths of northern Iraq on June
11, stoking concern that crude production will be hurt and
pushing Brent oil prices over $115 for the first time since
September. While the return was more than 14 times the average
for emerging-market debt, the extra yield of 8.63 percentage
points that investors demand to own Venezuela''s bonds instead of
U.S. Treasuries is still the highest in the world. </p>
<p>Any extra cash generated by the OPEC member''s oil exports
is likely to be siphoned off to pay for imports of consumer
goods amid shortages of drinking water, toilet paper and
medicine that have sparked anti-government protests, according
to Daniel Volberg, an economist at Morgan Stanley in New York.
After currency devaluations and energy output declines,
President Nicolas Maduro is struggling to prop up an economy
posting the world''s fastest inflation and facing the worst
growth prospects outside Equatorial Guinea, according to the
International Monetary Fund. </p>
<p>The level of macroeconomic dysfunction is so deep that
the story really isn''t about oil prices anymore, said Alberto Ramos, the chief Latin American economist at Goldman Sachs in
New York. Unless policies change dramatically, I''d be
concerned even with the oil price at $150. </p>
<h2>Currency Controls </h2>
<p>Since Maduro succeeded his mentor, the late Hugo Chavez, in
March 2013, the economy''s stagnation has deepened as currency
controls impeded imports and factories shut down. The number of
cars built in Venezuela fell 77 percent in the first five months
of this year as automakers including Ford Motor Co. and Toyota
Motor Corp. froze production while American Airlines Inc. (AAL) and
Air Canada have cut back flights to the country because of
difficulty getting money out. </p>
<p>Still, the nation has kept paying its debt. </p>
<p>Venezuelan dollar bonds have returned 19 percent this year,
the best performance among developing countries, as suppressed
interest rates in the U.S. and Europe boosted demand for higher-yielding assets. The average yield on Venezuela''s dollar debt is
the highest in the world at 11.16 percent, 0.8 percentage point
more than lower-rated Argentina, which faces default as soon as
July 30. </p>
<h2>Bank Meetings </h2>
<p>Venezuela will continue to meet its obligations, Rafael
Ramirez, the economy vice president, said June 27. Officials are
meeting representatives of Bank of America Corp. Citigroup Inc.,
Credit Suisse AG, Deutsche Bank AG and Goldman Sachs in Caracas
to discuss debt, Ramirez said. </p>
<p>Venezuela''s Finance Ministry didn''t respond to e-mail
messages sent yesterday seeking comment on the government''s
debt-payment policies. </p>
<p>Drew Benson, a spokesman for Credit Suisse in New York
declined to comment, as did Kerrie McHugh, a spokeswoman for
Deutsche Bank in New York. Press officers at Bank of America,
Citigroup and Goldman Sachs didn''t respond to requests for
comment. </p>
<h2>Economic Fundamentals </h2>
<p>This year''s rally in the bonds doesn''t make sense given
the direction fundamentals are going in Venezuela, Volberg
said. </p>
<p>The country''s international reserves fell 18 percent in the
last 12 months to $21 billion on June 27. Arrears to importers
and their banks may be worth as much as half the central bank''s
reported reserves, Volberg said. </p>
<p>Annual inflation reached 61 percent in May after the
government carried out its biggest devaluation since the
introduction of currency controls in 2003. The economy will
probably contract this year and next by as much as 1 percent,
according to the IMF. </p>
<p>While higher oil provides some benefits, signs that Maduro
is turning toward more pragmatic policies after four months of
unrest across the country may be more encouraging to investors,
according to Bank of America. </p>
<p>Last month Maduro fired Planning Minister Jorge Giordani, a
long-term advocate of currency controls who taught Chavez
economics in jail in the early 1990s. The country plans to merge
its three official foreign exchange rates, Ramirez told
investors in London in June. </p>
<h2>Exchange Rate </h2>
<p>The rates range from 6.3 bolivars per dollar to 50 bolivars
per dollar. On the black market, the bolivar trades at 72.18 per
dollar. The government is likely to unify exchange rates at
about 25 per dollar, according to Bank of America. </p>
<p>The cost to the government of exchanging its oil dollars
for bolivars at the official rate is the equivalent of 10
percent of gross domestic product, and authorities make that up
by printing money, according to Francisco Rodriguez, an
economist at Bank of America in New York. </p>
<p>Venezuela has a source of revenue it can use and with
unification it would pretty much solve its fiscal problem,
Rodriguez said by phone yesterday. </p>
<p>The country''s oil exports are falling as production wanes
at state-run Petroleos de Venezuela SA. Oil sales declined 8.4
percent last year to $114 billion, the company said June 27.
Output sank about 11,000 barrels a day in 2013 to a total of 2.9
million. </p>
<p>Technical indicators based on historical prices also
indicate the Venezuelan bonds may have risen too far, too fast.
The 14-day relative strength index on dollar bonds has been
above 70 since June 19, indicating they''re the most overbought
in two months. </p>
<p>The question is how long the markets are willing to give
Venezuela a free pass and how long this process can go on before
you have a more disorderly adjustment, Volberg said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bob Van Voris and Max Abelson" date="Jul 02, 2014  1:11 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-02/goldman-sachs-boy-s-club-accused-of-mocking-women.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Boy''s Club'' Accused of Mocking Women</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) was accused by two former employees seeking to expand their lawsuit of discriminating against women while male colleagues engaged in binge drinking and took clients to strip clubs. </p> <p>The women asked a federal judge in Manhattan yesterday to let them sue on behalf of current and former female associates and vice presidents. Support for their claims includes statements of former Goldman Sachs employees, expert statistical analyses and evidence on earnings and promotions from the firm''s own records, they said in a court filing. </p> <p>Women report a boy''s club'' atmosphere, where binge drinking is common and women are either sexualized or ignored, according to the filing. </p> <p>The two women, H. Cristina Chen-Oster and Shanna Orlich, sued in 2010 and are seeking to broaden the case to include more than a decade of claimed discrimination at Goldman Sachs. A decision by U.S. District Judge Analisa Torres to allow the women to sue as a class would increase the risk to the New York-based company. </p> <p>In the lawsuit, filed in 2010, the women seek unspecified damages and an order requiring Goldman Sachs to fix the alleged gender bias at the firm. </p> <h2>Salaries, Promotions </h2> <p>Female vice presidents earned 21 percent less than men and female associates made 8 percent less, the former employees claimed. About 23 percent fewer female vice presidents were promoted to managing director of the bank relative to their male counterparts, they said. </p> <p>Those statistics are attributed to an analysis of Goldman Sachs pay data by Henry S. Farber, a Princeton University economist. His samples included all associates and vice presidents in the firm''s New York class from 2003 to 2011 and throughout the U.S. from 2005 to 2011, according to a court filing yesterday. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs has denied the women''s claims and is fighting the case. The bank believes the statistical arguments are misleading and don''t compare similar employees to one another, said a person briefed on its legal strategy who requested anonymity because the firm hasn''t responded to the data in court. </p> <p>This is a normal and anticipated procedural step for any proposed class action lawsuit and does not change the case''s lack of merit, David Wells, a Goldman Sachs spokesman, said yesterday in an e-mailed statement. </p> <h2>Strip Clubs </h2> <p>Chen-Oster and Orlich are seeking to persuade Torres that their claims are sufficiently similar to those of other women at Goldman Sachs so they can represent them in a single case. </p> <p>They''re asking Torres to certify a class of female associates and vice presidents who worked for the company in the U.S. in its investment banking, investment management and securities divisions beginning Sept. 10, 2004. The start date for employees who worked in New York City would be July 7, 2002. </p> <p>Denise Shelley, a vice president who left the firm in 2009, said in a court filing that men at Goldman Sachs repeatedly called women bimbos, mocked a new hire who had won a beauty pageant and took clients to strip clubs. Shelley said in the filing that she sat on the steering committee of the firm''s network for women and, after joining colleagues at a bar, was called a party girl by a managing director. </p> <p>The case is Chen-Oster v. Goldman Sachs  Co., 10-cv-06950, U.S. District Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jul 02, 2014 10:28 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-02/jpmorgan-investors-show-support-for-dimon-in-cancer-fight.html"><headline>JPMorgan Investors Show Support for Dimon in Cancer Fight</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Jamie Dimon, whose eight years atop JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) have made him one of Wall Street''s most powerful leaders, said he''ll start treatment for throat cancer, raising new questions about succession plans at the biggest U.S. bank. </p> <p>Dimon, the company''s chairman and chief executive officer, told employees and shareholders in a memo his condition is curable and that he''ll continue running the firm as normal during eight weeks of radiation and chemotherapy. The treatment will start soon at Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center in New York, limiting his travel, the CEO said. </p> <p>Dimon, 58, has led New York-based JPMorgan since the end of 2005, navigating the 2008 financial crisis without a loss and doubling annual profit as the lender''s shares climbed about 45 percent. Six months ago, the board credited his ability to resolve government probes of the bank. The illness will revive questions about how the panel would theoretically handle his succession, said Ralph Cole, a portfolio manager at Ferguson Wellman Capital Management Inc. in Portland, Oregon. </p> <p>Transition has always been a question and now that will be at the top of investors'' minds, Cole said. They have to be very vocal about who''s going to be stepping up during the eight-week period. They''ve got to be clear with everybody about who that is. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
James "Jamie" Dimon, chief executive officer of JPMorgan Chase  Co., outside of the White House after meeting with with President Barack Obama in this Oct. 2, 2013 file photo. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Candice Zachariahs" date="Jul 02, 2014  3:35 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-02/goldman-names-hutton-to-head-bond-currency-sales-in-australia.html"><headline>Goldman Names Hutton to Head Bond, Currency Sales in Australia</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. has
appointed Nell Hutton to head its fixed-income, currency and
commodities sales for Australia and New Zealand, an internal
memo showed. </p>
<p>Hutton will report both to Simon Rothery, chief executive
officer of Goldman Sachs'' Australian operations, and to James Houghton, head of fixed-income, currency and commodities
distribution for Asia Pacific ex-Japan, according to the memo
seen by Bloomberg News. Hutton, who previously oversaw corporate
advisory solutions in the region, joined Goldman in 1999 in
London, relocated to Australia in 2006, and was named a managing
director in 2007, the memo showed. </p>
<p>Rothery said in a Feb. 27 interview that Australian fixed-income trading was his biggest growth area in the country. </p>
<p>Australia''s stable AAA credit rating made the nation a
haven and has encouraged inflows from sovereign-wealth funds, he
said. Goldman Sachs also saw opportunities to arrange debt
offerings and capture more of the market for Kangaroo bonds, or
Australian dollar-denominated securities sold by overseas
borrowers, Rothery said at the time. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Rakteem Katakey" date="Jul 02, 2014  2:08 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-02/exxon-to-invest-1-billion-to-produce-diesel-at-antwerp-refinery.html"><headline>Exxon to Invest $1 Billion to Produce Diesel at Antwerp Refinery</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM), the world''s
biggest energy company by market value, will invest $1 billion
to increase diesel production at its Antwerp refinery . </p>
<p>The company will add a delayed coker unit at the 320,000
barrel-a-day refinery in Belgium that will convert high-sulfur
oil to diesel for use in trucks and ships, the Irving, Texas-based company said in a statement today. Exxon has spent $2
billion in the past decade on expansions in the refinery
including a 130 megawatt power plant and hydrotreater unit that
reduces sulfur from fuels, the company said. </p>
<p>The investment addresses an industry shortfall in
capability to convert fuel oil to products such as diesel,
Exxon said in the statement. The expansion is the first of
several being evaluated to further strengthen strategic
refineries in Europe to more successfully face the challenging
industry environment. </p>
<p>Exxon''s announcement comes after Total SA (FP), the biggest
refiner in western Europe, reported a 10 percent decline in
profit in the quarter ended March 31 on smaller crude-processing
margins caused by overcapacity. European refinery margins shrank
to $6.60 per metric ton of crude processed in the three months
from $26.90 a year earlier, Total said in April, citing its
European Refining Margin Indicator. </p>
<p>Exxon''s shares have increased 0.2 percent this year,
compared with the 6.8 percent gain in the SP 500 Index (SPX) and a
2.3 percent advance in the Dow Jones Industrial Average. The
stock gained 0.7 percent to $101.36 in New York yesterday. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Natalie Obiko Pearson" date="Jul 03, 2014  5:14 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-03/goldman-backed-renew-power-raises-additional-140-million.html"><headline>Goldman-Backed ReNew Power Raises Additional $140 Million</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>ReNew Power Ventures Pvt., a
financier of wind and solar farms in India, raised $140 million
from Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), the Global Environment Fund and
Asian Development Bank. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs will provide an additional $70 million, ReNew
said today in an e-mailed statement. It has already invested
$385 million in the Gurgaon-based developer since 2011. The ADB
will invest $50 million and an Indian fund managed by GEF will
provide $20 million, according to the statement. </p>
<p>The money will allow ReNew to double its clean-energy
portfolio to 1,000 megawatts by 2015, ReNew said. Goldman Sachs
has invested more than $3 billion in clean energy companies such
as Nordex SE (NDX1) and Dong Energy A/S, according to the statement. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kevin Crowley and Rene Vollgraaff" date="Jul 04, 2014 11:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-04/general-motors-halts-south-africa-plant-as-union-wage-talks-fail.html"><headline>GM Halts South Africa Carmaking After Wage Talks Collapse</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Wage talks to end a four-day strike
by more than 220,000 metalworkers in South Africa failed
yesterday as protests turned violent and General Motors Co. (GM) and
Bayerische Motoren Werke AG halted production. </p>
<p>The National Union of Metalworkers of South Africa rejected
an improved offer from the Steel and Engineering Industries
Federation of Southern Africa, the employer group said in an e-mailed statement today. The strike that began on July 1 has been
marred by violence and prompted Moody''s Investors Service to
warn yesterday that the country''s credit rating may be at risk. </p>
<p>Seifsa, as the employers'' group is known, said its offer to
raise wages for the lowest-paid workers by 10 percent this year
was the best it could make. No further talks are planned with
Numsa, which is demanding a 12 percent pay increase and a ban on
labor brokers. </p>
<p>General Motors shut its plant in the eastern coastal city
of Port Elizabeth as the strike in the metal and engineering
sector has impacted upon supply of components to our production
line, Gishma Johnson, the company''s spokeswoman, said in an e-mailed statement. </p>
<p>GM, which has a target to build 50,000 vehicles a year in
South Africa, said its assembly of light commercial autos such
as Isuzu trucks and Chevrolet utility vehicles is affected by
the stoppage. </p>
<h2>Vehicle Loss </h2>
<p>BMW brought forward a week of planned maintenance at its
plant outside Pretoria, halting production on July 1, spokesman
Guy Kilfoil said by phone today. The factory will reopen on July
8 with two shifts instead of the normal three if the strike
continues, he said. That may result in the loss of 120 vehicles
a day, he said. </p>
<p>If the strike goes beyond two weeks, the risks to vehicle
manufacturers and production plants will increase
substantially, Nico Vermeulen, director of the National
Association of Automobile Manufacturers of South Africa, said by
phone from Pretoria. </p>
<p>A Numsa strike over pay at carmakers between August and
October last year cost the industry at least 20 billion rand
($1.8 billion) in revenue, according to Naamsa. </p>
<p>The current stoppage follows a five-month strike by more
than 70,000 platinum miners that caused South Africa''s economy
to contract in the first quarter of the year. Finance Minister
Nhlanhla Nene said this week the government''s economic growth
target of 2.7 percent this year will probably be missed. </p>
<h2>Labor Talks </h2>
<p>Labor Minister Mildred Oliphant is meeting with employers
to seek a resolution to the strike and will hold talks with
union leaders later, Mokgadi Pela, her spokesman, said by phone. </p>
<p>Police arrested 26 people today after several incidents of
violence by striking workers at factories around Johannesburg.
In Benoni, east of Johannesburg, more than 2,000 workers forced
their way onto business premises, damaging equipment and
computers, police said in an e-mailed statement. Protesters were
shot with rubber bullets after stoning police and breaking
through a factory gate in Elandsfontein. </p>
<p>Companies including Bell Equipment Ltd. (BEL) and Evraz Highveld
Steel  Vanadium Ltd. as well as units of Murray  Roberts
Holdings Ltd. and Aveng Ltd. (AEG) are affected by the stoppage. </p>
<p>The strike is also harming construction at Eskom Holdings
SOC Ltd.''s Medupi and Kusile power plants. Police used rubber
bullets to disperse 400 to 500 protesting workers at the Medupi
site in Limpopo province yesterday. There were no reported
incidents today, Eskom spokesman Andrew Etzinger said by phone. </p>
<p>Numsa yesterday denied allegations that its members were
involved in violence, saying in a statement that the reports are
part of a cheap ploy by the employers to undermine the
integrity of our struggle for a living wage and improved
conditions of employment. </p>
<p>Castro Ngobese, the union''s spokesman, wasn''t immediately
available when contacted by phone today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Gaspard Sebag and Aoife White" date="Jul 04, 2014 10:04 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2014-07-04/microsoft-taxes-said-to-face-scrutiny-as-eu-quizzes-luxembourg.html"><headline>Microsoft Taxes Said to Face Scrutiny as EU Quizzes Luxembourg</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), the world''s biggest
software maker, is among companies embroiled in a European Union
inquiry into Luxembourg''s tax treatment of multinational firms,
according to three people familiar with the EU''s review. </p>
<p>The European Commission has quizzed Luxembourg about how it
taxes Microsoft''s intellectual property, said one of the people,
who asked not to be identified because the matter is private.
Competition regulators also asked questions about McDonald''s
Corp. (MCD)''s taxes in Luxembourg, two of the people said. Amazon.com
Inc.''s tax affairs there are also being looked at, the Financial
Times reported yesterday, citing an EU official. </p>
<p>Amid a global crackdown on tax avoidance, EU competition
regulators last month opened a probe into suspected tax breaks
for Apple Inc. (AAPL) in Ireland, Starbucks Corp. (SBUX) in the Netherlands
and Fiat Finance  Trade SA in Luxembourg, the bloc''s richest
country in per capita terms. </p>
<p>We are in constant contact with the European Commission
on all these tax issues and Luxembourg is pretty confident in
the way it handles its taxation issues and so we''re going to
monitor the information with the commission and hand over the
information that is requested, Pierre Gramegna, Luxembourg
Finance Minister, said today on CNBC. </p>
<p>The scrutiny of Luxembourg is also a potential
embarrassment for Jean-Claude Juncker, who is primed to become
the next president of the commission -- the EU''s executive arm
in charge of the investigation. Juncker, who led Luxembourg
until last year, helped the country win a reputation as an
attractive location for international companies. </p>
<h2>Member States </h2>
<p>The commission continues to gather information about
certain tax practices in several member states, Antoine Colombani, spokesman for Competition Commissioner Joaquin Almunia, said. However we will not make any comment on whether
specific companies may or may not be covered by this information
gathering exercise. </p>
<p>Sabina Gockel, a spokeswoman for Microsoft in Brussels,
declined to comment. Joanna Kwiatkowska, a spokeswoman for
McDonald''s in the U.K., didn''t immediately respond to calls and
an e-mail seeking comment. </p>
<p>Natasha Bertaud, a spokeswoman for Juncker at the
commission, said the former Luxembourg premier also has no
comment. Lawmakers at the European Parliament are scheduled to
vote on his appointment later this month. </p>
<p>Lucien Michels, a spokesman for Luxembourg''s finance
ministry, declined to comment on Amazon''s possible involvement
in the tax inquiry. He didn''t immediately respond to e-mailed
questions concerning other companies. </p>
<h2>French Unit </h2>
<p>McDonald''s denied earlier this year a magazine report that
it avoided paying taxes related to more than $3 billion of
revenue in France since 2009, saying inspections by fiscal
authorities at its French unit were routine. </p>
<p>The EU''s investigations of Apple, Starbucks and Fiat
Finance focus on so-called transfer-pricing arrangements on
taxing commercial transactions between company units. </p>
<p>The commission has said it will continue a wider inquiry
into those deals, including information gathering from the U.K.,
Belgium, Cyprus and Malta. Governments can be ordered by the
European Commission to claw back unfair aid. </p>
<p>The EU has also sought details from Belgium, Spain, France,
Hungary, Luxembourg, the Netherlands, the U.K., Cyprus and Malta
on so-called patent boxes, which allow tax reductions on income
from patents. </p>
<p>The EU request for information on Amazon relates to whether
Luxembourg''s tax decisions on the company complied with state-aid rules, the FT said. Amazon''s press office in the U.K. didn''t
respond to a call for comment. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry></news>