<?xml version='1.0' encoding='us-ascii'?>
<news><entry author="By Peter J. Brennan" date="Nov 04, 2007  2:38 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-11-04/berkshire-dte-energy-lilly-pfizer-u-s-equity-preview.html"><headline>Berkshire, DTE Energy, Lilly, Pfizer: U.S. Equity Preview</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;The following is a list of companies
whose shares may have unusual price changes in U.S. exchanges
tomorrow. This preview includes news that broke after exchanges
closed. Stock symbols are in parentheses after company names. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abbott Laboratories (ABT) : The drugmaker's experimental
combination pill Simcor worked as well as the two drugs it seeks
to replace in lowering the harmful form of cholesterol and
increasing the beneficial type, a study showed. Abbott stock
fell 7 cents to $54.05 on Nov. 2. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;American International Group Inc. (AIG) : The company's
former chief executive, Maurice ``Hank'' Greenberg, began a
campaign to shake up the insurer's management and may seek the
sale of some units, he said Nov. 2 in a filing. The shares of
New York-based AIG, the world's largest insurer, rose $2.43, or
4.1 percent, in extended trading to $61.55. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Berkshire Hathaway Inc. (BRK/A) (BRK/A US): The investment company
controlled by billionaire investor Warren Buffett said third-quarter profit surged 64 percent after gains from its investment
in PetroChina Co. The stock rose $1,250 to $132,500 in regular
trading. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Citigroup Inc. (C) : The crisis of leadership at the
largest U.S. bank may hit a climax this weekend amid speculation
that Chief Executive Officer Charles O. ``Chuck'' Prince III
will resign. The company has had widening losses from bad
mortgage debts. The stock gained $1.31, or 3.5 percent, to
$39.04 in extended trading. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Delta Petroleum Corp. (DPTR US): The U.S. oil and gas
producer may fall at least 20 percent this year and possibly
into the next without a gas discovery soon, Barron's said,
without citing anyone. Delta Petroleum shares fell 61 cents, or
3.5 percent, to $16.94 on Nov. 2. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DTE Energy Co. (DTE) : The owner of Michigan's largest
utility said operating earnings excluding synthetic fuel are
expected to be $425 million to $450 million this year, down from
a previous forecast of as much as $485 million. The stock rose
27 cents to $48.99 in regular trading on Nov. 2. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eli Lilly  Co. (LLY) : The drugmaker's experimental drug
with Daiichi Sankyo Co., prasugrel, for blocking clot formation
is potentially more dangerous than Plavix, the best-selling
medicine for this condition, a study found. The research
compared prasugrel to Bristol-Myers Squibb Co. (BMY)'s and Sanofi-Aventis SA's Plavix. Lilly shares fell 10 cents to $52.67 in
regular trading, and Bristol-Myers declined 28 cents to $28.88. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Force Protection Inc. (FRPT US): The largest supplier of
blast-resistant trucks to the U.S. Marine Corps said it extended
royalty fees to through 2012 to the Republic of South Africa's
Council for Scientific and Industrial Research for the transfer
of intellectual property rights, according to a regulatory
filing. The stock lost 1 cent to $17.75 in regular trading. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;KB Home (KBH) : The homebuilder said in a regulatory
filing that Ray Irani resigned from the company's board. No
reason was given for the move by Irani. The stock fell 77 cents,
or 3 percent, to $25.11 in regular trading on Nov. 2. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kenneth Cole Productions Inc. (KCP US): The designer of
shoes and handbags may reach $50 as it expands into men's
sportswear and clothing, Barron's reported, without citing
anyone. Kenneth Cole gained 9 cents to $18 in regular trading. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mattel Inc. (MAT) : The world's largest toymaker may rise
to $30 in the next 12 months as it rebounds from toy recalls,
Barron's said, citing Linda Bolton Weiser, a toy analyst at
Oppenheimer  Co. Mattel stock fell 4 cents to $20.50 on Nov. 2. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Northern Trust Corp. (NTRS) : The Chicago-based custodian
of financial assets may climb 10 percent or more annually,
because its loans aren't threatened by the upheaval in the
credit and housing markets, Barron's reported, without citing
anyone. Northern Trust gained $1.35 to $72.84. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer Inc. (PFE) : The drugmaker said it will present
new data about its top-selling Lipitor cholesterol pill's
effects on patients' cardiovascular and kidney function tomorrow
and Nov. 6 at a heart conference. The company's stock fell 28
cents to $23.67 on Nov. 2. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seaboard Corp. (SEB) : The second-largest U.S. hog
producer said third-quarter net income fell 14 percent to $52.6
million, or $41.75 a share. The stock rose $6.12 to $1,607.12 in
regular trading. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;WellCare Health Plans Inc. (WCG) : The provider of
managed-care services said a board committee will investigate
matters raised in probes by state and federal agencies. WellCare
also will delay filing its quarterly financial report. The
company cited a U.S. Department of Justice press release on Oct.
24 that said review shouldn't ``have any impact upon, the
delivery of any health care service.'' In after hours trading,
the stock rose $6.61, or 24 percent, to $33.98. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Peter J. Brennan in Los Angeles at 
pbrennan3@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Sylvia Wier at  swier@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Lisa Rapaport" date="Nov 08, 2007  4:16 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-11-08/j-j-pfizer-drugs-may-reap-1-billion-fighting-germs-update2-.html"><headline>J&amp;amp;J, Pfizer Drugs May Reap $1 Billion Fighting Germs</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;The outbreak of drug-resistant
infections in U.S. hospitals and schools may provide both
Johnson  Johnson (JNJ) and Pfizer Inc. with a $1 billion windfall in
a market that analysts expect will double in five years. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JJ, the world's largest health-products company, and
Pfizer, the biggest drugmaker, are poised to release new
antibiotics next year to treat MRSA, or methicillin-resistant
Staphylococcus aureus. The germ sickens about 2 million
Americans annually, costs about $20 billion a year to treat, and
has reinvigorated the search for new antibiotics. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two experimental drugs, modified versions of older
medicines, may create a $2.5 billion market in treatments
against MRSA and other drug-resistant bacteria that kill 20,000
Americans a year, analysts say. New York-based Pfizer needs new
medicines by 2011 to counter generic competition for drugs that
generated about half of 2006 revenue. JJ faces a similar
erosion beginning in 2009 of 41 percent of last year's drug
sales. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``Pfizer and JJ are going to get a survivor benefit from
sticking with antibiotics after almost every other big
pharmaceutical company cut back in this area,'' said Les Funtleyder, an analyst with Miller Tabak  Co. in New York, in a
telephone interview. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wyeth's Tygacil, the first in a new family of medicines for
MRSA known as glycylcyclines, was introduced in 2005 and will
have peak sales of more than $1 billion, the Madison, New
Jersey-based drugmaker projects. Its success, and the rising
MRSA menace, has spurred antibiotic research, analysts say. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;`Urgent Need' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``Given the urgent need for more effective antibiotics
against MRSA, I would expect the new entries from Pfizer and JJ
to perform as well as Tygacil, if not better,'' said Danielle
Drayton, an analyst with Waltham, Massachusetts-based drug
research firm Decision Resources, in a telephone interview. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JJ rose 68 cents, or 1.1 percent, to $64.59 at 4:01 p.m.
in New York Stock Exchange composite trading, and has declined
2.2 percent this year. Pfizer fell 21 cents to $23.11, and has
fallen 11 percent in 2007. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, Pfizer and New Brunswick, New Jersey-based
JJ separately obtained the drugs from biotechnology companies
working on rival antibiotics. Pfizer's $1.9 billion acquisition
of Vicuron Pharmaceuticals Inc. in June 2005 provided access to
dalbavancin, an updated version of a class of medicines known as
glycopeptides introduced in 1958. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JJ in February 2005 agreed to pay Basilea (BSLN) Pharmaceutica
AG, based in Basel, Switzerland, about $308 million to jointly
develop ceftobiprole, part of a group of antibiotics known as
cephalosporins. First marketed 40 years ago, the group includes
Roche Holding AG's Rocephin. JJ won rights to ceftobiprole
after Roche, also based in Basel, declined to license it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;`Strategic Deals' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``These strategic deals have positioned Pfizer and JJ to
come out ahead as panic over MRSA spins out of control,'' said
Funtleyder. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MRSA is found in about 4.6 percent of hospital patients,
and accounts for almost two-thirds of skin infections in
emergency rooms, up from just 2 percent 35 years ago. About one
in 20 patients hospitalized with the drug-resistant bacterium
dies, according to the U.S. Agency for Healthcare Research and
Quality. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because JJ's new antibiotic is in a class that works
against a wider variety of germs, it may have an edge over
Pfizer (PFE)'s product, said Drayton. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``Doctors will use a broad spectrum agent like ceftobiprole
early as a single therapy to replace older regimens that
included multiple antibiotics,'' she said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Outside the Hospital &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer's dalbavancin may be chosen to treat patients
outside the hospital because it can be injected once a week.
Vancomycin, the oldest medicine in this family, must be injected
as often as four times daily, requiring costly hospitalization
until patients complete treatment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dalbavancin was delayed by the U.S. Food and Drug
Administration in June 2006. The company resubmitted its
application to the FDA in June 2007 and expects a decision this
year, said Pfizer spokesman Francisco Gebauer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bacteria frequently mutate into forms that aren't sensitive
to existing antibiotics. Staph bacteria typically enter the body
through a cut or scrape and cause only minor skin problems.
These can escalate into fatal bloodstream infections and
pneumonia in children, the elderly and patients whose disease-fighting immune systems are weakened. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``As MRSA infections spread from the hospitals into the
community we're seeing that the more drugs you use, the more
resistance you get,'' said Richard Wenzel, chair of internal
medicine at Virginia Commonwealth University School of Medicine
in Richmond. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;`Swiss Cheese' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When 5 percent of patients stop responding to a medicine
for MRSA, hospitals need another option. ``We're talking about
patients who present in shock with lungs that look like Swiss
cheese,'' said Wenzel. ``If we keep using a drug until one in 10
people can't take it, all we do is breed an even worse strain of
MRSA.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concern that medicines were breeding resistance led
doctors to reserve vancomycin for the most critical patients.
Now, vancomycin use is growing in response to more deadly germs,
and so is resistance to it. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``Antibiotics like vancomycin that were kept on the shelf
for emergencies for decades are losing effectiveness and we
don't have anything yet to replace it,'' said Janice Reichert, a
senior research fellow at the Tufts Center for the Study of Drug
Development in Boston. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Theravance (THRX) Inc. of South San Francisco, California, is
seeking FDA approval for its glycopeptide called Televancin. The
agency sent the company a letter last month delaying approval by
asking how the drug is made and how the label will be worded,
analysts say. Thervance is developing the antibiotic with Tokyo-based Astellas Pharma Inc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Competitors' Drugs &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Targanta Therapeutics Corp. of Cambridge, Massachusetts, is
also in the final stages of human testing for a new
glycopeptide, called oritavancin, and plans to seek FDA approval
in the first quarter of 2008. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New York-based Forest (FRX) Laboratories Inc. is in the final
stages of human trials with another new cephalosporin, called
ceftaroline, which the company gained from its $480 million
purchase of closely held Cerexa Inc. last year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Lisa Rapaport in New York at 
Lrapaport1@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Robert Simison at 
rsimison@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Yi Tian" date="Nov 23, 2007 11:59 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-11-23/apple-citigroup-jpmorgan-whole-foods-u-s-equity-movers.html"><headline>Apple, Citigroup, JPMorgan, Whole Foods: U.S. Equity Movers</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;The following is a list of companies
whose shares are having unusual price changes in U.S. exchanges
today. U.S. stock markets were closed yesterday for
Thanksgiving. Stock symbols are in parentheses after company
names. Share prices are as of 11:40 a.m. in New York. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apple Inc. (AAPL)  gained $2.01, or 1.2 percent, to
$170.47, the highest in two weeks. The maker of the iPod music
player agreed to pay $10 million to settle a patent-infringement
lawsuit by Burst.com Inc. (BRST US) over technology that stores
audio and video files. The settlement, which isn't yet final,
provides Apple with a license to Burst.com's patents, plus a
pledge that Burst won't sue Apple again over future patents,
Burst said. Burst.com lost 26 cents, or 47 percent, 29 cents, a
four-year low. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E*Trade Financial Corp. (ETFC)  gained the most since
Nov. 13, rising 92 cents, or 22 percent, to $5.18. The third-largest online broker is in talks to sell all or part of itself,
financial news channel CNBC reported, citing people familiar
with the discussions whom it didn't identify. Pam Erickson, a
spokeswoman for E*Trade, did not immediately return a call
seeking comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frontline Ltd. (FRO)  gained the most since August 2005,
adding $3.62, or 8.5 percent, to $46. Prices for shipping Middle
East crude to Asia, the world's busiest market for supertankers,
surged by the most in more than two years yesterday as an
oversupply of vessels cleared. Frontline is the biggest operator
of supertankers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teekay Corp. (TK) , the largest owner of oil-tankers,
gained 10 percent to $53.16. Overseas Shipholding Group Inc.
(OSG US), the largest U.S.-based oil tanker owner, increased 9
percent to $65.70. Nordic American Tanker Shipping Ltd. (NAT) , an operator of crude-oil tankers, jumped 8.6 percent to
$32.60. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM)  was the biggest gainer in the
Dow Jones Industrial Average, adding $1.30, or 3.2 percent, to
$41.98. The Wall Street Journal reported that Citigroup Inc. (C) , Bank of America Corp. (BAC US) and JPMorgan, which have
been putting together a plan to revive credit markets, are
likely to start asking other banks to sign up to specific
financial terms next week. Citigroup rose 2.7 percent to $31.55.
Bank of America gained 2.2 percent to $43.07. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Millicom International Cellular SA (MICC US) rose the most
since Nov. 13, gaining $4.64, or 4.4 percent, to $109.12. Morgan
Stanley lifted its share-price estimate for the Luxembourg-based
mobile-phone company to $150 from $109. Subscriber market share
may accelerate in Latin America, analysts wrote, citing a
``recent more aggressive approach'' to growth in Africa. The
stock remains among their ``top picks,'' they said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nastech Pharmaceutical Co. (NSTK US) dropped 17 cents, or
4.2 percent, to $3.87, the lowest since May 2000. The developer
of medicines given by nasal spray said it began cutting 72 jobs,
or about a third of its workforce, after a collaboration with
Procter  Gamble Pharmaceuticals Inc. ended. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PMI Group Inc. (PMI US) gained the most since Nov. 13,
rising $1.25, or 12 percent, to $11.44. Financial Guaranty
Insurance Co., the bond insurer partly controlled by PMI Group
and Blackstone Group LP (BX) , may get the capital it needs to
avoid losing top credit rankings after French banks bailed out
competitor CIFG Guaranty, Fitch Ratings said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blackstone, manager of the world's biggest leveraged buyout
fund, added 1.8 percent to $21.40. MBIA Inc. (MBI) , the
biggest bond insurer, climbed 6.9 percent to $34.40. Ambac
Financial Group Inc. (ABK US), the second-largest, rose 6.4
percent to $25.68. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Temple-Inland Inc. (TIN US) gained the most since Nov. 13,
adding 73 cents, or 1.7 percent, to $42.77. Billionaire Carl Icahn increased the stake in the paper-packaging maker to 9.7
percent from 8.9 percent, according to a Securities and Exchange
Commission filing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tibco Software Inc. (TIBX)  gained the most since Oct.
12, climbing 50 cents, or 7.4 percent, to $7.25. The maker of
business programs was upgraded to ``peer perform'' from
``underperform'' at Bear Stearns  Co. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whole Foods Market Inc. (WFM)  had the steepest decline
in the Standard  Poor's 500 Index, dropping $1.43, or 3.5
percent, to $40. Shares of the largest U.S. natural-foods grocer
may not be worth the premium investors have been paying over
U.S. supermarket rivals because competition and higher costs may
impede its profit growth, the Wall Street Journal said in its
``Heard on the Street'' column. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Yi Tian in New York at  tian8@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Chris Nagi at  chrisnagi@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Dermot Doherty" date="Nov 30, 2007 12:31 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-11-30/roche-may-take-cholesterol-market-after-pfizer-failed-update4-.html"><headline>Roche May Take Cholesterol Market After Pfizer Failed</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Roche Holding AG may transform
itself from the largest seller of cancer therapies to the
biggest drugmaker in the $15 billion-a-year cholesterol market
by succeeding where a Pfizer Inc. (PFE) medicine failed last year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roche will probably begin a clinical trial for regulatory
approval of a heart-disease treatment next year. The Basel,
Switzerland-based company says its candidate, called R1658,
doesn't cause the blood-pressure increase that forced Pfizer to
terminate testing of a similar pill. The drug would head off
heart attacks by raising levels of HDL, the body's so-called
good cholesterol. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost 50 percent of Roche's 33.3 billion Swiss francs ($30
billion) in pharmaceutical revenue came from Avastin and tumor-fighting medicines last year, and the sales growth of one,
Herceptin for breast cancer, is slowing. A blockbuster
cholesterol treatment will keep Roche's profit rising after
Herceptin and other older products lose patent protection. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``It could be the most expensive trial Roche has ever run,
but it could be worth it as the drug has the potential to
eventually replace the sales of Avastin,'' said Denise Anderson,
an analyst at Landsbanki Kepler in Zurich. Avastin ``is such a
big drug that you'd need 10 normal-sized drugs, or one huge
drug, to replace it.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Avastin brought in 1.06 billion Swiss francs in the third
quarter, when Roche's total sales missed analyst estimates and
the company had its biggest decline in 13 months in Zurich
trading. Herceptin third-quarter revenue rose at the slowest
rate in five quarters. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Share Performance &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roche gained 1.4 Swiss francs to 215.5 francs in Zurich
trading. The shares have fallen about 1.4 percent this year
while Switzerland's benchmark SMI Index of 20 companies has
risen 0.5 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merck  Co. (MRK) is working on a cardiac drug similar to the one
Roche is developing, and Pfizer is reviewing two new cholesterol
treatments. R1658 and its Actemra arthritis medicine are among
the most promising new drugs Roche has in development. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``It's certainly got mega-blockbuster potential,'' Anderson
said. ``Merck and Roche would have the market to themselves, and
that's $15 billion for the winner.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lipitor, the world's best-selling drug, with $12.9 billion
in sales last year, accounts for about 40 percent of New York-based Pfizer's profit. Generic copies of cholesterol-fighting
Lipitor may come on the market as early as 2010 when its patent
expires. Pfizer shares have fallen about 13 percent in the past
12 months as the drugmaker has failed to find a Lipitor
replacement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Competitors Products &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Development (ROG) of the Roche cholesterol medicine won't be
cheap, or without risk. Pfizer spent about $1 billion before
halting work on torcetrapib, the drug it had intended to replace
some of the revenue lost when Lipitor loses patent protection.
U.S. regulators will probably demand rigorous testing of
compounds in the unproven class called CETP inhibitors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``This could potentially be a massive market, but the
endpoints of these trials are very hard to reach,'' said Andrew Fellows, an analyst at Helvea Ltd. in London. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Merck, based in Whitehouse Station, New Jersey, is still
reviewing data from Pfizer's torcetrapib study to determine
whether it will begin the final stage of testing of anacetrapib,
spokesman Ron Rogers said in an e-mail. Pfizer has two other
CETP inhibitors in the first of three clinical trials required
for U.S. regulatory approval. The U.S. drugmaker has suspended
development of both compounds and hasn't disclosed its plans for
the medicines, said Vanessa Aristide, a Pfizer spokesperson. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Good Cholesterol &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CETP inhibitors block the cholesterol ester transfer
protein that turns good cholesterol into LDL, the fatty protein
that at high levels can lead to clogged arteries. The HDL form
of cholesterol is linked to a reduced incidence of heart attacks
and cardiovascular disease. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roche has provided few details on the compound, licensed
from Japan Tobacco Inc. of Tokyo in 2004. The Swiss drugmaker
said last month it was leaning towards starting a phase III
trial, the last generally needed for regulatory approval. Roche
has also said results from a previous study were encouraging. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``It's got a unique chemical structure that's different to
that of our competitors' compounds and it's been generally well
tolerated, which is why we think that the CETP mechanism itself
is not associated with an increase in blood pressure,'' said
Martina Rupp, a spokeswoman at Roche. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Backed by Studies &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roche's position is backed by studies reported at the
American Heart Association's annual meeting in Orlando, Florida
earlier this month. Data showed Pfizer's torcetrapib increased
levels of a hormone called aldosterone that may trigger fatty
plaque formation and hypertension. Merck's medicine didn't cause
similar increases in mice, suggesting the rise in blood pressure
wasn't a flaw common to the whole class but one associated with
Pfizer's compound. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Erik Stroes, a doctor at the Academic Medical Center in
Amsterdam involved in studies of the Roche and Pfizer drugs,
said side effects from the Swiss drugmaker's compound were minor
to modest and centered on gastro-intestinal reactions at higher
doses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``There's abundant evidence on the Roche CETP inhibitor and
in none of the groups studied was there a hint of increased
blood pressure,'' Stroes added. He said there's ``good
rationale'' to continue development. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;R1658 raised good cholesterol levels by 35 to 40 percent,
compared with 60 to 80 percent for torcetrapib, according to
Stroes. The studies Stroes worked on didn't look at survival
rates or measure either plaque levels or the thickening of
arteries in patients. Merck said last month its compound raised
HDL levels by as much as 139 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Late-Stage Plan &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Roche may try to base a late-stage trial around the drug's
effectiveness in raising good cholesterol levels or reducing
plaque build-up, rather than its ability to prolong life, said
Karl Heinz Koch, an analyst at Bank Vontobel. Such a move could
spare the Swiss drugmaker the costs Pfizer had to shoulder and
also cut the time needed to bring the treatment to market. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``It's not $1 billion anymore because Roche is currently
discussing a more targeted program with the FDA,'' Koch said.
``But it's still a big ticket for a product that doesn't have
the validation you'd like to have at this stage''. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, the Food and Drug Administration may insist on a
mortality study given what happened with torcetrapib, Koch said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About 44 million Americans, or one in six, have low levels
of good cholesterol, which may help sweep artery-clogging LDL
out of the bloodstream, according to the American Heart
Association. About 650,000 people die in the U.S. each year from
heart disease. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Dermot Doherty in Geneva at 
Ddoherty9@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Chris Elser in London at 
celser@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry></news>