
<news><entry author="By David Reilly" date="Feb 02, 2010  9:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-02-02/goldman-sachs-wimps-out-in-buck-breaking-brawl-david-reilly.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Wimps Out in Buck-Breaking Brawl: David Reilly</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Throughout the financial crisis,
Goldman Sachs Group Inc. extolled the use of market prices to
value holdings, saying this instills needed discipline. The
firm''s hard-line stance turned to mush, though, when it came
time to end a market myth that fueled 2008''s meltdown. </p>
<p>Goldman, along with the mutual-fund industry, argues that
it is fine for money-market funds to use historical values,
rather than market prices, to value holdings. This helps money-
market funds maintain a stable price of $1 a share. </p>
<p>The problem: the $1 share price gives investors the false
impression that money-market funds are like bank accounts and so
can''t lose money. That myth was shattered in 2008, and the
resulting panic worsened the credit crunch, forcing the
government to backstop these funds. </p>
<p>In the face of opposition from the fund industry and from
firms such as Goldman, the Securities and Exchange Commission so
far has failed to force the $3.3 trillion money-market industry
to face reality by requiring the funds to show that their shares
rise and fall in value, even if by miniscule amounts. This
inaction creates the possibility of future market runs and the
need for more government bailouts. </p>
<p>At a meeting last week, the SEC endorsed beefed-up
disclosures for money-market funds, along with other technical
changes such as requiring funds to boost cash holdings. It
stopped short, though, of even proposing that funds be required
to post values that wouldn''t always neatly show up as $1 a
share. </p>
<p>More Action Needed </p>
<p>SEC Chairman Mary Schapiro did say the agency would
continue to evaluate money-market fund reforms, including one to
require floating values. </p>
<p>More forceful action is needed, though, especially given
that there have been calls for more than a year, most notably
from a group run by former Federal Reserve Chairman Paul Volcker, to require that money-market funds either use floating
values -- and so prepare investors for the idea that these
instruments can lose money -- or be regulated as if they are
bank products. </p>
<p>Recall that the failure of Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc.
led to losses that caused the $62.5 billion Reserve Primary
Fund, the oldest U.S. money-market fund, to break the buck.
This meant losses fell outside a preset range, so the value of
its shares suddenly fell below the fixed $1 price. </p>
<p>Panicky Investors </p>
<p>This led to panic as investors realized money-market funds
weren''t as safe as bank accounts and weren''t insured by the
Federal Deposit Insurance Corp. The federal government had to
step in and insure money-market investments until September
2009. Fresh memories of the money-market panic even played a
role in the decision to bail out American International Group
Inc. </p>
<p>Appearing before Congress last week, Thomas Baxter, general
counsel of the Federal Reserve Bank of New York, submitted
testimony saying that money-market funds couldn''t have weathered
an AIG failure. While those funds held $5 billion of commercial
paper issued by Lehman, they held about $20 billion in notes
issued by AIG, he said. </p>
<p>Losses to these funds would have had potentially
devastating effects on confidence and would have accelerated the
run on financial institutions of all kinds, according to
Baxter''s testimony. </p>
<p>Requiring money-market fund values to float would help head
off such problems. Investors would learn that these investments
are just like other mutual funds, and so can lose money. </p>
<p>Wake-Up Call'' </p>
<p>Our experience with the Reserve Fund and other funds is a
wake-up call that stable net asset value money funds are
susceptible to runs, and we must more fundamentally rethink how
they are regulated, SEC Commissioner Kathleen Casey said at
last week''s meeting. </p>
<p>Casey added that if the funds aren''t to face bank-like
regulation, they need to move to floating values. </p>
<p>The industry''s case against floating values is that
investors would pull cash out of money-market funds because they
want investments with a stable value. That, the argument goes,
would deprive American companies of a vital source of funding,
since money-market funds are big buyers of short-term commercial
paper issued by companies. </p>
<p>That is a well-worn ploy from the financial-services
industry to counter any change that cuts into business. Banks
used this tactic effectively in 2003 and 2004, for instance, to
pressure the Financial Accounting Standards Board to water down
rules that would have limited banks'' ability to use off-balance-
sheet vehicles. </p>
<p>Goldman''s Case </p>
<p>The result was out-of-control securitization and under-
capitalized banks, both of which played huge roles in crashing
the financial system. </p>
<p>Goldman made the exact same We can''t crimp companies''
funding argument in a September comment letter to the SEC on
money-market reforms. Most egregious is that Goldman''s letter
argues in favor of using historical prices for money-market fund
values, even though the firm has championed the use of market
values for investments and financial holdings. </p>
<p>In an op-ed article last autumn, Goldman Chief Executive
Officer Lloyd Blankfein wrote, Markets, and ultimately
investors, are better served with information that more closely
reflects the judgment of the market rather than the historical
price. </p>
<p>Now Blankfein''s boys are trying to play Jack Nicholson in
A Few Good Men, screaming at the SEC and investors: You
can''t handle the truth! </p>
<p>Guess what? It''s Goldman and money-market funds who can''t
handle the truth. Investors can, if it means they don''t have to
face more market crashes and government bailouts. </p>
<p>(David Reilly is a Bloomberg News columnist. The opinions
expressed are his own.) </p>
<p>Click on Send Comment in the sidebar display to send a
letter to the editor. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bob Van Voris, Cary O''Reilly and Margaret Cronin Fisk" date="Feb 22, 2010  6:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-02-22/pfizer-begins-trial-of-300-million-neurontin-claim-of-misuse-by-kaiser.html"><headline>Pfizer Begins Trial of $300 Million Neurontin Claim of Misuse by Kaiser</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. illegally promoted the
epilepsy pill Neurontin for unapproved uses, causing health-care
plans to needlessly pay hundreds of millions of dollars, lawyers
for a California insurer told a jury in federal court. </p>
<p>Kaiser Foundation Health Plan Inc. and Kaiser Foundation
Hospitals claim they were misled into believing Neurontin was
effective for migraines, bipolar disorder and other conditions
in addition to epilepsy, for which the U.S. Food and Drug
Administration approved the drug in 1993. Kaiser is seeking
$100 million, an amount that may be tripled under federal civil-
racketeering law. </p>
<p>This is a case about fraud, Thomas Greene, a lawyer for
the plaintiffs, told jurors today in Boston. Pfizer and its
Warner-Lambert unit lied about the effectiveness of Neurontin.
My client, Kaiser, paid millions of dollars for a medicine that
was no more effective than sugar pills. </p>
<p>The trial began today with jury selection under the
supervision of U.S. District Judge Patti Saris, who is
overseeing federal lawsuits from throughout the U.S. targeting
Pfizer with injury claims and allegations of fraudulent sales
and marketing of the drug. </p>
<p>A verdict in the case may influence other Neurontin suits
against Pfizer, the world''s largest drugmaker. In a ruling last
year, Saris said that fraud findings against Pfizer could be
binding against the New York-based company in future trials. </p>




Source:  Pfizer Inc. via Bloomberg

<p>
This is an undated company photo of a bottle of Neurontin 600 mg tablets. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David Pauly" date="Feb 23, 2010  9:01 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-02-23/exxon-buffett-stir-takeover-pot-for-good-or-bad-david-pauly.html"><headline>Exxon, Buffett Stir Takeover Pot, for Good or Bad: David Pauly</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Wall Street''s mergers and
acquisitions machine is recovering from its recession doldrums,
raising the old question of whether the takeovers investment
banks foster do anything more than make companies bigger and
harder to manage.
     Schlumberger Ltd. this week said it would buy oil-field
services rival Smith International Inc. for about $11 billion
and, according to Bloomberg News, Thermo Fisher Scientific Inc.
is offering about $6 billion for Millipore Corp., adding
biotechnology customers to its market for laboratory equipment. </p>
<p>There already have been some eye-popping deals. Exxon Mobil
Corp., the biggest U.S. oil company, in December offered about
$31 billion for XTO Energy Inc., to add the target company''s
huge reserves of natural gas. </p>
<p>Warren Buffett''s Berkshire Hathaway Inc. on Feb. 12
completed its $26.7 billion offer for full control of Burlington
Northern Santa Fe Corp., which vies with Union Pacific Corp. as
the nation''s biggest railroad. </p>
<p>Takeovers are good for Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and Citigroup Inc., which currently top the 2010 list of U.S. merger
advisers. It''s good too if corporate executives have renewed
confidence in the economy -- though acquisitions usually destroy
jobs rather than create them. </p>
<p>The spectacle of hostile takeovers such as Kraft Foods
Inc.''s contested acquisition of British candy maker Cadbury Plc
might spark investor interest in the stock market. </p>
<p>Bad-mouthing </p>
<p>A similar battle for control was brewing this week. Airgas
Inc., the largest distributor of industrial gases in the U.S.,
blew off an unsolicited $5.1 billion bid from Air Products 
Chemicals Inc. We are concerned about Air Products'' ability to
manage the business, said Airgas Chief Executive Officer Peter McCausland, who owns 9.34 percent of his company''s shares. </p>
<p>Once the merger parade accelerates, investors will buy
shares of other oil, chemical, food and railroad companies
betting they will also be taken over. </p>
<p>CEOs and their Wall Street advisers always rationalize
their deals -- never mentioning such things as empire-building
or increased pay for running bigger companies. </p>
<p>Schlumberger says it needs Smith International''s drill bits
added to its drilling, logging and seismic businesses to compete
as the search for crude oil moves into more difficult areas both
on land and at sea. </p>
<p>There''s enough similarity in the companies'' products that
some will have to be divested to satisfy government antitrust
officials. </p>
<p>Power Moves </p>
<p>Electric utility FirstEnergy Corp.''s plan to buy Allegheny
Energy Inc. for $4.7 billion in stock gives the buyer access to
Allegheny''s cheaper power and gives the seller access to capital
for expansion. It had better work: FirstEnergy offered a 32
percent premium for Allegheny shares. </p>
<p> Walgreen Co. is the biggest U.S. drugstore chain but it''s
nowhere in New York City. Last week, it offered $618 million for
Duane Reade Holdings Inc., which has 257 stores in the largest
pharmacy market in the country. </p>
<p>While Walgreen used to open new stores on its own, buying
Duane Reade was a quick entry into New York and the seller,
leveraged buyout firm Oak Hill Capital Partners, no doubt was
eager to get out. Walgreen''s offer was less than the $680
million the LBO outfit paid for the New York stores in 2004. </p>
<p>Unfortunately, there''s no historical record to praise
takeovers or to condemn them. Though studies show the stocks of
buyers tend to decline in the short run, it''s impossible to say
how merged companies would have done if they hadn''t combined. </p>
<p>There are obvious successes, like Exxon''s acquisition of
Mobil, and clear disasters such as Time Warner Inc. and what''s
now AOL Inc. </p>
<p>Takeovers are part of the corporate psyche in any case. The
best thing about the latest batch is that they indicate the
economy is approaching normalcy. Whether it''s shooting free
throws in the last seconds of a basketball game or risking
millions on a new factory, confidence is the key. </p>
<p>(David Pauly is a columnist for Bloomberg News. Opinions
expressed are his.) </p>
<p>Click on Send Comment in the sidebar display to send a
letter to the editor. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Mark Gilbert" date="Feb 24, 2010  7:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-02-24/goldman-sachs-is-innocent-of-greece-s-swap-crimes-mark-gilbert.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Is Innocent of Greece''s Swap Crimes: Mark Gilbert</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>For once, the whipping boys and
girls of finance are innocent. </p>
<p>The European Union is investigating Goldman Sachs Group
Inc.''s role in the financial sleight of hand that helped Greece
use swaps to postpone the day of economic reckoning past its
ascension to euro membership. Goldman says, rightly, there was
nothing inappropriate in the transactions it facilitated. </p>
<p>Most of the elements of a crime are present. There''s a
victim -- trust in the common-currency project. There''s a
weapon, in the form of the derivatives that trimmed 2.37 billion
euros ($3.2 billion) off the nation''s debt burden. And there''s a
perpetrator, the Greek government, which knew its finances were
too shaky to ditch its currency, the drachma. </p>
<p>There also seems to be an accomplice -- Goldman Sachs,
which had the financial-engineering skills to crack open
Greece''s budget deficit and spirit enough of its obligations
away to a future date to ensure it qualified to join the euro. </p>
<p>What''s missing is any broken law. The architects of
European integration knowingly and with malice aforethought
added the words additional measures in a footnote to the
blueprint, letting Italy fudge its numbers to get into the club. </p>
<p>Slapping Kittens </p>
<p>That''s the same loophole Greece was able to exploit, in
line with the rules, aided and abetted by Goldman Sachs. So
while German Chancellor Angela Merkel said this month it''s a
scandal if it turned out that the same banks that brought us to
the brink of the abyss helped fake the statistics, she''s
wagging her finger at the wrong party. </p>
<p>The DNA of investment bankers drives them to find and
exploit malleable clauses, bend rules, take maximum advantage of
the unintended consequences of legislation. Chastising Goldman
Sachs for flexing its muscles on behalf of a customer is akin to
slapping a kitten for its adventures with a ball of wool. </p>
<p>Society doesn''t want to outlaw investment banking (not yet,
anyway), any more than it wants to euthanize wool-bothering
kittens. The trick is to keep the knitting supplies locked in a
cupboard; the EU cannot leave the door ajar for reasons of
Italian political expediency, and then complain when the floor
ends up resembling a Jackson Pollock. </p>
<p>Balance-Sheet Shifts </p>
<p>Creative accounting -- which is just a polite way to talk
about cooking the books -- is nothing new for countries. Italy
used a yen-denominated swap to give its finances a one-time puff
and avoid the ignominy of failing to qualify for the euro. </p>
<p>In the U.K., so-called public-private partnerships and
private finance initiatives allow the government to shift the
burden of costly infrastructure onto the balance sheets of
companies that tender successfully to manage and build the
projects. The companies get access to rampant profit potential,
in return for the government suppressing its debt burden. </p>
<p>Greece is a particularly apt subject for the old joke about
lies, damned lies and statistics. In September 2004, the nation
had to revise up its deficits for 2000, 2001 and 2002. The gap
for the first year was more than doubled to 4.1 percent, while
that of the two later years almost tripled to 3.7 percent. </p>
<p>Put bluntly, it turned out that the country had missed the
3 percent deficit threshold for euro membership in every single
year since joining the common currency -- transgressions that
went unpunished. So no one should be surprised that Greek
Finance Minister George Papaconstantinou confessed to some
sleight of hand in Greece''s 2009 deficit numbers. </p>
<p>Sovereign Risk </p>
<p>The Greece debacle is likely to hasten and worsen increased
oversight of the derivatives market. In particular, contracts
where the buyer doesn''t have any skin in the game are akin to
writing auto insurance for people who don''t own a car and don''t
even have a driver''s license, but who nevertheless fancy a bet
on the likelihood of a car crash. </p>
<p>Financial authorities will probably outlaw such behavior,
ignoring the difficulties of differentiating between efficient
risk management and risk creation. Moreover, governments are
clearly uncomfortable with the concept of investors being able
to bet against a country''s creditworthiness in the credit-
default swaps market. This may spur an unwelcome and unnecessary
intervention by the dead hand of regulation. </p>
<p>The trick Goldman Sachs employed to help Greece massage its
debt figures hinged on using historical, rather than prevailing,
currency rates in a series of swap transactions. While that
undoubtedly comes under the heading of fast-and-loose, it''s not
illegal; swaps are over-the-counter contracts between consenting
adults, so no matter how divorced the values are from reality,
it really isn''t anybody else''s business. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs has become the lightning rod for public anger
about the global bailout of the finance industry. The vexation
is appropriate; there''s too little humility and too much
arrogance, and scant recognition that every financial firm, no
matter how clever its partners, would be dead without an ocean
of taxpayers'' money keeping the system afloat. </p>
<p>In the case of Greece''s swaps, though, Goldman Sachs has
done nothing wrong. The EU''s forensics squad should be looking
closer to home for its culprit. </p>
<p>(Mark Gilbert, author of Complicit: How Greed and
Collusion Made the Credit Crisis Unstoppable, is the London
bureau chief and a columnist for Bloomberg News. The opinions
expressed are his own.) </p>
<p>Click on Send Comment in the sidebar display to send a
letter to the editor. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Patrick Cole" date="Feb 24, 2010 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-02-24/morgan-stanley-s-mack-clooney-help-charities-beat-recession.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley''s Mack, Clooney Help Charities Beat Recession</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>George Clooney worked the
phones day and night to produce a telethon last month that
raised $66 million for Haitian earthquake victims. </p>
<p>Actor Alyssa Milano asked for donations instead of
presents for her birthday party and raised $92,000 for
charity: water, a New York nonprofit that builds wells in
developing countries. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley Chairman John Mack and Chief Executive
Officers Leslie Moonves of CBS Corp. and Frank Bennack of
Hearst Corp. helped Partnership for a Drug Free America
raise $2 million at its December gala, topping the
organization''s goal by $500,000. </p>
<p>With the U.S. in a severe economic slump, nonprofit
groups must work harder to raise money and find new ways to
reach patrons. While some are focusing on wealthy
executives and celebrities, others are utilizing social
network sites such as Facebook to reach a younger audience. </p>
<p>The nonprofits that ask more people for donations
are the ones that are succeeding, Stacy Palmer, editor of
the Washington-based Chronicle of Philanthropy, said in a
phone interview. They just have to work harder at it. </p>
<p>Declining Donations </p>
<p>Charitable donations by U.S. corporations may decline
by up to 10 percent in 2009, according to Melissa Berman,
chief executive officer of Rockefeller Philanthropy
Advisors in New York. In 2008, those companies gave away
$14 billion. </p>
<p>The organizations that come to us are run like a
business, and they have to show that they can have an
impact, said Shannon Schuyler, corporate responsibility
leader for the Americas at PricewaterhouseCoopers LLP in
Chicago. They didn''t come to us saying, We''re having
hard times, write us a check.'' </p>
<p>Dozens of cultural organizations have shut down over
the past two years, including the Fresno Metropolitan
Museum in California, the Milwaukee Shakespeare Co. and the
Las Vegas Art Museum. </p>
<p>However, the economic downturn didn''t stop charity:
water from boosting donations to $9 million in 2009, a 30
percent increase over the previous year. Facebook and
Twitter have helped the 4-year-old nonprofit build a list
of 80,000 donors, President Scott Harrison said in a phone
interview. </p>
<p>A number of charities make the mistake of not
continuing an aggressive fundraising approach, said
William Woodson, managing director and head of family
wealth management for Credit Suisse Private Banking USA in
Chicago. We found that those that retained a rigorous
approach were exceedingly effective. </p>
<p>Bigger Pledge </p>
<p>Persistence paid off for the Lupus Research Institute
in New York. After a regular donor
pledged $50,000 instead of the $100,000 that was requested,
director of major gifts Dorey Neilinger called him and
managed to increase the donation to $75,000. Then Margaret
Dowd, the institute''s chief executive, followed up with
another call that resulted in the full $100,000 pledge. </p>
<p>It''s the cause and the mission that makes these
gifts possible, and we never give up, Dowd said in a
phone interview. </p>
<p>Showing donors that their money will be used for an
important cause is essential in a recession, said Joel
Simon, executive director of the New York-based Committee
to Protect Journalists. Explaining how his nonprofit aids
imprisoned and tortured journalists helped convince
Microsoft Corp. to buy a $25,000 table at the
organization''s November gala, Simon said. </p>
<p>Santa Barbara </p>
<p>The Santa Barbara Bowl Foundation, which raises money
to renovate the California city''s 74-year-old outdoor
amphitheater, received a $250,000 gift from a donor in
November after board chairman Paul Dore made a personal
pitch. </p>
<p>Dore, a managing director at Santa Barbara Asset
Management and a former Credit Suisse wealth manager,
showed the patron the architect''s blueprint for renovating
the facility. </p>
<p>Donors said, I see what you''re doing, and we''re on
board,'' Dore said. We lead horses to water and hope
they drink. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Daniel Taub and Prashant Gopal" date="Feb 25, 2010  5:19 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-02-25/general-growth-is-biggest-fight-since-equity-office-update1-.html"><headline>General Growth Is Biggest Fight Since Equity Office</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The battle for General Growth
Properties Inc. (GGP), owner of more than 200 U.S. malls from Boston
to Los Angeles, is turning into the biggest real estate fight
since the sale of Sam Zell''s Equity Office Properties Trust. </p>
<p>Westfield Group (WDC), a Sydney-based property investor with
stakes in 55 U.S. retail centers, signed an agreement letting it
assess General Growth''s finances, a person familiar with the
pact said yesterday. That may put Westfield in position to vie
for the bankrupt company''s assets as part of a contest already
embroiling Simon Property Group Inc. (SPG) and Brookfield Asset
Management Inc. (BAM/A) </p>
<p>For many years, the investing community failed to
understand the real value of high-quality regional malls, said
Rich Moore, managing director at RBC Capital Markets in Solon,
Ohio. We''ve just gone through the worst recession in our
history and these things are largely unscathed. </p>
<p>Commercial real estate deals in the U.S. dropped to $44
billion last year, down 67 percent from 2008 and the lowest in
records going back to 2001, according to New York-based property
research company Real Capital Analytics Inc. Globally, retail
real estate transactions totaled $50 billion, down 40 percent
from a year earlier. </p>




Photographer: Jin Lee/Bloomberg

<p>
Shoppers walk in General Growth Properties Inc.''s South Street Seaport Mall in New York, on Feb. 17, 2010. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bill Rochelle" date="Feb 25, 2010  9:34 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-02-25/general-growth-white-birch-madoff-gm-bankruptcy-update1-.html"><headline>General Growth, White Birch, Madoff, GM: Bankruptcy</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Shopping center owner General Growth
Properties Inc. (GGP) has an agreement in principle for Brookfield
Asset Management Inc. (BAM/A) to finance a reorganization plan by
investing $2.65 billion cash in return for 30 percent of the
stock. </p>
<p>The plan supported by Toronto-based Brookfield will pay all
creditors in full, with interest, while giving existing General
Growth stockholders new shares worth $15 each. </p>
<p>The Brookfield proposal, which is subject to bankruptcy
court approval, is intended to provide a floor in the search for
better offers to finance the reorganization. </p>
<p>Absent a better offer, shareholders would receive one share
of new stock, at an assumed value of $10 each, for each existing
share. Shareholders also would receive one share in a new
company called General Growth Opportunities, which will own the
master-planned communities and other properties that currently
generate little or no net income. </p>
<p>Each share of GGO is calculated to be worth $5. </p>
<p>Brookfield will buy $2.5 billion of General Growth stock at
$10 a share. It will also backstop an equity offering by buying
up to $125 million in stock of GGO for $5 a share. GGO intends
to raise another $125 million through the rights offering. </p>
<p>Brookfield''s offer isn''t conditioned on a financial
investigation and has no financing conditions. It would emerge
owning 30 percent of General Growth while allowing the company
to raise up to an additional $5.8 billion through sales of
equity, assets, or debt. </p>
<p>In return for providing the backstop, Brookfield is only to
receive seven-year warrants to buy 60 million shares at $15 a
share. Brookfield is a real estate investor and manager with
more than $100 billion of assets under management. </p>
<p>On paper, the arrangement with Brookfield betters the offer
publicly disclosed last week in which Simon Property Group Inc. (SPG)
was offering the equivalent of $9 a share to existing
shareholders while paying creditors in full with interest. </p>
<p>Indianapolis-based Simon responded to what it called
Brookfield''s highly speculative and risky proposal by
issuing a statement where it contended that General Growth is
embarking on a risky equity play on the backs of its unsecured
creditors. </p>
<p>To read other Bloomberg coverage, click here. To see the
General Growth press release, click here. </p>
<p>The official creditors'' committee and the U.S. Trustee are
both opposing General Growth''s proposal to have two investment
banks. The controversy is on the bankruptcy court''s calendar for
March 3. </p>
<p>The committee contends that the guaranteed fees for the two
investment bankers, UBS Securities LLC and Miller Buckfire  Co.
LLC, would be the highest ever approved in a bankruptcy case. </p>
<p>The U.S. Trustee, an arm of the Justice Department, takes
aim at Stamford, Connecticut-based UBS, saying it''s disqualified
because the firm is already a shareholder, creditor and agent
for the lenders in the Chapter 11 case. The committee piles on,
saying UBS is disqualified because it already represents the
official equity holders'' committee. </p>
<p>The committee is against the idea of changing the
compensation formula for New York-based Miller Buckfire, so the
firm would have a guaranteed fee of $30.25 million, or $10.75
million more than the current formula. </p>
<p>Both the U.S. Trustee and the committee see no need for two
investment banks to perform the same services. </p>
<p>At the March 3 hearing, the committee will also oppose a
six-month extension of General Growth''s exclusive right to
propose a reorganization plan. The committee says there have
been no negotiations on a plan while the company puts creditors
at risk by searching for sponsors to finance a reorganization
for the benefit of stockholders. To read Bloomberg coverage,
click here. </p>
<p>In three sets of confirmations in December and January,
Chapter 11 plans were approved for property-owning General
Growth subsidiaries having 111 loans representing $11.6 billion
in debt. Last week, the bankruptcy court signed a confirmation
order approving the reorganization for three more subsidiaries. </p>
<p>Before last week''s plan approvals, 35 properties with $3.3
billion in loans remained to be restructured. Similarly, the
holding companies must reorganize their debt. </p>
<p>General Growth began the largest real estate reorganization
in history by filing under Chapter 11 in April. The books of the
Chicago-based company had assets of $29.6 billion and total
liabilities of $27.3 billion as of Dec. 31, 2008. It owns or
manages more than 200 shopping-mall properties. </p>
<p>The case is In re General Growth Properties Inc., 09-11977,
U.S. Bankruptcy Court, Southern District of New York
(Manhattan). </p>
<h2>New Filings </h2>
<p>Newsprint Maker Files for Reorganization in Canada and U.S. </p>
<p>White Birch Paper Co., the second-largest newsprint maker
in North America, filed for bankruptcy reorganization yesterday
in Quebec while U.S. subsidiary Bear Island Paper Co. LLC filed
a Chapter 11 petition in Richmond, Virginia. </p>
<p>Nova Scotia-based White Birch didn''t make interest payments
due in September to its secured creditors. The companies had
$667 million in sales during 2009, with $125 million coming from
Bear Island. </p>
<p>White Birch blamed the filing on the declining demand for
newsprint, the strength of the Canadian dollar, and low interest
rates that generated liabilities under swap agreements. The
parent and Canadian subsidiaries are undergoing reorganization
in the Quebec Superior Court under the Companies'' Creditors
Arrangement Act. The Canadian companies are also filing
petitions for protection in the U.S. under Chapter 15. </p>
<p>Secured liabilities include $438 million on a first-lien
term loan, $104 million on a second-lien term loan, $50 million
on an asset-backed revolving credit, and $51.5 million on swap
agreements. </p>
<p>Trade suppliers are owed $9.5 million, according to a court
filing. </p>
<p>The company said it would use the reorganization process
for fixing the capital structure. </p>
<p>In addition to the Bear Island plant in Ashland, Virginia,
White Birch has three pulp and paper mills in the province of
Quebec. </p>
<p>White Birch has $140 million in financing for the
reorganization, according to a company statement. </p>
<p>White Birch is controlled by Brant-Allen Industries,
according to Bloomberg Data. </p>
<p>The case is In re Bear Island Paper Co. LLC, 10-31202, U.S.
Bankruptcy Court, Eastern District Virginia (Richmond). </p>
<h2>EPV, Solar Panel Maker, Files in Trenton, New Jersey </h2>
<p>EPV Solar Inc., a producer of thin-film photovoltaic solar
modules, filed a Chapter 11 reorganization petition yesterday in
Trenton, New Jersey, to stop the first-lien lender from
foreclosing after the debt matured. </p>
<p>The Robbinsville, New Jersey-based company owes $3.6
million on the first-lien term loan to an affiliate of private-equity investor Patriarch Partners LLC. </p>
<p>EPV owes another $55.5 million on subordinated notes. </p>
<p>The petition says assets and debt both exceed $50 million. </p>
<p>The case is In re EPV Solar Inc., 10-15173, U.S. Bankruptcy
Court, District of New Jersey (Trenton). </p>
<h2>China Club, Manhattan Nightclub, Files to Reorganize </h2>
<p>China Club, a nightclub on 47th Street in Manhattan between
Broadway and 8th Avenue, filed a Chapter 11 petition yesterday
in New York, saying assets are $2 million while debt is almost
$6.9 million. </p>
<p>The club said it was forced into bankruptcy by the
recession and the need to borrow to pay for renovations. </p>
<p>The case is In re Nightlife Enterprises LP, 10-10956, U.S.
Bankruptcy Court, Southern District New York (Manhattan). </p>
<h2>Occupational  Medical Innovations Files Chapter 15 </h2>
<p>Occupational  Medical Innovations Ltd., a developer of
safety products for the health-care industry from Australia,
filed for protection from creditors in the U.S. on Feb. 23. </p>
<p>The petition, filed in Tyler, Texas, said assets are less
than $10 million while debt exceeds $100 million. </p>
<p>Chapter 15 is not a full-blown reorganization like Chapter
11. If the U.S. bankruptcy judge decides the company is
eligible, he will stop creditor actions in the U.S. As a
consequence, creditors would be compelled to prove up their
claims and take distribution from the court abroad. </p>
<p>The case is In re Occupational  Medical Innovations Ltd.,
10-60181, U.S. Bankruptcy Court, Eastern District of Texas
(Tyler). </p>
<h2>Updates </h2>
<h2>Madoff Customers Sue SIPC Directors for Fraud </h2>
<p>Three customers of Bernard L. Madoff Investment Securities
Inc. filed a purported class-action suit yesterday against the
president and directors of the Securities Investor Protection
Corp., alleging they conducted a fraudulent investors
insurance scheme causing billion in damages to brokerage
customers. </p>
<p>The suit wasn''t filed in U.S. Bankruptcy Court in Manhattan
where the Madoff liquidation is being conducted under the
Securities Investors Protection Act. Instead, the suit was filed
in U.S. District Court in Newark, New Jersey. </p>
<p>The suit is based on the same dispute currently being
decided by the bankruptcy judge in New York. The Madoff trustee
and SIPC, based in Washington, take the position that the amount
of a customer''s claim shouldn''t be determined by the last
account statement. Rather, SIPC told the bankruptcy judge at a
hearing early this month that a customer''s claim should equal
the amount of cash deposited less the amount of cash taken out. </p>
<p>Because the Madoff firm never bought any securities with
investors'' funds, SIPC believes the net equity in the account,
the basis usually used to determine customers'' claims in SIPA
cases, shouldn''t be employed given the magnitude of the Madoff
fraud. </p>
<p>Customers argued to the bankruptcy judge this month that
the SIPA statute requires using the so-called net equity shown
in account statements, even though based on fictitious trades. </p>
<p>The plaintiffs in the 72-page New Jersey suit, represented
by lawyer Helen Davis Chaitman, contend the SIPC president and
directors should be personally liable for cheating
customers of their promised insurance. Chaitman has been
active representing customers in the bankruptcy court. </p>
<p>SIPC issued a statement calling the lawsuit frivolous.
SIPC maintains a fund paying customers up to $500,000 per
account following the bankruptcy of a stock broker. </p>
<p>The SIPC directors can attempt to move the lawsuit to
bankruptcy court in New York on the theory it''s related to the
Madoff liquidation. Where ever the case ends up, the SIPC
directors can argue there are immune from suit under a doctrine
known as quasi-judicial immunity. </p>
<p>Bernard Madoff is serving a 150-year prison sentence
following a guilty plea. The Madoff firm began liquidating in
December 2008 with the appointment of a trustee under the SIPA.
Madoff himself went into an involuntary Chapter 7 liquidation in
April. His bankruptcy case was consolidated with the firm''s
liquidation. </p>
<p>The new lawsuit is Lissa Canavan v. Stephen Harbeck, 10-00954, U.S. District Court, District of New Jersey (Newark). The
SIPA case is Securities Investor Protection Corp. v. Bernard L.
Madoff Investment Securities Inc., 08-01789, U.S. Bankruptcy
Court, Southern District New York (Manhattan). The criminal case
is U.S. v. Madoff, 09-cr-00213, U.S. District Court for the
Southern District of New York (Manhattan). </p>
<h2>Midway Files Plan with up to 25% for Unsecureds </h2>
<p>Midway Games Inc., the creator of Mortal Kombat and
other video games, filed a liquidating Chapter 11 plan and
explanatory disclosure statement telling unsecured creditors of
the parent that they stand to recover 16.5 percent. </p>
<p>Unsecured creditors of the subsidiaries are in line for 25
percent, according to the disclosure statement filed Feb. 23
along with the plan. A hearing for approval of the disclosure
statement is set for March 23. </p>
<p>Midway sold assets to generate $43 million cash, leaving no
substantial secured claims unpaid. Most of the assets were
purchased in July by a subsidiary of New York-based Time Warner
Inc. (TWX) for $33 million plus accounts receivable. The non-bankrupt
European subsidiaries were sold in August for nominal
consideration. </p>
<p>Unsecured creditors of the parent have claims estimated to
total $155 million while there are almost $37 million of
unsecured claims against the subsidiaries. Holders of
subordinated notes are not to receive a distribution. </p>
<p>Recoveries by unsecured creditors could be greater should
the creditors'' committee succeed in overturning the bankruptcy
judge who dismissed most of a lawsuit against Sumner Redstone
and companies he controls. Redstone previously owned Midway.
Click here to see a rundown on the ruling. </p>
<p>Chicago-based Midway filed under Chapter 11 in February
2009, listing assets of $168 million and debt of $281 million.
Including foreign subsidiaries not in bankruptcy, the asset and
liability totals were $178 million and $337 million. </p>
<p>Midway''s debt originally included $150 million in
convertible notes, $29 million on a secured term loan and
revolving credit, $40 million on a secured loan facility and $20
million on a subordinated loan. Unsecured claims by suppliers
totaled $96 million, the company said in a court filing at the
outset. </p>
<p>The case is In re Midway Games Inc., 09-10465, U.S.
Bankruptcy Court, District of Delaware (Wilmington). </p>
<h2>Station Casinos Has Mortgage Deals on Four Casinos </h2>
<p>Casino operator Station Casinos Inc. said in a regulatory
filing that it reached an agreement in principle on a
comprehensive reorganization with the mortgage lenders on
four casinos. The company said details will be provided in three
weeks. </p>
<p>Station also said there is significant progress with
other creditors on a reorganization plan to be filed in March.
The plan is to reduce debt while including a new revolving
credit and certain equity infusions. </p>
<p>The regulatory filing said current management will stay in
place given significant new equity investments. </p>
<p>The properties covered by the agreement in principle are
the Red Rock Casino, Palace Station Hotel  Casino, Boulder
Station Hotel  Casino, and Sunset Station Hotel  Casino. </p>
<p>The company''s promise to file a plan in March may be the
result of a warning issued by the bankruptcy judge at a hearing
in January when he said extraordinary circumstances would be
required before he extends the company''s exclusive right to
propose a Chapter 11 plan beyond the March 25 deadline. </p>
<p>U.S. Bankruptcy Judge Gregg Zive in Reno, Nevada, also said
at the hearing that he would reconsider giving creditors
authority to file suits after the company files a reorganization
plan. </p>
<p>Last month the judge denied creditors permission to bring
two suits, one contending the leveraged buyout in November 2007
resulted in fraudulent transfers and the second seeking to
recharacterize leases as disguised financings. The judge said he
saw no evidence of an intent by management to defraud creditors. </p>
<p>The committee has been arguing that the 2007 buyout left
the company with $1.7 billion in new debt, a crushing burden
that offered virtually no value in return. </p>
<p>Station Casinos filed under Chapter 11 in July. It has 13
properties in Las Vegas plus five joint ventures. It also
operates casinos for American Indian tribes. Station''s debt was
the result of a leveraged buyout in November 2007 by Feritta
Colony Partners LLC. </p>
<p>The case is In Re Station Casinos Inc., 09-52477, U.S.
Bankruptcy Court, District of Nevada (Reno). </p>
<h2>Fifth Third Opposes Cash Use by Zayat Stables </h2>
<p>Fifth Third Bank (FITB), a secured lender owed more than $34
million by Zayat Stables LLC, said in a Feb. 23 bankruptcy court
filing that the horse racing operation is incurring staggering
cash losses. </p>
<p>The Cincinnati-based bank said it will ask the bankruptcy
judge at a March 8 hearing to deny continuing use of cash except
to take care of the horses until they can be sold. </p>
<p>Where the bank previously said it would ask for the
appointment of a Chapter 11 trustee, it now promises to file a
motion for a modification of the so-called automatic stay to
allow foreclosure of the horses. </p>
<p>The bank previously accused the company of fraud,
dishonesty, incompetence, and gross mismanagement. The bank
says it holds personal guarantees given by Ahmed Zayat of as
much as $38.7 million. Zayat said he personally invested $40
million in the business. </p>
<p>The stables, based in Hackensack, New Jersey, filed for
Chapter 11 protection on Feb. 3 in Newark, contending that the
bankruptcy was precipitated by the bank''s predatory lending
practices. The bank was seeking the appointment of a receiver
at the time. </p>
<p>Revenue for 2009 was $21 million. The horses, which are
collateral for the bank loan, are worth $37 million, according
an appraisal mentioned in a court paper. </p>
<p>The case is In re Zayat Stables LLC, 10-13130, U.S.
Bankruptcy Court, District of New Jersey (Newark). </p>
<h2>Haights Cross Confirms Prepack Reorganization in 44 Days </h2>
<p>Haights Cross Communications Inc., a publisher of
supplemental educational materials for libraries and schools,
filed a prepackaged reorganization on Jan. 11 and persuaded the
bankruptcy judge at yesterday''s confirmation hearing to sign an
order approving the Chapter 11 plan. </p>
<p>The company said it intends to emerge from reorganization
in the middle of March. The plan reduces debt from $380 million
to $180 million. Votes on the plan were solicited before the
Chapter 11 filing. </p>
<p>The holders of $138.8 million in 11.75 percent senior notes
are receiving 92 percent of the new stock plus $80 million in
new second-lien notes, for a recovery estimated to range between
87.1 percent and 90.2 percent. </p>
<p>The holders of $135 million in 12.5 percent senior discount
notes are to have 8 percent of the new stock plus warrants.
Their recovery is an estimated 4.2 percent. </p>
<p>The existing $110 million term loan was to be paid in full
in cash, either through refinancing or with cash and a new $100
million first-lien loan. </p>
<p>White Plains, New York-based Haights Cross reported a $14.4
million net loss over the first half of 2009, on revenue of
$73.2 million. At June 30, total assets were $232 million,
compared with $433 million in total liabilities. </p>
<p>The case is In re Haights Cross Communications Inc., 10-10062, U.S. Bankruptcy Court, District of Delaware (Wilmington). </p>
<h2>New Bankruptcy Judge Named </h2>
<h2>Willkie Farr''s Shelley Chapman to be New York Judge </h2>
<p>Shelley C. Chapman was named by the U.S. Court of Appeals
in New York to take over one of the two openings in the U.S.
Bankruptcy Court in Manhattan. </p>
<p>Chapman, who graduated with honors from Harvard Law School,
will assume her duties on March 5. She was a partner at the New
York firm Willkie Farr  Gallagher LLP practicing bankruptcy
law. </p>
<p>There is one other opening on the bankruptcy bench in New
York caused by the retirement of Prudence Carter Beatty at the
end of 2009. The process of selecting Beatty''s replacement began
last year. </p>
<p>Unlike U.S. district judges, bankruptcy judges aren''t
appointed for life. They serve 14-year terms and may be
reappointed. </p>
<h2>Briefly Noted </h2>
<h2>Mediation Approved for Some Claims Against Old GM </h2>
<p>Old General Motors Corp., now formally named Motors
Liquidation Co., was authorized by the bankruptcy court on Feb.
23 to use mediation for the resolution of some of the 68,000
claims that were filed for $217 billion. To read about old GM''s
mediation process, click here. Old GM sold the core business,
taking back 10 percent of the stock of the new company plus
warrants for 15 percent. The warrants are to have value when and
if the new company is sufficiently profitable to raise the
company''s value to specified levels. The new GM is 60.8 percent
owned by the U.S. government. Old GM began the largest
manufacturing reorganization in history by filing under Chapter
11 on June 1. The sale was completed on July 10. GM listed
assets of $82.3 billion against debt totaling $172.8 billion.
The case is In re Motors Liquidation Co., 09-50026, U.S.
Bankruptcy Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). </p>
<h2>Foothills Consummates Reorganization Plan; Regiment Takes Over </h2>
<p>Foothills Resources Inc., an independent oil and natural
gas exploration and production company, implemented the
reorganization plan that the bankruptcy judge approved in a Jan.
29 confirmation order. The plan gives control to Regiment
Capital Special Situations Fund III LP in exchange for secured
debt. To read about the plan, click here to see the Nov. 16
Bloomberg bankruptcy report. In the Chapter 11 filing in
February 2009, assets were listed for $89.5 million against debt
totaling $78.8 million as of Sept. 30, 2008. At the time, $71.2
million was owing to secured creditors on term loan and
revolving credit agreements. Foothills properties are on the
Texas Gulf coast, in northern California and in western
Oklahoma. The case is In re Foothills Texas Inc., 09-10452, U.S.
Bankruptcy Court, District of Delaware (Wilmington). </p>
<h2>Colonial BancGroup Asks for Longer Plan Exclusivity </h2>
<p>Colonial BancGroup Inc. filed under Chapter 11 in August
after the bank subsidiary was taken over by the Federal Deposit
Insurance Corp. For a second time, Colonial is asking for an
extension of the exclusive right to propose a plan. The case is
still being held up by disputes over the validity of three
secured claims. If granted by the bankruptcy court in
Montgomery, Alabama, the new plan deadline would be June 18. The
FDIC is claiming a security interest in several bank accounts at
Branch Banking  Trust Co. holding $38.4 million. The bank
contends it has a security interest in the same accounts.
Alabama taxing authorities are claiming $7 million. The Colonial
holding company, based in Montgomery, Alabama, listed assets of
$45 million against debt of $380 million. It provided loans to
mortgage loan originators to tide them over until mortgages
could be packaged and sold to investors in securitizations. The
holding company was being investigated with regard to accounting
practices and the warehouse loan operation. The case is In re
Colonial BancGroup Inc, 09-32303, U.S. Bankruptcy Court, Middle
District of Alabama (Montgomery). </p>
<h2>Exchange Offer News </h2>
<h2>Reddy Ice Has Exchange Offer and Refinancing </h2>
<p>Reddy Ice Holdings Inc., a Dallas-based ice maker and
distributor, announced an exchange offer late last week in which
$150 million in 10.5 percent senior discount notes can be
swapped for new senior secured second-lien notes. </p>
<p>At the same time, the company is refinancing the $240
million term loan at the operating company with $300 million in
new senior secured first-lien notes. </p>
<p>Standard  Poor''s said yesterday that it is giving a CCC
rating to the new second-lien notes. If the exchange offer and
refinancing is completed, SP said it expects Reddy Ice will
have a B- corporate rating. </p>
<p>Although the transactions will increase debt by $60
million, SP observed that they will push out maturities and
provide liquidity. </p>
<h2>Watch List </h2>
<h2>Blockbuster Closing up to 545 Additional Stores </h2>
<p>Blockbuster Inc., the movie rental chain, will close as
many as 545 more stores this year, the company said yesterday in
announcing results for the fourth quarter. The closings this
year come on top of 347 locations that were shuttered in 2009. </p>
<p>For the fourth quarter, earnings before interest, taxes,
depreciation and amortization were $16.5 million. The quarter''s
operating loss was $394 million, including impairment charges.
Excluding closing costs, the adjusted operating loss for the
quarter was $6.3 million. </p>
<p>The net loss in the fourth quarter was $435 million. </p>
<p>Standard  Poor''s said earlier this month that Blockbuster
is vulnerable to default. Carl Icahn, who held 30 percent of
the stock, resigned from the board. </p>
<p>Dallas-based Blockbuster had 5,220 company-owned and 1,300
franchised stores as of Jan. 3. </p>
<p>To read other Bloomberg coverage, click here. </p>
<h2>Beltway News </h2>
<h2>Bill to Prohibit Executive Bonuses in Bankruptcy </h2>
<p>Senate Majority Leader Dick Durbin from Illinois and House
Judiciary Committee Chairman John Conyers from Michigan
introduced legislation to amend bankruptcy law by prohibiting
bonuses and other forms of incentive compensation to senior
officers of companies in bankruptcy reorganization. </p>
<p>If adopted, the legislation proposed by the two Democrats
would prohibit senior executives from receiving retirement
benefits if workers lose retirement or health benefits. </p>
<p>The bill would increase the priority for wage claims to
$20,000 and remove the limitation that only allows priority for
wages earned with 180 days of filing. It would also establish a
new priority for severance pay. </p>
<p>The senator and the congressman also want Congress to
restrict the ability of companies to terminate or amend union
contracts. The bill would prohibit singling out non-management
workers for the loss of retirement benefit. </p>
<h2>Downgrades </h2>
<h2>Standard Steel, Railcar Wheel Maker, Lowered to Caa1 </h2>
<p>Standard Steel LLC, a Pittsburgh-based manufacturer of
railcar wheels and axles, has slim interest coverage and
potential for violating a loan covenant this year, in the
judgment of Moody''s Investors Service. </p>
<p>Consequently, Moody''s lowered the corporate credit
yesterday by one grade to Caa1. The second-lien debt went down
one notch to Caa3. </p>
<p>Absent a material improvement in the market, Moody''s
believes that refinancing first-lien debt in June 2012 will be
challenging. </p>
<p>Standard  Poor''s and Moody''s both issued downgrades this
time last year. </p>
<p>Revenue for a year ended in September was $186 million,
compared with $221 million for the same period the year before. </p>
<p>The company was acquired in 2006 by Trimaran Capital
Partners LLC. </p>
<h2>AIG''s American General Demoted Four Notches by SP </h2>
<p>American General Finance Corp., a subsidiary of American
International Group Inc. (AIG), lost investment grade status one year
ago from Standard  Poor''s and was downgraded another four
notches yesterday to a B corporate grade. </p>
<p>SP noted that American General sold or securitized almost
$4 billion of its highest quality assets in 2009 to satisfy
liquidity requirements. </p>
<p>Although AIG says it supports American General, SP
believes the support has its limits. </p>
<p>The new SP rating lines up with the action taken in
December by Moody''s Investors Service, which had doubts about
the duration and extent of the parent''s financial support. </p>
<p>American General, from Evansville, Indiana, is a provider
of credit insurance and retail consumer finance products. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Patrick Cole" date="Feb 25, 2010 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2010-02-25/goldman-s-dean-backer-helps-hedge-funds-care-on-2-million-goal.html"><headline>Goldman''s Dean Backer Helps Hedge Funds Care on $2 Million Goal</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Growing up in the Long Island, New
York, village of Seaford, Dean Backer went door-to-door with his
mother on Friday evenings seeking donations for a cancer
charity. </p>
<p>At a very early age, my parents instilled in us the need
to give back in any way we could, said Backer, 43, a Goldman
Sachs Group Inc. executive for two decades. </p>
<p>It''s a conviction he took to Goldman, where he is global
head of sales and capital introduction for its securities
services, a job that includes working with hedge funds. For 12
years Backer has been involved in New York-based Hedge Funds
Care, a nonprofit that funds organizations working with child
abuse, and last month he became a board member. </p>
<p>It''s an issue that doesn''t get a lot of press, Backer
said in a telephone interview. </p>
<p>Backer will serve as a co-chairman for tonight''s 12th
annual Open Your Heart to the Children Gala at Cipriani 42nd
Street, which seeks to raise about $2 million. About 1,100
hedge-fund and finance-industry workers are expected to attend
the cocktail reception. </p>
<p>Richard H. Baker, president and chief executive officer of
the Washington-based Managed Funds Association, an organization
of hedge-fund managers, is also a co-chairman for the event. At
tonight''s benefit, the Hedge Funds Care Award for Caring will be
given to Michael Novogratz, president of the buyout and hedge-
fund firm Fortress Investment Group LLC, and supermodel Liya
Kebede, who heads her own charity, the Liya Kebede Foundation. </p>
<p>Precious'' Director </p>
<p>Lee Daniels, director of the Oscar-nominated film
Precious: Based on the Novel Push'' by Sapphire, will
receive Hedge Funds Care''s Founders Award. A representative for
Daniels will accept the award for him. Precious is the story
of Claireece Precious Jones, a 16-year-old girl who is
impregnated twice by her father and abused by her mother. </p>
<p>Founded in 1998, New York-based Hedge Fund Cares has
counted on the generosity of hedge funds so it can award grants
to nonprofits in New York, New Jersey and Connecticut.
Recipients include the Coalition on Child Abuse and Neglect and
Girls Educational and Mentoring Services. </p>
<p>Backer has also donated time and money to the Robin Hood
Foundation, which supports poverty-fighting organizations, and
he serves on the board of Comprehensive Development Inc., a
nonprofit that prepares older high-school students to enter the
job market. </p>
<p>I don''t think I''ve seen a more difficult climate than
last year, he said. But even in difficult times, you do see
the good in people come out. I do think this is one of those
occasions where people dig deep down into their pockets. </p>
<p>The Hedge Funds Care Open Your Heart to the Children
benefit is tonight at 6 p.m. at Cipriani 42nd Street, 110 E.
42nd St. in Manhattan. Tickets are $1,500. Information: 1-212-
991-9600, ext. 342; or http://www.hedgefundscare.org. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry></news>