<?xml version='1.0' encoding='us-ascii'?>
<news><entry author="By Angela Greiling Keane and Jonathan D. Salant" date="Jun 11, 2007 11:10 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-06-11/goldman-macquarie-face-fight-on-private-toll-roads-update1-.html"><headline>Goldman, Macquarie Face Fight on Private Toll Roads</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;The trucking industry and
congressional Democrats are trying to put the brakes on state
efforts to lease toll roads to Macquarie Bank Ltd., Goldman Sachs
Group Inc. (GS) and other private investors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Urged on by truckers such as U.S. Xpress Enterprises Ltd.,
House Democrats are considering withholding highway funds from
states whose leases with companies fail to meet proposed federal
standards. Critics of leasing say private investors are more
likely to raise tolls than government authorities are. Private
investors would also find it easier to fire toll collectors and
other employees. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New federal restrictions could make investments in the $1.7
trillion of public roadways less attractive to private interests.
And the mere fact of congressional attention might have a
chilling effect on such deals, says Mike McDermott, an analyst
who works on toll-road transactions in the New York office of
Fitch Ratings Ltd., which rates debt used to finance
infrastructure. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``Those kinds of public debates would make politicians at
the state level more cautious,'' he says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For states with heavily traveled roadways, lease agreements
with the likes of Macquarie and Goldman are potential windfalls
that would allow them to meet budget needs without raising taxes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Leasing the Turnpike &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pennsylvania, which says it faces a $1.7 billion shortfall
in transportation funds during the next 20 years, might raise as
much as $12 billion to $18 billion by leasing the 537-mile
Pennsylvania Turnpike, according to an analysis by Morgan
Stanley. New Jersey Democratic Governor Jon Corzine, 60, is also
looking at leasing state toll roads to raise money for highway
construction and maintenance. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such arrangements are common in Australia, Chile, Spain and
elsewhere around the world. Sydney-based Macquarie, the world's
largest private manager of public facilities, said last month
that it raised $10 billion to buy more infrastructure assets in
Europe and North America. Those assets would be added to its
existing stakes in the Indiana Toll Road -- leased in 2006 for
$3.85 billion -- and the Chicago Skyway, leased for 99 years in
2005 for $1.83 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New York-based Goldman Sachs, the biggest U.S. securities
firm by market value, raised $6.5 billion last year for a new
fund to invest in toll roads and other infrastructure. Goldman is
one of 48 firms interested in leasing the Pennsylvania Turnpike. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Shortchanging the Public &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alex Doughty, a spokesman for New York-based Macquarie
Infrastructure Group, didn't respond to requests for comment.
Goldman Sachs spokesman Michael DuVally declined to comment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;House Democrats say they are concerned the public will be
shortchanged by long-term private leases. ``Public-private
partnerships need to take the public interests in mind,'' House
Transportation Committee Chairman Jim Oberstar, 72, a Minnesota
Democrat, said in a statement provided by his office. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oberstar's proposed guidelines for private leasing
agreements would include guarantees that states could upgrade
highways parallel to leased toll roads and protection against
price gouging by private companies. States that didn't comply
would face the loss of federal highway funds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oberstar and House highways subcommittee chairman Peter DeFazio have sent letters to state officials urging them to go
slow. ``If public-private partnerships are abused, what you will
cause is a reaction on the state and federal level that will put
an end to this,'' says DeFazio, 60, an Oregon Democrat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A `Patronage Bastion' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pennsylvania Governor Edward Rendell -- like Oberstar and
DeFazio, a Democrat -- says the congressional concerns are
overblown. In his state, Rendell, 63, said in an interview, much
of the opposition to leasing the turnpike has come from
entrenched partisan interests fearing the loss of what has been a
``huge patronage bastion for both political parties.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congressional Democrats have found unlikely allies in
Chattanooga, Tennessee-based U.S. Xpress and other trucking
companies, which in the last 10 years have given about 80 percent
of their campaign donations to Republicans, according to the
Center for Responsive Politics, a Washington-based research
group. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The growing interest in road leasing shows that ``someone's
figured out how to make a lot of money doing these deals and also
that someone, probably the users of these roads, is going to pay
exponentially,'' says former Kansas Governor Bill Graves, 54,
chief executive of the American Trucking Associations. The trade
group, based in Alexandria, Virginia, represents among others
U.S. Xpress and Overland Park, Kansas-based YRC Worldwide Inc. (YRCW),
the largest U.S. trucking company. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Taxes Over Tolls &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truckers' trade group says the industry pays $3 billion
to $4 billion a year in tolls now. Graves, a Republican, says the
industry would prefer higher fuel taxes to increased tolls. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Large trucking companies typically sign long-term contracts
with customers that factor in fuel-price fluctuations. Patrick Quinn, 61, president of U.S. Xpress and chairman of the ATA, said
in an interview that private control of U.S. highways is
``unpredictable and unknown'' and could increase tolls. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frequent toll hikes, Quinn says, would make cost planning
difficult. ``We feel kind of comfortable with the system'' now,
he says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After Indiana signed its lease agreement, truck tolls on its
157-mile toll road rose 24 percent -- the first increase since
1985. They rose another 25 percent in April and are due to go up
again in 2008 and 2009. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Benefits and Risks &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For politicians, there may be both benefits and risks in
such arrangements. Private control may free officials from being
blamed for higher tolls, says McDermott, the Fitch Ratings
analyst. They can say ``it's not me that's raising rates,'' he
says. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, the higher charges in Indiana helped
Democrats capture control of the state House of Representatives
and win a congressional seat in the district that straddles the
highway. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``People thought it was done in an unfair way, and they
wanted someone who would stand up for it,'' says Democratic U.S.
Representative Joe Donnelly, 51, who ousted Republican Chris Chocola, 45. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matt Pierce, a spokesman for the Indiana Toll Road, says the
lease benefits motorists. ``Our primary responsibility is to the
consumers who travel the road,'' he says. ``We're selling them
time. We're selling them that ease of moving the goods.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Bush administration is backing the states' drive to get
business investment to run highways. ``Public-private
partnerships are vital to fixing this nation's mounting mobility
crisis because private investment is based on demand and not
political influence,'' Transportation Secretary Mary Peters, 58,
told a highway group in Myrtle Beach, South Carolina, on June 1. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Bush's backing, and given the financial needs of the
states, Pennsylvania's Rendell predicts more such deals in the
future. The balding governor says he'll be able to ``comb my hair
in a pompadour'' before Congress clamps down on the trend. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporters on this story:
Angela Greiling Keane in Washington at 
agreilingkea@bloomberg.net;
Jonathan D. Salant in Washington at 
jsalant@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Michael Forsythe at  mforsythe@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Haslinda Amin and Anuchit Nguyen" date="Jun 20, 2007  8:20 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2007-06-20/chevron-ptt-get-extension-on-thai-oil-exploration-update1-.html"><headline>Chevron, PTT Get Extension on Thai Oil Exploration</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Chevron Corp. (CVX) and PTT Exploration
and Production Pcl (PTTEP), Thailand's two biggest natural gas
producers, have got an extension on their exploration and
production contracts at some fields. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chevron can continue exploration and production at three
blocks in the Gulf of Thailand for another 10 years, Energy
Minister Piyasvasti Amranand said in an interview in Bangkok
today. PTT Exploration will also receive permission to develop
the Bongkot field for another 10 years, he said. The contracts
for those gas and oil fields were scheduled to expire in 2012. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thailand has given more areas to Chevron, PTT Exploration,
Hess Corp. and other companies to explore as part of the
government's attempt to boost domestic output of natural gas
and oil. The country imports almost all of its crude oil and
about a third of natural gas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``Those companies should give more time to develop those
fields as they have done a very good job in exploration and
production,'' said Piyasvasti. ``There are significant amounts
of remaining natural gas reserves in those fields that need
additional investments to be developed.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chevron may invest $8 billion in the Southeast Asian
nation should the government extend its concessions for another
10 years, the Bangkok Post reported today, citing Songpop
Polachan, deputy director of the Mineral Fuels Department. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chevron is working with the department to extend
production period for Blocks 10 to 13 under the existing
concessions until 2022, Nicole Hodgson, Chevron's spokeswoman
in Bangkok, said in an e-mailed response to a question today.
Hodgson declined to comment on the report about Chevron's
investment plan, saying: ``Chevron does not release forward
looking investment figures by country.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chevron, the second-biggest U.S. oil company, had invested
$11.2 billion in gas and oil exploration and production in
Thailand between 1962 and 2005, according to the company's data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Anuchit Nguyen in Bangkok at 
anguyen@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Tony Jordan at  tjordan3@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry></news>