<?xml version='1.0' encoding='us-ascii'?>
<news><entry author="By Shannon D. Harrington" date="Apr 10, 2008  3:49 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-04-10/goldman-merrill-debt-risk-rises-on-concern-losses-may-increase.html"><headline>Goldman, Merrill Debt Risk Rises on Concern Losses May Increase</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;The cost to protect the debt of
banks and securities firms from default rose for a third day amid
renewed concern that losses will increase after declining asset
values forced Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. to bail out five
funds. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Credit-default swaps tied to Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS),
Merrill Lynch  Co. and Lehman Brothers reached the highest
levels since the start of the month, signaling a decline in
investor confidence. Benchmark credit indexes in the U.S. and
Europe rose earlier today, before falling back to little changed
as stocks in the U.S. rallied. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lehman took $1.8 billion in assets from five of its short-term debt funds onto its balance sheet last quarter after
``market disruptions.'' Goldman, the most profitable securities
firm, late yesterday reported a 39 percent increase in hard-to-value assets, and some analysts have scrapped their earnings
estimates for Merrill Lynch and are now predicting a first-quarter loss. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``When the banks report in the next couple of weeks, there's
going to be a reminder to a lot of investors that there's more
damage to balance sheets beyond structured finance, beyond
leveraged finance,'' said Ricardo Kleinbaum, a credit analyst at
BNP Paribas in New York. ``It's extending to a broader range of
credit classes.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Credit-default swaps on Goldman climbed 8 basis points to
133 basis points, Phoenix prices show. They earlier reached
140 basis points, the highest since March 31. Lehman contracts
climbed 17 basis points to 212 and traded as high as 217, Phoenix
prices show. New York-based Merrill, which is scheduled to report
earnings April 17, rose 15 basis points to 200. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;$245 Billion &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Credit-default swaps, financial instruments based on bonds
or loans, were conceived to protect bondholders by paying the
buyer face value in exchange for the underlying securities should
the borrower default. A decrease in the price indicates improving
perceptions of credit quality, an increase shows deterioration. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world's largest banks and securities firms have reported
$245 billion of asset writedowns and credit losses amid record
home foreclosures and a loss of investor confidence in so-called
structured securities linked to home loans. The housing turmoil
triggered a collapse of the subprime mortgage market and spread
to debt once considered among the safest, including commercial
paper backed by assets such as mortgage securities. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman Chief Executive Officer Lloyd Blankfein told
investors today that the credit crisis is nearing an end. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``We're closer to the end than the beginning,'' Blankfein,
53, said today at the company's annual shareholder meeting in New
York. ``We're maybe at the end of the third quarter, or the
beginning of the fourth.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Money-Market Funds &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New York-based Lehman, the fourth-biggest securities firm,
recorded a $300 million loss from the bailout of five short-term
debt funds, according to a person familiar with the writedown.
Lehman's actions followed a $780 million charge by Credit Suisse
Group in February after the Zurich-based firm bought assets from
its money-market funds that had fallen in value because of a
freeze in some commercial paper markets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bank of America Corp. (BAC) and Legg Mason Inc. also have propped
up money-market funds and General Electric Co.'s GE Asset
Management liquidated a short-term bond fund in November after it
lost about $225 million. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the funds held commercial paper and medium-term
notes issued by structured investment vehicles, which were shut
out of debt markets last year amid concern that some of them
bought securities linked to subprime mortgages. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman, also based in New York, disclosed in a regulatory
filing yesterday that its so-called Level 3 assets, those hardest
to value, jumped to $96.4 billion at the end of February, with
the ratio to total assets rising to 8.1 percent from 6.2 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Asian Markets &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``Investors don't like the uncertainty that it brings to
balance sheets,'' said Mark Bayley, director of credit and
structuring at ABN Amro Holding NV in Sydney. ``It indicates a
deterioration of liquidity and transparency in the markets.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Credit-default swaps on the Markit CDX North America
Investment Grade Index, linked to the debt of 125 companies in
the U.S. and Canada, fell 2 basis point to 122 basis points as of
2:59 p.m. in New York, according to Phoenix Partners. The index
earlier reached 130 basis points, the widest since April 1. The
Markit iTraxx Europe index fell 0.5 basis point to 104.5 basis
points in London, according to JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Asia, the Markit iTraxx Japan index rose 16 basis points
to 120 basis points, according to Morgan Stanley. The benchmark
gauge of credit risk has erased almost half its decline this
month. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bear Stearns &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The iTraxx and CDX indexes reached record highs last month
after a cash squeeze at Bear Stearns Cos., the fifth-biggest U.S.
securities firm, prompted the Federal Reserve to back an
emergency sale of the firm to JPMorgan Chase  Co. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fed's intervention in the Bear Stearns crisis on March
14, and its creation of a new lending facility designed to
prevent other banks from collapsing, eased investor concern and
sent credit-default swaps plunging from their record highs. The
North American investment-grade index reached a record 198.5
basis points on March 14, according to CMA Datavision in London. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``I think we're going to settle into a range here for a
little bit; the market needs to figure out what it wants to do
next,'' said Ashish Shah, head of credit strategy at Lehman
Brothers in New York. ``The good news is that you are going
through the de-levering process as banks and brokers try to shed
assets they don't want and continue to raise capital.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporters on this story:
Shannon D. Harrington in New York at 
sharrington6@bloomberg.net; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editors responsible for this story:
Emma Moody at 
emoody@bloomberg.net; &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Eric Martin" date="Apr 28, 2008  9:08 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-04-28/u-s-stock-index-futures-advance-wrigley-visa-ford-climb.html"><headline>U.S. Stock-Index Futures Advance; Wrigley, Visa, Ford Climb</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;U.S. stock futures rose as Wm.
Wrigley Jr. Co. agreed to a $23 billion takeover bid, Kirk Kerkorian bought a stake in Ford Motor Co. and Verizon
Communications Inc. posted higher earnings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wrigley, the world's biggest maker of chewing gum, jumped on
Mars Inc.'s offer to buy the company for 28 percent more than its
closing price last week. Ford rallied after investor Kerkorian
said he has purchased a 4.7 percent stake in the second-largest
U.S. automaker and plans to buy more. Verizon, the second-biggest
U.S. phone company, climbed after customers spent more on text
messaging and wireless Internet browsing. Futures pared gains
after Warren Buffett told CNBC the U.S. economy is in a recession
that won't be ``short and shallow.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Standard  Poor's 500 Index futures expiring in June
increased 1.8, or 0.1 percent, to 1,398.9 at 9:05 a.m. in New
York. Dow Jones Industrial Average (INDU) futures were unchanged at
12,875 and Nasdaq-100 Index futures gained 5.5 to 1,926.5. Shares
in Asia and Europe rose. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``With a number of companies having their stocks being
depressed in this environment, the strongest players are
looking to take advantage of that, to come out of this downturn
in a better strategic position than when they went in,'' Stefan Selig, the global head of mergers at Bank of America Corp.,
said in an interview with Bloomberg Television. ``There are a
number of factors that will cause MA activity to pick up.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SP 500 (SPX) has climbed 9.8 percent since reaching a 19-month low March 10, helped by earnings from Google Inc., Intel
Corp., Boeing Co. and American Express Co. Earnings have topped
analysts' estimates at 69 percent of the 239 companies in the
index that have reported fist-quarter results so far, according
to data compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;`Further Rally' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. strategist Ian Scott, who
advised investors to buy global stocks before the past month's
rebound, said better-than-expected earnings will pave the way for
a bigger rally. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``The market was priced in for a substantial `miss,'''
Scott, managing director for global equity strategy at Lehman,
wrote in the note dated April 25. ``This has patently not
happened. These first-quarter numbers ought to provide the fuel
for a further rally in the market.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Eric Martin in New York at 
emartin21@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Chris Nagi at  chrisnagi@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry></news>