
<news><entry author="By Darrell Preston" date="Jun 05, 2009  3:52 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-06-05/general-motors-municipal-debt-holders-are-in-limbo-update1-.html"><headline>General Motors'' Municipal Debt Holders Are in Limbo</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Municipal bondholders with $700
million of General Motors Corp.-backed debt will have to wait
until the company develops a plan to exit bankruptcy to find out
how much, if anything, will be repaid. </p>
<p>GM, the largest manufacturer to go bankrupt, has used the
municipal bond market to pay for features at plants from
Michigan to Georgia. The Detroit-based carmaker''s plan for
repayment is still being evaluated, and a decision will be
made by the time a new company is formed to emerge from
bankruptcy, said GM spokeswoman Julie Gibson. </p>
<p>The investors are in limbo, said Richard Lehmann, a
registered investment adviser in Miami Lakes, Florida, and
president of Income Securities Advisors Inc. There''s real
concern for the bondholders. </p>
<p>Unsecured corporate bondholders will share in a 10 percent
stake in the new GM when the company emerges from Chapter 11
bankruptcy, according to court documents. The new government-controlled GM will keep major assets of the old company. GM
backed 15 bond issues in eight states totaling just over $700
million, Bloomberg data show. </p>
<p>There is uncertainty about what''s going to happen in
bankruptcy, said Dan Solender, who oversees $10 billion as
director of municipal bond management at Lord Abbett  Co. in
Jersey City, New Jersey. His firm owns about $7 million of GM-backed bonds in Ohio and Michigan, according to Bloomberg data. </p>
<h2>Tax Exempt </h2>
<p>Federal laws allow state and local governments to lend
their names to corporations wanting to sell tax-exempt debt for
specific types of facilities at plants such as pollution-control
or sewer systems. </p>
<p>The municipalities that allow their names to be used to
sell the debt don''t bear any liability for repayment. So far,
none of the General Motors-backed debt has missed any payments,
according to Bloomberg data. A June 1 payment due for bonds sold
for pollution-control equipment at a facility in Fort Wayne,
Indiana, was made, according to Bloomberg data. </p>
<p>Repayment will hinge, as it has in other bankruptcies
involving corporate-backed municipal debt, on whether GM decides
to keep an asset funded with the debt in the company going
forward, said James Spiotto, a partner and municipal bankruptcy
expert with the law firm of Chapman  Cutler in Chicago. </p>
<p>Until it is clear what''s going to happen with the assets,
you can''t predict what''s going to happen with the debt,
Spiotto said. </p>
<h2>Anticipating Bankruptcy </h2>
<p>Prices of some GM-backed municipal bonds had fallen in
recent months to less than 10 cents on the dollar, Bloomberg
data show, as investors sold the debt in anticipation of
bankruptcy. Those prices are similar to unsecured benchmark GM
corporate bonds, which have risen since the filing. </p>
<p>GM-backed municipal debt has risen since the filing earlier
this week. A GM-backed bond for a solid waste disposal facility
at a plant in Moraine, Ohio, traded at 9.75 cents on the dollar
in April. After the filing it rose as high as 15 cents. </p>
<p>The prices are based on investors'' estimates about how much
debt in the new company will be worth, said John Miller, chief
investment officer of Nuveen Asset Management in Chicago.
Nuveen, which has about $115 billion under management, sold its
GM-backed municipal securities earlier this year. </p>
<p>Fifteen cents on the dollar is probably pretty close to
what GM''s unsecured obligations are worth today, Miller said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Adam L. Freeman and Francesca Cinelli" date="Jun 25, 2009  2:25 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-06-25/generali-l-espresso-telecom-italia-italian-equity-preview.html"><headline>Generali, L''Espresso, Telecom Italia: Italian Equity Preview</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The following companies may have
unusual price changes in Italian trading. Stock symbols are in
parentheses and share prices are from the previous close. </p>
<p>Italy''s FTSE MIB (FTSEMIB) Index advanced 576.53, or 3.12 percent,
to 19,040.59. </p>
<p>Assicurazioni Generali SpA (G) : Bank of America
Corp. upgraded Italy''s biggest insurer to neutral from
underperform. The shares added 47 cents, or 3.3 percent, to
14.6 euros. </p>
<p>Banca Monte dei Paschi di Siena (BMPS IM): Italy''s third-largest bank is scheduled to hold an extraordinary shareholders''
meeting to approve new governance and compensation rules. The
shares rose 3 cents, or 2.7 percent, to 1.10 euros. </p>
<p>Fiat SpA (ISP) : Morgan Stanley said in a note today it''s
increasing its conviction on overweight-rated Fiat ahead of
second-quarter results. The brokerage said that market hype
around Fiat''s drive for consolidation has calmed following its
failure to acquire Opel. </p>
<p>Fiat added 19 cents, or 2.9 percent, to 6.82 euros. </p>
<p>Gruppo Editoriale L''Espresso SpA (ES) : The Italian
publisher hired lawyers to explore legal action against Prime
Minister Silvio Berlusconi related to remarks in which he
allegedly invited companies to boycott advertising in La
Repubblica newspaper. The publisher''s stock climbed 9 cents, or
8.25 percent, to 1.14 euros. </p>
<p>Safilo Group SpA (SFL) : Moody''s Investors Service
downgraded Safilo''s Corporate Family Rating to Caa2 from B3, and
the Probability of Default Rating to Caa3 from Caa1. </p>
<p>Separately, Standard  Poor''s Ratings Services lowered its
long-term corporate credit rating to CC from CCC+. The outlook
is negative. </p>
<p>Shares of the world''s second-largest maker of eyewear added
2.9 cents, or 6.4 percent, to 47.95 cents. </p>
<p>Telecom Italia SpA (TIT) : Goldman Sachs Group Inc. added
Italy''s biggest phone company to its conviction buy list,
citing its strong re-rating potential. The shares gained
1.25 cents, or 1.3 percent, to 94.85 cents. </p>
<p>UniCredit SpA (UCG) : Chief Executive Officer Alessandro
Profumo will speak at a Rome event organized by the bank. The
shares advanced 9.6 cents, or 5.5 percent, to 1.84 euros. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry></news>