
<news><entry author="By Victoria Slind-Flor" date="Jul 10, 2009  7:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-07-10/pfizer-ocean-spray-google-intellectual-property-update1-.html"><headline>Pfizer, Ocean Spray, Google: Intellectual Property</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer Inc. (PFE), the world&#8217;s biggest
drugmaker, failed to maintain its patent on the hypertension
drug Norvasc in Canada after a federal judge granted Ratiopharm
GmbH permission to sell a generic version of the medicine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than 7.8 million prescriptions of amlodipine besylate,
marketed by Pfizer as Norvasc, are sold annually in Canada, Ulm,
Germany-based Ratiopharm said yesterday. A generic version
probably will save Canadian patients about C$180 million ($155
million) a year, the closely held company said. Pfizer said it
will appeal. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;We are extremely pleased at the decision by the Federal
Court,&#8221; Jean-Guy Goulet, chief executive officer of Ratiopharm
Canada, said in a statement. &#8220;This decision opens the
amlodipine patent to generic manufacturers in Canada, the last
major jurisdiction where the patent was held.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ratiopharm challenged the Canadian patent in 2004 and won
in 2006. Pfizer successfully reversed the ruling on appeal.
Ratiopharm then sued to invalidate Pfizer&#8217;s patent, with Judge
Roger Hughes ruling in favor of Ratiopharm yesterday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three-paragraph judgment says the patent is &#8220;invalid
and void&#8221; and orders the Canadian Patent Office to record an
entry to that effect. Hughes didn&#8217;t release the reasons for his
decision, giving the two sides 20 days to make submissions on
which portions of the reasons should remain confidential. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pfizer said in a statement that it will ask the Federal
Court of Appeal of Canada to overturn the decision. The New
York-based company also said legal challenges to the patent in
Canada by other drugmakers are still pending. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Pfizer remains committed to protecting its intellectual
property rights and to ensuring the long-term viability of its
research and development programs,&#8221; the company said in the
statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ratio-Amlodipine, Ratiopharm&#8217;s version of Norvasc, will be
available in Canadian pharmacies &#8220;imminently,&#8221; the company
said. Norvasc sales plunged 52 percent in the first quarter of
2008 to $513 million after generic copies of the medicine came
on the U.S. market in March 2007. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Ratiopharm Inc. v. Pfizer Ltd., T-1712-07,
Federal Court of Canada (Toronto). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Ocean Spray Patents Cranberry-Based Breast-Cancer Treatment &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ocean Spray Cranberries Inc. (OCESO), a marketing cooperative based
in Lakeville, Massachusetts, received a U.S. patent on a method
of using cranberry seed oil to treat and prevent breast cancer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Patent 7,517,540, covers cranberry seed oil used to lower
blood cholesterol, prevent blood clotting, inflammatory
illnesses, autoimmune disorders and cancer. The patent also
covers methods of extracting cranberry seed oil in a form
suitable for adding to food, dietary supplements, or
pharmaceutical compositions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ocean Spray applied for the patent in November 2003, with
the assistance of Boston&#8217;s Lahive  Cockfield LLP. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Vizio Gets Favorable U.S. Customs Ruling Against Funio Patent &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vizio Inc., the maker of flat-panel television sets sold by
Costco Wholesale Corp. and Wal-Mart Stores Inc., will be able to
continue bringing its Taiwan-made televisions into the U.S., the
Irvine, California-based company said in a July 8 statement.
Vizio says it&#8217;s the No. 1 seller of flat-panel high-definition
television sets in the U.S. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company said the U.S. Customs and Border Protection
Agency issued a ruling finding the Vizio sets don&#8217;t infringe
U.S. Patent 6,115,074 owned by Japan&#8217;s Funai Electric Co. In
March, the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office issued its final
rejection of the disputed patent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vizio then sued Funai in federal court in Virginia on May
20, accusing the Japanese company of infringing seven patents
related to flat-panel televisions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rob Brinkman, Vizio&#8217;s vice president of operations, said
the customs ruling, together with the patent office action, will
bring the question of whether it&#8217;s infringing Funio&#8217;s patent to
a close. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Vizio v. Funai Electric Co., 2:09-cv-00236-RGD-JEW, U.S. District Court, Eastern District of Virginia
(Norfolk). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;310 Holdings Seeks U.S. Patent on Plastic-to-Oil Process &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;310 Holdings Inc. filed an application for a U.S. patent on
a process for breaking down molecules in order to extract fuel
from plastic, the Niagara Falls, Ontario-based company said in a
statement yesterday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process, known as &#8220;Plastic2Oil,&#8221; can extract one
liter of fuel from a kilogram of plastic, according to the
statement. The process can be completed in four hours from &#8220;a
large source of raw unwashed, mixed plastic,&#8221; the company said
in its statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#8217;s acquiring from China the apparatus used to perform
this process, the company said, with the arrival expected in
mid-August. John Bordynuik, 301 Holdings&#8217; president and chief
executive, said in the statement that his company will
demonstrate the process as soon as its application is accepted
by the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office and the apparatus
arrives from China. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Operations will take place at a new office in Cambridge,
Massachusetts, according to the company statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Copyright &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;EU Seeks to Reform Copyright Rules to Compete With Google Books &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The European Union&#8217;s executive arm plans to change
copyright rules that have prevented the bloc&#8217;s Internet
companies from competing with Google Inc. (GOOG)&#8217;s book-scanning
service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Viviane Reding, European media commissioner, said common EU
rules are needed so companies can provide an alternative to
Google&#8217;s Web-based book publication service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reding said she understands &#8220;the fears of many publishers
and librarians facing the market power of Google.&#8221; Internet
companies are frustrated by the &#8220;fragmented regulatory system
in Europe,&#8221; she said in a speech in Brussels yesterday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reding&#8217;s call for harmonized rules follows complaints from
German authors that Google, owner of the most-visited Internet
search engine, is violating copyright laws by allowing their
works to be viewed online free of charge and without previous
author approval. Google, based in Mountain View, California, is
creating an online book database by scanning millions of titles
from libraries. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company reached a $125 million deal with publishers
last year to settle copyright issues. The U.S. Justice
Department began an antitrust probe last month of the
settlement, which could make Google the main online source for
millions of out-of-print books. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;Book digitization projects send a strong signal that
authors, publishers, libraries and technology companies can work
together to bring back to life the world&#8217;s lost books,&#8221;
Santiago de la Mora, Google&#8217;s head of European book
partnerships, said in an e-mailed statement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Germany asked European regulators in May to look into how
the settlement, which must be reviewed by a U.S. federal court,
affects authors&#8217; rights in the EU. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reding said 90 percent of books in Europe&#8217;s national
libraries are no longer commercially available for scanning.
That&#8217;s because they are either out of print or so-called orphan
books, titles for which no one can be identified to give
permission for digital use, she said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without change &#8220;attractive content offers won&#8217;t take place
in Europe, but on the other side of the Atlantic,&#8221; Reding said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She proposed a registry for out-of-print and orphan books
that would allows authors to get &#8220;fair remuneration&#8221; for
online publications. A registry would help end the &#8220;rather
ideological debate&#8221; on Google books, she said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Symantec Gets $18 Million in Judgments Over Software &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Symantec Corp. (SYMC), the world&#8217;s largest maker of security
software, said yesterday it was awarded a total of $18.6 million
in damages against two closely held companies that it accused of
distributing fake versions of its products. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Federal courts in Los Angeles and San Jose, California,
ruled against V-Micro Inc. and Higher Model Computer LLC in
February, court records show. Symantec waited to publicize the
awards to &#8220;squeeze&#8221; the companies for information about their
distribution networks and locate &#8220;bigger fish,&#8221; said Cris Paden, a spokesman for Cupertino, California-based Symantec. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;We&#8217;ve never really focused on recovering damages in these
types of rulings,&#8221; Paden said yesterday in an e-mail. &#8220;Our
main focus has always been to protect unsuspecting users and
prospective customers.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;U.S. District Judge Samuel Conti on Feb. 4 ordered New
Jersey-based V-Micro to pay Symantec $9.7 million for violating
its trademarks and copyrights by distributing counterfeit
software. Two weeks later, U.S. District Judge Stephen Wilson in
Los Angeles ordered Connecticut-based Higher Model to pay $8.9
million. Court records show that neither company had responded
to the complaints, which were filed in 2007 and 2008. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;The damage awards are a way of financially crippling the
piracy rings by having a legal ruling to seize their assets,
usually to pay for damages,&#8221; Paden said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The companies were accused of selling knockoffs of Symantec
products including Norton Antivirus and Norton Ghost. The
default judgment rulings against the companies bar them from
using the copyrighted software or the trademarked product names. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Representatives of V-Micro and Higher Model couldn&#8217;t be
reached for comment through phone directory listings, and
lawyers for the companies weren&#8217;t listed on court dockets. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Higher Model was sued by Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) in 1999 for
dealing in counterfeit software, Symantec said in court papers.
A federal court in Connecticut awarded Microsoft money damages
and a court order barring Higher Model from violating its
trademarks or copyrights, Symantec said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Symantec learned that Higher Model was buying Symantec-branded software from unauthorized distributors and selling it
to customers who thought it was legitimate. Symantec bought the
disks and inspected them for authenticity. In 2006, the company
warned Higher Model it was dealing in counterfeit products and
later sent it a cease-and-desist letter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;The defendants willfully and maliciously continued to
purchase and sell counterfeit Symantec products even after they
were given an opportunity by Symantec to purchase from
legitimate distributors,&#8221; the software maker said in court
filings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cases are Symantec Corp. v. Higher Model Computer LLC,
2:07-cv-06581, U.S. District Court, Central District of
California (Los Angeles) and Symantec Corp. v. V-Micro Inc.,
3:08-cv-02063, U.S. District Court, Northern District of
California (San Jose). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Trademark &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Mary Kay Sues Yahoo! for Infringement by Hyperlinks in E-Mails &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mary Kay Corp. sued Yahoo! Inc. for trademark infringement. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sunnyvale, California-based Internet media company is
accused of inserting hyperlinks that infringe the Mary Kay
trademarks into messages sent to those who receive e-mail on
Yahoo! Mail. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These hyperlink ads are often from unauthorized resellers
of Mary Kay cosmetics and neither the Dallas-based cosmetics
company nor its independent sales agents have authorized their
use of the company trademarks, according to court papers filed
July 6 in federal court in Dallas. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mary Kay says a &#8220;substantial number&#8221; of the recipients of
marketing emails sent by the cosmetics company or its authorized
independent consultants are users of Yahoo! Inc.&#8217;s e-mail
service. The recipients are likely to believe the hyperlink ads
were authorized by Mary Kay and are likely to be confused and
follow the links to unauthorized sellers, according to court
papers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hyperlink ads appear &#8220;with no indication that the e-mails were manipulated and revised en route by Yahoo! without
the authorization of Mary Kay,&#8221; the cosmetics company said in
its pleadings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mary Kay asked the court for an order barring Yahoo from
inserting &#8220;any hyperlinks, Webtags, advertisements, text or
other materials&#8221; using its marks into e-mails sent or received
by the Yahoo! Inc., e-mail subscribers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, it&#8217;s seeking an accounting and award of
Yahoo!&#8217;s profits related to the alleged infringement, attorney
fees and money damages. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Veronica S. Lewis and Allen W. Yee of Houston-based Vinson
 Elkins LLP represent Mary Kay. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case is Mary Kay Inc., v. Yahoo Inc., 3:09-cv-01278-M,
U.S. District Court, Northern District of Texas (Dallas). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Moulin Rouge SA Forces New Jersey Salon to Change Its Name &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite having spent years decorating the shop with a Paris
cabaret theme, owners of a New Jersey hair salon are changing
its name after being threatened with a trademark-infringement
suit, the Philadelphia Enquirer reported yesterday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Owners of Salon Moulin Rouge in Rockaway Township received
a letter from a lawyer representing Belgium&#8217;s Moulin Rouge SA,
according to the Enquirer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Belgian company, which is represented by Deborah Nilson
of New York-based Rozan  Nilson, seldom licenses its name, the
lawyer told the Enquirer. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Owners of the salon will invite members of the public to
pick a new name, the Enquirer reported. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;University of Utah Protests Shot of Logo in HBO&#8217;s &#8216;Big Love&#8217; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Time Warner Inc. (TWX)&#8217;s HBO received a cease-and-desist letter
from the University of Utah after a scene in the cable channel&#8217;s
polygamy drama &#8220;Big Love&#8221; showed what appeared to be the
university&#8217;s logo on a piece of letterhead, Salt Lake City&#8217;s
Deseret News reported. July 7. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The use of the letterhead &#8220;may have led some viewers to
believe the school is associated with &#8216;Big Love,&#8217;&#8221; when it is
not, university spokeswoman Coralie Alder told the Deseret News. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;We will not tolerate a misuse of our trademarks,
especially if it could lead the public to erroneously believe
the university is associated with a production over which the
university has no control, Michael Young, the university&#8217;s
president, said in a statement, according to the Deseret News. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cease-and-desist letter, sent on the university&#8217;s
behalf by its licensing agent, Collegiate Images, demanded that
shots including the logo be deleted from the episode and never
used again, the Deseret News reported. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By John F. Wasik" date="Jul 21, 2009  9:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-07-21/goldman-sachs-alum-decries-second-banking-crisis-john-f-wasik.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Alum Decries Second Banking Crisis: John F. Wasik</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Banks continue to feast at the
bailout banquet while consumers are getting thrown the crumbs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most vexing result of last year&#8217;s financial meltdown is
that loans are harder to get and more expensive, even if your
credit is good. Yet on Wall Street, happy days look like they
are here again. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To almost no one&#8217;s surprise, the nation&#8217;s largest banks are
returning to their old, pre-crisis ways, even in the midst of a
$23.7 trillion bailout, the biggest financial rescue in history. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banks based on trading and highly leveraged business models
still pose a huge risk to the financial system, so much so that
our government has enshrined as policy the doctrine of &#8220;too big
to fail.&#8221; Haven&#8217;t we learned anything from the past year? &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While trading and investment-banking profits for Goldman
Sachs Group Inc. and JPMorgan Chase  Co. soared in the second
quarter, Washington&#8217;s attitude toward policing financial
services practices is still a weak, unpracticed theory. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second banking crisis unfolds with the realization that
&#8220;reckless banking practices&#8221; translated into $65 trillion in
global wealth lost since September 2007, says Nomi Prins, a
former Goldman Sachs managing director, who is publishing a book
on the financial debacle titled &#8220;It Takes A Pillage.&#8221; This
meltdown will continue to pummel Western economies for years if
not decades. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Culture Thriving &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prins, who once marketed collateralized debt obligations --
which were often used to bundle toxic mortgages -- notes that
the largest banks have actually grown during this crisis: Bank
of America Corp. took over Merrill Lynch  Co., JPMorgan assumed
Bear Stearns Cos. and Wells Fargo  Co. acquired Wachovia Corp. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bigger isn&#8217;t better for consumers. Prins says these
institutions have &#8220;less incentive (since they have more market
share) to offer higher savings rates, or broader credit terms to
consumers, or open mortgage restructuring policies, or even
lower fees on regular accounts -- they simply don&#8217;t have to, and
it was not a condition of their bailout money to make it so.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nothing has changed in recent months, except that taxpayers
are increasingly getting treated as if they&#8217;re homeless and
begging for money. Congress has yet to find the gumption to make
lower financing rates and foreclosure-halting mortgage
modifications mandatory. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banks are bringing in more money, although they aren&#8217;t
making credit widely available, prolonging the recession. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consumers Aren&#8217;t Helped &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While two-thirds of all government-insured banks reported
asset growth in the first quarter, total loans fell by about
$160 billion, or 2.1 percent, according to the Federal Deposit
Insurance Corp. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of those banks that received bailout money from the
government&#8217;s Troubled Asset Relief Program, or TARP, only 29 of
103 surveyed said they loaned out funds for &#8220;residential
mortgage activities.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A July 21 report from the TARP special inspector general
also noted that 17 of 61 banks surveyed said they were doing
&#8220;other consumer lending&#8221; and only nine of 34 banks were doing
mortgage-loan modifications. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banks are missing in action on the foreclosure front as
well. Only a handful of mortgages for those facing default due
to higher adjustable rates or job losses are being modified. A
recent Federal Reserve of Boston study found that only 3 percent
of &#8220;seriously delinquent loans&#8221; were being made more
affordable by the banks they studied. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, lending across the board has tightened.
Mortgages are difficult to obtain -- even for the most
creditworthy -- and banks are lowering credit-card limits, which
can impair one&#8217;s ability to borrow if your credit scores drop. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Little Support &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even as the cost of funds to banks has held near historic
lows since the end of last year, annual credit-card finance
rates rose from an average of 12.02 percent to 13.08 percent
between November and February, according to the Congressional
Oversight Panel. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If anything, fees on credit cards and bank accounts will
continue to rise as banks try to recoup their losses and shift
their risk to you through obnoxious overdraft fees, higher
finance rates and lower credit limits. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Want to push back? Just maybe the best treatment for mega-
banking&#8217;s avarice-addled culture is for us to stop enabling
their addiction. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your best recourse may be to limit credit card use, make
insured deposits at local thrifts and regional banks -- the
deposit insurance limit is generally $250,000 per account
through 2013 -- and turn to alternative sources of lending such
as credit unions and your own family. Avoid commission-based
services through banks, insurers and brokers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A brand-name big bank may represent the old way of doing
business. And that&#8217;s been one of the surest ways to part you
from your wealth. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(John F. Wasik, author of &#8220;The Cul-de-Sac Syndrome,&#8221; is a
Bloomberg News columnist. The opinions expressed are his own.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Michael Lewis" date="Jul 27, 2009  9:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2009-07-27/bashing-goldman-sachs-is-simply-a-game-for-fools-michael-lewis.html"><headline>Bashing Goldman Sachs Is Simply a Game for Fools: Michael Lewis</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;From the moment I left Yale and
started working for Goldman Sachs, I&#8217;ve felt uneasy interacting
with those who don&#8217;t. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&#8217;s not that I think less of Goldman outsiders than I did
while I remained among you. It&#8217;s just that I feel your envy, and
know that nothing I can do or say will ever persuade you that I
am no more than human. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thus, like many of my colleagues, I have adopted a
strategy of never leaving Goldman Sachs, apart from a few brief,
spasmodic attempts to make what you outsiders call &#8220;love&#8221; or
&#8220;the beast with two backs.&#8221; Goldman recognizes how important
it is for its people to replicate themselves. We bill no
performance fees for the service. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, the sheer volume of irresponsible media commentary
has forced us to reconsider our public-relations strategy. With
every uptick in our share price it&#8217;s grown clearer that we who
are inside Goldman Sachs must open a dialogue with you who are
not. Not for our benefit, but for yours. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;America stands at a crossroads, and Goldman Sachs now owns
both of them. In choosing which road to take, ordinary Americans
must not be distracted by unproductive resentment toward the
toll-takers. To that end we at Goldman Sachs would like to
dispel several false and insidious rumors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rumor No. 1: &#8220;Goldman Sachs controls the U.S.
government.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time we hear the phrase &#8220;the United States of
Goldman Sachs&#8221; we shake our heads in wonder. Every ninth-grader
knows that the U.S. government consists of three branches.
Goldman owns just one of these outright; the second we simply
rent, and the third we have no interest in at all. (Note there
isn&#8217;t a single former Goldman employee on the Supreme Court.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What small interest we maintain in the U.S. government is,
we feel, in the public interest. Our current financial crisis
has its roots in a single easily identifiable source: the envy
others felt toward Goldman Sachs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bozos at Merrill Lynch, the dimwits at Citigroup, the
nimrods at Lehman Brothers, the louts at Bear Stearns, even that
momentarily useful lunatic Joe Cassano at AIG -- all of these
people took risks that no non-Goldman person should ever take,
in a pathetic attempt to replicate Goldman&#8217;s financial returns. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For too long we have allowed others to emulate us. Now we
are working productively with Treasury Secretary Tim Geithner
and the Congress to ensure that we alone are allowed to take the
sort of risks that might destroy the financial system. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rumor No. 2: &#8220;When the U.S. government bailed out AIG, and
paid off its gambling debts, it saved not AIG but Goldman
Sachs.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The charge isn&#8217;t merely insulting but ignorant. Less
responsible journalists continue to bring up the $12.9 billion
we received from AIG, as if that was some kind of big deal to
us. But as our CFO David Viniar explained back in March, we were
hedged. Our profits from AIG &#8220;rounded to zero.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People who don&#8217;t work at Goldman Sachs, of course, find
this implausible: How could $12.9 billion round to zero? Easy,
but you just need to understand the mathematics. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#8217;s assume AIG transferred $12,880,560,250.34 of taxpayer
money to Goldman Sachs. A Goldman outsider, asked to round this
number, might call it $12,880,560,250.00. That&#8217;s not how we look
at it; at Goldman we always round to the nearest $50 billion, so
anything less than $25 billion rounds to zero. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think of it that way and you can see that
$12,880,560,250.34 isn&#8217;t even close to not rounding to zero. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rumor No. 3: &#8220;As the U.S. government will eat the losses
if Goldman Sachs goes bust, Goldman Sachs shouldn&#8217;t be allowed
to keep making these massive financial bets. At the very least
the $11.4 billion Goldman Sachs already has set aside for
employees in 2009 -- $386,429 a head, just for the first six
months -- is unfair, as the U.S. taxpayer has borne so much of
the risk of the wagers that generated the profits.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really, we don&#8217;t know where to begin with this one. It is
wrong-headed in so many different ways! &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&#8217;s begin with the idea that the taxpayer is running a
bigger risk than we are. The billions he stands to lose are
trivial; after all, they round to zero. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The real risk, when you think about it even for a minute,
is the risk we take ourselves: that Goldman will cease to exist
and we will cease to be Goldman employees. To flirt with such
tragedy we obviously need to be paid. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rumor No. 4:  &#8220;Goldman employees all look alike.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several recent newspaper photos have revealed that a
surprising number of Goldman Sachs workers are white, male and
bald. That non-Goldman people glance at such photos and think
&#8220;Holy crap, they even look alike!&#8221; just shows how deeply anti-
Goldman bigotry runs in American life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We at Goldman represent unique clusters of DNA; if we bear
some faint surface resemblance to one another, and to creatures
from the 24th century, it is only because our superior powers of
reasoning lead us to hold in our minds exactly the same
thoughts, at exactly the same time. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A shared disinterest in growing hair, for instance, isn&#8217;t a
coincidence of nature but an expression of healthy like-
mindedness. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#8220;The world is a pool table,&#8221; our naked-headed CEO likes
to tell us. &#8220;And all the people in it are either stripes or
solids. You alone are the cue balls.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rumor No. 5: Goldman Sachs is &#8220;a great vampire squid
wrapped around the face of humanity, relentlessly jamming its
blood funnel into anything that smells like money.&#8221; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those words are of course taken from a recent issue of
Rolling Stone magazine and they are transparently false. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For starters, the vampire squid doesn&#8217;t feed on human
flesh. Ergo, no vampire squid would ever wrap itself around the
face of humanity, except by accident. And nothing that happens
at Goldman Sachs -- nothing that Goldman Sachs thinks, nothing
that Goldman Sachs feels, nothing that Goldman Sachs does --ever
happens by accident. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Michael Lewis is a columnist for Bloomberg News and the
author of &#8220;Liar&#8217;s Poker,&#8221; &#8220;Moneyball&#8221; and &#8220;The Blind
Side,&#8221; soon to be a major motion picture. The opinions
expressed are his own.) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry></news>