<?xml version='1.0' encoding='us-ascii'?>
<news><entry author="By Loveday Morris" date="Jun 09, 2008 11:56 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-06-09/dsg-declines-as-goldman-sachs-cuts-rating-to-sell-update1-.html"><headline>DSG Declines as Goldman Sachs Cuts Rating to `Sell'</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;     June 9 (Bloomberg) -- DSG International Plc, the U.K.'s
largest consumer electronics retailer, slid in London trading
after Goldman Sachs Group Inc. cut its rating on the stock to
``sell,'' saying heightened competition, price deflation and a
slowing housing market will hurt sales. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DSG fell 2 percent after Goldman analysts led by Lucy Chamberlain lowered their recommendation on the Hemel Hempstead,
England-based retailer from ``neutral,'' in a note distributed
after markets closed on June 6. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``We believe the electricals sub-sector faces enormous
structural issues,'' Chamberlain wrote. ``We expect trading to
deteriorate in the coming months. We also expect further
weakness in the housing market to impact sales'' of so-called
white goods such as refrigerators, washing machines and ovens. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DSG has cut profit forecasts twice this year as it loses
sales to Web retailers and supermarkets, and may face stiffer
competition as Best Buy Co. plans its first British stores. The
retailer, which also must contend with ebbing consumer confidence,
said this month it would close as many as 77 stores and cut its
dividend by 50 percent, after three years of falling earnings. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DSG dropped 1.25 pence to 61.25 pence in London. The shares
have slid 38 percent this year, after falling 48 percent in 2007. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Loveday Morris in London at 
lmorris7@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Keith Campbell at  k.campbell@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Andrea Rothman and Gareth Gore" date="Jun 13, 2008 11:52 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-06-13/michelin-peugeot-join-goldman-conviction-buy-list-update3-.html"><headline>Michelin, Peugeot Join Goldman `Conviction Buy' List</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Michelin  Cie. (ML), the world's second-largest tiremaker, and PSA Peugeot Citroen (UG), Europe's No. 2
carmaker, were added to the ``conviction buy list'' at Goldman
Sachs Group, which cited efficiency measures and product pricing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michelin rose the most in 4 1/2 months in Paris trading
after Goldman said the Clermont Ferrand, France-based company
will probably ``demonstrate success'' in raising tire prices. A
reorganization and sales growth abroad will help Paris-based
Peugeot limit the effects of higher raw-material costs, London-based analysts Stefan Burgstaller, Shane McKenna and Tim Rothery
wrote in a note to investors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Record oil prices and slowing economies have discouraged car
purchases in Europe, and the Goldman analysts reduced the auto
industry to ``neutral'' from ``attractive.'' New registrations in
the region dropped 7.8 percent to 1.33 million vehicles in May
from 1.45 million a year earlier, and five-month deliveries
declined 0.7 percent, the Brussels-based European Automobile
Manufacturers Association said today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``Against a backdrop of slowing global growth since the
onset of the credit crisis last summer, the European automotive
sector has fallen 38 percent since the market peak'' on Oct. 31,
the analysts wrote. ``European automotive share prices have been
quite volatile, trading within a 30 percent trading range on
average. We believe this is likely to continue until the market
adopts a more positive stance on the economic outlook.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;BMW Reorganization &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bayerische Motoren Werke AG (BMW), the world's largest maker of
luxury vehicles, was downgraded to ``neutral'' from ``buy'' by
the analysts, who said a reorganization at the Munich-based
carmaker ``is occurring more slowly than we expected.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BMW's 12-month stock-price estimate was cut to 44 euros from
49 euros by the analysts, who said key risks include lower-than-forecast sales volumes as well as foreign-exchange effects. The
analysts estimated Peugeot's share price may reach 53 euros in
the next year, and they increased the price target for Michelin
to 65 euros from 57 euros. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michelin rose 3.40 euros, or 7.1 percent, to 51.41 euros,
the biggest jump since Jan. 24. Peugeot rose 1.45 euros, or 4
percent, to 37.37 euros, the largest gain since March 25. BMW
shares fell 11 cents, or 0.3 percent, to 33.56 euros in German
trading. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman also advised clients in a separate note today to
sell Peugeot put options, calling the shares inexpensive. Jason Cuttler, a London-based analyst, recommended that investors sell
put options expiring in December at a strike price of 35 euros,
or 2.6 percent below the stock's 35.92-euro closing price
yesterday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Put options give the buyer the right, but not the
obligation, to sell stock at a certain price on a set date.
Selling a put option means an investor is betting the purchaser
will choose not to exercise the contract, allowing them to keep
as profit the premium paid for the option. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Andrea Rothman in Paris at 
aerothman@bloomberg.net;
Gareth Gore in Madrid 
ggore1@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Christopher Jasper at  cjasper@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Nesa Subrahmaniyan" date="Jun 18, 2008  4:57 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-06-18/oil-s-bull-run-may-end-on-supplies-jpmorgan-says-update2-.html"><headline>Oil's `Bull Run' May End on Supplies, JPMorgan Says</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Crude oil's ``bull run'' may be over
as prices become increasingly volatile and Saudi Arabia pledged
to boost supplies, according to JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the third-largest U.S. bank. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prices are expected to ``correct'' over the next few
months, JPMorgan analysts led by Brynjar Eirik Bustnes said in a
report today. Spare production capacity may reach 5 million
barrels a day by 2010, similar to levels in 2002 to 2003, when
oil was $30 a barrel, the analysts said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oil price volatility over a 30-day period reached the
highest since February 2007 on June 11 after New York crude
futures had their biggest one-day gain of $10.75 a barrel on
June 6. The Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries last
week cut its 2008 global oil demand forecast for a fifth month
as record prices curb consumption while stockpiles have
increased. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``Saudi has pledged to increase production by around
500,000 barrels a day over the next two months, which should
show up in inventory increases,'' Bustnes said. New production
from OPEC and non-OPEC would be enough to meet demand growth in
until 2010, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JPMorgan's crude oil price estimate is substantially below
the consensus compiled by Bloomberg, Bustnes said in the report.
JPMorgan's estimate for Brent crude oil in 2008 is $90 a barrel
compared with the consensus analysts' estimate of $108, and from
2009 to 2011 it is forecast at $85 a barrel versus prices of
$110, $105 and $100, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Record Price &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crude oil in New York rose to a record $139.89 a barrel on
June 16 even after Saudi Arabia, the world's biggest producer,
said it is boosting output and called for a meeting in the Red
Sea city of Jeddah between producers, consumers and financial
institutions on June 22 to discuss ways to stabilize prices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brent crude oil for August settlement traded at $133.61 at
9:37 a.m. London time after dropping as low as $133 a barrel on
London's ICE Futures Europe exchange today. Prices reached a
record $139.32 on June 16. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The International Energy Agency, the energy adviser to 27
nations, on June 10 cut its forecast for global oil demand for a
fifth month on falling consumption. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IEA reduced its 2008 forecast by about 70,000 barrels a
day to 86.77 million barrels a day from 86.84 million last
month, the Paris-based agency said, leaving demand growth for
this year at 0.9 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OPEC in its monthly report said oil demand this year will
rise 1.1 million barrels a day to 86.88 million barrels, about
60,000 barrels a day lower than last month's estimate of 86.95
million barrels a day. Saudi Arabia is pumping an additional
300,000 barrels of crude oil a day this month. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;OPEC Higher &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``Interestingly, OPEC now has higher demand growth than
IEA, which is very unusual considering their positions as
exporters and importers of crude,'' Bustnes wrote in the report. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OPEC's spare production capacity will increase just as non-OPEC producers boost supplies, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oil companies, or so-called upstream producers such as
Cnooc Ltd. (883), PTT Exploration  Production Pcl (PTTEP), and Cairn Energy
Plc (CNE), ``offer the best leverage to oil prices,'' the JPMorgan
analysts said in the report. The shares of these companies
haven't risen along with the increase in crude oil prices, the
analysts said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upstream producers have underperformed crude prices in the
past four months by 40 percent, the report said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While using $90 a barrel as the oil price estimate for this
year, JPMorgan is using $85 a barrel for its long-term oil price
estimate for 2009 onwards, the analysts said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``If we are wrong on oil prices, so much the better,'' they
said in the report. ``Lower oil prices appear to be priced in.
High oil prices fuels upgrades in earnings.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Nesa Subrahmaniyan in Singapore at 
nesas@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Clyde Russell at  crussell7@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Nesa Subrahmaniyan" date="Jun 18, 2008  2:45 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-06-18/oil-s-bull-run-may-be-over-on-supply-jpmorgan-says-update1-.html"><headline>Oil's `Bull Run' May Be Over on Supply, JPMorgan Says</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Crude oil's ``bull run'' may be over
as prices become increasingly volatile and Saudi Arabia pledged
to boost supplies, according to JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the third-largest U.S. bank. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prices are expected to ``correct'' over the next few months,
JPMorgan analysts led by Brynjar Eirik Bustnes said in a report
today. Spare production capacity may reach 5 million barrels a
day by 2010, similar to levels in 2002 to 2003, when oil was $30
a barrel, the analysts said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oil price volatility over a 30-day period reached the
highest since February 2007 on June 11 after New York crude
futures had their biggest one-day gain of $10.75 a barrel on June
6. The Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries last week
cut its 2008 global oil demand forecast for a fifth month as
record prices curb consumption while stockpiles have increased. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``Saudi has pledged to increase production by around 500,000
barrels a day over the next two months, which should show up in
inventory increases,'' Bustnes said. New production from OPEC and
non-OPEC would be enough to meet demand growth in until 2010, he
said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JPMorgan's crude oil price estimate is substantially below
the consensus compiled by Bloomberg, Bustnes said in the report.
JPMorgan's estimate for Brent crude oil in 2008 is $90 a barrel
compared with the consensus analysts' estimate of $108, and from
2009 to 2011 it is forecast at $85 a barrel versus prices of $110,
$105 and $100, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Record Price &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Crude oil in New York rose to a record $139.89 a barrel on
June 16 even after Saudi Arabia, the world's biggest producer,
said it is boosting output and called for a meeting in the Red
Sea city of Jeddah between producers, consumers and financial
institutions on June 22 to discuss ways to stabilize prices. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The International Energy Agency, the energy adviser to 27
nations, on June 10 cut its forecast for global oil demand for a
fifth month on falling consumption. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The IEA reduced its 2008 forecast by about 70,000 barrels a
day to 86.77 million barrels a day from 86.84 million last month,
the Paris-based agency said, leaving demand growth for this year
at 0.9 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;OPEC in its monthly report said oil demand this year will
rise 1.1 million barrels a day to 86.88 million barrels, about
60,000 barrels a day lower than last month's estimate of 86.95
million barrels a day. Saudi Arabia is pumping an additional
300,000 barrels of crude oil a day this month. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;OPEC Higher &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``Interestingly, OPEC now has higher demand growth than IEA,
which is very unusual considering their positions as exporters
and importers of crude,'' Bustnes wrote in the report. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the new production coming from OPEC in the next few
years to 2010 would probably be part of ``spare capacity'' as
non-OPEC increase supplies, he said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oil companies, or so-called upstream oil producers such
Cnooc Ltd. (883), PTT Exploration  Production Pcl, and Cairn Energy
Plc (CNE), ``offer the best leverage to oil prices,'' the JPMorgan
analysts said in the report. The shares of these companies
haven't risen along with the increase in crude oil prices, the
analysts said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upstream producers have underperformed crude prices in the
past four months by 40 percent as higher prices haven't been
priced in the shares of the companies, Bustnes and his colleagues
wrote. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While using $90 a barrel as the oil price estimate for this
year, JPMorgan is using $85 a barrel for its long-term oil price
estimate for 2009 onwards, the analysts said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``If we are wrong on oil prices, so much the better,'' they
said in the report. ``Lower oil prices appear to be priced in.
High oil prices fuels upgrades in earnings.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Nesa Subrahmaniyan in Singapore at 
nesas@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Clyde Russell at  crussell7@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Ron Harui" date="Jun 20, 2008  4:32 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-06-20/sell-south-african-rand-on-economy-rate-outlook-goldman-says.html"><headline>Sell South African Rand on Economy, Rate Outlook, Goldman Says</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Investors should sell the South
African rand on speculation the economy will slow and because
the central bank may be ``behind the curve'' in raising interest
rates to curb inflation, according to Goldman Sachs Group Inc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;South Africa's currency may also decline as the current-account deficit widens, said Goldman Sachs, the world's largest
securities firm. The bank recommended investors buy the dollar
around 8 against the rand, and place an automatic order to sell
the U.S. currency should it post a daily close below 7.78. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``Attracting sufficient funding inflow becomes ever more
challenging,'' wrote Goldman's analysts Thomas Stolper, Themos
Fiotakis, Jens Nordvig and Fiona Lake in research note to
clients yesterday. ``Rapidly deteriorating inflation
expectations suggest policy should be tightened more.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rand has dropped 4.3 percent this month as the central
bank last week increased borrowing costs by less than economists
estimated, Goldman's analysts wrote. The South African Reserve
Bank boosted the key rate by 50 basis points to 12 percent.
Economists had predicted an increase of 1 percentage point,
according to the median of 25 estimates in a Bloomberg News
survey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inflation, which accelerated to an annual 10.4 percent in
April, will peak at 12 percent in the third quarter and stay
outside its target range of 3 to 6 percent, according to the
central bank. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;South Africa's rand traded at 7.9538 versus the U.S.
currency as of 8:50 a.m. in Johannesburg, compared with 7.9462
late yesterday. It reached 8.1783 on June 13, the weakest since
March 31. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Foreign Investment &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current-account shortfall, the broadest measure of
trade in goods and services, swelled to 9 percent of gross
domestic product in the first quarter, the central bank said
this week. That's the most in 26 years, from 7.5 percent of GDP
in the fourth quarter. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This ``adds to the pressure on the rand,'' wrote the
Goldman analysts. Stolper, Fiotakis and Lake are based in London,
while Nordvig is based in New York. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;South Africa relies mainly on foreign investment in stocks
and bonds to finance its import needs. Inflows began to dry up
in the fourth quarter as investors sold riskier, emerging market
assets. There was a net outflow of portfolio investment for the
first time since 2005 in the first quarter, fueling a 13.6
percent decline in the rand versus the dollar this year, the
worst performer among the 16 most-active currencies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Technical Charts &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technical charts that traders use to predict price
movements also suggest the U.S. dollar will strengthen versus
the rand, according to Goldman. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``Dollar-rand posted 10 successive higher closes up to last
Thursday after holding above key retracement support at 7.48 in
mid-May,'' the analysts said. ``Such impulsive moves are rare.
We would expect to see acceleration above the 8.2525 March high
to target a long-term retracement level from 2001 at 8.7545.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Support at 7.48 is a 50 percent retracement of the dollar's
rise from the Jan. 14 low of 6.7105, according to a series of
numbers known as the Fibonacci sequence. Support is where buy
orders may be clustered. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The target of 8.7545 is a 23.6 percent retracement of the
dollar's decline from the high of 13.8401 on Dec. 21, 2001. The
8.7545 level was last seen in January 2003. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Ron Harui in Singapore 
rharui@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Sandy Hendry at 
shendry@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Francesca Cinelli" date="Jun 26, 2008  7:15 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-06-26/italy-stocks-update-buzzi-fiat-trevisan-tiscali-unicredit.html"><headline>Italy Stocks Update: Buzzi, Fiat, Trevisan, Tiscali, UniCredit</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Italy's SP/MIB Index declined 316,
or 1.1 percent, to 29,693. Futures expiring in September lost
333, or 1.1 percent, to 30,000. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following were among the most active stocks on the
Italian market today. Share symbols are in parentheses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assicurazioni Generali SpA (G) , Europe's third-biggest
insurer, pared losses, adding 139 cents, or 0.5 percent, to
24.79 euros. UBS AG raised its recommendation on the stock to
``neutral'' from ``sell'' and expects higher investment income
on the back of rising bond yields. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Atlantia SpA (ATL) , Europe's largest toll-highway
operator, slipped for the third consecutive day, losing 66
cents, or 3.2 percent, to 20.04 euros. The breakup of former
holding Schemaventotto became effective yesterday. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buzzi Unicem SpA (BZU) , Italy's second-biggest cement
maker, rose 44.9 cents, or 2.8 percent, to 16.3 euros. ``We
consider Buzzi as an interesting investment story on the back of
company's presence in growing Eastern Europe,'' said Davide
Pasquali, a fund manager at Pharus Management SA in Mendrisio,
Switzerland. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fiat SpA (ISP) , Italy's largest manufacturer, shed 43.9
cents, or 3.9 percent, to 10.71 euros. Fiat's performance will
``continue to suffer for a few months'' because of the economic
downturn, Chairman Luca Cordero di Montezemolo said, according
to Il Sole 24 Ore. Automobile stocks were the second-worst
performers among the 18 industry groups in Europe's Dow Jones
Stoxx 600 Index today. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finmeccanica SpA (FNC) , Italy's biggest defense company,
dropped 37 cents, or 2.2 percent, to 16.5 euros. Societe
Generale cut its price estimate on the stock to 17 euros from 20
euros. Separately, Thales SA, Europe's biggest military-electronics maker, said it isn't planning to try to top
Finmeccanica SpA's offer for DRS Technologies Inc, denying a
report in Les Echos. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luxottica Group SpA (LUX) , the world's biggest maker of
eyeglasses, fell 80 cents, or 4.9 percent, to 15.53 euros. The
company is scheduled to hold a conference call with analysts and
confirm annual forecasts. The key element will be cost-cutting
effectiveness in order to meet Luxottica's full-year targets,
Euromobiliare analysts wrote in a research report. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Saipem SpA (SPM) , Europe's largest oil-field services
contractor by market value, pared losses, adding 15 cents, or
0.52 percent, to 28.81 euros. The company announced it won $1.1
billion in onshore drilling contracts in South America and
Ukraine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ERG SpA (ERG) , Italy's biggest crude oil refiner by
sales, surged 24 cents, or 1.6 percent, to 15.41 euros. UBS AG
upgraded the stock to ``buy'' from ``sell.'' Goldman Sachs
increased its price estimate on the stock to 16.1 euros from
13.2 euros. ``ERG's decision to enter into a partnership with
Lukoil is a sensible move achieved at a good price,'' Goldman
Sachs analysts wrote in a research report. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tiscali SpA (TIS) , the Italian Internet provider that's
for sale, climbed 4.8 percent to 2.13 euros. Telecom Italia SpA
(TIT IM) is ``evaluating the sale of Tiscali very closely,''
Chief Executive Officer Franco Bernabe told la Repubblica in an
interview. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trevisan Cometal SpA (TRV IM), the aluminum coatings and
engineering company whose clients include Alcoa Inc., fell to a
record, losing 10.85 cents, or 5.4 percent, to 1.91 euros. Banca
Akros cut its price estimate on the stock to 2.6 euros from 2.9
euros, citing poor prospects for results improvements this year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UniCredit SpA (UCG) , Italy's biggest bank, declined for
the first time in four days, losing 15.8 cents, or 3.8 percent,
to 3.97 euros. The lender's new business plan, presented today
in Vienna, ``seems prudent, presenting conservative numbers,''
Deutsche Bank analysts wrote in a research report. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banca Monte dei Paschi di Siena SpA (BMPS IM), Italy's
third-biggest bank, dropped 5.4 cents, or 3 percent, to 41.76
euros. Cheuvreux reiterated its ``underperform'' recommendation
on the stock. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporters on this story:
Francesca Cinelli in Milan at 
fcinelli@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Daniel Hauck at  dhauck1@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry><entry author="By Andy Fixmer" date="Jun 27, 2008  4:04 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-06-27/disney-s-wall-e-garbage-robot-may-spur-u-s-sales-update2-.html"><headline>Disney's `Wall-E,' Garbage Robot, May Spur U.S. Sales</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;``Wall-E,'' the movie about a trash-compacting robot, may end a slide in U.S. box-office sales for
Walt Disney Co. (DIS) and its Pixar animation studio. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film, opening in about 4,000 theaters today, probably
will exceed Pixar's 2007 release ``Ratatouille,'' which garnered
$47 million in its first weekend, according to Steve Mason, an
analyst in Los Angeles at FantasyMoguls.com, a box-office Web
site. He estimated weekend sales of $55 million. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disney, which bought Pixar in 2006, needs a hit to climb
from last place among the largest studios in 2008 U.S. sales.
``The Chronicles of Narnia: Prince Caspian'' missed Box Office
Mojo LLC's $86.9 million estimate last month, taking in $55
million in its opening weekend. Through June 22, Disney's
domestic ticket sales dropped 36 percent to $457.4 million,
according to the Burbank, California-based film tracker. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;```Wall-E' translates well around the world because of the
physical comedy and emotional aspects,'' Mark Zoradi, president
of Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures Group, said in an
interview. ``Nothing binds it to the United States. It's a
creative project that will work in 100 countries around the
world.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The movie from ``Finding Nemo'' creator Andrew Stanton
follows Wall-E, short for Waste Allocation Load Lifter Earth-Class, who clears garbage left by humans who fled the planet to
live on space ships. He falls in love with another robot, Eve,
the Extra-terrestrial Vegetation Evaluator sent to Earth to look
for signs of life. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;`Love Story' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The film may take in as much as $210 million in ticket
sales during its U.S. run, said David Joyce, an analyst at
Miller Tabak  Co. in New York, who recommends shares of
Burbank, California-based Disney and doesn't own them. That
would pass the $206 million of ``Ratatouille,'' according to
Internet Movie Database Inc., a unit of Amazon.com Inc. that
provides film data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;```Wall-E' boasts the best love story I've seen in 2008,''
said Gitesh Pandya, editor of industry newsletter
BoxOfficeGuru.com in New York. ``Word of mouth will be terrific
with all ages and this will last a long time.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disney, the second-largest U.S. media company, rose 4 cents
to $31.57 at 4 p.m. in New York Stock Exchange composite
trading. The shares have slipped 2.2 percent this year, compared
with a 13 percent drop in the SP 500 Index. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2003 Peak &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2003's ``Finding Nemo,'' the No. 2 animated film of
all time according to Box Office Mojo, each Pixar release has
produced lower U.S. box-office sales, a benchmark for subsequent
sales of DVDs and television revenue. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``U.S. box office is the most important factor in
anticipating all the other ancillary revenue streams,'' said
David Davis, founder of Arpeggio Partners LLC, a Santa Monica,
California-based consultant to Hollywood studios. ``It's not the
only factor, but it's the best indicator.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;U.S. box-office sales for Pixar, which Disney bought for
$8.06 billion, peaked in 2003 with ``Finding Nemo,'' which was
produced for $94 million and took in $340 million, according to
Internet Movie Database. ``Ratatouille'' cost $150 million,
while ``Wall-E'' cost $120 million, IMDB said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``The jury is still out'' on the Pixar purchase, said Tuna Amobi, an analyst at Standard  Poor's in New York who
recommends Disney shares and doesn't own them. ``It was a hefty
price, no doubt about it. Disney is looking at it as a marathon,
not a sprint.'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Fewer Films &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since buying Pixar, Disney has cut film production overall,
betting it could boost profit by making fewer, more popular
movies. Last year, filmed entertainment generated profit of $1.2
billion, a sixfold increase over two years, on slightly lower
sales of $7.49 billion. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company produced 13 films last year, down from 17 in
2005, and will release 11 in 2008. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year is proving tougher. Through the first half of
fiscal 2008, studio profit rose 6.5 percent to $891 million,
while sales gained 6.7 percent to $4.46 billion. For the year
ending in September, the unit's profit is likely to fall 1
percent to $1.19 billion, as sales dip 1.8 percent to $7.36
billion, according to Michael Nathanson, an analyst with Sanford
C. Bernstein  Co. in New York. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Robert Iger, Disney's chief executive officer, said last
month at an investor conference that Hollywood makes too many
movies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;``It shouldn't surprise anybody in the business why there
is so much failure and why the returns on investment are so
modest,'' Iger said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following table ranks Pixar movies by their worldwide
box-office sales. Figures are in millions of dollars. &lt;/p&gt;

Movie          Year      Budget      U.S.        Worldwide
                                    Total         Total
Finding Nemo   2003       $94       $340          $865
Incredibles    2004        92        261           631
Ratatouille    2007       150        206           621
Monsters Inc.  2001       115        256           525
Toy Story 2    1999        90        246           485
Cars           2006       120        244           462
Bug's Life     1998        45        163           363
Toy Story      1995        30        192           362

Sources: Internet Movie Database Inc., Box Office Mojo LLC

&lt;p&gt;To contact the reporter on this story:
Andy Fixmer in Los Angeles at 
afixmer@bloomberg.net &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To contact the editor responsible for this story:
Jennifer Sondag at 
jsondag@bloomberg.net. &lt;/p&gt;
</body></entry></news>