
<news><entry author="By Aaron Clark and Michael Patterson" date="Jan 23, 2008  6:56 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-01-23/financial-stocks-jpmorgan-bank-of-america-rally-update3-.html"><headline>Financial Stocks, JPMorgan, Bank of America Rally</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Financial stocks staged their biggest
rally since 2002 on speculation the Federal Reserve''s largest
interest rate cut in 23 years will bolster earnings at banks,
brokerages and insurers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bank of America Corp. and JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the biggest
U.S. lenders by market value, rallied after Bear Stearns Cos.
advised buying shares of large banks. Ambac Financial Group Inc. (ABKFQ)
climbed the most in the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index after New
York State''s insurance regulators met with banks to discuss
raising new capital for bond insurers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Financial companies posted the biggest gains among 10
industries in the SP 500 as the benchmark for U.S. equities
rallied for the first time in six days. The SP 500 Financials
Index rose 6.8 percent, bringing its two-day advance to 9.2
percent since the Fed cut its target rate for overnight loans by
0.75 percentage point, its first emergency reduction since 2001. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eighty-seven of 92 companies in the SP 500 financial index
increased. The gauge remains 27 percent below its record high on
Feb. 20. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fed move ''''is a good sign and that''s giving some
investors courage to tiptoe back in,'''' said Keith Wirtz, who
oversees about $22 billion as chief investment officer of Fifth
Third Asset Management in Cincinnati. ''''The group is so out of
favor, it''s almost like a spring that''s been coiled tightly. When
a rotation starts to occur, that coil will relax and you''ll see
these stocks up substantially.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Bear Stearns Upgrade &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JPMorgan climbed $4.86, or 12 percent, to $45.72, its
biggest rally since July 2002. The stock is 14 percent below its
2007 high of $53.20. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bank of America added $3.18, or 8.5 percent, to $40.57, its
largest gain in eight years. The company said it plans to raise
$6 billion by selling preferred shares. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bear Stearns analyst David Hilder upgraded banks to ''''market
overweight'''' from ''''market underweight,'''' saying that lenders
have historically outperformed during ''''aggressive'''' Fed easing
cycles. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''In looking back at bank stock relative performance in the
1990 recession, it is clear that the trigger for bank-stock
outperformance was the beginning of more aggressive Fed easing,''''
Hilder wrote in a note to investors today. ''''We believe
additional downside in bank stocks is limited.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hilder''s top picks were JPMorgan and Bank of New York Mellon
Corp. He said the companies would benefit from lower exposure to
bad real estate loans than their rivals. Bank of New York, the
world''s largest custodian of financial assets, rose $1.18 to
$46.23. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Profit Outlook &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Financial company profits may rise 28 percent this year, the
average estimate of analysts in a survey by Bloomberg. The
group''s earnings probably fell 26 percent in 2007, according to
data compiled by Bloomberg. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ambac, which was stripped of its top AAA grade by Fitch
Ratings this month, gained $5.73, or 72 percent, to $13.70. Talks
in New York with the unnamed banks are part of Insurance
Superintendent Eric Dinallo''s effort to stabilize the bond
guarantors and bolster the market''s financial condition, said
agency spokesman Andrew Mais in an interview. MBIA Inc., the
biggest bond insurer, added $4.08 to $16.61. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Financial stocks in the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index slid 21
percent last year for their biggest decline since 1990. The index
trades for 11.5 times estimated profit over the next 12 months,
compared with 13.6 times historical profits at this time last
year. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday''s reduction by the Fed was the biggest since
October 1984, when the central bank lowered rates by 1.75
percentage point. The Fed began using target overnight lending
rate as the principal tool of monetary policy around 1990. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Laurence Frost" date="Jan 30, 2008 12:38 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-01-30/european-carmakers-decline-on-goldman-estimate-cuts-update2-.html"><headline>European Carmakers Decline on Goldman Estimate Cuts</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Volkswagen AG, Europe''s largest
automaker, and Renault SA (RNO) declined after Goldman Sachs trimmed
2008 earnings estimates for the continent''s car manufacturers by
an average of 25 percent on concern that sales will slow. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Volkswagen dropped 1.8 percent in German trading and Renault
plunged 6 percent in Paris after the investment bank also cut
recommendations on their shares. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''We now assume no growth in global automotive car sales in
2008,'''' analysts led by London-based Stefan Burgstaller said in a
note to investors. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Automotive stocks have suffered in a broad selloff sparked by
fears of a U.S. recession and slowing global growth. The Dow Jones
Stoxx index of European carmakers and parts suppliers has fallen
29 percent from an Oct. 29 high, outpacing a 17 percent decline by
the broader Stoxx 600 index. A tightening of credit and a gloomier
macroeconomic picture ''''have raised concerns over the outlook for
global car sales,'''' the Goldman analysts said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bank cut full-year earnings estimates for France''s PSA
Peugeot Citroen (UG) and smaller domestic rival Renault by 37 percent
each, the biggest reductions. The investment bank reduced its
recommendation on Renault shares to ''''neutral'''' from ''''buy'''' and
kept a ''''sell'''' rating on Peugeot, ''''the most challenged carmaker
in our coverage universe.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Renault Goals Questioned &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Renault''s net income may fall 16 percent this year, Goldman
said, ''''implying that CEO Carlos Ghosn will miss the 2008
milestone margin target'''' of 4.5 percent and fail to deliver the
3.33 million vehicle sales pledged for next year. Renault shares
dropped to 75.14 euros, extending their decline this year to
23 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bank reduced its recommendation on Wolfsburg, Germany-based VW to ''''neutral'''' from ''''buy,'''' saying the shares ''''offer
only a modest upside potential'''' after recent gains. The stock,
which has advanced 79 percent in the past 12 months, declined to
153.62 euros in Frankfurt. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman kept Bayerische Motoren Werke AG (BMW) on a ''''conviction
buy'''' list even as the bank trimmed estimated earnings, based on
net operating profit after tax, by 18 percent. Munich-based BMW
may get a boost when managers meet European and U.S. investors
next week, the analysts said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tiremakers &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bank downgraded Michelin  Cie., the world''s second-largest tiremaker, to ''''sell'''' from ''''neutral,'''' cutting its six-month price estimate to 57 euros from 87 euros on less demand from
carmakers and an increase in raw materials costs. Continental AG,
the No. 4 tiremaker previously unrated by Goldman, was added to
the ''''conviction sell'''' list. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Michelin shares fell 2.69 euros, or 3.9 percent, to 66.43
euros in Paris. Continental lost 4.2 percent in Frankfurt. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Burgstaller, along with analysts Shane McKenna and Tim Rothery, pared Fiat SpA''s (F) six-month price estimate to 19 euros
from 26 euros even as they recommended buying the Turin, Italy-based company''s shares. ''''We continue to view Fiat as the most
attractive fundamental equity story'''' among European carmakers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''While we see risk in the short term of a further 15 percent
to 20 percent decline in European automotive equities, we see
substantial value upside in the long term,'''' the analysts wrote. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Tracy Alloway and Laurence Frost" date="Jan 30, 2008  4:48 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-01-30/european-carmaker-earnings-estimates-cut-by-goldman-update1-.html"><headline>European Carmaker Earnings Estimates Cut by Goldman</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;European carmakers including Renault
SA (RNO), Bayerische Motoren Werke AG (BMW) and Fiat SpA (F) had earnings
estimates cut by an average of 25 percent at Goldman Sachs on
concern that sales will slow. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''We now assume no growth in global automotive car sales
in 2008,'''' analysts Stefan Burgstaller, Shane McKenna and Tim Rothery wrote in a note to investors. ''''The ongoing liquidity
crisis in financial markets and market concerns over the
macroeconomic outlook have raised concerns over the outlook
for global car sales.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The London-based analysts cut full-year estimates of net
operating profit after tax for French carmakers PSA Peugeot
Citroen (UG) and Renault by 37 percent each, the biggest reductions.
The investment bank reduced Renault''s rating to ''''neutral'''' from
''''buy'''' and maintained a ''''sell'''' recommendation on Peugeot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peugeot, Europe''s second-largest carmaker, ''''remains
industrially the most challenged carmaker in our coverage
universe,'''' Goldman said. Renault''s net income may fall 16 percent
in 2008, ''''implying that CEO Carlos Ghosn will miss the 2008
milestone margin target'''' of 4.5 percent and fail to deliver the
3.33 million vehicles sales pledged for next year, the bank said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Goldman kept BMW on its ''''conviction buy'''' list even as it
pared estimated operating profit by 18 percent. Munich-based BMW
may get a boost when managers meet European and U.S. investors
next week, the analysts said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Burgstaller''s team trimmed Fiat''s six-month target price to
19 euros from 26 euros and continued to recommend buying the
Turin, Italy-based company''s shares. ''''We continue to view Fiat as
the most attractive fundamental equity story'''' among European
automotive stocks, the group said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''While we see risk in the short term of a further 15 percent
to 20 percent decline in European automotive equities, we see
substantial value upside in the long term,'''' the analysts wrote. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry><entry author="By Ari Levy" date="Feb 01, 2008  4:25 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2008-02-01/google-drops-as-net-misses-microsoft-bids-for-yahoo-update5-.html"><headline>Google Drops as Net Misses, Microsoft Bids for Yahoo</headline><body>
&lt;p&gt;Google Inc. (GOOG), the most popular Web
search engine, fell the most since it went public after fourth-quarter profit missed estimates, signaling investors have soured
on one of the fastest-rising technology stocks of the decade. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google lost $48.40, or 8.6 percent, to $515.90 at 4 p.m.
New York time in Nasdaq Stock Market trading, the biggest drop
since its August 2004 initial public offering. The decline,
which dropped Google from the 20 biggest U.S. companies by
market capitalization, came the same day Microsoft Corp. bid
$44.6 billion for Yahoo! Inc. (YHOO), Google''s closest rival. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sales growth of 52 percent wasn''t enough for some
investors, who had watched Google beat profit estimates in 11 of
the previous 13 quarters. An economic slowdown and a drop in
online traffic may be crimping ad spending. Google also received
less money than expected from ad deals with social-networking
sites such as News Corp.''s MySpace. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''You''ve seen the peak in the pace of growth,'''' said
analyst Clayton Moran of Stanford Group Corp. in Boca Raton,
Florida. ''''They''re probably not going to be able to repeat the
60, 70, 80 percent growth rates that they had in the past.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today''s decline follows the worst month for the stock since
Google''s IPO, the biggest technology offering in the past four
years. The stock reached a record high of $741.79 on Nov. 6. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Lower Targets &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analysts at Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc., Goldman Sachs
Group Inc., Citigroup Inc. and Bear Stearns Cos. cut their price
targets for the shares after yesterday''s report. Jefferies  Co.
dropped its rating to ''''hold'''' from ''''buy.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fourth-quarter net income rose 17 percent to $1.21 billion,
or $3.79 a share, from $1.03 billion, or $3.29 a share, a year
earlier, Google said after the market closed yesterday. That
fell short of the $3.91 average analyst estimate in a Bloomberg
survey. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sales, excluding revenue passed on to partner sites,
climbed 52 percent to $3.39 billion. Analysts in the Bloomberg
survey predicted $3.45 billion. Excluding stock-based
compensation costs, profit was $4.43 a share, missing the $4.45
estimate of analysts. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google shares closed at their biggest discount ever to
their 200-day moving average. Since its record high on Nov. 6,
the stock is now down 30 percent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Yahoo Deal &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In bidding for Yahoo, Microsoft Chief Executive Officer
Steve Ballmer is attempting the biggest-ever technology takeover
after failing to compete with Google in the market for Internet
search services and advertising, which may almost double to $80
billion by 2010. Google has grown faster than Redmond,
Washington-based Microsoft in every quarter since the 2004 IPO
as its search engine won more users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''A combination of Yahoo and Microsoft will have lots of
money to spend in the battle with Google,'''' said Jack Neele, who
helps manage $194 billion, including Yahoo shares, at Robeco NV
in Rotterdam. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2006, Google forged an agreement with MySpace to provide
online-search and advertising features on the site, the most
visited social-networking service. The deal includes a
guaranteed payment of $900 million over three years from Google
to News Corp. (NWSA) &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''I don''t think we have the killer best way to advertise
and monetize social networks yet,'''' Google co-founder Sergey Brin said yesterday on a conference call with analysts. ''''Some
of the things we were working on in Q4 didn''t pan out, and there
were some disappointments there.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft `Pounced'' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft saw an opening in that admission, said analyst
Brian Bolan of Jackson Securities LLC in Chicago. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''Microsoft sees the Google challenge in this space as a
weakness and has pounced,'''' he wrote in a note to investors.
''''They believe the recent weakness in Google makes this the best
time to get the deal done.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rising energy costs and a housing slump pushed down
consumer confidence to almost a two-year low in January,
according to the Conference Board. Google investors are
concerned that customers may respond by cutting their ad
budgets. The number of U.S. Internet queries dropped 3.9 percent
in December, according to research firm ComScore Inc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;''''There is no evidence to date of an economic slowdown,''''
Google Chief Executive Officer Eric Schmidt said in an interview
yesterday. ''''If there were, we would be pretty well
positioned.'''' &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Market Share &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company''s share of the U.S. Internet search market rose
to 56.3 percent in December from 50.8 percent at the end of
2006, while Sunnyvale, California-based Yahoo''s share fell,
according to Nielsen Online. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google accounted for 75 percent of U.S. search advertising
in 2007, up from 60 percent in 2006, according to New York-based
research firm EMarketer Inc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company also is seeking to bring advertisers to its
YouTube video site. Google began letting marketers buy ads in
YouTube clips last year. Last month, YouTube opened up its
complete library of homemade clips and television shows to
mobile-phone users. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;YouTube is seeing ''''strong user growth,'''' Brin said on the
call. The site is now available in 17 languages. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google also started selling ads on Web sites designed for
mobile phones. In 10 to 20 years, most Internet searches will be
on mobile devices, Schmidt said. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;</body></entry></news>