
<news><entry author="By Naomi Kresge and Makiko Kitamura" date="Sep 03, 2012  7:02 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-03/pfizer-boehringer-s-drug-helped-to-delay-asthma-attacks.html"><headline>Pfizer, Boehringer''s Drug Helped to Delay Asthma Attacks</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A lung drug from Boehringer
Ingelheim GmbH and Pfizer Inc. (PFE) helped delay severe episodes in
asthma patients, researchers said today in two studies that may
result in broader use of the medicine. </p>
<p>Spiriva, known chemically as tiotropium and delivered by
the Respimat Soft Mist inhaler, cut the risk of a severe flare-
up by 21 percent when given in addition to standard treatments,
according to a company-sponsored study presented today at the
European Respiratory Society''s meeting in Vienna. The research
was published simultaneously in the New England Journal of
Medicine. </p>
<p>A standard treatment for chronic obstructive pulmonary
disease, or COPD, Spiriva has been on the market for a decade
and had 3.15 billion euros ($3.96 billion) in sales last year.
Today''s results were a valuable but intermediate step toward
using drugs like Spiriva safely in asthma patients, Elisabeth
Bel, a pulmonologist at the Academic Medical Center in
Amsterdam, wrote in an editorial published alongside the trial
results today in the NEJM. </p>
<p>A word of caution seems appropriate, Bel wrote, adding
that the medicine may be risky for patients with a history of
heart problems. </p>
<h2>Asthma Potential </h2>
<p>Treating asthma may boost sales significantly for drugs
like Spiriva, including those from GlaxoSmithKline Plc (GSK) and
Novartis AG (NOVN), Sam Fazeli, a London-based analyst for Bloomberg
Industries, wrote in a May report. </p>
<p>Safety over longer time periods is the key question,
Fazeli wrote. </p>
<p>A review of five studies published last year in the British
Medical Journal found the use of Spiriva in mist form was
associated with a 52 percent increase in mortality risk.
Boehringer has said data from those trials is already
appropriately reflected in Spiriva''s label. </p>
<p>No patients died during the trials published today, and
adverse events were similar in patients who got the drug and
those who didn''t, the investigators wrote. The two identical
studies excluded people with unstable heart disease. They
divided a total of 912 patients into groups that got inhaled
steroid hormones and long-acting beta-agonists and groups that
took tiotropium alongside the other two types of drugs. </p>
<h2>Already Prescribing </h2>
<p>I''m already prescribing tiotropium as an add-on therapy
to my patients, said Richard Russell, one of the study''s U.K.-
based investigators and consultant chest physician at Wexham
Park Hospital. Still, if people have a history of cardiac
disease and cardiac arrhythmia, I do not give them Spiriva using
a Respimat device. </p>
<p>The results are important because tiotropium helped people
who were already getting drugs in high doses, and still had
flare-ups, said Huib Kerstjens, a professor at the University of
Groningen in the Netherlands and one of the study''s authors. </p>
<p>And still in this population where we have a problem, we
could reduce these exacerbations, Kerstjens said. That''s
meaningful to patients. </p>
<p>Even before the study, Kerstjens had prescribed tiotropium
off-label for asthma, he told reporters in Vienna today. The
next step is to see if tiotropium works in patients with more
moderate asthma, he said. </p>
<p>Boehringer is conducting a total of 11 final-stage clinical
trials on tiotropium in asthma, Jennifer Haddon, the Ingelheim,
Germany-based company''s respiratory medicine adviser, said in a
telephone interview. Haddon declined to give details on how soon
Boehringer might request regulatory approval to sell tiotropium
in asthma or on its sales potential. </p>
<p>Closely held Boehringer markets Spiriva for COPD patients
together with New York-based Pfizer. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Anna Edney" date="Sep 04, 2012  5:05 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-04/pfizer-wins-approval-for-drug-to-treat-type-of-leukemia.html"><headline>Pfizer Wins Approval for Drug to Treat Type of Leukemia</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE), the world''s largest
drugmaker, won U.S. regulatory approval of its treatment for one
of the four most common types of leukemia. </p>
<p>The Food and Drug Administration cleared the drug, to be
known as Bosulif, for adults with previously treated chronic
myeloid leukemia who also have an abnormality known as the
Philadelphia chromosome, the New York-based company said today
in a statement. There are expected to be about 5,400 new cases
and 610 deaths from the blood cancer this year, according to the
American Cancer Society in Atlanta. </p>
<p>Bosulif will compete with Novartis AG (NOVN)''s Tasigna and
Bristol-Myers Squibb Co. (BMY)''s Sprycel. Pfizer''s treatment is
expected to generate $171 million in sales in 2015, according to
the average estimate of six analysts compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Bosulif is an important new addition to the CML treatment
landscape, Jorge Cortes, a professor of medicine at the
University of Texas MD Anderson Cancer Center, and a lead
investigator of the Pfizer-sponsored study on the drug, said in
the company''s statement. Despite recent advances, an unmet
need remains. </p>
<p>Treatment is improving based on a better understanding of
the molecular basis of the disease, Richard Pazdur,director of
the Office of Hematology and Oncology Products in the FDA''s
Center for Drug Evaluation and Research, said in a statement
from the agency. The FDA designated Bosulif as an orphan drug,
meaning it treats a disease that affects fewer than 200,000
people. Bosulif is chemically known as bosutinib. </p>
<h2>Pfizer''s Drugs </h2>
<p>This is Pfizer''s third oncology drug approved in the past
13 months, preceded by Xalkori for lung cancer and Inlyta for
advanced kidney cancer. </p>
<p>Chronic myeloid leukemia produces an excess of white blood
cells. The disease is one of the four main types of leukemia and
accounts for 15 percent of all leukemia worldwide, according to
Pfizer. </p>
<p>Novartis''s Tasigna generated $716 million in sales last
year and Sprycel by Bristol-Myers, based in New York, made $803
million. </p>
<p>Gleevec, from Basel, Switzerland-based Novartis, is the
most-popular initial treatment for chronic myeloid leukemia with
$4.7 billion in sales last year, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Ariad Pharmaceuticals Inc. (ARIA), based in Cambridge,
Massachusetts, asked the FDA to review its chronic myeloid
leukemia drug ponatinib in July. Ariad said in a July 30
statement that it expects approval in the first quarter of 2013. </p>
<p>Ariad is seeking accelerated approval in patients with
resistant or intolerant chronic myeloid leukemia based on the
second of three phases of trials typically required for approval
on the condition the company proves ponatinib''s benefit in later
studies. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Sep 04, 2012 11:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-04/microsoft-aims-for-vmware-with-debut-of-windows-for-cloud.html"><headline>Microsoft Aims for VMware With Debut of Windows for Cloud</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) released a new
version of Windows for running corporate networks, trying to
take share from VMware Inc. (VMW) and gain ground as companies seek to
cut the cost of managing business programs. </p>
<p>Windows Server 2012 improves features for virtualization,
which allows companies to cut costs by using fewer server
computers in their data centers. More businesses are relying on
virtualization technology amid the shift to so-called cloud
computing, where information is managed and stored remotely,
rather than on local software and hardware. </p>
<p>The new program has already won over customers such as
Equifax Inc. (EFX) and Bank of Montreal, which tried out early
versions of the product, said Satya Nadella, president of
Microsoft''s server and tools division, in an interview. </p>
<p>Microsoft, the world''s largest software maker, wants to
boost sales of Windows Server by getting customers to set up so-
called private clouds, which are accessed from within a
corporate network, rather than the wider Internet. Forrester
Research Inc. forecasts spending on private clouds will top $20
billion in sales next year, allowing companies to get the
benefits of running applications on large pools of servers and
storage machines while keeping programs secure on their own
servers. </p>
<p>They have to go into hand-to-hand combat with strong
competitors, said Al Gillen, an analyst at IDC. VMware is
very, very well established and has a very strong platform. </p>
<p>VMware rolled out its latest offering last month. </p>
<h2>Competitive Offering </h2>
<p>Microsoft doesn''t break out annual sales of Windows Server,
which market research firm IDC estimated at more than $5 billion
in 2011. </p>
<p>Included in Windows Server is a program called a
hypervisor, a piece of software that lets companies run multiple
operating systems on a single server, helping cut costs. Many
customers will stick with their current hypervisor vendor when
setting up private clouds, Gillen said. </p>
<p>That''s a disadvantage for Microsoft, which had 26 percent
of the hypervisor market last year, compared to VMware''s 58
percent, according to IDC. </p>
<p>Part of the issue is that for years Microsoft didn''t have a
competitive hypervisor offering, so even companies using
Microsoft products for things such as e-mail and internal
company websites chose VMware when they wanted to use
virtualization software on fewer servers, Nadella said. </p>
<h2>Good Enough </h2>
<p>Now Microsoft is trying to get those customers back and
attract new ones, Nadella said. One such company is window-maker
Pella Corp., which mostly uses Microsoft programs yet chose
VMware for virtualization software in 2004. The company, which
plans to deploy Windows Server 2012, will save hundreds of
thousands of dollars in the costs of licensing the software
compared with what Pella paid VMware, Nadella said. </p>
<p>The refrain was hey we are good enough,'' Nadella said
about Microsoft''s previous appeal to VMware customers. For the
first time we can claim we are better. </p>
<p>VMware executives said they''ve heard that before. </p>
<p>This is not a new strategy for Microsoft, said former
VMware Chief Executive Officer Paul Maritz, in an interview on
Aug. 27. A former Microsoft executive until 2000, Maritz left
VMware on Sept. 1 to become chief strategist at EMC Corp. (EMC), which
owns 79 percent of VMware. This is the third or fourth time
they''re coming to market saying, Our product is now good
enough.'' </p>
<p>Equifax, which provides credit reports, is using Windows
Server 2012 to handle the data that enables lenders to verify
the employment status of people applying for credit or buying a
home. Next, the company will probably start using Windows Server
hypervisor software for virtualized networks and the company
plans to turn to Microsoft to build its first private cloud,
said Equifax''s Chief Technology Officer Bryan Garcia in an
interview. </p>
<p>This one is really data center quality, Garcia said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Charles Mead" date="Sep 04, 2012  9:45 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-04/general-electric-offering-three-10-year-debt-in-benchmark-sale.html"><headline>General Electric Offering Three-, 10-Year Debt in Benchmark Sale</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>General Electric Co. (GE), the biggest
maker of power-generation equipment with $32 billion of bonds
maturing in the rest of 2012, plans to sell three- and 10-year
notes. </p>
<p>The company intends to issue new 10-year securities and
additional 1.625 percent debentures due in July 2015 through its
GE Capital unit for general corporate purposes, according to a
person familiar with the offering who asked not to be identified
because terms aren''t set. The deal will be of benchmark size,
typically at least $500 million, the person said. </p>
<p>GE''s $1.2 billion of 2015 notes, which priced to yield 125
basis points more than similar-maturity Treasuries when they
were sold on June 27, traded at 102 cents on the dollar last
week to yield 0.94 percent with a 64.7 basis-point spread,
according to Trace, the bond-price reporting system of the
Financial Industry Regulatory Authority. </p>
<p>The bonds may be rated A1 by Moody''s Investors Service, its
fifth-highest level, and AA+ by Standard  Poor''s, that
company''s second-highest grade, the person said. </p>
<p>Bank of America Corp., Barclays Plc, Citigroup Inc. and
Credit Suisse Group AG are managing the Fairfield, Connecticut-
based company''s sale of the 10-year bonds, the person said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bloomberg News" date="Sep 04, 2012  1:50 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-04/goldman-sachs-cuts-chinese-earnings-forecasts-as-economy-slows.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Cuts China Earnings Forecasts as Economy Slows</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. lowered
earnings growth forecasts for China''s companies and Credit
Suisse Group AG cut the nation''s stock index targets as the
economy slows. </p>
<p>Profits for companies in the MSCI China Index (MXCN) may increase
1.8 percent this year and 8.6 percent in 2013, compared with
previous growth estimates of 6 percent and 12.3 percent, Helen Zhu and Timothy Moe, analysts at the U.S. bank, wrote in a
report dated yesterday. Credit Suisse lowered its 12-month
target for the index to 60 from 70, analysts Vincent Chan and
Peggy Chan said in a report today. </p>
<p>Third-quarter earnings growth may not yet show a clear
inflection point, Goldman''s Zhu and Moe wrote. We expect
further earnings cuts in the coming months, albeit at a slower
rate, as current revision sentiment is very weak already. </p>
<p>The Shanghai Composite Index (SHCOMP) has retreated 6.8 percent this
year on concern two reductions in borrowing costs and bank
reserve ratios this year will fail to halt a decline in economic
growth. China''s economy grew 7.6 percent in the three months
through June, the slowest pace since 2009, as Europe''s debt
crisis hurt exports and a crackdown on property speculation
damped domestic demand. </p>
<p>Manufacturing shrank for the first time in nine months in
August as new orders contracted and output rose at a slower
pace, according to the Purchasing Managers'' Index released by
the statistics bureau on Sept. 1. </p>
<h2>Growth Target </h2>
<p>Earnings per share for companies in the MSCI China Index of
mainly Hong Kong-listed Chinese companies rose 2 percent in the
first six months of 2012, slowing from 28 percent growth in the
same period a year earlier, according to the Goldman Sach
report. China''s economy may risk missing the government''s 2012
growth target of 7.5 percent, according to Lu Ting, head of
Greater China economics at Bank of America Corp. </p>
<p>The MSCI China lost 0.4 percent to 52.65 as of 1:49 p.m. in
Hong Kong, taking its drop this year to 0.7 percent. The
Shanghai Composite Index dropped 0.5 percent to 2,049.86. </p>
<p>The Hang Seng China Enterprises Index, which tracks so-
called H shares traded in Hong Kong, has slumped 7 percent this
year. It fell 0.5 percent to 9,238.53. The Credit Suisse
analysts lowered their target for the Hang Seng gauge to 12,000
from 13,000, based on an assumption of flat earnings growth
in the next three years. </p>
<h2>Lower Valuations </h2>
<p>For stocks to rise, we will need either a stabilized
global economy or the Chinese government''s macro policy
addressing stimulus or structural reform, the analysts said.
They downgraded China''s banking stocks to market weight from
overweight. </p>
<p>The Shanghai Composite trades at 9.3 times estimated
profit, near the lowest level since January, while the Hang Seng
China Enterprises Index (HSCEI) is valued at 7.7 times, 41 percent lower
than its seven-year average, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. The Hang Seng gauge trades for 1.25 times book value,
compared with its seven-year average of 2.28. </p>
<p>Stocks may rebound in the next three-to-six months on
valuations, according to Credit Suisse''s analysts. Current
earnings forecasts have already factored in weak economic
conditions, Minggao Shen and Ben Wei, analysts at Citigroup
Inc., wrote in a report dated yesterday. </p>
<p>Further policy easing looks inevitable after weak August
data, cost pressure will be lessened and restocking before year-
end is possible, all contributing to a better earnings
outlook, Shen and Wei said. </p>
<p>--Zhang Shidong. With assistance from Jan Dahinten and Weiyi
Lim in Singapore. Editors: Darren Boey, Richard Frost </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Sep 05, 2012  4:26 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-05/morgan-stanley-s-fleming-visits-brokers-amid-technology-flaws.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley''s Fleming Visits Brokers Amid Technology Flaws</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) Smith Barney
President Greg Fleming, seeking to avert broker defections, met
with financial advisers in the U.S. to discuss disruptions
caused by a new technology and operations system. </p>
<p>Fleming assured employees that the brokerage, a joint
venture with Citigroup Inc. (C), is working to make improvements,
said Jim Wiggins, a spokesman for New York-based Morgan Stanley.
Fleming, 49, traveled to Atlanta, Boston, Houston, Los Angeles,
Miami, New York and San Francisco to meet with the advisers,
according to Wiggins. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley finished integrating its brokerage unit with
Smith Barney in July, an effort that included developing a
technology system for all financial advisers. Some brokers
complained of a more cumbersome process to enroll new clients
and less automation with some distributions, Wiggins said. </p>
<p>There has been no mass defection threatened, we have not
seen any spike in attrition by financial advisers, and we
haven''t seen an impact on the business, Wiggins said.
Wherever we can make changes to cut through some of the
problems that exist and make improvements, we''re doing it. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley, which owns 51 percent of the brokerage, is
in the process of buying an additional 14 percent from
Citigroup. Perella Weinberg Partners LP will set the price of
the purchase by Sept. 10 as the two banks failed to agree on a
value for the venture. </p>
<h2>Arbitration Cases </h2>
<p>Erwin Shustak, a lawyer who represents brokers in employee-
dispute cases, said he received about six inquiries in the past
two weeks from Morgan Stanley Smith Barney advisers related to
the integration. Brokers who choose to stay with the company
still could bring arbitration cases against the firm for damages
suffered because of the disruptions, he said. </p>
<p>Wiggins said Morgan Stanley hasn''t faced arbitration cases
over the technology changes. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley brought some advisers onto the new system
last year and transitioned Smith Barney brokers in three waves
from February through about mid-year, Chief Financial Officer
Ruth Porat said in July. Those three waves involved transferring
2 billion documents and 47 million client positions, she said. </p>
<p>Given the low attrition while going through platform
integration, we do view that as a real positive, because human
nature is people don''t like change, Porat said. </p>
<p>Fox Business Network reported Fleming''s meetings earlier
today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Zachary R. Mider" date="Sep 05, 2012 11:17 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-05/goldman-sachs-energy-banker-batchelder-joins-rbc-in-new-york.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Energy Banker Batchelder Joins RBC in N.Y.</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)''s Eric Batchelder, a managing director who advised energy and power
companies, left to join Royal Bank of Canada (RY)''s investment-
banking unit. </p>
<p>Batchelder joined RBC Capital Markets LLC as a managing
director last week, spokeswoman Elisa Barsotti said. He will
focus on investment banking for master limited partnerships,
companies that mainly manage oil and gas pipelines. </p>
<p>Batchelder had worked at New York-based Goldman Sachs since
at least 2002, according to the Finra website. He was promoted
to managing director, the company''s second-highest rank behind
partner, in 2011. The records show he remains based in New York. </p>
<p>Batchelder helped advise Louis Dreyfus Highbridge Energy
LLC last year on the $1.9 billion sale of a collection of plants
and pipelines in Texas and Louisiana to partnerships controlled
by Energy Transfer Equity LP. (ETE) </p>
<p>Batchelder also advised on fundraising efforts for Longview
Power LLC, which built a $2 billion coal-fired power plant in
West Virginia. </p>
<p>Sparkspread.com reported earlier this year that Batchelder
was leaving Goldman Sachs. </p>
<p>Doug McGregor, co-head of RBC Capital Markets, said in an
interview in December that the unit was slowing its expansion
after more than doubling headcount during the previous five
years. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jonathan D. Salant and Roxana Tiron" date="Sep 05, 2012  4:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-05/goldman-sachs-joins-boeing-in-nixing-convention-donations.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Joins Boeing in Nixing Convention Donations</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group (GS), Lockheed Martin
Corp. (LMT) and Boeing Co. (BA) gave a total of $1.3 million to the host
committees funding the Democratic and Republican conventions
four years ago. This time, they aren''t on either party''s donor
lists. </p>
<p>They''re among the companies that are opting out of funding
the party''s quadrennial presidential nominating sessions at
which thousands of delegates and elected officials are inundated
with products and pitches by corporations seeking to elevate
their political profiles. </p>
<p>With extra scrutiny of the mingling of delegates and
special interests, some companies may have decided they didn''t
want the attention, said Sheila Krumholz, executive director of
the Center for Responsive Politics, a Washington-based research
group that tracks campaign contributions. </p>
<p>For the corporations to transfer funds from their general
treasuries to the conventions may be of less value than in
past years, Krumholz said. There''s too much of a
spotlight. </p>
<p>Some companies are back in the convention business,
including ATT Inc. (T) and Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), according to lists of
donors released by both host committees. </p>
<p>New York-based Goldman Sachs contributed $250,000 to the
Denver host committee for the 2008 Democratic convention and
$255,000 to the Minneapolis-St. Paul committee for the
Republican gathering, according to the Campaign Finance
Institute, a Washington-based research group that studies
convention giving. </p>
<h2>Goldman Giving </h2>
<p>While Goldman employees are the largest company source of
campaign contributions to Republican presidential nominee Mitt Romney''s campaign and were the biggest for President Barack Obama four years earlier, the company is sitting out the
conventions this time. </p>
<p>We are operating in a constrained spending environment,
so we''ve had to cut back in a number of areas, said David Wells, a spokesman. </p>
<p>Lockheed Martin, the world''s largest defense contractor,
and Chicago-based Boeing, the world''s largest aerospace company,
also have decided not to give to either convention host
committee. </p>
<p>Their decisions come just months before $1.2 trillion in
automatic spending cuts over a decade -- half of which would
affect the Defense Department -- are scheduled to kick in. </p>
<h2>Defense Cuts </h2>
<p>The reductions are required by the 2011 agreement to raise
the U.S. debt limit. The cuts, also known as sequester, were
designed to force Congress to find alternative deficit-reduction
proposals. Lawmakers, so far, haven''t agreed on such a plan.
Both Obama and Republican vice-presidential nominee Paul Ryan, a
Wisconsin congressman, backed the debt-limit agreement. </p>
<p>The Bethesda, Maryland-based Lockheed Martin gave $200,000
in Denver and $150,000 in Minneapolis-St. Paul to help finance
the partisan festivities. This year, company officials simply
attended the conventions. </p>
<p>We take a bipartisan approach in participating in the
political process and engaging with federal, state and local
political leaders committed to national security, homeland
security, education and technology issues, said Jennifer Whitlow, a spokeswoman. </p>
<p>Boeing also decided not to contribute to the host
committees this year, according to a spokesman, Tim Neale, after
giving $225,000 to the Democratic host committee and $200,000 to
the Republican committee in 2008. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Cliff Edwards" date="Sep 06, 2012  6:13 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-06/microsoft-says-u-s-stores-sold-193-000-xbox-players-in-august.html"><headline>Microsoft Says U.S. Stores Sold 193,000 Xbox Players in August</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) said U.S. retailers
sold 193,000 Xbox video-game consoles last month, citing data
from market researcher NPD Group Inc. </p>
<p>The sales represented 48 percent market share for current
generation consoles, Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft said
today in an e-mailed statement. Stores sold 308,000 Xbox players
in the same month a year ago, according to NPD data at the time. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bob Van Voris" date="Sep 06, 2012 11:10 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-06/goldman-sachs-securities-class-action-revived-by-appeals-court.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Securities Class Action Revived on Appeal</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A class-action suit against Goldman
Sachs Group Inc. (GS) over mortgage-backed securities was revived by
a federal appeals court in New York. </p>
<p>Investors in 17 securities offerings, led by the NECA-IBEW
Health and Welfare Fund, sued Goldman Sachs over securities
backed by pools of residential mortgages originated by National
City Mortgage Co., Countrywide Home Loans, Washington Mutual
Bank and others, according to an opinion by the court today. </p>
<p>U.S. District Judge Miriam Goldman Cedarbaum dismissed the
suit in 2010, ruling that NECA, which purchased certificates
from only two of the offerings, lacked standing to represent
investors in the other 15. A three-judge panel of the appeals
court reversed that ruling today. The court also reversed
Cedarbaum''s ruling that NECA failed to claim a sufficient loss
from the investments. </p>
<p>We hold that plaintiff has class standing to assert the
claims of purchasers of certificates backed by mortgages
originated by the same lenders that originated the mortgages
backing plaintiff''s certificates, because such claims implicate
the same set of concerns'' as plaintiff''s claims, U.S. Circuit
Judge Barrington Parker said in the opinion. </p>
<p>Michael DuVally, a spokesman for New York-based Goldman
Sachs, declined to comment immediately on today''s ruling. </p>
<p>The case is NECA-IBEW Health and Welfare Fund v. Goldman
Sachs  Co., 11-2762, U.S. Court of Appeals for the Second
Circuit (Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ercan Ersoy" date="Sep 06, 2012  3:08 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-06/exxon-seeks-turkish-shale-gas-exploration-license-hurriyet-says.html"><headline>Exxon Seeks Turkish Shale-Gas Exploration License, Hurriyet Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) is in talks with
Turkiye Petrolleri AO, Turkey''s state oil and gas company, known
as TPAO, to explore for shale gas in southeast Turkey, Hurriyet
reported, citing unidentified Energy Ministry officials. </p>
<p>The area for which Exxon seeks a license is adjacent to the
Saribugday-1 field in Diyarbakir province, where Royal Dutch
Shell Plc (RDSA) and TPAO started exploring last week, the newspaper
said. </p>
<p>There may be 13 trillion cubic meters of shale-gas
reserves, 1.8 trillion of which are recoverable, Ismail
Bahtiyar, chairman of the Turkish Association of Petroleum
Geologists, said April 20. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David McLaughlin" date="Sep 07, 2012  1:18 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-07/goldman-sachs-sued-by-dz-bank-in-new-york-over-mortgage-bonds.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Sued by DZ Bank Over Mortgage Securities</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) was sued by
German lender DZ Bank AG over $188.6 million in mortgage-backed
securities, at least the third investor this week to sue the
bank over mortgage bonds. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs made material misrepresentations about loans
that were bundled into the securities, DZ Bank said in a filing
today in New York State Supreme Court. The claims include fraud
and negligent misrepresentation, the lender said. </p>
<p>Two other German lenders -- IKB Deutsche Industriebank AG (IKB)
and Bayerische Landesbank -- are suing New York-based Goldman
Sachs over losses on mortgage bonds, according to filings this
week in state supreme court. </p>
<p>Michael DuVally, a spokesman for Goldman Sachs, declined to
comment. </p>
<p>The case is Deutsche Zentral-Genossenschaftsbank AG v.
Goldman Sachs Group Inc., 653134-2012, New York State Supreme
Court, New York County (Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lananh Nguyen and Rupert Rowling" date="Sep 07, 2012 10:41 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-07/morgan-stanley-gasoline-traders-said-to-quit-for-mercuria.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Gasoline Traders Said to Quit for Mercuria</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Three of Morgan Stanley''s (MS) gasoline
traders have quit the bank to join Mercuria Energy Trading SA,
according to four people with knowledge of the matter. </p>
<p>Leo Sint Nicolaas, Sebastian Ferraccu and Louis Mitchell
resigned from their posts in London, according to the people,
who declined to be identified because the information hasn''t
been made public. They left this week, one of the people said. </p>
<p>Tom Walton, a spokesman for Morgan Stanley in London,
declined to comment by phone today. Geneva-based Mercuria didn''t
immediately respond to a voicemail message or an e-mail seeking
comment. </p>
<p>Mercuria hired staff for its energy business from other
banks earlier this year, including Roger Jones, former global
head of commodities and Phil Sutterby, a senior natural gas
trader at Barclays Plc. (BARC) Andrew Perkins joined the company from
Morgan Stanley this year to head its new global agriculture team
in Singapore. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s second-quarter net revenue from
commodities and fixed income sales and trading fell 59 percent
to $770 million from $1.9 billion a year earlier, the bank said
in a statement on July 19. The drop reflected the challenging
global market environment with reduced levels of client
activity, it said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Mulholland" date="Sep 07, 2012  7:50 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-07/goldman-sachs-citigroup-lead-cmbs-sales-in-most-deals-since-07.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs, Citigroup Lead CMBS Sales in Most Deals Since ''07</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Banks are marketing $2.25 billion of
U.S. commercial-mortgage bonds as investors gird for the largest
wave of new deals since the market''s peak five years ago. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) and Citigroup Inc. (C) are offering
$967 million of securities linked to office buildings, shopping
malls and hotels, according to people familiar with the offering
who asked not to be identified because terms aren''t public. UBS
AG (UBSN) and Barclays Plc are preparing about $1 billion of similar
debt, while Bank of America Corp. (BAC) is offering $280 million of
bonds backed by extended-stay hotel properties. </p>
<p>Lenders are looking to sell as much as $8 billion in
commercial-mortgage backed securities in coming weeks after a
two-month rally, according to Deutsche Bank AG. September
issuance will probably be the biggest monthly volume since sales
revived after coming to a halt amid the 2008 credit seizure,
Deutsche Bank analysts led by Harris Trifon said in a Sept. 5
report. </p>
<p>As long as the deals are of decent credit quality, there
will be enough demand to absorb the new issuance, Credit
Suisse Group AG analysts led by Roger Lehman said in a Sept. 5
report. </p>
<p>Top-ranked bonds tied to commercial-property loans are
yielding 143 basis points more than Treasuries, the lowest
spread since at least January 2008, Barclays data show. That''s
down from a more than three-month high of 210 basis points, or
2.1 percentage points, on June 4. </p>
<p>Lenders have arranged about $20.5 billion in commercial-
mortgage bonds this year, compared with $28 billion in 2011,
Bloomberg data show. Credit Suisse forecasts as much as $45
billion in 2012 issuance. Sales are down from a record $232
billion in 2007. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Sep 09, 2012  6:56 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-09/jpmorgan-weighs-dimon-bonus-cut-wall-street-journal-says-1-.html"><headline>JPMorgan Weighs Dimon Bonus Cut, Wall Street Journal Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the biggest
U.S. bank by assets, is considering cutting 2012 bonuses for
senior managers including Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon,
according to the Wall Street Journal. </p>
<p>The bank''s board of directors is weighing the cuts after
botched bets on derivatives, the newspaper reported today,
citing people close to the discussions whom it didn''t identify.
Joe Evangelisti, a JPMorgan spokesman, declined to comment. </p>
<p>The market value of New York-based JPMorgan has dropped by
$20 billion since Bloomberg News first reported April 5 that the
firm amassed a large and illiquid position in credit derivatives
at its chief investment office in London. The bank lost $5.8
billion on the trades during the first six months of this year
and has said it could lose as much as $7.5 billion total while
closing out the position. </p>
<p>Dimon, who was awarded $23 million in salary and bonuses
for his performance in 2011, said previously it''s up to the
board whether his pay will be reduced when an internal task
force concludes an investigation into the botched trades. </p>
<p>The board, as an independent group, is still guiding this
task force and will come to its own conclusions, Dimon, 56,
said on a July 13 conference call with analysts and investors. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Sep 10, 2012  4:53 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-10/microsoft-may-raise-dividend-by-15-percent-this-month.html"><headline>Microsoft May Raise Dividend by 15 Percent This Month</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) may announce a 15
percent increase to its quarterly dividend later this month,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg, as the world''s largest
software maker faces a growing cash position. </p>
<p>The company''s board typically holds its annual meeting to
set the dividend in September and has boosted the payout in each
of the previous two years, including a 25 percent increase last
year. Analysts estimate the software maker will raise the
dividend by three cents to 23 cents a share. </p>
<p>Microsoft''s cash and short-term investments as of June 30
surged to more than $63 billion, from $52.8 billion a year
earlier, just before the last dividend increase. While another
boost would benefit investors, the company''s ability to increase
the payout is constrained because most of its cash is held
overseas and would be taxed if it were brought back. </p>
<p>The board is likely to consider factors such as available
onshore cash in making its decision, Heather Bellini, an
analyst at Goldman Sachs Group Inc., said in a research note. </p>
<p>One benchmark the company and the board look to when
determining the dividend increase is the growth in the prior
year''s operating income, wrote Bellini,  who is expecting a 2
cent, or 10 percent, higher dividend. As such, given that
operating income only grew 3 percent in fiscal 2012 versus 12
percent in fiscal 2011, we also would expect the dividend
increase to moderate from the 25 percent increase. </p>
<h2>Smaller Boost </h2>
<p>Peter Wootton, a spokesman for Redmond, Washington-based
Microsoft, declined to comment. The company has increased the
dividend regularly since it began payouts in 2003 </p>
<p>About $54 billion of Microsoft''s cash and equivalents was
held overseas and would be subject to material repatriation
tax effects if the company were to shift it back to the U.S.
for uses such as the dividend, the software maker said in a July
filing with the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission. </p>
<p>A smaller increase could disappoint some investors since
Microsoft options have a 3-cent dividend priced in to them,
Bellini said, citing calculations by Goldman''s options
strategists. Currently Microsoft has a dividend yield of 2.6
percent, less than more than half of the companies in the Dow
Jones Industrial Average. Still its yield is larger than many of
its technology rivals such as Oracle Corp. (ORCL) and International
Business Machines Corp. (IBM) </p>
<p>Bellini also said she doesn''t expect a significant number
of shares to be repurchased in the current fiscal year.
Microsoft has about $8.2 billion remaining in the last share
buyback program approved by the board, she said. </p>
<p>Bloomberg dividend forecasts look at seven criteria,
including dividend history and public estimates. </p>
<p>Microsoft''s shares have increased 18 percent this year. The
shares fell less than one percent to $30.74 at the close in New
York. </p>
<p>-- Editors: Reed Stevenson, Lisa Rapaport </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christine Harper and Donal Griffin" date="Sep 10, 2012  3:51 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-10/goldman-sachs-analysts-decide-u-s-bank-slowdown-isn-t-temporary.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Analysts Say Bank Slowdown Isn''t Temporary</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>New bank regulations and capital
requirements are structural changes to the industry that are
more to blame for declining profits than the U.S. economic
slump, Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) analysts said. </p>
<p>The operating environment is unlikely to change any time
soon, and we see shareholders of challenged banks becoming more
demanding in asking management teams to lay out a path to
unlocking value in the near term, analysts led by Richard Ramsden in New York wrote in a report published today. </p>
<p>Their view contrasts with Goldman Sachs Chief Executive
Officer Lloyd C. Blankfein, who said in November, I don''t
think we can conclude that the slowdown is secular rather than
cyclical change. Goldman Sachs, based in New York, is the
fifth-biggest U.S. bank by assets. </p>
<p>More than half of the top 25 U.S. banks aren''t earning
enough to cover their cost of capital, leading to stock prices
that are significantly lagging previous global recoveries,
according to the note. The vast majority of the reduction
relative to pre-crisis levels is attributable to structural
issues like deleveraging and regulatory reform. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley, the sixth-biggest U.S. bank, and similar
firms could improve returns by shrinking businesses like fixed-
income trading and distressed-mortgage investing that require
high levels of capital, according to the note. Using that
capital to buy back shares instead could be meaningfully
accretive to shareholders, the analysts wrote. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
Goldman Sachs has stopped offering two-year contracts to its most junior investment bankers. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Noah Buhayar" date="Sep 10, 2012 12:34 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-10/goldman-sachs-s-kostin-says-fiscal-cliff-may-be-averted.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs''s Kostin Says Fiscal Cliff May Be Averted</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>U.S. tax increases and spending
cuts set for the beginning of next year may be averted by
lawmakers in Washington, Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)''s chief U.S.
equity strategist David Kostin said. </p>
<p>This is unlikely to be resolved in a smooth fashion,
Kostin said today at a conference in San Diego sponsored by the
Insured Retirement Institute. The fiscal cliff will probably
will be resolved in a messy way, he said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christie Smythe" date="Sep 11, 2012  7:16 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-11/visa-mastercard-swipe-deal-faces-retail-group-opposition.html"><headline>Visa, MasterCard Swipe Deal Faces Retail Group Opposition</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The National Retail Federation said
it will try to block a settlement of as much as $7.25 billion
with Visa Inc. (V) and MasterCard Inc. (MA) over the fees they charge
stores when customers pay with credit cards. </p>
<p>The Washington-based group, which represents more than
9,000 retailers, said the proposed settlement of merchants''
price-fixing claims does nothing to prevent Visa and MasterCard
from raising the so-called swipe fees in the future. </p>
<p>Proponents of the deal will be able to file papers formally
seeking a judge''s approval ahead of an Oct. 19 deadline, lawyers
for the plaintiffs said today in federal court in Brooklyn, New
York. </p>
<p>We will try to find the most forceful way we can to let
the court know that this deal is so unfair that it needs to be
rejected at the outset, Mallory Duncan, the group''s general
counsel, said today in a phone interview. </p>
<p>The settlement, which must be approved by a federal judge,
would put to rest about seven years of litigation over
allegations that San Francisco-based Visa and Purchase, New
York-based MasterCard conspired to fix the fees. </p>
<p>At today''s hearing on the status of the settlement, U.S.
Magistrate Judge James Orenstein rejected a request for
information made by a lawyer, Jeffrey Shinder, who is
representing some of the objecting groups, including the
National Cooperative Grocers Association and the National
Association of Convenience Stores. </p>
<h2>Premature'' Request </h2>
<p>Orenstein said Shinder''s request seeking full access to the
court record in the case was premature.. </p>
<p>K. Craig Wildfang, a lawyer for the plaintiffs who is
advocating for the settlement, said after the hearing that he is
absolutely confident the deal will move forward. </p>
<p>This is not really the way class actions get resolved,
he said about NRF''s opposition. We don''t really take a vote. </p>
<p>Trish Wexler, a spokeswoman for the Electronic Payments
Coalition, which favors the settlement, said that the NRF and
other groups have political ulterior motives for opposing
the deal. </p>
<p>U.S. Senator Richard Durbin''s office has told retailers
that they may lose out on legislative opportunities to rein in
credit-card fees if they support the settlement. Durbin, a
Democrat from Illinois, secured the inclusion of limits on swipe
fees for debit cards in the 2010 Dodd-Frank Act, trimming
revenue for the largest U.S. banks by about $8 billion. </p>
<h2>Possible Competition </h2>
<p>Opposition may also be related to recently announced
efforts to establish payment networks that may compete with Visa
and MasterCard, she said. </p>
<p>In a conference call on July 25, Visa Chairman and Chief
Executive Officer Joseph W. Saunders told investors that he
expected a federal judge to grant preliminary approval to the
settlement this year. </p>
<p>Visa executives remain confident that the settlement
will be approved, Chief Financial Officer Byron Pollitt said
today at an investor conference in Las Vegas. </p>
<p>We''re getting a lot of noise, and I think we will
continue to have a lot of noise with regards to the merchants''
side not being happy with the suit or the settlement, Pollitt
said. </p>
<p>The case is In re Payment Card Interchange Fee and Merchant
Discount Antitrust Litigation, 05-md-01720, U.S. District Court,
Eastern District of New York (Brooklyn). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Sep 11, 2012  6:26 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-11/morgan-stanley-says-fixed-income-reduction-to-deepen.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Says Fixed-Income Reduction to Deepen</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley, which announced in
July that it planned to shrink its fixed-income trading business
amid new capital rules, said today that the reduction will be
bigger than previously forecast. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley plans to cut the unit''s risk-weighted assets
under Basel III rules by at least 35 percent from the third
quarter of 2011 through the end of 2014, Chief Financial Officer
Ruth Porat said at an investor conference. Chief Executive
Officer James Gorman said in July that the reduction would be at
least 30 percent, prompting analysts including Goldman Sachs
Group Inc. (GS)''s Richard Ramsden to call for a bigger cut. </p>
<p>Fixed-income and commodities accounted for $320 billion of
the $500 billion risk-weighted assets as of June 30, Porat said,
providing those figures for the first time. Porat said that the
firm could cut RWAs from the fixed-income division to $255
billion by the end of 2014 without drastically reducing revenue
or alienating clients. </p>
<p>We''re very confident there is upside beyond the plan
summarized here while continuing to invest in these businesses
to maintain a vibrant, profitable, and client-focused fixed-
income business, said Porat, 54. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS)''s securitized products business, which
includes mortgage securities, provides an example of how the
firm will shrink the business, Porat said. The group''s quarterly
revenue was 8 percent higher in the first half of 2012 than in
2010 and 2011, while it shrank 42 percent on the bank''s balance
sheet, according to Porat''s presentation. </p>
<p>The firm did this by cutting distressed holdings and
unwinding certain derivatives, Porat said. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley''s interest-rates and foreign-exchange
trading units have generated more than half of fixed-income
revenue over the last six quarters, compared with being smaller
than the contributions from credit, commodities and securitized
products in 2009, Porat said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Malavika Sharma" date="Sep 11, 2012  5:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-11/coca-cola-masala-gets-5-billion-to-catch-pepsi-in-india-retail.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Masala Gets $5 Billion to Catch Pepsi in India: Retail</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Coca-Cola Co. (KO) is spicing up its
struggle with PepsiCo Inc. (PEP) for dominance in India, the company''s
fastest growing major market. </p>
<p>The world''s biggest soft-drinks maker is reviving RimZim, a
masala soda flavored with cumin and other spices shelved
after its 1993 takeover of local rival Parle Group. Coke is
bringing back old brands and expanding distribution networks as 
part of a $5 billion drive in India, where its sales per capita 
are one-seventh the global average. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola has struggled to replicate the global success of
its eponymous cola, which trails Pepsi in India as well as Thums
Up -- another Parle acquisition. Brands appealing to local
tastes and investment in Parle''s old bottling and logistics
systems are crucial to meet Chief Executive Officer Muhtar Kent''s target of doubling worldwide revenue this decade. </p>
<p>To be first to reach out to the entire mass of India is a
virgin opportunity, said Ankur Bisen, associate vice
president, at Technopak Advisors Pvt., a Gurgaon, India-based
firm that advises consumer companies. There are still many
pockets that most of these soft drinks have not gone to. </p>
<p>Dilapidated infrastructure means Coca-Cola is only reaching
about one in five, or 1.7 million, of the potential outlets.
That''s higher than PepsiCo, which says it has 1.2 million and
wants double that in five years. Coke says it aims to be in at
least one in three outlets within three years. </p>
<p>India''s 1.2 billion people on average consume 12 Coca-Cola
beverages a year, compared with a global figure of 92. With
about 350 million people aged under 15 -- more than the combined
populations of Brazil and Mexico -- and the changing lifestyle
that goes with economic growth and urbanization, the potential
for the Indian beverage industry is unlimited, said Arun Kejriwal, a director of advisory firm Kejriwal Research 
Investment Services Pvt. in Mumbai. </p>
<h2>$7.5 Billion </h2>
<p>India''s market for soft drinks is expected to expand to
$7.2 billion in 2015 from $3.1 billion in 2010, according to
Euromonitor International. China''s will rise to $79 billion from
$40.2 billion in the same period, the London-based researcher
estimates. </p>
<p>Markets outside the U.S. are increasingly important as
consumption of fizzy drinks there declines. The volume of
carbonated soft drinks sold in the U.S. fell 1 percent in 2011
to about 9.27 billion cases, the lowest level since 1996,
according to trade publication Beverage Digest. </p>
<p>About 80 percent of operating income at Coca-Cola came from
outside North America last year. PepsiCo got 55 percent of its
pretax income outside the U.S., according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. </p>
<h2>Indian Sales </h2>
<p>Coca-Cola said in July that Indian sales by volume in the
second quarter of this year jumped 20 percent. Its share of the
Indian carbonated-beverage market rose to 60 percent last year,
from 55 percent in 2005, Euromonitor data shows. PepsiCo''s share
declined to 37.2 percent from 41 percent. </p>
<p>Atlanta, Georgia-based Coca-Cola quit India in 1977 after
the government demanded companies reveal ingredients in their
products -- which would have forced Coke to hand over its secret
cola formula. It returned in 1993, four years behind PepsiCo.
Both companies have been dogged by accusations that their drinks
were contaminated with pesticides and their bottling operations
depleted water tables. </p>
<p>PepsiCo hasn''t ceded ground easily. Gautham Mukkavilli, who
heads its India business, estimates sales grew double digits
in 16 of the past 22 quarters. Like its competitor, PepsiCo is
boosting distribution and relaunching brands purchased in the
1994 takeover of 105-year-old Indian soft-drinks maker Duke 
Sons Ltd. for an undisclosed amount. </p>
<p>Pepsi has re-introduced Duke''s Masala Soda brand, and is
testing a spiced lemonade under its 7-Up brand called Nimbooz
Masala Soda, Mukkavilli said. </p>
<h2>National Network </h2>
<p>Still, in Parle, Coca-Cola acquired 54 bottlers and a
national distribution system. Duke was focused on the western
state of Maharashtra, said Harish Bijoor, whose Harish Bijoor
Consults Inc. in Bangalore advises companies on brands. </p>
<p>Coke CEO Kent on a June visit to New Delhi said the company
and its local partners plan to spend $5 billion in India by
2020, part of which will be on new trucks, refrigerators and
bottling plants. </p>
<p>The emphasis will be on Coke''s distribution network, to
make it stronger, and on its advertising and marketing, so that
it can reach more people, said Sananda Mukhopadhyay, an
analyst at Netscribes Inc., a consultancy company. </p>
<p>PepsiCo has spent $1 billion in India over the past four
years and hasn''t announced any new investment. </p>
<h2>Thums Up </h2>
<p>Parle also gave Coca-Cola India''s two favorite drinks at
that time. Sales of Thums Up, a cola with a stronger flavor and
more carbonation than others, grew 15 percent in 2011, the
company said in its annual report, and had a 5.9 percent market
share. Maaza, a mango drink, accounted for 5.5 percent of non-
alcoholic beverage sales after an 11 percent jump last year. </p>
<p>Thums Up finally lost its top spot last year -- to Coca-
Cola''s Sprite, which held a 6.1 percent share of the market.
Leveraging off its bigger distribution network, Sprite outsells
7-Up by more than two-to-one. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola is now preparing to resurrect a lime beverage
acquired with Parle called Citra -- selling it at a price 30
percent below Sprite''s to take on cheaper local brands. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola''s trademark Coke held a 3.2 percent market share
in India, behind Pepsi''s 5.4 percent, according to Euromonitor. </p>
<p>The company''s standard-bearer accounted for 49 percent of
worldwide sales by volume, according to Coca-Cola''s annual
report for 2011. That''s down from 51 percent in 2009. Growing
concerns over obesity and diabetes are also shifting consumers
to juices and less sugary drinks globally. </p>
<h2>Nostalgic Taste </h2>
<p>Six decades after Coca-Cola first branched out into new
beverages with its orange-flavored soda Fanta, the company has
more than 500 brands worldwide, tailored to local tastes,
according to its website. </p>
<p>Rimzim, I loved it! said Nikhil Kumar, 29, New Delhi-
based managing director at The Storytellers Pvt., a public-
relations company. For me and my friends, it will be
nostalgic, it''ll bring back some memories. It''s a really good,
typical Indian drink. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michelle Fay Cortez" date="Sep 11, 2012  4:30 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-11/pfizer-j-j-alzheimer-s-drug-shows-promise-for-early-use.html"><headline>Pfizer-J&amp;amp;J Alzheimer''s Drug Shows Promise for Early Use</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Johnson  Johnson (JNJ) and Pfizer Inc. (PFE)''s
bapineuzumab, an experimental drug that failed to help
Alzheimer''s symptoms in a study, showed signs of reducing
physical damage in the brain, according to a deeper analysis. </p>
<p>The medicine lessened a measure of nerve cell damage in the
brain and the buildup of amyloid plaque, hallmarks of
Alzheimer''s, in people who are genetically predisposed to the
disease, the research found. Test results released last month
showed that bapineuzumab and a similar drug from Eli Lilly 
Co. (LLY), solanezumab, didn''t improve patients'' memory or thinking. </p>
<p>Today''s report at a medical meeting in Sweden renews hope
that medicines designed to attack amyloid may be beneficial when
given before irreparable harm occurs to brain cells, said Reisa
Sperling, a professor of neurology at Harvard Medical School.
U.S.-funded studies testing the theory in high-risk people are
being planned and may take three to five years to complete. </p>
<p>The disease begins 10 to 20 years before there are any
symptoms, and now we are better at detecting some of those
changes, said Steve Salloway, director of Neurology and the
Memory and Aging Program at Butler Hospital and professor of
neurology at Brown University in Providence, Rhode Island.
Drugs like this that lower amyloid will probably have their
greatest impact earlier on. We have to test that. </p>
<p>Pfizer gained less than 1 percent to $24.17 at the close in
New York while JJ also rose less than 1 percent to $68.20.
Pfizer has increased 32 percent in the past 12 months, while JJ
has advanced 7.2 percent. </p>
<h2>Profit Delayed </h2>
<p>Drugs to slow the progression of Alzheimer''s disease could
have created a market worth $20 billion, said Barbara Ryan, an
analyst with Deutsche Bank, in a June note to clients. It will
take years for additional studies to determine if the drugs
prevent disease when given earlier, eating into their patent
lives. A positive result would create an even larger market as
more people take the medicines for longer. </p>
<p>The research led by New Brunswick, New Jersey-based JJ was
presented at the European Federation of Neurological Societies
meeting in Stockholm. Two additional clinical trials conducted
outside the U.S. by New York-based Pfizer were halted last
month. The companies are still studying a version of the drug
that''s given as a shot, rather than intravenously. </p>
<p>The findings are weak and at best suggestive that targeting
amyloid may be beneficial, said Erik Gordon, a professor at the
University of Michigan''s Ross School of Business, in an e-mail.
While the idea that amyloid is a trigger for Alzheimer''s disease
is popular, it hasn''t been proven, he said. </p>
<h2>Slimmest Threads'' </h2>
<p>We are so desperate, given the failures in Alzheimer''s,
that we cling to the slimmest threads, Gordon said. Trials
that are failures but not total failures are considered
successes. </p>
<p>There are about 5.4 million Americans with Alzheimer''s
disease, and the number is expected to surge as the population
ages, according to the Alzheimer''s Association. The only drugs
available currently for the condition temporarily treat its
symptoms, rather than slowing or reversing it the brain-wasting
disease. </p>
<p>One study involved about 1,100 people with mild-to-moderate
Alzheimer''s who had a gene known as ApoE4 that puts them at risk
for the condition and leads to increased amyloid buildup. </p>
<p>Patients getting bapineuzumab had significantly less
amyloid in the brain on advanced imaging tests and lower levels
of phospho-tau in their spinal fluid, a marker of nerve cell
injury, said Sperling, who led one of the studies. </p>
<h2>Brain Fluid </h2>
<p>The drug didn''t appear to slow brain shrinkage, the study
found. About 15 percent of patients getting bapineuzumab
developed a condition marked by fluid leaking into the brain
from blood vessels, compared with 0.2 percent of placebo
patients. Most had no symptoms, and many were able to resume
taking the drug after a break in treatment. Seizures were also
more common in the drug-treated patients. </p>
<p>Six bapineuzumab patients developed cancer and died,
compared with none of those getting a placebo, the study found.
A panel of safety experts reviewed the cancer finding and looked
at the results of other studies as well. No one cancer stood out
and the increased risk ebbed when the data from all the research
was collated, Sperling said. </p>
<p>Bapineuzumab is affecting the brain at the intended target
and may influence the biology of the disease, Sperling said.
Declining levels of phospho-tau, also a chemical sign of
Alzheimer''s progression that is measured in cerebral spinal
fluid, are compelling, she said. </p>
<h2>Earlier Treatment </h2>
<p>We have seen that in people who are already in advanced
stages of Alzheimer''s, it''s very hard to move this disease,
said Maria Carrillo, the Alzheimer''s Association''s director of
medical and scientific relations. The scientific community is
recognizing that the potential we are looking for, a delay in
the disease progression, may come if we go earlier. </p>
<p>Doctors are getting new tools that allow them to peer into
the brain to detect Alzheimer''s disease based on amyloid buildup
that starts years before symptoms. Amyvid from Indianapolis-
based Lilly won U.S. approval earlier this year to help spot the
protein deposits that previously were found only during autopsy.
General Electric Co., based in Fairfield, Connecticut, says it
will file for a similar product by the end of 2012. </p>
<p>The researchers haven''t yet analyzed the data to determine
whether patients with the mildest symptoms, presumably earlier
in the disease process, fared better than those with moderate
levels of dementia, Salloway said. Additional analysis for
biological markers of the disease also is under way, he said. </p>
<h2>Second Study </h2>
<p>The second study, involving 1,331 patients without the
ApoE4 gene, included two different doses of bapineuzumab. The
researchers found no differences in amyloid buildup, phospho-tau
or brain volume, Salloway said. </p>
<p>Patients getting the higher dose had lower phospho-tau
levels and there was a trend in the imaging scans for less
amyloid buildup in the brain, Salloway said in a telephone
interview. The risk of fluid buildup and bleeding in the brain
and seizures rose in conjunction with the drug dose, though
there weren''t more cancer deaths in bapineuzumab patients. </p>
<p>While patients in the study were considered to have mild or
moderate dementia, it''s important to fully understand what that
means, he said. </p>
<p>It''s mild in the degree of dementia, but it''s not mild in
terms of what is happening in the brain, he said. To be
diagnosed with dementia, you have to have significant impairment
and neuronal injury. </p>
<p>The idea that amyloid triggers a cascade of events that
damage the brain is the leading hypothesis for the cause of
Alzheimer''s disease, said Ronald Petersen, a neurologist at the
Mayo Clinic in Rochester, Minnesota. </p>
<p>Now researchers need to determine if stopping the amyloid
earlier will improve the health of patients, he said. </p>
<p>This is encouraging, but the proof is in the pudding down
the road here, he said in an interview. Now we need to
determine if it has a biological effect that leads to
prevention. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore and Donal Griffin" date="Sep 11, 2012  2:19 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-11/morgan-stanley-prevails-as-mssb-valuation-set-at-13-5-billion.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Prevails as MSSB Value Set at $13.5 Billion</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) agreed to buy the
rest of its brokerage joint venture from Citigroup Inc. (C) at a
fixed price that values the entire unit at $13.5 billion -- or
about 40 percent less than Citigroup''s estimate two months ago. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley will pay $1.89 billion for a 14 percent
stake this year and $4.73 billion for the remaining 35 percent
by 2015, New York-based Citigroup said today in a filing. The
lender said it expects to take a $2.9 billion third-quarter
charge, a sum that exceeds the average profit estimate by
analysts in a Bloomberg survey. </p>
<p>The valuation -- closer to Morgan Stanley''s $9 billion
estimate than Citigroup''s $22 billion -- reflects the venture''s
struggle to boost earnings amid a trading slump and global
economic weakness. Still, the price is a steal for New York-
based Morgan Stanley, said David Trone, a JMP Securities LLC
analyst. Both banks'' shares rose as the deal may help avert
future disputes when Citigroup sells its remaining stake. </p>
<p>Establishing certainty regarding the divestiture of this
business is in the best interests of our shareholders,
Citigroup Chief Executive Officer Vikram Pandit, 55, said in a
statement. As we have shown, the more we put the past behind
us, the more we can focus on our future, which is in the core
businesses in Citicorp. </p>
<h2>Shareholders React </h2>
<p>Morgan Stanley climbed 3.2 percent to $17.14 at 1:56 p.m.
in New York. Citigroup advanced 2.6 percent to $32.67. </p>
<p>The two banks in 2009 formed the venture, with the most
financial advisers of any brokerage, and Morgan Stanley paid
$2.75 billion for a 51 percent stake and the right to buy the
rest over time. Morgan Stanley agreed to buy the next 15 percent
piece of the brokerage by June and complete the purchase by June
2015. </p>
<p>Citigroup''s charge on a pretax basis was $4.7 billion,
exceeding the $4.4 billion predicted by Ed Najarian, an analyst
at International Strategy  Investment Group Inc. The lender may
post a $2.72 billion profit for the third quarter, according to
the average estimate of nine analysts surveyed by Bloomberg. The
sale of the 14 percent stake should boost the bank''s Tier 1
common equity ratio under Basel III rules by 0.14 percentage
point, the bank said. </p>
<h2>Casts Doubt </h2>
<p>The pricing victory for Morgan Stanley also casts doubt on
the prospects of one of its most crucial businesses. CEO James Gorman, 54, has said the purchase of the whole brokerage is a
key to his strategy of making the firm less reliant on trading
revenue and improving profitability. </p>
<p>A valuation of $13.5 billion suggests a long-term earnings
growth rate of less than 3 percent, assuming a 10 percent
discount rate, according to Goldman Sachs Group Inc. analysts.
The business, which had 16,934 financial advisers as of June 30,
has struggled to make progress toward Gorman''s goal of a 20
percent pretax profit margin. The unit hasn''t topped 12 percent
since the venture was formed. </p>
<p>The unit has also faced broker complaints about disruptions
caused by a new technology and operations system. Greg Fleming,
who runs the business, met with financial advisers in the U.S.
during the past few weeks to assure them the firm is working to
make improvements. </p>
<p>The agreement allows us to focus completely on bringing
our clients superior service as we continue our work to build
the leading U.S. wealth management platform, Gorman said today
in a memo to employees. </p>
<h2>Remaining Stake </h2>
<p>Morgan Stanley also received control of about $5.5 billion
of deposits for no premium, according to today''s statement. The
investment bank will have about $122 billion in deposits once it
owns the entire venture, which will lower funding costs and
increase flexibility, David Russo, the firm''s treasurer, said
last month. </p>
<p>Citigroup estimated in a July 19 regulatory filing that its
49 percent stake was worth $11 billion and said Morgan Stanley''s
bid was 40 percent of that. Because the banks were more than 10
percent apart, they hired Perella Weinberg Partners LP as an
outside appraiser. The banks said today that they reached an
agreement that allows them to avoid repeating that process when
selling additional stakes. </p>
<p>Under the terms of the original agreement, the gap between
the banks'' estimates was to be divided into thirds. If Perella''s
estimate fell in the middle portion, the transaction price was
to be set at that level. If it were in the upper or lower third,
the final price would be the average of Perella''s estimate and
the closest bank estimate, according to a procedure Morgan
Stanley outlined in a May filing. </p>
<p>The brokerage is largely composed of the Smith Barney and
Dean Witter businesses. Gorman said in June that he will change
the name of the unit to Morgan Stanley Wealth Management. </p>
<p>Fleming, 49, last year laid out a plan to improve the
margin to mid-teens by the middle of 2013. That included
generating more revenue from deposits, lending and transaction
services and increasing the amount of assets in fee-based
accounts, as well as decreasing integration expenses. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christine Harper" date="Sep 12, 2012  3:11 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-12/goldman-sachs-s-keats-joins-kirkland-ellis-as-partner.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs''s Keats Joins Kirkland &amp;amp; Ellis as Partner</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Michael C. Keats, a former managing
director in Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)''s legal department, joined
law firm Kirkland  Ellis LLP as a litigation partner this week. </p>
<p>Keats, 43, was associate general counsel in the litigation
and regulatory proceedings group at Goldman Sachs, which he
joined in 2007, according to a statement on the law firm''s
website. He was previously a securities and global enforcement
partner in O''Melveny  Myers LLP''s New York office. </p>
<p>His experience at Goldman Sachs during a period of
extraordinary change and enforcement activity on Wall Street
will be a tremendous asset to our clients, Jeffrey C. Hammes,
chairman of Kirkland''s global management executive committee,
said in the statement. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs, the most profitable securities firm in Wall
Street history before converting to a bank in 2008, paid $550
million last year to settle a fraud accusation from the
Securities and Exchange Commission and was accused by the U.S.
Senate''s Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations of misleading
clients. The Justice Department said last month that it wouldn''t
pursue criminal charges against New York-based Goldman Sachs
related to information uncovered by the Senate subcommittee. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Sep 12, 2012  2:45 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-12/jpmorgan-names-carlos-hernandez-head-of-investor-services.html"><headline>JPMorgan Names Hernandez, Blythe Masters to New Posts</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the biggest
U.S. bank, named Carlos Hernandez head of investor services and
announced new leadership for the corporate and investment bank
division formed in July. </p>
<p>Hernandez, who had run equities, takes over a business that
combines the New York-based firm''s prime-brokerage, financing
and securities-services units, JPMorgan said today in a memo
obtained by Bloomberg News. Tim Throsby, who led equity
derivatives, will take over as head of equities, according to
the memo, the contents of which were confirmed by Jennifer Zuccarelli, a company spokeswoman. The Wall Street Journal
reported the appointments earlier today. </p>
<p>JPMorgan shook up its top management in July following a
$5.8 billion trading loss in its chief investment office, naming
Daniel Pinto and Mike Cavanagh to lead the corporate and
investment bank. That division combined the investment bank,
corporate bank and treasury and securities-services units. </p>
<p>JPMorgan, which made more revenue from fixed-income trading
than any other bank in the world last year, won''t have heads of
fixed-income, a role previously held by Pinto and Matt Zames,
now co-chief operating officer of the company. Troy Rohrbaugh
will lead the rates, foreign-exchange and public-finance parts
of fixed-income, while Guy America will run credit trading and
Matt Cherwin will head securitized products. </p>
<p>Blythe Masters will continue to run commodities trading,
and also will lead regulatory affairs for the corporate and
investment bank, reporting to Barry Zubrow. James Kenny will
head emerging markets and the special opportunities group. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Frier" date="Sep 12, 2012 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-12/ibm-boosts-social-network-with-feed-for-facebook-twitter.html"><headline>IBM Boosts Social Network With Feed for Facebook, Twitter</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines
Corp. (IBM), the largest computer services provider, has bolstered its
social networking tool for companies by integrating e-mail and
adding a news feed with Twitter Inc. and Facebook Inc. (FB) </p>
<p>The enhanced product, called Connections, enables streaming
from social networks alongside business capabilities, such as
document authorization, reporting expenses and reviewing e-
mails, IBM said in a statement today. The Armonk, New York-based
company is also adding more tools to the mobile version of the
service, including location tracking, said Alistair Rennie,
general manager of social business. </p>
<p>You need to have a platform that is really social,
powered by very deep analytics and ready to integrate business
information into the stream in real time, Rennie said in a
telephone interview. It''s an area we''re fairly serious about
investing in. </p>
<p>IBM is betting the enhanced service, which features
analytical tools, will gain customers in the face of increasing
competition from companies including Salesforce.com Inc. (CRM) and
Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), which in July bought Yammer Inc., a Facebook-
like corporate networking tool. Social network services will
help IBM make $16 billion from business analytics by 2015, the
company has said. </p>
<p>Connections will also integrate tools IBM gained through
acquisitions, tying in capabilities from Kenexa Corp. (KNXA), a maker
of Web-based human-resources and recruiting services, which it
is buying for about $1.3 billion. </p>
<p>IBM''s service, which debuted in 2007, now counts Primerica
Inc. (PRI), the life insurer formerly owned by Citigroup Inc. (C),
Colgate-Palmolive Co. (CL) and Bayer AG among its users. Connections
works for both internal communication and for interacting with
customers, Rennie said. </p>
<p>IBM is opening offices in Manila and Sao Paolo to support
customers in emerging markets using social network tools, the
company also said today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Sep 13, 2012  7:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-13/jpmorgan-erases-stock-drop-fueled-by-london-trading-loss.html"><headline>JPMorgan Erases Stock Drop Fueled by London Trading Loss</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the lender
that plunged as much as 24 percent in the month after disclosing
a multibillion-dollar trading loss, has erased that decline. </p>
<p>The bank''s stock climbed 3.7 percent to $41.40 yesterday in
New York, eclipsing the $40.74 closing price of May 10, when
Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon announced what was then a
trading loss of about $2 billion at the chief investment office
in London. The loss this year now stands at $5.8 billion. </p>
<p>The wrong-way bets on derivatives are the focus of an
escalating investigation by a U.S. Senate panel and at least 11
agencies, including the Justice Department and Securities and
Exchange Commission. The stock remains 6.6 percent below the
April 5 close, when Bloomberg News first reported the lender had
amassed an illiquid position on credit derivatives, and is the
second-worst performer in the 24-company KBW Bank Index. (BKX) </p>
<p>Though the loss was quite large, it was a loss that was
not systemic to their investment-securities portfolio or their
capital-markets operations, said Gerard Cassidy, an analyst at
RBC Capital Markets who rates the shares outperform. The
bigger picture for the company has and continues to improve. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
JPMorgan Chase  Co. bank branch in New York. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christine Harper" date="Sep 13, 2012  5:12 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-13/goldman-sachs-stops-giving-two-year-contracts-to-junior-bankers.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Stops Giving Two-Year Contracts to Junior Bankers</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) has
stopped offering two-year contracts to its most junior
investment bankers, typically new college graduates, ending a
quarter-century practice, a company spokesman said. </p>
<p>Analyst-level recruits at Goldman Sachs''s investment
banking and investment management divisions for 2013 aren''t
receiving the contracts, which typically ended with either a job
offer at the firm or a move to graduate school or another
company, said David Wells, a spokesman in New York. </p>
<p>We will continue to provide the skills and time needed to
understand our hiring and developing the careers of analysts in
our banking and investment management divisions, Wells said.
Making this change allows us to emphasize the longer-term
career opportunities available at the firm. </p>
<p>Two-year contracts will continue to be used for analyst-
level employees in the sales and trading and research divisions,
Wells said. He declined to say how many people are employed in
the analyst programs. The Wall Street Journal reported the
recruitment policy change earlier today. </p>
<p>Wall Street firms have been seeking ways to reduce employee
costs, even at the most junior levels. The practice of providing
junior bankers with automatic annual pay increases came under
review at firms including Credit Suisse Group AG (CSGN) and Goldman
Sachs earlier this year, people familiar with the deliberations
said in January. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
Goldman Sachs has stopped offering two-year contracts to its most junior investment bankers. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Sep 13, 2012  3:58 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-13/morgan-stanley-s-porat-says-bank-roe-drop-is-part-secular.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley''s Porat Says Bank ROE Drop Is Part Secular</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) Chief Financial
Officer Ruth Porat said the drop in the financial industry''s
return on equity is part cyclical and part secular as banks will
be forced to hold more equity capital. </p>
<p>While firms will increase earnings as the global economy
rebounds, they will post lower returns on equity than before the
crisis, Porat, 54, said today at the Bloomberg Markets 50 Summit
in New York. Lower ROEs will be offset by the benefits of a
safer financial system, she said. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley posted a 4 percent return on equity for 2011
and 1 percent in the first six months of this year, below the
firm''s cost of capital, which Fiona Swaffield, a Royal Bank of
Canada analyst, estimated last year at 11.5 percent. Porat said
the bank has a sense of urgency in improving returns, which
she said can surpass its cost of capital. </p>
<p>If our returns in the 80''s and 90''s were 20s-plus, and we
now have higher capital and it''s a safer structure, there is
room for lower returns that are still attractive and
meaningfully ahead of your cost of capital, Porat said.
Returns have come down, but they need to be in excess of the
cost of capital, or investors won''t stay invested. </p>
<p>In addition to benefiting from an improving economy, banks
will also be able to boost earnings by reducing costs and
capitalizing as competitors exit certain businesses, Porat said.
European lenders have been pulling back from some regions as
they shore up capital and liquidity, she said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Camila Russo and Nathan Crooks" date="Sep 17, 2012  5:22 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-17/jpmorgan-raises-argentine-bonds-to-overweight-cuts-venezuela.html"><headline>JPMorgan Raises Argentine Bonds to Overweight, Cuts Venezuela</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) raised
Argentine bonds to overweight from marketweight, saying debt
prices already reflect investor concern about capital controls
and nationalizations and that economic growth could quicken. </p>
<p>Argentina''s economy has touched bottom and is in the
process of benefiting from both a cyclical lift and a more
comfortable balance of payments position that should extend into
2013, Vladimir Werning, a JPMorgan economist in New York,
wrote in a report. </p>
<p>While government intervention will continue to generate
headline risk, it is already reflected in asset prices,
Werning said. </p>
<p>The government is scheduled to release second-quarter
growth figures on Sept. 21. The economy probably expanded 0.5
percent in the quarter from the year-earlier period, according
to the median forecast from 10 analysts surveyed by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>While raising Argentine debt to overweight, JPMorgan cut
Venezuela to marketweight after a four-month rally in the
securities. </p>
<p>The extra yield investors demand to own Argentine
government dollar debt over U.S. Treasuries fell 24 basis points
to 846 basis points at 6:20 p.m. in Buenos Aires while
Venezuela''s bond spread rose 10 basis points to 956 basis
points, according to JPMorgan''s EMBIG index. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kevin Dugan" date="Sep 17, 2012  2:57 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-17/morgan-stanley-sells-largest-note-tied-to-amazon-com-this-year.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Sells Largest Note Tied to Amazon.com This Year</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) sold $16.2 million
of one year auto-callable notes tied to Amazon.com Inc. (AMZN), the
biggest offering linked to the world''s largest Internet retailer
since December. </p>
<p>The securities, issued Sept. 12, pay 3.588 percent each
quarter that the company''s stock is at least 75 percent of its
initial price, according to a prospectus filed with the U.S.
Securities and Exchange Commission. They are automatically
redeemed if the shares are higher than or equal to the starting
value. The bank distributed the notes for a 1.5 percent fee. </p>
<p>On Dec. 15, HSBC Bank Plc sold through its U.S. unit $19
million of one-year securities tied to the Seattle-based company
that pay 10 percent annually, with an additional 7.65 percent if
the stock gains at least 10 percent, according to a prospectus
filed with the SEC. Since the note''s issuance, the company''s
shares have climbed about 43 percent, while the value of the
security has increased 9.7 percent, according to Trace, the
bond-price reporting system of the Financial Industry Regulatory
Authority. </p>
<p>Earlier this month, the online goods seller unveiled new e-
readers, including a Kindle Fire with an 8.9-inch screen. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Linda Sandler" date="Sep 17, 2012  2:04 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-17/jpmorgan-sued-by-lehman-over-2-2-billion-derivatives-claims-1-.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sued by Lehman Over $2.2 Billion Derivatives Claims</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), fighting over
$6.3 billion it says Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. owes it, was
sued by the defunct investment bank as it seeks to reject $2.2
billion in derivatives obligations. </p>
<p>A U.S. bankruptcy judge should rule on the overstated
demands by the bank, which never supplied supporting documents
for its claims, Lehman said in a filing in federal court in
Manhattan. Lehman is seeking unspecified damages from the
biggest U.S. bank, as well as money due from JPMorgan under the
derivatives contracts. </p>
<p>The JPMorgan entities'' derivatives claims should be
reduced or disallowed, Lehman said in the Sept. 14 filing. </p>
<p>The derivatives claims also feature in Lehman''s $8.6
billion suit against JPMorgan, which was the main short-term
lender to Lehman around the time of its 2008 collapse during the
credit crisis. Now out of bankruptcy, Lehman is gathering money
for its second payment to creditors on Oct. 1. It has said it
expects to pay creditors 18 cents on the dollar by 2016 or so. </p>
<p>Last month, Lehman lost a bid to persuade a judge to revise
his ruling on the $8.6 billion suit against JPMorgan, which
alleges that the New York-based lender helped cause its collapse
by taking collateral for its loans. </p>
<h2>Payment Demands </h2>
<p>U.S. Bankruptcy Judge James Peck dismissed some of the
investment bank''s claims that might have brought creditors
hundreds of millions of dollars, according to Lehman. Peck told
Lehman it has other ways of obtaining money from JPMorgan, such
as fighting the bank''s payment demands. </p>
<p>Jennifer Zuccarelli, a spokeswoman for New York-based
JPMorgan, didn''t immediately respond to a phone call and e-mail
seeking comment on the suit. </p>
<p>The bank, which loaned Lehman''s brokerage $70 billion
around the time of the bankruptcy, has denied causing the firm''s
collapse. After giving Lehman almost $700 million to settle part
of the $8.6 billion suit, it continues to fight most of Lehman''s
allegations. </p>
<p>Peck ruled in April that Lehman cannot claim money from
JPMorgan for securities transactions governed by so-called safe
harbor law, devised to protect banks dealing with weak
companies. Lehman is entitled to pursue the remaining complex,
fact driven causes of action, he said. </p>
<p>Lehman filed the biggest bankruptcy in U.S. history in
September 2008, listing $613 billion in debt. </p>
<p>The case is Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. v. JPMorgan Chase
Bank NA, 12-01874, U.S. Bankruptcy Court, Southern District of
New York (Manhattan). The earlier case is Lehman Brothers
Holdings Inc. v. JPMorgan Chase Bank NA, 10-03266, U.S.
Bankruptcy Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Rodrigo Orihuela" date="Sep 17, 2012  1:34 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-17/chevron-said-to-expand-brazil-monitoring-amid-spill-lawsuit-1-.html"><headline>Chevron Said to Expand Brazil Monitoring Amid Spill Lawsuit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX) is creating three
teams and hiring executives in Brazil to oversee risk and
containment at its Frade field as it challenges a ban on
operations and lawsuits because of a spill, a person familiar
with the hirings said. </p>
<p>The second-biggest U.S. oil company is hiring about 16
people in coming months for Brazil, including five executives,
said the person, who can''t be named because the hirings aren''t
public. The positions include managers for the teams, a deputy
country manager and an asset development manager for the
offshore Frade project where the spill occurred in November, the
person said. </p>
<p>The 3,000-barrel leak at Frade prompted federal prosecutors
to sue Chevron for a total of 40 billion reais ($20 billion) for
harming the environment, as well as environmental criminal
charges. The San Ramon, California-based company voluntarily
suspended operations in Brazil in March following a second leak
at the field off the country''s southeastern coast. </p>
<p>Brazil will fine Chevron 35 million reais for the spill,
Magda Chambriard, the head of Brazilian oil regulator ANP, said
today in Rio de Janeiro. </p>
<p>In August, a court ordered Chevron and Transocean Ltd. (RIG),
owner of the rig used at Frade, to suspend all operations in the
country. Last week the ruling was upheld by the Superior Justice
Tribunal, the country''s second-highest court, and may be
appealed at the Federal Supreme Court. </p>
<h2>All Legal Means'' </h2>
<p>Chevron will seek all legal means at our disposal to
overturn the ban, the company said in a Sept. 12 statement after
the court order was upheld. Transocean said in a separate
statement it has many ways to contest the injunction. </p>
<p>Kurt Glaubitz and Jim Craig, spokesmen for Chevron, didn''t
respond to e-mails and telephone messages seeking comment on the
hirings. </p>
<p>Frade is Chevron''s sole operating field in the country. The
company voluntarily halted about 60,000 barrels a day of output
at Frade in March. </p>
<p>Chevron gained 0.7 percent to $118.08 at 1:17 p.m. in New
York. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Linda Sandler" date="Sep 17, 2012  9:24 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-17/jpmorgan-sued-by-lehman-over-derivatives-claims.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sued by Lehman Over Derivatives Claims</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), which has
been fighting defunct Lehman Brothers Holdings Inc. over about
$6 billion of claims for payment, was sued by Lehman over
$2.2 billion in derivatives obligations, according to a
bankruptcy court filing in Manhattan. </p>
<p>Lehman is asking a judge to rule on the overstated
demands by the bank, which was the main short-term lender to
Lehman around the time of its 2008 collapse. </p>
<p>Previously, Lehman sued JPMorgan over $8.6 billion in
collateral that it wants back. The latest suit was filed Sept.
14. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lisa Rapaport" date="Sep 18, 2012  4:36 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-18/microsoft-reduces-size-of-board-as-director-gilmartin-to-retire.html"><headline>Microsoft Director Gilmartin to Retire Reducing Board Size</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) director Raymond Gilmartin, former chief executive officer of Merck  Co., will
leave the software maker''s board, reducing the size to ten
directors. The company also raised its dividend by 15 percent. </p>
<p>Gilmartin is retiring after 11 years of service and won''t
seek re-election to the board at the company''s 2012 annual
meeting, Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft said today in a
statement. </p>
<p>Microsoft increased its quarterly dividend by 3 cents to 23
cents, payable to shareholders of record on Nov. 15. The world''s
largest software maker has increased the payout in each of the
previous two years, including a 25 percent boost in 2011.
Microsoft''s cash and short-term investments as of June 30 surged
to more than $63 billion, from $52.8 billion a year earlier,
just before the last dividend increase. </p>
<p>The shares have advanced 20 percent this year. Microsoft
was little changed at $31.18 at the close in New York. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christine Harper" date="Sep 18, 2012  4:29 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-18/goldman-sachs-s-schwartz-to-succeed-viniar-as-firm-s-cfo.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs''s Schwartz to Succeed Viniar as Firm''s CFO</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)''s David A. Viniar, the longest-serving chief financial officer of a major
Wall Street firm, will retire at the end of January and be
replaced by Harvey M. Schwartzfrom the sales and trading unit. </p>
<p>Viniar, 57, will join the New York-based bank''s board of
directors when he retires, the company said in a statement
today. Schwartz, 48, will assume oversight of operations,
technology and finance as well as co-head of the firm-wide risk
committee, the company said. Schwartz has worked at Goldman
Sachs since 1997. </p>
<p>I have sought Harvey''s advice on risk judgments and
market knowledge for a long time and I know he will be an
outstanding chief financial officer, Viniar said in the
statement. I look forward to continuing to contribute to
Goldman Sachs as a member of our board of directors. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs was the most profitable securities firm in
Wall Street history before converting to a bank in 2008. Viniar
helped steer the firm through the financial crisis and guided
the company through its initial public offering in 1999. </p>
<p>The firm plans to appoint more independent directors to the
board in the near future, according to the statement. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Cliff Edwards" date="Sep 18, 2012  4:04 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-18/microsoft-hires-ex-cbs-executive-to-oversee-xbox-content.html"><headline>Microsoft Hires Ex-CBS Executive to Oversee Xbox Content</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) hired former CBS
Corp. (CBS) television executive Nancy Tellem to oversee content
produced for the company''s Xbox entertainment console. </p>
<p>Tellem, who was president of CBS Network Television
Entertainment Group, has joined Microsoft as entertainment and
digital media president, according to a statement today from the
Redmond, Washington-based company. </p>
<p>The appointment highlights Microsoft''s increased emphasis
on delivering movies, sports and television shows through the
Xbox 360, a gaming console about to enter the seventh year since
its release. It has more than 65 applications that connect to
such services as Netflix, Hulu Plus and Time Warner Inc. (TWX)''s HBO
GO. Xbox Live''s 44 million subscribers spend on average 80 hours
a month consuming online video, said Phil Spencer, corporate
vice president of Microsoft Studios. </p>
<p>The box has really evolved into a platform for creators
and consumers to find all the content they love, Spencer said
in a telephone interview. </p>
<p>Tellem, who will head a new production studio in Los
Angeles, will examine Microsoft''s portfolio of games for sources
of content, and also will mine Hollywood for movies, television
shows and Web content, she said, speaking in the same interview. </p>
<p>It''s all about creating compelling content, Tellem said.
We''re opening our doors to all types of talent. </p>
<p>Though the executives declined to discuss specific budgets
for such content, Spencer said the company plans to make a
significant commitment since being state-of-the-art and
extremely high-quality is critical to gaining consumer mind
share. </p>
<p>Tellem oversaw network entertainment at CBS until 2009,
when she stepped down to become an adviser to Chief Executive
officer Leslie Moonves. </p>
<p>Microsoft was little changed at $31.18 at the New York
close. The shares have risen 20 percent this year. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bob Van Voris" date="Sep 18, 2012 12:58 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-18/pfizer-unit-must-face-investor-class-action-over-pristiq.html"><headline>Pfizer Unit Must Face Investor Class Action Over Pristiq</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE)''s Wyeth unit must face
a class action by investors claiming the drugmaker hid negative
data on Pristiq, an anti-depressant marketed as the first non-
hormone menopause treatment. </p>
<p>U.S. District Judge Richard Sullivan today granted a
request by two pension funds to sue on behalf of all investors
who bought Wyeth common stock from June 26, 2006, through July
24, 2007. The plaintiffs claim Wyeth misled them by failing to
disclose information about Pristiq''s effects on the heart and
liver, which delayed the drug''s approval by the U.S. Food and
Drug Administration. </p>
<p>The suit was filed in 2007 by the City of Livonia
Employees'' Retirement System. The plaintiffs, led by the
Pipefitters Union Local 537 Pension Fund, say Wyeth stock
dropped $5.70 after the company disclosed the negative effects
publicly. The investors are seeking unspecified damages. </p>
<p>Pfizer, the world''s biggest drug company, acquired Wyeth in
2009. </p>
<p>The court''s decision is limited to preliminary procedural
issues, Chris Loder, a spokesman for the New York-based
company, said in an e-mailed statement. The opinion does not
address the merits of the case. He said the company will fight
the lawsuit. </p>
<p>The case is City of Livonia Employees Retirement System v.
Wyeth, 07-cv-10329, U.S. District Court, Southern District of
New York (Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Neil Callanan" date="Sep 18, 2012 12:56 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-18/goldman-trading-murals-for-london-office-faces-flood-hotspot-2-.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Allowed to Move Murals to Build London Offices</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) will be
allowed to move a set of protected murals from a building in the
City of London financial district, a decision that may clear the
way for the investment bank''s new European headquarters. </p>
<p>The vote by the City''s council gives a Goldman Sachs unit
the option to develop an office building at 70 Farringdon
Street, about a minute''s walk from its existing London
headquarters on Fleet Street. </p>
<p>Planning permission for a 54,400-square-meter (585,500-
square-foot) office development at the Farringdon Street site
was first granted in 2005 and renewed in September 2011. The
murals, nine semi-abstract ceramic panels by artist Dorothy
Annan, were listed for preservation last year and incorporate
stylistic images of telecommunications equipment, according to
documents given to council members in advance of the vote. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs had been somewhat concerned that their
development may be scuppered by having to keep the murals in
place, Peter Rees, chief planning officer for the City of
London, told council member''s today. </p>
<p>Joanna Carss, a spokeswoman for Goldman Sachs in London,
declined to comment. </p>
<p>The murals will initially be stored and may eventually be
displayed near the Guildhall School of Music, about a mile from
the Farringdon Street site, the documents provided to the
council said. Goldman Sachs'' new office building is unlikely to
be a suitable location for the murals at least in the view of
the developers, Rees said at the meeting. </p>
<h2>Sewer Overload'' </h2>
<p>Goldman Sachs bought an adjoining site at Plumtree Court in
February, according to documents filed with the U.K.''s Land
Registry. An application is expected for a comprehensive
redevelopment of the sites, the City of London said in the
documents provided to the borough''s council. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs will have to show how it plans to reduce
the risk of sewer overload in this area during development,
the City of London told the New York-based bank''s planning
adviser DP9 Ltd. in an Aug. 30 letter. The area is a flood
risk hotspot, according to the letter. </p>
<p>Vibrations during construction may also lead to water
main bursts and or sewer collapses, the City wrote. The
borough released the letter following a request by Bloomberg
News. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs''s London Property unit had assets of 73.7
million pounds ($120 million) through December and paid 103.4
million pounds for a development site this year, according to a
filing with Companies House in August. </p>
<p>Chinese Estates Holdings Ltd., controlled by Hong Kong
billionaire Joseph Lau, bought River Court, part of Goldman
Sachs existing European headquarters, from a group of Irish
investors advised by Warren Private Clients Ltd. for about 280
million pounds last year. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Aoife White" date="Sep 18, 2012 10:52 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-18/microsoft-said-to-face-eu-antitrust-complaint-on-browser-choice.html"><headline>Microsoft Said to Face EU Antitrust Complaint on Browser Choice</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>European Union regulators are
preparing an antitrust complaint over Microsoft Corp. (MSFT)''s failure
to comply with a settlement to give users a choice of web
browsers, according to two people familiar with the matter. </p>
<p>There''s no set timing for the European Commission to send
the statement of objections, said the people who asked not to be
identified because the complaint isn''t public. A statement of
objections lists alleged violations of competition rules and is
a precursor to possible fines. </p>
<p>EU Competition Commissioner Joaquin Almunia said in July
that Microsoft may have misled regulators by failing to display
a browser choice screen to users of the Windows operating system
since February 2011. The world''s largest software company blamed
a technical error for not showing the screen to some users and
offered to extend until March 2016 a commitment to show it. </p>
<p>Microsoft has already been fined 1.68 billion euros ($2.2
billion) in EU antitrust probes, including an 899 million-euro
penalty for failing to obey an order to share data with
competitors. The Redmond, Washington-based company agreed to
offer access to rival browsers as a part of a 2009 settlement to
repair its relationship with the bloc''s regulators. It told
regulators last December that it was complying with its
commitments. </p>
<p>Microsoft''s press office in Brussels declined to comment
beyond a July statement in which the company expressed its
regret that the error occurred and understood that regulators
may penalize it. </p>
<h2>Technical Error </h2>
<p>The company said it only learned in July that it didn''t
offer its browser choice software to some 28 million computers
running Windows 7 Service Pack 1, or 10 percent of the computers
that should have received it. It blamed a technical error and
said it has already started distributing a fix. </p>
<p>The European Commission declined to comment. </p>
<p>Under the terms of Microsoft''s 2009 pledge, consumers who
buy personal computers were given a choice of the 12 most widely
used browsers to install in addition to, or instead of,
Microsoft''s Internet Explorer. </p>
<p>Any fines for Microsoft may take into account repeat
offenses, Almunia said in July in a reference to the EU''s 2008
penalty for the company''s failure to obey an earlier EU
decision. That ruling also ordered it to provide information to
software developers to make compatible products. EU antitrust
fines are usually capped at 10 percent of yearly revenue. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Sep 19, 2012  4:40 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-19/morgan-stanley-wells-fargo-challenged-on-73-billion-in-rmbs.html"><headline>Wells Fargo, Morgan Stanley Faulted on RMBS Servicing</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A law firm that won an $8.5 billion
settlement from Bank of America Corp. (BAC) tied to faulty mortgage
bonds said Wells Fargo  Co. (WFC) and Morgan Stanley (MS) failed to
service $73 billion of similar securities, creating a default. </p>
<p>Gibbs  Bruns LLP cited at least $15 billion of Wells
Fargo''s residential mortgage-backed securities and $5 billion
from Morgan Stanley where holders have 25 percent or 50 percent
or more of the voting rights, according to a statement today
from the Houston-based law firm. The dispute also covers $23
billion of Morgan Stanley-issued RMBS and $30 billion of Wells
Fargo''s RMBS where holders have significant voting rights, but
less than 25 percent or 50 percent, the firm said. </p>
<p>Faulty mortgages and foreclosures have cost the largest
U.S. home lenders at least $84 billion since the start of 2007,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg, and have been blamed by
regulators for discouraging banks from making new loans. Kathy Patrick, a partner at Gibbs  Bruns, led a bondholder group that
reached a settlement in June 2011 with Bank of America covering
mortgage trusts with an original loan balance of $424 billion. </p>
<p>We will review any communication we receive and respond
appropriately, said Mary Eshet, a spokeswoman for San
Francisco-based Wells Fargo. Mary Claire Delaney, a spokeswoman
for New York-based Morgan Stanley, declined to comment. </p>
<h2>Minimum Level </h2>
<p>Gibbs  Bruns represents at least 20 bondholders including
BlackRock Inc., Goldman Sachs Asset Management, Pacific
Investment Management Co., Western Asset Management Co. and TCW
Group Inc., according to two people with direct knowledge of the
matter, who asked not to be identified because the information
hasn''t been made public. </p>
<p>Patrick''s firm said in January it was seeking information
on pools securing more than $19 billion of RMBS issued by
affiliates of Wells Fargo, which says it''s the biggest U.S.
home-mortgage lender and servicer. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley also received a letter in October from the
law firm, which said it was representing holders of at least 25
percent of voting rights in 17 trusts with more than $6 billion
in outstanding balances, according to a filing. </p>
<p>The percentage of holders matters because claims must meet
specific minimums before parties to mortgage-bond deals can be
declared in default. If not cured, the defaults can give
investors the right to sue bond creators, the deal''s trustees or
both. Typically, trustees must take action on their behalf. </p>
<h2>Serious Questions'' </h2>
<p>Bank of America''s settlement with 22 bondholders, including
BlackRock and Pimco, seeks to allow it to pay 2 percent of the
faulty bonds'' face value to avoid repurchasing the underlying
loans. </p>
<p>While Bank of America''s deal is awaiting court approval,
attorneys general from New York and Delaware have intervened to
seek more information. New York has said there are serious
questions about the fairness and adequacy of the accord, which
covers a small fraction of losses. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley earlier this year sold its Saxon Mortgage
Services Inc. unit to Ocwen Financial Corp., exiting the
servicing business it bought before the housing market
collapsed. Mortgage servicers handle billing and collections and
oversee foreclosures when borrowers fail to pay. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Mulholland" date="Sep 19, 2012  3:45 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-19/jpmorgan-said-to-break-moody-s-lock-on-commercial-mortgage-bonds.html"><headline>JPMorgan Said to Break Moody''s Lock on Commercial-Mortgage Bonds</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) has selected
Standard  Poor''s to rate its planned $1.5 billion commercial
mortgage bond offering, breaking the stranglehold Moody''s
Investors Service has had on the market for 14 months. </p>
<p>The transaction is set to be offered to investors next week
without a rating from Moody''s, according to a person familiar
with the deal who declined to be identified because the
transaction hasn''t been announced. Elizabeth Seymour, a
spokeswoman for JPMorgan, declined to comment. </p>
<p>Wall Street banks have been bypassing SP''s ratings for
commercial-mortgage bonds since the company derailed a $1.5
billion sale by Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and Citigroup Inc. last
year by pulling its grades on the securities. Since then, SP
hasn''t rated a so-called conduit deal composed of loans from
multiple borrowers, the biggest part of the market, according to
data compiled by Bloomberg. JPMorgan''s offering was reported
earlier today by the Wall Street Journal. </p>
<p>Demand for commercial-mortgage backed securities is surging
as investors seek riskier assets with the Federal Reserve saying
it''s likely to hold its benchmark lending rate near zero at
least through mid-2015. Yields on debt linked to shopping malls,
skyscrapers and hotels reached a record low 2.19 percent
yesterday, according to the Barclays Investment Grade CMBS
index. </p>
<p>Wall Street banks have issued about $3.83 billion in
commercial-mortgage backed securities this month, Bloomberg data
show. Issuance will likely surpass $40 billion this year,
Jefferies Group Inc. analysts said in a Sept. 11 report. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Miles Weiss" date="Sep 19, 2012  2:22 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-19/morgan-stanley-says-funds-took-2-facebook-at-38-a-share.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Says Funds Took 2% Facebook at $38 a Share</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS), the underwriter that took Facebook Inc. (FB) public at a record high market value, said its own money-management unit bought more than 2 percent of the shares sold through the $16 billion offering. </p> <p>Morgan Stanley Investment Management invested about $380 million in Facebook''s initial public offering, according to regulatory filings late last month, the first to show its IPO purchases. A dozen funds run by the advisory unit''s growth team, headed by Dennis Lynch, each allocated 6.8 percent of their net assets to buying Facebook stock at the IPO price of $38 a share. </p> <p>Facebook has fallen 42 percent since its offering, increased in size and price at the 11th hour. The drop erased $39 billion in market capitalization, ranking the stock as the worst-performing large technology IPO ever based on the early loss in value, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. The decline crimped the performance of Lynch''s growth team, described as a crown jewel of Morgan Stanley Investment Management, and left the bank''s fund investors behind on the investment. </p> <p>Facebook has underperformed because they took the last dime off the table on the IPO price, said Tom Forte, an analyst at New York-based Telsey Advisory Group who has been following IPOs since the 1990s. They did an incredible job of getting every last penny for existing shareholders, seemingly to the detriment of the new shareholders. </p>




Photographer: Matthew Staver/Bloomberg

<p>
Morgan Stanley U.S. Growth Investments Head Dennis Lynch. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Doug Alexander" date="Sep 19, 2012 10:52 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-19/goldman-sachs-s-blankfein-would-go-long-on-real-estate.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs''s Blankfein Would Go Long'' on Real Estate</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Lloyd C. Blankfein, chief
executive officer of Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), said he would
invest in real estate as central banks around the world focus on
avoiding deflation. </p>
<p>I accept that invitation to have higher asset prices, and
so I would go long more the real assets, including real
estate, Blankfein, who turns 58 tomorrow, said in a discussion
today with Royal Bank of Canada (RY) CEO Gordon Nixon, at an event
hosted by the Canadian Club of Toronto. </p>
<p>The Bank of Japan (8301) today joined the Federal Reserve and
European Central Bank in acting against threats of an economic
contraction five years after the U.S. mortgage meltdown derailed
the global economy. The BOJ expanded its asset-purchase fund by
10 trillion yen ($127 billion). The Fed said last week it would
buy $40 billion a month of mortgage debt in a third round of so-
called quantitative easing. </p>
<p>The central banks are obviously putting a real penalty on
holding cash and are trying to incentivize everybody into going
into higher assets, Blankfein said. They may be
unsuccessful, but I tell you if more inflationary expectations
seeped into the world, that would be very positive today for the
economic system. </p>
<p>Blankfein said he would follow the will of the central
banks, which are trying to avoid deflation even at the risk of
spurring inflation. They want asset prices to inflate, he
said. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs, the most profitable securities firm in Wall
Street history before converting to a bank in 2008, announced a
new round of cost-cutting in July after reporting the lowest
first-half revenue in seven years. In a research report last
week, Goldman Sachs''s bank analysts said the industry''s decline
in profit has been driven primarily by increased capital
requirements and regulation, rather than the economic slowdown. </p>
<p>Blankfein''s discussion today follows appearances at the
Economic Club of Washington, the St. Petersburg International
Economic Forum, the Chicago Club and on MSNBC earlier this year.
Goldman Sachs is based in New York. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By James Callan" date="Sep 19, 2012  9:38 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-19/general-mills-profit-tops-estimates-on-sales-abroad.html"><headline>General Mills Profit Tops Estimates on Sales Abroad</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>General Mills Inc. (GIS), the maker of
Cheerios cereal, reported first-quarter profit that topped
analysts'' estimates as sales gained in Europe and Canada. </p>
<p>Net income rose 35 percent to $548.9 million, or 82 cents a
share, from $405.6 million, or 61 cents, a year earlier, the
Minneapolis-based company said today in a statement. Excluding
some items, profit totaled 66 cents a share. Analysts projected
62 cents, the average of 17 estimates compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>International sales increased 27 percent to $1.09 billion.
On a constant-currency basis, sales gained 51 percent in Europe
and 28 percent in Canada. Results were helped by its Yoplait
International acquisition, General Mills said. Total sales rose
5.3 percent to $4.05 billion. </p>
<p>General Mills advanced 1.7 percent to $39.96 at 9:36 a.m.
in New York. The shares had dropped 2.7 percent this year
through yesterday. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Neal Armstrong" date="Sep 19, 2012  8:47 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-19/goldman-sachs-ends-trade-recommendation-to-buy-euro-for-7-gain.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Ends Trade Recommendation to Buy Euro for 7% Gain</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. ended a
trade recommendation to buy the euro against the dollar, after
the 17-nation currency rallied following European Central Bank
measures to stem the sovereign debt crisis. </p>
<p>With much of the expected developments now past us, our
initial target of $1.30 reached and a period of further
consolidation possible, we consider it prudent to close our
recommendation for a potential gain of about 7 percent,
Goldman Sachs foreign-exchange analysts led by London-based
Thomas Stolper wrote today in an e-mailed report. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christine Harper and Michael J. Moore" date="Sep 19, 2012  6:11 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-19/goldman-sachs-s-schwartz-to-succeed-viniar-as-firm-s-cfo.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs''s Schwartz to Succeed Viniar as Firm''s CFO</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) Chief Financial Officer David A. Viniar, who guided the firm through its 1999 initial public offering and the 2008 financial crisis, will end his 32-year career as an employee in January. </p> <p>Viniar, whose 12 years in the role make him the longest- serving CFO on Wall Street, will be succeeded by Harvey M. Schwartz, 48, one of three global co-heads from the sales and trading division, the New York-based bank said in a statement yesterday. Goldman Sachs will add Viniar, 57, as well as some independent directors to the 10-member board, the firm said. </p> <p>Goldman Sachs, the most profitable securities firm in Wall Street history before converting to a bank in 2008, has climbed 33 percent this year in New York trading, and the U.S. Justice Department and Securities and Exchange Commission have dropped probes into the company. Viniar told an analyst last year he wouldn''t leave until a sense of calm was restored. </p> <p>We''ve always worried what would happen when David Viniar left, said Jim Rothenberg, who runs Los Angeles-based Capital Group Cos., a Goldman Sachs client and its second-biggest shareholder, after the bank''s own employees. Every change gets people somewhat nervous, but I don''t know that there''s a better individual there to take over this function. </p> <p>Viniar, during a conference call with investors after his retirement was announced, said he''s comfortable leaving now because the firm is in very good financial shape. </p> <p>We are performing as well as we could given the operating environment, he said. </p> <h2>Public Face </h2> <p>Viniar served under Chairman and Chief Executive Officer Lloyd C. Blankfein, 57, and his predecessor, Henry M. Paulson, who left in June 2006 to become U.S. Treasury Secretary under then-President George W. Bush. </p> <p>Under both executives, Viniar served as the most public face of the firm, speaking to analysts and investors about quarterly results and at conferences. Meredith Whitney, the analyst and founder of Meredith Whitney Advisory Group LLC, said in a note to investors yesterday that Viniar set the gold standard for CFOs across the industry. </p> <p>The move may indicate that Goldman Sachs management feels it''s past the worst of the financial crisis and the legal scrutiny that followed, including a $550 million settlement with the SEC over claims that the firm misled investors in a mortgage-linked security, said Benjamin B. Wallace, an analyst at Westborough, Massachusetts-based Grimes  Co. </p> <h2>Blankfein''s Tenure </h2> <p>I''d assume it''s been a rather stressful couple of years there, said Wallace, whose firm doesn''t own Goldman Sachs stock. There will obviously be some questions about when Lloyd is going to step down as well. </p> <p>Blankfein is scheduled to speak today at an event hosted by The Canadian Club of Toronto. </p> <p>Viniar''s role has been broader than at some other companies, leading people familiar with the matter to say last year that they weren''t sure one executive could assume all of his duties when he left. </p> <p>Schwartz said he will follow Viniar in taking on responsibility for the entire administrative side of the firm -- known as operations, technology and finance or by its nickname, The Federation -- because regulatory changes make it important to coordinate all those areas. </p> <p>I don''t see any material changes to the way we want to operate the business, Schwartz said on yesterday''s conference call. He''s a pretty tough act to follow. </p> <h2>Team Continuity </h2> <p>Viniar said there aren''t any changes expected in his team, which includes Treasurer Elizabeth Liz Beshel Robinson, who joined the company in 1990 and was trained by him to handle the firm''s financing and liquidity. Robinson and Sarah Smith, Goldman Sachs''s controller and chief accounting officer, are among deputies that were viewed as potential successors to Viniar, people familiar with the matter said last year. </p> <p>I''ll be relying on the staff extensively, Schwartz said. I''ll be relying on them as much as David has. </p> <p>Schwartz graduated from Rutgers University in 1987 and earned a master''s degree in business administration from Columbia University in 1996. He joined Goldman Sachs''s commodities sales and trading unit J. Aron in 1997 and spent most of his career in sales, except for two years in the financing group that advises corporate clients on debt and equity financing. </p> <p>His start at J. Aron is similar to that of Blankfein and Chief Operating Officer Gary D. Cohn, 52, who both began their Goldman Sachs careers in that business. By contrast, Viniar joined the investment-banking department in 1980 and was promoted to CFO after serving as deputy chief financial officer under then-CFO John A. Thain. Before that, Viniar oversaw the firm''s treasury and controllers. </p> <h2>Schwartz''s Career </h2> <p>Schwartz became co-head of the securities division in February 2008, giving him oversight of the company''s biggest business by revenue. Isabelle Ealet, 49, the French-born former commodities chief who helps run securities from London, and Pablo J. Salame, 46, the New York-based Ecuadoran citizen who has experience overseeing equities, credit and emerging markets, will be left in charge of the business after Schwartz''s move. </p> <p>In his new post, Schwartz will receive a base salary of $1.85 million as well as a bonus, Goldman Sachs said in a filing today. </p> <h2>Lot of Credit'' </h2> <p>Viniar, who was awarded $11.85 million in salary and bonuses for 2011, held about 1.83 million shares of Goldman Sachs stock as of March 26, according to the firm''s annual proxy filing. His holding is valued at more than $219 million, based on yesterday''s closing price of $119.88 a share. </p> <p>I will continue to be a large stockholder for many years to come, Viniar said in response to an analyst''s question about whether he planned to sell any of his shares when he leaves. I''m confident that Harvey as a CFO will continue to get the stock price higher. </p> <p>Viniar will get a lot of credit for managing the firm''s risk through the financial crisis and helping the company emerge in a strong position relative to peers, Roger Freeman, an analyst at Barclays Plc''s investment-banking unit in New York, said in an interview. </p> <p>It''s obviously not fair to credit one person for that but everything they''ve done, he''s been on top of, Freeman said. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Cathy Chan" date="Sep 19, 2012  6:02 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-19/jpmorgan-names-rob-sivitilli-asia-ex-japan-m-a-head-memo-says.html"><headline>JPMorgan Names Sivitilli Asia Ex-Japan M&amp;amp;A Head, Memo Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) appointed Rob Sivitilli, head of mergers and acquisitions for Asia outside of
Japan, according to an internal memo obtained by Bloomberg News. </p>
<p>The bank also hired Lian Lian from Citigroup Inc. as co-
head of north Asia mergers advisory, according to the document.
Marie Cheung, a Hong Kong-based spokeswoman at the firm,
confirmed the contents of the memo. </p>
<p>Sivitilli will remain in his role as head of corporate
finance and mergers advisory for Southeast Asia. Lian Lian, who
worked for Citigroup for six years, will be based in Hong Kong
and work alongside Sanjeev Malkani in her new role, according to
the memo. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Richard Rubin" date="Sep 20, 2012  5:46 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-20/microsoft-avoided-billions-in-u-s-tax-senate-memo-says.html"><headline>Microsoft Avoids U.S. Tax Along With HP, Senate Memo Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A U.S. Senate committee memo said Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) used aggressive international tax maneuvers to avoid billions of dollars in taxes over the past three years. </p> <p>The committee memo, released for a hearing today in Washington, said Microsoft used transactions with subsidiaries in Puerto Rico, Ireland, Singapore and Bermuda to save at least $6.5 billion in taxes. The committee also revealed that Hewlett- Packard Co. (HP) has used a series of short-term internal loans that allowed the company to tap its offshore cash for domestic operations without paying taxes, according to the memo. </p> <p>Senator Carl Levin, a Michigan Democrat and chairman of the Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations, didn''t accuse the companies of acting illegally, though he said he was highly dubious that HP was in compliance with the tax law. </p> <p>Such financial maneuvers may be in your temporary interest as a corporation, Levin told Bill Sample, Microsoft''s corporate vice president for worldwide tax, at the hearing. It increases your profits and reduces your taxes, but there''s a heavy cost to the United States, Levin said. </p> <p>Levin and the panel''s top Republican, Tom Coburn of Oklahoma, sent the memo to committee members. </p> <p>Coburn described the moves as properly legal tax avoidance by companies taking advantage of a tax code that needs an overhaul. </p> <p>Our report is about the symptoms of the disease, not the real disease, he said at the hearing. </p> <h2>Global Business </h2> <p>The report describes the ways companies can move profits outside of the country and keep them there to avoid U.S. taxes. </p> <p>We comply with U.S. and foreign tax laws, Sample said at the hearing. That is not to say that the rules cannot be improved. </p> <p>U.S.-based companies owe U.S. taxes on profits they earn around the world. They receive credits against that liability for taxes paid to foreign governments, and they don''t have to pay U.S. taxes until they bring the money home. </p> <p>The gap between the 35 percent U.S. corporate tax rate and lower tax rates in the rest of the world gives companies an incentive to book profits outside of the U.S. Levin said technology companies can easily move intangible assets such as patents outside of the U.S. with intra-company transactions at low prices. </p> <h2>Hard to Value </h2> <p>Those intangible assets are hard to value, and disputes about the correct price for such intra-company transactions are common. When foreign subsidiaries in low-tax countries pay too little, either up front or over time, they can get annual profits paid to them out of proportion to what they paid. </p> <p>The high-tech industry is probably the number-one user of these offshore entities to transfer intellectual property, Levin said. </p> <p>In questioning Sample, Levin outlined how Microsoft uses transactions within the company, all with its own money, to assign about 47 percent of its income from U.S. sales to a Puerto Rico subsidiary, and how it shifts some income from around the world to a Bermuda subsidiary that has no employees. </p> <p>Levin''s investigators sent letters to companies and used subpoenas to get information that companies don''t typically disclose. He said they focused on Microsoft and HP to show patterns that are common across U.S. companies. </p> <h2>IRS Enforcement </h2> <p>Levin attributed such tax avoidance in part to a lack of enforcement by the Internal Revenue Service, gaps in IRS regulations and loopholes created by Congress. </p> <p>Levin emphasized HP''s use of loans to tap its offshore cash. The loans, the report said, are structured to comply with the letter of tax rules that allow short-term loans from subsidiaries in Belgium and the Cayman Islands to the parent company. </p> <p>Although long-term loans would trigger tax consequences, the alternating-loan program provided a potential continuous stream of money for HP. </p> <p>The memo, citing company documents, said as much as $5 billion was available to the parent company in 2008 and that the company borrowed from $6 billion to $9 billion in 2010. HP holds $29.1 billion in untaxed earnings outside the U.S., according to the company''s most recent annual filing. </p> <h2>Fiscal Calendars </h2> <p>IRS rules allow companies to take loans from foreign subsidiaries without tax consequences within a given fiscal quarter. The Belgian and Cayman subsidiaries have different fiscal calendars. </p> <p>The company developed a schedule that allowed loans from the Belgian subsidiary within its fiscal quarters, and then loans from the Cayman subsidiary with a calendar that covered the periods when the Belgian subsidiary was crossing from one quarter to the next. </p> <p>Lester Ezrati, a senior vice president for tax at HP, said at the hearing that the company did have gaps in its borrowing from the foreign subsidiaries. He also said the IRS didn''t raise concerns when it examined the loans during a recent audit. </p> <p>HP has fully complied with U.S. tax law, the company said in a statement. </p> <p>We are disappointed to see what appears to be a politically motivated attack on one of America''s largest employers, it said. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kasia Klimasinska" date="Sep 20, 2012  4:39 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-20/jpmorgan-power-trading-business-faces-suspension-ferc-says.html"><headline>JPMorgan Power-Trading Business Faces Suspension, FERC Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The Federal Energy Regulatory
Commission has accused J.P. Morgan Ventures Energy Corp. of
misleading regulators and said its authority to sell electricity
might be suspended. </p>
<p>FERC issued an order today that directs the unit of New
York-based JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) to show that it didn''t violate
FERC regulations and explain why its authorization to sell
electric energy and related services at market-based rates
should not be suspended. </p>
<p>That can be more serious than a penalty, that could be
more serious than disgorging profits, said Susan Court,
principal at SJC Energy Consultants LLC in Arlington, Virginia,
and a former FERC enforcement director. That could entail a
lot more money than just paying a penalty. </p>
<p>The order is part of FERC''s effort to increase transparency
and eliminate manipulation of the electricity market. The agency
is investigating JPMorgan''s power trading in California and the
Midwest. That investigation came to light when FERC went to
court seeking internal e-mails from JPMorgan, saying the bids
from the company might have resulted in at least $73 million in
improper payments to generators. </p>
<p>FERC Chairman Jon Wellinghoff has pledged to expand
oversight of the multibillion dollar energy-trading business. In
February, the agency created a division within its enforcement
office to police the markets where electricity is bought and
sold by power generators and utilities. </p>
<h2>California Grid </h2>
<p>The dispute stems from requests in 2011 by the California
Independent System Operator, a grid operator, for information
about JPMorgan''s energy profits. JPMorgan told the operator that
the matter should be referred to FERC, even though FERC directed
CAISO to get the information from the company. </p>
<p>JPMorgan eventually provided the information, though said
it was doing so voluntarily even as FERC told the company it was
obliged to comply, according to the order posted on FERC''s
website today. </p>
<p>The order preliminarily finds that JPMorgan may have
omitted material information or submitted misleading
information four times in communications with FERC, the
California grid operator and that agency''s Department of Market
Monitoring, according to FERC. </p>
<p>JPMorgan must respond within 21 days of the order being
published in the Federal Register. </p>
<h2>Wholesale Markets </h2>
<p>Power companies can sell wholesale energy at market-based
rates, or cost-based rates, which are usually lower. FERC, which
grants the authority to sell electricity at market-based rates,
does so assuming that a company''s behavior will not involve
fraud, deception or misrepresentation, the commission said
today in the order. </p>
<p>Thus, the commission has repeatedly emphasized that
companies failing to adhere to the commission''s rules and
regulations are subject to suspension or revocation of their
market-based rate authority, according to the order. </p>
<p>It''s hard to prove market manipulation, but filing a
false document that''s material -- that''s not so hard to prove,
SJC Energy''s Court said. Either you did it or you didn''t. </p>
<p>Jennifer Zuccarelli, a JPMorgan spokeswoman, declined to
comment because the company hadn''t seen the FERC order. </p>
<p>Wall Street firms have been players in energy trading at
least since the late 1990''s, when many states restructured their
power markets. In so-called deregulated markets, buyers bid for
electricity from power generators. Consumers then purchase the
power from their local utility. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lisa Abramowicz" date="Sep 20, 2012  2:24 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-20/goldman-sachs-s-pope-said-to-be-leaving-leveraged-loans-post.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs''s Pope Said to Be Leaving Leveraged Loans Post</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Michael Pope, a managing director
in loan sales at Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), is leaving the firm,
according to two people familiar with the matter. </p>
<p>Pope, who joined the bank in 1999, is departing almost two
years after being promoted to the firm''s second-highest ranking
after partners, said the people who declined to be identified
because the move hasn''t been made public. Pope and Tiffany
Galvin, a spokeswoman in New York, declined to comment. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs, the fifth-biggest U.S. bank by assets, has
reduced its staff by almost 10 percent from the end of 2010 as
its revenue from sales and trading declined. Pope joins other
managing directors in corporate debt who have left in the past
12 months, including Courtney Mather, who headed U.S. loan
trading, Buckley Ratchford, who ran global bank loan trading and
distressed investing and Stephen Hickey, who led global
leveraged finance. </p>
<p>The bank said in July that it plans to eliminate $500
million from annual expenses, mostly from compensation, after
reporting its lowest first-half revenue since 2005. It employed
32,300 people at the end of June compared with 35,700 in
December 2010, according to the bank''s filings. </p>
<p>Chief Financial Officer David A. Viniar, who will end his
32-year career at Goldman Sachs in January, said on a July 17
conference call with investors that the firm expected to reduce
people-related costs by shifting to a more junior and less
senior weighted head count going forward. </p>
<p>Harvey M. Schwartz, one of the firm''s three global co-heads
from the sales and trading division, will take over as chief
financial officer, the New York-based bank said on Sept. 17. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bloomberg News" date="Sep 20, 2012 12:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-20/microsoft-said-to-ask-china-to-stop-piracy-at-four-state-firms.html"><headline>Microsoft Said to Ask China to Stop Piracy at Four Firms</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) asked China to stop
the alleged use of pirated versions of its Office software by
China National Petroleum Corp. and three other state-owned
companies, three people familiar with the situation said. </p>
<p>The world''s biggest software company filed its complaint
against CNPC, China Post Group, China Railway Construction Corp.
and Travelsky Technology Ltd. (696) last month to a government panel
led by Vice Premier Wang Qishan, said the three people, who
asked not to be identified because the filing isn''t public.
Microsoft alleged that more than 40 percent of Office and
Windows server client software used by CNPC, parent of China''s
largest company by value, is unlicensed, the people said. </p>
<p>Microsoft spokesman Charles Shen said he didn''t immediately
have any information on the filing. Liu Weijiang, a Beijing-
based spokesman at CNPC, said the company hadn''t heard about
Microsoft''s complaints. Liu declined to comment on whether CNPC
used pirated versions of the Office software. </p>
<p>Xu Zhaohui, who is in charge of hardware and software for
China Post, said Microsoft''s allegations were inaccurate.
The company, which delivers mail, received a complaint from
Microsoft within the past month and has sent a written response,
Xu said by telephone yesterday. </p>
<h2>Piracy Rates </h2>
<p>Microsoft alleges that 84 percent of China Railway
Construction''s Office software is unlicensed along with 97
percent of its Windows server client software, according to the
complaint, the people said. </p>
<p>Those estimates greatly exaggerated the use of
unlicensed software by China Railway Construction, the company
said in an e-mailed response supplied by Kevin Mao, an outside
public relations representative for the listed unit. </p>
<p>We do not rule out the possibility some subsidiary units
may have used unauthorized software, but it certainly is not
such a large proportion, China Railway Construction said in
the statement. The company attaches great importance to this
matter, and we are holding an internal inquiry. </p>
<p>Calls to the Travelsky headquarters number listed on its
website weren''t answered. </p>
<p>Microsoft Chief Executive Officer Steve Ballmer met Wang in
Beijing in May, and the vice premier pledged to crack down on
software piracy, the official Xinhua News Agency reported at the
time. In a speech at Peking University during the trip, Ballmer
said intellectual property protection in China is weak,
making it hard to sell legitimate software. </p>




Photographer: SeongJoon Cho/Bloomberg

<p>
In a speech at Peking University, Microsoft Chief Executive Officer Steve Ballmer said intellectual property protection in China is weak, making it hard to sell legitimate software. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Marek Strzelecki" date="Sep 20, 2012  8:53 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-20/exxon-will-return-two-polish-shale-gas-permits-to-government.html"><headline>Exxon Will Return Two Polish Shale Gas Permits to Government</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) will return two
of its six Polish shale gas exploration licenses to the
government after it decided to leave the country in June, the
world''s biggest energy company said today. </p>
<p>The company will return its Werbkowice license owned
jointly with Total SA (FP) and Legionowo permit in central Poland and
has not decided about the future of the remaining four licenses,
Adam Kopysc, public and government affairs adviser for Exxon
Mobil Exploration and Production in Warsaw, said today in an e-
mailed statement. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Aaron Kirchfeld" date="Sep 20, 2012  8:50 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-20/jpmorgan-s-adam-brett-said-to-plan-to-leave-lender.html"><headline>JPMorgan''s Adam Brett Said to Plan to Leave Lender</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Adam Brett, a managing director at
JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), is set to leave the bank, a person with
knowledge of the situation said. </p>
<p>Brett has served as the head of the bank''s metals and
mining group, and also sits on the Financial Services
Authority''s Listing Authority Advisory Committee, according to
the agency''s website. He joined Flemings in 1998 and JPMorgan in
2000. </p>
<p>An official at JPMorgan declined to comment. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Amanda Gould" date="Sep 21, 2012  1:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-21/jpmorgan-asset-management-s-quinsee-says-trading-has-improved.html"><headline>JPMorgan Asset Management''s Quinsee Says Trading Has Improved</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Paul Quinsee, who oversees $120
billion as head of JPMorgan Asset Management''s large-
capitalization core equity division, comments on how trading is
generally cheaper than it used to be. He spoke in an interview
with Erik Schatzker and Stephanie Ruhle on Bloomberg
Television''s Market Makers. </p>
<p>On high-frequency trading: </p>
<p>High frequency is one of these issues that we hear is
putting off the stock market, and I think that''s a great pity.
Because net, we think that our ability to trade stocks for
clients actually over the last five years is considerably
improved. </p>
<p>We''ve had to really raise our game. We''ve made a lot of
investments in technology. It''s generally cheaper to trade
stocks now than it used to be, and that''s got to be a good thing
for our clients. </p>
<p>On markets and Europe: </p>
<p>What''s happening in Europe has been very helpful in
calming people down. One outcome of that is that people feel a
bit more comfortable about owning stocks and we''re seeing this
sort of very high frequency stocks fall off the edges. Low
volumes are not necessarily a bad thing. </p>
<p>When you start to compare valuations with bonds, which is
where of course so much of the money has been going recently,
things look really quite interesting there. One-third of the SP
is still yielding more than the 10-year Treasury. We haven''t
seen that in modern times. That''s a very unusual balance still
very much in favor of stocks. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Matthew Leising" date="Sep 21, 2012 11:42 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-21/jpmorgan-swaps-loss-leads-bank-trading-revenue-lower-occ-says.html"><headline>JPMorgan Whale Loss Leads U.S. Bank Revenue Lower, OCC Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The trading loss at JPMorgan Chase
 Co. (JPM) helped cut revenue from cash and derivative positions at
U.S. commercial banks by 73 percent, compared with a year ago,
the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency said. </p>
<p>While both normal seasonal weakness and reduced client
demand played a role, it was clearly the highly publicized
losses at JPMorgan Chase that caused the sharp drop in trading
revenues, Martin Pfinsgraff, deputy comptroller for credit and
market risk, said today in a statement. Commercial banks had $2
billion in trading revenue for the second quarter, the
Washington-based regulator said. </p>
<p>The agency said its main measure of credit risk in
derivatives markets, the so-called net current credit exposure,
rose 9 percent, or $32 billion, to $410 billion. </p>
<p>JPMorgan, based in New York, lost $5.8 billion on credit-default swaps trades in the first six months of the year. About
$3.7 billion of that came in the second quarter, according to
Pfinsgraff, which caused the bank to post a $420 million trading
loss. </p>
<p>The biggest U.S. bank by assets is facing regulatory
scrutiny and criminal probes over losses in the Chief Investment
Office, which Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon pushed in
recent years to make bigger and riskier bets with the bank''s
money. The loss, which Dimon said stemmed from positions that
were poorly monitored, prompted calls from Congress for
tighter bank regulation and triggered criminal investigations by
the U.S. Department of Justice and Federal Bureau of
Investigation. </p>
<p>The trades in question, made by a CIO group that included
Bruno Iksil, nicknamed the London Whale because his positions
grew so large, were on portions of credit-swap indexes, people
familiar with the transactions have said. Tranches allow
investors to wager on varying degrees of risk among a pool of
companies. Credit swaps pay the buyer face value if a borrower
fails to meet its obligations, less the value of the defaulted
debt. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Sep 21, 2012 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-21/microsoft-deploys-college-kid-cool-in-windows-8-apps-race-tech.html"><headline>Microsoft Deploys College-Kid Cool in Windows 8 Apps Race: Tech</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) is forging a future
in tablets with students like Joe Shapiro, a computer science
major who had never crafted applications for the company''s
Windows software until he won an internship to try it out. </p>
<p>Shapiro, a senior at Brown University, spent the summer in
the Foundry paid internship program at Microsoft''s New England
Research  Development Center, known as NERD. He helped build a
commuter-transit app, Catch It, that should be available for
download later this month in the online store for Windows 8, the
new tablet-friendly version of Microsoft''s flagship operating
system. And, crucial to Microsoft''s ambitions, he plans to make
more apps. </p>
<p>Microsoft, the world''s largest software maker, designed
Windows 8 for touch-screen technology included in the company''s
first tablet, Surface, and other devices coming this year. To
gain share in tablets, a market expected by DisplaySearch to
reach $66.4 billion in 2012, Microsoft needs enough apps to
challenge the more than 200,000 available for Apple Inc. (AAPL)''s iPad. </p>
<p>The apps ecosystem is probably the single most important
factor in a customer''s experience, said Al Hilwa, an analyst
at market researcher IDC. It dictates what books you read,
what music you listen to, what movies you see, what social
activities you take part in. Problem is, you can''t have half a
million apps overnight. </p>
<p>Interns, also deployed to write prototype apps for the
Windows 8 preview last year, produced six apps through Foundry,
generating enough interest among computer science students for
the company to make the pilot program permanent. Using student
recruits is one way Microsoft can woo app developers who are
used to building programs for mobile phones and tablets, where
the company has little and no share, respectively. </p>
<h2>College Struggle'' </h2>
<p>Microsoft has struggled to get college kids interested in
developing for Windows, said Wes Miller, an analyst at
Directions on Microsoft, who is based in Kirkland, Washington. </p>
<p>Luring programmers before graduation is particularly
critical for recruitment in the U.S., which lags behind
countries such as India and China in its ability to crank out
qualified engineers. The U.S. ranks 23rd among developed nations
in the percentage of students with undergraduate degrees in
science or engineering who are employed in related fields, the
Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development reported
last year. The report analyzed employment trends for people age
25 to 34. </p>
<p>Like their counterparts already in the workforce, student
developers have focused programming efforts on apps for Apple''s
iOS software, which powers the iPad, and Google Inc. (GOOG)''s Android
operating system, used in an array of handheld devices,
including Amazon.com Inc. (AMZN)''s Kindle. </p>
<p>Microsoft''s version of the Surface tablet that is most
comparable to the iPad won''t be able to run older Windows apps,
forcing developers to start from scratch. </p>
<h2>Playing Catch-Up'' </h2>
<p>Windows 8 is the first Microsoft operating system that will
work on computers running chips based on ARM Holdings Plc (ARM)
technology. These chips are widely used in mobile devices,
including the iPad. The ARM-based products will run only apps
designed specifically for the new version of Windows -- and none
of the programs already available for Microsoft software on
machines made for Intel Corp. (INTC)''s chips. </p>
<p>Microsoft is definitely playing catch-up with respect to
the global app marketplace, said David Hilal, an analyst at
FBR Capital Markets, in an interview. Their challenge is a
chicken-and-egg problem. They need to get more users for their
apps to entice developers, but they need better apps to attract
more users. </p>
<p>Enter NERD interns to help fill the void. This summer''s
group of 21 interns produced three apps already in the Windows
store, and two more that are expected to follow soon. </p>
<h2>Intern-Built </h2>
<p>One of the intern-built apps is Trackage, which enables
users to locate packages shipped by FedEx Corp. (FDX), United Parcel
Service Inc. (UPS), the U.S. Postal Service and LaserShip Inc. using a
single app rather than having to go to each service''s website
separately. Another, Never Late, is an alarm clock app. </p>
<p>Inkarus is a physics game in which users collect gears and
feathers to help a chubby penguin build a flying machine that
must steer clear of things like antigravity fields and
rainstorms. </p>
<p>The NERD building, located in Cambridge''s Kendall Square,
lets Microsoft maintain a base near the Massachusetts Institute
of Technology and Harvard University as well as offices
belonging to Google, VMware Inc. (VMW) and other biotechnology and
venture capital firms. </p>
<p>Parts of the facility, which also houses a research lab and
some of Microsoft''s Office employees, was designed by Ray Ozzie,
former chief technology officer at the company. Intern desks
have stunning views of the Charles River. Walls are adorned with
banners from an advertising campaign Microsoft ran in places
such as Boston''s subway, with lines like Softwayah -- or
software pronounced with a Boston accent. </p>
<h2>Shapiro''s App </h2>
<p>The app that Shapiro and two other students built for
Boston public transit may be available in Microsoft''s online
store by the end of the month. Shapiro, now well-versed in
Microsoft''s C# programming language, wants to make more. </p>
<p>I''m a completely C# convert now, Shapiro said. I
never want to go back. </p>
<p>Another intern-made app, FaceReel, also awaits approval. It
uses facial-recognition software to generate videos out of a set
of images -- think of it as a way to create a birthday or 50th-
anniversary video without all the complicated editing or
PowerPoint work. </p>
<p>FaceReel was made by a team that included Jancarlo Perez
and Jasmine Huynh, students at MIT who, like Shapiro, hadn''t
worked on apps for Windows prior to the internship. They, too,
plan to develop Windows apps again. </p>
<p>Perez described the Windows 8 development environment as
fast and fluid, echoing the oft-repeated phrase Microsoft
executives have used to describe the program. </p>
<h2>App Exposure </h2>
<p>NERD interns who later opt for a career making apps for
Microsoft may find it''s easier to get exposure for their work
because the field isn''t as crowded as it is for apps built for
Apple or Google operating systems, said Hilal, the FBR analyst. </p>
<p>As an app developer, you take a little bit of a leap of
faith today with Microsoft, Hilal said. You can get a lot of
downloads with Apple, but there''s a lot of competition. </p>
<p>Beyond fostering a desire to work at Microsoft, NERD aims
to create a devoted group of Windows 8 converts who will spread
their enthusiasm among fellow computer science majors and design
students. </p>
<p>Because Windows 8 is pre-release, it''s been so exciting
to get my hands on it before other people have been able to,
said Emily Lin, a media arts and sciences major at Wellesley
College, who served as the designer on the Catch It team. When
I tell my friends, they say, That''s so cool that you are
getting to develop on Windows 8.''  </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Zijing Wu" date="Sep 24, 2012 12:12 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-24/morgan-stanley-said-to-drop-out-of-asiacell-s-iraqi-ipo.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Said No Longer Bookrunner of Asiacell IPO</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) is no longer a
bookrunner for the initial public offering of Asiacell, the
Iraqi telecom operator majority-owned by Qatar Telecom QSC (QTEL), said
three people with knowledge of the discussions. </p>
<p>While Morgan Stanley is still an adviser on the deal, the
U.S. bank will not manage Asiacell''s share sale because it
doesn''t have a client base inside Iraq, where most of the demand
for this IPO is expected, said one of the people. </p>
<p>New York-based Morgan Stanley was originally hired with
HSBC Holdings Plc (HSBA) as managers for the IPO, which may happen as
early as next month, said two of the people, who asked not to be
identified because the plans are private. The IPO of Asiacell,
Iraq''s first mobile phone operator, could raise as much as $1
billion with the sale of a 25 percent stake in the company,
making it the biggest ever in the country, the people said. </p>
<p>Rabee Securities, a Baghdad-based brokerage, is also
managing Asiacell''s IPO. </p>
<h2>Doubled Stake </h2>
<p>Doha-based Qatar Telecom, known as Qtel, agreed this year
to double its stake in the Iraqi mobile operator Asiacell to 60
percent for $1.47 billion. Qtel, which owns stakes in companies
from Tunisia to Indonesia, has sought to grow outside its home
market, where it faces rising competition from Vodafone Qatar. (VFQS) </p>
<p>A London-based official at Morgan Stanley declined to
comment, as did a Qtel spokesman. </p>
<p>The IPO, if successful, could double the market
capitalization of the Iraq Stock Exchange, which is about $4
billion, according to the Baghdad-based bourse. </p>
<p>Asiacell has about 9.5 million users, Qtel''s Chief
Executive Officer Nasser Marafih said in June. </p>
<p>Zain Iraq, Asiacell''s main competitor and a unit of
Kuwait''s Mobile Telecommunication Co. (ZAIN), plans to go public in
Iraq this year as well, the parent company''s former chief
executive officer, Emad Makiya, said in April. Makiya stepped
down last month. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Claudia Carpenter" date="Sep 24, 2012  5:57 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-24/goldman-sachs-forecasts-18-2-return-on-commodities-in-12-months.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Forecasts 18.2% Return on Commodities in Year</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. forecasts
an 18.2 percent return from commodities in the next 12 months,
with energy and industrial metals leading the way. </p>
<p>The Standard  Poor''s GSCI Enhanced Commodity Index gain
will include 26.5 percent for energy, 10 percent for industrial
metals and 6 percent for precious metals, Jeffrey Currie, an
analyst at Goldman Sachs, said in a Sept. 21 report. In three
months, the gauge will be up 8.6 percent, beating equities, 10-
year government and five-year corporate bonds, cash and the euro
and yen against the dollar, according to the report. </p>
<p>Apart from being attractive in its own right, we also
continue to see an overweight in commodities as a hedge against
the risk of the impact of sharply higher commodity prices on
economic growth and other asset classes, if oil supplies were to
disappoint against a backdrop of very limited spare capacity,
Currie said. </p>
<p>The SP GSCI Enhanced gauge advanced 19 percent since June
21 on speculation that China will act to bolster its economy
after the U.S., Japan and the European Central Bank took steps
to boost growth. Copper prices will be higher in the first half
of 2013 on growth in China''s construction and the third round of
quantitative easing by the Federal Reserve, Currie said. </p>
<h2>Iran Sanction </h2>
<p>Sanctions against Iran have limited oil supplies and global
economic growth is strong enough that overall output may stay
short of demand in the second half this year, according to
Goldman. Oil in New York climbed 14 percent in the past year. </p>
<p>The 18.2 percent return for the GSCI in 12 months would lag
behind a 32.8 percent jump forecast for the Tokyo Stock Exchange
Topix and 25.5 percent jump in Stoxx equity index, according to
the report. The SP 500 Index of shares will be down 10.4
percent in three months and 5.4 percent lower in a year, Goldman
Sachs said. </p>
<p>In commodities, agriculture will be down 5 percent in 12
months and livestock up 4.5 percent, Goldman Sachs said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tiffany Kary" date="Sep 25, 2012  4:08 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-25/visa-mastercard-swipe-deal-faces-restaurants-opposition.html"><headline>Visa, MasterCard Swipe Deal Faces Restaurants'' Opposition</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The National Restaurant Association
said it will reject a proposed settlement of as much as $7.25
billion with Visa Inc. (V) and MasterCard Inc. (MA) over the fees they
charge stores when customers pay with credit cards. </p>
<p>The settlement won''t change a broken system on how the so-
called swipe fees are set, the association said in a statement
today. </p>
<p>Without meaningful reform, there is concern that
restaurateurs -- many of whom are small businesses -- will
continue to be negatively impacted by the unfair, non-
transparent system that exists today, Dawn Sweeney, the
Washington-based industry group''s president, said in the
statement. </p>
<p>The settlement announced July 13 still needs approval by a
federal judge. It would put to rest about seven years of
litigation over claims that San Francisco-based Visa and
Purchase, New York-based MasterCard conspired to fix fees. The
accord calls for a temporary reduction in rates for merchants
and would allow them to impose surcharges on customer purchases. </p>
<p>The restaurant association joins the National Retail
Federation, which represents more than 9,000 retailers, in
opposing the settlement. The retailer association said on Sept.
11 that the proposed agreement does nothing to prevent Visa and
MasterCard from raising swipe fees in the future. </p>
<p>A case-management conference is scheduled for Sept. 27 in
federal court in Brooklyn, New York. </p>
<p>The case is In re Payment Card Interchange Fee and Merchant
Discount Antitrust Litigation, 05-md-01720, U.S. District Court,
Eastern District of New York (Brooklyn). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Sep 25, 2012  9:17 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-25/morgan-stanley-drops-smith-barney-name-from-brokerage.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Drops Smith Barney Name From Brokerage</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) dropped the Smith
Barney name from its brokerage joint venture, changing the brand
to Morgan Stanley Wealth Management after buying an additional
piece of the unit from Citigroup Inc. (C) </p>
<p>The name change comes three years after the joint venture
was formed and two months after Morgan Stanley completed the
integration of the two units, the New York-based firm said today
in a statement. Morgan Stanley Chief Executive Officer James Gorman said in June that the name would be changed. </p>
<p>The Smith Barney name stood for investment excellence for
three-quarters of a century, and Morgan Stanley Wealth
Management will provide the first-class service that has
distinguished Morgan Stanley as a firm for more than 75 years,
Gorman said in the statement. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lisa Abramowicz" date="Sep 25, 2012  8:57 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-25/morgan-stanley-recommends-investors-reduce-junk-bond-holdings.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Recommends Investors Reduce Junk Bond Holdings</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Investors should reduce their
holdings of speculative-grade bonds going into the last three
months of the year as yields on the notes hover near record
lows, according to Morgan Stanley. (MS) </p>
<p>Risk/reward for the asset class is less attractive today
than at any other point this year, analysts Adam Richmond and
Jason Ng wrote in a report dated today. The main driver of our
downgrade is unattractive total return prospects going
forward. </p>
<p>Junk-debt funds recorded $3.63 billion of deposits in the
week ended Sept. 19, the second-biggest volume ever, according
to data compiled by EPFR Global, as the Federal Reserve said it
expected to hold its target rate near zero for at least another
three years. Yields on speculative-grade bonds in the U.S. fell
to an unprecedented 6.95 percent on Sept. 19, according to Bank
of America Merrill Lynch index data. </p>
<p>Though spreads could tighten further, especially if rates
rise, we think dollar prices are topping out, the Morgan
Stanley analysts wrote. Also, weaker economic data is putting
pressure on the credit quality of speculative-grade borrowers,
according to the analysts. </p>
<p>High-yield, high-risk bonds, graded below Baa3 by Moody''s
Investors Service and lower than BBB- at Standard  Poor''s, have
gained 12.5 percent this year, Bank of America Merrill Lynch
data show. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Mark Drajem" date="Sep 25, 2012 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-25/chevron-under-epa-probe-for-avoiding-refinery-monitors-in-2009.html"><headline>Chevron Under EPA Probe for Avoiding Refinery Monitors in 2009</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX), which paid $170,000
to settle California pollution allegations at a refinery, may
face more penalties including prison sentences for employees
stemming from a federal investigation of the case. </p>
<p>The Environmental Protection Agency is investigating
actions at the company''s Richmond, California, refinery after
local officials in 2009 determined that pollution controls were
bypassed, according to company and local officials. </p>
<p>The Bay Area Air Quality Management District, which
enforces air-pollution rules in nine counties near San
Francisco, discovered Chevron employees routed gas emissions
around monitoring equipment then burned off the excess,
violating local rules. The agency forced the company to end the
practice it said was used at least 27 times in four years, said
Wayne Kino, the district''s enforcement manager. Chevron paid a
$170,000 penalty to settle the agency''s civil case. </p>
<p>It now appears that EPA has chosen to take that case as
a criminal prosecution, Kino said yesterday in an interview.
There are indications that they are investigating, but they
don''t talk about it. </p>
<p>A flaring system is used in emergencies to eliminate gases
that could be increasing to dangerous levels, Kino said.
Refineries had been flaring gas for routine maintenance before
the local air quality board imposed standards in 2004, he said. </p>
<p>A criminal prosecution might mean further fines or even
jail time for employees involved at the Richmond refinery. A
total of 249 individuals or companies were charged last year
after an EPA criminal investigation. Agency prosecutions last
year resulted in sending violators to prison for 89.5 years and
fines of $35 million. </p>
<h2>Currently Cooperating'' </h2>
<p>The EPA doesn''t comment on pending investigations, Alisha
Johnson, a spokeswoman for the agency, said in an e-mail. </p>
<p>We are currently cooperating with the government''s
investigation, Sean Comey, a Chevron spokesman, said in an e-
mail. The company estimates total emissions identified by the
state agency at about 200 pounds of sulfur dioxide, compared
with total sulfur-dioxide emissions in the Bay Area of 25
million pounds annually. </p>
<p>This was certainly not done intentionally, Comey said
yesterday during a news conference at the refinery called to
discuss an unrelated Aug. 6 fire there. Safety and protecting
people and the environment is one of our core values as a
company and we take that responsibility very seriously. </p>
<p>The refinery resolved the issue three years ago  by
rerouting a pipe through a metered system, Nigel Hearne, manager
of the Richmond plant, said during the news conference. He
described the pipe as an equalization line that helps
control pressure buildup at the refinery. </p>
<p>The August fire injured five workers and forced the company
to shut a unit at the Richmond plant. </p>
<p>Chevron said yesterday that it suspects that a
phenomenon known as sulfidation corrosion caused a pipe to
rupture and led to the fire. The refinery is inspecting all
similar pipes and has found at least one that must be replaced,
Hearne said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Drew Armstrong" date="Sep 26, 2012  5:48 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-26/pfizer-bristol-myers-to-get-march-fda-ruling-on-eliquis-drug.html"><headline>Pfizer, Bristol-Myers to Get March FDA Ruling on Eliquis Drug</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE), the world''s largest
drugmaker, and Bristol-Myers Squibb Co. (BMY) may have to wait until
March for word on whether their experimental blood thinner
Eliquis passes U.S. regulatory scrutiny. </p>
<p>The pill was rejected by the Food and Drug Administration
in June after the agency said it needed more information from
the companies'' existing trials. The two New York-based companies
said in a statement today they had given the FDA all the data
requested and were assigned a target decision date of March 17. </p>
<p>Revenue from Eliquis has the potential to peak at $4.7
billion if approved, Catherine Arnold, an analyst with Credit
Suisse Group AG in New York, estimated in a note this month. The
pill, which could replace the drug Warfarin as the standard of
care, would also help make up for sales that the companies have
lost from their own top-selling blockbusters. </p>
<p>Pfizer''s Lipitor and Bristol-Myers''s Plavix lost patent
protection within the past 12 months and now face generic
competition. </p>
<p>Johnson  Johnson (JNJ), based in New Brunswick, New Jersey, and
Leverkusen, Germany-based Bayer AG (BAYN) have a competing pill
Xarelto, as does Boehringer Ingelheim GmbH, of Ingelheim,
Germany. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Brian Chappatta" date="Sep 27, 2012 12:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-27/morgan-stanley-sees-sales-surge-fueling-worst-month-muni-credit.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Sees Sales Surge Fueling Worst Month: Muni Credit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The $3.7 trillion municipal-bond
market is heading for its worst monthly performance since June.
If the past decade is any guide, October may be even worse. </p>
<p>Munis on average have lost 0.41 percent in October since
2001, the biggest decline for any month, Bank of America Merrill
Lynch indexes show. This month, local-government bonds have
gained about 0.21 percent, the least since they lost 0.07
percent in June. </p>
<p>With muni mutual funds adding the fewest assets since April
and localities issuing the most debt in three months, that trend
is poised to continue, said John Dillon, chief municipal-bond
strategist at Morgan Stanley Smith Barney in Purchase, New York.
States and cities that end their fiscal years June 30 tend to
wait a few months before coming to market, which may account for
the sales surge, he said. </p>
<p>We are on the tail end of robust demand, and we are at
the front end of a step-up in supply, said Dillon, whose
company oversees more than $150 billion in local debt. There''s
this supply-demand imbalance that''s opposite what you had in
June, July and August. It''s a seasonal trend reversal. </p>
<p>The tax-exempt market has returned 6.2 percent this year as
investors sought a haven from Europe''s debt crisis. The gain is
more than triple that of Treasuries, which have returned 2
percent, Bank of America data show. That''s the biggest
differential for the period since 2009. </p>
<h2>October Flood </h2>
<p>In the three months beginning July 1, the muni market has
returned about 2 percent, the data show. That''s the seventh-
straight quarter of gains, the longest stretch since 2001. </p>
<p>The rally is poised to pause in October, the month with the
most local-government sales for the past three years, data
compiled by Bloomberg show. The New York State Dormitory
Authority and Kansas State Department of Transportation are
among issuers planning deals next month, Bloomberg data show. </p>
<p>The jump in supply caused yields on top-rated general-
obligation bonds, which move inversely to prices, to rise in
eight of the past 10 Octobers, Bloomberg data show. Such
predictable patterns cause buyers to wait to invest, said Peter Hayes, head of muni bonds at New York-based BlackRock Inc., the
world''s biggest money manager. </p>
<p>If you look historically at price performance in October,
you can see the market exhibits some seasonal weakness, said
Hayes, whose company oversees about $106 billion of munis. If
you have cash and bonds coming due, you just sit on it a little
bit longer and wait for the market to adjust. </p>
<h2>Fund Flows </h2>
<p>That mindset may be behind the slowing of cash flowing into
municipal-bond mutual funds. They added about $256 million in
assets during the week ended Sept. 19, the fewest since April,
Lipper US Fund Flows data show. Inflows this year total $23
billion, the most since 2009. </p>
<p>The drop in demand comes as issuers are selling $9.3
billion this week, the most in three months, Bloomberg data
show. In the week ended Sept. 21, municipalities issued $9.1
billion of debt. </p>
<p>Municipalities have sold about $257.5 billion in debt this
year, close to the $258 billion issued in all of 2011, Bloomberg
data show. About 51 percent has been to retire previously issued
debt, which has helped create net negative supply, or when
cash to investors from redemptions and refunding exceeds sales. </p>
<p>That phenomenon will reverse in September and October, when
new debt may exceed maturing securities and bond calls by about
$27 billion, the most for a two-month period since December
2010, according to Citigroup Inc. data. </p>
<h2>Tax Exemption </h2>
<p>The U.S. presidential election and potential changes to the
municipal-bond tax exemption may heighten the trend of
localities issuing debt next month, Dillon said. In October
2010, three months before the expiration of the Build America
Bonds program, states and cities sold $54 billion, the most
since at least 2003 and more than any month since. </p>
<p>Muni yields heading into October are hovering near record
lows. The interest rate on 10-year benchmark AAA munis was 1.76
percent yesterday. It fell to 1.63 percent on July 27, the
lowest since at least January 2009, Bloomberg data show. </p>
<p>The yield on that debt rose 0.28 percentage point in
October 2011. That was the biggest jump since October 2009, when
interest rates rose 0.49 percentage point, Bloomberg data show. </p>
<p>Last year, the interest rate plunged 0.62 percentage point
in November and December, sending rates near the lowest since
Lyndon Johnson was president. </p>
<p>Yields have fallen awfully far and awfully fast, Hayes
said. Any time they rise, it does create a better opportunity,
and that''s what we''re looking forward to. </p>
<p>Following are pending sales: </p>
<p>MINNESOTA OFFICE OF HIGHER EDUCATION is set to issue $375
million of revenue debt as soon as next week, according to the
preliminary official statement. Standard  Poor''s rates the
bonds AA-, fourth-highest. (Added Sept. 27) </p>
<p>NORTH TEXAS TOLLWAY AUTHORITY plans to sell about $136
million in revenue bonds as soon as next week for refunding,
according to an offering document. Moody''s Investors Service
rates the debt A2, sixth-highest. (Added Sept. 27) </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Carla Main" date="Sep 28, 2012  8:13 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-28/goldman-pay-to-play-libor-probe-u-a-e-bank-compliance.html"><headline>Goldman Pay-to-Play, Libor Probe, U.A.E. Bank: Compliance</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) will pay
$14.4 million to resolve regulatory claims that a former banker
made improper campaign contributions to the treasurer of
Massachusetts while seeking underwriting business. </p>
<p>Neil Morrison, who was a vice president in Goldman Sachs''s
Boston office, worked for Treasurer Timothy P. Cahill''s
unsuccessful gubernatorial campaign from November 2008 to
October 2010, sometimes during his office hours, the U.S.
Securities and Exchange Commission said in a statement
yesterday. That constituted in-kind contributions and broke pay-
to-play rules, the SEC said. </p>
<p>The settlement, which includes $4.6 million paid to
Massachusetts, is the SEC''s first involving noncash
contributions and is the latest since the agency began
bolstering oversight of the $3.7 trillion municipal-bond market
in 2010. At that time, SEC Enforcement Director Robert Khuzami
set up a task force to investigate bid-rigging for municipal-
investment contracts. The agency is looking into banks, local
governments that don''t disclose their true financial condition,
and public officials who hire advisers based on political
contributions. </p>
<p>The campaign work by Morrison, 38, disqualified Goldman
Sachs from underwriting bonds for Massachusetts and its agencies
for two years after the contributions, the SEC said.
Nevertheless, the New York-based firm participated in 30
prohibited underwritings, earning more than $7.5 million in
improper fees, according to the agency. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs didn''t admit or deny wrongdoing. A telephone
call to Thomas Kiley, Morrison''s lawyer, wasn''t immediately
returned. </p>
<p>For more, click here. </p>
<h2>Compliance Policy </h2>
<h2>FSA to Oversee Libor in Streamlining of Tarnished Benchmark </h2>
<p>Oversight of Libor will be handed to the U.K.''s financial
regulator, and dozens of the currencies and maturities that make
up the benchmark axed, under proposals designed to revive
confidence in a rate tarnished by scandal. </p>
<p>The British Bankers'' Association should be stripped of the
responsibility for managing the rate and other organizations
invited to replace it, Financial Services Authority Managing
Director Martin Wheatley said in London today. More than 100
Libor rates tied to currencies and maturities where there isn''t
enough trading data to set them properly should be scrapped, and
a code of conduct introduced for how lenders contribute to the
benchmark backed by criminal penalties, he added. </p>
<p>Wheatley began his review at the request of Chancellor of
the Exchequer George Osborne after Barclays Plc (BARC), Britain''s
second-biggest lender, paid a record 290 million-pound
($470 million) fine in June for manipulating the London
interbank offered rate, used to set rates for more than
$300 trillion of securities. </p>
<p>The FSA should receive greater powers to vet bankers who
contribute to the rate, according to Wheatley, who will become
the chief executive officer of the Financial Conduct Authority
when the FSA splits into two agencies next year. </p>
<p>He stopped short of advocating scrapping Libor, saying that
would be too disruptive to borrowers whose existing contracts
reference the rate. </p>
<p>Separately, Financial Secretary to the Treasury Greg Clark
said the U.K. government will move at the maximum possible
pace to implement a proposed overhaul of the oversight of
Libor and will give a formal response in the week beginning Oct.
15. </p>
<p>For more, click here and click here. </p>
<h2>APRA Releases Final Basel III Capital Reform Package </h2>
<p>The Australian Prudential Regulation Authority commented in
a statement on its website about the key features to be included
in a new definition of regulatory capital, under which common
equity is the predominant form of Tier 1 capital. </p>
<p>Under the new definition, common equity Tier 1 capital must
be at least 4.5 percent of risk-weighted assets and the Tier 1
capital ratio at least 6 percent, according to the statement. </p>
<p>A new 2.5 percent capital conservation buffer will place
constraints on capital distributions, the authority said. In
addition, a countercyclical buffer of as much as 2.5 percent
will apply when excessive credit growth points to a system-wide
build-up of risk, the authority said in the statement. </p>
<p>Authority Chairman John Laker said reforms will lead to a
stronger Australian banking system, as well as make banks well
placed to meet Basel III timetable. </p>
<h2>Network Operators Submit Power-Trading Rules to EU Regulators </h2>
<p>European electricity-network operators submitted rules for
power trading that will help the bloc to achieve its goal of a
single market by 2014 to European Union regulators. </p>
<p>The capacity-allocation and congestion-management code
contains rules for day-ahead and intraday markets and the
calculation of capacity as well as defining bidding zones,
Entsoe, a Brussels-based body that represents national
operators, said yesterday in an e-mailed statement. </p>
<p>The Agency for the Cooperation of Energy Regulators has
three months to assess the code and if approved, it will become
law, Entsoe said. </p>
<h2>Compliance Action </h2>
<h2>SEC Issues Report to Help Brokers Safeguard Confidential Info </h2>
<p>The U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission issued a staff
report for broker-dealers to help them determine the
effectiveness of their controls over sensitive information, the
SEC said in e-mailed statement. </p>
<p>The Report by the Office of Compliance Inspections and
Examinations addresses the prevention of insider trading and
details appropriate controls over matters such as e-mail,
information given to external parties, and disposal of
confidential documents. </p>
<p>The report also describes various methods that broker-
dealers use to manage conflicts. </p>
<h2>U.S. Criminal Libor Probe Said to Seek London Trader Interviews </h2>
<p>U.S. investigators conducting a criminal probe of interest-
rate manipulation have asked their British counterparts for
permission to interview London traders, two people familiar with
the investigation said. </p>
<p>The U.S. Justice Department filed a request with the U.K.
Home Office for access to dozens of bankers in conjunction with
British prosecutors who are also investigating the rate rigging,
said one of the people, who declined to be identified because
the proceedings haven''t been made public. </p>
<p>The move may indicate the U.S. wants to pursue criminal
charges against individuals in the U.K. that may lead to
extradition, said Bradley Simon, a former federal prosecutor in
Brooklyn, New York. </p>
<p>Regulators from Tokyo to London to New York are probing how
derivatives traders and bankers who submitted interest-rate data
colluded to rig benchmarks including the London Interbank
Offered Rate. Royal Bank of Scotland Group Plc, UBS AG (UBSN) and
Deutsche Bank AG (DBK) are among lenders awaiting information about
their fate. The Justice Department''s criminal probe is running
in parallel with civil investigations being conducted by its
fraud division, the U.S. Commodity Futures Trading Commission
and the U.K. Financial Services Authority. </p>
<p>The U.K. Serious Fraud Office opened its criminal case in
July at the request of British politicians after Barclays Plc
was fined a record 290 million pounds ($470 million) for rate
manipulation. The agency previously declined to get involved in
the case, according to the FSA. Barclays Chief Executive Officer
Robert Diamond and Chairman Marcus Agius resigned following the
fine. </p>
<p>A Home Office spokesman declined to comment on any
cooperation request. A spokesperson for the U.S. Justice
Department didn''t immediately respond to a request seeking
comment on cooperation with U.K. authorities. </p>
<h2>Blocking Identity Theft Is U.S. Goal Ahead of Tax Filing </h2>
<p>The U.S. Justice Department and the Internal Revenue
Service are working to head off identity theft aimed at stealing
people''s tax refunds when the filing season begins in January,
the government''s top tax prosecutor said. </p>
<p>The Justice Department will draw information from local
prosecutions to identify patterns in the cases and help the IRS
create computerized filters to block potentially fraudulent
refunds. They peak each year in the first few weeks of the
filing season as criminals try to get refunds under legitimate
taxpayers'' names before those people file their own returns. </p>
<p>In a typical case, criminals steal or illegally purchase
taxpayers'' identifying information from hospitals, medical
offices, prisons and other places that have the data. They then
file false tax returns, claim a refund and have the money
deposited on a prepaid debit card. </p>
<p>In a Sept. 15 speech in Boston, IRS Commissioner Douglas
Shulman said his agency this year stopped more than 3 million
tax returns and determined that 90 percent of them were bad. </p>
<h2>CFTC Orders ANZ to Pay $350,000 for Violating Position Limits </h2>
<p>The Commodity Futures Trading Commission ordered Australia
 New Zealand Banking Group Ltd. (ANZ) to pay $350,000 for exceeding
speculative-position limits in wheat and cotton futures traded
on the Chicago Board of Trade and ICE Futures U.S. in New York. </p>
<p>The bank violated CBOT wheat limits in August 2010, and
held a net-short position that was greater than allowed for ICE
cotton contracts in February 2011, the CFTC said in a statement
yesterday. </p>
<h2>BofA Expects U.A.E. Central Bank to Extend New Lending Rules </h2>
<p>The United Arab Emirates'' central bank may extend a
deadline by six months for banks to comply with new rules that
limit lending to governments and their entities, Bank of America
Corp.''s Merrill Lynch unit said. </p>
<p>The U.A.E. central bank said April 4 that banks in the
U.A.E. must not lend more than 100 percent of their capital to
local governments and the same to government-related entities
known as GREs to help reduce risk. Banks had until Sept. 30 to
comply. There was no limit under previous rules. </p>
<p>The U.A.E. central bank is holding separate discussions
with each bank about the rules, a spokesman for Emirates NBD
PJSC (EMIRATES), who declined to be identified because of company policy,
said. The Emirates Banks Association, a body representing U.A.E.
banks, led discussions with the central bank earlier, although
talks are being held separately with each bank about the rules
because of differences with each bank''s portfolio, he said. </p>
<p>The exposure of Emirates NBD PJSC, the U.A.E.''s biggest
bank by assets, to sovereign and quasi-sovereign clients is 192
percent of regulatory capital, while that of National Bank of
Abu Dhabi PJSC and Abu Dhabi Commercial Bank PJSC (ADCB), the second-
and third-biggest U.A.E. lenders, are 199 percent and 108
percent, according to Deutsche Bank AG estimates in April. </p>
<h2>SEC Review Finds Gaps on Insider Trading at U.S. Broker-Dealers </h2>
<p>Traders at broker-dealers often interact with bankers who
know confidential information, raising concerns about undetected
insider trading, the U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission
said. </p>
<p>Senior executives at some broker-dealers are allowed access
to non-public information from one group while overseeing
employees who could benefit from it, the SEC''s Office of
Compliance Inspections and Examinations said yesterday in a
report. Allowing some supervisors to be above the wall
dividing traders from those with the information may facilitate
insider trading, according to the report, which didn''t name any
firms where such practices exist. </p>
<p>The SEC''s review of secrecy procedures at broker-dealers
follows a nationwide crackdown on insider trading by the Federal
Bureau of Investigation in New York and prosecutors in the
office of Manhattan U.S. Attorney Preet Bharara that began five
years ago. </p>
<h2>Courts </h2>
<h2>Ex-Credit Suisse CDO Boss Won''t Go to U.S. Before Plea Deal </h2>
<p>Kareem Serageldin, the ex-global head of Credit Suisse
Group AG (CSGN)''s CDO business charged in a bonus-boosting fraud tied
to a $5.35 billion trading book, will fight extradition to the
U.S. until he reaches a plea deal. </p>
<p>Serageldin''s lawyer told a London court yesterday that his
client''s arrest Sept. 26 outside the U.S. Embassy was a result
of miscommunication. Ben Brandon said Serageldin was
negotiating a plea bargain with U.S. prosecutors before the
arrest. He was released on a 150,000-pound ($243,000) security
until a Nov. 28 court hearing. </p>
<p>Serageldin has absolutely no intention of whatsoever of
fleeing, Brandon said yesterday. </p>
<p>Serageldin, a U.S. citizen who lives in England, was
charged in February with masterminding a scheme to fake
collateralized debt obligations. In February, when he was first
charged in Manhattan federal court, Serageldin said through his
lawyers that he was surprised since he had been cooperating with
U.S. investigators for four years. </p>
<p>Serageldin was named in an indictment unsealed in February
accusing him of conspiracy, falsification of books and records
and wire fraud. The conspiracy charge carries a maximum five-
year prison term on conviction. The other counts are punishable
by as many as 20 years. The case is being investigated by agents
of the Federal Bureau of Investigation in New York. </p>
<p>Judge Michael Snow, who said the allegations are very
serious, told Serageldin he must not leave his home between 11
p.m. and 6 a.m., and must wear an electronic tag. </p>
<p>Serageldin, who was born in Egypt, wants to renounce his
U.S citizenship and serve part of any sentence in the U.K.,
Brandon said. </p>
<p>The U.S. criminal cases are U.S. v. Higgs, 12-cr-00088, and
U.S. v. Siddiqui, 12-cr-00089, U.S. District Court, Southern
District of New York (Manhattan). The SEC case is U.S.
Securities and Exchange Commission v. Serageldin, 12-cv-00796,
U.S. District Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). </p>
<h2>Interviews </h2>
<h2>SEC''s Gallagher Calls for Floating Price for Money Funds </h2>
<p>U.S. Securities and Exchange Commission member Daniel
Gallagher, who helped derail efforts to tighten rules for money-
market mutual funds, said he would probably support a measure
forcing the industry to abandon its marquee $1 share price. </p>
<p>Requiring money funds to have a fluctuating share price
is an attractive option that I am likely to support,
Gallagher, a Republican, said in an interview. </p>
<p>The remarks may help revive the debate at the SEC and offer
a path toward compromise for SEC Chairman Mary Schapiro, whose
proposal ran aground last month. </p>
<p>Gallagher said he couldn''t vote for Schapiro''s plan because
its centerpiece was to make the funds hold extra capital. The
cushion was too small to protect investors, Gallagher said,
leading him to believe the money would be used as collateral in
case the funds needed to borrow from the Federal Reserve. </p>
<p>I could not be complicit in a rulemaking that purported
to eliminate bailouts but would actually do the opposite,
Gallagher said. </p>
<p>SEC spokeswoman Judith Burns declined to comment. </p>
<p>For more, click here. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Drew Armstrong" date="Sep 30, 2012  3:00 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-09-30/pfizer-lung-cancer-drug-doubles-benefit-researchers-say.html"><headline>Pfizer Lung Cancer Drug Doubles Benefit, Researchers Say</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE)''s lung-cancer medicine
Xalkori extended the lives of patients without their disease
worsening for twice as long as the standard therapies, according
to a study sponsored by the New York-based drugmaker. </p>
<p>In a trial of 347 previously treated patients whose non-
small lung cancer showed mutations in the gene known as ALK,
those given Pfizer''s Xalkori experienced progression-free
survival to 7.7 months, compared with 3 months for patients on
the other treatments, according to results presented today at
the European Society for Medical Oncology in Vienna. </p>
<p>The study is the first to compare Pfizer''s drug against the
standard of care, the chemotherapy drug docetaxel, made by
Sanofi (SAN) and now available in a generic version, and Eli Lilly 
Co. (LLY)''s Alimta, which generated $2.46 billion in sales last year.
The results suggest Xalkori should be the new standard as a
second-line therapy in patients whose non-small cell lung cancer
has mutations in the ALK gene, researchers said. </p>
<p>Xalkori''s results were many months longer than what
chemotherapy might afford, said Alice Shaw, a doctor at
Massachusetts General Hospital Cancer Center in Boston, and the
study''s lead author, in a telephone interview. The drug from
Pfizer, the world''s largest drugmaker, also showed improved
quality of life compared with the current therapy, she said. </p>
<p>Shaw said the study hadn''t determined the survival benefit,
because patients on the other drugs had been allowed to switch
to the Pfizer medicine during the trial. </p>
<p>This makes determination of overall survival benefit very
difficult, she said in a statement. It may take as much as a
year before researchers on the study, which is continuing, can
report that data. </p>
<h2>Top Killer </h2>
<p>Lung cancer is the top killer among malignancies in the
U.S. and is expected to cause about 160,000 deaths this year,
according to the National Cancer Institute. The Food and Drug
Administration approved Xalkori last August, along with a test
made by Abbott Laboratories (ABT) to determine whether patients carry
the mutation. </p>
<p>While the drug is approved as a first-line therapy for ALK-
positive patients in the U.S., European regulators want more
data on Xalkori as a first-line therapy and have ruled that it
should be used after patients fail other drugs first. </p>
<p>Most of us who work in this area feel pretty strongly
that if a patient has a known, targetable target like ALK, that
they should get it as a first-line therapy, Shaw said. </p>
<p>While the ALK mutation is present in just five percent of
non-small cell lung cancers, the most common form of the
malignancy, it''s a large absolute number, Shaw said in the
interview. Unlike other lung cancer patients, who are in their
mid-60s or 70s, ALK-positive patients are about 50 years old on
average and don''t have a history of smoking, she said. </p>
<p>Researchers still need to look at how to treat ALK-positive
patients who relapse after taking Pfizer''s drug. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry></news>