
<news><entry author="By Julie Johnsson" date="Dec 02, 2012 12:46 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-02/exxon-mobil-baton-rouge-refinery-pipeline-leak-releases-benzene.html"><headline>Exxon Mobil Baton Rouge Refinery Pipeline Leak Releases Benzene</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>About 10 pounds of benzene was
released by a pipeline leak at Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM)''s Baton Rouge
Refinery in Baton Rouge, Louisiana, according to a report made
to the National Response Center. </p>
<p>Atmospheric monitoring is being conducted at the site and
absorbent pads have been placed under the leak, according to the
report, which was taken at 2:08 p.m. yesterday. </p>
<p>U.S. refineries must notify the National Response Center if
they release hazardous substance in excess of reportable
quantities, according to the Comprehensive Environmental
Response, Compensation, and Liability Act, commonly known as
Superfund. </p>
<p>Bloomberg News couldn''t immediately verify the information
in the filing was accurate. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David McLaughlin" date="Dec 03, 2012  7:58 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-03/jpmorgan-gets-some-mass-foreclosure-claims-dismissed.html"><headline>JPMorgan, Citi Must Face Massachusetts Foreclosure Claims</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), Citigroup Inc. (CITI), and Wells Fargo  Co. (WFC) must face claims over home foreclosure practices in a lawsuit brought by the Massachusetts attorney general, a judge ruled. </p> <p>Allegations that the banks violated state law by conducting invalid foreclosures can proceed, according to a decision by Justice Judith Fabricant of Suffolk County Superior Court in Boston dated Nov. 30. </p> <p>Invalid foreclosures resulting in properties with clouded titles may have caused harm to third-party purchasers and the real estate market as a whole, and thereby to the public, Fabricant wrote. </p> <p>The three banks along with Bank of America Corp. and Ally Financial Inc. (ALLY)''s GMAC Mortgage were sued last year by Attorney General Martha Coakley. Coakley accused the lenders of using fraudulent documents in home foreclosures, foreclosing without legal authority, undermining public land records and misrepresenting loan-modification programs. </p> <p>Some of the claims in the lawsuit were settled as part of a $25 billion agreement between the banks and 49 states reached earlier this year. </p> <h2>Consumer Law </h2> <p>Coakley claimed the banks violated the state''s consumer protection law by initiating foreclosures on homes before holding the mortgage. Fabricant said that claim could move forward against the banks except Bank of America. The judge said the state didn''t identify any instance in which the bank conducted a foreclosure sale when it didn''t hold the mortgage, the judge said. </p> <p>Fabricant dismissed claims related to the registering of real estate records. </p> <p>Bank of America spokesman Lawrence Grayson said the Charlotte, North Carolina-based bank is pleased with the decision. Wells Fargo spokeswoman Vickee Adams said the San Francisco-based lender will continue to represent our point of view in the litigation. Danielle Romero-Apsilos, a spokeswoman for New York-based Citigroup, declined to comment. Representatives for GMAC and JPMorgan didn''t respond to requests seeking comment. </p> <p>Brad Puffer, a Coakley spokesman, said the office was reviewing the decision. </p> <p>The case is Commonwealth of Massachusetts v. Bank of America NA, 11-4363, Suffolk County Superior Court (Boston). </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass and Tom Keene" date="Dec 03, 2012  1:32 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-03/microsoft-analyst-sherlund-sees-no-growth-in-pc-market.html"><headline>Microsoft Analyst Sherlund Sees No Growth in PC Market</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The market for traditional personal
computers has no growth left because people are increasingly
using mobile devices to connect to the Web, said Rick Sherlund,
an analyst at Nomura Holdings Inc. covering Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) </p>
<p>As consumers shun personal computers in favor of
smartphones and tablets, the PC market will contract by 1.2
percent to 348.7 million units this year, according to IHS
ISuppli, the first annual decline since 2001. The recent debut
of Windows 8, the latest version of Microsoft''s flagship
operating system, hasn''t delivered a sales boost, according to
NPD Group Inc. </p>
<p>Windows 8 is off to a very rough start, not all the
hardware is out yet, not all the hardware vendors have done a
good job yet, Sherlund said today in a radio interview on
Bloomberg Surveillance with Tom Keene. </p>
<p>Sherlund recommends buying Microsoft shares, according to
data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft said last week that it
has sold 40 million software licenses since Windows 8, went on
sale on Oct. 26. Some of that tally includes versions shipped to
corporate customers with multiyear contracts, making it a poor
indicator of consumer demand. </p>
<p>NPD said U.S. retail sales of PCs running Windows have been
weak, with revenue declining 21 percent since the latest
software release, compared with the same period a year earlier. </p>
<h2>Surface Tablet </h2>
<p>The decrease has been fueled by a 24 percent drop in sales
of notebook computers as many customers opt for Apple Inc. (AAPL)''s
iPad or tablets powered by Google Inc. (GOOG)''s software instead of
Windows, NPD said. The report excluded Microsoft''s own stores,
where the company''s Surface tablet is sold. </p>
<p>People just don''t need PCs the way they used to,
Sherlund said. They''ve got alternatives now for accessing the
Internet. They''ve got smartphones and tablets, so there''s really
no growth left in the traditional PC market. </p>
<p>Microsoft said last week that it will charge a minimum of
$899 for its Surface Pro tablet, the version that has an Intel
Corp. (INTC) chip, and is targeted at corporate customers or those who
want to use older Windows programs. The high price has analysts
such as Wes Miller at Directions on Microsoft concerned it will
put off tablet shoppers. </p>
<p>In order to better compete with Apple and Google, Microsoft
is moving to a new software development system for Windows that
would involve issuing smaller, more frequent updates on more of
an annual cycle, according to people familiar with the matter.
The first such update is planned for next year. </p>
<p>It will take another quarter or two until Windows machines
with compelling features and prices to reach consumers, Sherlund
said in the interview. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Dec 04, 2012 10:06 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-04/morgan-stanley-s-cost-cuts-enough-to-reach-brokerage-goal.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley''s Cost Cuts Enough to Reach Brokerage Goal</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley''s wealth-management
business can reach profitability targets solely through cost
cuts, meaning revenue improvements may provide a further boost,
said Greg Fleming, president of the unit. </p>
<p>Integration expenses will end this quarter, allowing the
pretax profit margin to increase next year, said Fleming, who
last year laid out a goal of a mid-teens margin by the
middle of 2013. The brokerage is also trying to boost revenue
through more lending and moving additional client assets into
managed accounts, he said today at an investor conference in New
York. </p>
<p>Integration of the brokerage joint venture with Citigroup
Inc. (C) took longer than the firm expected and the business missed
the 15 percent profit target Morgan Stanley Chief Executive
Officer James Gorman had forecast for the end of 2010. The
margin was 13 percent in the third quarter, excluding one-time
items. Morgan Stanley (MS) plans to ask the Federal Reserve for
approval to buy Citigroup''s remaining 35 percent stake next
year, a person familiar with the strategy said in October. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley today also quantified the impact
improvements in the equity market would have on the New York-
based firm''s pretax profit. The brokerage''s pretax earnings
would climb $250 million if the Standard  Poor''s 500 Index (SPX) rose
to 1,600 from yesterday''s close of 1409.46, according to
Fleming''s presentation. Profit would jump $750 million if the
SP 500 increased to 2,000. The unit had pretax earnings of
$1.28 billion in 2011. </p>
<p>If the Fed raised its benchmark funds rate by 1.5
percentage points and Morgan Stanley acquired the rest of the
business from Citigroup, gaining access to $58 billion of
additional deposits, the unit''s pretax profit would climb $1.1
billion, according to the presentation. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Susan Decker" date="Dec 04, 2012 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-04/microsoft-google-patent-fight-rests-on-defining-fairness.html"><headline>Microsoft, Google Patent Fight Rests on Defining Fairness</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A federal judge''s ruling last week that Google Inc. (GOOG) can''t wield some patents to block the sale of Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) products may point toward resolution of a fundamental question underlying the global smartphone wars -- what constitutes a fair and reasonable royalty? </p> <p>In cases across the U.S. and Europe, Google, Microsoft and other companies are battling over the power of patents used in industrywide standards for technologies, such as Wi-Fi, that let competing products work together. Patent owners who help set those specifications pledge to license their inventions on fair, reasonable and non-discriminatory terms. </p> <p>No court has defined that concept, helping spark conflict when companies can''t agree on a fee. U.S. District Judge James Robart in Seattle may become the first. </p> <p>There is so much litigation going on trying to determine what a reasonable royalty is, said James Kulbaski, a patent lawyer with Oblon Spivak in Alexandria, Virginia. Everyone has agreed to pay it, but no one knows what it is. </p> <p>Robart ruled on Nov. 30 that, because Google''s Motorola Mobility had agreed to license its standard-essential patents, it was only entitled to seek fair royalties from Microsoft, not to ask the court to forbid sales of Microsoft products that use standards including those patents. The judge''s next step is to figure out what fees Microsoft should pay. </p> <p>That threshold question is bedeviling the U.S. Federal Trade Commission, the European Commission, the U.S. International Trade Commission and courts on four continents. While the concept of fair and reasonable royalties for essential technologies has been around for decades, the debate heated up with the global legal actions over smartphones and tablet computers. </p> <h2>Important Step'' </h2> <p>Somehow, this judge is going to have to define fair and reasonable, Kulbaski said. Defining what''s reasonable is a key question to all patents related to standards and will be an important step in future license negotiations. </p> <p>Google paid $12.5 billion to buy Motorola Mobility, an early pioneer in the mobile phone market, in part to get access to its patents on industry-standard technologies. The FTC, in a broad-ranging probe of Google, is looking at whether the Mountain View, California, company is improperly using those patents to stifle competition. </p> <p>Most of the patents in the smartphone wars don''t relate to industry standards. Still, defining fair and reasonable -- eliminating that contentious issue -- could be a springboard for resolving lawsuits over other patents. </p> <h2>Inefficient Litigation </h2> <p>The litigation we''re seeing, which is costing hundreds of millions, if not billions of dollars, is inefficient and it would be good to reduce the litigation if possible, said Jorge Contreras, an associate law professor at American University in Washington. </p> <p>When a company agrees to license its patents on fair terms, the patent holder has told the market that it does not need exclusivity and is willing to accept money in return, Contreras said. The only question is how much money it is owed, a question that the court should answer soon. </p> <p>Apple Inc. (AAPL), based in Cupertino, California, and Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft argue owners of standard-essential patents shouldn''t be able to obtain orders that block the use of inventions, a position backed by Robart''s decision. </p> <p>Limits on the patents could discourage companies from participating in groups that set specifications that make electronics work more efficiently, said Adam Mossoff, a George Mason University law professor. </p> <h2>Low-Cost Infringement </h2> <p>The people who are saying it''s a problem have dominated the public discourse to the point where everyone says there''s a problem, but the facts on the ground don''t support that, Mossoff said. The companies are using the legal system to get away with infringement at a lower cost. </p> <p>Mossoff said these types of disputes have been around for decades, and companies decide what''s fair without governmental intervention. </p> <p>There is zero evidence of any actual harm to consumers, Mossoff said. We all have our smartphones, tablets exist and there is amazing technology that comes out every week. </p> <p>Motorola Mobility contends it met its obligations and neither Microsoft nor Apple would bargain. The Libertyville, Illinois-based handset maker made an opening request for 2.25 percent of the retail price of Apple and Microsoft products, a figure both companies called exorbitant as they filed breach-of- contract claims. </p> <h2>Apple Suit </h2> <p>Apple''s case in Wisconsin was thrown out after the iPhone maker said it would agree to a court-determined royalty only if it was less than $1 per unit. Microsoft, which has agreed to pay a royalty rate set by Robart, has told the judge that an appropriate figure would be for pennies per unit, or less than $1 million a year. </p> <p>ITC Judge David Shaw is scheduled to hear arguments this week in a dispute between Motorola Mobility and Microsoft over some of the same patents that are involved in the Seattle federal-court lawsuit. </p> <p>The agency, which has the power to block U.S. imports of products that infringe American patents, is considering whether it should issue bans on products based on standard-essential patents in a case filed by Samsung Electronics Co. against Apple. At the same time, Samsung is accused by Ericsson AB of refusing to pay fair royalties on wireless standards. </p> <p>The Federal Trade Commission and members of Congress have argued that patent owners shouldn''t be able to use the threat of a U.S. import ban as a weapon in disagreements about royalty payments. </p> <h2>Standard Setting </h2> <p>The FTC has signaled it wants a greater role in determining what''s fair and reasonable. The agency, in a 3-2 decision Nov. 26, forced Robert Bosch GmBh to make standard-essential patents for air conditioners available to competitors as a condition for approving acquisition of the patent owner. </p> <p>The FTC is right to take a look at this because we don''t have any overarching group looking at the standard-setting organizations, said Robert Stoll of Drinker Biddle in Washington. The consumer is harmed if the other companies can''t use those standards. The purpose of fair and reasonable'' is to give everyone an even playing field. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ian King and Dina Bass" date="Dec 04, 2012 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-04/microsoft-intel-push-to-combat-apple-in-tablets-sputtering-tech.html"><headline>Microsoft-Intel Push to Rival Apple in Tablets Sputtering</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A push by Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) and Intel Corp. (INTC) to combat Apple Inc. (AAPL)''s iPad in the $63.2 billion tablet market is getting off to a slow start. </p> <p>Of more than a dozen tablets Microsoft and Intel touted for the new version of Windows, only five can be purchased for immediate U.S. delivery. Early demand for Microsoft''s first computer, the Surface tablet, seems disappointing, said Craig Berger, an analyst at FBR Capital Markets. And computer makers have been hampered in introducing tablets by limits Microsoft imposed on which manufacturers got a crack at prototypes, and by delays in Intel power-management software. </p> <p>The holdup is making it harder for personal-computer makers, already beleaguered by plummeting demand, to challenge Apple and Google Inc. (GOOG) during the year-end holiday shopping season. While PC variants running Windows abound, tablets built on ARM Holdings Plc (ARM) technology-based chips or low-power processors from Intel are scarce. </p> <p>You can hardly even find one, said Bob O''Donnell, an analyst at market researcher IDC in Framingham, Massachusetts. So even if you wanted to buy it, it would be difficult. </p> <p>The list of Windows tablets is short. In addition to Microsoft''s Surface, Asustek Computer Inc. (2357)''s Vivo Tab RT and Lenovo Group Ltd. (992)''s IdeaPad Yoga run the RT version of Windows and boast ARM-based chips. Samsung Electronics Co. (005930)''s ATIV Smart PC and Acer Inc. (2353)''s Iconia run Windows 8, and rely on Intel chips. </p>




Photographer: David Paul Morris/Bloomberg

<p>
Two of them, the Surface and the Acer device, are only available at Microsoft''s own stores, which number just more than 60 for the holidays. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Cliff Edwards and Christopher Palmeri" date="Dec 05, 2012  4:15 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-05/disney-s-netflix-deal-gives-top-billing-to-online-movies.html"><headline>Disney''s Netflix Deal Gives Top Billing to Online Movies</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Netflix Inc. (NFLX)''s deal with Walt Disney
Co. (DIS) to stream new releases, including those from Pixar and
Marvel, signals online viewing has become mainstream and poses a
major threat to traditional pay TV. </p>
<p>Starting in 2016, Netflix gains exclusive U.S. TV rights to
movies from Disney, the world''s largest entertainment company,
according to a statement yesterday. That gives the Los Gatos,
California-based video service new films in a time frame
historically reserved for premium channels like Liberty Media
Corp. (LMCA)''s Starz, as soon as seven months after theaters. </p>
<p>The accord underscores the shift away from a decades-old
model in which studios prospered by offering blockbuster films
to home viewers on DVD and premium cable channels such as Starz,
Disney''s current pay-TV partner. Subscription and on-demand
services are becoming an important source of revenue for studios
coping with shrinking DVD sales. Netflix, the online leader, is
now a competitor to Starz, HBO and Showtime. </p>
<p>This is a big win for Netflix, Jaison Blair, an analyst
with Telsey Advisory Group in New York, said in a telephone
interview. </p>
<p>Financial terms weren''t disclosed. Tony Wible, an analyst
at Janney Montgomery Scott LLC who follows both companies,
projects Netflix will pay Burbank, California-based Disney more
than $350 million a year. Barton Crockett, an analyst with
Lazard Capital Markets, estimated Disney gets about $200 million
a year now. </p>
<h2>Exclusive Programs </h2>
<p>Netflix gets immediate access to classic titles like
Alice in Wonderland and Dumbo. Next year, the service
adds direct-to-video titles, while new films start in 2016.
According to IMDB.com, Disney plans to release Marvel''s Dr.
Strange and Pixar''s Finding Nemo 2 that year. The studio
hasn''t announced any 2016 pictures. </p>
<p>The deal is a coup for Netflix Chief Executive Officer Reed Hastings, who faces emerging competition in online video and
pressure to sell the company from billionaire Carl Icahn. He
said last month he expects Icahn, who controls almost 10 percent
of the company through stock and options, to start a proxy
battle. </p>
<p>Hastings has been pushing to make Netflix available around
the world, arguing people will pay for near-instant access to
content online instead of scheduled TV on premium outlets such
as Time Warner Inc. (TWX)''s HBO or CBS Corp. (CBS)''s Showtime. </p>
<p>The agreement highlights efforts by Ted Sarandos, the chief
content officer at Netflix, to obtain exclusive rights to films
in the same pay-TV time frame as HBO, Showtime and Starz, or
about seven months to a year after theaters. </p>
<h2>Sony Rights </h2>
<p>Netflix beat out several competitors for Disney pictures,
Sarandos said, without identifying them. The company will bid
aggressively for exclusive rights to Sony Corp. (6758) films when that
studio''s contract with Starz ends around 2016, he said. </p>
<p>They negotiate a long way out and we''ll be at the table
for each of them, Sarandos said. </p>
<p>Paula Askanas, a Sony spokeswoman, said the company had no
comment on Sarandos''s remarks. </p>
<p>Netflix fell 3.8 percent to $83.37 at the close in New
York. The shares have advanced 20 percent this year, including
yesterday''s 14 percent surge. John Malone''s Liberty Media added
0.8 percent to $106.40. Disney rose 0.6 percent to $49.59. </p>
<p>Courtnee Ulrich, spokeswoman for Englewood, Colorado-based
Liberty Media, didn''t return a phone call seeking comment. </p>
<p>Films from Star Wars creator Lucasfilm, which Disney is
buying for $4.05 billion, will be included once the purchase is
completed, Sarandos said today at a UBS AG (UBS) conference in New
York. He was interviewed by Harvey Weinstein of the independent
studio Weinstein Co., which also has an exclusive Netflix deal. </p>
<h2>Deeper Library </h2>
<p>The Disney deal won''t trigger a price increase, Sarandos
said. The company will keep up an emphasis on exclusive content,
and is considering ways to promote its original shows, including
Web ads, he said. Relations with Icahn are very positive,
according to Sarandos. </p>
<p>With Disney, Netflix will be able to stream current or
catalog films from several studios. </p>
<p>Viacom Inc. (VIAB)''s Paramount Pictures, home of the Star Trek
series, Lions Gate Entertainment Corp. (LGF), owner of the Hunger
Games films, and Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Inc. sell to Netflix
through their jointly owned cable channel, Epix. Relativity
Media LLC has an exclusive multiyear agreement with Netflix, as
does DreamWorks Animation SKG Inc. (DWA), maker of the Shrek
movies. </p>
<h2>Kids'' Programming </h2>
<p>Yesterday''s agreement makes Disney the first major studio
to bypass a traditional cable-TV outlet with its movies. </p>
<p>With pictures geared to children and families, Netflix can
build a base of subscribers less likely to cancel for competing
offerings, said Scott Devitt, an analyst with Morgan Stanley (MS) who
has a buy rating on the shares. </p>
<p>The company is focusing on building a highly
differentiated content catalog aimed at kids, which is a
demographic that has relatively homogeneous tastes, Devitt
wrote in a research note. </p>
<p>With 30 million users worldwide, Netflix is extending its
lead over competing video services by Amazon.com Inc. and Redbox
Instant, from Verizon Communications Inc. (VZ) and Coinstar Inc. (CSTR),
which begins public testing this month. </p>
<h2>Domestic Customers </h2>
<p>Netflix is also adding exclusive programs such as
Lilyhammer and House of Cards as it seeks earlier and
fuller home-video access to studio movies for its customers. </p>
<p>The company has about 25.1 million U.S. subscribers,
compared with 20.7 million for Starz as of October. </p>
<p>Disney embraced online media sooner than its competitors,
becoming the first major studio to sell and rent TV shows and
movies through Apple Inc. (AAPL)''s iTunes. The company''s largest
shareholder is the trust of late Apple co-founder Steve Jobs. </p>
<p>One risk for Disney is that viewers will cancel their
traditional pay-TV service, costing the company subscription
revenue it gets for networks such as ESPN and the Disney
Channel, according to Michael Morris, an analyst with Davenport
 Co. in Richmond, Virginia. </p>
<p>Disney has been clear they are platform agnostic, said
Morris, who recommends the stock. </p>
<p>While Netflix bolsters its film lineup, the announcement
doesn''t settle a tug-of-war among investors over the company''s
prospects, said Arvind Bhatia, a Sterne, Agee  Leach analyst
who has a neutral rating on the shares. </p>
<p>With about $4.5 billion in streaming content obligations
due before the Disney films are available, and losses from
international expansion, Netflix must increase subscribers or
raise its $7.99-a-month price for unlimited viewing to remain
viable long-term, Bhatia said. </p>
<p>It''s a big get, but clearly there are several unknowns
out there to determine if it''s a good get, Bhatia said.
Though we don''t know the financial terms, it''s clear this was
not a cheap deal. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michelle Fay Cortez" date="Dec 05, 2012  4:11 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-05/pfizer-experimental-drug-slows-late-stage-breast-cancer.html"><headline>Pfizer Experimental Drug Slows Late-Stage Breast Cancer</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE)''s experimental breast
cancer drug stopped progression of an incurable form of the
disease for more than two years in a study, a dramatic delay for
those with the second-deadliest cancer in women. </p>
<p>Patients were given the medicine, called PD 0332991, along
with Novartis (NOVN) AG''s Femara. The findings, reported today at the
San Antonio Breast Cancer Symposium, showed no tumor progression
for a median of 26.1 months, compared with 7.5 months in those
who received Femara alone. Results were from the second of three
stages of testing normally needed for U.S. approval. </p>
<p>The medicine is the first in a new class of agents that
works by blocking a protein critical in the cancer cell cycle,
said lead researcher Richard Finn. It''s also among the most
promising in New York-based Pfizer''s drug development pipeline,
with the potential for generating $5 billion in annual sales for
breast and other tumor types, Andrew Baum, an analyst at
Citigroup Inc. in London, wrote in a note to investors. </p>
<p>This magnitude of benefit is probably one of the largest
with any new agent in breast cancer, or perhaps any solid
tumor, Finn, an associate professor of medicine at the Jonsson
Comprehensive Cancer Center at the University of California, Los
Angeles, said in a telephone interview. It''s dramatic to see
this level of benefit with a new agent. </p>
<h2>Noteworthy Findings </h2>
<p>The findings are noteworthy because of the size of the
benefit and comparative safety of the experimental treatment,
said Claudine Isaacs, an oncologist and professor of medicine at
Georgetown Lombardi Comprehensive Cancer Center in Washington.
The study, involving 165 patients with metastatic disease, was
small and must be confirmed in larger trials, she said. </p>
<p>The study included women with tumors fueled by the hormone
estrogen, the most common type of breast cancer. All had
metastatic disease, which had spread to other parts of the body
and is no longer considered curable. </p>
<p>Breast cancer is the most common tumor in women. Almost
230,000 women in the U.S. will be diagnosed with it this year,
and more than 39,900 will die from it, according to the American
Cancer Society. Lung cancer is the deadliest form of the disease
for women. </p>
<p>It does make you stop and look, Isaacs said in a
telephone interview. The results are much more marked than we
typically see. It''s hard to ignore that, she said. It''s not
something that is changing practice today, but it''s definitely
something to keep one''s eye on. </p>
<h2>Mega-Blockbuster Potential'' </h2>
<p>Investors have overlooked the drug''s mega-blockbuster
potential, said Baum, the Citigroup analyst. Pfizer is at
least two years ahead of its closest competitors, Eli Lilly 
Co. (LLY) and Novartis, with similar cancer drugs in development, he
said in his Nov. 29 investment note. </p>
<p>Pfizer rose 1.9 percent to $25.64 at 4 p.m. New York time.
The shares have gained 29 percent in the past 12 months. Onyx
Pharmaceuticals Inc., which licensed rights to the experimental
drug to Pfizer, rose 3.4 percent to $77.05. </p>
<p>The results presented today stem from an interim review of
the data and come on top of potent treatment, Finn said. </p>
<p>Forty-five percent of patients given the drug combination
responded to therapy, compared with 31 percent given Femara
alone. When the researchers included women who had stable
disease for six months or more, 70 percent given both drugs
benefited, compared with 44 percent of those given Femara. </p>
<p>Pfizer is moving the compound into the final stage of
testing needed for approval as quickly as possible, with an
international trial in the same type of cancer slated to begin
next year, said Mace Rothenberg, senior vice president of
clinical development in the company''s oncology unit. Additional
research is examining other types of tumors, he said. </p>
<h2>Regulatory Discussion </h2>
<p>The company is also talking to regulators to determine what
kind of information will be needed to win marketing approval of
the medicine, he said in a telephone interview. While the U.S.
Food and Drug Administration typically requires two studies
confirming the benefits of an investigational agent, it has
leeway to expedite the process for promising drugs. </p>
<p>About one in three patients needed to have their dose of
the experimental drug lowered during the study. Side effects
included low levels of infection-fighting white blood cells,
anemia and fatigue, though there weren''t any serious cases of
fever tied to the low white blood cells. </p>
<p>The first 66 patients were post-menopausal women with
estrogen-receptor positive cancer. The second 99 patients also
had tumors that were fueled by estrogen, though they had genetic
alterations the researchers hoped could further identify people
who would benefit from the therapy. </p>
<h2>Advanced Disease </h2>
<p>About half the women were initially diagnosed with advanced
disease and hadn''t gotten previous drug treatment. The other
half had previously received chemotherapy or treatment after
surgery to remove the tumor, Finn said. Laboratory work
conducted before the study began suggested the Pfizer medicine
was particularly potent against estrogen-receptor positive
cancers. </p>
<p>There were no differences in response among women with the
biomarkers and those who didn''t have them, Finn said. Both sets
of patients had a significant benefit. </p>
<p>The drug obviously hits a critical pathway in estrogen-
receptor positive breast cancer, he said. If we took triple
negative breast cancer, we wouldn''t expect this result. </p>
<p>Pfizer is reaching out to cancer experts to help devise the
most efficient studies to answer questions about when and how
the drug should be given, and what other medicines should be
given with it to maximize the benefit, Rothenberg said. </p>
<p>It''s an irony of having a drug moving forward as quickly
as we can, Rothenberg said. There will be gaps in our
knowledge of how to give it and when. We''re trying to move
forward with a thoughtful, methodical approach. </p>
<h2>Metastatic Cancer </h2>
<p>The study targeted women who were newly diagnosed with
metastatic, or spreading, breast cancer. There are several other
effective treatments available even after the experimental
compound stops working, Finn said. </p>
<p>The magnitude of this benefit I don''t think should be
underestimated, Finn said. These are patients who have
incurable breast cancer. A lot of drugs in oncology have been
approved or are getting a lot of traction because of
improvements that last weeks to a few months. We have gone from
7 months to 26 months. That''s groundbreaking. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Dec 05, 2012  2:21 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-05/jpmorgan-appoints-mark-o-donovan-to-be-corporate-controller.html"><headline>JPMorgan Appoints Mark O''Donovan to Be Corporate Controller</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co., the largest
U.S. bank by assets, named Mark W. O''Donovan corporate
controller, succeeding Shannon S. Warren. </p>
<p>O''Donovan has been global controller for the firm''s
investment bank since 2010, the New York-based lender said today
in a regulatory filing. Warren was named co-chief control
officer of the firm. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore and Zeke Faux" date="Dec 06, 2012  8:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-06/morgan-stanley-revises-broker-compensation-plan-for-2013-1-.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Alters Broker Pay Plan as Revenue Bonus Takes Hit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS), the brokerage with
the biggest corps of financial advisers, changed its wealth-
management compensation plan to encourage brokers to increase
revenue and allow them to buy discounted stock. </p>
<p>The 2013 program pays a bonus of 2 to 5 percentage points
of revenue for advisers who bring in new assets and are in the
top 40 percent in revenue growth, according to terms outlined in
a summary obtained yesterday by Bloomberg News. That comes at
the expense of a 2 percentage-point reduction in the revenue
bonus paid to all brokers who generate at least $750,000. </p>
<p>Greg Fleming, president of Morgan Stanley''s wealth-
management business, is seeking to control costs while avoiding
defections and meet his target of a mid-teens pretax margin next
year. Wealth-management employees typically have been paid a
higher portion of revenue than colleagues in trading units
because the brokerage business takes less risk and demands lower
levels of capital. </p>
<p>There remains a lot of pressure from a recruiting
standpoint, Fleming, 49, said at a Dec. 4 investor conference
in response to a question about possible changes to pay
structure. The existing system for compensation also works for
shareholders. </p>
<p>The changes don''t affect the so-called grid payout, usually
the largest portion of a broker''s compensation, or the bonus
based on tenure. </p>
<h2>Street''s Richest </h2>
<p>The growth bonus, in addition to the revenue percentage
award, includes as much as $285,000 for bringing in more money
from customers and making additional loans to clients, according
to the document. The bonus, which the firm described as
richest on the Street, is paid upfront in 2014 and
structured as a five-year forgivable loan. </p>
<p>Brokers can invest as much as $250,000 of their
compensation in Morgan Stanley stock and will get as much as a
25 percent bonus on shares they purchase, according to the plan.
The bonus shares vest in April 2016, when the purchased shares
are distributed. </p>
<p>Fleming said this week that his unit can reach
profitability targets solely through cost cuts, meaning revenue
improvements may provide a further boost. Integration expenses
will end this quarter, allowing the pretax profit margin to
increase next year, Fleming said. The margin was 13 percent in
the third quarter, excluding one-time charges. </p>
<h2>Brokerage Venture </h2>
<p>Morgan Stanley now owns 65 percent of the brokerage after
paying Citigroup Inc. (C) $1.89 billion for an additional 14 percent
stake in September following a two-month fight over the value of
the venture. The two banks agreed on a valuation for the
purchase of the remaining 35 percent stake, which Morgan Stanley
must acquire by June 2015. The firm will probably ask the
Federal Reserve for approval to purchase the rest next year, a
person briefed on the bank''s thinking said in October. </p>
<p>The brokerage is seeking to boost revenue through more
lending and moving additional client assets into managed
accounts, Fleming said. The average annualized revenue per
adviser in the third quarter was $790,000. About 1,900 of the
firm''s 16,829 brokers produce more than $1 million in annual
revenue, he said. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley tweaked the pay structure last year as well.
The firm raised the minimum amount of revenue a broker must
generate to avoid pay cuts to $300,000 from $250,000. It also
reduced bonuses based on revenue production by 1 percentage
point across the board, while introducing new bonuses for
bringing in assets and making loans to customers, a person
briefed on the plan said at the time. </p>
<p>Employees across Wall Street are facing pay cuts or losing
their jobs as revenue growth wanes and shareholders demand
higher returns. JPMorgan Chase  Co.''s bonus pool for its
corporate and investment bank may shrink as much as 2 percent
this year as the firm completes performance reviews, three
executives with direct knowledge of the process said yesterday. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Carroll" date="Dec 06, 2012  4:49 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-06/chevron-seen-eyeing-cobalt-to-kosmos-in-oil-hunt-real-m-a.html"><headline>Chevron Seen Eyeing Cobalt to Kosmos in Oil Hunt:Real M&amp;amp;A</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX), the U.S. oil giant
facing its longest slide in energy output in four years, could
tap record cash to reignite growth by acquiring Cobalt
International Energy Inc. (CIE) or Kosmos Energy Ltd. (KOS) </p>
<p>Oil and natural gas production from Chevron''s wells during
the third quarter dwindled to the lowest since 2008, slashing
profit by one-third and adding to declines that had already
forced the world''s fourth-largest energy company to abandon its
full-year output target. Even after the earnings drop, Chevron''s
cash stood at an all-time high of $21.3 billion, exceeding that
of bigger rivals Exxon (XOM) Mobil Corp. and Royal Dutch Shell Plc (RDSA),
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>While Chevron is spending more than $45 billion to harvest
Australian natural gas fields that will produce enough of the
fuel to supply all of China''s gas-import terminals, Phoenix
Partners Group LP says the company still has ample resources to
expand into nascent oil-exploration regions. Cobalt''s billion-
barrel discovery off the coast of Angola could bolster Chevron''s
deep-water African reserves, and Kosmos and Ophir Energy Plc (OPHR)
control significant untapped deposits from Tanzania to
Morocco, according to Tudor Pickering Holt  Co. </p>
<p>Chevron is going to have to grow through acquisitions,
Chris Kettenmann, chief energy strategist at Phoenix Partners in
New York, said in a telephone interview. They are going to
have to come to the market because they haven''t returned the $21
billion on the balance sheet to shareholders. </p>
<h2>Heavy Investment'' </h2>
<p>Lloyd Avram, a Chevron spokesman, said in an e-mailed
statement that the San Ramon, California-based company''s cash
position supports our long-held financial priorities, and
declined to comment on any acquisition plans. He referenced a
March presentation to analysts in which Chief Financial Officer
Pat Yarrington listed the company''s priorities, which included
paying dividends, funding capital projects and returning surplus
cash to shareholders. </p>
<p>We are in a period of heavy investment and our cash
balance allows us to weather lower commodity prices, Avram
wrote. We view a strong balance sheet as a risk mitigation
tool. </p>
<p>Chevron, with a market value of $206 billion, said last
month that it pumped 3.2 percent less oil and gas from its
56,000 wells during the third quarter compared with a year
earlier, extending the company''s streak of production declines
to a seventh straight quarter, the longest since a nine-quarter
stretch that ended in 2008. Shutdowns related to weather and
repairs contributed to the recent drop, the company said. </p>




Photographer: David Paul Morris/Bloomberg

<p>
Chevron Corp. signage is displayed at a gasoline station in San Francisco, California, U.S. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christopher Palmeri" date="Dec 06, 2012  4:08 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-06/disney-world-s-300-million-makeover-means-no-waiting-for-dumbo.html"><headline>Disney World''s $300 Million Makeover Means No Wait for Dumbo</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS) opens an expanded section of its Magic Kingdom today with the aim of drawing more visitors to a Florida park battling stagnant attendance for the past five years. </p> <p>Disney World employees at the Dumbo the Flying Elephant ride now hand out pagers to guests, who can take children to an air-conditioned play area until their turn comes. Customers are also able to purchase beer and wine in the park for the first time at a new restaurant modeled after the animated movie Beauty and the Beast. </p> <p>The changes to the Fantasyland area, estimated by Sanford C. Bernstein  Co. to cost $300 million, mark the biggest expansion in the 41-year history of Disney''s Magic Kingdom in Orlando. They are part of a wider effort by the world''s largest theme-park company to find high-tech ways to shorten lines and boost sales. </p> <p>With new technologies, we''ve got greater capability to immerse people in stories, Thomas Staggs, chairman of Disney parks and resorts, said in an interview. The food can come out sort of magically and appear. In the Little Mermaid queue, it''s not so much waiting as playing a game and interacting with the crabs. That''s technology that wasn''t there when Walt was first envisioning the park. </p> <h2>Bibbidi Bobbidi </h2> <p>Reducing wait times for rides frees guests to spend money elsewhere in the park and should lead to higher profit eventually, according to Jaison Blair, an analyst with Telsey Advisory Group in New York. </p> <p>If you''re not standing in line you''ll take your daughter to the Bibbidi Bobbidi salon or your son to the store to buy something, Blair said. </p> <p>The changes aren''t cheap. Jay Rasulo, Disney''s chief financial officer, said on a Nov. 8 conference call that investments in the resorts unit, including new cruise ships and the remodeling in Orlando, will lead to roughly $500 million in added revenue this fiscal year -- and a similar rise in costs. </p> <p>Bulls like me say, Yes, you are managing this asset for a lifetime and you must do periodic projects like this,'' said Todd Juenger, an analyst with Sanford C. Bernstein in New York. Bears look at the same situation and say, That''s why I don''t like the parks business, it''s a capital sinkhole.'' </p> <h2>Hologram Crabs </h2> <p>The goal is a more enjoyable experience for customers. Guests waiting to ride the new Under the Sea: Journey of Little Mermaid attraction can peer through portholes and tell hologram crabs to collect treasure from the ocean floor. Diners at the castle-themed Be Our Guest restaurant enter orders on a touchscreen and head to their tables with a plastic rose- imprinted device that directs servers to their location. </p> <p>Disney is also serving beer and wine with dinner at the restaurant, a first for the park. Among the options, a $69 bottle of the Lasseter Family St. Emilion Red Blend from the winery of John Lasseter, chief creative officer of Disney''s animation studios. </p> <p>Fantasyland, one of the original themed areas in the park and home to attractions such as Cinderella Castle and It''s a Small World, is more than doubling in size with the makeover, according to the company. </p> <p>During the two-year-plus construction, Disney closed Mickey''s Toontown Fair, a 1988 addition, and built an Enchanted Forest with waterfalls and castles tied to The Little Mermaid and Beauty and the Beast animated films. </p> <p>The additions include Maurice''s Cottage, where kids can take part in an interactive play with Belle, a character from Beauty and the Beast, and Beast''s Castle, where parents can dine on thyme-scented pork chops as fake snow falls outside of windows nearby. </p> <h2>Next Generation </h2> <p>It is a quantum leap forward in atmosphere for a Disney restaurant, said Kevin Yee, a former employee who blogs at Ultimateorlando.com. They''ve obviously spent a ton of money. </p> <p>With the use of pagers, new restaurant technology and interactive entertainment for waiting riders, the Fantasyland redo marks a step in a larger initiative that Disney calls next generation. The goal is for guests to pick rides and attractions before and during their trips to skip lines or shorten waits, according to Staggs. </p> <p>Walt Disney''s resorts division, which includes the parks, cruise ships and a Hawaiian hotel, is the Burbank, California- based company''s second-largest business after television networks, contributing 31 percent of revenue and 19 percent of operating income in the last fiscal year. </p> <h2>Most Popular </h2> <p>While the Magic Kingdom remains the world''s most-popular theme park, attendance has been little changed at around 17 million visitors annually for the previous five years, according to a report by the Themed Entertainment Association and the consulting firm Aecom. </p> <p>Universal Studios'' nearby Islands of Adventure boosted attendance 66 percent to 7.6 million over two years, after opening the Wizarding World of Harry Potter in 2010, according to the report. Universal Studios is owned by Comcast Corp. </p> <p>Disney rose 0.5 percent to $49.06 at the close in New York. The shares had gained 31 percent this year, to rank eighth in the 16-stock SP 500 Media Index. Comcast, up 57 percent, is first. </p> <p>The broader strategy is to meet Universal head on, said John Gerner, a theme-park consultant in Richmond, Virginia. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David McLaughlin" date="Dec 06, 2012  2:47 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-06/goldman-sachs-barclays-join-creditor-group-in-amr-bankruptcy.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs, Barclays Join Creditor Group in AMR Case</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and Barclays
Plc (BARC) joined a creditor group in American Airlines'' bankruptcy
case that may provide financing for the carrier''s restructuring. </p>
<p>The committee has expanded to 20 members from 12 since
September, according to a filing today in U.S. Bankruptcy Court
in New York disclosing its members and their company debt
holdings. </p>
<p>American Airlines'' parent, AMR Corp. (AAMRQ), said in court papers
in August that it would negotiate with the group about potential
financing for its reorganization. It won court approval to pay
fees of the group''s advisers as negotiations proceed. </p>
<p>The group holds claims against American Airlines and AMR,
according to today''s filing. Besides Goldman Sachs and Barclays,
members include JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), Credit Suisse Group AG,
Claren Road Asset Management and Marathon Asset Management. </p>
<p>The case is In re AMR Corp., 11-15463, U.S. Bankruptcy
Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Glenys Sim" date="Dec 06, 2012  3:55 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-06/morgan-stanley-backs-gold-corn-soybeans-as-best-picks-in-2013.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Backs Gold, Corn, Beans as Best Picks in 2013</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Gold, silver and corn will outperform
other raw materials next year as a weaker dollar and rising
investor demand bolster precious metals while supply curbs aid
grains, Morgan Stanley said, listing top picks for 2013. </p>
<p>Silver will track gold, which is poised to gain on low real
interest rates, buying by central banks and geopolitical
uncertainty, analysts including Peter Richardson and Hussein Allidina wrote in a report today, reiterating an October call.
Corn and soybeans should benefit from harvest delays in South
America, they said. The bank is bearish on aluminum, sugar,
nickel and uranium as supplies are set to outpace demand. </p>
<p>Commodities as tracked by the Standard  Poor''s GSCI Spot
Index are down 0.4 percent this year, led by declines in coffee,
cotton and sugar. The gauge almost doubled in the three years to
2011 as central banks and governments around the world took
action to boost their economies hurt by the global financial
crisis in 2008. Morgan Stanley joins Goldman Sachs Group Inc. in
predicting the so-called super-cycle isn''t over. </p>
<p>Higher prices in recent years have brought both a supply
and demand response, bringing many to call for the end of the
super-cycle, they wrote. We view this as too simplistic.
Commodities are cyclical but the elasticity of supply and demand,
as well as the length of the cycle, vary significantly. </p>
<p>Gold may average $1,853 an ounce in 2013, while silver may
be $35 an ounce, Morgan Stanley said. That compares with gold''s
average of $1,668 so far this year and $31.1542 for silver.
Soybeans may average $15.70 a bushel in 2012-2013, it said. </p>
<h2>Overweight Call </h2>
<p>Goldman reiterated an overweight call on commodities,
yesterday, forecasting prices will return 7 percent in 12 months,
Jeffrey Currie, head of commodity research, wrote in a report.
Citigroup Inc. believes the super-cycle has ended, according to
Edward L. Morse, global head of commodities research, on Nov. 19. </p>
<p>With commodity-supply constraints easing, Chinese growth
slowing and producer-company returns normalizing, it is
tempting to say the super-cycle is over, Currie wrote. Current
developments are simply the next phase of a commodity-investment
cycle that began in the late 1990s. We therefore view the
current transition as a renaissance, rather than an end. </p>
<p>Goldman, backing crude, corn and copper, expects gold to
peak in 2013 on a recovery in the U.S. economy. In contrast,
Morgan Stanley called for higher prices on low nominal and
negative real interest rates, as well as risks in the Middle
East and central-bank buying. So-called negative real interest
rates describe savings rates that are lower than inflation. </p>
<h2>Central Banks </h2>
<p>Spot gold, up 8 percent in 2012, is rallying for a 12th
year as central banks join investors buying bullion to diversify
assets. South Korea, Brazil and Russia are among those adding to
gold reserves this year. Holdings in exchange-traded products
are at a record, data compiled by Bloomberg show. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley expects higher corn and soybean prices on
the potential for lower supplies from South America. Rains and
flooding have impeded planting in Argentina, while dry weather
in Brazil is threatening beans. </p>
<p>The bank is bearish on aluminum as an increase in
production capacity exacerbates an oversupply. So-called
financing transactions and long waiting times for delivery from
London Metal Exchange warehouses are supporting output, the bank
said. Aluminum may average $2,300 a ton in 2013, the bank said,
compared with $2,049 a ton so far this year. </p>
<p>Global sugar supply may outpace demand on rising Brazilian
crush volumes and stable Indian production, said Morgan Stanley,
while China''s import demand may slow on high inventories and
improved domestic output. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Olga Kharif" date="Dec 06, 2012 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-06/mobile-app-makers-seek-angry-birds-fame-with-analytics.html"><headline>Mobile App Makers Seek Angry Birds Fame With Analytics</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Joel Auge, who devised a mobile game that pits a fictitious king against the mice infesting his kingdom, wanted to keep players engaged longer. So he turned to Swrve New Media Inc. for advice. </p> <p>With a surge in the number of games and tools available for download through online stores run by Apple Inc. (AAPL) and Google Inc. (GOOG), it''s getting harder for developers like Auge to vie for the attention of fickle mobile-device users. </p> <p>Not every mobile application can be the next Angry Birds. To improve their chances, programmers in growing numbers are turning to Swrve and other companies, such as App Annie Ltd and Localytics, which use mathematical models and behavior data to help mobile developers court users. Only a sliver of the more than 700,000 apps on Apple''s App Store or Google Play are poised to benefit from the $46 billion ABI Research predicts mobile apps can generate in 2016. So startups are eager for any help they can get in climbing store rankings and retaining users. </p> <p>You''ll see a dramatic improvement, Auge, HitGrab Inc.''s co-founder and chief executive officer, said in an interview. Without Swrve, running the business was like driving blind, he said. </p> <p>While the analytics industry is small, it''s expanding fast. Venture investment in apps-data companies more than tripled in the first half of this year to $16.8 million, compared with the same period in 2011, according to Rutberg  Co. Over that time, funding of mobile developers grew 35 percent to $1.24 billion. </p>




Photographer: Chris Ratcliffe/Bloomberg

<p>
The ''''Angry Birds'''' mobile-phone game, designed by Rovio Mobile Oy is seen on an Apple Inc. iPhone 4 smartphone in this arranged photograph in London, U.K. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Silla Brush" date="Dec 07, 2012  4:30 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-07/goldman-fined-for-failing-to-prevent-trader-s-8-3-billion-bet.html"><headline>Goldman Fined for Failing to Block Trader''s $8.3 Billion Bet</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) will pay
$1.5 million to settle U.S. Commodity Futures Trading Commission
claims the firm failed to supervise a trader who hid an $8.3
billion position. One CFTC commissioner dissented, saying the
penalty is far too small. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs inadequately policed trades made by Matthew
Marshall Taylor on seven days in late 2007, ultimately suffering
more than $118 million in losses as his bets were unwound,
according to the CFTC. Later, Goldman Sachs didn''t send the
regulator important information on the incident that was
provided to another industry watchdog, the CFTC said. </p>
<p>Given the egregious nature of the failure to supervise
adequately, combined with the high number of violative
transactions, I believe that the monetary penalty should be
significantly higher, Bart Chilton, one of three Democrats at
the CFTC, wrote in a dissent posted on the regulator''s website.
Fines should represent more than a slap on the wrist, he
said. </p>
<p>Taylor concealed the position by bypassing the New York-
based firm''s internal system for routing trades to the Chicago
Mercantile Exchange and manually entering fabricated futures
trades in a different internal system, the CFTC wrote in a
complaint filed against him at federal court last month. His
attorney disputed those allegations at the time. </p>




Photographer: Jin Lee/Bloomberg

<p>
Goldman Sachs Group Inc. inadequately policed trades made by Matthew Marshall Taylor on seven days in late 2007, ultimately suffering more than $118 million in losses as his bets were unwound, according to the CFTC. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chris Dolmetsch" date="Dec 07, 2012  1:33 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-07/goldman-in-mediation-with-cifg-to-settle-mortgage-suit.html"><headline>Goldman in Mediation With CIFG to Settle Mortgage Suit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) and CIFG
Assurance North America Inc. retained a mediator as the two
companies seek to settle a lawsuit in New York state court in
Manhattan, according to a filing. </p>
<p>The insurer sued Goldman Sachs in New York State Supreme
Court in August 2011, accusing the New York-based investment
bank of making misrepresentations in connection with the
securitization of a portfolio of 6,204 mortgage loans. </p>
<p>The two sides have participated in one mediation session
and have scheduled another for Dec. 19, according to a document
filed in court yesterday. </p>
<p>Justice O. Peter Sherwood in May granted Goldman Sachs''s
motion to dismiss three counts in the lawsuit, including one for
fraudulent inducement, while refusing to throw out three claims
for breach of contract. He also granted a motion by Buffalo, New
York-based MT Bank Corp. to remove it as a defendant </p>
<p>CIFG and Goldman Sachs appealed Sherwood''s decision, and
the judge in July ordered the two sides to engage in mediation,
according to court filings. </p>
<p>CIFG filed another lawsuit against Goldman Sachs in the
same court this week, accusing the bank of fraudulently inducing
the insurer to provide a policy on a credit default swap
guaranteeing $325 million of notes in a collateralized debt
obligation called Fortius II Funding Ltd. </p>
<h2>No Comment </h2>
<p>In a phone interview today, Michael DuVally, a spokesman
for Goldman Sachs, declined to comment on yesterday''s filing or
the CIFG suit filed this week. Attorneys for CIFG didn''t
immediately return voice-mail messages and e-mails seeking
comment. </p>
<p>CIFG, based in New York, has taken similar actions in the
same court during the past three years, including a $277 million
suit against GreenPoint Mortgage Funding Inc. filed in October
and a $150 million suit against Bank of America Corp. filed last
month. </p>
<p>The case is CIFG Assurance North America Inc. v. Goldman,
Sachs  Co., 652286/2011, New York Supreme Court, New York
County (Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michelle Wiese Bockmann" date="Dec 07, 2012 10:30 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-07/general-maritime-to-manage-unipec-tanker-pool-tradewinds-says.html"><headline>General Maritime to Manage Unipec Tanker Pool, Tradewinds Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>General Maritime Corp. will place as
many as 19 of its tankers in a pool to transport crude for China
International United Petroleum  Chemical Co., or Unipec,
shipping newspaper Tradewinds said, citing unnamed sources. </p>
<p>General Maritime, a New York-based tanker owner, will also
manage the pool for Unipec, the world''s second-largest tanker
charterer, with ships replacing those from the Tankers
International pool, the Oslo-based newspaper said today. </p>
<p>Unipec, the trading division of China Petroleum  Chemical
Corp. (600028), or Sinopec, the nation''s largest refiner, didn''t respond
to an e-mail to its London office, and phone calls outside
business hours to its Beijing operations weren''t answered.
Tankers International doesn''t comment on its activities, said a
woman from the London office who returned a call from Bloomberg
seeking comment. She didn''t provide her name and didn''t say why
she can''t be identified. </p>
<p>Jeffrey Pribor, General Maritime''s chief financial officer,
was out of the office and not available for comment, according
to an unidentified woman who answered his phone at the company''s
New York-based office. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Stephen Bierman" date="Dec 07, 2012  3:44 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-07/exxonmobil-to-spend-300-million-on-rosneft-tight-oil-pilot.html"><headline>ExxonMobil to Spend $300 Million on Rosneft Tight Oil Pilot</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) plans to spend as
much as $300 million on a pilot project with OAO Rosneft to tap
tight oil resources in Russia. </p>
<p>State-run Rosneft will own 51 percent and Exxon will hold
49 percent of the venture that will explore the Achimov and
Bazhenov formations in western Siberia next year, according to a
statement today. The work will focus on 23 license blocks. </p>
<p>Exxon formed a partnership with Rosneft last year in which
the Irving, Texas-based company also gained access to offshore
deposits in Russia''s frontier Arctic and Black Sea region.
Russia, which vies with Saudi Arabia as the world''s largest oil
producer, may overhaul its tax system to support tight oil
production, according to Rosneft. </p>
<p>The partnership will select blocks for commercial
development in 2015. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki" date="Dec 09, 2012  2:59 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-09/jpmorgan-said-to-ask-employees-to-help-fund-u-k-tax-settlement.html"><headline>JPMorgan Said to Ask Staff to Help Fund U.K. Tax Settlement</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) asked more than
2,000 current and former employees to contribute to a settlement
with the U.K.''s tax authority over their use of an offshore
trust for bonus payments, according to a person briefed on the
situation. </p>
<p>Employees who participated in the trust were asked to help
fund a payment of at least a few hundred million pounds if they
want to settle with Her Majesty''s Revenue and Customs, the U.K.
tax authority, the person said, asking not to be named because
the talks are private. The bank and workers may pay about 500
million pounds ($802 million) total, the Financial Times
reported yesterday, without saying where it got the information. </p>
<p>Corporations including Starbucks Corp. (SBUX), Amazon.com Inc. and
Google Inc. have come under attack from British lawmakers and
protesters for using complex accounting methods to minimize tax
liabilities in the U.K. The government will invest in the part
of the tax office that targets multinational companies,
Chancellor George Osborne said last week. </p>
<p>The case involving JPMorgan focuses on a Jersey-based trust
established 20 years ago, according to the FT. Such entities,
typically holding bonus payments that can''t be repatriated
without triggering tax payments, are being closed after they
were targeted in legislation last year, the FT said. </p>
<p>Our employee trust has always been transparent to HMRC,
and its independent trustee has consistently paid taxes in
accordance with U.K. tax law, JPMorgan said in an e-mailed
statement. </p>
<h2>Blind Auction </h2>
<p>In addition to taxes paid by the trust, the bank has paid
more than 1 billion pounds of corporate and payroll taxes to the
U.K. authority annually over the past decade, according to the
statement. </p>
<p>People who used JPMorgan''s trust told the FT they were
asked to participate in a so-called blind auction, in which they
would volunteer to pay a tax rate of their choosing. </p>
<p>If the auction fails to generate enough money to fund the
settlement, people who submitted less than the average bid would
be excluded from the deal and face a 52 percent tax rate when
the trust''s assets are liquidated, the newspaper said. </p>
<p>People who don''t wish to participate can try to fight the
government''s demand, the person briefed on the situation said. </p>
<p>HMRC cannot comment on individual cases, spokesman Patrick
O''Brien wrote by e-mail, citing confidentiality rules. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dawn Kopecki, Elisa Martinuzzi and Liam Vaughan" date="Dec 10, 2012  2:15 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-10/jpmorgan-chase-names-willsey-global-chairman-of-capital-markets.html"><headline>JPMorgan Promotes Willsey as Investment Bank Shakeup Continues</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), the largest
U.S. bank by assets, shuffled management around the world at its
newly combined corporate and investment bank to take advantage
of any rebound in capital markets. </p>
<p>Kevin Willsey, 49, was elevated from co-head of the
investment bank in North America to global chairman of capital
markets, according to an internal memo from the New York-based
bank today. Larry Slaughter, who ran the North American division
with Willsey, will become global chairman of diversified
industries. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon, 56, has overhauled
management during a year marred by more than $6.2 billion in
trading losses and as banks struggled with weak revenue. In
July, he also combined treasury services with the corporate and
investment banks to create the new unit. Former investment bank
CEO James Jes Staley, 55, relinquished day-to-day management
responsibilities to Michael Cavanagh and Daniel Pinto at the
time and was appointed the division''s chairman. </p>
<p>The bank wants a more holistic approach to coverage as
others step back and capital-markets activity picks up, Viswas Raghavan, 46, who was promoted to head of banking for Europe,
Middle East and Africa, said in an interview today. The worst
is probably past in Europe, and though it won''t be smooth
sailing, a new balance will be found. </p>
<h2>New Posts </h2>
<p>Raghavan, the former head of global equity capital markets,
was among about a half dozen executives in Europe, Asia and
Latin America to also get new jobs today. The changes were
announced by Jeff Urwin, 56, the global head of investment
banking, and Don McCree, 51, who was named chief executive
officer of global corporate banking earlier this month, in a
memo to employees of the recently combined corporate and
investment bank. </p>
<p>Alejandro Guevara and Lisandro Miguens were named as co-
heads of banking in Latin America. Tom DuCharme and Therese Esperdy will also co-run investment banking in Asia Pacific,
according to a separate memo confirmed by a spokeswoman in
London today. </p>
<p>Eric Stein, 45, who ran the diversified industries group in
investment banking in North America, will become head of
investment banking coverage for the same region, reporting to
Urwin, according to today''s memo. Liz Myers will succeed
Raghavan as global head of equity capital markets, reporting to
Urwin. </p>
<p>Bill Contente, the former co-head of equity capital
markets, is returning to the firm in January after a leave of
absence and will become a vice chairman of equity capital
markets, reporting to Myers, according to the memo. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elisa Martinuzzi and Liam Vaughan" date="Dec 10, 2012 12:07 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-10/jpmorgan-names-raghavan-head-of-banking-for-emea-in-revamp.html"><headline>JPMorgan Names Regional Banking Heads for Europe, Asia in Revamp</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) named Viswas Raghavan head of banking for Europe, Middle East and Africa, and
chiefs for Asia and Latin America as part of a revamp to improve
coverage of corporate clients. </p>
<p>The lender appointed Alejandro Guevara and Lisandro Miguens
co-heads of banking in Latin America, while Tom DuCharme and
Therese Esperdy will be co-heads of banking in Asia Pacific,
according to a memo confirmed by a spokeswoman in London today. </p>
<p>The executives will oversee investment banking, corporate
banking and treasury services in their regions as the biggest
U.S. bank combines those units into one. New York-based JPMorgan
shook up its top management in July after a $6.2 billion trading
loss in its chief investment office, and earlier this month
named Don McCree to oversee corporate banking with Jeff Urwin,
who heads investment banking. </p>
<p>The objective is to broaden the client footprint and have
a more holistic approach to coverage as others step back and
capital-markets activity picks up, Raghavan, 46, the former
head of global equity capital markets, said in a phone
interview. The worst is probably past in Europe, and though it
won''t be smooth sailing, a new balance will be found. </p>
<p>JPMorgan ranks eighth this year among so-called mandated
arrangers of loans to European companies, up from 12th last year
and the highest since 2006, data compiled by Bloomberg show. </p>
<p>The company also announced Todd Marin, formerly co-head of
investment banking in Asia Pacific, will become vice chairman of
investment banking for the region, reporting to Urwin. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elisha Bala-Gbogbo" date="Dec 10, 2012 11:18 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-10/exxon-mobil-lifts-force-majeure-on-nigerian-qua-iboe-crude.html"><headline>Exxon Mobil Lifts Force Majeure on Nigerian Qua Iboe Crude</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (CVX) lifted its force
majeure on Qua Iboe crude exports from Nigeria, Africa''s largest
oil producer, a company official said. </p>
<p>The force majeure, a legal step that protects a company
from liability when it can''t fulfill a contract for reasons
beyond its control, has been removed, Paul Arinze, general
manager in charge of public and government affairs, said in a
statement released today in Lagos, Nigeria''s commercial capital. </p>
<p>The loading halt had been in place since Nov. 20 after a
Nov. 9 pipeline leak from an Exxon Mobil offshore facility in
the southern Akwa Ibom state spilled crude into the sea. The
facility was shut a day after the incident. </p>
<p>Force majeure on Royal Dutch Shell Plc''s Forcados grade was
lifted on Nov. 29, while a similar halt by Total SA on gas
shipments to Nigeria LNG Ltd. was also ended on the same day and
normal production resumed from onshore block OML 58 that pumps
90,000 barrels a day of oil. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Erik Larson" date="Dec 10, 2012  9:12 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-10/microsoft-seeks-to-invalidate-motorola-patent-in-u-k-trial.html"><headline>Microsoft Seeks to Invalidate Motorola Patent in U.K. Trial</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), the world''s biggest
software maker, asked a U.K. judge to invalidate Motorola
Mobility''s European patent protection for synchronizing message
statuses across multiple devices. </p>
<p>Microsoft sued Google Inc. (GOOG)''s Motorola Mobility last
December in a preemptive challenge to a 2002 patent it claims
shouldn''t have been issued because the technology was obvious to
experts in the field at the time, Microsoft''s lawyers said at a
week-long trial scheduled to end today in London. </p>
<p>We''re grateful for the chance to demonstrate that
Motorola''s claims based on this patent are unfounded, David
Howard, a deputy general counsel at Microsoft, said in an e-
mailed statement about the latest salvo in a global dispute. </p>
<p>The companies are locked in legal battles over patents for
smartphone technology and Xbox gaming software in the U.S. and
Germany. Microsoft claims all devices that run on Google''s
Android operating system use its technology and is seeking
royalties from Motorola Mobility. Motorola Mobility, which
Mountain View, California-based Google acquired in May, says
it''s owed royalties on the Xbox for use of the company''s Wi-Fi
and video-compression technology. </p>
<p>Motorola''s lawyer, Zoe Butler of Powell Gilbert in London,
declined to comment. The company''s press office didn''t
immediately respond to a phone message. </p>
<p>While the patent in the U.K. trial relates to pager
technology from the 1990s, the arguments center on its
application to newer mobile devices and computers. </p>
<p>The case is running parallel to Motorola''s lawsuit against
Microsoft over the same patent in Germany, where the companies
are awaiting a decision from a judge. Google has said it bought
Motorola Mobility in part because of its patents and history of
innovation in mobile phones. </p>
<p>The case is: Microsoft Corporation v. Motorola Mobility
Inc., case no. HC11C04536, High Court of London, Chancery
Division (London). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Stephanie Bodoni" date="Dec 10, 2012  9:09 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-10/visa-europe-challenges-eu-refusal-on-debit-card-fee-caps.html"><headline>Visa Europe Challenges EU Refusal on Debit-Card-Fee Caps</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Visa Europe Ltd. challenged the
European Union''s refusal to allow it to change a 2010 cap on
debit-card transaction fees paid by retailers. </p>
<p>The European Commission''s July 31 decision to reject Visa
Europe''s request should be overturned, the operator of Europe''s
largest payment-card network said in an appeal to the bloc''s
second-highest court. The commission violated the EU''s Charter
of Fundamental Rights by refusing Visa Europe the opportunity
to effectively make known its views on the relevant facts. </p>
<p>The commission also committed a manifest error of
assessment by rejecting evidence by Visa Europe on the basis
of flawed considerations, the London-based company said in its
appeal, details of which were published today. </p>
<p>Visa Europe reduced debit-card transaction fees in 2010 as
part of a settlement of a 2009 statement of objections by the EU
antitrust regulator. In July, Visa Europe was sent another EU
statement of objections for possible violations of EU
antitrust rules concerning multilateral interchange fees for
transactions with consumer credit cards set by the company. Visa
Europe split from Visa Inc. (V) before the U.S. card company''s
initial public offering in early 2008. </p>
<p>Visa Europe declined to comment beyond confirming it had
filed the appeal. </p>
<p>The case is: T-447/12, Visa Europe v. Commission. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Dec 11, 2012  7:53 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-11/microsoft-increases-production-of-surface-expands-distribution.html"><headline>Microsoft Increases Surface Production, Retail Outlets</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) said it has boosted
the production of its Surface RT tablet computer and will make
the device available at more retail stores. Staples Inc. (SPLS) and
Best Buy Co. (BBY) will start sales tomorrow. </p>
<p>Customers will be able to buy the Surface running Windows
RT software, an update to the company''s flagship operating
system, at an expanded list of retail stores in the U.S. and
Australia as early as mid-December, Microsoft said today in
a statement. The Redmond, Washington-based company also will
extend its Microsoft holiday stores, including turning some of
the temporary outlets into permanent ones. </p>
<p>Microsoft has been selling the devices since Oct. 26 only
at its more than 60 retail locations in the U.S. and Canada, and
online in seven countries. The company has declined to provide
sales numbers, leading some analysts to express concern demand
might be falling short. </p>
<p>Best Buy said it will offer Surface tablets online from
tomorrow, and in some retail outlets starting Dec. 16. </p>
<p>With the added distribution, Microsoft should sell about a
million units this quarter, according to Rick Sherlund, an
analyst at Nomura Holdings Inc. </p>
<p>Additional retailers will be added in a number of
countries in the coming months, Microsoft said in the
statement. The company didn''t elaborate or say how much it
expanded production. </p>
<p>Microsoft said last month that it will introduce a new
model of the device, the Surface Pro, in January. That device
features an Intel Corp. (INTC) i5 processor. Microsoft may release a
version with Intel''s Clover Trail chip, which would offer better
battery life and performance, perhaps by March, Sherlund
said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By James Paton" date="Dec 11, 2012  3:49 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-11/exxon-forecasts-energy-demand-to-increase-35-by-2040-wsj-says.html"><headline>Exxon Forecasts Energy Demand Will Gain 35% by 2040, WSJ Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) forecasts global
energy consumption will rise 35 percent by 2040, driven by China
and India, the Wall Street Journal reported, citing the
company''s latest long-term energy outlook. </p>
<p>Exxon projects North America will become a net energy
exporter by 2025 because of an increase in oil and gas
production and improvements in energy efficiency, the newspaper
said. The Irving, Texas-based company is the world''s biggest
energy producer by market value. </p>
<p>The use of coal will decline 33 percent by 2025, compared
with a previous estimate of 23 percent, as more natural gas-
fired power stations are built, the report said. The growth of
U.S. and Canadian oil and gas production may lead to an increase
in international shipments, according to the report. </p>
<p>Exxon compiles the outlook annually to guide long-term
investment decisions. </p>
<p>Demand in developed regions such as the U.S., Canada and
Europe will be unchanged or decline as they become more
efficient, according to the newspaper report. While developed
nations by 2040 are forecast to generate 80 percent more
economic output than in 2010, they will use the same amount of
energy, the newspaper said, citing the outlook. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christie Smythe and Karen Gullo" date="Dec 11, 2012 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-11/visa-fee-accord-preliminary-approval-appeal-is-rejected.html"><headline>Visa Fee Accord Preliminary Approval Appeal Is Rejected</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p> Home Depot Inc. (HD) and other retailers
lost their bid to appeal a judge''s preliminary approval of Visa
Inc. (V) and MasterCard Inc. (MA)''s proposed $7.25 billion settlement of
a merchant fee price-fixing case. </p>
<p>A federal appeals court in Manhattan refused to give
expedited treatment to the retailers''s appeal and deferred the
matter until after the judge has given final approval and
entered a final judgment in the case, according to a filing
yesterday. </p>
<p>Lawyers for the retailers had sought a hearing and decision
on the appeal as soon as possible because they said the trial
judge in the case granted an injunction that makes them part of
the settlement group without rights to opt out of the accord or
bring future lawsuits, according to a Nov. 29 court filing. </p>
<p>Stephen Neuwirth, an attorney for Home Depot, and Wesley
Powell, a lawyer for the credit card companies, didn''t
immediately respond to e-mails sent after regular business hours
seeking comment on the ruling. </p>
<p>U.S. District Judge John Gleeson gave preliminary approval
of the $7.25 billion settlement on Nov. 9 over objections by
retailers opposing the deal. The decision allowed plaintiffs to
begin signing up more than 7 million retailers that might be
eligible to participate. A final approval hearing is scheduled
for Sept. 12. </p>
<p>The accord, estimated to be the largest-ever antitrust
settlement, would end a seven-yearlong case alleging that the
card companies conspired with major banks to fix interchange, or
swipe, fees charged to merchants when customers pay with
plastic. Retailers opposed to the deal claim it forces them to
give up too many rights to sue over card company practices in
the future. </p>
<p>The case is In re Payment Card Interchange Fee and Merchant
Discount Antitrust Litigation, 05-md-01720, U.S. District Court,
Eastern District of New York (Brooklyn). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Aaron Clark" date="Dec 12, 2012  5:05 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-12/goldman-sachs-energy-research-head-greely-leaves-for-bridgewater.html"><headline>Goldman Energy Research Head Greely Leaves for Bridgewater</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>David Greely, Goldman Sachs Group
Inc. (GS)''s head of energy research, is joining Bridgewater
Associates LP, according a spokeswoman for Bridgewater. </p>
<p>Greely is joining the Westport, Connecticut-based employee-
owned hedge fund sponsor as a portfolio manager, said the
spokeswoman, who did not want to be identified. </p>
<p>Leslie Shribman, a New York-based spokeswoman for Goldman
Sachs, declined to comment. </p>
<p>Greely is known in part for forecasting Feb. 23 that West
Texas Intermediate''s discount to Brent oil would narrow to $5
within six months because the reversal of the Seaway pipeline by
Enterprise Products Partners LP and Enbridge Inc. (ENB) would ease a
bottleneck of oil in the center of the U.S. that had depressed
prices of WTI. </p>
<p>Seaway began moving oil May 19 to Texas refiners from
Cushing, Oklahoma. The spread shrank to $11.03 in June from
$15.79 on Feb. 23 before widening again. It was $22.73 a barrel
based on today''s settlement prices. </p>
<p>Greely''s prediction countered those of analysts at
Citigroup Inc. and Barclays Plc who said surging U.S. production
and limited pipeline space would keep Cushing supplies high and
the WTI-Brent spread wide. </p>
<p>WTI traded at an average 32-cent premium to Brent between
2005 and 2010. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Anna Edney" date="Dec 12, 2012  3:09 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-12/pfizer-s-chantix-produced-more-heart-concerns-fda-says.html"><headline>Pfizer''s Chantix Produced More Heart Concerns, FDA Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE)''s anti-smoking drug
Chantix produced a higher rate of heart attacks or strokes in
patients using the treatment than those who didn''t take the
product, according to an analysis of clinical trials. </p>
<p>The number of cardiovascular issues in patients on Chantix
and those who took a placebo was uncommon, the U.S. Food and
Drug Administration said today in a safety notice on its
website. While the increased risk wasn''t statistically
significant for those on Chantix, it seems more likely that it
is related to the drug and not purely a chance finding, the
agency said. </p>
<p>Chantix carries a warning that it raises the risks of
suicide and may be tied to higher heart danger in patients with
cardiovascular disease. The warning label had been changed last
year after regulators cited the heart concerns and asked New
York-based Pfizer to further evaluate the risks with a large
analysis of existing studies of the drug. The agency''s
announcement today followed that analysis. </p>
<p>Of 4,190 Chantix users, 13 were found to have experienced a
major cardiovascular event such as heart attack or stroke
compared with six of 2,812 who took a placebo in 15 Pfizer-
sponsored clinical trials, the FDA said. </p>
<p>The benefits of Chantix outweigh the risks, MacKay Jimeson,
a spokesman for Pfizer, said in an e-mail. </p>
<p>The benefits of quitting smoking are immediate and
substantial, Jimeson said. Chantix has been demonstrated to
increase the likelihood of abstinence from smoking for as long
as one year compared to treatment with placebo. </p>
<p>Smoking is a major risk factor for heart disease, the FDA
said. </p>
<h2>Chantix Sales </h2>
<p>Patients taking Chantix should contact their doctor if they
experience new or worsening symptoms of cardiovascular disease,
such as chest pain, shortness of breath, calf pain or sudden
onset of weakness, numbness or difficulty speaking. </p>
<p>Chantix generated $720 million in sales last year for
Pfizer, the world''s largest drugmaker, according to data
compiled by Bloomberg. The FDA notice said that about 2.3
million Chantix prescriptions were dispensed in the year ended
in September. </p>
<p>Pfizer faces a January trial in federal court in Florence,
Alabama, in a lawsuit claiming the anti-smoking drug caused
psychiatric disorders that led a man to be placed in a mental
hospital. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David Fickling" date="Dec 12, 2012  1:57 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-12/coca-cola-amatil-drops-as-consumer-sentiment-hits-volume.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Amatil Drops as Consumer Sentiment Hits Volume</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Coca-Cola Amatil Ltd. (CCL), Australia''s
largest beverages company, fell the most in more than a year in
Sydney trading after saying weak consumer sentiment and
discounting by competitors hurt growth in sales volume. </p>
<p>The stock declined 2.6 percent, its biggest drop since Nov.
17, 2011, to A$13.56 at the close in Sydney, with trading volume
at more than three times the daily average in the past three
months. Price-driven competitor activity has restrained
sales volume growth in the second half of the year, and
consumer spending levels continue to be soft, the Sydney-
based company said in a statement today. </p>
<p>The Coca-Cola Co. bottler has been so highly rated by the
markets that its share performance won''t permit any
disappointment, Dan Hurren, an analyst at UBS AG, said by phone
from Sydney. It''s the second-highest valued large Australian
consumer staples company, using a measure of enterprise value
and estimated earnings, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>The valuation hasn''t taken into account that there''s
natural risk around the weather for this stock, said Hurren,
who rates Coca-Cola Amatil sell. We''ve had a relatively cool
start to the summer months in Australia. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola Amatil said it still expects to boost volume and
sales in the six months through December in Australia, its
largest market responsible for about 70 percent of revenue. </p>
<p>Strong growth continues in the Indonesia and Papua New
Guinea operations, while earnings in New Zealand and Fiji will
fall in line with the broader market, the company said, without
providing earnings figures. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola Amatil''s enterprise value is about 10.4 times
estimated earnings this year, the second-highest after Treasury
Wine Estates Ltd. (TWE) among Australian consumer staples companies
with more than A$1 billion ($1 billion) in annual sales,
Bloomberg data show. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Dec 13, 2012  6:46 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-13/morgan-stanley-ficc-cuts-may-go-to-2017-chen-says.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley FICC Cuts May Go to 2017, Chen Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley may continue cutting
assets in its fixed-income business for another five years as it
seeks higher returns, said Howard Chen, a Credit Suisse Group
Inc. analyst. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley must return capital freed up by the
reductions to shareholders, buy the rest of its brokerage joint
venture and lower its funding and operating costs, New York-
based Chen wrote in a note to clients yesterday. Achieving those
goals can allow the firm, which will probably produce a 5
percent return on tangible equity this year, to earn a 9 percent
ROTE even without an improving environment, Chen said. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer James Gorman pledged to improve
returns as his bank''s stock has lagged below its book value for
more than two-and-a-half years. Gorman, 54, said in October that
it didn''t take heroic assumptions to see how his plans will
get the New York-based firm''s returns to its cost of capital,
usually estimated at around 10 percent. </p>
<p>We believe franchise restoration, healthier market
conditions and the absence of new negatives from here should
drive further share-price outperformance, Chen wrote.
Further proof points and effectuation of the ROTE expansion
plan, with hopefully a better revenue backdrop, will drive a re-
rating of Morgan Stanley (MS) shares from still depressed
valuations. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley has laid out a plan to cut risk-weighted
assets in its fixed-income business, which were $390 billion a
year ago, to $255 billion by the end of 2014, under Basel III
rules. The firm will probably continue to wind down longer-
duration exposures for years after that to arrive at less than
$200 billion by 2017, Chen said. </p>
<h2>Cost Savings </h2>
<p>The bank has about $46 billion of non-productive assets
based on its low fixed-income revenue relative to its peers and
its size, Chen estimated. Those assets, including
uncollateralized over-the-counter derivative trades, face heavy
risk-weightings and may account for one-third of the firm''s $320
billion in RWAs. </p>
<p>Almost half of the estimated increase in the firm''s returns
will come from expense reduction, Chen wrote. The bank has
targeted $1.7 billion in cost savings over the next two years
from actions including completing the integration of its
brokerage and reducing the number of employees, he wrote. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley can also increase pretax earnings by about
$370 million by buying the rest of its brokerage joint venture
and using the deposits gained to replace $22.5 billion of
maturing long-term debt over the next two years, Chen wrote. </p>
<p>There''s a decent likelihood Morgan Stanley will buy
Citigroup Inc.''s remaining 35 percent stake in the brokerage
next year, Chen said. Improvements in that business represent a
low-risk way to improve the firm''s returns, he wrote. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley can raise earnings from its brokerage by
increasing lending and boosting adviser productivity, Chen said.
Mark Lake, a Morgan Stanley spokesman, declined to comment on
Chen''s note. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley gained 0.6 percent to $17.80 in New York.
The shares have climbed 18 percent this year, compared with a 23
percent advance in the 81-company Standard  Poor''s Financial
Index. (S5FINL) </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bryan Bradley" date="Dec 13, 2012  6:40 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-13/microsoft-wins-case-to-close-lithuania-file-share-site-bns-says.html"><headline>Microsoft Wins Case to Close Lithuania File-Share Site, BNS Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) won a court case in
Lithuania to shut down a file-sharing website for copyright
violations and get compensation from the site''s owner, Baltic
News Service reported. </p>
<p>Vilnius Regional Court today fully satisfied the claim that
Microsoft filed in 2009, ordering UAB N5 Grupe to close the site
linkomanija.net and pay damages of 130,000 litai ($49,164), BNS
said, citing the judge, Ona Gasiulyte. </p>
<p>The decision can be appealed, the newswire said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Kathleen Chu and Katsuyo Kuwako" date="Dec 13, 2012  4:56 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-13/morgan-stanley-said-to-sign-lease-to-move-its-tokyo-office.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Signs Mitsubishi Estate Lease for Tokyo Office</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) signed an office
lease with Mitsubishi Estate Co. earlier this month to move its
Japan operations back to Tokyo''s Otemachi business district amid
lower rents. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley will move to Otemachi Financial City South
Tower, in an area neighboring the Imperial Palace, from Tokyo''s
Ebisu district in the first quarter of 2014, the New York-based
company said in an e-mailed statement. Chika Kanamori, a
spokeswoman at Mitsubishi Estate, confirmed the signing of the
lease in an e-mail. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley is taking advantage of lower office rents as
the vacancy rate in Tokyo rose to a record high earlier this
year, while rents in the capital reached a record low in
November, according to Miki Shoji Co., a Tokyo-based office
brokerage company. Otemachi and Marunouchi, both around Tokyo
Station, are home to the local units of financial companies
including JPMorgan Chase  Co. and Citigroup Inc. </p>
<p>Our decision to pursue a new space in Otemachi Financial
City was driven by the rising technological demands of the
business, combined with the attractive conditions for tenants of
prime commercial locations, Morgan Stanley said in the
statement. We believe the relocation will be another positive
development for Morgan Stanley''s franchise in Japan. </p>
<h2>Yebisu Garden </h2>
<p>Sapporo Holdings Ltd. (2501), the landlord of Yebisu Garden Place,
where the New York-based company''s Tokyo office is currently
located, has been notified that Morgan Stanley will be moving
out, said Yuki Hattori, a Tokyo-based spokesman of Sapporo. </p>
<p>We have gotten a number of inquiries about our building
already, said Hattori. We have plenty of time to look for
new tenants. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley moved to Ebisu from Otemachi in 1996,
according to the company''s Japanese website. Ebisu is a mainly
residential neighborhood of boutiques and restaurants, whose
main tourist attraction is the area around Yebisu Garden Place,
where Morgan Stanley is currently based and which also houses
the headquarters of Sapporo Breweries. </p>
<p>Otemachi Financial City, which was completed in October,
consists of two office towers developed and owned by Mitsubishi
Estate, NTT Urban Development Corp. and Tokyo Tatemono Co. A
unit of JFE Holdings Inc. is another confirmed tenant for the
south tower, Mitsubishi Estate said. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Dec 13, 2012 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-13/microsoft-rankles-advertisers-with-web-user-privacy-plan.html"><headline>Microsoft Rankles Advertisers With Web User-Privacy Plan</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) is sticking with a
decision to make it harder to track users'' online behavior,
earning plaudits from privacy groups while drawing fire from the
advertisers its money-losing Web unit needs most. </p>
<p>After months of criticism that the new tools cut off
valuable customer-targeting information, the software maker has
no plans to change the automatic setting in its newest Internet
Explorer browser that tells websites not to track user behavior,
General Counsel Brad Smith said in an interview. </p>
<p>We crossed the Rubicon and are completely comfortable
being on the other side of the river, he said. We have no
intention of going back and have no intention of engaging in
discussion on that possibility. Smith will provide an update
on the company''s position today in a blog posting. </p>
<p>The so-called Do Not Track feature has been at the center
of privacy debates over browsing data and how websites and
marketers use it to make money. For Microsoft and the
advertisers, at stake is a $31.7 billion U.S. Internet ad market
that grew 22 percent in 2011, according to the Interactive
Advertising Bureau, much of it generated by ads tailored to user
behavior. </p>
<p>Now Microsoft, whose banner advertising business was
already losing market share to Facebook Inc. and Google Inc., is
being criticized by trade groups and facing opposition from
advertisers and even partners like Yahoo! Inc. (YHOO), who say they
will ignore privacy signals transmitted by Internet Explorer 10. </p>
<h2>Achilles Heel'' </h2>
<p>Advertisers have invested a lot in their ad platforms and
the Achilles heel is the consumers aren''t aware that their data
is being bought and sold, said Anthony Mullen, an analyst at
Forrester Research Inc. That being exposed, which is what this
Microsoft initiative does, is healthy, but I can see why the ad
industry is nervous. </p>
<p>Microsoft wants to engage in talks with advertisers and
standards bodies to assuage some concerns, Smith said. </p>
<p>In May, Microsoft surprised privacy advocates and some of
its own managers by saying its Internet Explorer 10 browser, the
version included in the new Windows 8, would automatically turn
on a signal that tells advertisers not to follow user behavior.
Other browsers, by contrast, have the Do Not Track signal turned
off and give users the option to turn it on. In Explorer, users
can choose to change the setting to off to enable tracking. </p>
<h2>Default Setting </h2>
<p>Association of National Advertisers President and CEO Bob Liodice said his group opposes the decision to turn on the
signal by default, even after Microsoft made some changes that
make the setting clearer to users. The group, whose board
includes members from Coca-Cola Co. (KO), Wal-Mart Stores Inc.,
Unilever NV and Intel Corp. (INTC), has written Microsoft to register
its opposition. </p>
<p>In an interview, Liodice said Microsoft has expressed a
willingness to talk to advertisers, and they seem amenable to
compromise. </p>
<p>Microsoft''s Smith said the company is willing to discuss
tweaks to how it describes the setting to users, and how easy it
is for users to alter. He also wants the group working on Do Not
Track to set up an easy way for trusted advertisers to gain user
consent to be followed. </p>
<p>For Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft, the world''s
largest software maker, the kerfuffle is the latest challenge to
its ad business. The company wrote down $6.2 billion from the
unit in the quarter that ended June 30, and Microsoft''s U.S.
display business is forecast to grow 13 percent this year, while
the total U.S. market for display ads expands by more than 20
percent, according to data from EMarketer Inc. </p>
<h2>Limited Use </h2>
<p>For now, a lot of the debate over Do Not Track is just
saber-rattling. Internet Explorer 10 was released on Oct. 26
with the newest Windows software, so it''s not in use on many
systems yet. Advertisers are unlikely to pull listings from
Microsoft''s websites in retaliation if the ads make money, said
Clark Fredricksen, a vice president at EMarketer. </p>
<p>Still, advertising industry groups are concerned that
Microsoft may crimp future ad-spending growth by creating a
larger group of Web users who object to being tracked. </p>
<p>Almost all sites collect browsing data and track Web
surfers'' habits to decide which ads to show consumers, and use
the demographic information to persuade advertisers to buy
space. Without this information, ads would be far less
effective, making it harder to generate the ad revenue that
Liodice said pays for much of the content on the Internet. </p>
<h2>Privacy Complaints </h2>
<p>In response to a 2007 complaint by privacy groups such as
the Electronic Frontier Foundation and the Consumer Federation
of America about the tracking and selling of private user data,
the U.S. Federal Trade Commission began examining the idea of a
Do Not Track list. Do Not Track now works by having a browser
send a signal to websites, stating that the user doesn''t want
his or her behavior to be monitored. As the feature was
envisioned, advertisers would voluntarily comply. </p>
<p>All the major browser makers -- Microsoft, Google Inc. (GOOG) and
Mozilla Corp. -- have incorporated Do Not Track signals into
their products. Google and Mozilla have the setting turned off
as a default, requiring users to actively turn it on to block
tracking. </p>
<p>For now it''s not even clear how advertisers wanting to
comply with Do Not Track should behave. A World Wide Web
Consortium working group tasked with devising a standard for Do
Not Track has labored for about 18 months without coming to an
agreement. </p>
<h2>Surprise Decision </h2>
<p>Microsoft''s move was surprising to people both inside and
outside the company. The Internet Explorer team made the
decision over the objections of some of Microsoft''s advertising
officials, said people familiar with the matter, who asked not
to be named because the decision was confidential. </p>
<p>Before the announcement, even Microsoft officials on the Do
No Track working group had raised questions about whether it
made sense to turn the signal on by default, said Jonathan Mayer, a member of the group and a Stanford University graduate
student who is one of the researchers who came up with the
initial idea for the standard. </p>
<p>The Internet Explorer group itself, though, decided that
starting with the setting activated was the best way to protect
consumers. </p>
<p>Seventy-five percent of the consumers we surveyed in the
U.S. and Europe said they wanted DNT on by default,
Microsoft''s Smith wrote in an October blog post. </p>
<h2>Google Challenge </h2>
<p>Microsoft may also be aiming to use privacy as a stick to
beat rival Google with, Mayer said. Google''s Chrome browser has
gained share, rising to 15 percent of the market last month from
10 percent at the end of 2010, according to Net Applications.
Internet Explorer fell to 48 percent from 57 percent. Google is
also poised to seize the No. 1 spot in the display-ad market
this year from Facebook, EMarketer forecasts. </p>
<p>Still, it''s not clear whether the more consumer-oriented
approach will win Microsoft any Chrome users, and it has already
alienated one group -- big advertisers. </p>
<p>In its October letter to Microsoft, Liodice''s Association
of National Advertisers said the default Do Not Track setting
will hurt advertising, reduce the amount of Internet content
supported by those ads and ultimately undermine American
innovation and leadership in the Internet economy. </p>
<p>Both that association and the Digital Advertising Alliance
are recommending advertisers ignore Do Not Track signals coming
from Internet Explorer 10. Yahoo, the biggest U.S. Web portal
and Microsoft''s partner in search, has said it will ignore the
setting. </p>
<h2>Consumer Information </h2>
<p>The Internet is funded by advertisers, Liodice said.
The ability to reach our consumers requires that we absorb
information from them. </p>
<p>And even if Microsoft and the advertisers can make peace,
Do Not Track still faces major challenges. Every Wednesday at 9
a.m. San Francisco time, Mayer spends 90 minutes on a conference
call with other members of the workgroup and any advertisers or
industry members that want to join. There''s been no progress
toward agreeing on a standard to guide advertisers on how to
abide by Do Not Track, he said. </p>
<p>Everything that could be said has been said, he said.
There are fundamental differences of opinion. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Robert Fenner and Brendan Case" date="Dec 14, 2012  4:18 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-14/coca-cola-femsa-to-pay-689-million-for-51-in-philippines-firm.html"><headline>Coca-Cola Femsa to Buy 51% of Coke Bottler in Philippines</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Coca-Cola Femsa SAB (KOFL), the largest
publicly traded Coke bottler by volume, agreed to buy a 51
percent stake in Coca-Cola Bottlers Philippines Inc. for $689
million in its first acquisition outside of Latin America. </p>
<p>The agreement includes an option for Coca-Cola Femsa to buy
the rest of the Philippines bottler within seven years of the
deal closing, the Mexico City-based company said in a statement.
It will also have the option to sell its ownership to Coca-Cola
Co. (KO) any time during year six, it said. </p>
<p>The deal gives Coca-Cola Femsa access to a nation of about
95 million people with a Coke-products consumption per capita
that was 40 percent above the worldwide average last year. The
Philippines operation will sell about 530 million cases of
beverages this year, about 17 percent of Coca Cola Femsa''s
volume, according to JPMorgan Chase  Co. estimates. </p>
<p>The Mexican bottler is buying its way into what could
potentially become a whole new Southeast Asian opportunity in
the long term, Antonio Gonzalez, an analyst with Credit Suisse
Group AG, wrote in a report. There are not that many bottlers
in a position to have such serious global aspirations. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola Femsa rose 1.2 percent to 187.93 pesos at the
Mexico City close. Fomento Economico Mexicano SAB, which
controls the bottler, rose 1.1 percent to 126.01 pesos. Coca-
Cola, based in Atlanta, rose 0.2 percent $37.66 in New York. </p>
<h2>Enterprise Value </h2>
<p>The deal is expected to close early next year, according to
the statement. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola, the world''s biggest soft-drink maker, has owned
all of the Philippines unit since buying the 65 percent stake
owned by San Miguel Corp. (SMC) in 2007 for $590 million. </p>
<p>This announcement reflects our long-standing belief in
the global franchise system, Coca-Cola Chief Executive Officer
Muhtar Kent said in the statement. </p>
<p>The purchase price represents an enterprise value of $1.35
billion for the Philippines bottler, at a multiple of about 13.5
times expected 2012 earnings before interest, tax, depreciation
and amortization, or Ebitda, according to the statement. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola Femsa spent more than 24 billion pesos ($1.88
billion) since the start of 2011 to acquire soft drink makers
and add bottling rights. It bought the beverage unit of Grupo
Fomento Queretano for 6.6 billion pesos and the bottling
operations of Grupo Cimsa for 11 billion pesos. The company also
paid 6.55 billion pesos for the Coke division of Grupo Tampico
SA. </p>
<h2>Deal Multiples </h2>
<p>Those deals had multiples of between 9.6 times and 10 times
Ebitda, according to Alan Alanis, an analyst at JPMorgan in New
York. Coca-Cola Femsa paid about $2.50 per unit case of volume
in the Philippines deal, compared with about $4.80 in its
Mexican deals, Gonzalez said. </p>
<p>Coca-Cola Femsa is 49 percent owned by Fomento Economico
Mexicano and Coca-Cola has a 29 percent stake, according to its
website. The Bill  Melinda Gates Foundation and Cascade
Investment LLC, which manages money for billionaire Gates, own
about 19 percent of Coca-Cola Femsa''s American depositary
receipts, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>In addition to its home market, Coca-Cola Femsa has rights
to sell drinks such as Coke, Sprite and Fanta in parts of
Guatemala, Nicaragua, Costa Rica, Panama, Colombia, Venezuela,
Brazil and Argentina, according to its website. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Dec 14, 2012  3:40 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-14/morgan-stanley-names-heads-of-merger-advisory-for-u-s-europe.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Names Merger-Advisory Chiefs for U.S., Europe</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS), the second-ranked
adviser of announced mergers this year, named Bob Eatroff and
Jim Head co-chiefs of mergers and acquisitions in the Americas
as the firm reshapes its investment bank''s leadership. </p>
<p>Colm Donlon and Johannes Groeller will lead MA in Europe,
the Middle East and Africa, according to an internal memo
obtained by Bloomberg News. Rob Kindler, 58, remains global head
of the business. Mary Claire Delaney, a spokeswoman for New
York-based Morgan Stanley, confirmed the contents of the memo. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley is shuffling top executives in its
investment bank after Colm Kelleher, 55, took control of that
business in addition to his oversight of the firm''s trading
operations. Paul Taubman, 51, who oversaw investment banking,
said last month he was retiring at the end of this year. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley has ranked first or second in advising on
mergers and acquisitions each year since 2008. The firm produced
$915 million in advisory revenue in the first nine months of
2012, a 31 percent drop from a year earlier as completed global
deal volume fell 23 percent. </p>
<p>The Wall Street Journal reported the appointments earlier
today. The changes are effective Jan. 1. </p>
<p>Mark Eichorn, who previously led MA in the U.S., was named
global co-head of investment banking with Franck Petitgas, 51,
last month. Michele Colocci, who was named head of the MA group
in Europe in 2010, will become a vice chairman of investment
banking and will remain chairman of European MA, according to a
person briefed on the matter, who asked not to be identified
because the information hasn''t been made public. </p>
<h2>Eaton Deal </h2>
<p>Eatroff previously ran Morgan Stanley''s technology
investment-banking group on the East Coast and advised Deutsche
Telekom AG on the pending merger of its T-Mobile USA unit with
MetroPCS Communications Inc. He also advised Comcast Corp. on
its purchase of a controlling interest in NBC Universal. </p>
<p>Head previously helped lead the firm''s financial services
merger-advisory group for the U.S. and Canada. He was on the
team that advised the Federal Reserve Bank of New York on its
dealings with American International Group Inc. during the
financial crisis, and advised First Data Corp. on its 2007 sale
to KKR  Co. </p>
<p>Donlon advised equipment maker Eaton Corp. on its $11.8
billion purchase of Cooper Industries Plc, a maker of electric-
distribution equipment, which was completed last month. He also
advised Dutch lender ABN Amro Bank NV on its 2007 sale to Royal
Bank of Scotland Plc. </p>
<p>Groeller previously served as co-head of investment banking
in Germany and Austria. He advised Porsche SE on the sale of its
automotive business to Volkswagen AG, and Daimler AG on its
disposition of a stake in European Aeronautic, Defence  Space
Co. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Anchalee Worrachate" date="Dec 14, 2012  2:02 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-14/jpmorgan-names-chang-as-global-head-of-fixed-income-research.html"><headline>JPMorgan Names Chang as Global Head of Fixed-Income Research</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) named Joyce Chang as its global head of fixed-income research, according to
an internal company memo seen by Bloomberg News and confirmed by
London-based spokesman Patrick Burton. </p>
<p>Chang replaced Terry Belton, who was appointed the head of
global portfolio strategy in the bank''s chief investment office
last week, Burton said. Chang, who is based in New York, was
previously the company''s global head of emerging-market
research. In her new role, she will assume global responsibility
for foreign-exchange, rates, securitized-products and public-
finance research, the memo said. </p>
<p>John Normand''s role as the global head of foreign-exchange
strategy in London will be expanded to include interest-rate
strategy for Europe, Japan and Australia, according to the same
document. He will report to Chang, the memo showed. </p>
<p>Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon has overhauled
management during a year marred by more than $6.2 billion in
losses at JPMorgan''s chief investment office. In July, he
combined treasury services with the corporate and investment
banks to create a new unit. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Bob Van Voris and Andrew Harris" date="Dec 15, 2012 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-15/jpmorgan-muni-bond-rigging-settlement-wins-final-approval-1-.html"><headline>JPMorgan Muni Bond Rigging Accord Wins Final U.S. Court Approval</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) won a judge''s
final approval of a $44.6 million settlement of a class-action
lawsuit alleging that the bank rigged bids for municipal bonds. </p>
<p>U.S. District Judge Victor Marrero in New York issued the
order yesterday. The judge had given preliminary approval to the
accord in June. </p>
<p>The settlement was attained following an extensive
investigation of the facts, Marrero wrote in his five-page
order. It resulted from vigorous arm''s-length negotiations
which were undertaken in good faith by counsel with significant
experience litigating antitrust class actions. </p>
<p>The case was filed by bond issuers alleging JPMorgan Chase
and other banks rigged bids and restrained, suppressed or
eliminated competition for municipal derivatives, according to
court papers. </p>
<p>The accord approved by Marrero yesterday involved only
JPMorgan Chase and its Bear Stearns unit. Other banks settled
previously. </p>
<p>In his June 4 preliminary-approval order, the judge had
certified a class of state, local and municipal government and
other entities that had purchased municipal derivatives through
negotiation, competitive bidding or auction, from the bank or
any alleged provider or broker co-defendant or co-conspirator
between January 1992 and August 2011. </p>
<h2>Escrow Account </h2>
<p>JPMorgan, which has already deposited $24 million into a
settlement escrow account, must now add $18.6 million more,
according to Marrero''s order. The bank''s agreement to settle
didn''t constitute an admission of wrongdoing that can be used in
any other civil or criminal proceeding, the judge said. </p>
<p>Its the beginning of a series of other settlements that
we will be announcing over time, in the municipal derivatives
litigation, plaintiffs'' lawyer Michael D. Hausfeld said in a
phone interview. </p>
<p>He called yesterday''s approved accord satisfactory in the
context of earlier settlements between the defendant banks and
states'' attorneys general. Hausfeld is the principal of the
Washington law firm Hausfeld LLP. </p>
<p>Jennifer Zuccarelli, a spokeswoman for the New York-based
bank, declined to comment on the court order. </p>
<p>The case is In Re Municipal Derivatives Antitrust
Litigation, 08-cv-2516, U.S. District Court, Southern District
of New York (Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Janelle Lawrence" date="Dec 15, 2012 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-15/goldman-sachs-handled-dragon-sale-well-ex-analyst-says.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Handled Dragon Sale Well, Ex-Analyst Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A former Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS)
analyst testified that his team did a great job in helping
Dragon Systems Inc. sell itself to a Belgian firm that dissolved
in an accounting scandal six months later. </p>
<p>Alexander Berzofsky, speaking in a videotaped deposition
played yesterday for jurors in federal court in Boston, answered
questions from a lawyer for Dragon Systems'' former owners, who
are suing the bank over its advice on the deal. </p>
<p>You''re saying Goldman did a great job for Dragon? asked
Alan K. Cotler, the attorney for Jim and Janet Baker who founded
the speech recognition developer in their suburban Boston home
30 years ago. </p>
<p>Yes, Berzofsky replied. </p>
<p>The fact that Jim and Janet Baker lost their life''s work
doesn''t affect your opinion that Goldman did a great job for
them, right? Cotler asked. </p>
<p>Correct, said Berzofsky, who left Goldman Sachs in 2000
and is now a managing director at Warburg Pincus LLC, a private
equity firm. </p>
<p>Dragon''s founders claim that a four-man team of Goldman
Sachs bankers assigned to the transaction committed gross
negligence by failing to pursue questions about Lernout 
Hauspie Speech Products NV''s finances that should have led them
to avoid the $580 million all-stock deal. </p>
<p>They say they lost their company and access to the
technology they had spent their careers developing, including
Dragon NaturallySpeaking dictation software, when Lernout 
Hauspie filed for bankruptcy protection in November 2000. The
deal closed in June of that year. </p>
<h2>Competent Advice </h2>
<p>Goldman Sachs claims its team gave Dragon competent advice
and says it urged company management to press their accountants,
at Arthur Andersen LLP, to probe Lernout  Hauspie''s finances. </p>
<p>U.S. District Judge Patti Saris, who is presiding over the
case, said the trial, which began Dec. 10, may last until Jan.
25. </p>
<p>On Dec. 13, the jury heard testimony from Richard Wayner, a
senior member of the Goldman Sachs team on the Dragon deal.
Wayner said Goldman Sachs had unanswered questions about Lernout
 Hauspie''s suspicious surges in sales in Asia -- revenue that
turned out to be fictitious -- but never sought to stop Dragon
from selling. </p>
<h2>Satisfactory Answers'' </h2>
<p>Wayner said that after informing Dragon that Goldman Sachs
didn''t received satisfactory answers from Lernout  Hauspie, it
was the client''s decision whether or not they want to do the
deal. </p>
<p>Berzofsky, a 1996 Harvard graduate who was 25 at the time
of the Dragon sale, said due diligence was up to Dragon. His
team''s job wasshepherding the deal, he said. </p>
<p>Attorneys for Dragon showed him Goldman Sachs marketing
materials touting the firm''s devotion to its clients and
commitment to excellence. </p>
<p>Did it ever cross your mind that after Lernout  Hauspie
went bankrupt and was found out to be a fraud, did it ever cross
your mind that maybe you and your team did not meet that
principle of achieving excellence on behalf of Jim and Janet
Baker? Cotler asked. </p>
<p>It never crossed my mind, Berzofsky replied. </p>
<p>During the deposition, Berzofsky lounged back in his chair,
ate snacks and repeatedly stroked the back of his head. </p>
<h2>No Recall </h2>
<p>He yawned when attorneys show him a document related to
Goldman Sachs''s decision to walk away from making any
investments of its own in Lernout  Hauspie in the late 1990s
and said he didn''t recall ever seeing the document. </p>
<p>Dragon paid Goldman Sachs $5 million for its work under an
agreement that would have paid the bankers only $150,000 per
quarter if the sale didn''t occur, according to testimony in the
case. </p>
<p>What did you do for $5 million? Cotler asked. </p>
<p>We gave them advice on how to sell their company,
Berzofsky replied. </p>
<p>The case is Baker v. Goldman Sachs  Co., 09-cv-10053, U.S.
District Court, District of Massachusetts (Boston). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Chris Dolmetsch" date="Dec 17, 2012  6:31 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-17/jpmorgan-goldman-ask-judge-to-dismiss-mortgage-lawsuit.html"><headline>JPMorgan, Goldman Ask Judge to Dismiss Mortgage Lawsuit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), Goldman Sachs
Group Inc. (GS) and other banks asked a New York state judge to
dismiss a $1.8 billion lawsuit brought by residential mortgage-
backed securities investors. </p>
<p>The investors, which included Phoenix Light SF Ltd., sued
New York-based JPMorgan, Goldman Sachs and the other lenders in
New York state Supreme Court in Manhattan in May, accusing them
of making misrepresentations about the loans backing the
securities. </p>
<p>The defendants in documents filed on Dec. 14 asked Justice
Charles E. Ramos to dismiss the suit, saying the investors
failed to show they''re entitled to the requested relief and that
their claims are barred by a three-year statute of limitations
under German law. The defendants also say the investors have
failed to identify any actionable misrepresentation that
they relied upon. </p>
<p>Plaintiffs made their purchases before the bulk of the
prospectus supplements containing the alleged misrepresentations
were even created or filed, and, as some of the most
sophisticated investors in the world, plaintiffs had an
affirmative duty to conduct an independent investigation into
the risks associated with their investments, the banks said in
the court documents. </p>
<h2>Legal Claims </h2>
<p>Phoenix is a limited liability company based in Dublin that
inherited legal claims from six separate legal entities that
collapsed or nearly collapsed, according to the complaint. </p>
<p>The entities include Dusseldorf, Germany-based WestLB, the
180-year-old German state-owned lender that ceased operations on
June 29 as part of European Union conditions tied to a 17
billion-euro ($22.4 billion) bailout following the 2008
financial crisis, according to the complaint. </p>
<p>Investors including Phoenix Light have filed similar suits
in the same court over the past year, including a complaint
filed against Deutsche Bank AG in February and actions against
Bank of America filed in September and November. </p>
<p>Pools of home loans securitized into bonds were a central
part of the housing bubble that helped send the U.S. into the
biggest recession since the 1930s. The housing market collapsed,
and the crisis swept up lenders and investment banks as the
market for the securities evaporated. </p>
<p>The case is Phoenix Light SF Ltd. v. JPMorgan Securities
LLC, 651755-2012, New York state Supreme Court (Manhattan). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Maria Kolesnikova and Joe Richter" date="Dec 17, 2012  5:53 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-17/jpmorgan-wins-approval-for-first-u-s-physical-copper-etf.html"><headline>JPMorgan Wins Approval for First U.S. Physical Copper ETF</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) won regulatory
approval for the first U.S. exchange-traded fund backed by
physical copper, which some industrial users said may disrupt
the market. </p>
<p>The proposed rule change by NYSE Arca Inc. to list JPM XF
Physical Copper Trust was approved, the regulator said in an
order on its website dated Dec. 14. BlackRock Inc. (BLK) and ETF
Securities Ltd. also have said they plan to start physically
backed ETFs for industrial metals in the U.S. </p>
<p>A group of industrial copper consumers including AmRod
Corp., Southwire Co. and Encore Wire Corp. (WIRE) and hedge fund RK
Capital LLP opposed the plan, saying funds backed by copper
would leave less of the metal available for manufacturers,
creating shortages and driving up prices. Senator Carl Levin, a
Michigan Democrat who in July had advised rejecting the ETF,
said in a statement today that the approval is a blow to
American businesses and consumers that rely on copper, and
that Congress should review the move. </p>
<p>A study released last month by an SEC division concluded
that asset flows from exchange-traded products tied to metals
don''t have a significant impact on the price of the commodity.
Those findings were disputed by the copper-users group. </p>
<p>Patrick Burton, a London-based spokesman for JPMorgan,
declined to comment on when the firm plans to introduce the
fund. </p>
<p>ETFs trade like stocks, giving investors access to
commodities such as copper without taking physical delivery. ETF
Securities started the first exchange-traded products backed by
copper, nickel and tin in London in December 2010. Company data
shows that the copper fund holds about 2,000 metric tons of the
metal, compared with more than 20 million tons that the
International Copper Study Group said will be mined and used
this year. </p>
<h2>Surplus Metal </h2>
<p>Copper will have its first production surplus in four
years, with output set to top demand by 458,000 tons next year,
the ICSG said Oct. 10. </p>
<p>Inventories of the metal in warehouses tracked by the
London Metal Exchange, down 19 percent this year, climbed 9.5
percent in a day to 298,625 tons, the most since Sept. 5, 2008,
exchange data showed today. Inventories tracked by the Shanghai
Futures Exchange advanced for a second week, rising 7,406 tons
to 205,385 tons, data from the bourse showed Dec. 14. </p>
<p>NYSE Arca Inc., the electronic platform of NYSE Euronext,
filed with the SEC to list and trade JPM XF Physical Copper
Trust, according to an April 2 document. It sought approval to
list BlackRock''s iShares Copper Trust on June 19. </p>
<p>Through Dec. 14, copper for delivery in three months
climbed 6.1 percent to $8,065 a ton on the LME this year. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Edward Klump" date="Dec 17, 2012  4:09 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-17/exxon-agrees-to-buy-stake-in-offshore-south-africa-blocks.html"><headline>Exxon Agrees to Buy Stake in Offshore South Africa Blocks</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM), the biggest U.S.
oil company, will begin exploring off the coast of South Africa
after it agreed to buy a 75 percent stake in blocks owned by
Impact Oil  Gas Ltd. </p>
<p>Exxon will control operations in the area it''s acquiring in
the Tugela South Exploration Right from closely held Impact,
according to a statement from the Irving, Texas-based company
today. Terms weren''t disclosed for the acquisition, which
includes the right to buy a 75 percent stake in three other
offshore areas Impact has permits to study. </p>
<p>Exxon has been facing production declines as discoveries
from past decades falter and governments in the Middle East and
Latin America prohibit exploration by foreign businesses or make
it too expensive. The company is turning to South Africa, which
has become one of Africa''s hottest attractions for energy
producers such as Royal Dutch Shell Plc (RDSA) and Anadarko Petroleum
Corp. (APC) </p>
<p>South Africa is one of the new areas offshore that there
seems to be growing interest in, Brian Youngberg, an analyst
at Edward Jones in St. Louis, said in a telephone interview.
Thoughts have been that South Africa is probably an uptapped
market that could really see production grow in coming years. </p>
<p>Exxon doesn''t have any existing operations in South Africa
and will explore for oil and natural gas, Patrick McGinn, a
company spokesman, said in e-mailed responses to questions
today. Information on the cost and schedule of Exxon''s
exploration program is considered confidential, he said. </p>
<h2>Exploration Rights </h2>
<p>The Tugela South Exploration Right covers 2.8 million acres
near Durban off the east coast of South Africa, in water depths
of as much as 6,500 feet (2,000 meters). The additional
exploration rights cover 16 million offshore acres. </p>
<p>Impact, based in London, has one of the largest holdings
off the South African coast by a closely held company, according
to its website. </p>
<p>We believe South Africa has significant potential and we
will continue to look for additional opportunities there,
Stephen Greenlee, president of Exxon''s exploration company, said
in the statement. </p>
<p>Separately, the company also got a permit from the South
African government to study the potential of the deep-water
Durban Basin, covering about 12.4 million acres. Exxon has
exclusive rights to study the area for a year and can seek a
permit if it wants to explore further. </p>
<h2>Orange Basin </h2>
<p>Last month, The Hague-based Shell said it was collecting
seismic data in the Orange Basin off the north-west coast of
South Africa. The company may make a decision on drilling in the
next year or so. Anadarko, based in The Woodlands, Texas, has
interests in about 24 million gross acres off western South
Africa, according to a company presentation. </p>
<p>Exxon is lagging behind rivals in finding new energy
sources. It found enough oil and gas last year to replace 107
percent of what it pumped from wells, a so-called reserve-
replacement ratio that was less than one-third that of OAO
Rosneft, data compiled by Bloomberg show. Exxon formed a
partnership with Russia''s Rosneft last year to increase its
access to resources in the Arctic and Black Sea region. </p>
<p>Exxon, in a report earlier this month, raised its long-term
global energy-demand growth estimate to 35 percent from 32
percent as expanding populations in Africa and India use more
electricity. </p>
<p>The company remains growth-challenged given its size and
scale, and it''s hard for Exxon to find new areas that can
really move the needle, said Youngberg, who has a hold
rating on Exxon shares and doesn''t own any. If South African
exploration is successful, production may come online near the
end of the decade, he said. </p>
<p>They have the cash flow to explore numerous areas around
the world on an ongoing basis in order to hopefully find some
new production that could help them over time, Youngberg said. </p>
<p>Exxon rose 0.9 percent to $88.87 at the close in New York. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Andrew Harris and Jesse Hamilton" date="Dec 17, 2012 12:48 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-17/jpmorgan-sued-by-credit-union-agency-over-mbs-documents.html"><headline>JPMorgan Sued by Credit Union Agency Over MBS Documents</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The National Credit Union
Administration board sued a J.P. Morgan Chase  Co. (JPM) unit
claiming Bear Stearns  Co., which it acquired in 2008, used
misleading documents in selling $3.6 billion in mortgage-backed
securities to four credit unions that later failed. </p>
<p>The documents said the mortgage originators had adhered to
underwriting guidelines that actually had been systematically
abandoned, the credit union agency said in a federal court
lawsuit filed Dec. 14 in Kansas City, Kansas. </p>
<p>Because the mortgages in the pools collateralizing the
RMBS were largely underwritten without adherence to the
underwriting standards in the offering statements, the RMBS were
significantly riskier than represented, the National Credit
Union Administration said in its complaint. </p>
<p>The Alexandria, Virginia-based agency is responsible for
recovering losses to minimize the costs to its industry-funded
stabilization fund. Its complaint was filed as liquidator of the
U.S. Central Federal Credit Union and the Western Corporate
Federal Credit Union, both placed into conservatorship in 2009
and involuntary liquidation a year later, and the Southwest
Corporate Federal Credit Union and Members United Corporate
Federal Credit Union, which were placed in conservatorship and
then liquidation in 2010. </p>
<h2>JPMorgan Spokeswoman </h2>
<p>Jennifer Zuccarelli, a JPMorgan spokeswoman, didn''t
immediately respond to a telephone message seeking comment. </p>
<p>Today''s complaint follows similar lawsuits the credit union
agency filed against other banks, including one in September
against Barclays Plc (BARC) and those previously against a unit of
Credit Suisse Group AG, Royal Bank of Scotland Group Plc, the
Wachovia Corp. unit of Wells Fargo  Co. (WFC) and Goldman Sachs Group (GS)
Inc. </p>
<p>JPMorgan was also the target of a separate claim in June
2011. </p>
<p>Barclays last month filed papers seeking dismissal of the
lawsuit against it, arguing the claims were filed too late. </p>
<h2>Earlier Accords </h2>
<p>Deutsche Bank AG, Citigroup Inc. (C) and HSBC Holdings Plc (HSBA)
agreed in November 2011 and March to pay a combined $171 million
to resolve similar accusations, with $145 million from Deutsche
Bank, $20.5 million from Citigroup and $5.3 million from HSBC.
The banks didn''t admit or deny wrongdoing. </p>
<p>Firms like Bear, Stearns acted unfairly by ignoring the
rules for underwriting, NCUA Board Chairman Debbie Matz, said
today in a statement. They packaged these securities and then
told buyers the paper was sound. When the securities plunged in
value, we learned the truth. NCUA is now working to hold these
underwriters accountable and secure recoveries on behalf of
federally insured credit unions. </p>
<p>The case is National Credit Union Administration Board v.
Bear Stearns  Co., 12-cv-2781, U.S. District Court, District of
Kansas (Kansas City). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Elizabeth Campbell, Joe Richter and Nicholas Larkin" date="Dec 18, 2012  6:14 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-18/goldman-bullish-with-hedge-funds-amid-citi-warning-commodities.html"><headline>Goldman Bullish With Hedge Funds Amid Citi Warning: Commodities</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Investors almost doubled purchases
of commodities this year, at a time when Goldman Sachs Group
Inc. and Morgan Stanley are forecasting higher prices and
Citigroup Inc. (C) says the best returns are over. </p>
<p>Money invested in commodity funds increased by $21.6
billion this year, up 92 percent from the gain in 2011,
according to Cambridge, Massachusetts-based EPFR Global, which
tracks the flows. Hedge funds'' bets on a rally are 51 percent
bigger than a year ago, U.S. government data show. Precious
metals will lead returns in 2013, rising as much as 25 percent,
as grains advance 18 percent and industrial metals 16 percent,
according to a Bloomberg survey of 131 traders, investors and
analysts across 15 raw materials. </p>
<p>While commodities are headed for their first annual retreat
since 2008, growth in emerging markets will boost demand and
tighten supply, Goldman Sachs'' analysts said in a report Dec. 5.
The Standard  Poor''s GSCI gauge of 24 raw materials almost
tripled in the past decade as producers failed to keep up with
consumption. That super cycle of returns has now ended
because China is growing more slowly and supply has caught up,
Citigroup''s analysts said in a report last month. </p>
<p>It comes back to the uncertainty about the economy, and
the government policies that are going to be enacted or
potentially changing over the next year, said Peter Jankovskis, who helps oversee about $3 billion of assets as co-
chief investment officer at Lisle, Illinois-based Oakbrook
Investments LLC. That''s why you''re seeing that disparity in
the outlooks of many of these forecasting firms. </p>
<h2>Trading Partners </h2>
<p>The SP GSCI fell 0.7 percent this year, the worst
performance since a 43 percent drop in 2008, with the biggest
declines in coffee, cotton, sugar and crude oil. The MSCI All-
Country World Index (MXWD) of equities advanced 14 percent and the
Dollar Index, a measure against six major trading partners,
dropped 1 percent. Treasuries returned 2 percent, a Bank of
America Corp. index shows. </p>
<p>The declines in crude and gasoline are driving the SP GSCI
lower because energy accounts for about 70 percent of the gauge
by weight. Eighteen members of the index advanced this year, led
by gains of 23 percent or more in wheat and soybeans as U.S.
farmers endured the worst drought in a half century. Gold is
headed for a 12th consecutive annual increase, driven by central
bank stimulus, and corn and cattle reached records. </p>
<h2>Increasing Consumption </h2>
<p>Accelerating economic growth in the second half of 2013
will spur more demand, said Jeffrey Currie, Goldman''s New York-
based head of commodity research, predicting a 7 percent return
in commodities over 12 months. Increasing consumption will curb
available supply, boosting near-term prices relative to longer-
dated contracts, he wrote in the report. </p>
<p>Demand for energy and grains will be resilient and
delayed harvests in South America will limit corn and soybean
supplies, Hussein Allidina and Peter Richardson, analysts at
Morgan Stanley in New York and Melbourne, wrote in a Dec. 6
report. Economies will accelerate in the second half of next
year should central banks extend stimulus measures, they said.
Policy makers from Japan to China to Europe to the U.S. have
pledged to do more if growth weakens. </p>
<p>Citigroup says prices that have risen in nine of the past
10 years are spurring more investment in production, creating
supply gluts, according to a Nov. 19 report by Edward L. Morse,
the bank''s New York-based global head of commodities research.
Output will exceed demand next year in 10 of the 15 commodities
covered in the Bloomberg survey, according to supply and demand
estimates from either Barclays Plc or Rabobank International. </p>
<h2>Central Bank </h2>
<p>The European Central Bank said Dec. 6 it expects the 17-
nation euro-area''s economy to shrink 0.3 percent next year,
having previously forecast growth. Europe accounts for about 18
percent of copper demand and 14 percent of global energy
consumption, Barclays and BP Plc (BP/) data show. </p>
<p>Hedge funds pared bullish wagers in the fourth quarter,
with net-long positions dropping 35 percent since the end of
September, U.S. Commodity Futures Trading Commission data show.
While the Bloomberg survey shows that everything from cotton to
soybeans will gain at least 9.9 percent in 2013, the analysts
have been wrong before. In last year''s survey, only three of the
15 commodities covered reached their projected highs in 2012. </p>
<p>Commodities tend to be victims of their own success,
said Jack Ablin, who helps oversee about $66 billion of assets
as chief investment officer of BMO Private Bank in Chicago. If
you think about industrial metals, we have now dug a little
deeper, and we''ve mined a little more, and now we have
unprecedented inventories. </p>
<h2>World Growth </h2>
<p>Commodity assets under management rose 8.6 percent to $429
billion in the first 10 months of 2012, according to London-
based Barclays. Contracts outstanding across the members of the
SP GSCI advanced 12 percent this year, data compiled by
Bloomberg show. Holdings in gold-backed exchange-traded products
jumped 12 percent and were last valued at $143.6 billion. </p>
<p>World growth will accelerate to 3.6 percent in 2013, from
3.3 percent this year, according to the International Monetary
Fund. China''s economy, the biggest consumer of everything from
coal to cotton to copper, will accelerate in the fourth quarter,
after slowing for seven consecutive quarters, the median of 30
economist estimates compiled by Bloomberg show. </p>
<p>More central-bank stimulus means investors will continue to
buy gold to protect against inflation and currency debasement,
and prices will average a record $1,853 an ounce in 2013, Morgan
Stanley predicts. Gold for immediate delivery slid 1.6 percent
to settle at $1,671.10. Goldman says the prices will probably
peak next year because of improving U.S. growth. </p>
<h2>Tax Increases </h2>
<p>Demand for gold may also be boosted by mounting concern
that U.S. growth will slow. The Federal Reserve doesn''t have
the tools to counter the risks should lawmakers fail to reach
an agreement on about $600 billion in tax increases and spending
cuts that start automatically next month, Chairman Ben S.
Bernanke said Dec. 12. Bullion will rise as much as 18 percent
to $2,000 in 2013, the median of 49 estimates in the Bloomberg
survey shows. </p>
<p>Soybeans and corn reached records this year and wheat
touched an almost four-year high as drought parched fields in
the U.S., the biggest agricultural exporter. Wheat will beat
corn and soybeans in 2013, advancing as much as 18 percent,
according to the median of 32 predictions. Citigroup expects
grain and soybean prices to be supported in the first half of
next year as supplies remain tight. </p>
<p>Arabica coffee is expected to have the biggest gain among
the 15 commodities in the survey, climbing as much as 33 percent
after slumping 36 percent in 2012. Nickel may be the best-
performing industrial metal, rising as much as 16 percent, while
copper will gain 12 percent, the survey showed. </p>
<h2>Profit Measure </h2>
<p>The gains may boost earnings for suppliers. BHP Billiton
Ltd. (BHP), the largest mining company, will report a 6.7 percent gain
in its most-closely tracked profit measure to $7.66 billion in
its fiscal second half ending June 30, the mean of five
estimates shows. Shares of the Melbourne-based producer rose 6.5
percent this year, and may climb 4.4 percent to A$38.28 in 12
months, according to the average of 20 forecasts. </p>
<p>It won''t be a straight line higher, but there''s a pretty
good undertow for commodities, said James Paulsen, the
Minneapolis-based chief investment strategist at Wells Capital
Management, which oversees about $325 billion of assets.
Commodities in general will trend higher the next few years,
but there''s room for selectivity. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Drew Armstrong" date="Dec 18, 2012  4:15 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-18/pfizer-to-fire-about-20-percent-of-u-s-primary-care-sales-force.html"><headline>Pfizer Said to Fire 20% of U.S. Primary-Care Sales Force</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE), the company that lost
its patent a year ago on the top-selling drug Lipitor, is firing
almost 20 percent of its roughly 3,000-person sales force for
primary-care drugs, said a person familiar with the matter. </p>
<p>The cuts, about 600 positions, are to begin this month and
are part of the New York-based company''s continuing effort to
lower costs, said the person, who asked not to be named because
they weren''t authorized to discuss the matter publicly. </p>
<p>Pfizer has been cutting expenses under Chief Executive
Officer Ian Read as it seeks to reposition itself after the loss
of Lipitor, the cholesterol-lowering medicine that generated
$9.6 billion in revenue in 2011. Read has said he''s refocusing
the company to bring new drugs to market as it continues to
integrate a decade''s worth of acquisitions. </p>
<p>As part of our strategy to allocate our resources,
investments and people to the areas that best serve our patients
and customers, we continually evaluate how we can be more
efficient and effective, Mackay Jimeson, a Pfizer spokesman,
wrote in an e-mail. As a result, we are making changes in some
segments of our field force to better match the future needs of
the business. </p>
<p>Pfizer rose 1.1 percent to $25.64 at 4 p.m. New York time.
The stock is up 18 percent since the start of the year. </p>
<p>Primary-care drugs make up Pfizer''s top-selling products,
and include the erectile dysfunction pill Viagra, pain therapy
Lyrica and the arthritis treatment Celebrex. </p>
<p>Pfizer had 103,700 employees at the end of 2011, according
to corporate filings. The company may hire more workers this
spring, assuming the U.S. approval and sales start of its
experimental blood thinner Eliquis, according to the person.
Pfizer is developing Eliquis with Bristol-Myers Squibb Co. (BMY) The
two companies will split sales. </p>
<p>Before the firings, Pfizer had about 3,000 primary-care
salespeople and managers, according to PharmaForce
International, which tracks drugmaker sales forces and provides
market intelligence. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Stephanie Bodoni" date="Dec 18, 2012  3:51 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-18/microsoft-scrutinized-by-eu-privacy-watchdogs-for-policy-changes.html"><headline>Microsoft Scrutinized by EU Privacy Watchdogs for Policy Changes</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT)''s policy changes for its Internet products including Hotmail and Bing are being formally examined by European data protection regulators for potential privacy issues. </p> <p>Updates to Microsoft''s services agreement, which took effect Oct. 19, are being formally reviewed, EU privacy regulators wrote to Microsoft Chief Executive Officer Steve Ballmer and the head of Microsoft Luxembourg. Luxembourg''s and France''s data protection commissions are leading the examination, according to the Dec. 17 letter, obtained by Bloomberg News. </p> <p>Given the wide range of services you offer, and popularity of these services, changes in your Services Agreement and the linked Privacy Policy may affect many individuals in most or all of the EU member states, wrote Jacob Kohnstamm, who leads the association of EU data protection commissioners. They decided to check the possible consequences for the protection of the personal data of these individuals in a coordinated procedure. </p> <p>The review will verify whether the changes could entail new risks for users'' privacy. The examination is also checking whether Redmond, Washington-based Microsoft''s privacy policy meets European standards on notifying users and allowing them a choice of services, Gerard Lommel, head of the Luxembourg privacy regulator, said in an interview in October. </p> <h2>Privacy Policy </h2> <p>In updating the Microsoft Services Agreement we did not change our privacy policy, said Robin Koch, a spokesman for Microsoft in Brussels. We are confident they will find Microsoft''s long-standing commitment to privacy has not changed. </p> <p>The 27 EU data protection regulators, who work together in the so-called Article 29 Data Protection Working Party, urged Google Inc. to address concerns about its privacy policy in October following a review of changes implemented this year. </p> <p>Data protection is currently policed by separate regulators across the EU. As part of an overhaul of the union''s 17-year-old rules on the issue, its executive body wants to simplify the system so companies deal with only one regulator in the region. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Dec 19, 2012  3:51 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-19/morgan-stanley-makes-newtown-gifts-to-honor-employees-relatives.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Makes Newtown Gifts to Honor Employees'' Relatives</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) contributed $150,000
to charities honoring victims of the mass shooting at a Newtown,
Connecticut, elementary school that killed 20 children and six
adults, including three relatives of bank employees. </p>
<p>The firm set up a fund to support services such as grief
counseling and is contributing to other charities, Chief
Executive Officer James Gorman wrote in a memo to employees
yesterday that was obtained by Bloomberg News. About 1,400
employees have contributed a total of more than $1 million. </p>
<p>Jack Pinto, 6, was the son of Dean Pinto, a Morgan Stanley
lawyer. Mary Sherlach, the school''s psychologist who was killed,
was the wife of Bill Sherlach, a broker at the firm. Grace
McDonnell, 7, was the niece of Paul Minella, who also works in
the firm''s brokerage. Two other Morgan Stanley employees are
married to teachers at the school who were not injured. </p>
<p>No word or deed can right these wrongs or take away our
colleagues'' suffering - but as a firm, we can lend them
support, Gorman wrote in the memo. </p>
<p>President Barack Obama pledged his administration will
draft concrete proposals by the end of next month to help
stem gun violence in the U.S. after the Dec. 14 shooting. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Pablo Gonzalez and Rodrigo Orihuela" date="Dec 19, 2012  3:42 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-19/chevron-ypf-sign-venture-to-develop-argentine-shale-oil.html"><headline>Chevron, YPF Sign Venture to Develop Argentine Shale Oil</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX) signed a deal with YPF
SA, (YPFD) Argentina''s largest energy company, which paves the way for
it to become the first major oil company to partner with the
Buenos Aires-based producer since its nationalization in April. </p>
<p>According to the agreement signed today by Miguel Galuccio,
chief executive officer of YPF, and Ali Moshiri, Chevron''s head
of Latin America, Middle East and Africa, the San Ramon,
California-based company gets an exclusive right for four months
to negotiate final terms for YPF to transfer a 50 percent
interest in Loma de la Lata Norte and Loma Campana, YPF said in
an SEC filing. The fields comprise an area of 290 square
kilometers (180 miles) in southwestern Argentina, YPF said. </p>
<p>Chevron is committed to make the expenditures in
accordance with a development program, for an estimated 100
wells, in these areas during a 12-month period, YPF said in
the filing. </p>
<p>The pilot program in Neuquen Province would cost $1 billion
and may eventually expand to an estimated 2,000 wells at a
pricetag of about $15 billion,Galuccio said in a
videoconference from Houston withMoshiri. </p>
<p>The companies plan to identify additional exploration
blocks in an estimated 600-square kilometer area, where Chevron
will pay for the investments, YPF said in the filing. In
exchange, YPF said it will give Chevron 50 percent interest in
the blocks. </p>
<h2>Irrelevant'' Lawsuit </h2>
<p>The final agreement, if signed, will be the first YPF
reaches with a foreign oil company to invest in Argentina since
the government nationalized 51 percent of the company by seizing
shares from Repsol SA (REP) in April. </p>
<p>In August, Chevron and YPF signed a memorandum of
understanding, the first step toward a development partnership. </p>
<p>Repsol, based in Madrid, filed a complaint Dec. 4 in a
federal court in Manhattan accusing Chevron of improperly
obtaining rights to develop Argentine shale and natural gas
resources. </p>
<p>Repsol''s lawsuit against Chevron for partnering with YPF is
irrelevant, Moshiri said. </p>
<p>Our goal is to start as soon as possible and the only
thing we need is to push our teams to put a definitive agreement
together as soon as possible, he said. </p>
<h2>Dead Cow </h2>
<p>Vaca Muerta, which means dead cow in Spanish, holds at
least 23 billion barrels of oil equivalent, according to a
report by independent auditor Ryder Scott released in February
by YPF. Argentina holds the world''s third-largest shale gas
reserves, according to US Energy Administration data. </p>
<p>Galuccio said the signing of the preliminary deal marks a
very important day for YPF. In August, he said that to boost
output YPF needs to invest $37.2 billion in the next five years,
$2.5 billion of which is to come from strategic partners, $5
billion from bond sales and bank loans, while the remainder
should come from its own cashflow. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Ari Levy and Douglas MacMillan" date="Dec 19, 2012  3:09 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-19/morgan-stanley-case-leaves-facebook-with-similar-legal-challenge.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Case Exposes Facebook to Similar Challenges</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Facebook Inc. (FB), the world''s largest
social-networking company, could be exposed to legal challenges
surrounding its initial public offering similar to those faced
by Morgan Stanley (MS), according to legal experts. </p>
<p>In the first regulatory claims to flow from the May 17 IPO,
Massachusetts officials said on Dec. 17 that they fined Morgan
Stanley $5 million for letting its investment bankers provide
research analysts specific revenue information that was not
disclosed by Facebook to the general public. That broke a
decade-old rule enacted after the dot-com crash to block bankers
from influencing analysts, Massachusetts said. </p>
<p>The settlement includes for the first time details of the
closed-door conversations between Morgan Stanley and Facebook
ahead of the IPO, including testimony from Michael Grimes, who
led the deal for the bank. According to the consent order,
Grimes wrote a script for Facebook''s then-treasurer to read to
analysts that detailed Facebook''s lowered revenue estimates. </p>
<p>Grimes did everything but make the phone calls himself,
the regulator said in a statement. Grimes was identified in the
settlement only as a senior investment banker, though it
provided biographical details that match his. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
Facebook shares have tumbled 27 percent since they started trading for $38 on May 18, to $27.71 as of the close yesterday. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Renee Dudley" date="Dec 19, 2012  9:48 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-19/general-mills-profit-tops-estimates-helped-by-sales-of-yoki.html"><headline>General Mills Profit Tops Estimates Helped by Sales of Yoki</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>General Mills Inc. (GIS), the maker of
Cheerios cereal, reported fiscal second-quarter profit that beat
analysts'' estimates, helped by sales from its Yoki Alimentos
business in Brazil. </p>
<p>Net income rose 22 percent to $541.6 million, or 82 cents a
share, from $444.8 million, or 67 cents, a year earlier, the
Minneapolis-based company said today in a statement. Excluding
some items, profit totaled 86 cents a share. Analysts projected
79 cents, the average of 18 estimates compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Net sales rose 5.6 percent to $4.88 billion in the quarter
after General Mills benefited from the addition of Yoki, which
it acquired this year for $860.9 million to more than double
sales in Latin America. </p>
<p>General Mills fell 0.6 percent to $41.50 at 9:45 a.m. in
New York. The shares had advanced 3.4 percent this year through
yesterday. </p>
<p>The company also boosted its full-year profit forecast to
as much as $2.67 a share from $2.65 a share. Analysts'' projected
$2.67, the average of estimates compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass and Tim Culpan" date="Dec 19, 2012 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-19/microsoft-htc-draw-closer-to-create-rally-in-smartphones-.html"><headline>Microsoft-HTC Draw Closer to Create Rally in Smartphones:</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) Chief Executive
Officer Steve Ballmer, on a swing through Taiwan this month,
made time to meet with Peter Chou, his counterpart at HTC Corp. (2498) </p>
<p>On Chou''s agenda: the low screen resolution that prompted
HTC to scrap plans for a bigger smartphone using Microsoft''s
mobile software, a person familiar with the matter said this
week. </p>
<p>Ballmer needs to stay on Chou''s good side. HTC could help
his company vie with Apple Inc. (AAPL) and Google Inc. (GOOG) in the 718-
million-unit smartphone market, where, according to researcher
IDC, Microsoft has only a 2.6 percent share. After trying to
gain ground for a decade without success, Microsoft needs HTC --
which has drawn praise for its current Windows devices -- to
help it win over consumers with a hit product. </p>
<p>HTC is important to Microsoft because they put together
one beautiful smartphone and when you have that kind of DNA, you
have a company that can boost general acceptance and market
share, said Ramon Llamas, an analyst at IDC. If you want
bigger market share, getting multiple vendors is the name of the
game. </p>
<p>Microsoft is also relying on Nokia, which became the lead 
Windows partner last year through a multibillion-dollar 
marketing agreement, to expand in smartphones. </p>
<p>To strengthen ties to HTC, Ballmer and Chou meet in person
a few times a year and exchange phone calls and e-mails
frequently, according to a person with knowledge of the matter.
It helps that Taoyuan City, Taiwan-based HTC runs its U.S.
operations out of Bellevue, Washington, a Seattle suburb next
door to Redmond, where Microsoft is based. </p>
<h2>HTC Struggles </h2>
<p>In other evidence of the closer cooperation between HTC and
Microsoft, the HTC 8X is shown in about 70 percent of
Microsoft''s advertising highlighting a specific phone, said
Jason Mackenzie, HTC''s president for global sales. </p>
<p>Both companies need a hit. Microsoft, two years after
completely overhauling its mobile software, risks being shut out
of the growing market by smartphones based on Google''s Android
software and Apple''s iPhones. </p>
<p>HTC, which also makes Android phones, in October forecast
its lowest sales in 11 quarters as it loses Android customers to
Samsung Electronics Co. HTC had a 4.7 percent share of the
global smartphone market in the third quarter, IDC said, down
from a peak of 10.7 percent in the second quarter of 2011. </p>
<p>Samsung dominated the Android market with 41 percent share
of those phones in the third quarter, IDC''s Llamas said. HTC,
with 5.5 percent, is in a battle for the No. 2 spot with seven
other vendors, he said. </p>
<h2>Android Dependence </h2>
<p>HTC can''t afford to lose further ground. Chou decided to
scrap plans for a large-screen Windows smartphone because a low-
resolution version wouldn''t have been competitive, a person
familiar with the project said this week. That left HTC with
only Android for phones measuring larger than 5 inches
diagonally, and fewer products to claw back share from Samsung,
which offers Galaxy Note devices with bigger screens. </p>
<p>Windows Phone is very much a blue ocean -- there''s no
dominant player, Michael Gartenberg, an analyst at Gartner
Inc., said in an interview. The opportunity for HTC to become
the flagship device would give them a chance to not be as
dependent on Android. </p>
<p>Still, since HTC released the new Windows-based phones last
month, its monthly revenue has increased. Sales in November
jumped 23 percent from October, ending a four-month revenue
decline. HTC is on track to meet its fourth-quarter sales
forecasts, in part because of demand for new models such as the
Windows Phones, Jasmine Lu, an analyst at Morgan Stanley, wrote
in a Dec. 10 note. </p>
<h2>Go Big'' </h2>
<p>The relationship between Microsoft and HTC goes back at
least a decade. HTC made the first-ever smartphone with Windows
in 2002. It also made the first phone showcasing the Android
operating system, and for the past several years, HTC has
devoted almost all of its marketing and its best designs to the
software made by Microsoft rival Google, said Mackenzie. </p>
<p>We just weren''t promoting it, Mackenzie said of Windows
Phone. We just didn''t see the opportunity to get massive
sales. What changed is with Windows Phone 8, we saw a massive
opportunity. </p>
<p>Ties between the companies got a restart in February, when
Mackenzie and Chou met in Barcelona with Ballmer and Microsoft
Windows Phone chief Terry Myerson. Ballmer urged HTC to go
big on using Windows Phone, Mackenzie said. HTC came prepared,
walking into the meeting with prototypes that, for the first
time in years, reflected high-quality design work. </p>
<h2>Ballmer''s Phone'' </h2>
<p>They were devices that were going to be unique to Windows
Phone, Myerson said. I remember thinking they were beautiful
devices. </p>
<p>Engineers from both companies soon began meeting weekly if
not more frequently, and officials jointly started pitching
wireless carriers on selling the devices, Myerson said. HTC also
opted to use the Windows Phone brand in the name of its products
-- something Nokia (NOK1V) hasn''t done with its Lumia lineup. </p>
<p>Microsoft''s Myerson even found himself dragged up on stage
by HTC''s Chou to sing karaoke at the W Hotel in Taipei in June,
at a dinner celebrating the company''s 15th anniversary dinner. </p>
<p>HTC has been rewarded for its efforts. When Microsoft
decided to show Ballmer''s phone at an October event to
unveil Windows Phone 8, it was a red HTC 8X with tiles showing
updates from Ballmer''s wife, Connie, as well as Microsoft
Chairman Bill Gates. </p>
<h2>Nokia Ties </h2>
<p>As Microsoft and HTC forge closer ties, at least one
company that stands to lose is Nokia. Through last year''s deal,
Nokia switched its smartphones to Windows in exchange for
marketing and development funds. That agreement was crafted by
Nokia CEO Stephen Elop, a former Microsoft executive. </p>
<p>Nokia, which posted six straight quarterly losses totaling
$6.3 billion since the move to Windows, said its relationship
with Microsoft has enabled Nokia to offer truly differentiated
products. </p>
<p>We view Android and Apple as our primary competition,
said Doug Dawson, a spokesman for Nokia. As such, we welcome
the momentum behind the Windows Phone ecosystem. </p>
<p>Still, Mackenzie says the bulk of Microsoft''s ads that
focus on just one handset will feature the 8X, including a
recent spot with musician Gwen Stefani showing her HTC phone.
The smartphone has received several positive reviews. </p>
<p>The 8X is a cutting-edge phone in virtually every way
except maybe capacity, said Gartner''s Gartenberg. It''s a
thin and light device. The Nokia 920 has a lot of high-end
features but it''s a polarizing device. It''s huge and it''s heavy.
It''s like the SUV of phones. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Aaron Clark" date="Dec 20, 2012  3:11 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-20/exxon-said-to-plan-february-chalmette-catalytic-cracker-work.html"><headline>Exxon Chalmette Said to Plan February Catalytic Cracker Work</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) will shut a fluid
catalytic cracker at the Chalmette, Louisiana, refinery in
February for maintenance, according to a person with knowledge
of the situation. </p>
<p>An alkylation unit will also be shut during the work, which
is scheduled to begin Feb. 24 and last about a month, said the
person, who asked not to be identified because the information
isn''t public. </p>
<p>Rachael Moore, a Fairfax, Virginia-based spokeswoman for
Exxon, declined to comment in an e-mail. </p>
<p>The plant has a capacity of 200,700 barrels a day,
according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Olga Kharif" date="Dec 20, 2012  2:40 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-20/goldman-sachs-backed-backoffice-buys-out-founders-as-ipo-planned.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs-Backed BackOffice Buys Out Founders as IPO Planned</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>BackOffice Associates LLC, a
provider of data-management software and services, bought out
its founders today as an early step toward holding an initial
public offering, said Chief Executive Officer David Booth. </p>
<p>The South Harwich, Massachusetts-based company, which is
backed by Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS), bought out founders Tom and
Patricia Kennedy today for an undisclosed sum, obtained through
a loan from Royal Bank of Scotland Group Plc, Booth said in an
interview. The buyback leaves Goldman Sachs with controlling
interest in the company, which is also owned by management and
employees, he said. </p>
<p>The buyout brings BackOffice closer to its goal of going
public in 12 to 18 months, according to Booth. Web-data analysis
provider Splunk Inc. (SPLK) has surged 73 percent since it went public
in April, while Workday Inc. (WDAY), a maker of human resource
applications, has almost doubled since its October debut,
reflecting robust investor demand for software companies that
cater to business. </p>
<p>The market is not as vibrant as it was two years ago, but
there''s still a lot of interest in quality firms, Booth said.
We now have a simplified ownership structure. It will help
accelerate the continued move toward going public. </p>
<p>BackOffice is discussing hiring Goldman Sachs, as well as
other banks, to handle its IPO, Booth said. The company plans to
use proceeds to pay back the new loan, as well as to expand
globally, particularly by adding staff in Latin America, Booth
said. </p>
<p>The global market for data management software will grow 21
percent to $1.9 billion this year, according to estimates by
researcher Gartner Inc. Other companies competing for this
market include Informatica Corp. (INFA), Talend Inc., Utopia Inc. and
International Business Machines Corp. BackOffice recently added
to its lineup by becoming a reseller for products from software
maker SAP AG. </p>
<p>BackOffice is highly profitable, and has annual sales
of $100 million to $200 million, Booth said in May. Revenue
growth is in double-digits, he said then. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Douglas MacMillan" date="Dec 20, 2012  2:10 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-20/jpmorgan-said-to-buy-daily-deal-site-bloomspot-for-35-million.html"><headline>JPMorgan Said to Buy Coupon Site Bloomspot for $35 Million</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) agreed to acquire online coupon site Bloomspot Inc. for $35 million as it seeks to offer credit card holders more discounts to local shops, according to a memo obtained by Bloomberg News. </p> <p>The deal will bring Bloomspot''s technology and about 100 employees into the credit card unit, Bloomspot Chief Executive Officer Jasper Malcolmson said in the memo, which was e-mailed to investors. Closely held Bloomspot, which competes with Web- coupon leader Groupon Inc. (GRPN), sells online discounts to luxury spas, high-end restaurants and weekend getaways. </p> <p>JPMorgan''s consumer division is working to build loyalty in customers by letting them redeem discounts similar to those offered by Groupon. The deal comes amid slumping demand for Internet coupons, as Groupon''s stock has plummeted 76 percent this year and LivingSocial Inc., the second-biggest provider of online daily deals, has announced plans to cut jobs. </p> <p>After the sale to JPMorgan, investors in Bloomspot will receive a 67 percent return of invested capital, Malcolmson wrote in the e-mail. The deal is expected to be completed by the end of January. </p> <p>While we are disappointed that the deal is not generating a positive return for our investors, given alternatives, we believe this is a good outcome for our equity investors, Malcolmson wrote. </p> <h2>Venture Investments </h2> <p>Bloomspot, based in San Francisco, has raised more than $40 million from investors including venture capital firms True Ventures, Menlo Ventures and Columbia Capital. In August 2011, it received $35 million in financing from several venture firms and $5 million of venture debt from Western Technology Investment, according to a statement last year. </p> <p>Earlier this year, Bank of America Corp. introduced online and mobile cash-back deals in the U.S., giving customers discounts after they visited stores including Aeropostale Inc. and The Body Shop Inc. </p> <p>American Express Co., whose finance chief Daniel Henry sits on Groupon''s board, has partnered with mobile location service Foursquare Labs Inc. to deliver coupons to customers at stores where they have checked in with the application. </p> <p>Lily Shen, chief marketing officer at Bloomspot, didn''t respond to a voicemail seeking comment. Paul Hartwick, a spokesman for JPMorgan, declined to comment. </p> <p>Dow Jones earlier reported the deal. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Dec 20, 2012 10:12 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-20/morgan-stanley-to-buy-stake-in-eris-rate-swap-exchange.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley to Buy Stake in Eris Rate-Swap Exchange</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley, the sixth-largest
U.S. bank by assets, plans to purchase a stake in Eris Exchange
LLC and become a liquidity provider for the interest-rate swaps
futures market. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley will participate in electronic and block
trading on Eris early next year, the New York-based company said
today in a statement. The bank will also join the board of
directors of Chicago-based Eris as part of the deal, the terms
of which weren''t disclosed. </p>
<p>New rules are pushing more derivatives onto exchanges as
regulators seek to reduce the risk resulting from a trading firm
defaulting on its obligation in a transaction. Unlike over-the-
counter products, those traded on exchanges are usually
standardized and cleared by an organization that guarantees the
contract will settle. </p>
<p>As the traditional OTC rates-swap market undergoes
significant structural, economic and regulatory changes, Morgan
Stanley (MS) believes that Eris Exchange and its futurized swaps are
ideally suited to provide our clients with flexible
alternatives, Patrick Haskell, Morgan Stanley''s U.S. head of
liquid flow rates, said in the statement. </p>
<p>Standard interest-rate swap futures contracts traded on the
exchange carry margins that are 40 percent to 80 percent less
than over-the-counter agreements, according to the statement. </p>
<p>Morgan Stanley increased its interest-rates trading
headcount by more than 20 percent in 2010 and hired Goldman
Sachs Group Inc. trader Glenn Hadden last year in an effort to
turn around the business. Rates and currency trading contributed
more than half the firm''s fixed-income revenue in the 18 months
ended in June, from less than half in 2009, an increase driven
primarily by rates, Chief Financial Officer Ruth Porat said
in September. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Aoife White" date="Dec 20, 2012  8:08 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-20/microsoft-set-to-face-eu-decision-on-browser-antitrust-violation.html"><headline>Microsoft Set to Face Possible EU Fines on Browser Violation</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) faces possible
European Union fines as soon as next month over its failure to
comply with a settlement to give users a choice of web browsers. </p>
<p>Regulators are close to a decision which would be one of
the first in 2013, Joaquin Almunia, the EU''s antitrust chief,
told reporters at a European Commission press conference in
Brussels today. </p>
<p>The world''s largest software maker was sent EU antitrust
objections in October, a preliminary step before being punished
for failing to abide by a promise to show a browser-choice
screen to users of its Windows operating system. The company was
also warned to modify how it presents its Internet Explorer
browser in Windows 8 to avert another antitrust clash. </p>
<p>Microsoft has already been fined 1.68 billion euros ($2.23
billion) in EU antitrust probes, including an 899 million-euro
penalty for failing to obey an order to share data with
competitors. The Redmond, Washington-based company agreed in
2009 to offer access to rival browsers as a part of a settlement
to repair its relationship with the bloc''s regulators. It told
regulators last December that it was complying with its
commitments. </p>
<p>Robin Koch, a spokesman for Microsoft in Brussels, declined
to comment on Almunia''s remarks. </p>
<p>Almunia didn''t mention possible penalties, which can be as
high as 10 percent of yearly sales for breaching an antitrust
settlement. </p>
<h2>Internet Explorer </h2>
<p>Under the terms of Microsoft''s 2009 pledge, consumers who
buy personal computers were given a choice of the 12 most widely
used browsers to install in addition to, or instead of,
Microsoft''s Internet Explorer. </p>
<p>The company said in July it only learned that month that it
didn''t offer its browser choice software to some 28 million
computers running Windows 7 Service Pack 1, or 10 percent of the
computers that should have received it. It distributed a
software fix to computers that were affected. </p>
<p>Any fines for Microsoft may take into account repeat
offenses, Almunia said in July in a reference to the EU''s 2008
penalty for the company''s failure to obey an earlier EU
decision. That ruling also ordered it to provide information to
software developers to make compatible products. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David Scheer" date="Dec 21, 2012  2:45 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-21/jpmorgan-promotes-owen-to-cfo-of-consumer-community-banking-1-.html"><headline>JPMorgan Promotes Owen to CFO of Consumer, Community Banking</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>     Dec. 21 (Bloomberg) -- JPMorgan Chase  Co. named David Owen to be chief financial officer of the firm''s consumer and
community banking unit, after predecessor Marianne Lake was
promoted as part of a management overhaul. </p>
<p>Owen, who joined the company in 2011 as CFO of the consumer
bank, will also become a member of the firmwide management team,
the New York-based lender said today in a statement. Lake was
selected last month to become the company''s CFO in the first
quarter of 2013. </p>
<p>Owen previously worked for Charlotte, North Carolina-based
Bank of America Corp.''s consumer division. He is a graduate of
the U.S. Army Airborne School. </p>
<p>JPMorgan said it will announce a successor for his consumer
CFO role in coming weeks. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jesse Hamilton and Robert Schmidt" date="Dec 21, 2012 12:51 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-21/jpmorgan-said-to-face-enforcement-action-on-whale-loss.html"><headline>JPMorgan Said to Face Enforcement Action on Whale Loss</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) will be the
target of a regulatory enforcement order stemming from mistakes
that led to at least $6.2 billion in trading losses, according
to a person briefed on the situation. </p>
<p>The Office of the Comptroller of the Currency is preparing
to issue a cease-and-desist order requiring the largest U.S.
bank to fix internal risk controls that contributed to its
wrong-way bet on credit derivatives, according to the person,
who asked not to be named because the discussions aren''t public.
Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon, 56, said in May that the
firm''s strategy was beset by errors, sloppiness and bad
judgment. </p>
<p>The timing of the enforcement is uncertain, the person
said. </p>
<p>Joe Evangelisti, a JPMorgan spokesman, and Bryan Hubbard,
an OCC spokesman, declined to comment on any potential
enforcement actions, reported yesterday by the Wall Street
Journal. </p>
<p>The faulty trades within the bank''s chief investment office
-- associated with London-based trader Bruno Iksil, widely known
as the London Whale -- may eventually cost more than $6.2
billion, Dimon has said. </p>
<p>That investment office within JPMorgan''s national bank
suffered from inadequate risk management, Comptroller of the
Currency Thomas Curry said during U.S. Senate testimony in June. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
Chief Executive Officer Jamie Dimon, 56, said in May that the firm''s strategy was beset by errors, sloppiness and bad judgment. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Susan Decker" date="Dec 21, 2012 12:40 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-21/disney-wins-u-s-appeals-court-ruling-over-pooh-trademark.html"><headline>Disney Wins U.S. Appeals Court Ruling Over Pooh Trademark</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co., (DIS) the world''s largest
entertainment company, won an appeals court ruling that protects
its trademark rights to the Winnie-the-Pooh characters. </p>
<p>The U.S. Patent and Trademark Office was correct to throw
out challenges to the trademark ownership filed by Stephen
Slesinger Inc., which has waged a decades-long battle with
Disney over ownership of the Pooh characters, an appeals court
in Washington said today. Slesinger had already litigated the
issue and lost in district court, the U.S. Court of Appeals for
the Federal Circuit said in an opinion posted on its website. </p>
<p>A.A. Milne, who wrote the Pooh books, transferred
merchandising rights to Stephen Slesinger in 1930, and his widow
licensed the rights to Disney in 1961. The Slesinger company and
Disney have been fighting in court over royalties since at least
1991. </p>
<p>In 2009, a federal court ruled that Slesinger had
transferred all of its rights in the Pooh works to Burbank,
California-based Disney. The Federal Circuit today said that,
based on that 2009 ruling, the trademark office was right to bar
Slesinger from seeking to cancel the Disney trademarks. </p>
<p>Disney fell $1.08, or 2.1 percent, to $49.85 at 12:28 p.m.
in New York Stock Exchange composite trading. The shares have
risen almost 33 percent so far this year. </p>
<p>The case is Stephen Slesinger Inc. v. Disney Enterprises
Inc., 2011-1593, U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit
(Washington). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dalia Fahmy" date="Dec 21, 2012 11:49 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-21/goldman-sachs-group-selling-17-german-stores-for-1-45b.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Group Selling 17 German Stores for $1.45B</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Signa Holding, a property investor
managed by Austrian Rene Benko, agreed to buy 17 German
department stores, including the country''s largest, for 1.1
billion euros ($1.45 billion) from investors that include
Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) </p>
<p>The stores are leased to retailer Karstadt Warenhaus GmbH
and the transaction will be completed next year, Richard Speich,
a spokesman for the investment group called Highstreet that''s
selling the stores, said today. The biggest of the 17 properties
is the historic KaDeWe store in Berlin. </p>
<p>Companies outside of Germany are buying real estate in the
country''s large cities to gain safer investments as the euro
region copes with a recession. Retail rents in the second half
of 2012 rose 13 percent in Berlin and 7 percent in Cologne,
according to data compiled by Chicago-based broker Jones Lang
LaSalle Inc. (JLL) </p>
<p>Highstreet is made up of Goldman Sachs'' Whitehall Street
Real Estate Funds, Deutsche Bank AG (DBK)''s RREEF Real Estate (GRNDBIN)
affiliate, Prelios SpA (PRS) and Generali Real Estate Fund SA. Signa
is an Austrian investment firm with 4.5 billion euros in assets
that last year tried to acquire German department store chain
Kaufhof. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Erik Larson" date="Dec 21, 2012 11:20 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-21/microsoft-wins-u-k-court-ruling-over-motorola-pager-patent-1-.html"><headline>Microsoft Wins U.K. Court Ruling Over Motorola Pager Patent</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp., the world''s biggest
software maker, won a U.K. ruling invalidating Motorola Mobility
Holdings Inc.''s patent protection for technology synchronizing
message statuses across multiple devices. </p>
<p>The 2002 patent owned by Google Inc. (GOOG)''s Motorola Mobility
unit shouldn''t have been issued because the technology was
obvious to experts in the field at the time, Judge Richard Arnold said in a decision in London today. A week-long trial
ended earlier this month. </p>
<p>The patent is invalid and should be revoked, Arnold
said during a 30-second hearing. Both companies had received the
written judgment in advance. </p>
<p>The companies are locked in legal battles over patents for
smartphone technology and Microsoft''s Xbox gaming software in
the U.S. and Germany. Microsoft claims all devices that run on
Google''s Android operating system use its technology and is
seeking royalties from Motorola Mobility, which Mountain View,
California-based Google acquired in May. </p>
<p>Microsoft, based in Redmond, Washington, filed the lawsuit
against Motorola Mobility in London a year ago in a pre-emptive
bid to invalidate the patent before it could be sued for
infringement. </p>
<h2>German Cases </h2>
<p>The case is running parallel to Motorola''s lawsuit against
Microsoft over the same patent in Germany, where the companies
are awaiting a decision. Google has said it bought Motorola
Mobility in part because of its patents and history of
innovation in mobile phones. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
Microsoft claims all devices that run on Google''s Android operating system use its technology and is seeking royalties from Motorola Mobility, which Mountain View,
California-based Google acquired in May. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Aoife White" date="Dec 21, 2012  7:28 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-21/disney-wins-eu-approval-to-buy-star-wars-producer-lucasfilm.html"><headline>Disney Wins EU Approval to Buy Star Wars'' Producer Lucasfilm</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Walt Disney Co. (DIS) won European Union
approval to buy George Lucas''s Lucasfilm Ltd. for $4.05 billion
in cash and stock, combining two of Hollywood''s most lucrative
film franchises. </p>
<p>The European Commission, the EU''s antitrust regulator,
said overlaps were very limited for the two companies''
activities in home entertainment, gaming software, film
production and distribution and licensing for both broadcast
rights and merchandise, according to an e-mailed statement
today. </p>
<p>The commission therefore concluded that the transaction
would not significantly impede effective competition in
Europe, the Brussels-based authority said in the statement. </p>
<p>The deal, announced in October, will add Star Wars and
Indiana Jones to Disney''s roster of film hits including
The Avengers and Finding Nemo. The Star Wars films
have generated $4.54 billion in worldwide ticket sales, second
to Warner Bros.'' Harry Potter, according to Box Office Mojo.
Indiana Jones pictures have collected $1.95 billion. </p>
<p>The acquisition complements Disney Chief Executive Officer
Robert Iger''s focus on sequels and film franchises, fitting the
same profile as its purchase of Marvel three years ago. Disney
paid a combined $11 billion for Pixar and Marvel in the past
decade. </p>
<p>Lucas, 68, the sole owner of Lucasfilm, will receive half
of the purchase price in cash and the balance in stock, becoming
a major investor in the film, theme-park and TV company,
according to an Oct. 31 statement from Burbank, California-based
Disney. Lucas will receive about 40 million Disney shares,
becoming the second-largest non-institutional shareholder with
about 2.2 percent of the company, data compiled by Bloomberg
show. The largest is the trust of late Apple Inc. co-founder
Steve Jobs, who sold Pixar to Disney in 2006. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Lucy Meakin" date="Dec 21, 2012  4:59 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-21/morgan-stanley-says-currency-recommendations-made-5-7-this-year.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Says Currency Recommendations Made 5.7% This Year</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) said a portfolio
based on its currency recommendations returned 5.72 percent this
year, the best performance since 2008. </p>
<p>The returns were based on 45 trades held for an average of
38 days each, the New York-based bank said in a note to clients.
The best recommendations were to buy the Russian ruble against
the yen from Oct. 23 to Dec. 14, which returned 7.1 percent, and
to purchase the dollar versus Japan''s currency from Sept. 25 to
Dec. 14, which gained 6.6 percent, Morgan Stanley said. </p>
<p>The worst-performing trade was to bet the pound would
weaken versus the ruble between Aug. 15 and Aug. 30, which lost
2.3 percent. A prediction the Australian dollar would depreciate
against the yen from July 13 to July 27 lost 2.1 percent. </p>
<p>We still believe several of our best-performing trades,
particularly those funded in yen, have further to gain over the
coming year, and we will look to re-establish strategies along
this line in the new year, strategists in the global currency
research team led by Hans Redeker in London, wrote in the note
published yesterday. </p>
<p>The yen has tumbled 12.4 percent this year, the worst
performer of 10 developed-nation currencies tracked by Bloomberg
Correlation-Weighted Indexes. The euro declined 1.1 percent and
the dollar fell 3.2 percent. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Jim Polson and Rebecca Penty" date="Dec 24, 2012  2:42 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-24/chevron-buys-encana-eog-stakes-in-kitimat-lng-terminal-1-.html"><headline>Chevron Buys Encana, EOG Stake in Kitimat LNG Terminal</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Chevron Corp. (CVX), the second-largest
U.S. oil company, agreed to buy a 50 percent stake in the
proposed Kitimat liquefied natural gas terminal from Encana
Corp. (ECA) and EOG Resources Inc. (EOG), joining the competition to ship
the fuel from North America to Asian markets. </p>
<p>Chevron will also acquire 50 percent of a pipeline serving
the Canadian project and drilling rights for 644,000 acres in
British Columbia''s Horn River and Liard basins, according to a
statement from the San Ramon, California-based company today. It
will operate the LNG terminal and pipeline, and project partner
Apache Corp. (APA) will handle the acreage. </p>
<p>Chevron joins Royal Dutch Shell Plc (RDSA) and Malaysia''s
Petroliam Nasional Bhd in pursuing gas exports from western
Canada to Asian markets, where the heating and power plant fuel
sells at a premium to North American prices. The Kitimat project
has a license from Canadian regulators to export 10 million
metric tons a year of the liquefied fuel. </p>
<p>The involvement by Chevron in Kitimat LNG elevates the
probability of this project going ahead and expedites the
timeframe, said Daniel Cheng, a portfolio manager who helps
oversee C$375 million ($378 million) at Matco Financial Inc. in
Calgary, including Encana and EOG shares. The partners in that
project were stalling because they were having a hard time
securing long-term, oil-linked price customers. </p>
<p>Chevron will probably pay a total of $1.3 billion, William Featherston, an analyst for UBS AG in New York, wrote in a note
today. All of the companies involved declined to provide terms
of the deal. </p>
<h2>LNG Costs </h2>
<p>Apache Chairman and Chief Executive Officer Steven Farris
estimated in March the Kitimat project would cost $15 billion,
including the terminal, pipeline and investment in related
drilling wells. </p>
<p>The cost of building LNG terminals, which chill gas to -260
degrees Fahrenheit (-160 Celsius) to make it a liquid that can
be shipped on tankers, has surged in recent years as competition
for materials and workers has increased, James T. Jensen,
president of Jensen Associates, said in a phone interview today. </p>
<p>Apache is still completing the design process that will
help develop cost estimates, Paul Wyke, a spokesman for the
Houston-based company, said in an e-mail today. Chevron hasn''t
set a schedule for a final investment decision on the projects
or for when exports will begin, Gareth Johnstone, a company
spokesman, said in a phone interview. </p>
<p>Chevron and Apache are already partners in the Wheatstone
LNG export project in Australia. Chevron also is developing the
Gorgon LNG project in Australia, an effort that may cost as much
as A$52 billion ($54 billion) and begin first shipments in 2015. </p>
<h2>Australian Competition </h2>
<p>The British Columbia projects are trying very hard to
compete with Australia, Jensen said. The fact that Chevron
is getting in suggests that they''ve found it interesting
compared to what else they have. </p>
<p>The Kitimat project is 400 miles (650 kilometers) north of
Vancouver. The Pacific Trail pipeline would stretch 290 miles,
connecting the terminal to a pipeline system owned by Spectra
Energy Corp. (SE) </p>
<p>The project is ideally situated to meet rapidly growing
demand for reliable, secure and cleaner-burning fuels in Asia,
which are projected to approximately double from current levels
by 2025, Chevron Vice Chairman George Kirkland said in the
statement. The transaction, subject to approval from Canadian
regulators, is expected to close by the end of March. </p>
<h2>Apache Net </h2>
<p>The Horn River and Liard shale basins hold an estimated 50
trillion cubic feet of potential gas, Farris said in a separate
statement today. </p>
<p>Apache expects to net about $400 million on the
transaction, according to the statement. It will sell a 50
percent stake in the Liard acreage to Chevron for $500 million
and pay Chevron to raise its stake in the terminal, the pipeline
and the other producing areas to 50 percent from 40 percent. </p>
<p>Chevron is the premier LNG developer with longstanding
relationships in key Asian markets,Farris said. </p>
<p>Both EOG and Encana held 30 percent stakes in the Kitimat
project. Apache said it and Chevron will explore sales of stakes
in the terminal and acreage to customers. </p>
<p>EOG, based in Houston, is selling to focus on onshore crude
oil production, which is generating more immediate
reinvestment opportunities, Chairman and CEO Mark Papa said in
a separate release. K Leonard, a spokeswoman for the company,
didn''t immediately return voicemail messages seeking comment. </p>
<h2>Global Player'' </h2>
<p>For Encana, Canada''s largest gas producer, we do not have
former experience in LNG projects and Chevron does, Jay Averill, a spokesman for the Calgary-based company, said by
phone today. Bringing in a global player like Chevron, which
does have the experience and the financial ability to bring this
to fruition, takes the project to the next step. </p>
<p>Chevron fell 1 percent to close at $108.63 in New York.
Apache dropped 1.7 percent to $78.68 and EOG dropped 0.7 percent
to $122.77. Encana declined 2.3 percent to C$19.66 in Toronto. </p>
<p>Chevron was one of a fairly short list of natural
buyers, Menno Hulshof, an analyst at TD Securities in Calgary,
said in a note to clients today. </p>
<p>RBC Capital Markets acted as financial adviser for Apache,
Encana and EOG on the Horn River acreage sale. </p>
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) is the largest U.S. oil company. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Dina Bass" date="Dec 24, 2012 12:35 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-24/microsoft-says-mundie-shifts-to-new-role-will-retire-in-2014.html"><headline>Microsoft''s Mundie Shifts to New Role Before Retirement</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT) said Chief Research
and Strategy Officer Craig Mundie plans to retire in 2014 after
two decades and has shifted to a new role as a senior adviser to
Chief Executive Officer Steve Ballmer. </p>
<p>Eric Rudder, chief technical strategy officer, is taking
over some of Mundie''s duties overseeing research, privacy and
security, as well as technology policy, Ballmer said in an e-
mail to staff on Dec. 14 that Microsoft, the world''s largest
software maker, made public today. </p>
<p>Mundie''s job switch marks the second change to Microsoft''s
senior leadership team within the past two months. On Nov. 12,
the company announced that Windows chief Steven Sinofsky was
leaving. After releasing the latest version of its flagship
operating system in October, Ballmer is putting in place a new
team to start planning the next upgrade to help Microsoft
compete in a market that has shifted to mobile devices and
computing over the Internet. </p>
<p>The team led by Rudder continues to help shape the long-
term technology-policy landscape in ways that will give our
future products a clear path in the marketplace, Ballmer wrote
in the memo. </p>
<p>During his time at Microsoft, Mundie, 63, was responsible
for the company''s early efforts in software for handheld
organizers, cars and televisions. He also developed technology
policy in areas such as privacy and security, oversaw the
Microsoft Research unit and the company''s technology policy
relationships with governments such as China and Russia. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
Microsoft Chief Research And Strategy Officer Craig Mundie has shifted to a new role as a senior adviser to Chief Executive Officer Steve Ballmer as Mundie gets ready for retirement in 2014. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Victoria Slind-Flor" date="Dec 26, 2012 12:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-26/microsoft-nokia-black-rain-intellectual-property.html"><headline>Microsoft, Nokia, Black Rain: Intellectual Property</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT), the world''s biggest
software maker, won a U.K. ruling invalidating Motorola Mobility
Holdings Inc.''s patent protection for technology synchronizing
message statuses across multiple devices. </p>
<p>The 2002 patent owned by Google Inc. (GOOG)''s Motorola Mobility
unit shouldn''t have been issued because the technology was
obvious to experts in the field at the time, Judge Richard
Arnold said in a decision in London last week. A week-long trial
ended earlier this month. </p>
<p>The patent is invalid and should be revoked, Arnold
said during a 30-second hearing. Both companies had received the
written judgment in advance. </p>
<p>The companies are locked in legal battles over patents for
smartphone technology and Microsoft''s Xbox gaming software in
the U.S. and Germany. Microsoft claims all devices that run on
Google''s Android operating system use its technology and is
seeking royalties from Motorola Mobility, which Mountain View,
California-based Google acquired in May. </p>
<p>Microsoft, based in Redmond, Washington, filed the lawsuit
against Motorola Mobility in London a year ago in a pre-emptive
bid to invalidate the patent before it could be sued for
infringement. </p>
<p>The case is running parallel to Motorola''s lawsuit against
Microsoft over the same patent in Germany, where the companies
are awaiting a decision. Google has said it bought Motorola
Mobility in part because of its patents and history of
innovation in mobile phones. </p>
<p>We''re pleased the court granted our request to invalidate
Motorola''s patent and welcome yet another step toward clarifying
the cases between our companies, David Howard, Microsoft''s
deputy general counsel, said in an e-mailed statement. </p>
<p>Motorola''s lawyer, Zoe Butler of Powell Gilbert in London,
didn''t respond to a call seeking comment on the ruling.
Motorola''s press office didn''t immediately respond to an e-
mailed request for comment. </p>
<p>While the patent in the U.K. trial related to pager
technology from the 1990s, the arguments centered on its
application to newer mobile devices and computers that also rely
on synchronizing messages statuses such as whether an e-mail has
been read by the user, or is unread. </p>
<p>If the patent were valid, Microsoft''s Live Messenger
instant-messaging system and Exchange ActiveSync protocol, used
by the company''s customers to synchronize e-mail statuses across
devices, would have violated the intellectual property,
according to the judgment. </p>
<p>The patent in the case had a so-called priority date of
Aug. 31, 1995, when Motorola was creating technology for the
first two-way pager system that would allow message recipients
to respond to communications on the devices for the first time. </p>
<p>The case is Microsoft Corp. v. Motorola Mobility Inc.,
case no. HC11C04536, High Court of London, Chancery Division
(London). </p>
<h2>Nokia Signs Patent-Licensing Deal With RIM, Ending Disputes </h2>
<p>Nokia Oyj (NOK), the Finnish mobile-phone maker struggling to
reverse a slide in sales, agreed to a patent-licensing deal with
BlackBerry maker Research In Motion Ltd. (RIM), ending all legal
disputes between the companies. </p>
<p>RIM will make a one-time and ongoing payments to Nokia,
the Espoo, Finland-based company said. Financial terms weren''t
disclosed. </p>
<p>Nokia is trying to add revenue from its patent portfolio as
sales at its unprofitable smartphone unit drop. It may get a
one-time payment of $150 million to $200 million, and about $50
million annually over the next 10 to 15 years, depending on when
the patents expire, according to estimates by Hannu Rauhala, an
analyst at Pohjola Bank Oyj in Helsinki. </p>
<p>Nokia has sold units and assets including its headquarters
to boost its cash position. Its cash reserves have shrunk by
about half in the past five years and will drop below 3 billion
euros by year-end, Standard  Poor''s estimated in August. Its
debt is at junk status at the three main rating companies. </p>
<p>In May, Nokia said it filed patent-infringement lawsuits
against Waterloo, Ontario-based RIM, HTC Corp. (2498) and ViewSonic
Corp. over inventions in mobile devices including phones and
tablets. The RIM deal signals that the disputes with HTC and
ViewSonic could be settled within six months, Sarkamies said. </p>
<p>The new agreement is less lucrative than the one Nokia
signed with Apple Inc. last year because RIM''s device volumes
are so small and the BlackBerry maker is going through such
difficult times, he said. </p>
<p>Both Nokia and RIM are struggling to compete with Apple''s
iPhone and smartphones using Google Inc.''s Android software,
including those from market leader Samsung Electronics Co. (005930)
Android and Apple accounted for 90 percent of global smartphone
shipments last quarter, compared with 4.3 percent for the
BlackBerry and less than that for Nokia, according to research
firm IDC. </p>
<p>For more patent news, click here. </p>
<h2>Trademark </h2>
<h2>Gunmaker Black Rain Sues Glockplates.com for Infringement </h2>
<p>Black Rain Ordnance Inc., a maker of semi-automatic rifles,
sued an online dealer of gun parts over trademark infringement. </p>
<p>Glockplates.com of Brainerd, Minnesota, is accused of
infringing the Let it Rain! trademark used by Black Rain. In
a complaint filed Dec. 19 in federal court in Joplin, Missouri,
the Neosho, Missouri-based gun manufacturer says it used that
phrase to surround a biohazard symbol, and that Glockplates.com
is using it without authorization on its website. </p>
<p>The goods that are sold under its mark are confusingly
similar to authentic Black Rain products, according to court
papers. The public is confused, Black Rain claims, and is likely
to assume falsely that an affiliation exists between the two
companies. </p>
<p>The Missouri gunmaker claims it is harmed by
Glockplates.com''s actions and its reputation has been tarnished. </p>
<p>It asked the court for an order barring further
unauthorized use of its marks, and for seizure of all allegedly
infringing promotional material. Additionally, it seeks an award
of all of Glockplates.com''s profits derived from the alleged
infringement, together with money damages, attorney fees and
litigation costs. </p>
<p>Black Rain also requested that the damages be tripled to
punish Glockplates.com for its actions. </p>
<p>Glockplates.com didn''t respond immediately to an e-mailed
request for comment. </p>
<p>The case is Black Rain Ordnance Inc. v. Glockplates.com,
3:12-cv-05130-RED, U.S. District Court, Western District of
Missouri (Joplin). </p>
<h2>EU Tobacco Directive Permits Nations to Require Plain Packs </h2>
<p>The European Commission is proposing revisions to its
Tobacco Products Directive that permits member states to require
plain packaging on tobacco products. </p>
<p>According to a statement from the commission, all cigarette
and roll-your-own cigarette packaging must contain a combined
picture and text warning that covers 75 percent of the front and
back of the package. </p>
<p>Australia, which isn''t a member state of the European
Union, was the first nation to adopt a law requiring plain
packaging. The changeover began in October, and now cigarettes
sold in that country may bear photos of a gangrenous limb or a
cancer victim. </p>
<p>For more trademark news, click here. </p>
<h2>Copyright </h2>
<h2>Paramount, Puzo Agree to End Lawsuit Over Godfather'' Rights </h2>
<p>Paramount Pictures Corp. and Mario Puzo''s heirs agreed to
drop legal action that began when the movie studio sued estate
of the author of The Godfather to prevent the publication of
a sequel to the novel about a fictional Mafia family. </p>
<p>The parties voluntarily dismissed the lawsuit, according to
a stipulation filed Dec. 20 in federal court in Manhattan. No
details of any settlement were given. </p>
<p>The case is settled and we''re very happy about it,
Bertram Fields, a lawyer for the Puzo estate with Los Angeles-
based Greenberg Glusker Fields Claman  Machtinger LLP, said in
a telephone interview. Because of the confidentiality
provisions, I can''t disclose the terms of the settlement. </p>
<p>Paramount, a unit of Viacom Inc. (VIAB), sued Anthony Puzo,
Mario''s son and the executor of his estate, in February to stop
the publication of a new sequel to The Godfather, claiming
it wasn''t authorized. The heirs countersued in April to cancel
the contract between the studio and Mario Puzo. </p>
<p>U.S. District Judge Alison Nathan in September denied the
Puzos'' bid to terminate the agreement. </p>
<p>Paramount said in its complaint that after Puzo died in
1999, the company agreed to allow Bertelsmann AG''s Random House
to publish one Godfather sequel, The Godfather Returns,
which came out in 2004. The estate published another novel,
The Godfather''s Revenge, in 2006, without Paramount''s
approval, the studio said. Paramount sued after the estate
announced a plan to publish a third sequel, The Family
Corleone. </p>
<p>Richard Kendall, a lawyer for Paramount, didn''t immediately
return a message seeking comment on the dismissal. </p>
<p>The sequel, written by Ed Falco, was published in May by
Grand Central Publishing, a unit of Paris-based Hachette Livre
SA. The terms of an interim settlement reached earlier this year
between Paramount and Puzo stated that proceeds from the book
would be put in escrow pending the outcome of the litigation,
according to court papers. </p>
<p>A notice was mailed to the U.S. Register of Copyrights to
report the termination of the lawsuit, according to a court
filing. </p>
<p>The first Godfather film came out in 1972 and won the
Academy Awards for best picture and adapted screenplay, for
which Puzo shared the credit. Francis Ford Coppola directed the
three Godfather movies. </p>
<p>The case is Paramount Pictures v. Puzo, 12-01268, U.S.
District Court, Southern District of New York (Manhattan). </p>
<p>For more copyright news, click here. </p>
<h2>IP Moves </h2>
<h2>EFF Hires Daniel Nazer From Stanford''s CIS Fair Use Project </h2>
<p>The Electronic Frontier Foundation hired Daniel Nazer as a
staff attorney, the San Francisco-based digital rights advocacy
group said in a statement. </p>
<p>His hiring is funded as part of a $250,000 donation from
Dallas Mavericks owner Mark Cuban aimed at improvement of the
U.S. patent system. </p>
<p>Nazer joins EFF from Stanford Law School''s Center for
Internet and Society where he was a non-resident fellow at the
Fair Use Project. Before that, he practiced IP law at San
Francisco''s Keker  Van Nest LLP. </p>
<p>He has served as a judicial clerk to Justice Susan Kenny of
the Federal Court of Australia and to Chief Judge William K. Sessions III of U.S. District Court for the District of Vermont. </p>
<p>Nazer has an undergraduate degree in philosophy from the
University of Western Australia, a master''s degree in philosophy
from Rutgers University, and a law degree from Yale Law School. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Drew Armstrong" date="Dec 28, 2012  5:31 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-28/pfizer-bristol-myers-blood-thinner-approved-by-u-s-fda.html"><headline>Pfizer, Bristol-Myers Blood Thinner Approved by U.S. FDA</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Pfizer Inc. (PFE) and Bristol-Myers Squibb
Co. (BMY)''s blood thinner Eliquis was approved by U.S. regulators
after more than a year of review, giving the companies a new
potential blockbuster heart drug. </p>
<p>Eliquis was cleared by the Food and Drug Administration for
the prevention of blood clots that develop in patients with the
heart rhythm disorder atrial fibrillation, the agency said today
in a statement. The approval comes three months before the FDA''s
most-recent March deadline for a ruling on the drug, allowing
the two New York-based companies to start sales sooner. </p>
<p>The new anticoagulants are really exciting
developments, William Zoghbi, president of the American
College of Cardiology, said in a telephone interview. They
address some of the concerns that traditional warfarin has
offered. Warfarin is the half-century-old drug that has been
the standard of care before new medicines like Eliquis. </p>
<p>The government''s sign-off ends several setbacks in the
efforts by Pfizer and Bristol-Myers to win sales clearance for
the blood thinner. The FDA delayed approval in March 2012 and
rejected the therapy in June, saying it needed more data from
the companies'' clinical trials. Pfizer, the world''s largest
drugmaker, and Bristol-Myers will split sales, which may total
$5.2 billion by 2020, Catherine Arnold, an analyst at Credit
Suisse in New York, said in a note to clients. </p>
<p>Pfizer shares rose less than 1 percent in extended trading
to $24.99 at 4:57 p.m. New York time, after closing at $24.89.
Bristol-Myers rose 1.9 percent after closing at $31.90. </p>
<h2>Common Condition </h2>
<p>About 2.66 million people in the U.S. have atrial
fibrillation, the most common type of irregular heart beat,
according to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention in
Atlanta. The disease becomes more common with age. Patients have
a higher risk of blood clots, which can cause strokes, and of
heart failure. </p>
<p>Eliquis will provide another option for the prevention of
blood clots and strokes, and the drug showed in clinical trials
that it was more effective than warfarin, the FDA said in its
statement. It is among a group of new blood thinners such as
Boehringer Ingelheim GmbH''s Pradaxa and Johnson  Johnson (JNJ) and
Bayer AG (BAYN)''s Xarelto,  that are potential replacements for
warfarin, which requires regular blood monitoring by doctors. </p>
<p>The new drugs carry some risk of bleeding, as does
warfarin. Bleeding can happen in the stomach, under the surface
of the skin, or most dangerously, in the brain. </p>
<p>The new blood thinners offer a better trade-off between
bleeding and stroke-prevention, said Andrew Epstein, a professor
of medicine at the University of Pennsylvania in Philadelphia.
One intracranial bleed is a small price for the great decrease
in morbidity and mortality, Epstein said in a telephone
interview. There ain''t any free lunch. </p>
<p>Eliquis has been approved in Europe and Japan. Pfizer and
Bristol-Myers also want to gain approval for use in clots
elsewhere in the body, including the legs and lungs. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Grant Smith and Rupert Rowling" date="Dec 31, 2012  8:29 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2012-12-31/morgan-stanley-buys-north-sea-forties-crude-shell-total-bid.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Buys North Sea Forties Crude; Shell, Total Bid</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley bought a cargo of
North Sea Forties crude from BP Plc at the highest price in more
than a week, while Royal Dutch Shell Plc and Total SA placed
unsuccessful bids for cargoes. </p>
<p>Supplies from Angola will increase this month while output
from Nigeria will fall, according to researcher JBC Energy GmbH. </p>
<h2>North Sea </h2>
<p>Morgan Stanley paid 45 cents more than Dated Brent for a
shipment of Forties, F0108, loading on Jan. 14 to Jan. 16, a
Bloomberg survey of traders and brokers monitoring the Platts
pricing window showed. That''s the highest since Dec. 20, when a
Forties lot traded at a 60 cent premium. BP had bought lot F0108
at parity to the benchmark on Dec. 24. </p>
<p>Shell bid 55 cents more than Dated Brent for a cargo
loading on Jan. 14 to Jan. 16 and a second consignment on Jan.
19 to Jan. 21. Total bid 30 cents more than the benchmark for a
shipment on Jan. 23 to Jan. 28, according to the survey. </p>
<p>Trafigura Beheer BV offered a consignment of Forties on
Jan. 21 to Jan. 28 at 85 cents more than Dated Brent, without
finding a buyer. </p>
<p>Reported crude trading typically occurs during the Platts
window, which ended at 12:30 p.m. London time today, earlier
than its usual finish of 4:30 p.m. because of the New Year
holiday. Forties loading in 10 to 25 days was 4 cents less than
Dated Brent on Dec. 28, data compiled by Bloomberg show. That
compares with a 9 cent discount on Dec. 27. </p>
<p>Brent for February settlement traded at $109.55 a barrel on
the ICE Futures Europe exchange in London at the close of the
window, compared with $110 in the previous session. The March
contract was at $108.37 a discount of $1.18 to February. </p>
<h2>Mediterranean/Urals </h2>
<p>There were no bids or offers for Russian Urals grade,
according to the Platts survey. </p>
<p>The Urals differential to Dated Brent in the Mediterranean
was at minus $1.01 on Dec. 28, according to data compiled by
Bloomberg. In northwest Europe, the discount to Dated Brent was
at $1.35, the data showed. </p>
<h2>West Africa </h2>
<p>Qua Iboe blend was at $2.46 a barrel more than Dated Brent
on Dec. 28, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>Angola''s output will increase by 30,000 barrels a day in
December with the start of work at the project known as PSVM,
while Nigeria''s production will decline by 25,000 barrels a day
because of terrorist attacks, according to Vienna-based JBC
Energy. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By With assistance from Manish Modi" date="Jan 01, 2013  1:23 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-01-01/goldman-rate-cut-call-gains-ground-in-swap-market-india-credit.html"><headline>Goldman Rate-Cut Call Gains Ground in Swap Market: India Credit</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc.''s call for a
half percentage point interest-rate cut by India''s central bank
this month is gaining support in the swap market, where
borrowing costs fell for the third quarter. </p>
<p>The price of derivative contracts that fix rates for a year
fell two basis points last quarter to 7.61 percent, taking the
drop since March to 42 basis points, data compiled by Bloomberg
show. A similar measure rose 19 basis points to 3.34 percent in
China. Speculation that the Reserve Bank of India will ease
policy is strengthening after the government cut its estimate
for economic growth in the year through March to as little as
5.7 percent, the least in a decade, on Dec. 17. </p>
<p>RBI Governor Duvvuri Subbarao said last month that policy
makers'' focus needs to shift toward supporting the economy from
curbing inflation. Goldman Sachs forecasts the repurchase rate,
held at 8 percent since April, will be lowered to 7.5 percent at
the next review on Jan. 29, while BNP Paribas SA sees a 25 basis
point reduction. Eleven of 20 analysts surveyed by Bloomberg see
a 50 basis point decrease by March 31. </p>
<p>Indian markets are positioning for a rate-cutting cycle,
given the shift in RBI''s focus to growth from inflation,
Nagaraj Kulkarni, a Singapore-based strategist at Standard
Chartered Plc, said in an interview yesterday. We expect a 25
basis point reduction in the repo rate this quarter. </p>
<h2>Rate Outlook </h2>
<p>The one-year swap rate has slid 67 basis points, or 0.67
percentage point, from its 2012 peak of 8.26 percent in
February, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. The measure
declined seven basis points since Subbarao said Dec. 18 that
slowing inflation increases room for the central bank to ease
policy. Annual gains in the nation''s benchmark price index
slowed to 7.24 percent in November, the least since January. </p>
<p>The RBI has held its repo rate unchanged since April, when
it was lowered by 50 basis points in the first reduction since
2009. The benchmark was boosted by a record 375 basis points, or
3.75 percentage points, through 2010 and 2011 to contain the
fastest price increases among the largest emerging markets. </p>
<p>In view of inflation pressures ebbing, monetary policy
has to increasingly shift focus and respond to the threats to
growth, the RBI said in a statement on Dec. 18. </p>
<h2>Easing Cash </h2>
<p>Swap rates also declined as Subbarao took steps to ease a
cash squeeze at banks. Three-month interbank funding costs fell
by 92 basis points in 2012 to 8.92 percent as the RBI pumped
more than 2.7 trillion rupees into the financial system by
cutting lenders'' reserve requirements and buying sovereign debt.
The monetary authority cut the proportion of deposits lenders
must set aside as reserves by 175 basis points last year to a
36-year low of 4.25 percent. </p>
<p>The yield on 10-year government bonds slid 52 basis points
in 2012 as traders boosted rate-cut bets. The yield on the
benchmark 8.15 percent debt due June 2022 fell six basis points
today to 7.99 percent today, offering an extra amount of 629
basis points over U.S. Treasuries, while the rupee advanced 0.3
percent to 54.8150 per dollar. </p>
<p>We have a constructive outlook on Indian government
bonds, Standard Chartered''s Kulkarni said. Bonds are lagging
the swap curve in pricing in forthcoming rate cuts. </p>
<p>The cost to insure the debt of government-controlled State
Bank of India (SBIN), a proxy for the sovereign, for five years slid
172 basis points last year to 223, according to data provider
CMA, which is owned by McGraw-Hill Cos. and compiles prices
quoted by dealers in privately negotiated markets. Credit-
default swaps for China fell 82 basis points to 65. </p>
<p>Growth is a concern and expectations for a rate cut are
quite legitimate given that headline inflation is coming
lower, Lakshmi Iyer, Mumbai-based head of fixed income at
Kotak Mahindra Asset Management Co. overseeing the equivalent of
$5.6 billion, said in an interview yesterday. Markets are
pricing in a cut in the repo rate on Jan. 29 to 7.75 percent or
even 7.5 percent. </p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Christine Harper" date="Jan 02, 2013  9:13 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-01-02/goldman-sachs-sped-up-65-million-in-stock-awards.html"><headline>Goldman Sachs Sped Up $65 Million in Stock Awards</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) accelerated
delivery of $65 million in stock awards to 10 executives,
including Chief Executive Officer Lloyd C. Blankfein, helping
them avoid higher tax rates that take effect this year. </p>
<p>The awards are restricted stock granted for years prior to
2012, according to 10 separate filings made public at about 8
p.m. New York time on Dec. 31. Each executive surrendered 45
percent to 50 percent of their awards in order to pay taxes,
according to the filings. The firm''s stock climbed 41 percent in
2012, its first annual gain since 2009. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs, the fifth-biggest U.S. bank by assets,
typically delivers executives'' restricted stock during January.
The decision to speed up the delivery came as the U.S. Congress
debated and ultimately passed a bill that would increase tax
rates on capital gains and on individuals who make taxable
income of $400,000 or more. </p>
<p>The December delivery of shares went to a wider group of
employees than the named executive officers who were included
in the filings, said Michael DuVally, a spokesman for the New
York-based firm. He declined to comment on the reason for the
accelerated delivery or on which other employees received stock
early. </p>
<p>Blankfein, 58, has said he would be willing to pay higher
taxes if they were part of a fiscal compromise to reduce the
budget deficit. Today he praised the bill that passed the House
of Representatives yesterday. </p>
<h2>Step Forward'' </h2>
<p>This agreement is a step forward to injecting growth and
investor confidence into the U.S. economy, he said in an e-
mailed statement. While more progress clearly will be needed,
particularly in regards to restraining the growth in government
spending, this measure lays the foundation for more economic
growth. </p>
<p>Blankfein received 66,065 shares of restricted stock on
Dec. 31, worth $8.43 million at the closing share price that
day, according to a company filing. The filing shows that he
sold 33,245 shares for $126.24 apiece, although a footnote
explains that those shares were in fact retained by the company
to satisfy withholding obligations. </p>
<h2>Changing Landscape </h2>
<p>One of Goldman Sachs''s Wall Street rivals took a different
approach to the changing tax landscape. Jefferies Group Inc. (JEF),
the investment bank that agreed in November to sell itself to
its biggest owner, Leucadia National Corp. (LUK), accelerated the
delivery of dividends to all shareholders, including executives,
on Dec. 31, according to company filings. </p>
<p>We expedited the regular dividend payment for all
Jefferies shareholders in anticipation of increased rates, the
New York-based firm said in a statement. Our top executives
were treated identically to every other shareholder. </p>
<p>Some of the executives'' dividends were awarded as deferred
stock, according to the filings. Those shares will be taxed at
the higher rates when they ultimately vest, the company said.
Jefferies CEO Richard Handler, 51, received 36,872 deferred
shares at $18.57 each, worth $684,713. Brian Friedman, 57,
chairman of Jefferies''s executive committee, got 9,321 shares at
that price, valued at $173,091. </p>
<p>Gary D. Cohn, 52, Goldman Sachs''s president and chief
operating officer, and David A. Viniar, 57, the firm''s chief
financial officer, received the same number of shares as
Blankfein and had the same amount withheld, according to
filings. </p>
<h2>Surrendered Shares </h2>
<p>The other executives who received and surrendered shares
for withholding purposes were Vice Chairmen John S. Weinberg,
55, and J. Michael Evans, 55; Edith Cooper, the 51-year-old head
of human capital management; John F.W. Rogers, the firm''s 56-
year-old chief of staff; General Counsel Gregory K. Palm, 64;
Global Head of Compliance Alan M. Cohen, 62; and Chief
Accounting Officer Sarah Smith. </p>
<p>Goldman Sachs is required to file disclosures of changes in
stock ownership by its 12 executive officers. The firm made no
disclosures of stock activity on Dec. 31 by Vice Chairman
Michael S. Sherwood, a 47-year-old British citizen based in
London, or by Mark Schwartz, the Hong Kong-based head of the
firm''s Asian business. Schwartz, a 58-year-old U.S. citizen,
rejoined the firm in June after 11 years away. </p>
<p>Below is a table of stock delivered to each of the Goldman
Sachs executives and the amount surrendered for withholding
purposes, according to company filings. </p>
<p>*T Executive           Stock Delivered     Stock Surrendered </p>
<h2>for Withholding </h2>
<p>Lloyd C. Blankfein      66,065              33,245
Gary D. Cohn            66,065              33,245
David A. Viniar         66,065              33,245
John S. Weinberg        66,065              30,438
J. Michael Evans        66,065              29,896
Edith W. Cooper         45,126              20,791
John F.W. Rogers        41,876              19,294
Gregory K. Palm         36,860              18,549
Alan M. Cohen           30,085              15,141
Sarah G. Smith          23,832              11,994 </p>
<p>(Source: Company filings) </p>




]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Silla Brush and Matthew Leising" date="Jan 02, 2013  9:02 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-01-02/jpmorgan-to-barclays-register-as-swap-dealers-under-dodd-frank.html"><headline>JPMorgan Among 65 to Register as Swap Dealers Under Dodd-Frank</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM), Goldman Sachs
Group Inc. (GS) and Barclays Plc (BARC) are among the first banks to
register swap-dealer divisions under the Dodd-Frank Act, which
requires higher capital, collateral and trading standards. </p>
<p>The 65 trading units that have registered include the
biggest banks in the U.S., U.K., France, Germany, Switzerland
and Japan, according to the Commodity Futures Trading
Commission. The list, which is expected to grow, reflects
companies that had at least $8 billion in swap-dealing business
in October and had to register by the end of last year. </p>
<p>This is at the heart of financial reform: dealers
registering and coming under common-sense rules of business
practice, reporting, capital and margin and that the public gets
to see the actual transactions, CFTC Chairman Gary Gensler
said in a telephone interview yesterday. </p>
<p>The Dodd-Frank rules, more than two years in the making,
seek to improve oversight of a market that for three decades
largely escaped federal regulation. The law was enacted after
swap trades helped fuel the 2008 credit crisis and led to the
U.S. rescue of American International Group Inc. </p>
<p>Swap dealers will eventually face the highest requirements
for capital and collateral to back their trades and will have
the stiffest reporting and trading standards. The financial
firms that dominate swap dealing generate more than $30 billion
in annual profit, according to an estimate from consulting firm
Oliver Wyman, a unit of Marsh  McLennan Cos. (MMC) </p>
<h2>Full Force </h2>
<p>Swap dealers won''t immediately face the full force of Dodd-
Frank regulations, with capital and margin rules yet to be
completed by U.S. or international authorities. A requirement to
guarantee trades at central clearinghouses doesn''t take effect
in the U.S. until mid-March at the earliest for interest-rate
and credit trades. Rules governing swap-trading platforms have
yet to be completed. The CFTC also is still debating when Dodd-
Frank rules will apply to overseas trades. </p>
<p>With their registration, swap dealers will begin reporting
interest-rate and credit trades to databases. This is changed
market behavior, Gensler said. As of Monday, there was the
public seeing the transaction price and volume. We had never had
that before. </p>
<p>The list of 65 entities includes the biggest U.S. swaps
dealers, according to the Office of the Comptroller of the
Currency. JPMorgan leads the list with $72 trillion in
derivatives contracts outstanding at the end of September,
according to the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency. Bank
of America Corp. (BAC) follows with $64 trillion and Citigroup Inc. (C) is
third-largest with $55 trillion. There''s no comparable ranking
for banks globally. </p>
<h2>Six Divisions </h2>
<p>The list also includes six Goldman Sachs divisions,
including commodities trading arm J. Aron  Co. that was once
managed by Lloyd C. Blankfein, the bank''s CEO. Morgan Stanley
registered six entities, including London-based unit Morgan
Stanley  Co. International Plc. </p>
<p>The CFTC had estimated that there would be about 125
entities registering as dealers. I think it''s an initial list
and that there will be others, Gensler said. </p>
<p>Energy companies that lobbied on the swap dealer definition
including BP Plc, Shell Energy North America LP and Vitol Inc.
weren''t on the initial list. The CFTC in October delayed a
requirement to count energy trades guaranteed at clearinghouses
to determine if a company crossed the $8 billion threshold. I
would anticipate over time that we would see some particularly
if people are transacting or dealing over $8 billion of swaps in
the bilateral world, Gensler said. </p>
<h2>Energy Traders </h2>
<p>John Parsons, a professor at the Massachusetts Institute of
Technology, said he was surprised that Shell and BP weren''t on
the initial list because of the size of their derivatives-
trading businesses. Presumably that will happen as the list
grows, he said in a telephone interview yesterday. If it
doesn''t that will be very telling about the regulations. </p>
<p>Gensler said last March when the agency was preparing to
complete the rule defining swap dealers that it was very
clear the intent was to apply to financial and non-financial
firms. </p>
<p>In the past some entities were left out of regulation
just because of what they called themselves, Gensler said on
March 2. I think it would be a mistake to end up with this
era''s Enron loophole, and something that might be a loophole for
others. </p>
<p>In 2000, certain electronic markets were excluded from
commission oversight under the so-called Enron loophole, named
for the energy company that collapsed in late 2001. I think it
would be a mistake to end up with what would be sort of this
era''s BP loophole, Gensler said. </p>
<p>Deutsche Bank AG (DBK) registered energy trading unit DB Energy
Trading LLC, while JPMorgan registered J.P. Morgan Ventures
Energy Corp. </p>
<p>CFTC list of provisionally registered swap dealers: </p>

Bank of America NA
Bank of Montreal
Bank of New York
Mellon Bank of Nova Scotia
Bank of Tokyo Mitsubishi UFJ Ltd.
Barclays Bank Plc
BNP Paribas
Canadian Imperial Bank of Commerce
Citibank NA Citigroup Energy Inc.
Citigroup Global Markets Inc.
Commerzbank AG
Commonwealth Bank of Australia
Credit Agricole
Corporate and Investment Bank
Credit Suisse International
DB Energy Trading LLC
Deutsche Bank AG
Goldman Sachs  Co.
Goldman Sachs Bank USA
Goldman Sachs Financial Markets LP
Goldman Sachs International
Goldman Sachs Mitsui Marine Derivative Products LP
Hongkong  Shanghai Banking Corp. Ltd.
HSBC Bank Plc
HSBC Bank USA NA
ING Capital Markets LLC
Intl Hanley LLC
J Aron  Co.
JPMorgan Securities LLC
JPMorgan Ventures Energy Corp.
JPMorgan Chase Bank
Macquarie Bank Ltd.
Macquarie Energy LLC
Merrill Lynch Capital Services Inc.
Merrill Lynch Commodities Inc.
Merrill Lynch Financial Markets Inc.
Merrill Lynch International
Merrill Lynch International Bank Ltd.
Mitsubishi UFJ Securities International Plc
Mizuho Capital Markets Corp.
Mizuho Securities USA Inc.
Morgan Stanley  Co. International Plc
Morgan Stanley  Co. LLC
Morgan Stanley Bank NA
Morgan Stanley Capital Group Inc.
Morgan Stanley Capital Services LLC
Morgan Stanley Derivative Products Inc.
National Australia Bank Ltd.
Natixis Newedge UK Financial Ltd.
Newedge USA LLC
Nomura Derivative Products Inc.
Nomura Global Financial Products Inc.
Nomura International Plc
Royal Bank of Canada
SMBC Capital Markets Inc.
Societe Generale SA
Standard Chartered Bank
State Street Bank And Trust Co.
The Royal Bank Of Scotland Plc
Toronto Dominion Bank 
UBS AG
US Bank NA
Wells Fargo Bank NA
Westpac Banking Corp.

<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Steven Church" date="Jan 03, 2013  4:12 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-01-03/disney-seeks-to-halt-bankruptcy-sale-of-3-d-technology.html"><headline>Disney Seeks to Halt Bankruptcy Sale of 3-D Technology</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>A Walt Disney Co. (DIS) unit asked a
federal judge to block a bankruptcy court ruling that would
allow another company to sell patents related to three-
dimensional movies. </p>
<p>Walt Disney Studios Motion Picture Production''s rights to
use the technology to convert traditional films into 3-D movies
will be harmed, the company said in its appeal yesterday in U.S.
District Court in Wilmington, Delaware. </p>
<p>The dispute involves the shell company left in bankruptcy
by the collapse of Digital Domain Media Group Inc., the provider
of special effects for the movies Transformers and
Titanic. That shell, known as DDMG Estate, held an auction
for the patents last month that was won by RealD Inc. (RLD) </p>
<p>Disney claims it has the right to use the technology
because of agreements it signed with the original patent holder
in 2008 and 2009. The agreements allowed Disney to use the 3D
conversion patents on the films Alice in Wonderland and G-
Force. </p>
<p>The G-Force agreement granted Disney the right to keep
using the 3D patents, Burbank, California-based Disney claims in
its appeal. </p>
<h2>In Perpetuity'' </h2>
<p>In a Dec. 10 ruling, U.S. Bankruptcy Judge Brendan Linehan Shannon disagreed with Disney''s position. The dispute raised the
question of whether Disney could use that technology, gratis,
in perpetuity, Shannon said in his ruling. He ruled the
company could not. </p>
<p>After his ruling, RealD won the auction with a bid of $5.45
million and Shannon later approved the sale, which hasn''t yet
closed. </p>
<p>U.S. District Judge Sue L. Robinson agreed to hold a
telephone hearing tomorrow so Disney can try to persuade her to
overturn Shannon''s ruling and temporarily prevent DDMG from
closing the sale. </p>
<p>DDMG lawyer Debra Grassgreen, with the law firm Pachulski,
Stang, Ziehl  Jones, declined to comment on Disney''s filing. </p>
<p>The other assets of Digital Domain (DDMGQ) were sold at a separate
auction in September for more than $30 million to a partnership
of Chinese and Indian film companies. </p>
<p>Digital Domain''s special-effects artists have won multiple
Academy Awards, including one for the Brad Pitt movie, The
Curious Case of Benjamin Button. </p>
<p>The appeal is In re: DDMG Estate, 13-cv-00007, U.S.
District Court, District of Delaware (Wilmington). </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Mulholland" date="Jan 03, 2013 12:50 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-01-03/morgan-stanley-said-to-lead-banks-prepping-8-billion-of-cmbs.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Said to Lead Banks Prepping $8 Billion of CMBS</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS) and Bank of America
Corp. (BAC) are marketing $1.4 billion of commercial-mortgage backed
securities as sales surge to the highest in five years. </p>
<p>The lenders plan to sell the bonds, linked to 123
properties spanning the U.S. from Manhattan to Riverside,
California, as soon as next week, according to people familiar
with the deal who declined to be identified because terms aren''t
public. Wall Street is planning as much as $8 billion in deals
for January, the highest monthly volume since Dec. 2007,
according to Deutsche Bank AG. </p>
<p>Banks are selling off commercial mortgages accumulated
during the fourth quarter as investor demand for risky assets
surges with the Federal Reserve holding interest rates at almost
zero for more than four years. The debt got a boost yesterday
after lawmakers reached an agreement to avert tax increases on
most Americans, with the relative yield on a benchmark issue
offered by Goldman Sachs Group Inc. and Royal Bank of Scotland
Group Plc in 2007 narrowing 15 basis points to 123 basis more
than the benchmark swap rate, according to Stephen Schwartz, who
trades the debt at RBC Capital Markets in New York. </p>
<p>CMBS joined in the significant rally seen across risk
markets on the back of the fiscal cliff deal, Schwartz said.
With more policy risk on the immediate horizon, increased
volatility in broader markets is anticipated. However, given the
strong technical tone underlying CMBS, volatility in this sector
should be reduced. </p>
<p>The legislation passed this week doesn''t address spending
cuts or the debt ceiling, meaning U.S. politicians are likely
headed for battle during the next two months. </p>
<h2>Strong Outlook'' </h2>
<p>Top-ranked securities linked to commercial mortgages are
yielding 103 basis points, or 1.03 percentage point, more than
Treasuries, according to a Barclays Plc index. The spread fell
to 87 basis points on Dec. 14, the lowest since at least 2007,
before climbing as Congress and President Barack Obama sparred
over a budget compromise. The spread was 247 basis points a year
ago, the index shows. </p>
<p>The markets are starting off with a strong outlook, but
there is a lot less room for error than in prior years,
Schwartz of RBC said. </p>
<p>Sales of bonds tied to shopping malls, skyscrapers and
hotels are poised to climb 50 percent to $60 billion in 2013 as
yield-starved investors chase bonds tied to everything from
commercial real estate to speculative-grade companies. Sales of
junk bonds in the U.S. market were a record $354.3 billion last
year, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p>
<p>The CMBS market is recovering after shutting down when
credit markets froze in 2008, Bloomberg data show. A record $232
billion was sold in 2007, the data show. </p>
<p>Late payments on commercial mortgages contained in bonds
climbed to records this year as property owners that piled on
debt during the boom failed to find financing for maturing
loans, though the rate has fallen in the past six months,
according to Trepp LLC. The delinquency rate was unchanged last
month at 9.71 percent, the New York-based commercial-mortgage
data provider said in a statement today. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Michael J. Moore" date="Jan 04, 2013  7:00 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-01-04/morgan-stanley-gives-taubman-1-7-million-retirement-deal.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Says Taubman to Remain Employee Until May</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Morgan Stanley (MS), the sixth-largest
U.S. bank by assets, said Paul J. Taubman will receive 2012
deferred compensation that will vest upon his departure in May
and will get an accelerated retirement package. </p>
<p>Taubman, who oversaw investment banking at Morgan Stanley,
will remain an employee of the New York-based bank until May 5,
according to a regulatory filing yesterday. The acceleration of
his executive retirement plan is worth $1.7 million, based on
his 27 years at the firm, according to the filing. </p>
<p>Taubman, 51, announced his retirement in November as Colm Kelleher, 55, took control of the investment banking business in
addition to his oversight of the firm''s trading operations.
Taubman and Kelleher had run the bank''s institutional securities
group since 2010. </p>
<p>His deferred compensation from previous years will vest on
May 5, and his 2012 awards will be distributed over four
installments through December 2014, the firm said in the filing.
The total value of his retirement package wasn''t disclosed. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Donal Griffin and Cecile Vannucci" date="Jan 04, 2013  5:50 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-01-04/goldman-sachs-tells-clients-to-bet-on-citigroup-before-earnings.html"><headline>Buy Citigroup Options Before Earnings, Goldman Sachs Advises</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Goldman Sachs Group Inc. (GS) told clients
to bet on Citigroup Inc. (C) shares before fourth-quarter earnings
later this month as new Chief Executive Officer Michael Corbat
cuts costs and withdraws from some markets. </p>
<p>Investors should buy call options on shares in Citigroup
before the bank announces its results Jan. 17, Goldman Sachs
said today in a note to clients. Calls are contracts that
provide the right to buy shares at a certain price. The New
York-based firm also added Citigroup to its conviction buy
list and said shares could rise to $49 within a year. </p>
<p>Corbat, 52, who replaced Vikram Pandit in October, is
laying off thousands of workers and pulling out of some
countries as he seeks to reduce costs at Citigroup. His plans,
announced last month, make the New York-based bank the best
large-cap restructuring story, Goldman Sachs analysts led by
Richard Ramsden said in another note. </p>
<p>Under new CEO Michael Corbat, we believe Citi is poised
to improve returns and increase efficiency, the analysts
wrote. Citi shares are mispriced given the company''s core
earnings power, especially considering further restructuring
could generate additional upside for shares. </p>
<p>Citigroup climbed 2.5 percent to close at $42.43 in New
York, outpacing the 1.7 percent gain of the 24-company KBW Bank
Index. (BKX) The shares have increased 7.3 percent this year. </p>




Photographer: Scott Eells/Bloomberg

<p>
Investors should buy call options on shares in Citigroup before the bank announces its earnings results Jan. 17, Goldman Sachs said today in a note to clients. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Sarah Frier" date="Jan 04, 2013  4:39 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-01-04/ibm-s-services-chief-will-step-down.html"><headline>IBM''s Services Chief Will Step Down</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>International Business Machines Corp. (IBM)
said Senior Vice President Mike Daniels is retiring after 36
years with the company, leaving two lieutenants in charge of
services, the company''s biggest division. </p>
<p>Daniels, 58, will leave Armonk, New York-based IBM on March
31. Instead of replacing him, Erich Clementi, senior vice
president for global technology services, and Bridget van Kralingen, senior vice president for global business services,
will now report to the chief executive officer, said Ed Barbini,
a company spokesman. </p>
<p>Daniels ran a business that accounted for about 60 percent
of revenue at IBM, the world''s largest provider of computer
services. He also was seen as a potential CEO candidate before
Ginni Rometty took the post a year ago. Daniels made his mark as
a cost cutter, helping boost IBM''s margins in recent years. </p>
<p>Daniels joined IBM straight out of college, with a
trajectory similar to Rometty''s through experience in sales and
services. In 2005, when then-CEO Sam Palmisano split the
services business into consulting and technology units, Daniels
first took over only the latter. </p>
<h2>Cost Cutter </h2>
<p>Daniels fired thousands of employees and moved jobs to
lower-cost regions such as India to trim expenses and boost
profits. IBM has a five-year plan to reach annual operating
earnings of at least $20 a share by 2015, up from $13.44 in
2011. </p>
<p>Rometty took the reins at IBM in January of last year,
becoming the company''s ninth CEO and first female leader. In
October, she became chairman of IBM''s board, replacing
Palmisano. </p>
<p>During her tenure, she has filled two other senior
executive positions with internal candidates. Bruno Di Leo took
the head of sales job she held before becoming CEO. Van
Kralingen was promoted to head of business services a year ago,
replacing Frank Kern, who retired after 35 years at the company.
Kern in October became CEO at Aricent Group, a technology
consulting firm. </p>
<p>IBM shares fell 0.7 percent to $193.99 at the close in New
York. The stock climbed 4.2 percent in 2012, marking its fourth
straight year of gains. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By David Scheer" date="Jan 04, 2013  4:24 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-01-04/morgan-stanley-says-paul-taubman-to-remain-employee-until-may.html"><headline>Morgan Stanley Says Paul Taubman to Remain Employee Until May</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Paul J. Taubman, the Morgan Stanley (MS)
investment bank co-president who announced in November that he
planned to retire at the end of 2012, will remain employed until
May 5, the bank said today in a regulatory filing. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Joe Carroll and Rebecca Penty" date="Jan 04, 2013  4:04 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-01-04/exxon-to-spend-14-billion-on-hebron-field-off-canada-s-coast.html"><headline>Exxon to Spend $14 Billion on Hebron Field Off Canada</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Exxon Mobil Corp. (XOM) and four partners will spend about $14 billion to develop the Hebron oil field off the coast of Canada that has lain fallow since its discovery more than three decades ago. </p> <p>The field, located about 350 kilometers (218 miles) southeast of St John''s, Newfoundland and Labrador, will produce more than 700 million barrels of crude during its lifespan, Irving, Texas-based Exxon said in a statement today. At current prices, that oil would be worth about $77.8 billion. </p> <p>Daily output from the field is expected to peak at 150,000 barrels after production begins in 2017, Exxon said. Discovered in 1980, Hebron is one of a string of multibillion-dollar projects Chief Executive Officer Rex Tillerson is pursuing to reverse production declines. Exxon''s output has fallen five straight quarters, the longest run of declines since 2008-2009, according to data compiled by Bloomberg. </p> <p>Exxon has been growth-challenged for some time, Brian Youngberg, an analyst at Edward Jones  Co. in St. Louis, said in a telephone interview today. Hebron can potentially help jump-start growth going forward. </p> <p>Exxon is operator of the Hebron development and owns a 36 percent stake, according to the project''s website. Other partners include Chevron Corp. (CVX), Suncor Energy Inc. (SU), Statoil ASA (STL) and Nalcor Energy Corp. </p> <p>The Hebron field is located about 30 kilometers southeast of the Exxon-operated Hibernia development, the largest single source of crude in Newfoundland and Labrador province. </p> <p>Previous plans to develop Hebron collapsed in 2006 amid a dispute with provincial officials over ownership stakes. Chevron, the second-largest U.S. oil company, later ceded control of the project to Exxon. </p> <p>Oil production from Newfoundland fields declined 29 percent during the first nine months of 2012, the provincial department of finance said on its website. </p> <p>Exxon rose 0.5 percent to $88.96 at the close in New York. </p> <p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Tom Giles" date="Jan 04, 2013 12:42 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-01-04/microsoft-windows-notebook-sales-drop-during-holidays-npd-says.html"><headline>Microsoft Windows Notebook Sales Drop During Holidays, NPD Says</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Microsoft Corp. (MSFT)''s Windows notebook
sales declined during the year-end holiday season as consumers
shunned traditional computers and flocked instead to other types
of electronics, according to NPD Group. </p>
<p>Windows notebook holiday unit sales fell 11 percent,
according to the Port Washington, New York-based researcher.
Sales of Windows notebooks that cost less than $500 fell 16
percent, NPD said today. </p>
<p>The introduction of the new Windows 8 software failed to
stoke much demand for notebooks boasting Microsoft''s flagship
operating system, NPD said. The figures released today exclude
tablets, such as Microsoft''s Surface and Apple Inc. (AAPL)''s iPad. </p>
<p>Despite the hype, and hope, around the launch of Windows
8, the new operating system did little to boost holiday sales or
improve the year-long Windows notebook sales decline, the
researcher wrote in a statement. </p>
<p>Apple MacBook sales also declined 6 percent during the
period, according to NPD. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Robert Schmidt and Jesse Hamilton" date="Jan 04, 2013 12:28 PM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-01-04/jpmorgan-faces-sanction-for-refusing-to-provide-madoff-documents.html"><headline>JPMorgan Faces Sanction for Withholding Madoff Documents</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>The U.S. Treasury Department''s inspector general has threatened to punish JPMorgan Chase  Co. (JPM) for failing to turn over documents to regulators investigating the bank''s ties to Bernard Madoff''s Ponzi scheme. </p> <p>Inspector General Eric Thorson gave the largest U.S. bank a Jan. 11 deadline to cooperate with the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency probe or risk sanctions for impeding the agency''s oversight. JPMorgan, according to the Dec. 21 letter, contends the information is protected by attorney-client privilege. </p> <p>Thorson''s letter didn''t spell out what documents the OCC is seeking or the focus of its investigation. Madoff is serving a 150-year sentence after confessing to the fraud that once claimed to have $65 billion in customer assets. </p> <p>The previously undisclosed OCC probe adds to the lender''s troubles in Washington, where several agencies and lawmakers are investigating the bank''s loss of at least $6.2 billion on botched derivatives trades. The losses have prompted regulators including the Federal Reserve to consider tightening proposed restrictions on proprietary trading. </p> <p>Jennifer Zuccarelli, a JPMorgan spokeswoman, said the bank will of course continue to work together with our regulators on the investigation. </p>




Photographer: Andrew Harrer/Bloomberg

<p>
Eric Thorson, inspector general of the Department of the Treasury, is seen here at a hearing on Wall Street and the Financial Crisis in Washington, D.C. on April 16, 2010. Close
</p>
]]> </body></entry><entry author="By Nariman Gizitdinov" date="Jan 04, 2013  6:01 AM ET" url="http://bloomberg.com/news/2013-01-04/chevron-led-kazakh-venture-ramps-up-output-as-power-restored.html"><headline>Chevron-Led Kazakh Venture Boosts Output as Power Restored</headline><body><![CDATA[
<p>Tengizchevroil LLP, a Chevron Corp (CVX).-
led Kazakh oil venture, will reach full production as soon as
possible after power at gas-processing and injection plants was
restored. </p>
<p>Operations at Tengiz partially lost electric power on
Jan. 3 due to a malfunction in one of its power-generation
turbines and failure of the Kazakhstan Electricity Grid
Operating Co.''s system, Atyrau-based Tengizchevroil said today
in an e-mailed statement without giving a specific date for full
production. </p>
<p>The Astana-based grid operator said in a separate e-mail
that the problem was with the venture''s electricity lines. </p>
<p>]]> </body></entry></news>